[Music]
so yeah i'm chuck willis and uh as i
mentioned you know this is we're gonna
be talking here about data at rest
encryption it's gonna actually you know
kind of follow on from the keynote that
we just had so i'm excited to get into
this topic
so just quick note about me i think he
already did a bit of the introduction
just uh i am in the dc area so i'm part
of the oauth northern virginia chapter
when there has been a marylander dc
chapter i usually participate in those
as well
i also um a while ago created the oauth
broken web applications project it's a
virtual machine full of web applications
with various types of vulnerabilities
you can use it for training or for
testing tools that sort of thing
if uh
you have any
uh i haven't updated that in a while so
but the the current version still works
it's a virtual machine so it actually
you know it gets more and more
vulnerability as time goes on it's the
the libraries and components that it
uses get older and older so
definitely check that out and uh my just
a random fact my favorite movie
the blues brothers i'm originally from
the chicago area so i think you're kind
of required to like that movie if you're
from that area
so i'm going to let weiss introduce
himself
hey everyone my name is weiss
i spent 20 years in the infosec
community
and
focused mostly on incident response and
threat countermeasures
as well as encryption and cryptography
i'm based in san diego so part of the
oauth san diego community
and i've lived in germany the us
singapore and japan and randomly my
favorite pizza topping is boringly
cheese
i'm glad you said it i wasn't gonna i
wasn't gonna call out the boringness of
the cheap topic
so here's a quick uh note of what we're
going to talk about so just really a
quick primer on cryptography
and encryption and key management just
to kind of make sure everyone's on the
same page
and then
uh weiss is really going to go into
detail on kind of you know the issues
with the current you know data at rest
encryption approaches that are used and
you know why that's a problem and then
i'll come back at the end to talk more
about you know some alternative
approaches that can help in kind of
closing the gap that's there
um we'll also have you know up till the
end of the end of the hour as far as for
q a so if you've got questions yeah
please submit those through the hoover
platform
and uh also you know keep an eye on that
as far as if you see questions that
you're interested in hearing us answer
you know upload those so that way
they'll kind of work their way to the
top and uh glenn will provide those at
the end
so yeah so cryptographic failures you
may know that from the new 2021 um oauth
top 10. so
um you can see that it used to be kind
of rolled into a bunch of other things
as part of sensitive data exposure uh in
but uh now it's been broken out into
kind of its own its own um separate line
item on the os top 10 uh as
cryptographic failures and it's also
moved up in popularity it's it's gone
above
um
injection and you know really above
everything else other than broken access
control so it's a very common problem
nowadays that people are recognizing i
think it's been around for a while it's
just that it's uh become more to the
forefront maybe uh partially because
we're trying to deal with things like
sql injection and cross-site scripting a
lot better as far as kind of the
framework layer
um so as those are less common that we
see you know access control and
cryptographic failures become kind of
relatively more common
um and if you look at the
uh the kind of the documentation for the
oauth top 10 that's on the website the
exact the first scenario here uh that's
shown is exactly kind of what we want to
talk about today so
in this case it's a it's at the example
it's an application that has credit card
numbers that it wants to protect
but the way it's protecting them is it's
got you know automatic database
encryption happening so there's you know
transparent encryption at either the
database or the the files
kind of block storage level
and
therefore
because it's automatically getting
encrypted and decrypted when you have a
sql injection flaw in the application
it's just going to pull out all the
decrypted data so there's no it's the
even though it's encrypted it's not you
know providing protection against this
type of attack
so
like i said uh
uh cryptographic dealers have been
around a while so you might think
they're the new kid on the block but in
reality they're more like the upper
right corner here it's the the current
version of the new kids on the block as
far as from their 2021 tour
promos so
it's uh it's been around for a long
time so let's go a little bit more in
detail into the situation so
you know you talk about cryptography i
mean cryptography you know existed long
before computers so they had you know
this type of instrument in the upper
right is you know a thing for a caesar
type cipher simple substitution cipher
um you have the enigma machines and
other sorts of kind of mechanical and
various sorts of cryptographic
systems that were around and so when
computer security came around both
computers came around the you know an
obvious application for them was
cryptography but also an obvious um kind
of mechanism that could be used as part
of securing computers was was
cryptography
and you know for you know some number of
years computer security really did focus
on cryptography they were really
concerned about this type of thing of
you know hey we want to you know encrypt
some data that's going to be sent over
you know an untrusted media medium like
you know radio waves therefore we need
to you know have
the ability to encrypt it and decrypt it
and there was quite a bit of work has
been done over the years into you know
algorithms and modes that are very
resistant to you know various types of
attacks so
uh you know on the left here lower left
we've got a kind of a diagram of the aes
algorithm and kind of the rounds that it
uses for you know encryption on the left
and decryption on the right going up
um on the bottom here we have the cipher
block chaining kind of mode of
encryption that allows you to
you know be more resistant to changes to
data or mixing of packets and things
like that so there's a there's been a
lot of work into that and it's it's paid
off pretty well
so you know if you're looking at kind of
directly attacking you know kind of
modern cryptography it's it's very
strong
you know not to say it's perfect you
know maybe nation states uh have the
ability to do certain things but i think
even in those cases you've got you know
additional mechanisms you can use if
you're really that concerned about you
know the cryptography itself
so one example is you could layer
encryption so you could have multiple
algorithms that are you know used at
different layers
uh example that might be you know you
might have a layer two encryption device
that does kind of point-to-point vpn
type connections and then have a layer 3
or a session layer https type encryption
on top of that
and uh
so so that's one option i know the
government sometimes will use multiple
types of commercial
you know vpn devices kind of layered on
top of one another in order to provide
additional security so even if there's a
vulnerability in you know
acme product uh then hopefully it's not
going to affect you know the other
product as well so by having kind of
these completely separate things layered
on top of one another you're giving
yourself a lot better
uh protection against attacks
um and then for some algorithms like
hashing algorithms or um in like rsa uh
asymmetric algorithms you know you can
basically have keys as long as you want
um so if you're really concerned about
brute force then you know you can make
that basically impractical um if you're
hashing passwords you can you know make
the um process to hash the password down
to the um
you know hash value take you know as
long as you want
so to make uh you know password stopping
type attacks take longer
and uh so there's uh quite a bit of
flexibility there
they've even got you know crypto
algorithms that have been designed to to
be resistant to quantum computing so
even if constant computers become you
know practical
then you could potentially uh
you know not have to worry about that as
far as in your system it might be worth
looking at if you're if you're building
kind of a
truss anchor that's going to be used for
for quite some time
and then there's also you know hardware
cryptographic devices so there's devices
that'll give you you know secure random
numbers that'll and devices that will
kind of come with pre-baked and keys
that you know can't be extracted so the
only way to encrypt or decrypt data is
to pass it to this cryptographic device
and it will
give you back the corresponding
ciphertext or plain text
but it basically prevents you from
losing the keys because they can never
leave the device
and you'll you can see microsoft i
believe is making use of the trusted
platform module on windows 11 to do some
of this kind of stuff to have kind of
that pressing root of the overall system
and then you know so the only real
limitation when it comes to kind of
layering these things or other things
that i just mentioned is performance so
if you're concerned about you know how
much your latency is going to be
affected or what your bandwidth is going
to be
then that's you know the only thing
really that you need to worry about but
the good thing is that you know
computers keeping faster and networks
keep getting bigger so i think that you
know you can pretty much wait a little
bit and uh
make up for that
so the the problem really as a as the
previous you know keynote speaker talked
about is really cheese so you need to
have severe cryptographic keys um if you
look in the bottom left there we've got
the the guy from the matrix the key
maker so you've got to make sure that
you're creating keys that are um
that are secure and you've got you know
secure source of randomness or whatever
to generate those keys
but it's more than just making the keys
there's a whole life cycle that goes
around keys so not just the generation
that's shown here but also where you're
storing them how do you distribute them
rotating and expiration all the stuff
that
goes into it so you don't just need a
key maker you really need the key master
so
this is just a bunch of quotes that from
various people that have uh said what uh
i think it's already been said today as
well it's you know really key management
is the hard part and
my favorite one is the one in the middle
here that you know cryptography turns
hard security problems into hard key
management problems
so it so that's not to say that you know
cryptography is is is worthless i mean
it's certainly helping you it's giving
you a a way of making the problem more
manageable but it does you know not
remove it entirely you've got to worry
about you know how are you going to
manage the keys that are associated with
this encrypted data and protect them
appropriately because that's where the
attackers are going to go after
and then just again as a primer just so
uh you know there's two types of uh used
use cases really for encryption so
you've got the ability to have uh
protection of data in transit so while
it's traversing the network um this is a
a
simpler problem i suppose then what
we'll talk about in a second because you
know there's a short period of time
between at least when the data is
encrypted and decrypted or signed and
verified
at least that's the intention um so you
can have um you know ephemeral keys
maybe that you you use some sort of
secure key exchange to come up with uh
as long as you have you know some sort
of trust anchor to make sure you're
creating the keys with the right people
um
you know you do need to worry about you
know what if somebody's gonna you know
capture all your network traffic and
then try to analyze it later so you want
it to be resistant against attacks in
the long term but as far as being able
to decrypt the data you don't
necessarily have to store the keys you
can as long as you have them for the
period of time the short period of time
that you need to decrypt them
and then the opposite is data so while
data is stored you need to worry about
you know not just encrypting the keys
but because there's a long time between
when the data is encrypted and then when
it's going to be decrypted or signed and
then verified uh
really the decryption keys the storage
and protection of those is very
important so you've kind of shifted the
problem from you know once the data is
encrypted and signed and everything
properly if you're using write
algorithms all that you know you don't
necessarily need to worry as much about
uh confidentiality or integrity of the
encrypted data but you do need to worry
about that for the keys
the thing is at least keys is a much
smaller piece of data that you need to
worry about than you know kind of
arbitrarily long
documents and other things
so the the good news is that uh you know
data in transit is really basically a
solved problem
um you know for
uh the fact is that you know if you're
communicating with some other system on
the network um you generally are going
to use you know tls or maybe one of its
predecessors and there's a
well-established mechanism for not only
kind of establishing keys and using the
right algorithms but also
for a certificate authority system and
how you can do that and you know web
browsers have their built-in certificate
authorities but if you don't care
if you don't necessarily trust all of
those certificate authorities then you
can have your own kind of more minimal
set of certificate authorities that
you're going to trust and you know use
as part of your system
so so that's really the the good news
and so now i'm going to kick it over to
weiss to really talk about
the rest of the problem
thanks chuck
so so on to the bad news um and i hate
to be the bearer of bad news but i think
most of the community has known sort of
this core problem for a while and it's
sort of now becoming more prominent
as we have sort of more modern
approaches
but the key takeaway here is is most
data arrest encryption solutions are
ineffective against modern threats
and that's primarily because they're
built on what's referred to as a
central implicit trust model
the idea being that the server and the
people who administer a server whether
it's a database server or a file server
have the ability to access data in the
clear and plain text
in order to perform their core job
functions
so as you as you can imagine this is
something that we definitely want to
tackle so moving on
i'll cover a little bit about the
central press and trust model
again the central implicit trust model
essentially suggests that key system
processes and users have access to plain
text data in order to perform a number
of job functions it could be to
administer a database server it could be
for the database server to
to operate so that you could perform it
tour functions
so this means that folks like database
admins system admins
database server itself the hypervisor
host if you're running in a virtualized
environment
they're
you're working with uh you know very
prominent
um
and they're sort of helping you manage
your infrastructure
uh or you have cloud administrators on
site with cloud uh
or the cloud provider
all these individuals have the ability
to view data in the plain text
that's a number of reasons which will
unpack uh in the next few slides
another thing i'll i'll mention uh
before we move on to sort of that and
some key examples of of how
those are
this this sort of flawed implicit model
is that
it happens to be the antithesis trouble
for trust model the whole idea is
that trust no one
should be no implied trump system
process or an individual
um except the central and pursuit plus
models built upon the exact opposite
which is we trust everyone uh and allow
them to be able to access data again in
the plain text
so you might be asking the obvious man
well what's the problem with the central
implicit trust model well consider two
scenarios i'm gonna walk you through
first is sort of logical vulnerabilities
and then i'll walk you through a number
of application specific vulnerabilities
so starting with the logical
vulnerabilities first
if you have a security incident
involving say as glenn mentioned earlier
an insider threat
say you have an employee with admin
access
the intention may not be nefarious but
they have admin access to to a database
or a data warehouse and they
accidentally you know export the data
into into a file share
or maybe it's a nefarious intended
individual they have access to the plain
text by the sheer virtue of the job that
they're performing as a database admirer
data warehouse admin or a cloud admin
consider the next scenario of a supply
chain attack let's say a provider that
you're working with whether it's a sas
provider or a cloud provider where
you're literally just hosting your data
imagine that they suffer a breach and
they're compromised for a period of time
and
that compromised environment is now
exposing your data
and the attackers who have compromised
the cloud provider then retrieve cloud
administrative credentials they have the
ability to view the data in plain text
and then lastly advanced attackers your
data theft um generally you're talking
about sort of nation-state attackers or
fairly more sophisticated attackers that
have the time resources to be able to to
compromise the network and ultimately
systems
one of the first things that they do is
they seek out credentials through
credential harvesting and once they have
those credentials for the databases or
the data warehouses or wherever the data
of value may be stored they then use
those authorized credentials to be able
to access data
they usually encrypt the data with a key
that you can't access and then they
exfiltrate it and we sort of know how
that story ends the key theme here is
that you know all these uh sort of
attacks are enabled by the fact that the
underlying systems that we rely on
heavily to ensure that data is encrypted
don't actually work and are not
effective against these types of more
modern attacks
now i'll spend a few minutes
covering application vulnerabilities and
i'll tie them to the various oauths top
list items
the first one is access control right an
attacker can modify an access control
check or metadata to get access to
privileged accounts and that's actually
the number one thing on the list
and i'll actually give you a real world
example of where this occurred in a
couple minutes but that's that's a very
very prominent one
the second area is around authentication
an attacker can perform a credential
stuffing attack chuck mentioned that a
few minutes ago as well
taking access to privileged accounts and
data very similar to some of the logical
vulnerabilities that i mentioned in my
previous slide um they're using some
sort of vulnerability whether it's
literally theft or credentials or
exploiting a vulnerability in the
application software itself or in the
structure
and that obviously ties to the
listener number seven of the offset 10
list identification and authentication
failures
and then lastly the other one that i
want to highlight is injection um and
sql injection is
i think like for the last 15 or 20 years
like the problem that as obvious as it
is to solve
um as much as we as a community have
been telling people like they just keep
happening um but this is the use of a
blind trust application framework as an
example
uh that an attacker can exploit to take
a a vulnerable query right someone that
all their attentions when they develop
the query
but unknowingly there's a vulnerability
to be able to form a sql ejection attack
and as chuck mentioned if you missed
both extract data from a database even
though that database has encryption in
it
and that's obviously item number three
on the list
so moving on from
really side i want to give you two real
world examples um and as you can imagine
we could probably come up with hundreds
of examples um
where you know
either vulnerable applications
or there's logical vulnerability
the first is i'll be talking about is
marriott um and this is the breach at
the
18 um if you recall there was also
another breach in 2020 but
a team breach first
they acquired a another hotel
which apparently hadn't been compromised
back in 2016 so it took them almost two
full years
to identify that
might start off as a spearfishing
uh attack um
enabled them compromising a number of
internal systems
they performed a bunch of credential
harvesting identified
access admin level access
to the that's poorly sensitive
information about folks yes sorry to uh
interrupt we have a tiny bit of lagging
could you maybe disable the video so we
hopefully have a better audio quality
sure sure all right thanks
yeah sure apologies for that san diego
internet uh usually really good but
today doesn't seem like it wants to
cooperate anyhow um moving back i'll
quickly run you the marriott use case
um again
so marriott again 2018 uh compromised
via a spearfishing attack which then led
to a lateral movement within the
environment ultimately credential
harvesting
and then they got access to database
admin credentials which allowed them to
actually trade they're saying up to 500
million guest records which includes
credit cards personal name
information
addresses and even some cases even
passport information and images of
password data which as you can imagine i
wouldn't want anyone else's hands
and then again in 2020 they had a much
smaller scale breach about five million
a record stolen but the same sort of
process so you know when you think about
of a company the sheer size of marriott
with the amount of capital they have to
invest in security these types of
attacks can happen even for
organizations that are that well funded
and then the application vulnerabilities
side
i wanted to highlight a sql ejection
attack that occurred several years ago
impacting 711
where attackers
performed a sql injection attack against
a publicly facing web server
ultimately that enabled them to get
access to a sensitive database
that housed over 130 million credit card
numbers which are stolen
the good news in this situation is that
the the attacker was ultimately
identified and then ended up i think
they're still in jail i think a 20-year
sentence but that occurred back in 2010
uh and then more recently
not mentioned on this slide but in 2019
7-eleven in japan actually
took to market a pay app
and they had a pretty critical flaw in
the design of the application where
passer resets didn't require any sort of
authentication
so you could literally open up the
application put in an email address and
asked for your password to be reset and
be able to right there and in the menu
window be able to reset the password
which was a massive flaw
for obvious reasons
over over six hundred thousand dollars
of consumer uh cash was stolen in that
event and they ended up shutting down
the application and never uh
reintroducing it to the market it's a
pretty catastrophic impact both to you
know the business model that they want
to approach and also all the poor
consumers are affected
so sort of in summary when you think
about the traditional encryption
controls you know we've been sort of
asked to use over the last 10 or 15
years like full disk encryption
transparency encryption
database encryption cloud storage
encryption you know popular things like
s3 encryption or blob encryption which
nowadays have been simplified to
literally checking a box off in an admin
panel or file sharing encryption
they're not going to help you in these
situations because they're designed for
very different types of threats and
frankly threats that are that are dated
um
so in most cases we're sort of on our
own
but
that being said they can protect you if
someone wants to steal your your laptop
or if you're running an old commodore
and they want to walk into your house
and steal that they can definitely
protect against that
um or you know literally walking into a
data center um whether it's one that you
operate or that a cloud provider
operates for you and stealing you know
servers out of racks which is a highly
unlikely scenario
the other thing is and this was
mentioned earlier i think anastasia
covered it maybe glenn you may have
touched on it
you know a lot of these encryption
controls do help you provide literally
the checkbox
so i think as an industry from an
abstract point of view there's
definitely approaches we can take to
sort of mitigate the risk um and have
more robust solutions in place
but one of the areas that i'd like to
see sort of more improvement is on the
compliance side
whether things like gdpr or hipaa or pci
that those sort of bodies and frameworks
start to take encryption and drill down
into controls that are more effective
versus what i refer to as checkbox
solutions like the ones i mentioned on
the slide here
so now i want to head over back to chuck
so he can talk about the better approach
over to you chuck
sorry about that yeah thank you weiss um
yeah and i definitely agree with what
you said which is that you know i would
love to see the audit and compliance
folks get more granular and kind of when
they look at encryption because it
really is currently it's basically do
you encrypt your data or not that's
really seems to be the level of
questioning that they have
but the reality as i mentioned earlier
is you know once you've encrypted the
data then all you've done is shift the
problem so now it's okay the data is
encrypted but how are you protecting the
keys
and so that's uh really what we would
like to see you know kind of as an
industry to move towards
or or sometimes you also get uh people
that maybe don't understand the
difference between um
at rest and in transit
encryption so they would say oh our data
is encrypted because we use tls and well
that you know protect against some types
of attacks but certainly not all of them
as we talked about earlier
so
really what what we should be doing is
is encrypting data you know higher in
the stack so
um
i'm hoping you guys can see my my
pointer but if not i'll just talk
through this uh thing on the right where
it's like you know this is kind of the
you think about kind of like an
application stack so you've got you know
bulk storage at the bottom
that's where the database stores its
files and then you've got a web server
up here that talks to the database
server and then you've got you know some
sort of a client application whether
it's a mobile app or it could be a
javascript you know type client
on a web page and then there's a user
that's you know using all this stuff so
if what you want to be doing if possible
is you want to have you know encryption
happening as high in the stack as
possible because what that's going to
give you
is that you know fewer devices and that
are going to see the data so i mean you
think in the extreme case if you know
if the if the human you know says okay
well i'm going to use some sort of code
word instead of my
you know
social security number that i'm going to
put in i'm going to put in a fake number
then obviously then you know the
encryption is happening all the way in
his head or her head and therefore none
of these systems are going to see the
real data
but you know that's not practical unless
you're you know one of the navajo code
talkers maybe from world war ii
you know most of the time you're going
to say okay we need you know an
automated system to do the encryption
but we want to be happening you know
here at the javascript or client with a
mobile app
and the reality you know is that the
more transparent the encryption is and
the decryption is then really the the
more exposure you have so you know down
here at the bottom if you know stuff is
encrypted at the you know bulk storage
type layer
then you know it's only going to be kind
of controlled by the keys that are used
to uh
you know as far as who can access that
so that you know the anything that's on
the database server is going to be able
to access that bulk encryption because
it needs to be able to access its files
but then there'd be other administrators
and stuff that can directly access the
bulk storage uh for things like backups
um you have to wonder if you have your
store if you're encrypting at that layer
uh and so the files themselves are not
encrypted then probably your backups are
not encrypted or at least not encrypted
in the same way you might be separately
encrypting your backups so there's you
know kind of more headaches there
um you know so the next layer up is at
the database server layer where it's
like okay that's where you have you know
what's called sometimes transparent data
encryption but for some databases or any
other sort of kind of database server
type encryption
and that's a little bit better because
there's you know fewer people that have
access to the database server that have
access to both the database server and
the volkswagen system and backups and
stuff but there's still quite a few
people that have access to this and and
in particular you know the web
application server has access to all of
the data on the database server and
there's no way that you know whatever is
controlling this stuff it's going to be
able to know you know who is the um
ultimately the user that's trying to
access this data and you know what data
they should have access to so if you're
you know our goal is to try to segregate
this data more at the database server
layer so that um
so that things that you know are
connecting to the database directly
you're not going to have the keys they
need to be able to decrypt all of the
data
so this is kind of a picture of that so
what what you end up with here is that
you'll have some sort of a key server
you know so this could be something you
build yourself or you know some of the
cloud service providers have those sorts
of things
other commercial vendors have them as
well
that is going to you know interface with
the user so whether directly or
indirectly maybe through the client or
something there will be you know some
authorization and authentication that
happens so that they'll be able to the
key server will know okay this is the
user that's trying to access the data
and these are the therefore these are
the keys that i'm going to give
um you know that are appropriate for
that user that can be used and so
ideally that would be happening here on
the client
but it could potentially happen at the
web application server or
in some limited cases it could even
happen as a database server if you've
got um kind of client-side encryption
client-aware encryption i guess that's
happening there uh where it passes the
keys through uh that some databases use
yeah so the idea is that you know we're
separating the data through the control
of encryption keys and so you could
almost think of it kind of like a
two-system control
where you know the the application
server itself is got you know some
access controls that's going to say okay
this user is supposed to be able to
access you know this type of data on the
system but then you know that's not
sufficient they also need to have the
right keys that go with it so
um
now you know what you do end up doing
potentially is you know implementing you
know authentication and authorization
logic
on both on both sides but that's kind of
the point here is that we want to be
more granular and get more specific so
the idea is that even if there's a sql
injection for example in the application
that's going to basically bypass this
level of authentication check all you're
going to get access to is a bunch of
encrypted data and the only keys you're
going to have to decrypt any of that
data is going to be the keys that are
associated with that user already so
it's the data that they can already
access
so you know as i mentioned this you know
protect you against you know not just
sql injection but also maybe
authentication or authorization bypass
types of attacks what we used to call
into trigger object references you know
various types of application layer
attacks and logical attacks as well as
his wife talked about earlier
and then it also gave you some defense
and depth so you've got a
then uh you've got again fewer people
that have access to the keys and
hopefully you know basically nobody has
access to all of the keys so your your
database server admins your web
application server admins all the people
that work at your cloud provider or you
know other you know customers of that
cloud provider you know none of them are
going to be able to you know even if
things are misfigured or that cloud per
service provider is breached or tokens
or whatever that are used to essentially
access some of these systems uh you know
get checked into github or something you
know you're still not going to have the
keys that you need in order to be able
to decrypt the data or
to encrypt data that's going to be
you know used basically for the uh
to add the database or update data
so uh just a simple example here is you
know let's say we've got a medical
record system and so
um the idea here is that we want to
encrypt you know some pretty
uh sensitive data that's there so we're
not encrypting everything you know we're
probably not going to be encrypting like
patient names and addresses and some of
that other stuff
um
as anastasia mentioned earlier you know
uh one of the limitations you'll have is
that you know if you're encrypting data
then it becomes more difficult to sort
and filter and and select down those um
that's the thing that can't be done
there are ways to be done but there's
definitely performance impacts so
uh we're going to say you know really
what we care about is things like you
know test results or diagnoses or other
you know sort of data values like that
that are pretty uh
sensitive for this person and need to be
protected by hipaa or maybe other sort
of regulatory requirements
and so what we're going to do is we're
going to have the system's going to
create an asymmetric key pair for each
patient
so you know myself as a patient i would
have you know a a key pair that's
created within the system that uh is
gonna you know have that relationship
like you would normally see in what we
call public and private keys in this
case we're gonna call them something a
little different because it's uh i think
it makes it more clear that we're gonna
have basically a read key and a write
key
so we're going to have one key that is
used to read data out of this system any
of these protected fields or attachments
and then a separate one that's used to
write the data
and so the idea here is that you know a
patient application for example would it
would only get the re-key so that that
way the patient can can only read their
data they can't create any new lab
results or sensitive data in the system
can't write themselves prescriptions for
example you know they're only going to
be able to read you know their data but
they get to read pretty much all of
their data because it's you know it's
their health
and uh uh conversely a lab for example
might might basically be the opposite
where they can only write data so
they're not going to be able to read any
of the existing data in that patient's
file
uh you know decrypted specifically i
guess uh but what they can do is they
can write data so they can create new
documents or attachments that are kind
of like lab reports or you know values
and things that associated with lab work
and the idea is that you know they're
putting that data in they're basically
kind of like a write only fashion so
they can't even read their own data
after they've uh put it in there
although certainly they would probably
have copies of it on their own systems
as well
and then a doctor is going to have you
know both keys so they're going to need
to both read the data that the lab put
in but also write you know other data
and diagnoses and stuff that the patient
is going to see so they would get both
so the idea here is that you know
depending on how this is all implemented
you can have you know kind of the you're
going to have the
you know very granular access control
around you know these keys specifically
for this patient
but then there's even just more general
things that are you can enforce that
it's like hey the patient application
itself regardless of which patient is
logged in it's only ever going to get
read keys so if you know you're kind of
able to do some kind of additional
layers of access control by saying you
know that the patient application is
never going to get a right key
regardless of what happens
and and vice versa for the lab so that
you're going to you'll be able to ensure
that
you know you've got like i said those
multiple layers to ensure that you've
got as much trust as possible that only
the right people are able to do the
right you know operations into your data
and so if you want to read more about a
a similar example there's one in the
mongodb documentation where they talk
about what they call field level
encryption that we'll talk about a
little bit but kind of walk through
exactly like yeah this is how we would
set it up and this is how you can
implement it in order to ensure that you
get the
security controls that you want to have
in place
so now so now we've got the general idea
of what we want to do then let's talk
about how we could do it so there's a
basically three options that
you've got available to you and
you know to implement this type of
encryption into a system
so the first is is what's called column
level encryption so the idea here is
that we're going to encrypt only you
know specific sensitive columns you know
maybe credit card numbers socials
passport numbers whatever and
that that way you know each of those
columns will actually be encrypted
separately so you know you might have
some people that can access credit card
numbers but can't access passport
numbers and vice versa so it gives you
again an overall access control not just
for
users as far as like database admins and
stuff but also potentially different
systems so your payment system you know
would have keys to be able to access the
credit card numbers but you know not
access some of those other sensitive
fields perhaps
and so
that's uh that's the idea here so it's
kind of more at the um
at the client level or it could be at
the specific user level as well
and you know again we're getting that
separation even uh against the database
encryption
uh database administrators and the key
here is that the decryption and
encryption is not happening on the
database server at least uh
in the
best implementation of this so what you
want is stuff that's really what uh
generally these are implemented in the
kind of client library that you use to
access the database server
so in something like you know mysql or
postgrad sql there'll be a you know
library that you use on the web
application server kind of side to
access the database and the encryption
is built into that
um so you would you know at this level
of the application server provide the
keys to that that would then get passed
through to the database server
so there's a few different
implementations of this it's a pretty
common technique um so i mean it's
pretty much all uh databases support it
you know sql microsoft has a couple
different kind of variants of it uh
where they call it you know either
always encrypted data or you know column
encryption
on google cloud um specifically has kind
of implementations for both mysql and
postpress sql
and the reason they have that is because
it's basically interfacing with their
key management system so it gives them
the ability to kind of have that um
you know a more centralized place where
you're storing the keys
but again in both cases you can see like
based on this url this is all
client-side and my client side here you
know that could be up here on the actual
client a mobile client or javascript
client or it could be on kind of the
database client library that's accessing
the database server
and then you can also do database client
encryption on aws so here's an example
of that um you know probably lots of
other
potential implementations uh one thing
to be aware of though is that i believe
oracle uses the term column level
encryption for some of their stuff
but in reality it's more like
transparent data encryption where it's
happening kind of all in the database
server and it's uh you know it doesn't
have the kind of security properties we
want here where you can get more
granular kind of control of the keys
so you do have to be a little bit
careful with some of this stuff that
different
systems or database implementations are
going to call things a little bit
different or call or use the same term
for something a little bit different
so definitely worth
doing a little bit of research on that
when you need to
and so the the next option is it was
called field level encryption and so
this is basically
sometimes people will say field level
encryption when they really need column
level encryption
because what field level encryption at
the the strictest sense is is is your
it's it's basically more specific than
column level encryption you're going to
have
the ability to encrypt a
uh specific
uh data fields that are in a column but
you're not necessarily encrypting all of
the rows of that so we're going to have
a
specific fields that uh you know that
the data in that field or maybe even
data in other fields are going to drive
the encryption that's used
so for whatever reason you know maybe we
want to encrypt you know encrypt just
the american express credit card numbers
and so we could do that with good level
encryption maybe we want to you know
encrypt only the credit card numbers
that are associated with customers that
are in europe for gdpr type reasons you
could even do something with field level
encryption where you could use different
encryption
um algorithms based on you know where
the user is so um you could think of a
world maybe that you know in america
they mandate that you must use aes to
encrypt data but then in you know some
other country they mandate that you must
use some other algorithm to encrypt the
data and so you would need to you know
have more granularity there in what
you're doing
so that's uh know gives you the ability
to meet those kind of use cases
and so again that it's not happening on
the database server generally for field
level encryption it's going to be all
the way up here on the client although
it could be down here
on the web application server but the
key is that it's you know again not on
the database server itself
and so there's really two main
implementations of this that uh
that i've identified you know so one is
you know mongodb was really the pioneer
for this that they created a whole
kind of mechanism around this uh that
you can read about in their
documentation of this link here
and um
so they they go into you know kind of
how they you can set up this on the the
client side
and they have you know full support for
it as part of their client libraries
that are used to connect to a
database
and then um amazon does this as well
although strangely it's part of their
cloud front um because they're basically
doing field level encryption that kind
of starts i think all the way at like
the http field level and uh again kind
of with that idea that you're encrypting
data as soon as possible uh in the in
the overall kind of stack so that's an
interesting implementation that you can
get into
looking at their documentation
so so those two field level encryption
and column level encryptions are the the
two kind of um
automated mechanisms i guess you could
say implementations that exist that
to do this
and so the last the last option is
really you know you just gotta do it
yourself so you know we can do uh
application level encryption so the idea
here is that you know you've got
logic built into the client whether it's
javascript or a mobile app or whatever
and it's going to do all of the you know
encryption and decryption
so this is you know obviously the most
flexible because you're you know
building it yourself you can do whatever
you want it's it's also kind of
technology agnostic you're not tying
yourself to a particular database back
end or cloud technology like we were
just talking about with field level
encryption
um you know for if you've got
multi-platform tech systems where maybe
you've got multiple types of
applications that are built on different
platforms that need to access the same
databases then you know uh doing it as
kind of at the application layer is
helpful because it allows you to be
agnostic to kind of what's underneath
and uh what's above as well so
it gives you a lot of flexibility
with the you know the cost of just being
you know a little bit more work and
complexity for you to deal with
so again you know you're not encrypting
the data on the database server you're
doing it in your own
custom application logic
and
you know the
what you can do is uh like i said this
is kind of technology agnostic but there
are different you know vendors that can
help you in implementation so again
you're kind of tying yourself to that
vendor but you know you can find vendors
that will basically be cloud agnostic so
you could you know use the same
data encryption scheme whether you're
putting data on
premise or in the cloud at amazon or in
the cloud and azure you know and you
know allow you to move data around
without being kind of tied to that
underlying technology
so if you if you want to learn more
about ale ale uh you could grab yourself
a glass of ale and read up on a couple
of these documents so we've got um you
know a
pretty good article here from infoq that
talks about you know software architects
and how you can use app application
layer encryption
and then a recent forbes article as well
that talks really about the specifics of
what they call they call it entity level
encryption but the idea is that you
string is granular it's possible in you
know the data that you're encrypting and
decrypting and that allows you to be a
defense against ransomware as well so
generally you know ransomware if it you
know kind of gets into your system is
going to be operating you know down here
at either like the bulk storage layer or
maybe some ransomware is kind of
database aware where if it you know was
able to get uh database credentials you
could go and start you know encrypting a
bunch of data in your database
um
then uh but if you're if you're
uh if your data is you know encrypted at
a higher layer then that's not gonna
necessarily help them so now
it gets to be clear so i mean ransomware
that just goes in and tries to ransom
your data you know they could they could
encrypt the data down at the lower layer
and you're still going to have to deal
with that as far as getting uh you know
through that hurdle hopefully you've got
good backups that are you know kind of
protecting against that sort of attack
so the really more concerning is kind of
what we've seen this year where
ransomware has moved from just
kind of preventing you from accessing
your data until you pay
to also being able to steal your data
and potentially posting it online and
doing other things with it so the data
theft portion of ransomware is what's uh
you know this entity level encryption
that they call it would really help you
with
so uh just a few kind of parting words
of crypto advice uh you know so if you
are uh involved in a cryptographic
project where you've got to you know
encrypt some data and take care of it
properly and uh you know here's our list
of do's and don'ts i'm not going to read
through them all hopefully they uh look
familiar and there's lots of good
documentation on the oauth side in other
places as well that kind of goes into
the details but
really what it comes down to is that
there are a lot of details you've got to
get right you know i mentioned earlier
that you know the the algorithms that we
have today things like aes and the gcm
encryption mode are very strong
but there is there is opportunity for
potentially um
some implementation flaws that could
cause you to have issues
and this is my last slide so i know
we're basically at time as far as we're
getting into the q a portion so i uh
definitely
appreciate you guys all coming and i i
hope that you've put some questions if
you haven't already put some into the uh
hoover chat and we'll be happy to answer
them uh as many as we can during this
period of time uh you can also feel free
to reach out to us via email you know
weiss and i are happy to to help as far
as responding to any any questions that
you have after after the talk as well