[Music]
today i'm going to be talking about how
to use your vulnerabilities to train
your developers on security uh security
training is becoming a much bigger topic
as seen as a you know high roi activity
in application security so i'm going to
go over
a few things today on the topic so i'm
going to start with
just some interesting things that we
found from training tens of thousands of
software developers
i'm gonna go over how to create a
successful secure coding training
program uh then i'm gonna talk uh more
about you know the the title of the
presentation how you train developers
using your own uh vulnerabilities and
then i'm going to do a demo of our
platform and kind of show you how you
can do this in practice
so
i'm going to start with as i mentioned
insights from tens of thousands of
developers and the data is from uh
lessons uh that we've that we have
assessments challenges reported
vulnerabilities and so the interaction
uh with these people is um
is what we've looked at to be able to
determine some some very interesting
insights
so
um one disclaimer before getting into it
is that uh we're talking about the 2017
oauth top 10 not the 2021 oauth top 10
that that was just uh published um so uh
we're currently updating our content and
um
and data so it will be reflective of the
new uh top 10 in in december
so what are the top two vulnerabilities
that developers find easiest to fix
they are external entities and
cross-site scripting
and so we looked at you know why might
this be the case why are those the two
easiest effects and and it really comes
down to two things education if you
educate developers on these
vulnerabilities they're extremely easy
to fix
as well as the fact that frameworks make
them
extremely easy so once developers have
the knowledge and understand the
frameworks they can more easily
fix these vulnerabilities so they're
very easy for developers to fix
what are the top two vulnerabilities
developers find hardest to fix
and so looking at at all of these
developers we found broken access
control and broken object level
authorization and so when looking into
the data you know why are developers
having issues with with these areas in
particular
well they're more complex to fix right
it's not
leveraging a framework or leveraging
something that's relatively easy
and there's no one way to fix these
issues there's a lot of issues that
encompass
access control and authorization so
um it's really about having a mindset to
think through all of the possible um
issues that can can arise and training
on the fundamentals rather than
memorizing a specific syntax or
framework or something like that so
that's why this is these are
particularly hard to fix
what are the top two vulnerabilities
that our customers tell us they're
having the biggest issues with so this
is not just from our data but this is
them uh telling us that they're having
these issues and one is uh using
components with known vulnerabilities so
open source software
and also again broken authentication
they know they're having issues with
those areas open source it's so easy now
to pull in third-party libraries it's
it's extremely common that
vulnerabilities creep in because of uh
third-party software
so do programmers in certain programming
languages uh make fewer vulnerabilities
so we looked into this and we we saw
that on average no however
certain languages there are certain
vulnerabilities that are more likely to
occur than others and so looking at all
the at all of the language's
vulnerabilities we found that these are
the most common vulnerabilities so for
net it's broken access control for java
it's command injection uh node is xxe
and php in ruby is sql injection
so we tried to dig in a little more like
why why this might be the case and we
were asking the questions you know
specifically you know is it the
programmers of that language
uh is it the language itself and kind of
digging in deeper we found it's it's a
little bit of both right so programmers
of the language are using certain
certain syntax or certain things that
are available in that language so
because of that it makes certain
vulnerabilities more more common than
others
and then you know we also asked the
question what are the top
vulnerabilities that developers fix
incorrectly so these are vulnerabilities
that developers know they have they may
have some knowledge of them and they go
to try to fix them and they find you
know they don't fix them exactly
correctly so they're fixing them in a
way where there might be you know some
gaps or something and there's still a
problem with these vulnerabilities and
so
we found command injection and sql
injection are most often fixed
incorrectly and so we look at why that
that's the case it really comes down to
developers wanting to go to regular
expressions because they lack the formal
training in understanding using you know
parameterized queries you know the right
way to fix these vulnerabilities and
instead they think oh i have to filter
out certain things for a particular case
and so that's why
these are often fixed uh incorrectly
so that was just some interesting data
to kind of
think through you know some of the
issues developers have
think through how training can enable
developers to make fewer vulnerabilities
now i'm going to go into how do you
create a successful secure coding
training plan
so when thinking through how to come up
with a successful secure coding training
plan you know you want to improve the
engagement if you get developers engaged
and they're interested and they're
actually taking the training you know
that's step one right and then the
second most important thing is okay now
we need to make sure it's effective and
increase the effectiveness so so these
are the two things we do at hacky to you
we really are are focused on improving
engagement and increasing effectiveness
if you do those two things you'll see
vulnerabilities um uh decrease in in
your software and so this is
recommendations based on working with
hundreds hundreds of customers over
years and looking at the data so we came
up with you know best practice in terms
of rolling out secure coding training
so first looking at the training content
um you know we found that multiple
choice videos slides just don't cut it
for videos in particular we've seen
developers play videos in the background
while they're coding so they're not
really paying attention so it's really
not effective it's not engaging
you know multiple choice
it doesn't that's not how developers
learn developers are problem solvers
they want to be thrown into a problem
and try try to solve that in a more
hands-on way and then we've also heard
from from some companies um that they
they tried a slide based approach um you
know the the
uh computer-based training where you
click you know click through and kind of
watch the animation run and we heard
that uh for one they looked at the
statistics of the training afterwards
and saw that developers were finishing
lessons in like seconds because they
were just clicking through as fast as
they could so obviously that's not
effective so requiring developers to
actually code is extremely important
getting them hands-on and practice
vulnerabilities because if they can do
that if they can find and fix
vulnerabilities in other people's code
they're more likely to be able to avoid
those mistakes in their own code um and
then third here you know offensive and
defensive approach is very good so as
mentioned with broken access control and
broken authentication it's less about
one right way to fix it and more about
having the mindset to think through how
are attackers looking at our
applications um you know having that
mindset and thinking through the
fundamentals of these vulnerabilities uh
rather than just one way to fix it is
extremely important and so giving the
offensive approach
really helps uh for that
and and it helps them more solve for the
general case rather than one one
specific case
so training schedule now we've you know
working with organizations uh developers
are
more
pressured today to write a lot of code
right they got to get that product
roadmap done there's no time for
training they have to move forward and
so
um
what we found is breaking up code into
smaller portions right so like 20
minutes or so
and then
assigning it throughout the year not one
chunk right away is extremely effective
so you know training continuously is
makes it so it's not a one-time event
right developers aren't going to take
training you know for two days out of
the year and then forget about it until
next year um you know that's not an
effective way to build the build
learning and it doesn't follow learning
science principles so learning science
principles say that learning should be
continuous throughout the year and that
knowledge should continually reinforce
itself so we recommend training every
single month for two to three hours and
breaking up the training into 20 to 30
minute chunks and so that will help
developers fit it in during compile time
during downtime during testing during
you know when they just need a break
from looking at code and it really
doesn't take away from the product
roadmap
so this is a way where
security can work with engineering such
that it works for for both organizations
so training topics um so you know owasp
puts out obviously a lot of really great
content good lists on things to focus on
and so the oauth top 10 is a great uh a
great place to start having the owasp
api top 10 if you do api or mobile
anything like that focusing on the
latest technologies and the latest
attacks
is extremely important so if you're
using new authentication you know
different authentication technologies
you should be training on that so jwt
authentication or
or oauth or something like train on the
technologies that you're using and then
also if there are any attacks that are
newer anything that um that might be
interesting learning those um those
newer attacks to be aware of them uh as
you're developing your own code
uh and then lastly here um you know
using role-based uh training so training
for particular
roles so front end might be taking
different training than back end um you
know qa might be taking different
training as well um there's usually a
lot of overlap but sometimes there are
specific things for specific roles as
well as seniority as well right someone
who's new uh you know out of out of
college they might have very different
training than someone who's been uh
developing for for 20 years so you want
to have a variety of training to be able
to
accommodate your your whole
development team
so
you know then you know we talked a
little bit how to make your training
effective things to focus on but now how
do you drive that engagement priest how
do you improve that
so one thing is having security and
engineering team unity now this is very
much you know
organization specific some organizations
have very good
security and engineering unity
part of it if you have good education
and you're educating the engineers on
some of these things you can help bridge
the gap between security and engineering
another thing is you know not having um
training that's just like you know hey
we're gonna do a week and stop
everything you know making sure you're
working with with engineering to have um
you know good camaraderie and uh working
towards the same effort uh
having this you know that that ties in
with security culture management buy-in
right you wanna have management um you
know at the highest levels buying into
these programs and things luckily today
it's much easier to have buy-in from
c-level executives on security because
of all the issues that have happened um
and then you know incentives so we've
seen there was one company we were
working with
they gave away
special backpacks that had a special
logo just for for their team for their
company and they gave those away for
everyone who completed training we saw
the rates of completion for those for
that organization was just through the
roof everybody wanted a backpack
everyone wanted to complete the training
so they had a really great time uh
getting everybody on board and actually
taking the training
so we saw this not only with that
organization but several other
organizations where they offered
incentives um so we saw it was so
effective we actually uh created uh a um
you know feature within our platform
called hackie rewards where we actually
offer a similar thing all managed within
our platform because we saw it is such
an effective way to engage uh developers
and get them to actually go in take the
training and complete it
uh and then the last thing here is
accountability so engaging is great you
want to engage developers
you want to get them doing the right
thing and if they don't you also want to
hold them accountable so something that
you can do
is hey when developers checking code is
there a way that you can remind them to
take training if they haven't or can you
even you know some organizations won't
do this but but some might block them
from checking in code if they haven't
completed the training
there are some tools out there that make
this available we have a tool that does
something similar and it's just another
way to remind developers hey if you're
checking in code into production you
should be making sure that you're up on
your training
so now i'm going to get into you know
how do you use your vulnerabilities to
train your your developers
so you know security metrics are
something that i think as a as a
community we all struggle with what are
the right metrics how are you measuring
the right things this is very difficult
so instead of looking at you know
metrics let's look at you know the tools
that are already in place uh what tools
can we leverage to improve the roi of of
training right and so looking at bug
bounty programs sas tools das tools your
current training aggregating all of that
data and then creating what what we call
uh adaptive training plans to really
try to change developer behavior and
help them think more
about security
and so what are adaptive training
uh plans and so this is essentially
taking all relevant vulnerabilities from
developers
vulnerabilities found the severity of
the vulnerabilities
applications where vulnerabilities are
found taking all of that information as
well as
developer knowledge you know what
lessons have they taken where are they
struggling what are they having issues
with and then assigning highly relevant
and timely lessons
based on those to help fix the mistakes
that they're making and so we've seen
this is is an extremely effective way to
train developers
not only is it targeting the issues
where they're having problems but it's
also very hard for them to say hey i
don't need security training it's not
relevant i'm a senior developer i don't
make mistakes right if you're showing
them like hey this is based on data and
your actual code then it's much more
palatable for developers and for them to
be able to
take take this
so now i'm going to jump into a demo and
so i'm going to demo first uh the hacky
u platform
talk about how we tried to improve uh
the ability to write secure software
you know boost um
uh developers understanding on how they
they uh
um
the how software systems are hacked and
and decrease the time to solve security
problems so i'll walk through the hacky
new platform and then i'll move into how
we use
vulnerabilities to help train
trained developers
so
okay so starting with um the hackity
platform uh so this is the hackyview
platform um this is just kind of general
general training and i'm gonna walk
through a particular lesson here so
if we go into our sql injection part one
lesson the way our
our training works is we have a tutorial
on the left side and then the most
important thing we do is try to get
developers hands on as quickly as
possible
as mentioned we have um
you know we have the offensive side is
where we start so we'll walk through the
offensive side of security and then and
then move on to the defensive side so
here for example
um we have a real running web
application it's a sandbox for this this
particular developer and so if i try to
log in i have um so
intercept request is on and i have a
proxy that's running so i can see the
requests that are going on to the server
i can modify requests and i could submit
it to the server so we're starting to
use the tools that security teams are
using that
that you know
attackers are using to analyze
applications so it gives developers a
better way to understand these things
and so
um so we start with the offensive side
of security
uh so for example you know this is sql
injection there's a sql
injection vulnerability uh we teach you
know how would you go about exploiting
this so you have a
an understanding of this and so for
example here i was just able to break
into this application that's what we're
teaching developers here um but they're
you know they're real vulnerabilities
the the platform is open for anyone to
exploit this you know kill the
you know drop tables kill the
application whatever completely fine if
they ever get the
application in a bad state they just hit
this reset sandbox
and they get a brand new one and could
continue on with the application
so that's the offensive side then we
move to the defensive side and so for
the defensive side we expose the source
code the developers can choose whatever
language
they want here they select the language
um you know that that they develop in uh
then they have to find and fix the
vulnerability in code
once they find once they find and fix
the vulnerability they hit run tests and
tests are actually run and they have to
actually solve it correctly before they
can pass a lesson and move on
so again hands-on training making sure
that developers are actually coding is
extremely important and then making sure
they're actually doing it correctly by
running tests against it
so that's how our lessons work uh we
have a full library of of uh of lessons
cover a lot of the oauth topics uh
additional topics we have challenges to
help gamify so there's a lot going on uh
in our platform
but now moving over to um
uh to to using your vulnerabilities so
um so as i mentioned we have uh
integrations with sas tools das tools
bug bounty programs everything is is
kind of pre-loaded here depending on
what uh what tools you use and then you
can connect it up and for this we have
hacker one connected for this um
organization
and as you can see here it's kind of um
categorize the vulnerabilities that are
found right so it's looking at the
vulnerabilities the severity the numbers
all of those different things and based
on that it's automatically assigning
me um training so you know broken
authentication and session management
you know as you can see here with this
integration you know there's an issue
there right and it's looking at as i
mentioned maybe the severity is there
more than others uh cross-site scripting
is another issue we actually have a you
know the myspace worm which was a
cross-site scripting issue so um maybe
because i already took an initial uh
uh cross-site scripting but i'm still
having problems i'll get that assigned
to me so this is all happening
automatically behind the scenes and so
that's how our training works in terms
of um
in terms of
looking and using your own
vulnerabilities in code
so
with that
i will
pause and see if there are any questions