[Music]
okay
first hello everybody um thank you for
attending our talk
um
in
in our talk
we
we speak about hackers about
some different kind of attack and all of
them it will be focused on software
development processes workflows
and so on um we'll try to
to
choose to show different canon attacks
and sometimes a different kind of
defenses right
okay a bit of spam about us
um
i think that nothing more to add or
do you want to add something faster
yeah yes i work on bbva next
technologies is a company of a
technology company from a spanish bank
and
i work for a long time with
data and now i'm focused
more on
security over data and security itself
and i must say that it's an exciting
work nowadays i learning a lot
nice um i only will add that i'm
currently working as a
security research api consultant for
photographs
um a company
focuses security in the apis and that's
it
you can
get in touch with
our twitter uh with linkedin
you can yes
it's this in this slide
or
okay now
first
a very big disclaimer about our talk
because uh
we will see some real attacks
and that we are
swinging our
our own opinions
uh espresso are not by um
a company that aren't employers to us
right
yes
legal reasons
okay let's let's start with the core
concepts so let's take a ten thousand
feet look at the modern software
pipelines next
okay first of all what continuous
integration is continuous integration
tools born from groups of developers
while they work on the same code by base
and they can talk each other
first we work in order to keep
correctness even after several code
merges then test drive development come
to town things start to be more
interesting now we can be sure that our
code is consistent and works on the most
important parts
also you have there the wikipedia
definition that it's a pretty boring
thing okay next
okay what continuous deployment is
in fact developers confidence was so
high that they start to automate push to
production machines without human
intervention or manual revision
testing techniques becomes
become the
safety net of developers now we feel
safe about our code
every commit now has high probabilities
to trigger and you deploy to production
and without the old struggle between
developers and operations new exciting
techniques born
like a b testing blue green deployment
zero downtime all that stuff
more aggressive and fast automatic
deploy techniques start to become very
popular and that's all the long story
short next
okay a little note about difference
between continuous delivery and
continuous deployment nowadays we have
an increasing number of continuous
deployment projects and also some
continuous delivery projects the main
difference between them is that on
delivery ones we keep a manual process
to trigger production deployment you can
see in the red square
okay
nanny go ahead
yeah my turn okay um
okay we're talking uh about
modern workflows and infrastructure and
so on um at this point we are reviewing
uh what happened in legacy systems right
legacy system the legacy environments
that right okay let's see it
okay the the first
scenario is when we
have not a cd or continuous deployment
right
um in this case
sorry
um
in this case we have an ops team that
are responsible to promote software
right to production environment right
obviously
this is a big
bottleneck
and need more people in ops team to
manage the process to deploy new
releases to to produce you right
but it could be worse that if we don't
have
a
c see
right
if we
let's remove the
that's ps that's the element now
uh that user upload to the control
system to the software control system
then will be sent to the ops team
right this is a bit more uh
a bit more and
hard on the star wars i mean her
scenario i think it's faster
finally we are on the health the head is
where the developers
post their call directly to production
this is a very good scenario for hackers
because
they can
find
a lot of
issues a lot of flaws a lot of both
probably in in production systems yes
manually
we have to say that developers manually
deploy code with no techniques no
automations and that's a very bad
scenario
right
cesar your turn ok
um some reasons next
why
we bother about this
okay we bother because reaching our
customers
more frequently and faster is a
competitive advantage
software leaders shown everyone
that this kind of techniques are
extremely profitable
instead spend several months planning
and develop software now we can change
it in a matter of hours safely
more extreme continuous deployment
techniques per suite that every commit
every commit hits production triggering
tens of deployeds on a single day
next
but
how
this becomes so popular nowadays it's
uncommon find a company that is not
using one of these tools to out of
automate at least one software project
in fact new jobs emerge around these
tools like devops software reliability
engineers sex devops all that kind of
stuff
the use of these tools is increasing
year after year
so let's talk about the lingo next
what a pipeline is
in order to achieve tens of deployments
every single day we need to decrease
human factor to its minimum to do this
we need to execute several
software in x specific sequence this
sequence calls pipeline a pipeline it's
made of several steps that can use
some programs and usually its name after
their goal like compile software testing
or
maybe
you know okay
next what a devops is
the struggle between the
development and operations begin became
so intense that we need to change our
company culture to achieve of our
objectives quickly
and from this close collaboration burn a
new being the mighty devops the one who
will bring understanding between these
two worlds and its name is devops
these new partners and with shared
responsibilities which usually no one
cares about
in the past scenario when you have
developers and operations sometimes
these two teams
fight each other
for uh who is the book blame off
okay
next
uh now we have another word is sec what
a debsec ops is
the next obstacle in our way to foster
deployment was security
in the same way the development and
operations did it before now security
must change their mindset to become
allies security usually it's seen as an
stopper in several projects involves
security from the beginning increase
development speed and reduce the risks
leading us now to modern internets like
threat modeling
okay sorry yeah
yeah
now
after that
we'll let's review some
some typical setups or infrastructures
and servers and workflow
there is some typical step uh when we
build software right uh the building
workflow it's it itself is like
uh like the picture we can see this
slide right from code comment c pipeline
cd right but it's not enough
uh
then we split each step and name them we
include
sorry
we include all the development steps and
also we added using a prediction step
because uh they are implied in the solar
development
um
now now we put
our names to software that could be used
in in each step
right
uh we can see that a typical software
component and solar
pss are github travis jenkins
bucket gitlab
and yes iftp
cost some time the developers of
software processes are
a bit
all processors somewhere finally and
seen an ftp
server but
the weaker the server
this is scenario is not enough we need
more pieces
and the pieces the missing pieces are
the deployment provider of course
and
also also as you can see in the right
and on the slide
you also have jurong
duron server and do a different provider
right um
this is the
um the big picture this is the the photo
that we use to explain
each attack in different steps
following uh this
scenario right
caesar
okay
now we are ready to deep dive into the
burning health of pipelines go next
we start in source code if we look our
treasure map we are now on the left side
of it okay
go for it first of all our first foe the
id leaks the internet development
environment links
please don't leak the tiles of your
internal deployment to the internet some
of the ties can be clues to find
security halls
when you are using an integrated
development environment usually these
put some files on your project and these
files must be ignored
you can see there on this picture that
you can access to the code styles and
some cache files product workspace file
files
and
the compiler the encodings
a lot of very interesting things to know
how your company works internally and is
very risky okay
go to next
the bad role granularity okay
sometimes you have no choice to set up
several roles
or maybe you can set permissions on
files or brands
if this is the case you are suffering
bar role generality
some can delete your production code
directly or using other attorneys and
you never know who was
if you can control
how your files are
managed
somewhere by error or
someone someone evil can delete all your
work and also even change your
source code history and you never know
that that
was
happening
a little note there
this can be even worse because all this
stuff can happen in the
developer computer
and we say later
we will see later more about this but
some kind of
developers tend to
keep the code only on their computer and
this is also a very risky thing
okay
next
this is um the dev machine has only
source code server as i say moments
before
and you
must ask yourself all these questions
there is a cowboy color in your team
let's see that beautiful image danny
okay sorry
now that's it
have you
you have very time software in
production only managed by one developer
you have a guru developer you have the
correct security at the workplace and
also are your developers buying bring
your own device to your office
all these things
um lead us to this risky thing
and we must avoid it we need to keep
safe or source code
made backups and keep the work pla the
work place safe also
is a good practice that more than one
person is aware of anything that is used
in production if you have this kind of
cowboy encoder that is very active and
do a lot of things when
this person leaves your company can be a
very very a problem a very big problem
because
they leave the
know-how of all these things okay let's
go next
okay
another typical site where developers go
when they have doubt is stack overflow
and these are the copy and paste the
source code that people write on the
stack overflow but we know that they did
that's the reason because we can phone
news like this the most copied pieces
java code on the stack before contains
an error
but
is
if
the piece of the of code have
and small turians it was copy two
i think that the answer could be
probably
then
please don't copy and paste source code
without analyze it
okay
our libraries allow
developers
very often are trusted and usually don't
check a pencil library that they use
and they don't check if libraries have
laboratories or trillian or if they have
some cbe
er in the diversity they are using um
as you can see okay
let me
oh sorry and turn into i
right
in this news we can see that popular
javascript library was infected with a
malware that is still bitcoin from
wallet right this th this kind of things
happens and we
uh
then on secret analytics something
people forgot that i did a repository
certain contains sensitive data
sometimes
by neglect and other because they don't
know that git
is not a backup system
they put sensitive data into them
in the slide
okay let me pass yeah it is like in the
slice picture we can see real sensitive
data and probably get a repository and
then i invite you to
to use the github search
inbox um put this just a string on
something similar and you can find a lot
of repositories with sensitive data be
careful with that
very popular one
and very useful useful right
okay now we move from the building a
step right the
uh move
right um following the robot diagram on
our in the middle left and building a
step
right now we are and control our default
repository okay the first case in the
building step that will cover is the
right active artifact repository control
because um
we should control not suit we must
control what a developer can publish to
a teflon repository otherwise
they can publish malicious artifacts
what happens
if they probably sat regulates
rt5
what happened when production system
deployed this
artifact to production environment
right that will happen is that where
we will have a backdoor in our
production system and this always is uh
not good business right
please
uh check it
okay
the environment leak it's very common in
cocd systems store sensitive data
like production apks credential even
amazon secret keys and so on
in variables usually usually this data
will pass to c
as intelligence environments
variables um
if these variables are not protected in
c system someone with access to the
the c or cd system can print these
variables and of course if they print
these variables
they can read the content of the
environment is very obvious right but
all of c cd says they have a solution to
protect the variables that contain
sensitive data as you can see in the
in this pictures gitlab for example for
example
um
a core
or have an special kind of environment
variable that they call as protected
and github has this special medium
variables that they call secrets
and this type of variable are not shown
in the ccd
a console even if a user
uh print their content and want to read
their content and then please it's very
easy then use it
okay this is a very nice
attack is a reverse shell in the
pipeline
all the developers have a limited access
to the c
right so they see system uh when i say
limited access and referring by using
arrow-based system for example they have
a developer role not an admin uh to the
c system but
um if they can execute arbitrary
binaries for example netcat is a very
common uh binary that is the most of the
unique systems they could create
a reverse cell
um if the c system doesn't doesn't
control the access to the internet
analysis developers could open a remote
backdoor in uc system
right
then let's see
uh in a small demo as a video
okay this is a fun picture
okay
in this video
we'll
uh put netcat to listen and they went to
three four port
right
waiting for the connection and then
in jenkins very famous right
we'll
create an squid console right nothing is
strained until now
but but
the thing that we are doing
is
to connect
to our
netcat
service that just put listen right uh
you can see
we created our
reverse cell and in this case we use
metasploitable meters yeah i mean
exploit connect and then at this moment
we have
a cell in the c system in this case is a
microsoft windows right it's very easy
this is a talk about very very powerful
okay let's talk about a little the the
github actions
the evil they have actions in fact
the code that you
that you use in your g-hub actions who
is written by
maybe they have evil objectives uh we
all know how a contributor and they have
actions start to send all environment
variables to their burden to harvard
secrets this vulnerability is known as
codecov
please use trusted popular actions and
check the latest changes frequently also
it's very important that
agents have a good firewall and don't
access the internet if they are not
meant to
also
your pipeline has critical deploy
information and be aware of that kind of
actions
that you use
and how they use this information danny
say a moment ago that environment
variables
are very important because our secrets
lie there and it's a very important
thing that i want to stop and i mean to
talk about please protect your
environment okay
next other thing that commonly we found
on the say cd systems
is a a mighty bot
delivery software in a company is a very
demanding task we feel tempted by
shortcuts
like do all ci actions by only
one an almighty bot account
if someone has bought credentials for
some automation tasks he has access to
everything and that is so spooky
use correct amount of service accounts
to the tasks that require it keep in
mind that the bot user can do what
developer demands because most
continuous delivery systems use a
software to
do their actions and you can write any
kind of software that you want there
so if
the bot has all permissions
and by extension the developer has all
permissions too
okay let's move to the next that's the
evil agent okay
if you can download and execute any
program you can use a continuous
deployment agent to perform
any evil action that you want but we see
as we see in a moment ago danny opened a
netcat but
it is in that case the netcat is in
their machine but you can do the same
from the pipeline you can download
binary a static link
in your pipeline and execute it
so
if file permissions are not correct
uh the pipeline also can infect with
malware an agent and uses as a zombie on
a botnet so
be aware of that okay
let's see in this small video how
this attack works
a moment i
that's it
now we see we will see how we can from a
pipeline with
any problem download and execute any
software that we want
and we can do this because this jenkins
is
with the file configurations security
and with no internet control access
that's the cool for the download
we are the loading map
yes a map that is a very useful software
to look your surrounding and maybe a
little step and that is running and
looking all of
our network that's it
okay
so we know that that's the thing
uh
how we learn from this limit internet
access in the pipeline perform a correct
hardening of the infrastructure and fix
the execution permissions and we say
that jenkins is on default settings okay
move next
docker hub leak
that's a very interesting one some
useful docker command can publish on
docker hub easily and you can send the
image full of secrets to a public docker
half profile
without even notice if you are using
your computer is very common mistake do
a docker publish and publish to the
wrong place
so
you must to ask yourself if you have
your own container registry if you check
that your docker files are correctly
right
and your pipelines has permission and
access to publish in a docker half
and
it's also good practice allow only some
agents to publish image and check docker
layer contents also check the docker
file and we have a notice
a new there
misconfigured joker registry could be
confidential data leads to a full scale
compromise and interrupt the business
operations it happened that scene that i
say a moment before a docker publisher
we have a very big problem okay
move next
keep your api safe nowadays it's common
to have several apis in your company so
usually some programs call to company
apa
also
do not open all apa to the internet only
those who need it
so as you're safe do you use the apa do
you control the ci cd network access
some tips disable access from
unnecessary places with a firewall we
saved several times
do not install vulnerable plugins we
have the two security
there in the in the
screen to see
okay
more things
source code run somewhere
have your own source source control
server is very convenient but keep it
safe it's not so easy in fact this kind
of servers with ransomware or create a
ransomware that use client permissions
to wipe and fifa user repositories is
already a used technique
don't keep the details of this api on
public code and keep a correct
authentication and authorization methods
for this kind of servers
more suitable to happen those that use
their own machines and mix personal
unprofessional configurations please
don't do that
and also if a ransomware exists because
it works check permissions duba caps
another tip another new about
hackers doing this
okay
move next
the fact docker an evil docker ladder
can contain software and grow massively
on deploy this can prevent to your
company as a sample to deploy security a
security patch
try to use only official image and keep
a local image repository if you can
sometimes a fact docker appears as the
result of back coding but can slow all
your company delivery actions massively
okay
okay i love the picture sorry
the evil docker twin very easy to
perform and very dangerous build an
ability joker container is very easy and
poison you can say also it is
keep under control your docker bills and
please use lighter verification
in your docker files that numbers that
go just the right of from
alpine maybe
okay
push a new docker image from your
pipeline called alpine is a simple test
to check this if you
can anyone on your organization can do a
huge damage in your deploy systems
because they have a complete ladder to
enjoy
okay move next
okay
the greedy service consumer these things
we see happening sometimes
if you use an external service be aware
of the limits some api limit the amount
of calls by ip if your continuous
integration or continuous deployment has
only one public ip
and
you have a graded user of one service
you can deplete the limits and let other
services stuck in your pipelines
keep in mind things like github big
companies a lot of person accessing
github and then all the thing
stop to work because you reach the limit
okay now next
the deployment step okay now we see the
map we are not on the right side of the
map
[Music]
we are almost in production
okay
a room free internet
production sector secrets lay on ci city
until they are deployed so security
concerns must be as important as
production we usually forgotten resource
is internet access keep accurate
firewall configurations to avoid secrets
exfiltrations or leaks
we say this a lot of times okay a trojan
jar
java rely on jar files to deploy most of
the time tools to build a fajr or
manipulate it at broadly available and
easy to use
the java native interface also allowed
the execution or arbitrary executables
keep an eye on the java jar supply chain
please
is very
very very easy and extremely hard to
detect
without
correct tools like our own artifact
repository okay go ahead danny
now okay uh the ship bomb okay
sibo is an old-fashioned attack but it
can be very dangerous in our c system
it's very easy to create
and explode them right in a brief
acid bomb attack consists in a special
created c5 that when a user tried to
uncompress it the seat bomb get a huge
amount on the space
in your heart almost infinite
until your hardness is completely full
right rc bombs format could be easily
detected
right
with a good hardening
but
there is a new ship a sip bomb variant
that is very hard to detect
um and
in this case we have a problem right
okay
the most interesting
about seat bomb is that there is a lot
of software that use
ship
as a package system like microsoft word
java with the jr files
with the word files excels a lot of
there is
some
application servers that deploy new
applications
that was packaged as a ship format like
apache contact
that deployed were files automatically
they were files are sheet format
package file as
i just say
that um
what
okay the question is what if we create
mlis uc bom file
rename us as
a word file
and try to deploy
this application in
in a server like apache tonkat right
what happened if we do that because it's
very very easy to do that you control
the
the cd
or c um workflow this is a a small video
with a
example about that okay before we played
it um
let's see what happens
we have splitted the terminal in three
rows the first one
on the top is so when hard is
free a space before deploy
the the c bomb right the second one is
referring to the free memory memory and
swap memory and third one we can see the
cpu usage
all right now
let's play video
okay no oh yeah okay
no uh we copy the c bomb
to the apache tonka directory when
apache token detected the new file they
try
to deploy it
i will copy the warfight
via ssh
or bias security copy
then we can see how
the uh
the amount of this that the ship pump
get the free the memory until
in
one hour
more or less system breakdown because
that is is for
if this is false means that we also
haven't
free virtual memory
for allocating new processes even for
that the root user can login in a
console to stop
the symbol
right and even more um this attack pass
more uh one hour in this game more or
less it's very very difficult to detect
it
right yes
it's um
funny attack funny if you are the
attacker of course
okay okay to prevent this kind of attack
you must perform accurate hardening of
your system by
limiting how much resources a process
can get it's very simple easier but
very effective
right okay the memory bomb
um not so no not so known as the memory
bond can be sneaky as a bad building
process and kill your machines again and
again
keep in mind that swap is also affected
and can take down your machine what is a
memory bomb a memory bomb is very
similar to the seat bomb but attacks
your memory your active memory your ram
but also your
swap and it's standard running in the
end
okay
what happened if you run a memory bomb
in a continuous integration organize
delivery system what if the continuous
integration is deployed as a multi-agent
let's see a little diagram to see
okay that's the sequence of events first
you put a memory bone in your jenkins
file remember that jji file is source
code you can put everything you want so
the jenkins master send the job to a
jenkins agent and runs the pipeline and
the memory bomb so the jenkins agent
breakdown jinx's master that said that
he would not finish it and send the same
job to another jenkins agent and the
same happen again so
go to stepdos to step two
okay
forward
that's it do we have we have the
ingredients now the demo
let's play it and see what happened with
the memory
execute the pipeline
okay
wait a minute
that's it
we will see the output
in that case we have a
executable file called bom
dot sh
and in a few moments old system will
help and
will not finish
even the machine breaks that's it
we reach everything is frozen even
the jenkins itself froze and
you can
survive this
uh
chicken is compared to frozen
yes you
nothing to do here
okay all the things
wait a minute
now recover from this
not don't recover
we are trying to but
the system is unresponsive in this
moment i'm trying to open a console or
do anything but i can because i execute
this attack on my own machine
sorry
no it's okay let's uh let's
continue uh just to know that memory
bomb is a less known but more effective
and even more effective in docker
because docker has different controls to
the for memory and that kind of stuff
today powerful computers can die very
fast with no clue that what pipeline is
responsible for
is a very fast as you can see and in a
couple of seconds is unresponsive in
responsive
at all
you can lose all your agents before you
find where the problem is
you have this kind of behavior that all
your agents are dying very fast one and
then another one and then another one
check this kind of
scripts
okay
let's move to the next one bomb
and and more traditional the fork bomb
is
the all good for bomb
when you uh
open
a lot of process and then your
system breaks down the all four bomb
stills still is a problem easy to
execute from the prime line can have
similar effects than memory bomb and
it's more easy to detect if you have
very very good loss but only in that
case let's see what happened with
the fork bomb
it's the behavior is almost the same
okay let's go play it that's it
with a very less criteria for my
perspective i execute this also on my
machine
and die very very fast also
okay now it's downloaded
the
files from the git
and
now execute it say that it's success but
the system is
also unresponsive and down in the image
i don't know you can see but the number
on orange from the left down that is
like 800 is our cpu usage on my machine
and
it's completely gone
thousand
[Music]
twelve hundreds
a lot of cpu usage and then
go down my machine also
totally die
very fast as you can see that's real
time in a matter of seconds
we have a responsive system
okay we can move next
yeah
now i'm pretty sure next
step now we are focusing on the final
step of the workflow the productions
down
is your api onus right new applications
are built
using apis
uh most of you or
most of our applications implement
implement
api to perform the most common tags that
usually data we use for example i don't
know twitter facebook and so on but
the the new apis
is the fact
standard
right but
you don't know
you have not a contract in most of the
cases
but
you don't know if your api's responses
that you
expect that they
should uh respond right
and that the question is are you sure
that your api sponsors
don't add
more fields that we define
in the contract
and
are you sure that your api doesn't
respond a different different type of
data that we define in the contract
or are you sure that a malicious
developer can use your api to exfiltrate
data by using extra fields or your api
did you
check that your api around s
okay
um
the
answer in this case is
very very very complicated
um
you should check that your apa contract
are following
um in this case we propose the two tools
the first one ap check is an open source
toolset for working with apis
and the second one is a product
and for a vendor that's
have
test cases to check
this specific
um
issues it does if your apa are honest
right
we don't put more tools because
we don't find it as open so or another
provider right
[Music]
right
keep secret safe um sometimes
we forgot that dog images are only a
package somewhere that could be opened
by someone in their computer
us we don't put
sensitive data
and
into an artifact that will be privileged
in approval repository we must not put
secret and sensitive data inside the
container this is obvious right but
by using
a simple great command we can find
expression like content password in a
docker images after we mount those
images
in my local machine and we can find
easily api kills amazon access case etc
well okay
this image okay as you can see in this
image in 2019
the fever-free intelligent team
were analyzed a thousand of the
kilometers powerless and polluting
repositories not only docker hub and
they found a lot of secrets
inside them there's
this is uh a real fault is and is is
very common
sorry to interrupt you we have about one
or two minutes uh
left so if possible please
please okay
okay okay
okay
well directly to the last demo on the
infrastructure uh the evil alias and
these attackers are fashion but useful
right
it's someone with access to a machine
could write a terminal alias it doesn't
matter the cell
they are using it it could be anyone um
the attack consists in replace a
legitimate command with analysis that
performs actions before around the real
command right um
okay as you can see this
image
as some example about
evil elias right
but with a demo it's nice
in this case in this demonstration we'll
use netcat and
listen to 1999 port and we use the
we create a new alias for the ls command
when a user type or execute an ls
command
these alias will send all of the
environment variables too or um or
server
very easy but very powerful
all right
now
we
reload the new configuration
and type
ls
right and that's it
very easy if we receive all of uh
environment variables and it could be
secrets and so on right
and finally this are uh infra
okay let me check if i have okay i have
no more demos right uh it's very common
to deploy the system production system
uh and share network the
the only thing in this case is please
use isolated
network for c
and the cc cd environment
uh then your production system
all right
okay i'm sorry about that i have no tech
please the the conclusion if you use dpc
vlans and something similar
um that's it the conclusion
the wrap-up is all this kind of stuff
we have
no
time to this this is only the type of
iceberg please be aware all of these and
we can ask us we can reach us in social
media okay next uh danny
and
you can see our twitter we are very
active on twitter
ask
anything any any question that you have
please no
all right that's it