[Music]
all right
uh thanks everyone for attending my talk
today i'll be talking through
essentially a tool that we built at
salesforce called metabadger and um
essentially helping to automate imds
protection at scale across various
infrastructure
and across your aws accounts
so a little bit about me
currently i'm a security engineer
at salesforce supporting various clouds
as kimberly mentioned um i work on a lot
of different business units and so we
deal with a various amount of problems
amongst these different cloud spaces
right different challenges across them
as well
so it's something that
we kind of constantly have to evolve to
and adapt to right so things are
shifting a lot and changing across the
board i really like automation and
putting in cloud automation where
possible right and leveraging public
cloud service providers to be able to
kind of let a lot of the robots do the
work for you rather than doing manual
work and also kind of reducing that
extra toil or friction that exists out
there i think that's super important in
every security program
it's just something that should
definitely be kind of top priority for
folks
um in general right shifting left and is
one thing in particular that i think is
super kind of
important to me and i think being able
to see where the industry is going and
then put controls in place that actually
prevent things from happening in the
first place is also an area where i'm
super interested in
how do we put more preventative
mechanisms in place
rather than going through and kind of
figuring out um more manual ways of
doing things right and so that's kind of
where a lot of my interest lies
currently and i think that's a super
cool space to be working in
um
and recently i've been
more so involved in building a lot of
tooling
for making different
security infrastructure changes or even
automating things within these
environments
i also think it's super helpful for
enabling engineers to help them and be
able to automate a lot of the work that
they do to you know whether it's for
meeting remediating vulnerabilities or
solving different application security
problems um and to be able to apply that
across the board there
so today you know kind of we're boiling
it down why are we talking about
metadata and what is it about metadata
that essentially gives you you know a
lot of different you know things to
consider as far as what you need to look
at um the service itself uh can give you
access to the user data which an
instance may use and also iem
credentials right so a lot of things
that you do from a fundamental um kind
of standpoint of spinning up an ec2
instance it will usually involve some
kind of iem role to talk to other
resources in your account
and from this point right and the
service that is used for that is the
actual embedded instance metadata
service which is abbreviated as imds um
and the instance role and credentials
and tokens as well will be used
throughout that to be able to kind of
pull data that the instance needs to be
able to talk to the resources as well as
kind of understand what its context is
and some other kind of pieces as part of
this metadata service um
and kind of breaking that down even more
right so why why would an attacker want
to leverage this right simply said right
if you can pull the credentials from the
metadata service then we know that hey
we can now pivot in the environment um
and uh ssrf attacks that are known um
and kind of have been used in the past
right
to exploit this particular vector which
uh definitely you know can do
essentially anything that instance can
do right so if somebody's to leverage
this they can go through take a look at
your environment take a look at what you
this instance can do and potentially
exfol data as well as send it elsewhere
um and so we've seen this on news a lot
of the texts that you've seen in the
news and elsewhere kind of have been
essentially this same vector right that
was used hey you know exfol that
metadata service credential or user data
or whatever it is that's accessible from
that and now exploit that give it to me
and i'm going to go and dump a lot of
stuff out of your aws account which can
be really scary when you think about it
because there's a lot of sensitive
things that live there
um the characters uh right can just
clearly dump the credentials and use
them and so that's one area we're like
hey how do we really mitigate against
this and why what can we do to solve
this particular problem
so just a high level a breakdown of sort
of what this attack chain and flow looks
like is we have a user that's exploiting
an ssrf web app vulnerability uh that
may exist on a web app or some kind of
customer facing or user facing form
right or input field where they're able
to kind of now leverage this and say hey
i'm going to get access to
talk to the instance and talk to what
the instance can do from the metadata
perspective
looking into this right we can see hey
we're able to run something now from the
web app the attacker has now kind of
understood this and they'll try usually
to see you know can we curl the metadata
service can i go ahead and talk to this
particular sensitive service that exists
out there which could help me pull down
the credentials the user data other
sensitive pieces of information that
could give away more information about
your environment from a reconnaissance
perspective perspective
and then get that back and bring that to
the actor as well
but so if they're actually successful in
getting to the point of of curling the
metadata service and getting those
credentials they're simply able to make
that request where
you know to the instance itself it may
seem like the instance is just making
that request on its own right because
it's coming straight from that
particular uh web app that's running on
it right and so this is looping back
talking to the metadata service the
instance simply returns that through to
the web app
kind of grabs it sends it to the bad
actor again and this is where you know
at that point the attacker will now use
a secret key and identification here the
kia key right and then as well as a
session token to say now can i use these
credentials and particularly assume the
role or even use those threads in
particular to access anything that that
instance had access to
and then this is where the the pivot
vector itself comes from right so now
they're able to pivot and traverse your
environment
take a look at various areas a lot of
discovery work happens at this point at
this point in time right so if you're
looking through and seeing
you know access to s3 or access to some
other resource they're able to dump
those or potentially even modify things
depending on what the instance can do
now if we look at v2 we can kind of see
how this changes a bit right so the same
exact flow would work in the sense that
you would still have the same web app
vulnerability that exists i would go
through and take a look at the instance
metadata service we've talked to it we
can go ahead and check hey are we able
to return this to like this request from
a crawl or can i even see anything
beyond this and that comes back
essentially to the web app
the attacker sees that finds that
and now it's returned they're able to
say hey can i use these credentials and
actually talk to different things and
this is the part where really we're
creating some extra friction and we're
making it harder for attackers to
actually look and get these credentials
and use them as easily as they could
before
so aws implemented v2 to essentially
prevent that particular attack factor
and harden that environment as far as
you know being able to exfil those
credentials from a vpc or from wherever
the instance is running and then use
them elsewhere
so we can see that access will be denied
right if they are getting that because
we're moving from a simple put request
model to a session based model and
what's important to note here is like
hey now we're going to need a token
and on top of that there's a couple
other pieces around ttl cracked headers
and so forth that we're going to be
looking at to really make sure that this
request is coming where it's coming
where it's from supposed to come from
right
and i think that's a super key indicator
to help you determine
hey you know now that we're validating
this request you can no longer you know
take those credentials and use them from
anywhere um and i you know on a high
level i think it's super fundamental to
understand that uh you know with these
requests are kind of being made from
somewhere that they're not supposed to
be they should never be ever kind of
like allowed to be made and you can
probably pair that with im policies et
cetera as well but just this simple flow
right and changing this one thing on the
instance because actually prevents you
from dealing with that particular
problem
so what are the larger differences in v1
and v2 and i kind of went through some
of these
we're really moving away from a simple
put request model to the session based
one
and we're asking for that token right so
anytime you request make a request of
metadata service you're going to have to
pass to the token and so you originally
originally have to essentially get a
token first put that into your request
and say hey i have a token now i'm going
to pass it to you um i'm coming from a
legitimate place and
we this request should go through and
you can give me back whatever
information i'm asking for um that the
actual token was not a requirement in v1
right so that was one area where i think
uh has improved over time and and it's
kind of why we need to do it this way um
as well as kind of changing the
different methods rate so that put
request model is changing now and we
have uh the get and head methods so
anytime you're making a request to the
metadata service we have to you know
essentially add that to the get method
itself and say hey we're inserting a
token here and if that token's not there
you're definitely going to get an
unauthorized you know access denied
you're you're not passing me the right
things i need now because we're adding a
layer of complexity um and also
preventing this larger pivot vector for
attackers to use um across the board
so why should we use it right and we
chatted through that you know we
emphasize that hey it's a session
requirement
and really it boils down to the fact
that this is really a hardening
configuration right um and you're
mitigating a good bit of risk in the
sense that a lot of those same attacks
that we were talking about are now a lot
harder and um actually can't even be
performed most of the time
and this pairing this paired together
with ssrf vulnerabilities i think
tackles a larger problem around how all
the metadata service um itself is being
used and how we're actually
communicating with it right and and how
attackers will leverage that and play
into the whole concept of hey i can now
steal your credentials because there is
no other mitigations in place to prevent
me from using them outside of your
account so we really want to make sure
that the the actual configurations on
these hosts are locked down and that can
be done via the api right uh we can make
it a requirement every time an instance
is spun up we can also do that via an
iem policy and say any requests going to
the metadata service itself should be
and um should always you know make sure
to be coming from a particular version
of that service right so if it's hey are
we talking about v1 or v2 it'll come
from v2 and a request from v1 on that
particular instance will actually fail
so you won't even be able to use v1 on
there
and those will fail so you're always
enforcing it
session tokens as well right so when
we're talking about having those enabled
and always mandatory we're restricting
it to simply say
every single request being made to that
service has to have that mandatory token
right so this is also where it gets
complicated because a lot of the
existing infrastructure you might be
running may not consider this and
we'll get into that a little later but
it's just another kind of step in the
process of talking to the service and
getting those credentials down
um the other larger call out is also the
the forwarded for header so a lot a lot
of the times attackers may actually use
some kind of proxy right to route
traffic through
and and actually pass things by in a
sense that when they're going through
the web app they'll try to get to the
instance that they're talking to and
um this information will get routed back
right and so what this particular uh
what the v2 of the service does is
actually limits that ability because
it'll validate the origination and
destination of that particular um that
header there to say are you coming from
a place where you're allowed to come
from um and if you're using this
particular header we're not even going
to allow this request to happen because
you're forwarding this particular
request to the to the metadata service
we don't really want this kind of
traffic happening in the first place
right because essentially the instance
should only be talking to the metadata
service
at the hypervisor level at the ec2 point
of view right so there should never be
something forwarding a request to the
metadata service
and if there was a use case like that i
don't know you know outside of some
attack scenario what that would be used
for but there could be
but in this particular scenario we are
we're kind of vending out a lot of those
particular proxy based attacks
uh tooling wise right so when i looked
at
solving this problem originally
you know the first thing you usually do
is kind of check hey is there like a
tool that does this already is there
something out there that can help us and
mitigate this problem and solve this
particular risk for us in an easy and
simple way
and kind of breaking that down i didn't
find anything that could really at the
time at least uh that was super granular
and preventing um this type of attack
and being able to
sort of hand pick what you wanted to fix
and what you wanted to upgrade um
there's a number of different things
that exist today
inside the cloud provider itself in aws
where you can use some cloud watch
metrics to kind of determine hey are we
using um v1 versus v2
can we actually track this and then can
we actually look at even the ec2 api
right to be able to look at hey is this
instance running which version right and
so there's a lot of different options
that you have um that exist today in
order to look at this uh but you can but
at the time i really wanted to gather
some kind of tool that would be able to
sort of scale as well right so a lot of
the times i'm looking at a different
infrastructure that could have anywhere
from like 80 000 plus instances right
which and in this span this could span
across multiple regions right so we're
really looking at a lot of
infrastructure a lot of different
running nodes and this can span across
your container infrastructure as well
which is could be running on ec2 right
and they also have a metadata service on
those every single ec2 will just it's
just the nature of how the instances
communicate up with the rest of the
resources in that particular account
but uh we really wanted to proactively
sort of see hey
are we able to check
on what and every single instance is
using and then are we able to kind of
validate that right so
in in our in our kind of like
brainstorming of the tool we wanted to
be able to
add the configuration options in there
to be able to harden the infrastructure
um and then you know take a look at what
we're dealing with from from the
infrastructure point of view on the
instances
um the scps that exist today as well are
is another aspect to point out so you
can actually have preventative policies
that will
be put in place where it says you can't
even spin up an instance that is using
v2 because our overarching service
control policy says that we can't do
that um this is a very kind of
shift-left way of of doing it i know in
gcp there there's also kind of policies
like that as well and this is aws's
version um i think they're great once
you kind of sort of know that everything
in your environment can run v2 but
there's a lot of discovery in the
process of making sure that you're
actually in a place to go ahead and put
a policy like that um down because once
you do there could be issues with
existing infrastructure um and i know
i've mentioned i you know throughout the
slides here that hey there's there's
definitely a lot of caution to be had
with deploying any of the v2 versus v1
because certain services and certain
infrastructure can only run with a
particular version just depending on
what it is uh because of like i
mentioned earlier right we do have to
kind of curl to get that token
a lot of things out of the box may not
know how to do that
sometimes we run into cases where
things might not know hey did you switch
versions like is this a session request
even with the methods of how is it being
communicated to
that's another piece of it that gets to
kind of come into consideration as well
so uh mentioning the discovery process
earlier right we had to go through and
take a look at how do we actually
determine what is using our metadata
service um and by looking at the
cloudtrail logs that's one really good
way i think to actually find out hey are
we using them out of that service and if
so like where is that coming from
and from our perspective the the real
lens of it right um that we wanted to
see is
the biggest kind of differentiator there
between the two is if we're going
through the sdk
we probably know that upgrading to v2
won't be as complicated of a problem
essentially because
they're um it's a lot easier to
have v2 going through the sdk and a lot
of the sdk versions actually support v2
out of the box so you're saying i i
don't actually have to go and curl the
metadata service and i'm just going
straight through the sdk it will
automatically just um use v2 because
that's the way it works right and if
it's on deleted the version that
supports that as well
you won't have to run into that issue
the other thing with the user data and
the user agent itself well the user
agent we could tell if it was coming
from a particular cli command because um
amazon actually will tell you hey you're
either going from you know a ck or
somebody's running a command versus with
the aws cli which could mean something
completely different which we'd have to
put some other scrutiny into right to
understand how does this work um what
does this look like and so forth uh the
user data itself is another area that i
think is important to look at so are you
calling the user data when you're
spinning up your instances this is also
another piece of it right because like
you're this is coming from the metadata
service so at any point during the
runtime or even while the instance is
running are you looking at pieces of the
user data that you're passing to the
instance for any kind of purposes
this will also be something that's
helpful if you look at the code base
itself and you know of something that's
running and you notice that you're
saying different user data being stored
and variables and you're saying
i need to figure out like where should i
be processing this and where where are
kind of like areas where we need to take
a little bit more concern and caution
because there could be situations where
v2 will cause problems with that
and i've also kind of
evaluate a different software right so
some reagents and software that runs on
host depending on what it is and
depending on if it's a vendor that
you're using or if it's some other open
source tool right sometimes they only
support one version of imps which is
super interesting um and this goes back
to the whole concept of hey you know is
there a token being used if not then
that may be the whole issue there around
what this particular service is doing
and what the agent is doing to be able
to kind of work with imds correctly and
that will definitely break at some point
which is why you know testing is super
super important here like depending on
the environment that you're in if you're
endeavor stage uh just testing this out
and making sure that you know once
you've updated the imds uh kind of
version you're testing and you're
thoroughly kind of going through and
making sure that all your unit tests and
everything else that your you know qa
process would hold in place is actually
complaining as as it should be
just because you know there you never
know when there's one service or
something that's leveraging the imds uh
kind of
larger service that may have a problem
or break at some point
um and then vlogs right so logs are
really really important as well to look
at um on actually workloads or instances
that you're running as well to see hey
is there something in here that would
tell us that we're actually talking to
this particular ip so we saw earlier
right we know that it's like 169 254
right and repeat it again
to be able to talk to that if we're able
to see hey alma instance itself or are
we actually doing anything or are there
the logs point to us talking to the
metadata service at all because this
will really tell you what exactly is
happening so any kind of like host based
logs that you're forwarding over if you
can take a look at those and actually
get a better understanding of where
those live i think that's super helpful
to just know and do more of like an
inventory to speak and then understand
where exactly that service
lives um and the tool we made was meta
badger um and kind of solves for some of
those larger pieces that we just
discussed um around checking to see
which version you're using and we want
to be able to do this a lot large amount
of scale i give insights into different
things like role attachments are we
using iem services
and are we you know kind of looking at
all the different precautions we want to
take around that right so being able to
iterate through every instance say oh
we're using iam here is there something
in particular we should be looking at
call out the role be able to understand
that and then also give us a lot of
different options as far as what we're
able to do so we want to have the
ability to not only just upgrade to v2
but we want to enable we want the
ability to enable it let's say it's
turned off somewhere where we need it
let's say we want to disable the actual
service itself or it's not needed and i
think that's actually a really good
approach because you know if you have an
aws account or something we're using a
bunch of instances and they really have
no need for the service then you know
you can simply disable it um and that
way you're kind of reducing any
potential there for
um if if something were to change on
that host or whatnot and so that's kind
of those are the two main main
functionalities as well as kind of
upgrading which is the base one right
from v1 to v2 uh we do a simple api
check we want to go through check to see
if in that returned object where you
know we're seeing v1 on that particular
host if so we would easily be able to
upgrade a v2 right and this is super
simple from the ec2 api to be able to go
through and do that
um and then you know as we're thinking
through this we're also considering hey
should there be a fallback option and as
always and in the world of technology
right you always want to be able to roll
back so we created some functionality
there about rolling back and being able
to go to v1 as well as kind of logging
every change there um
and being able to understand hey what is
actually what's being done right so we
include some things such as like a dry
run functionality and so forth to be
able to validate what you're doing and
making sure that all those all those
potential kind of config changes that
you're about to make are documented
somewhere and you're able to kind of
evaluate that on your own
the other piece that we wanted to kind
of also add was around the ability to be
super granular so like when it comes to
tagging and other instance ids
there's always going to be the question
of do we want to apply this across the
board or do we want to single out
certain instances or certain workloads
where you might not actually want to
update the service right like we
mentioned earlier if there was a issue
with the software or something else was
kind of problematic for you and you
wanted to hold off on upgrading certain
pieces of your environment you could do
that and so we added in the component of
looking through and having that a badger
go through and evaluate the tags as well
as kind of update instance ids based off
of passing in a file essentially to go
through and validate and say okay these
are part of
the list of things that i need to go and
update i'll go ahead and do that
so larger higher picture kind of problem
statement right that we mentioned um is
sort of putting in together the piece of
of kind of hey what are we solving for
here right uh and how are we kind of
approaching this problem right
and it kind of boils down to the you
have a bunch of web apps or load
balancers or whatever you're serving on
these ec2 instances right with sensitive
data and other things and all sorts of
right containers whatever it may be
that's running on these ec2s and if they
do have the ability to be susceptible to
ssrf attacks where
you know they could potentially get a
foothold on that on the ability to
inject something and then curl back a
you know response from the metadata
service then we're dealing with a larger
problem um and so these these
vulnerabilities could definitely exist
across the board the thing is we don't
really know right and our our kind of
main goal is to reduce that overall tax
surface to make sure that that doesn't
even the problem that isn't even a
problem in the future right when we're
looking into it and we shouldn't even
have to worry about the fact that a
particular ssrf vulnerability is going
to cause this issue if we're really
looking at a defense in-depth sort of
approach to it and layering on
additional kind of friction for an
attacker to have um to protect the
particular instance that we have
uh and then you know as far as the
attack surface goes we're really kind of
limiting the blast radius there as far
as what they can do from from the
credentials as well as as well as their
ability to even get those credentials
and move out there
um and then we you know back with with
with evaluating and doing the discovery
we want to make sure that everything
that we're doing and looking at as far
as instances go we can understand hey
are these actual um kind of like i am
roles that are being attached to these
instances should we like be looking at
these and then also we want to make sure
that we're pairing that data with our
meta data hardening right with the
actual tool itself can we now evaluate
everything and give us a better
understanding from the discovery process
so today you know we have a few things
baked into the tool
it is an open source project is
available today as well
but currently
these are some of the base
functionalities that that are built into
it so you know you can easily kind of
run meta badger and go through and
discover all the different metadata
usage depending on what version you're
on and then you can do this um really at
scale which i think is awesome in the
sense that
you know you will if if folks have ever
worked with both three before there's
definitely some cases where um you'll do
pagination if you're dealing with really
large data sets et cetera
and at scale right you really have to
build out
your code in a way where it's going to
be able to understand oh i'm looking at
tons and tons and tons of data
tons and tons of instance data as well
because there's so many of them and
being able to parse that out and
correctly kind of modify things in a way
where that makes sense and in a way
where you know you're not kind of
getting to the api and it's in a way
where it's going to kind of throttle you
or run into issues of that sort of
nature so that was a huge kind of
functionality that the main real
functionality we wanted to build out is
hey can we actually go through and
discover all this and actually go
through the hardening process the same
way
at scale and being able to build code
that functions in that aspect
and you know on top of that like i
mentioned the the discovery aspect of it
is also important so we wanted to see
where the roles were so we also go
through and kind of parse out the roles
that are being used per instance as well
as kind of all the functionality around
disabling updating it um if they're not
being used
we can actually go through and just
disable it and then we can also just
update and harden it across the board um
and recently we even added the
functionality to do that to do that
across like an entire account if you
wanted to pass in whatever regions you
want or if you wanted to just run the
all region flag on there you could
actually go through and just update
everything um all across the board and
then you know once you've done all this
work you should be able to kind of
produce a summary of hey
metrics wise right we love security
metrics we love to see how is my attack
surface changed how how many you know
instances are using one version
versus the other and we're able to break
down a percentage essentially of
where you know our problem areas might
lie and what percentage of coverage we
have for v2 as well
so some future architecture and design
kind of goals that we have on here in a
wish list as well it's just kind of
including functionality for some
automation right so we really wanted to
build in and potentially even build in
some lambdas that could do some auto
enforcement i know part of this already
exists with some config rules but we
were thinking of hey if we wanted to
kind of increase the automation behind
meta badger and have this running as a
continuous enforcement thing with those
same kind of mechanisms that you wanted
to pass through the tool uh we find that
that might be helpful for folks right so
being able to update things like tags or
instance ids or other kind of pieces and
components of it would be super helpful
to have that running in a continuous
enforcement environment because then you
can get granular and you can have your
automation kind of work for you in that
sense
and then you know moving back to the
shift left concept as well we you know
wanted the tool in the future
potentially to look at the different
kind of configurations that may already
exist out there so if you have a code
base where you're you know checking in
infrastructure as code such as cloud
formation or
even terraform and others and so forth
right how do we actually look at that
how do we look at the code that's used
to actually spin up the infrastructure
and even go through and call that out in
the code base so maybe we go through and
check all the different terraform
modules or validate anything that that
might be spinning up in ec2 right to see
hey are we actually using v1 or v2 here
are there any provisions that we're
putting into place there around like
validating that folks can't just use the
default version etc and then building
that into the tool to be able to
validate that um or even update it right
so going in there and like maybe even
adding in a config change to update your
your kind of metadata service to v2 is
something that we've thought about
um and then in aws i know that there's
option there's an option for v1 and v2
and some other cloud providers that were
that may or may not work differently
right so some of them enforce them being
on the latest by default others don't
it's just kind of variant depending on
the cloud but we find that there may be
some usage here around how this is being
how the service in particular across the
board across cloud providers is being
used so you know if there's if this tool
would be beneficial in that aspect we
may kind of span it out to at least do
some of like the discovery work or even
hardening work across the board there
so this is a quick demo i can kind of
show you how the tool itself
functions
we walk through and do just a simple
kind of meta badger discover metadata
right so this goes through and pulls
down all the different
um instances where you have that are
enabled or optional essentially optional
just means hey you can use v2 i mean
sorry you can use v1 because
v2 is totally optional and this is
coming straight from the api so that's
kind of like the language that's used
there and then we also get a breakdown
of which ones are enabled and then a
total instant count
so
we can see how we know what our
percentage of enforcement is um that
second command there is a discover role
usage one where like i mentioned right
being able to identify hey which
instances have a role attached can we
parse that down can we actually take a
look there this is just good for
you know doing a little bit of initial
reconnaissance to see
is i am being used is it kind of in play
here do we need to take extra caution
and finally harden metadata kind of goes
through it and we'll just do it default
on us west too to iterate through every
single instance and update that and so
this is just the super bass
functionality obviously there's a lot of
flags and things you can pass in like i
mentioned that's kind of honor actual
repos well if you want to read into it
but that is sort of a gist of what we
kind of built out in a quick little demo
of how that all works
let me go ahead and present back
um so yeah
onto the next slide here i just wanted
to give a quick kind of moment to uh
call out that we are hiring here at
salesforce um a couple few different
roles and type role types i guess you
could say as well that we're hiring for
so as far as the security architecture
goes um devsecops a lot of the work that
things like meta badger et cetera and
then kind of working on that within the
environment as well um threat
vulnerability management pen testing and
then recently just enterprise security
just came up as well so if you have any
interest at all if you want to chat
through it uh or if you want me to
connect you with the right folks feel
free to dm me at twitter on twitter and
then um i'm also in this really really
cool slack channel as well called cloud
security forum so folks join that
some folks that i know as well as some
other interesting folks in this space
who are always kind of solving the next
kind of
larger problems that exist which is
always involving right in cloud security
so feel free to connect on there
and yeah so this is a reference to the
actual repo itself and we really love uh
contributing with folks in the community
so if you have any ideas or feel like
there's some contributions that could be
made as well or even just questions you
know feel free to reach out super happy
to help and super happy to hear also
like experiences with using the tool and
how it looks in them and other people's
environments as well as if there's any
issues with it at all um
yeah i guess we're good to go to q a