[Music]
awesome thank you for that intro jason
hi everyone nice to meet you last
session of the date i guess i'm sitting
between you and beer for friday
so um i'll try to see if we can finish
this talk in 45 minutes or less
the goal of this talk is to make sure
that we understand how
various apsec testing methodologies can
work together and observability is
emerging as one of the one of the
popular uh
up and coming ways to
get visibility into applications
especially cloud native applications so
today we're going to talk about
why
what observability is
why is it kind of important um
especially given the cloud native
landscape and we're also going to touch
upon
um
why observability can stand on its own
and be useful but
for the purpose of this overwatch talk
we'll talk about how
observability when used in conjunction
with a das tool
and we're going to use osp zap as the
example here
it's it's one of those things where one
plus one can be greater than two
um so let's let's dig right in so these
are the things that i had in mind so i
also wanted to make sure that while we
talk about specific appsec technology
uh
technologies like observability or desk
we also kind of talk about the
underlying reasons why these tools are
important like for example
it makes sense to talk about these apps
challenges
that are out there that are causing
um
modernization of appsec modern apps are
being created these days which is
causing modern
the need for modern app seg technology
and that and we'll talk about a little
bit of that as well and then we'll talk
about the existing landscape of appsec
tools out there starting all the way
from sas to artifact scanners to gas and
so on and so forth and then figure out
you know how is what are the new things
that are emerging given cloud-native
applications and how can these new
technologies like observability
complement existing tools like adast or
like a software composition analysis as
well as provide additional visibility
into runtime behavior etc and we'll end
with if you were thinking about planning
your abstract strategy especially as
your team may be going through digital
transformation you're creating
cloud-native applications how do you go
about planning for that abstract
strategy and what are some general not
stars that people tend to look for and
uh if if you um
if you'd like to embark upon that
journey then you know it's good to think
about certain things uh as opposed to
kind of go for uh you know deal with it
when it happens kind of thing right
and then we'll end with q a
so a quick introduction about um what is
deep factor we're a silicon valley
company we're now a a global distributed
company
um we are a cloud native application
security platform
our goal is to enable engineering teams
to quickly discover resolve security
issues supply chain risks and compliance
issues
during the course of development so that
when the application ships
into production
it's already
there's there's much less number of
risks in that application from a
security perspective from a compliance
perspective et cetera how are we
different from other appsec tools and
why is there a need for a new generation
of apps tooling specifically targeted
towards cloud native applications it's
because cloud native applications have
changed the way we build applications
so as apps get modernized and broken
down into microservices
taking and you're moving into these
modern
application architectures with modern ci
pipeline tooling do you really want to
take the baggage of the older apps like
tools and move on instead a better way
to think about it is to use a platform
an abstract platform that is
purpose-built for
modern app applications
that's essentially what inspired us to
uh inspired me to quit cisco which was
my previous job i told my previous
company to cisco
and i was the head of the product team
at cisco's cloud business unit and i
quit my job and started deep factory too
to create a cloud-native application
security platform so deep factored
summarizes a unified appsec platform it
combines it provides a combination an
integrated experience between artifact
scanning it has software composition
analysis container scans
sbam etc as well as runtime visibility
in a unified experience targeted towards
cloud native applications and it uses
the concept of runtime observability to
actually observe what's happening when
the application is running by seamlessly
dropping into your kubernetes cluster or
your containerized application
and using the runtime information to not
only provide visibility to how your
application security risks are while
your app is running but also augment
other
asd tools like a das or like like a
software composition analysis to provide
that unified kind of experience that
results in comprehensive coverage and
yet lesser number of
high value insights
that's the customary one slide
that i have on deep factory and the rest
of this presentation obviously is going
to be vendor neutral and the goal here
is thought leadership not not to
pleasure product
um but there's some really interesting
technologies that we've created that i
think it make for a fantastic kind of
discussion
um what is obasp zap this group you guys
are all experts in this in this area so
you probably already already
you know all know about oh wasp zap it's
one of the popular
dast uh tools out there open source
built by the oas you know folks
and it allows uh both appsec teams as
well as engineers to automate uh you
know security testing uh from a dynamic
application security testing perspective
you can even tie that into your cicd
pipeline
so on and so forth
so let's talk about the broader abstract
challenges that are driving a change
in applications how application security
is actually done
the
we we're sitting at the intersection of
a couple of interesting trends number
one is
the number of security breaches and the
size of security breaches has increased
tremendously over the last couple of
years and that trend is only going one
way
number two
digital transformation
every enterprise company is a software
company now
and every enterprise is majority of them
are going through a digital
transformation
where they're embracing cloud native
applications their old monolithic
applications are being broken down into
microservices kubernetes serverless so
on and so forth
there's some interesting stats
that that are coming out when you think
about what's happening in this
cloud-native world number one is
because of the newness of cloud-native
applications everybody is kind of you
know a lot of the people are
experiencing security-related issues
with kubernetes with cloud-native
deployments
security-related issues cause breaches
security-related issues cause delays in
engineering you've caught early on
during the course of development but
they still have to go find fix it
takes time
the number of applications being
developed has skyrocketed
so idc report
says that by 2023 which is two years
from now we'll be looking at 500 million
cloud native applications total global
that's a lot of applications
and the number of developers today we're
sitting at about 26 million developers
worldwide
and that number is going to get to 45
million developers by 2030.
that's a lot of people as well so a lot
of people writing code a lot of
applications being created a lot of
applications being created with a modern
cloud native kind of point of view but
the number of cyber security jobs as you
guys all know especially from this
conference is very little there's only
three and a half million you know
there's still three and a half million
unfulfilled
cyber security jobs that are out there
as of 2021.
so
if you put all of these things together
apps are becoming more complex
they're shipping at a faster pace thanks
to cicd
there's more engineers writing code
there's more cloud native applications
being shipped
and there's not enough appsec people to
test all of those things so what is the
solution the solution is to make sure
that we automate as many security and
compliance related risk findings early
on during the course of development so
that the dev teams are equipped to
understand these risks
during the course of development and
deliver a secure application
enter devsecops
now what is
driving
this appsec modernization you know apps
are being modernized
that is that is causing appsec to be
modernized
as well
because
if you think about it if you if your
apps are are being modernized
you can't
rely on the old appsec tools you can i
mean
or you still have the option of putting
together a hodgepodge of five or six
different apps of tools and i'll go
over some of the tool options that we
have today
but that's cumbersome
instead
now
is a good time to start thinking about
how do you
how do you re-imagine your appsec
initiatives itself and especially um
absec initiatives that align with your
digital transformation initiatives so
when we talk to you know we've talked
over 100 enterprises over the last you
know year or so
and the reasons why each of these
organizations is going through uh and
thinking about appsec right now and cicd
et cetera is uh it can be broken down
into about five groups and that's kind
of what we've done one is app
modernization app modernization due to
containerization kubernetes serverless
etc is causing them to think about
what is the right way to secure these
applications
number two cause is
you know i want to make sure that i
proactively embed security into the cs
pipeline
so into my software development
lifecycle i want to make sure that
identifying risks and security is baked
in before that that's that's a common
theme that we hear from enterprises
alert fatigue resulting in slowing down
the release velocity is also a common
theme that we hear which is
i have a bunch of tools
you know one for code scanning one for
artifact scanning one for container
scanning so on and so forth these all
give me a lot of alerts
but it's it's too many alerts
and my team gets either frustrated with
it and ends up not fixing it or
they end up fixing
these alerts a lot of them which results
in the release is getting too late
the other thing is tool fitting now
there's there's a lot of tools out there
i don't want to put together five or six
or seven different tools as part of my
ci pipeline to get visibility into all
aspects of my application security
behavior
is it wouldn't it be great if i had
you know a unified kind of experience
across these tools
and lastly
especially as apps are being
modernized and put into the cloud-native
world
um
there's a need to understand how these
applications are behaving while they're
running
and that's what observability can help
us get to
that today is not possible with the
existing set of tools
um because they're either looking at
code
code scanners or they're looking at
artifact scanners or they're looking at
das or maybe i asked but i asked is you
know is was designed 10 years ago when
kubernetes didn't even exist so it
wasn't designed for these modern cloud
native kind of applications
so observability
is necessary because
the
not only because you want to find issues
in an application while the application
is running
but it's also important because you want
to correlate the observability findings
with what your other scanners have
produced so that you can reduce the
volume of insights and find richer
lesser number of insights for your
engineering team to be able to triage
them and results in greater velocity
so what is observability
as we discussed observability is the
method of evaluating applications
while the applications are running
to reach meaningful conclusions about
the health of the application
performance of the application and
security behaviors of the application
so far
over the last decade or so we've seen
the evolution of apm tools
apm tools were the first generation of
monitoring tools that were monitoring
applications performance and health
it with cloud native
with the advent of cloud-native
applications apm tools kind of morphed
into observability tools because they're
now starting using the more
accepted cloud-native interception
technologies to gather visibility into
cloud-native applications and they're
all calling themselves the new breed of
apm tools is observability tools but
they're still all looking at performance
logs metrics tracing you know that sort
of
visibility
there's a couple of you know a few
handful of companies that are now
beginning to use observability from an
absec perspective because the telemetry
that you gather from a running
application is the same whether you use
it for performance or whether you use it
for health or whether you use it for
security so far as an industry over the
last decade we've used it for
performance and health now we're
starting to we're starting to use it for
absec visibility
so why is observability important for
appsec
because number one
it helps you identify risky runtime
behaviors that are not caught by static
scanners
let's say for example you have a you
have a developer the developer brings in
a piece of code
third-party code
that piece of code passes your
uh
sca scans you know there's no cvs no no
critical cvs that are detected
great
but at runtime
what happens is it reaches out to a
certain geography let's say for example
antarctica
it makes an outbound connection to
you your developer did not know that
because that's not part of the code that
he wrote
your developer did not know that
the third party that he brought in did
it
because it passed
the
software composition analysis test and
there was no cve detected
this is not a cve it's a bad runtime
behavior
there's plenty of such runtime behaviors
i just gave you an example of one you
know networking behavior but it could be
things like you know your application
used a certain certain port that it's
not supposed to be used or your
application touched a certain file that
it wasn't supposed to touch or your
application loaded a library from slash
temp which is not accepted behavior so
the loss of risky run time behaviors
that
static code scanners will not catch
especially that runtime behavior exists
in your oss dependency or third-party
dependency that is part of your
application
and let's face it today 75 of most
applications is third-party code so it's
not only important for us to scan all of
these applications scan your custom code
not only important for us to get a list
of vulnerabilities by using software
composition analysis or container and
scanning but it's also important for us
to observe the application at runtime in
order for us to get a full picture of
the application security posture
the other benefit of observing an
application of runtime is you also get
to prioritize the vulnerabilities that
are detected by your software
composition analysis for example
based on which of these vulnerabilities
are actually executed or loaded at runta
for example
if your
blackduck scan tells you there are 200
vulnerabilities in your application
combining that with an observability
tool will tell you that out of the 200
your application only loaded 25 of them
it will help you reduce the alert volume
of your software composition analysis
tool and therefore reduce the alert
fatigue that your dev team might
be dealing with
so those are the two fundamental
benefits of using observability for
appsec you identify risky runtime
behaviors you also use it to make your
other security tools better such as
software composition analysis by
reducing the alert volume you can also
use use it to make das better which is
what i'm going to talk about
the rest of this discussion
and why is observability an absolute
must-have when it comes to cloud-native
applications because cloud-native
applications increase the
dimensions of complexity
in more than one way
number one it's written in multiple
languages
because you have one container that has
a c application another container that
has a golang application another
container that has a job application and
they're all written by different teams
maybe
some of these developers don't even have
standardized container based images so
they take one
you know that is an ubuntu based image
another container image could have
alpine in it and there's kind of no
standardization because all they did was
go to the the docker registry and get a
certain base image and started working
on it happens all the time
so it increases the surface area of risk
because your applications are broken up
into micro services there's a lot more
touch points to those applications that
need to be observed as well and purely
scanning your static code is not going
to cut it
number three is you're now shipping
faster
all the way through to prod with cicd
you're also releasing more frequently
and that makes static scans insufficient
because you need to complement it with
observability
now there's a few different ways to
observe
a running application
different technologies for the for the
engineers in you there are
approaches like agent based approaches
something like the cystic falco type
approach which allows you to
have an agent on each of the host in for
example your kubernetes cluster and each
of the agents will basically use
ebpf to track
application
traffic for file system behaviors or
kernel
system call behavior etc by looking at
how this the application behavior is
converting to system calls and tracking
those system calls using ebpf in the
kernel
the second approach to doing that is
sidecars now we've seen tools like aqua
or
palo alto uh networks uh the prismacloud
you know product twist lock in the past
those are all tools that actually
give you a sidecar and the sidecar loads
a privileged it's a privileged sidecar
so it loads a kernel driver that then
ends up using ebpf on your host to then
watch application system called queue
there's a third approach which is
loading or pre-loading a library into
your applications process that's more of
a user space approach
and it allows you to watch your
applications in the user space
without kernel mode drivers etc
and that's that's the approach that you
know companies like deep factory take so
we have we have different uh
technologies that are used to observe um
applications at runtime which one is
better for you depends on your use case
and and the problem that you're trying
to solve uh in some cases it also
depends on the persona that is trying
that you're trying to solve a problem
for if your goal is to identify
behaviors in production you know you
might have a certain uh you know and the
end users operations there's a different
uh
tool that might that might better fit
your use case but if you our goal is to
uh bake it into your devops pipeline and
let the developers consume the insight
then you might need to use a different
way of observing your application so it
really depends on which one
what problem you're trying to solve
let's take a look at the plethora of
abstech tools that are out there
interestingly enough these tools have
evolved over the last couple of decades
the funny thing is
all of those tools are actually
important because they do slightly
different things
and and we've mapped them all the way
from static to dynamic to runtime
on the static side we have
sas which is the most popular you know
asd tool
it's a code scanner
and recently we've started seeing
infrastructure as code scanners it's
still code but it's the infrastructure's
code code like terraform scripts and
whatnot
that's also a code scanner just a
different kind of code scanner so these
things
are static they scan your code
then you have artifact scanners still
static but they scan your build
artifacts like for example software
composition analysis will scan your jar
files or npm files and identify which
cvs exist in in those files uh in the
list of dependencies that you may have
orwas dep check is a great project from
the os group that actually
does a software composition analysis as
well
container image scanning
is absolutely essential again it takes
the artifact in this case the artifact
is a container image and then it tries
to find out risks that exist in the
container image based on a list of
publicly available vulnerability
database
for example the nist database which is
publicly available to anyone or
something like a more custom homegrown
database like a black duck or a snake
you know etc
then you have
dynamic scans
so static scans tell you
you know whether your code has some
vulnerabilities or whether your
artifacts has some known cvs
they're useful but they also spit out a
lot of alerts the volume is usually
pretty high and you need to make sure
that you
you reduce that volume
and prioritize it that's important
the second thing is they miss out on a
bunch of things that only dynamic
scanners can catch and that's where a
das comes in like oh wasp zap is a great
example
das allows you to scan the application
from the outside it's not looking at
your in your running application it is
sending your application a payload
and then your application returns a
certain result result and based on the
request and response it tells you if
your application is susceptible to any
of the owasp top 10 type issues you know
cross-site scripting sql injection
things like that
and then on the right side you have run
time
ast tools application security testing
tools
a popular one here is interactive asd
tools you know tools like contrast
security et cetera they were designed
you know 10 years ago
all these tools allow you to
um
in to instrument a language specific
agent like if it's a java application
you say okay install java agent if it's
a dot net application you install a java
you know document agent and they allow
you to get visibility into how your
application is behaving
um
you know by looking inside the
application
and then you have container security
tools container security tools allow you
to either you know these would be the
twist locks and the aquas of the world
or or de-factor
these tools allow you to get you know
either a sidecar or a process visibility
mechanism to get visibility into the
runtime of how your container
containerized application is behaving
when you use
if you're building an application
depending on the type of application
you're building you need
one or more of these types of tools in
order for you to get comprehensive
visibility and coverage into your
applications
the problem is too many tools
you've got time all together
you've got to manage them set up set
them up etc
and you also have to deal with the alert
volume in many cases
therefore in some cases some people add
uh additional yet another tool to take
all of these alerts and then dedupe them
fine-tune them reduce the alert volume
etc so that becomes another tool as well
in order to solve this problem
in the modern world in the cloud native
world
we can actually leverage observability
if you observe the application while it
is running
using any of the mechanisms like a
sidecar
or
an agent like i said or like a
process-based inspection
then
you get to see
all the behaviors that that application
is exhibiting while while it is running
you could track file behavior network
behavior process behavior memory
behavior so on and so forth and take all
of that telemetry
analyze that telemetry for anomalies put
that in time series database do anomaly
detection could be pattern based could
be ml based and then you come up with
runtime insights that actually can help
you identify runtime security risks that
lie in your application so using
observability
can essentially serve you know supersede
uh you know what i asked in in the past
kind of offered for your cloud native
applications it's much easier to drop in
because it's language agnostic unlike
the first generation of you know is type
tools
it allows you to watch your cloud native
application
while it's running without actually
changing any code or any any of the
container images just by dropping it
into your scheduler or in if you have
kubernetes you can drop it into your
code cluster and then you can start
watching your applications runtime
delivers runtime visibility great
but that's not just the use case that
that is only one of the possibilities
what observability can do for you
if if you use observability
in the context of your desk it can
actually help you enrich your
dashed scanner
by making it simpler faster and more
comprehensive i'm going to talk about
that in in a slight in
you know a double click on that in the
next couple of slides
the third thing that observability can
do for you if you do it right is to help
you prioritize the alerts that your
software composition analysis or
container element scanning tool is
producing and therefore reduce the
volume of insights that you're seeing
helping your developers make the most of
uh you know make your software
composition find value in your software
composition analysis tool
so
the recommendation here is no matter
which set of tools you use and no matter
whether you use it from multiple
different vendors one different vendor
think about using observability to
deliver runtime value to improve your
das scan behaviors and simplicity and
comprehensiveness and also improve your
software composition analysis and other
tools to prioritize and reduce the alert
volume
now let's double click
into
the middle part of here of this slide
which is let's focus on how
observability
can enrich
dust how does an observability is one of
those marriages where one plus one is
greater than two
let's take an example of a cloud native
application let's in this case i'm
talking about a kubernetes application
so you have an app you know four
services and those four services are
running in a kubernetes cluster
right
now you need to run a zap scanner
so you go you set up a zap server
and then you start um
configuring it
so that it points to your cloud native
application you ask your developer what
your endpoints it an endpoint is for the
app and then you start
scanning that endpoint
but oh wait
cloud native applications
are you know these containers are
fleeting they could come up and
up and down
and they're ephemeral that means the ip
address of these containers might change
so you decide to put a load balancer in
front of it but you can't do that
because you don't have access or your
permissions to some of the network stuff
so you bring in your network admin or
your your it admin to set it up for you
and therefore you create all of them
it's a cumbersome process today
so just to set up
to get started with a dashcam or
whatsapp or any any dashcam you need to
have all of the networking equipment etc
or or infrastructure configured
either by you or
in most cases the
network admin or it admin
to help you
so that so there's a a pretty
good amount of setup overhead involved
and it therefore becomes a project
let's say you've gone and you've set it
up
step one accomplished
then you go kick off your zap scan and
your zap scan is running
your application is being scanned and
zap when i say zap i'm referring to both
the web scan as well as the api scanners
app
so your application is being scanned
for web scan you use you know zap uses a
crawler for api scan it asks you to pass
in a swagger document so you give a
swagger document it scans the apis but
guess what your developers are not
generally keeping your swagger document
up to
maybe there are a set of apis that your
application is or uris that your
application is listening on
that are not documented as part of your
swagger
or maybe
those apis shouldn't even exist in the
first place they should have been
neutered or not unexposed but they
probably are still lying there exposed
so what do you do about them so it's
essentially the point is the challenge
here is
there is a coverage gap
with respect to the actual number of
apis and web services that are exposed
by your application and what is actually
being scanned because
especially for api scanning it purely
relies on
a well-documented swagger document or
equivalent
the third
challenge here
for running
zap with a cloud native application or
any dash scanner with a cloud-native
application
is typically the scans are not
intelligent enough to understand what
changed inside your application
therefore
every time the scan is run
you say scan this application it scans
the entire thing again and again takes a
lot of time
and scans many times are slow
so what is the fundamental problem here
the problem is
there is no feedback loop that is
telling the zap server to only scan
the changed web services in your
application because there's nothing
inside the application that is telling
the zap scanner
that these are the deltas that happened
between release one and release two
so these are the fundamental challenges
with running a das scanner setting it up
coverage gaps lack of apis that are
documented or always relying only on the
documented apis
and slow scans these are the challenges
when it comes to running a das scan with
a cloud native application
now let's see how observability
can help zap
or any dust get better
let's take
and observability let's say it's the
same application
but in this case
the application is being observed so you
pick whatever observability tool you
want to use whether it's a sysdig or
whether it's a d factor or whether it's
a
aqua
and you drop it into your coop cluster
what happens then is
your containers
are being watched or observed because
there's an agent that is agent or or
library or whatever approach you take
that is listening to these containers
and observing the changes in these
containers the ip changes which web
services are they listening on what
ports are they listening on all of that
is being observed by this watcher
let's call it a sensor
that is observing your containers
this sensor
if you pick the right tool
can actually have a feedback loop back
into your zap server or your das
platform
this is this is an area where uh you
know we actually ended up filing a
patent uh last year and it's super cool
in fact what we did was to solve this
problem number one which is enabling the
zap server to see
your application container and scan it
even though the ips of this application
keeps changing all the time we baked in
a little proxy
into the into this orange dot that proxy
allowed you allowed us
to tell the zap server
what our ipe is that it needs to start
scanning
so as soon as this container comes up
that proxy is there and the proxy tells
zap server that you can scan me i'm here
this is my ip
so now you don't need to go set up a
load balancer etc all you have to do is
drop little this little thing into your
cool cluster
and then you go to your zap
configure the integration
and
say scan
that eliminates the need to involve a
network administrator so now you know
you don't need that network
administrator to come and set up load
balancers all of that routing and that
routing doesn't need to be updated all
the time because anytime this new
container comes up your zap server knows
exactly where it lies what its ip is and
how to how to scan it
you can even use it actually to scan
internal services
not just the ones that are exposed
outside of your uh your network or the
externally exposed endpoints that are
typically scanned you can even scan the
internal endpoints and get some
interesting insights there too
number two is
you get a observability can enable you
to get a lot more comprehensive coverage
with respect to scans because it is
watching your application
for new web services created new apis
that it's that it's listening on etc and
therefore even if you have certain
undocumented uris or apis in your
application
the observability you know uh
sensor in your application now knows
that these are the new apis and then it
can go tell the zap scanner to go scan
those things
so it doesn't have to so you don't have
to have a properly documented swagger
interface you can actually
your zap scan now give you now can give
you a more comprehensive list of
coverage of your uris because
the sensor that is observing your
application from the inside actually has
a feedback mechanism into the zap scan
server
the third one is reducing of scan times
because now your application the
observability sensor in your application
is actually watching
the changes that have happened in your
application between release one and
release two so for example if your
application
opened a new web service or started
listening on a new web service
between release one and release two
then
you only need to scan that maybe you
don't need to scan all of the endpoints
all the time and that will help you
only scan the deltas
and by if the sensor tells zap scanner
to scan only the deltas then the scan
time will be drastically reduced as well
so these are three examples of how
observability if working together with a
with a das scanner can actually improve
the task scanner at the same time
providing value like one plus one
greater than two precisely
so let's circle back
back to you know hey i'm building a
cloud native application or my team's
building a cloud native application how
do i go about thinking
uh planning for my appsx strategy i'm
sure many of you guys are experts here
for those of you that are looking for
some guidance in this area then the the
guidance here is first think about your
business driver is your business driver
digital transformation or app
modernization or do you simply want to
take your legacy application but put
security into your cicd pipeline
are or are you more governance driven or
or compliance driven you know is it is
it the new biden
uh s-bomb uh
you know executive direction um that is
that is making you take this stance or
do you need to comply with something
once you understand your business driver
you need you also need to understand the
persona that is going to be using the
tool like is it is it your qa team your
ops team or do you want to have
visibility into the devs or maybe it's a
combination of the above where your
devops team with guidance from appsec
sets up your ci pipeline and base
security tools into it and your dev
teams up is the one that's consuming the
insight whichever it is i think you need
to properly understand that and have
some kind of a process so that you can
you can make sure that that's uh that's
a viable process triaging timelines
who's going to triage it at the end of
the day there's going to be some work
involved it's not it's never going to be
zero so you have to make sure that
that's you know that's that's planned
for it
the third one which is an important part
in this puzzle is what are your
technology requirements are you dealing
with a mobile or desktop application in
which case you need to pick a different
set of tools are you dealing with a
predominantly vm based deployment with a
legacy like net or you know type
workloads in which case you need to pick
a different type of tool or are you
dealing with uh some of the more modern
cloud native applications in which case
you need to pick a different set of
tools so understand that because one
tool does not fit all and
many times it's not it's it's not in
this abstract world it's not one tool
it's usually a combination of many tools
so pick the set of tools that make sense
for your application set
and lastly your budget timeline etc etc
with that
i wanted to conclude this presentation i
promised 35 to 40 minutes so here i am
37 minutes in
um
that's
my slideshow if you'd like to contact me
my email is here
uh you can always go to deepfactor.io or
you can go to you can email me at kiran
at or you can hit me up on linkedin
happy to take any questions