[Music]
thank you
appreciate that introduction and and
thank you for having me here today
um today my talk is about why
checking your infrastructure as code for
missed configurations is not enough
and
what we need to do to really secure
cloud native applications and
i know a lot of the audience may not be
as familiar with some of the
concepts or technologies that we'll be
talking about so i'll give a quick
primer and then we'll dive into it
so
a little bit about myself
you know i was counting yesterday as i
was preparing this slide as to how many
years i've been in the industry and
definitely makes me feel old
uh i've been in information security for
18 years uh long enough for
you know the term cyber security makes
me cringe
started off
doing security research focused on
critical infrastructure security
then moved on to academia's
work on trusted computing and
tamper-resistant systems and then from
there
joined the corporate world worked with a
lot of large organizations especially in
the healthcare space to help them build
security architecture practices to
really
look at security architecture
and how it fits into modern development
life cycles and then today
i
am
uh working on my own startup um i'm
co-founder and cto of oak 9 where we're
building automation
capabilities to secure cloud native
applications
so today's talk
is
about
some of the trends that we're seeing
with cloud native applications and what
we
as security practitioners as developers
as devops engineers need to do to really
address
security for cloud-native applications
and where we're falling short today
and you know what i'll do is i'll just
start off with a very quick primer
on infrastructure as code just so we're
all on the same page
so if i look back to my career and i
just look back 10 years ago as to how
software and infrastructure was
delivered
uh there were two different teams that
had to work together to deliver that
um software you had your software
development teams and your
infrastructure teams
what has fundamentally changed today is
now infrastructure
is designed and delivered as code
and more and more this infrastructures
code is falling under the umbrella of
software development
and we are affording it all of the best
practices that we've learned from a
software development standpoint
and
this is allowing development teams as a
whole
to accelerate at incredible velocity
so if we look at some of the surveys and
the results from those surveys you know
developers are seeing
over 100x
increase in velocity um businesses
see more agility as well as velocity and
fundamentally what infrastructure is
code allows you to do is it automates
and simplifies your infrastructure
provisioning so if you're not familiar
with infrastructure's code
it is a declarative way for you to
define your
infrastructure and the overall
architecture that that infrastructure
represents
and
it
provides organizations with a lot of
benefits um
besides you know kind of simplifying and
automating your infrastructure
provisioning it's repeatable scalable
uh version controlled modular there's
there's a lot of benefits in just
maintaining
uh complex architectures this way
one of the reasons why most
organizations shift infrastructures code
is because you know a lot of companies
over the last
you know 15 years
as they started moving towards
the cloud and really shifting uh their
workloads in the cloud initially you
know most organizations go through a
lift and shift
approach where they're really moving
from on-premise data centers and moving
vms into the cloud
and when you take that approach
initially right you don't necessarily
see all the benefits of
cloud capabilities because you're not
seeing that velocity and agility quite
yet
and so what organizations do is they
start breaking up their monoliths into
microservice based architectures
and really leveraging the native
capabilities that the cloud service
providers offer
and that's where these organizations
really start seeing
um
that
those benefits around velocity and
agility
but when you move towards these cloud
native architectures
what fundamentally happens is your
applications become more complex they're
harder to manage
and from an infrastructure standpoint
right if you were doing click ops
to deploy all of these different cloud
native capabilities it becomes unwieldy
you would need a incredibly large
infrastructure team to support that and
so this
dress code really helps automate and
simplify that provisioning
and helps you move faster and deploy
infrastructure in a version controlled
way
and if we look at what cloud native
application architectures look like
today
they're incredibly complex
you know the the other the advantage of
using infrastructure as code is it lets
you manage that complexity but at the
same time now you can build even more
complex architectures and this is an
example that i pulled from a blog post
this is a
architecture of a social media platform
and
the details of it are not as relevant as
you know anyone looking at this
particular architecture can see
that there's a lot of complexity there's
a lot of different components they're
all interacting with each other
and if you are a security architect
assigned to assess this application
architecture it is a daunting task
to understand
all of the different information flows
that are possible here
you know threat modeling this
application architecture would be um
would be quite
quite the endeavor and that's
that's fundamentally the challenge that
security organizations are facing today
and now
this entire cloud native architecture
today is actually represented in
infrastructure as code
and if i were to just take a rough
estimate of what this application
architecture would look like based on
kind of what i see with my customers
today this would easily be between 10
000 to 50 000 lines of infrastructure as
code and what's missing in in this
application architecture is a number of
different views of this application
architecture so we're missing um
you know configurations around the
network we're missing configurations
around identity and access management
user provisioning
and so
when it's all put together this would be
an incredibly complex infrastructure as
code deployment
and this is fundamentally creating
challenges for security teams to really
scale to support this trend
how do security teams
right get engaged and provide security
guidance to that application
architecture and impact its security
posture
you know most of what i see with my
customers and this is prevalent across
the industry is you know the the
the most predominant approach
to allowing security teams to scale
today is really
misconfiguration checking
so i'll define what i mean by
misconfiguration checking there's a lot
of different open source and commercial
you know tools that
help you do this
but essentially what misconfiguration
checking does is it queries for specific
known configurations of that
infrastructure
uh if it's looking at infrastructure as
code it's doing keyword based searches
to find that configuration
and then check to see that is set to the
right value so as an example
you can search for http protocol in your
infrastructure as code and make sure
that you know that key is set to the
value https
um
and what
what a lot of these approaches then do
is they create hundreds and thousands of
these rule sets for each configuration
they want to check for each type of
cloud
resource and so you have this kind of
static database of rule sets that you
can then check these application
architectures against
and
you know this is an incredibly important
endeavor
because as you guys are well aware
uh we continuously see new cloud
breaches and
you know
uh
almost every other day you hear about an
s3 bucket that was inadvertently
externally exposed
and you know it's it's a handful of
simple flags that control whether that
s3 bucket is internally exposed or
externally exposed
and these types of misconfiguration
checking approaches can find you know
find these really you know
basic hygiene mistakes that developers
often make in in a rush to deploy
something
and they can catch you know a lot of
critical issues before they get
deployed uh and
if you're not
using tls for your communication
security
and you're allowing http traffic
directly that more more more likely
means that you're not meeting your
compliance requirements around the
data that's being communicated from one
endpoint to another and so you know
these approaches then are also really
effective and then telling you
in the you know whenever they identify a
issue that
more than likely
creates a
challenge in meetings
some basic compliance requirements
so i want to talk a little bit about why
misconfiguration checking
is not enough and why
we really need to take
a more security engineering
approach to the broader problem that
we're seeing and i'll talk about some of
the trends in the space
so
as we look at modern application
architectures today in the cloud what we
are seeing is that the complexity and
the size of these application
architectures is growing you know if you
measure this application architecture
based on you know an entropy measurement
the overall entropy of these cloud
architectures are growing there's more
and more connectedness
across the different components of these
application architectures
and
this exacerbates
an already
existing challenge
for security teams most security teams
that i've worked with
you know we were constantly firefighting
we were going from one security issue to
the next and and you never really had
the time to strategically think about
the need for security
there are
you know i think estimates suggest
anywhere from like 1.5 to 2 million
unfilled jobs in security today
and most organizations are struggling
and as
development teams
are really shifting towards these
cloud-native architectures and building
more complex architectures it is really
exacerbating that problem for security
teams
the other challenge that you see is that
the cloud native capabilities are
rapidly evolving so all of the security
professionals
uh in the audience today
you know it's an incredibly hard
challenge to then keep up what the
different cloud service provider
capabilities
and how
how they're evolving what security
capabilities they have what are the best
you know design patterns to follow to
really
approach security for a particular use
case
in the cloud
and
you know the other challenge that we're
seeing is that more and more development
teams are being empowered to take
ownership of the entire release
management life cycle all the way you
know
from design coding to deployment and
then the feedback loop back and as well
as observability and so
development teams are really taking
ownership of that entire life cycle
and with that ownership they're getting
the freedom to pick the cloud service
providers they want to use the cloud
capabilities they want to use
and so the onus on the security team
then
is to really become familiar with all of
the different technologies that they may
be using in their application
architectures and as
cloud-native capabilities continue to
evolve that's
a just a continuous learning challenge
that all of us face as security
architects and security engineers
and i'll give you a data point
last year in uh 2021 i believe there
were four days where aws didn't make
changes to their api which fundamentally
means like their capabilities and their
offerings are continuously changing and
evolving and
it
creates
this
challenge for security engineers to now
stay abreast of all these changes
and finally you know i talked about how
all of these application architectures
are now represented as code
and what that does is it allows
development teams to actually deliver
infrastructure in an agile way
so from release to release from sprint
to sprint from deployment to deployment
these developers are now able to deliver
infrastructure capabilities
iteratively
as customers come to them and say hey
i have a new requirement
and uh i would like you know i would
like you to perform analytics on this
data that you are storing for me in this
application
unlike 10 years ago where the
development teams that i worked with
right would probably need you know a
two-month runway to deliver on a
capability like that today you know
experienced development teams can turn
turn around a proof of value within a
day
and and that type of speed and the rate
of change that they're able to make to
these application architectures creates
an incredible challenge for security
teams
and there's a lot of reasons why these
application architectures continue to
evolve
so so one example that i just gave is
you know business requirements are
changing
another example
is where the technology requirements are
changing and they want to use new
technologies integrate new technologies
into the application architecture
which may fundamentally
you know impact the security posture of
the application
another example is you know security is
driving the evolution because um
security requirements are changing um
there may be new compliance and
regulatory needs from a security
standpoint that this application needs
to meet
it may be that um
you know the threat landscape has
changed and the types of architectures
that security would like to adopt
are evolving
and
and so there's just a whole host of
reasons why these applications are
evolving but as they continue to evolve
right it creates a challenge for
under-resourced security teams to keep
up and assess the changes that are
happening to these application
architectures
and and you know one other point before
i before i kind of
um
keep going is
that these
when changes are made to the application
architecture these are foundational
changes that
if they lead to security issues there
are inherent risks in that application
potentially and
not checking for these inherent risks
and not addressing these inherent risks
before deployment could lead to you know
severe consequences for your business
and for your application
so i want to take a quick detour and
talk about complex systems and emergent
properties and we'll talk about ants for
a quick second
so you know if you were to take an ant
and put it on a flat surface
uh let her walk around you know its
actions would be erratic its actions
would be random eventually it would tie
itself out and without food it would
likely die
if you took 100 ants you would probably
see a very similar outcome but now if
you had you know hundreds of thousands
of ants or millions of ants
you would see something different you
know together these ants create a system
and
they're able to solve incredible
challenges
this is an example of ants creating a
bridge
but you know even things like ants
moving information um
you know ants figuring out
where
food is potentially in their environment
they're incredibly intelligent systems
that get created but individually these
ants are not remarkable it's together
and collectively where you see the
emergent properties of intelligence that
i'm referring to
and
you know security in a similar way is an
emergent property of a complex system
this is from nist 800 uh 160 it's the
system security engineering
special publication and
they're one of the first kind of
industry bodies
to really highlight this fact and and
talk about it and it's a great read if
you're a security engineer you know i
highly recommend it but i'll just read
one excerpt from um from this
publication so security like safety and
other system quality properties is an
emergent property of the system
system security is the application of
engineering and management principles
concepts criteria and techniques to
optimize security within the constraints
of operational effectiveness time cost
throughout all stages of the system life
cycle
and
as we look at
the the complexity and security being an
emergent property emerging from that
complexity
it's
really important that we as security
engineers you know have a grasp of that
and we understand kind of how to deal
with this as
the challenges that we face continue to
get more and more complex
and i'll take a
uh i'll continue on this quick detour
and just um you know talk about
different types of emergence and how
security kind of falls into that so
you know they're
the the study of emergence as a topic is
something that is still ongoing um this
is from
a
some academic research at indiana
university and i just want to kind of
break down how they
uh talk about different types of
emergence and where security really
falls in this so if we if we think about
kind of the simplest form of emergence
which is what they call type one
purposeful interaction
this is really characterized by simple
intentional designed interactions
between components of the system
and
you know most of the security problems
that we face today really fall into that
type one bucket so you know you have two
components that are interacting
uh if you need to
think about the potential attacks
associated with those components if you
need to think about the
the defensive measures that you might
take you know it really falls into that
type one category um
but as you move
to you know kind of
higher levels of emergence where type 2
really starts talking about
you know different entities in the
system really independently interacting
with other entities and receiving
feedback and creating more complexity
now we start seeing
more complexity
and as
we are moving towards cloud-native
architectures and we are moving towards
um you know interdependent interactive
systems
more and more right we are seeing
security
use cases that fall into that type 2
category
uh and as an example like the ants
example that i was giving where ants
fall into lying use pheromones to decide
how
um you know where to go and and how to
line up in a formation
that is an example of
of type two emergence
and then finally type three is an
example where you know you have multiple
types of feedback that's happening on
different time scales
and
um
when we look at threat modeling and we
look at you know modeling our
adversaries and really adding that human
element into
the overall assessment of security
that's that's where you know security
challenges start moving towards that
type three model
another example that i can give you here
is you know financial markets where
you know feedback loops positive
feedback loops create situations where
there's a herd mentality and a
particular asset class keeps going up in
price but eventually negative feedback
loops over time scales
you know have a higher impact than the
positive feedback loops and the bubble
bursts and prices fall
and
examples you know similar
in terms of you know security or really
you know the cat and mouse game that we
play between defenders and adversaries
is is is a
example of this multi-source feedback
where over time scales things are
changing and
you know the example that i was giving
about cloud native architectures and how
cloud-native architectures are really
evolving from release to release sprint
to sprint and more and more interactions
and connectedness happens within these
architectures we're starting to move
towards these type three problems and
that's going to create a lot of
challenges for us as security engineers
and then
finally type 4 which isn't something
that's relevant to today's conversation
but really things like consciousness
right are categorized under type four
so
with that in mind you know let's go back
and kind of revisit misconfiguration
checking and talk a little bit about why
you know just doing that right is is not
enough so
um
the complexity that we're seeing right
cannot really be addressed
through misconfiguration checking and i
want to give some examples right
of what i was talking about with
misconfiguration checking so
so this is uh it's an example terraform
module for an aws
application load balancer
and
i'll give you some examples of how
misconfiguration checking can really
help identify some critical issues that
might exist in this load balancer so
you can go into the listener
configurations and you can make sure
that https is enabled
you can make sure that this load
balancer is only internally accessible
versus externally accessible
you can look at the cipher suites that
are protect
are potentially being used by this load
balancer and make sure that it's
actually using the latest and greatest
cypher suite so
this is not a package of ciphers that
you want to use for tls today
if
as if you're not dealing with
legacy
operating systems and legacy browsers
they're there's a much more modern
package of forward secure ciphers that
aws supports today
and so
all of these things right can be
identified through misconfiguration
checking you know making sure that
you're using the right ports if that's
uh if that's something your organization
has rules around
uh making sure that talking to the
target groups you're actually using
https instead of http
and uh making sure that uh logging is
enabled
so all of these are just examples of
things that we can identify
through uh misconfiguration checking
and
as i mentioned earlier right the
approaches
and and the tools that that kind of
perform this analyses what they're
really doing is they're doing keyword
searches
on
this code finding the right
configurations and then making sure that
they're set to a specific static value
and now you know if you take this across
many many different types of cloud
resources across different cloud service
providers you can build a database of
thousands and thousands of these rules
and then you can start checking for
these things right so this is an example
of
a
database
and i'm going to
or an s3 bucket let's take that right
where you can decide whether
logging
and versioning is enabled you can decide
whether uh what algorithm is being used
and whether you know a
key management services being used or if
we're allowing dynamodb to manage its
keys on its own
uh then it would use a database within
natively us if you're not familiar and
so these are just all examples of kind
of individual configurations that we can
check for and we can look at whether or
not those configurations are set
appropriately and
this is as i mentioned earlier right
this is a
really
valuable
uh thing to identify it's really
important that we identify these types
of gaps but
it is not addressing
the emergent nature of security and is
not addressing the complexity of these
modern cloud native applications
it is
just scratching the surface of what
needs to be done from a security
engineering standpoint
and
what happens with these types of
approaches
you know another downside is really you
know you create thousands and thousands
of these rules but now you're gonna have
to create exceptions
so you know your particular application
use case has a different use case
is a unique use case and it needs an
exception to
you know
five of the thousand rules that it's
being assessed against and
[Music]
you know you'll create these exceptions
and now it becomes you know an
engineer's full-time job to manage and
maintain these exceptions
the other challenge you have is you know
we talked about how
when these
types of approaches
find true positives
we can almost automatically know that
they're not meeting some industry best
practice not meeting some
uh
compliance needs so as an example you
know if you were dealing with
healthcare data and
you did not set http protocol to https
it's pretty obvious that you're going to
have some issues with
meeting hipaa regulations uh being
compliant with high trust
but what they're not what these
approaches cannot tell you is
you know what are you doing to actually
be compliant and and if we look at the
broader needs of compliance right um so
instead of looking at it from
the perspective of here here are cases
where you're failing compliance what are
the cases we're actually needing
compliance and where
where does the gap exist
um that is not something these
approaches can do because fundamentally
right they they look at
individual configurations and report on
individual configurations
and and because of that right they have
no context of what your application is
if this was your company's cafeteria
menu and the daily menu is posted in
this application
uh these approaches assess that menu
application in the same way as they
would your most business critical
application
and so that's
kind of another reason right why you'll
end up having a lot of potential
exceptions that you create and then
managing those exceptions
so let's talk about how we're gonna how
we need to secure cloud native
applications and how we're going to deal
with this complexity that
is looming for all of us security
engineers
so when we look at the literature and we
look at you know kind of how
[Music]
the systems the complex systems
folks have addressed these problems you
know we can learn a lot from those
approaches and you know there's a lot of
organizations like i talked about you
know nist has has
uh
very correctly identified this saps out
many years ago right started talking
about this if you're not familiar with
zaps other
security architecture
um
organization that has you know
methodologies around um security
architecture but really you know what
they've all found right is we need to
really take approaches that are holistic
as opposed to just looking at individual
components of the system we need to look
at the broader system we need to
understand the interactions
we need to look at you know and this is
what we do when we do threat modeling
right is really understanding the the
system as a whole what are all of the
connections what are all the data flows
what are all the different components
and how are they interacting and really
taking that holistic systems engineering
approach as opposed to looking at
individual components and individual
misconfigurations
you know part of the challenge with the
types of complexity that we're seeing in
these cloud native applications
is
you know and and when we look at
security as an emergent property really
the best approach to to constrain that
is to not let these application
architectures get too complex and and
provide you know constrain these
application architectures in a
meaningful way and one of the best ways
you can do that is as you decompose your
application from a top-down perspective
you need to set the right business
objectives the right requirements around
security so that you can actually start
constraining the the security
engineering challenge from the very
beginning
uh reduce the complexity and
and enhance the simplicity of the design
you know we don't necessarily it is not
a good thing to to have
the level of complexity that leads to
these emergent properties and so we want
you know simpler architecture simpler
designs
um you know very simple design patterns
and then you know doing threat modeling
to actually holistically look at the
system
looking at strategies
that
assume certain threats and attacks will
be successful and how do we minimize the
impact architecturally so as an example
isolation and
segregation is a great approach
to
to look at you know separating the
impact of one component on the other
so that you know if
your cafeteria menu is
compromised
that compromise should not allow someone
to then have
a business impact to your business by
laterally moving in your environment
right so how can we build architectures
that really limit what the attacker can
do if a given application a given
service is compromised
and then as we look at that systems
engineering approach one of the most
critical things that you have to do is
look at people and process as an
integral part of that system because you
know the human element is really what
creates
a lot of the complexity in these
in these scenarios in these systems
and
os
you know
is has has identified this the same
trend as well and
you know for the first time in 2021
a new category was added
for
uh insecure design
and it focuses on the risk failure to
design flaws um and you know the
guidance that os has provided is exactly
spot on right we need to do more threat
modeling as
uh security professionals we need to
build security design practices
build our catalog of security design
patterns that we want the organizations
to follow you know define our security
design principles
and build reference architectures that
developers and our peers can use to
build secure systems
and and that is really the only approach
to addressing this complexity
and so this is an example of the types
of guiding principles that we should be
establishing
as we
look at that
systems engineering approach to security
making sure that we are considering
security early that we're building
security in that we're designing
security in
uh human factored security really
considers the end user it considers the
developer it makes sure that we are
actually solving the problems of those
end users and not creating barriers for
those users and implementers to adopt
security how can we make developers
build faster how can we allow those
developers
to to maintain that freedom in picking
the cloud service provider that they
want the cloud capabilities that they
want building
you know the the complex architectures
that they need to build to solve
customer use cases but doing so in a way
that's secure
and you know
things that um
we as security professionals are are
quite well familiar with you know making
sure that there's least privilege
there's separation of privilege
the one big change that happens in cloud
native applications is you know if
you're familiar with least common
mechanism
um
as a as a way to really minimize
shared security
controls
the cloud really changes
this paradigm and so
the goal here is to really reduce this
shared security mechanism so that on
different applications different
services and as much as possible are not
sharing those same security mechanisms
they're not dependent on those same
security mechanisms building security
that's scalable thinking about
scalability from the very beginning
looking at minimizing the attack surface
defense in depth and then you know going
back to simplicity right buildings
you know as much as possible building
simple security architectures
and and having an open design so that
we're not doing security by obscurity in
any of these situations
but even after we do all of this right
the challenge of the sheer number
the sheer complexity and the entropy
that
these modern cloud native application
architectures have
um really requires security
organizations to embrace automation and
and as we
modernize our security practices
automation has to be a key pillar of
those modern security practices we need
to fit into the development workflows so
that we get visibility into every change
that happens but also
because you know going back to human
factored security
we can fit into those development
workflows and provide feedback to the
developer within their own workflows we
can seamlessly integrate into their
day-to-day life cycle
so that they are getting security
guidance in a timely manner they're
getting security guidance that's
actionable achievable
applicable to what they're doing
but even if we do that right we then
need to
manage for drift
so this application architecture today
is no longer static it is changing
constantly
how do we maintain and manage that drift
how do we measure that drift and so
building capabilities to do that and
doing so through automation because
there is no way a manual approach will
scale to the size and complexity of
these application architectures
and that leads me to you know
one of the one of the core
aspects of how security organizations
will be able to scale to this problem is
using security as code-based approaches
you know if development teams are
leveraging infrastructure as code
security really needs to embrace
as a code approaches to build security
architectures as code really thinking
about you know building dynamic
architectures
that
can seamlessly address the use cases
that developers have and and help
simplify security for developers so how
can security organizations really
embrace as a code approaches to build
patterns and and codify them so that
they're not paper documents we're not
delivering excel spreadsheets and
powerpoint presentations or word
documents we are looking at using
automation to fit into that development
workflow leveraging security as code
to assess that application architecture
and provide feedback
to those developers
and and there's a lot of powerful
benefits of doing so right those
those security architectures that you
build as code are now version controlled
they're maintainable they're they can be
modular
they can be flexible
and they can dynamically apply security
as this application architecture is
changing so that if the developer starts
with the proof of value
and at that point you know their
business use case isn't dealing with
sensitive data it's not externally
exposed it's an internal proof of value
the security architecture that we apply
to that particular application should be
different than the one that we apply to
the beta version of that same product
that evolves
and now
you know has more stringent requirements
around security
and and having that uh you know being
able to apply security dynamically is
going to be critical
to to really address the complexity of
these
architectures
the other big piece of this is
visualization you know
it's really hard to secure what you
don't understand and if you cannot
visualize
what this application architecture is
what are all the different
endpoints that
components in this architecture are
connected to what are all the different
information flows you can't possibly
you know
effectively threat model this
application
to understand
where potential
uh
issues may lie
and
the challenge with visualization in this
space is that these application
architectures are getting incredibly
complex
so you know i have customers today that
deal with application architectures that
have over
you know 10 000 resources in a given
application architecture and it's all
you know when you look at
application architectures of that size
meaningful visualization is really
critical so that you can get the right
slice of the information that you're
looking for to
assess that application architecture and
and if we don't solve the visualization
problem we won't be able to really
understand what these application
architectures are doing and
effectively assess them
and finally you know one of the most
important probably the most important
thing right if i can leave you with one
thing is
none of this matters right
if we cannot drive the cultural change
that's necessary
for security teams to work effectively
with the business with development teams
with ops teams
and there has to be a top-down focus on
the people and process associated with
how we support cloud native application
architectures we really need to consider
the development teams and the ops teams
and the challenges that they have as
security professionals and really have
empathy for the types of pressures that
they're facing and similarly you know
development teams need to
have that empathy for the security
professionals that are underwater
struggling to
you know really keep up with challenges
across the application portfolio that
they may be supporting
and you know how do we get to
a future where
all of these teams can work autonomously
can collaborate effectively and share
responsibility around security
and and effectively drive the business
to the same goals so that we can we can
deliver faster
we can deliver more agile
applications and as a business
businesses can take advantage
of new market opportunities
fleeting opportunities that require
the organization to quickly react and
and how can security be a part of that
and really drive that change
so i'll
i'll
stop with some very simple examples
right of
of kind of how this manifests and um
and where
you know where we kind of see these
these complex relationships
interdependencies and and you know
emergent properties
so let's take you know to simplify
uh the example right what i'm using kind
of a graph visualization here but let's
say you have
an application load balancer uh if it's
a
elb in aws
then that load balancer you can
configure it to send its logs
to object storage you can configure what
logs you want to collect
and then from that object storage bucket
your seam solution can pick those
[Music]
pick those logs up
and you might have a serverless
architecture that is event based where
once logs are
submitted to object storage it triggers
a serverless function that then notifies
the scene to go pull those logs
and when you look at
you know just logging as an example and
you know going back to what i was
sharing earlier
[Music]
if i go back to this example
you know misconfiguration checking
will tell me that logs access logs are
enabled
right there right
so it's telling me that logging is
enabled but that is the extent of what i
know
based on static misconfiguration
checking
now if i
go back to this particular use case and
just that one requirement around logging
and really understanding how we can meet
our business objectives around audit and
accountability
we need to understand okay logging is
enabled where are logs being sent
what permissions does this load balancer
have
to talk to that s3 bucket
uh what is the im role within aws that's
been assigned to that load balancer is
it minimum necessary
does this object storage bucket right is
this a shared bucket or is this
purposely being purposefully being used
for storing logs is it limited to this
load balancer
and
how does this object storage bucket
ensure confidentiality and integrity of
those logs is it configured for
versioning is it configured for
[Music]
data at rest encryption if that's a
requirement that you have
from say a compliance framework that's
telling you that log should be encrypted
at rest
what else is talking to the storage
bucket what other i am roles have
permissions to this storage bucket
um how do logs from this storage bucket
end up in the scene what does the
architecture look like how is if you're
using um
splunk for example right and you have
a solution that's going and picking up
these logs or interacting with these
logs
how does how does that interaction work
what
what are the
the permissions being set there and what
types of access does that scene have
how does it how is the serverless
functions
defined and you know there was a great
talk yesterday about serverless security
and are we following all those best
practices for that serverless function
so just just to
understand whether a single requirement
is being met appropriately
there's
a lot of nuance in what we need to
assess
and if we had to do this at the scale of
these complex architectures right
without automation this is a incredibly
hard problem to solve
i'll give one other example before i
pause
let's say you wanted to
have a requirement that all interactions
with your databases
um
are inspected through
for sec for security purposes and they
go through some managed inspection point
where
you were able to configure rules um on
what you're checking for so you can
check for things like sql injection or
you can check for
uh
you know exfiltration of data based on
behavioral patterns
um and in this use case right
in a complex cloud native architecture
right you would need to understand
um
[Music]
okay what are the different
microservices or applications that are
that have access to this database
is there some sort of a gateway here
that is actually providing me the
capabilities that i need uh do i have an
enterprise standard
for
what types of gateways should be used
what types of capabilities should exist
how are they interacting
with the network that these database
tables are associated with how many
different database tables do i have you
know it's easy to spin up new tables in
the cloud and you might have
you know hundreds of these database
tables that you need to now uh protect
and are there other out-of-band channels
that essentially bypass that security
gateway because
they can you know there's a
security group configured that directly
allows access to that vpc now these are
pretty standard security engineering and
threat modeling
scenarios but
what
i'd love to point out here is that the
complexity of these very simple use
cases grows incredibly in these cloud
native application architectures because
there's just more and more connectedness
and so assessing these types of
architectures um
through a misconfiguration based
approach just isn't giving you the
complete picture and if you're an
organization that's really looking at
you know
misconfiguration based tooling that's
kind of in your pipeline to assess this
infrastructure as code that is important
that has to be a part of the solution
but it cannot be
the only solution if you are not
following good security engineering
practices if threat modeling is not part
of your workflow you are missing a big
part of the security puzzle and you are
not addressing the complexity and
inevitably you are deploying
applications that
potentially have inherent risks and are
posing inherent risks to your business
so with that i'll stop and i'd love to
take any questions