right now so again i'm jay garcia review
prefer uh just greg
and
at some point i had to protect some
assets using applocker so i decided to
dig a bit deeper scratch the surface to
under identify
if a blocker is
for fruit good enough for our things and
what i would like to cover today two
uplocker
internal mechanisms giving you somehow
unexpected
results
so let's go for the first one
when it comes to the blocker itself
a blocker consists of couple of
components of course we have some
management it is a kernel mechanism but
it stores its own database it is managed
from user mode there is a special
service translating
uh the database from the user mode to
the kernel mode the the app id svc which
must be running to have a blocker
running but the full thing within a
blocker protection is done by the driver
running within the kernel
applocker can work in
enforcement mode
meaning
non-listed apps non-white listed apps
are not allowed to be run and in the
audit mode meaning
any single application will run but
there will be a warning within the log
telling me it would be blocked if i play
seriously when it comes to rules a
blocker can use
first very big thing about a blocker
comparing for them example to wdac is it
can rely on user identity
but generally saying rules can be made
for a path so if the path matches the
application is allowed or not a rule can
be made based on a hash so the hash of
the file is being calculated and if the
hash much much as the application is
being allowed and on the digital
signature i will focus on harsh rules as
those are
the simplest one to show you today what
i want to show you
okay let's go to the imperfection number
one
because uh generally saying
i have my applocker up and running it is
working in the audit mode i can quickly
verify it here going to properties i can
see it is for executable only configured
within the audit
only mode
and i have kind of a typical
configuration meaning
if
something is within the program files it
is allowed to be run as regular user
cannot drop software there
and if something is within windows
folder is also allowed to be run if i
run anything let's do this with
char map my favorite
is even better better than calculator
charm up is up and running if i go to
the even block
f5 i can see
char map was allowed
to run which is quite obvious as it
stays within the windows folder
usually
for the simplicity
when a blocker is being deployed at
least at the initial stage we are not
deploying rules for dll files we are
focusing on executable files on exist
only
because it is simpler
when we go deeper into that blocker we
can realize one thing
if within the token of the process there
is a seat present s156
a blocker totally ignores such
executable file
so
i can steal such token or i can use a
trick allowing me to
have such token without
being blocked
i will
elevate
to
my process using this token using a dll
so it will be basically run dll32 as
this one is allowed as is in the windows
folder and i rarely can find
environments where it can can be
actually blocked
and then there is a dll
ignore pocket.tll there is a function do
it
and then c
windows system 32
and then cmd
and the cmd is being launched if i
try to investigate what is inside
who am i slash all
i can find
the seed i mentioned s156 here it is a
special seed for a service
so i have launched first process right
now i can say the second one the cmd
itself the who am i process i can launch
whatever notepad
uh it is allowed
on my desktop i have
yet another
special application right aaa special
application writing 100 a letters which
is perfectly well working if i refresh
the log
absolutely nothing about this is
appearing within the lock the last thing
that appeared was run dll which is
allowed absolutely everywhere
so if you are able
to launch a process
having s156 within the token it will be
just ignored by the applocker not
enforced not logged not
audited not blocked whatever
it will just totally ignore and is it is
for this single particular seat so
it is good to monitor somehow if you
have a process running with the seat
under normal conditions
it is only about services it is a legal
seat for services
but not for interactive applications so
you have to find your way to monitor
somehow
okay let's go to the
second a poker nice thing is about the
speed because i mentioned hashes
calculating a hash
is somehow i would say time consuming
why
not only because of the calculation
itself but about the need of reading
entire file from the disk
uh windows introduces prefetch etc all
for the
speed at the same time using a blocker
with
hashing every single executable file or
dll file
being launched would
slow down the computer significantly so
i will create a rule based on hash for
the
file i already have run so create new
role
next allo for everyone
file hash
next
browse files i will go to my file i have
it on the desktop
this is the one right aaa
open next create i have a rule for it
if i i will close this one as this one
is
ignored anyway i will go here
i will run this piece of code
right
100 letter a appears on the screen
f5
it was allowed to run
right now which is perfectly according
to our
expectations what i will do now i will
do a virtual uh
way of unplugging my hard disk
manipulating it on the another computer
and then tagging it back to my laptop so
how i will achieve this
i will go here
attach vhd
and then the name is
x
vhdx
and new x drive appears within my system
i will go here
i will copy
right iaa into the x drive
it was copied if i run it from the x
drive
obviously it will run and it will be
allowed
to be run x right ia
because the hash
clearly matches
i will manipulate this disk offline
right now by
detaching the vhd
yes
going to
hex editor
loading the vhd
finding
the pattern
it is here and i will replace the
pattern
within the executable file couple of my
a letters with a
x letter
close
reattach it
sorry it is c
temp
x v h the x
okay
it appeared again
and i will run
the same x right iaa
with the image being manipulated offline
and not the big surprise i have couple
of x letter
over here
do the hash of the executable file match
the previous one
not really
if i take a look into the log
over here
f5
here
hex editor was not allowed to be run not
a big surprise but the right aaa the
manipulated one was perfectly well
allowed to be run
it means
the hash of the file is being cached
somewhere
i will try to find it
okay let's go for the hashes first
cls and i will go
powershell
and
get
file hash
for right iaa the original one still
staying on my desktop
has a hash d35 and so on the manipulated
one
get file hash x
right ia has a totally different one
which is not the big
surprise
it is just a different executable file
let's take a look on the powershell rule
2 on the
applocker rules
right now
so
it would be
get
applocker policy
local
and then
to xml
and here i can find the
hash
being allowed
does it match any of those
it is strato56 obviously
it is
something
else not the first one not the second
one it is because uh the beauty of that
blocker it lies about the hashing
algorithm it is not schwa five six
it is so cold it is not officially
stated but it is so called
executable hash or authentic code hash
and so on the algorithm is documented
but no one is clearly saying a blocker
is using it so it is yet totally
different hash
by the way if you have hashes of your
files and you want to create a proper
rules based on your hashes you will fail
because applocker will not use real
strato56
there is undocumented xml parameter
called strat256 flat
being actually strato56 at the same time
i would not rely on this too much
as it is undocumented so
how to calculate this hash if you have a
file
get a block
up
locker file information
and then you can specify a file
and
the hash
you can see on the beginning i will not
format it nicely over here but you can
see it is exactly the harsh over here
not being schwa 256 at all despite what
microsoft is telling to telling us
okay
so this is the about hashing algorithm
now about the
how the hash is being stored where is
the hash
and uh how it was manipulated
the hash for applocker
is being
stored within so-called ntfs extended
attributes
you can think about ntfs extended
attributes somehow like you think about
alternate data stream is not the same
but it is somehow comparable to this
kind of
alternate data stream on steroids and so
on so if you want to display i will exit
my powershell
if you want to display
extended attributes i will launch one
console more it will be useful in a
moment
um
[Music]
desktop
fsu till
file
extended attrib
fsutil file and there is a query aaa
parameter for querying
extended attributes if you specify a
file let's say right aaa
you will see extended attributes
displayed over here you can see the
attribute
hash info
containing a
cache of the hash and if we if you
remember the hash
uh the one visible over here
six e3 and so on you can clearly find it
over here as as well this is the a
blocker hash of the file being stored
within the extended attribute so if you
manipulate the file offline the extended
attribute is not updated there is no
reason of doing it
and it means that
the extended attribute contains the old
hash which is perfectly well trusted by
the blocker driver
so
how we can manipulate
the hash slightly better way is not that
easy the idea of extended attribute is i
would say well documented
and there are two things over here
within the name of the extended
attribute the first thing within the
name is the dollar kernel
the attribute if the attribute name
starts with the dollar kernel it is
allowed to be manipulated only by the
kernel modules so you cannot create
manipulate change delete whatever such
attribute from the user mode
it is why it may be easier to manipulate
the drive offline or if you want to
plant your own driver into a kernel up
to you
another thing within the
extended attribute is the part part of
the name when you can see the part
within the name after dollar kernel
it is a signal for the ntfs ntfs.sys
driver telling
ntfs.driver
if the file content is being manipulated
anyway
the extended attribute must be removed
totally it is why i cannot change the
file
online
i have to go under ntfs driver
if i can do this online under the ntfs
driver it will be perfectly legit for my
purposes doing it on the vhd x drive is
just simpler and easier to
demonstrate so if i manipulate the file
the extended attribute will disappear
and if i run the file again the hash
will be calculated the new extended
attribute will be established and
applocker will start relying on this
extended attribute
i know manipulating the string within
the file it is not that complex but
sometimes it may be
sometimes maybe something more
sophisticated is needed for this purpose
i can plant
this particular
hash
within the extended attribute so i will
copy
my
hacking application to the x drive
and i will use
a setup locker a hash cache
file i have created
created
for the x
my hacking application and i will place
the hash over here i'm doing a simple
trick here as i said i cannot create a
dollar kernel extended attribute it is
not allowed for
mermortals at the same time i can create
a hush kernel and so on extended
attribute and this is what i did and i'm
displaying a nice
message now it is your job to rename it
somehow from the hash corner into the
dollar kernel
so
to do this
i will again
detach vhd
okay i will again run
a hex editor
reopen the same
file
and use ctrl r for replace and i will
replace replace hash
kernel
dot into the dollar kernel
dot
replace all
and
it was replaced you can see
it was this occurrence so it is probably
the right one it was the hash
something would be
dollar
something i will close it i will
reattach my
virtual
drive attach
c
temp
x vhdx
again
attach once i have
edited one file and attach another one
it is even worse than misspelling the
path c temp
x v hd x
it appeared i have my
hacking application x
p w n x
dot x z
it run
if you take a look into the log
it was perfectly well
allowed
to be run even if it's obviously it
or it should be obviously
being blocked by a blocker this warning
is about the hex editor which for reason
is being displayed here as it's not
covered by
any rule so it is not
effectively allowed so
what does it mean
we can manipulate the stuff
a blocker is
using some undocumented
internals
the first one i would mention is it is
ignoring s156
pre
processes when the token has
s156 on the list on the group being very
precise
the second thing is it relies on hashes
and the hash does not really match
schwa256 even if a blocker tries to tell
you so the second thing it relies on the
cache of the hashes
and on the cache of the
digital signature as well because for
the hashes it doesn't look like very
practical but we can use exactly the
same technique and it will work to
falsify
the digital signature
of for microsoft for example because if
the file is being digitally signed
here you can see
where is my
f7 uh
okay i will type the very complex
command again fsu till
file query
x
write aaa if the file is being digitally
signed i have digitally signed my
application
the digital signature will be stored
within the aid 3 stream and the extended
attribute will be called kernel purge
not very surprising app id for applocker
and then signer info you can manipulate
this particular piece of information as
well effectively meaning that
if you are using a blocker probably
whitelist some applications on the
digital signature very common practice
is to whitelist microsoft things
because microsoft tries to store stuff
within the user profile update and so on
so it is
safe
to whitelist anything from microsoft
effectively if you are able to
offline put such cash information about
microsoft signature
onto a file
on the offline media
if you plug the media in back and if you
run the executable file applocker will
believe it is perfectly
legit because it is digitally signed by
microsoft by the way yet another uh
beautiful thing within applocker we have
a powershell commandlet
about testing a blocker policy tesla
blocker police you have to specify xml
file and then executable file name and
you will see if this file will be
allowed to be run or not already the app
test applocker
policy
commandlet is using a real
calculated on-demand
hash of the file and not the stored one
so it is perfectly possible
to see i will not export xml policy and
so on but it is very easy my file with
the manipulated
hash
will run as a blocker will trust it if i
test it through powershell i will see
information it will be not allowed to be
run
because the test command relies on the
real content of the file and the
applocker itself relies on it on its
hash
they went too fast a bit i would say
when it comes to resources um there is a
short write-up somewhere there is a file
for copying extended attributes from one
file to another one something i i didn't
present but also working there is also
short demonstration on youtube i have
recorded if you are quick enough you can
type it in if you prefer go to the list
of those links you can go
by the code and that's basically it
thank you very much