[Music]
hello everyone my name is golan today
we're going to explore the topic of
digital signatures
specifically we'll talk about pe files
it's my first time here at zifcon i'm
very glad to be here glad to see you all
and let's begin
now
it's only fair that you also get to know
me so a little bit about myself
my name is golan cohen i work at
checkpoint which is based in tel aviv
israel
today i'm in charge of researching and
protecting infections that originate
from documents and email
but at the time of this research i was a
malware analyst
and as part of my job i monitored
suspicious files and our clients
telemetry
we also wrote protections and behavior
rules to detect those threats
also i recently became a father and here
you can see my daughter helped me
helping me out with this presentation
and on my free time i like to
explore electronics i like to take
things apart try to put them back
together
and that's it let's
begin
this is our agenda for the talk uh first
i'll explain how this research started
why we got into this
next we'll talk about the infection
chain this all started with a specific
campaign that we found so we'll go
through uh this
each of the steps that the threat actor
took
i'll uh explain what uh digital
signatures are and why they're important
specifically again for pe files
we'll talk about the file signature
vulnerability that was used in this case
which is very easy to uh
to exploit and i'll show you how to do
that
and at last we'll summarize and uh i'll
give my conclusions
so um how did this research start um
somewhere in september 2021 one of my
teammates sent me this article article
this article
was written by sentinel one labs
and it was about a particular uh malware
campaign
a z-loader campaign uh we'll get to what
z-loader is in a few slides it's a
basically a banking trojan
and just as a high overview of that uh
the previous campaign
it started with an installer um it's a
teamviewer.msi
next we see that we ran the thread
actors ran some batch scripts
we see they disabled windows defender
service and made some modifications to
it and at last
z loader payload was injected into msi
exec
using a specific malicious dll so just
remember this high overview because
we're going to see similar steps that
are taken in the the next campaign
um
this is also from this article this is
uh one of the scripts that the thread
actors ran on the machine uh this script
was in charge of making some changes to
windows defender adding some exclusions
to it i'm sorry for for the small font
but um you can see some pretty malicious
commands here like trying to exclude all
dot exit files from being scanned by
windows defender
another funny thing that i found
is like many of us we jump into writing
code without reading the documentation
first they try to also exclude exit and
dll files using a wildcard but
this argument does not accept a wildcard
so it's it's a funny thing that uh
that i found
so based on this script that we just saw
i wanted to search and try to look for
similar scripts that
are using the same
same type of attack
and i found
another script that was similar but had
some other commands so this first
detection that i found
we see also exclusion for msi exec if
you recall
what the threat actors did is they
injected the malicious payload into msi
exec
they disabled the scanning of downloaded
files and attachments by windows
defender they disable real-time
monitoring and many many other commands
we'll take a look at them in just a
second but from this first detection we
were able to map out the entire new
campaign of z-loader
so this is what this new campaign looked
like
we'll go through each of the steps
briefly
at first we see
there's a process called a terror agent
that ran on the machine
this attack agent ran a few batch
scripts
we see some downloaded downloading of
executable files and dlls
and at last we see also a malicious dll
that injects z-loader into msi example
so
um what is zotero a terra agent a simple
google search led us to atera's website
atera is a software company also based
in israel so close to home
and what they do is they do rmm software
which is for it professionals what is
rmm it's remote monitoring and
management software it allows them for
remote access and controlling of their
customers computers
and you can also try this software for
free you can sign up on the website and
get your free trial account by the way
we'll use this minimap on the top right
to keep track of where we are in this
infection chain
and just a nice anecdote
terra has been known to use uh to be
have been used previously by the conti
group
as an additional backdoor to computers
that they've infected alongside with a
cobol strike
so uh we signed up for a free account on
atera and we wanted to take a look at
the functions that you could do on
computers that have this software
installed on there
on the left here you can see some of the
functions that
you can run on the machine you can
view the task manager you can
start install processes you can
download and upload files to the machine
run scripts run powershell commands and
many other actions
and when you sign up for an account you
can also create a custom installer this
installer when installed on the machine
will automatically connect that machine
to your atera account so you will be
able to control it
next we see
the atari agent process ran two scripts
this is one of them it's called
defender.bet defender with two r's
that's how the uh
adversaries uh called this script and we
can see uh it had a it has about 10 more
commands than the previous
campaign that we saw
we see at the bottom the exclusion for
msi exec
and we see at the top that they still
didn't read the documentation and tried
to use wildcards
next we see a tear agent calling the
loader.script now as uh
it's pretty obvious this script is in
charge of loading another script at the
top we see
this new script being downloaded and at
the bottom we see some commands the some
implementation of a trial and error way
to uh
to run this new script using a self ping
instead of a sleep timer a sleep
function
now let's take a look at what this uh
new script that they downloaded uh does
now the this script is called new.bat
and
here they made us our job a little bit
easier for us and they left us comments
so from those comments we can easily see
that the script
first checks
for admin privileges
if we don't have admin then we kindly
request the user to give us admin
permissions
once we have those permissions
we download a new script and run it with
elevated permissions
now this uh new script this is where the
money is this is where the the brain of
the infection infection is
and we'll break it down uh into a few
categories
at the top we can see we're adding some
more exclusions into windows defender
these exclusions are for certain folders
where we will download some executable
files and dlls
we download those those files into
our app data folder
next we make some changes to the machine
that we're infecting in order to make
analyzing that machine just a little bit
harder
we disable task manager we disable
command line
registry tools and
also disable run from the menu
next we make some changes into the boot
configuration
now this line will dive into this line
in the next slide it's a pretty
important uh command
i'll skip it for now and at last we will
take care of
persistence and download a bad script
into the startup folder so what is this
command that we skipped
we see this command is running mshta on
a file a dll file that we that was just
downloaded
now um if you're not familiar with the
mshta mshta is a a program that is built
into the operating system to windows and
it stands for microsoft html application
it's used to run hta files
so the first question that we should be
asking ourselves is how is mshta run on
a dll file it's supposed to run on a dot
hta file maybe this is actually an hta
file and they just change the extension
no it's a dll file
so how is that possible
now the next question that we had
is uh mshta is as i said built into the
to the operating system inside a system
32 folder and it's assigned a program by
microsoft
and when we took a look at the
app.contest.dll the file was downloaded
by the script we saw that
it was a dll and it was also signed by
microsoft was a with a valid signature
but when running these uh this command
together we get the malicious payload
injected into uh msi exec
so how's that possible
i don't think that microsoft released a
malware
so we wanted to uh to take a look at
this
a bit further
but first um let's talk a little bit
about digital signatures
so
what's a digital signature it's a
mathematical mathematical scheme for
verifying the authenticity of
digital files
it allows us to confirm that the file
originated from the signer and has not
been tampered with or changed since it
left the steiner's computer
and there's this entity called
certificate authority which
gives out and issues
digital certificates in order to
have us sign those files
so how does the this whole process works
we have a user a software developer um
he wants to sign his software so he
contacts one of many third-party
trusted certificate authorities and
registers with him once he registers
with them he can get this digital
certificate that will allow him to sign
files
um if we uh take another step and
understand this process
then we have joe joe is a software
developer and he wants to sign his
software
so um he will use his personal private
key
and using this private key he can sign
his file
now we have bob who wants to use joe's
software and make sure that the software
is uh is valid and digitally signed by
uh by joe
so he will take joe's digital
certificate that was uh given to him by
the ca on this digital certificate uh it
holds joe's public key
and using that public key he can decrypt
the uh digital signature and make sure
that the file is legitimate
now let's see how this looks on the file
itself this is an abstract view of a pe
file
um
the file is divided into the pe headers
and the actual data data that we're not
going to go into the different sections
because it's not relevant for for our
case here but uh in general we have the
pe data and the uh that p headers and
the data itself uh p headers holds
information like a time of uh
when the file was compiled uh entry
point of the file different addresses of
the different sections and so on
now when we want to sign this file the
first step that we need to take is we
need to compute the digest of the file
uh digest of the file is also called the
image hash of the file it's a little bit
different than the actual hash of the
file because it doesn't take into
account the checksum and the signature
data that is present on the file itself
so we compute the digest
next we will take this digest and
encrypt it using our private key
and this data will be appended to the
file and along with some other
metadata for the signature this will be
our signature and now the file the file
is signed
now when bob wants to verify that this
file is signed what's happening behind
the scenes
is again bob will compute the digest of
the file excluding the signature data
and the checksum of the file
he will take the signature and decrypt
the signature using the joe's public key
and compare the two if they are the same
then the file is valid and digitally
signed
now before we go back to our campaign
why are we even talking about digital
signatures why is this important for us
you may be asking this
so um digital signature has been
digital signatures have been used for uh
evading detection
many security products and edr's rely on
digital signatures to verify files and
as was said here in previous talks
if a file is signed by microsoft then it
is a little safer
so
some of the minor techniques that we can
see that use digital signatures
are uh masquerading so you can append a
digital signature to a file uh just any
digital signature the file will show up
as having a digital certificate even
though this digital certificate is not
valid it will also show that
there's code signing so some threat
actors and adversaries have been known
to
make up bogus
companies and sign up with
cas to receive digital certificates
until they are revoked or there have
have been also instances of
adversaries stealing
legitimate digital certificates and
using that certificate to sign their
malware
and there's some
sub techniques
that are also mentioned like using uh
system binaries that are signed in order
to run malicious code
so let's get go back to our
our campaign
we have mshda running on
appcontest.dllo the dll that was found
downloaded
if we look at the properties of the dll
we see that it is signed
and signed by microsoft windows
and we also see that the original file
name of this dll is app
resolver.dll
so now we wanted to uh investigate and
see what is this app resolver file
this file is also found on our computers
it's a dll file that is in charge of
resolving apps to
extensions so we found this file and we
compared the two
i said using this simple comparison we
see that the files are different in just
a few places in the pe headers
on the left you can see the original
apersolar file and on the right you see
the malicious dll and you can see that
the malicious dll has a vbscript
appended to it
in this vbscript you can see the
malicious command that is used to inject
the malicious payload into msi exec
so this would explain how mshta
ran this code it looked for the script
tag and ran the code that's inside it
but the question that we should be
asking now is how is that possible how
did the adversaries make a modification
to the file while keeping the digital
signature valid
so we need to ask ourselves can we trust
a file's digital signature
and uh let's see how they did that so we
go back to our abstract view of a pe
file
again divide it into the p headers and
the data itself
inside the p headers we have a security
directory
this directory holds information about
the digital signature of the file
it has the size of the signature and its
location
on the file
in this case here this piece file is not
signed so the signature size field
inside the security directory is zero
now when we sign this file this field
will
correspond to the actual signature size
of the file
now once we make a change to the file
here we appended a malicious script it
could be any data that we append to the
file this
digital signature is no longer valid
so how do we
go about and fix this and make the
signature valid
we can compute uh a new signature size
so what we do we take the original size
of the signature we compute in bytes uh
the length of the data that we appended
to the file and we just changed this
secure signature size inside the p
header
and all of a sudden our file is valid
and digitally signed
so this is what happened in this
particular instance
now when we found this we were ecstatic
we thought this is a a great cve that we
can report and we were very happy with
it but apparently
this is not new
there are three different cves that talk
about this issue
first one is from 2012.
now
after the cve in 2012 microsoft actually
released the fix for this issue in 2013
the fix um
actually makes uh a more exhaustive
check for the digital signature
and it actually fixes this issue so if
it fixes the issue how do we find this
now in 2021
uh this was in
2021 but it's also relevant today
so what happened is in 2014 just a year
later
microsoft removed this fix as default
behavior you have to actively change a
few registry keys in order to have this
fix
applied to your machine
what they said in their blog post is
that impact to existing software could
be high and
we prefer not to uh do this as default
behavior
you just saw in the previous slide how
easily
exploitable this issue is and as we said
before many security products rely on
on digital signatures
so uh let's go uh
back to our uh campaign um just uh touch
on a few uh more issues what is z loader
uh z loader is uh uh malware uh banking
trojan slash botnet
it borrows a lot of functionality from
the infamous zeus
banking malware they're
very similar
it is a very stealthy uh malware and
they improve their uh evasion from one
campaign to another um
very uh sophisticated
uh what's a banking malware in just a
few uh words
um it's uh usually a banking trojan it's
a file pretending to be uh something
else uh they perform man in the browser
attack so they inject uh code into your
browser to look for certain websites
where you uh would input a sense of
information like your password and uh
and username
usually it would be for banking sites
and they would send this information to
their c2 servers
just to sum up some of the defense
evasion techniques that we saw in this
campaign
there was this at first we saw terra the
use of legitimate software in order to
uh backdoor the machine and installed
our scripts
we saw the impairing of defenses all
those commands that we saw to
turn off basically windows defender
injection techniques to inject our
malicious payload into
msi exec
system binary proxy execution is the use
of mshta to run this
malicious code
and we also see the use of a decade old
vulnerability that is not
fixed by default
so now after we went through the entire
campaign and we talked about the
signature vulnerability we had just one
other question uh to answer
um
where did a terror agent come from did
the malicious actors install this on the
machine themselves and connect it to
their account did they
were they able to take over an existing
account and use that legitimate account
to run those scripts
so we found out that there was uh they
installed it themselves the those actors
they used a file called java.msi
and z loader has been known to
masquerade itself as java
zoom and teamviewer as we saw in
in the previous campaign
how do we find this out
when we signed up to
the free account we downloaded the
custom installer that would connect the
machine to our account and we analyzed
it
and what we found on this on this
installer
we actually found the email that we used
to sign up to the account
followed by the string
integrator login
what this is is basically when the
installer runs on the machine it creates
a registry key
this registry key will hold the email of
the account that that machine is
connected to
and this gave us something tangible to
look for um
when we wanted to find this suspicious
suspicious uh insta installation
so we wanted to look for suspicious
installations of a terra agent
and uh we found this uh installation
right here
when the account name
sorry account email is antique.corp at
mailto dot plus
uh now mailto dot plus is a
temporary uh email email service that
you can sign up you don't even need to
sign up you just go on the website you
can specify whatever name you want for
the email it will be at mailto.plus and
you will have this email address for the
next 15 minutes
now when we
looked for this email address on vt we
actually found the java.msi it only had
three detections and all those
detections were for potentially unwanted
software
and remote agent installer
when we installed this msi on our
machine we actually saw all the
infection chain running on our computer
so let's talk a little bit about the
extent of the campaign and
we found out that this campaign
affected over 2 000 victims from 116
different countries mainly from the
united states and canada
now you may ask yourself
how do we find this out
well again the attackers
gave us clues we found an open directory
for
on the domain that they hosted their
malicious files and one of those file
files was entries
that's what it was called it was
basically a log of all of the infected
machines that the they were able to
infect for each machine it had the date
of time date and time of infection um
the ip address country and the user
agent that was used in order to download
the malicious files
so we parsed this file and created this
graph
let's talk a little bit about a little
bit about the impact
that we had after publishing our
research
so here
at the top you can see the malicious dll
with the script
on virustotal
you can see that in december this uh dll
had a sign tag on virustotal and just a
few months later after we published our
research the sign tag is no longer
present on this file we contacted
virustotal and we were told that after
our research was published they decided
to apply microsoft's fix to their system
and now files that make changes to those
uh to the signature
for pe files will no longer show up as
signed
so we're pretty uh proud of that and
also during the research um
when we found the campaign we were also
in contact with atera
and they blocked of course the malicious
account and also the use of temporary
email address
to be signed up for that
service
okay so um let's summarize what we went
through um
returning to our original question
can we trust a digital signature
we sort of can
you just don't know if there's any
additional data that can be appended to
the script
during our checks we saw that most
environments are
vulnerable to this
exploit
i haven't seen a single computer that
applied microsoft's fix
by themselves
this
as i said would require them to change
only two registry keys
so we recommend that you apply this
fixed and you previously saw how easy it
is to exploit this vulnerability it can
be used for
code execution delivery or data
exfiltration as well
so um
yep that's it