[Music]
hi
my name is rishi kesh and today we will
try learn something about
how one can sort cyber physical relevant
binaries may be malicious maybe benign
from
from a lot of collection of we can say
other binaries
so
yeah that's me
i work at mandiant as a researcher
most of the time
okay yeah
most of the times working on some
on some terminal so please forgive me if
there is some mystic on to onto
presentation part i'm really not good at
user interfaces
and yeah i i love diving deeper into
networks wireless data link layers
memories uh formal methods
and to some extent and yeah i'm big fan
and small contributor of linux kernel so
i try find
security bugs in linux kernel and
try to patch them upstream so far not so
successful in doing that though
so yes
this slide
there might be a question like why
certainly this slide
the reason being uh let me tell you some
small story like how this whole thing
begin
i mean how this
uh
whole exploration began like when i
started working in the cyber physical
relevant threads research team in
mandiant
initially i i went ahead with the normal
we can say normal flow of hunting
specific binaries specific threats it's
like apart from dark web onto onto
various uh file aggregation engines
uh
there were like a lot of binaries so i
did the typical search for say
uh scara or say uh plc or something and
and i got like you know thousands of uh
results and written
that was tricky to handle because
that was not time efficient as well at
resource efficient
so
i started drilling deeper and when i
when i tried analyzing these all type of
samples which were not
so closely relevant to cyber physical
systems yet had something to do with
cyber physical systems they were obvious
questions coming from the other end of
the
of the team like you know i'm part of
research and there is another analysis
team so they came up with a question
saying okay you say this is cyber
physical relevant binary why
so while answering these questions i was
fortunate enough to
come up with certain selection criteria
certain test of deductions which
actually helped me
uh
we can say you know second my uh own
opinion or my own thoughts saying okay
these these these are the reasons that
makes this particular executable file
sample as cyber physical relevant so
this whole talk is going to be around
this uh excursion we can say
yeah so coming back to the same slide ot
malware
back in 2010 stuxnet was uncovered we
don't know before that how many years
the stuxnet was
in operation and was evolving
now we are in 2022. if you see the
numbers
stuxnet 2010
2014 black energy 2015 in destroyer 2016
iron gate 2017
triton and recently there was
intercontroller
one two three four five six
twelve years and only six campaign
honestly i was not convinced
there must have been something huge
number of things going on which we are
missing
maybe from detecting maybe from
from some technical limitations or maybe
something else
so again my tests of deductions were my
small contribution or rather are my
small contribution to
kind of you know come up with some
bigger numbers here
maybe in future but yes that's the whole
thing
so i believe this explains like why we
need to understand more about
ot binaries uh okay uh mythologies i
didn't mention ot stands for operational
technologies for those who are not aware
yes this slide basically seconds this
one just because there are five or six
campaigns uncovered in last 12 years
we are feeling happy okay there is
something burning around but we at is
bothered just because we are not aware
of that particular thing right
now let's come to the point why can't we
find this particular type of samples
while doing analysis onto onto various
sandboxes manually static dynamic
multiple things
i've observed many things
uh majority of the sandboxes that do
analyze
malware so that matter
they have certain preset rules available
and
excuse me
many of the times the cyber physical
relevant binaries were flagged legit
cyber physical relevant binaries were
flagged as malicious just because they
were doing something
which was
which was defeating the rules there or
which was basically going against the
rules into the sandboxes
that base yeah that was one of the
earlier days when i i tried showing in
almost every other binary
which was having some similarity to
cyber physical relevance
and i got like you know a number of uh
wrongly reported behaviors from
sandboxes
so that was one thing
another thing low visibility into ot
systems yes this is one of really really
big thing reason being
the the softwares that we use in ot
they are custom made
so obviously just by doing a search on
on any search engine we don't get a lot
of information related to that software
neither the software as well
other part of the story is like even if
you get a part of software there are
multiple
uh we can say parts you need to
recombine and then the actual executable
will trigger
plus these things are super expensive
the the typical operational technology
setups including hardware and software
they are super expensive that makes them
a little less prevalent on to internet
we can say
uh when i say internet for searching
purpose
so i'm not talking about
search or something
the third thing few motivated actors so
far yes there were not many uh
actors who were interested in cyber
physical
relevant targets the reason being
somebody or other majority of actors
they wanted something in written so
voter systems were not really targeted
by them because of obvious not much of a
we can say
um a read on investment type of thing
happening there uh yes the last one not
documented or undetected yes as i said
already like you know
uh
these things i mean the cyber physical
relevant softwares and hardwares
are a little less prevalent on internet
to search or to download we can say
and when i say not not documented and
undetected reason being uh
suppose there is a custom protocol
written for say a very specific
functionality
for example
operating a
sugar cane juice
mechanism for example
so we won't find any specific
documentation how the protocol was
written which protocol was used and how
that was passed on to the other side of
the sensor network
so obviously if we try to target that
particular type of uh
setup that is going to be challenged
because nothing is available
so that makes it
whole operational technology we can say
a little
uh little difficult to detect
so let's begin the search
some basic graphic understanding of what
exactly ot is and where exactly it sits
into our whole internet architecture or
for that matter ict
majority of the times ot is sitting in
between your uh
normal network and a specific network
people say like okay we have our ot
setup which is completely isolated from
internet but then the fact is
the the machine operator was able to
access
uh some of his emails which was supposed
to be only operated from internet so
that way there was there was some access
on such system so
that is why there is an overlap between
normal operating
environment and od operating environment
yes so coming back to the same question
again and again
what we see here is self-explanatory i
would say what in a normal site what we
used to what we perceive as as a normal
activity
is actually
kind of really tricky activity to be
considered
in case of malicious behavior
the graphic says it all i think i
shouldn't
i shouldn't say
anything beyond that
so yes
we need legit ot binaries for for
various things
but then again
what is the problem here
as as we have already discussed no
documentation available for them
uh for for multiple reasons
and cryptic and unique behavior so here
when i say cryptic and unique behaviors
uh let me give you an example say
suppose there is a there is a modus
protocol implementation it is speaking
to
some server and some client
uh the server is sitting somewhere
outside the uh sorry so the client is
sitting somewhere outside the
normal network periphery but is
connected to the network
my typical malware sandbox will say okay
there is some p cap being generated
because of so and so traffic that's
happening between client and server
server sitting inside gives a red flag
saying okay this is something tricky
happening some compromise or something
of that sort
but is it really so no because that's
the typical implementation of we can say
modbus protocol per se
close source development yes many of the
times even if we get some particular
binary to analyze it is strict one you
won't find any debug symbols so
a little more difficult basically to
analyze them
uh yes again like specific to
proprietary and private devices as i
have already told these are
custom made things like you know
specifically built for a specific
purpose
so
tricky
yes i have already discussed uh usually
distributed in parts
the last two points are more interesting
one huge variety of manufacturers and
devices and more functions more codes
more secrets
so
um
so so for one particular functionality
or for maybe one particular purpose if a
person decides not to
buy something which is readily available
in the market they'll go and you know
develop that thing on their own
custom hardwares
that makes it you know
makes it more easy sometimes to develop
such things and that makes it
uh the number of
such implementations
that keeps growing just because of uh
similar things
so where exactly can we find these all
uh ot binaries first thing is
aggregation engines file aggregation
engines like you know malware analysis
platforms
uh
ot users or manufacturers i found many
of such samples in their discussion
forums so like usually there is somebody
complaining about okay i'm trying to run
so and so exe and i'm not getting so and
so uh since the data or so and so
uh client data how to how to go ahead
and then at many places i have found the
person actually mentioning
every minute detail about the executable
he is trying to trigger
including his credentials
so that was again really tricky thing
and in-house collection yes so that was
something
uh
we have been trying to do
uh with the with the help of some
some company or with the help of some uh
vendors
so that was a lot of theory lot of
boring thing let's go to tests of
deduction
so far i was able to uh come up with
these many criterias one two three four
eight in number
uh they are not just 18 number they
could be many more
or could be reduced or compressed to
something small as well
so uh these are this these are some of
the types of deduction for
for
maybe a threat researcher or a
stock analyst to
to determine if the binary in question
is cyber physical relevant is actually
having some cyber physical relevant
content or not
so let's look at them one by one static
strings very basic approach
most of the windows and linux
systems are equipped with those commands
as you can see here i have just run the
binary with strings as a command and
have seen
some interesting keywords uh coming up
into the
uh into the uh terminal say like you
know plc station number very specific uh
occurrence from from modbus perspective
so a small demo i actually wanted to
show you live demo but my
demo machine basically got crashed so i
have some pre-recorded demo here to show
you
so it's it's the same strings command
that i'm running over a specific
file you could see it it dropped
everything available on to that file as
uh text
yeah
so you could see couple of entries there
mentioning plc's
and and these are from the binaries so
something that can be used as a one of
the convincing factor that the binary
under
examination is cyber physical relevant
one another thing that was like status
rings which were available onto
or into the executable another one is
from dynamic strings so here we
try to do some formal methods uh
related work there's actually a tool
called slos and we have used that tool
to kind of you know carve some of the
such sums of strings from
from memory as well
so let's see a demo for that
too
you could see that i have used a tool
called floss so everything that you
would see in the demos is available
online and is open source
so there is nothing uh something
enterprise thing that i'm using here
now if you just compare these two
outcomes the first one is from the
dynamic strings outcome and second one
is static strings you could see dynamic
strings actually spelled couple of more
interesting
entries there
yes so this is something which will
actually convince us in little more
depths that whatever the binary that we
are trying to analyze is cyber physical
relevant here we are trying to
uh
drill a little deeper and understand if
if there is any presence of a
very specific function which is dealing
with
which is dealing with cyber physical
systems
so
so i have used here a tool called getra
again openly available
for reverse engineering
or actually it's not reverse engineering
it's just exploring the things around
so let's begin okay so in this
particular uh
video i'm showing usage of r2 that's
actually radar a2
another openly available
debugger and disassembler
so and purposely i have written the name
of file as modbus plc so that we will uh
have some understanding about what
exactly we are trying to target so i
have just run uh i i as a command and i
have seen like you know a lot many
functions and other calls
uh making
uh making a presence here that again is
something really tricky to go one by one
so i tried c
if something of this sword is happening
before going for the oh sorry i just
missed it it seems
okay
yeah before going further i wanted oh
sorry
yes i wanted to share something about
this particular open thing so why did i
try and search open as a keyword into
this whole functional or api
uh calls which were being recorded or
rather
being analyzed by r2 radar a2
for all of the operating systems in the
world that we use so far
everything that we read or write from is
a file
no matter if that is actually a file or
if that is a device
so this was actually an approach where i
i tried
uh see if if
the binary in in its context is trying
to reach out to a specific device and
the best way to find that is
see if there is any open call available
or open file call available specifically
that way i'll be able to understand if
there is anything which is
uh which is which is actually you know
if there is any functionality which is
trying to reach out to some hardware or
some virtual device or some sensor
uh outside the binary
so was the reason of that particular
search
open
and you could see that the first entry
there that say is open file
ah
i think i reset
the full
just a second
yeah so now i'm trying to search for
open as a keyword into the
list of available
calls you can say
now let's try digging deeper into the
first entry that is open file and see if
something of interest could be found
yeah again we got two entries in there
so i'll try and drill deeper into the
first entry out of the out of the twos
something interesting was shown there
sim dot modbus.txt something something
something but again not much much of the
uh convincing power it has so far
so i'll try seek that particular
address
and see if something could be found
there
yes
bingo
ah
here
string error accessing coil register
address field
this is a very specific description
uh of behavior of modbus relevant
binaries this gives me a
proper proof or an evidence that the
binary that i'm trying to analyze is
cyber physical relevant one
now let's go to another demo
let me just
quickly fold it
oh
sorry it was not highlighted earlier
ah same thing was repeating
okay now we'll we'll try to see the same
demo from uh gidra
i'll just skip some first
steps here
so that we could expediate
yeah so here as well i was i was trying
search find the presence of cyber
physical relevant functionalities
and
yes like every other lazy person i i
tried search interesting strings
interesting functions
uh using some of gydra's inbuilt
capabilities here
so this particular thing filter i later
discovered that can actually be used to
to search some interesting functions as
well
so this world uh video
is is not only about success of how did
i find something but is also about the
failures how how i could not find
something
so like for coil there was no
interesting thing i could find in the
symbol tree
so then i resorted to
another search
yes so here i got some interesting
instances like lplc strings
and and
the other one which was like from
ifcons.h
yes
this was the again concrete evidence i
was able to establish if it is plc that
i am dealing with into a particular
sample
and then resorting to typical string
search including pascal strings as well
and then filtering those search for very
specific keywords
yeah
as we could see like you know plc
station number again very unique uh
occurrence
for
for cyber physical relevance i would say
yeah
okay so there are a couple of more
similar thing i tried with modbus modbus
tcp cybers
spa bus
lib iec 61850
goose
goes over tcp as well
we will go to we will go through each of
them one by one
so yeah now we have got another proof
that whatever we are dealing with is
again having functionality specific to
modbus tcp as well
okay so there is some serial uh
protocol involved eth stands for maybe
ethernet
so this was just like you know some some
set of explorations
okay
i i won't be able to show demo on this
particular slide uh fuzzy hash or import
hash
because of some tricky nature or
behavior of samples we can say but what
here exactly i'm trying to do like you
know in previous demos we have seen some
very specific functions being used some
very uh specific calls being made so we
can actually calculate a fuzzy hash for
similar isolated functions and can run
them run them through maybe you know
various hunting mechanisms to see if
there is any
if there is any match available
api sequences another very important
thing i would say those who are malware
researchers here or reverse engineers
they know very well why this is
important because those who are seizing
malware researchers they can actually
identify whole malware including the
campaign and family just by looking at
the api call sequences being made into
the binary itself so similar approach
can be used in in
cyber physical or while establishing
cyber physical relevant
behavior of a binary as well
device probes as we have already seen in
the demo device probes is one of really
very important thing reason being
say out of if we consider 100 cyber
physical relevant uh samples
98 of them will be trying to speak to
some device
could be internally could be externally
could be onto a network could be on to
maybe some other custom protocol maybe
onto wire could be anything right
so finding these device probes can
actually
give us more
or rather can give us uh give our
statement more strength
about the cyber physical relevance
presence
so again a small demo here
so again same thing so let's not waste
time in this demo same demo but from a
different perspective i'm trying to show
you because the coils are nothing but a
remotely
available some hardware maybe sensors
analogous to sensors which we can say
and
yeah so here comes the network device
probes uh reason being as sensors the
majority of the times have some
capability to speak on network majority
of the times not always
there would be interesting things to to
look at or to search for
so this was the demo
let's begin
i'll skip the part which is actually
time consuming for no reason
yes
if you if you look at the string that we
tried find here is like ic61850
those who know this is nothing but kind
of uh
we can say you know power distribution
relevant technology or our standard that
we use
so iec 61850 underscore s may be slave
goose
another power transmission related
implementation that we use
spabus another interesting cyber
physical relevant implementation
so that says t underscores power bus
underscore m so maybe master instance
okay
so here i have tried enumerate some
more such cyber physical relevant uh
setups we can say or
functions
so
okay i probably missed the earlier one
the iec
or is it looping
just a second
ah yes so here again i have used
radar a2 to find some different
functions or protocol which are specific
to
cyber physical systems
so again i have used some different
binary here for for analysis purpose and
i purposely
fast forwarded initial steps that as we
have already gone through them
as you could see the occurrences
so same thing we can do with gidra as
well as with
a direct
i just am trying to highlight everything
that i was
able to find using these all
explorations
that's it
so yes those were some of the demos i
actually wanted to show you them all
live but
my setup could not could not run it
properly or basically it was messing up
into my
setup that i'm going to use tomorrow in
my workshop
so yes yara rules
so majority of the things that we have
seen so far can actually be converted to
yara rules and can be used as a as as a
detection mechanism
but
uh
when i try to do that majority of those
era rules
where were found to be a little more
noisy than expected so
sometimes i have got like you know ten
thousand hits twenty thousand hits for
for something
really not so obvious
results
uh this whole thing took me a few months
to basically formulate and come up with
some results
results were
honestly
average we can say
i was actually able to build some data
set which can be used as a benchmark or
to to begin
uh with
in in cyber physical threat hunting
process we can say
if we could automate these all tests
which are really easy to automate which
we did as well
that would be a lot of less effort
overhead we can say like you know uh for
example per uh per day there are around
150 000 uploads on on famous
you know
malware aggregation engines
uh sorting through them is is really
tricky if we happen to download them all
and
then do the
analysis part so here the automation can
actually help
yes as has already been mentioned it can
actually help in expediating or analysis
part as well
for the same reason out of 100 if there
are like one or two which are actually
cyber physical relevant binaries then we
need not analyze those hundred and then
reach to the conclusion okay these are
the cyber physical relevant binaries
instead we can pick the cyber physical
11 binaries and then go ahead and you
know
do the proper analysis on them
excuse me
yes like as already i have spoken it
helps reducing glitter
and the benchmark can be set quickly
so
after after going through these all
tests we can say like you know there is
no silver bullet there is no uh we can
say you know check box like things okay
these these things and
you are hitting the cyber physical
relevant sample
but whatever the types of deductions
that we have discussed so far can
actually help us
uh isolate some relatively
relevant samples from
uh from say like you know per day upload
of 100 150 000 samples
so that's most of it i had to share so
far
there is a lot of development also
happening into this particular topic
uh so far i have no
approvals to share that thing on the
stage
but as soon as i get that i'll probably
you know come up with uh more ideas to
present as well so there are already
things there are already developments in
place for this
so
and this talk was actually meant to
meant to you know share how
how from a completely unknown territory
we can go ahead in in hunting some very
specific type of binaries
so that's it