[Music]
okay thank you very much for all those
who are here as this is the last
conference sorry last presentation of
the conference and i know those can be
tough to attend especially after such
such intensive days as we have at xifcon
so on behalf of organizer i guess thanks
a lot as again so to cut to the point
and not to have this drug over for an
hour and a half or something like this
let's get started
on who on what we'll be talking about
and who i am and why am i talking about
i'm a great supporter of the inigo
montoya style of introduction so just
greeting we are there
is something about myself then
establishing a link
the
presentation we've heard were mostly on
the red team site hence i'm quite happy
about that because i would like to
present the
blue side of things that may be useful i
hope uh also for the purposes of the
adversary
emulation
and in terms of managing expectations i
hope to
to
alleviate threat intel analyst
in terms of in terms of how they
approach and how they address the
threats when something something big
happens in the world because sometimes i
feel that they might get overburdened
with what are the expectations from
management and how how the
uh how the support to the rest of kind
rest of organization can look like so we
will discuss some
actual case studies i mean it's of
course impossible to prove the negative
like the attack did not happen despite
some political tension or geograph
geopolitical relations
hence we will discuss
attacks that can be clearly traced to
those high-profile events but also we
will take a look at how the
uh how sometimes the analysts can
clearly overreach
uh with their with their predictions and
assessment and we will take a look at
the strategic
document of policy in the chinese five
years plan and how the analysts who are
dealing with the with the chinese-based
threat actors uh approach it there will
be also a short comment on how the
russian invasion of ukraine
changed the trent lance came back but i
will comment on that later and finally
we will
deal with conclusions and how to how to
address properly those those situations
so first of all who am i i'm working as
a principal threat intelligence analyst
at quo intelligence so we deliver
tailored
intelligence services and solutions
to our customers as a principal analyst
i'm working
uh i'm working directly with customers
gathering their intelligence
requirements making sure that our
products meet their expectations and
also doing the doing the research
activities
i like to share in low-range hence
sometimes i'm a teaching assistant for
sun cyber threat intelligence course if
you take the live online version usually
in the u.s time zone i might be there
and you can read my thoughts and
my
side work in on the ocean national
security and threat intelligence music
at my blog counterintelligence
counterintelligence.pl in my free time i
like i like flying stuff i like aviation
i've got my own adsb station so if you
use flight rather and look at what's
going on in poland you might get
flights that are captured by my station
i like flipping flipping valley songs
and also climbing mostly bouldering but
that's that's also on b so i had to go
with climbing and of course feel free
feel free to connect if you will have
any questions after the presentation
just reach me on linkedin twitter or or
email
it's easy to find
so when i saw that my presentation is
last on the second day i was like like
you know the expectations are low
uh it's just so that recently i'm the
only thing stopping you from going home
so so it might be mahesh but actually i
think the rota made quite quite great
decision because the scenario i wanted
to present or to introduce the narrative
is exactly that it's afternoon at friday
like friday four five pm and it is it's
friday uh four or five pm so in normal
circumstances you you would be
uh you would be preparing to head home
and it's common cliche in the
development circles that you should not
push things into into production at
friday 4 p.m because something will blow
up and it's of course not not the case
usually with security teams i mean if
you have access to edr and you might
pass some push some blocking rule that
will that will crush the infrastructure
but but otherwise that's that's not
that's not usually the case in our
sector but what is the case is that
either the incidence happens at the
least convenient moment or
uh that the wars event the media picks
up something and blows it so that it
gains visibility for the
uh to the c-level personnel and they
have to they usually as we will talk
about move to the to the intelligence
team for support and the best example of
this type of let's say bit of spreading
fear uncertainty and doubt is this
cyber pearl harbor scenario the the huge
destructive attack that will
that will happen and that will cause
massive damage to infrastructure and
it's uh it's something that
sea level might be worth of and not
without a reason because it came up
again and again the top example here is
actually from poland it's me it says
polish general we expected a bit of
cyber something like cyber per hubble
and he is
he is talking about situation in ukraine
lower you've got leon paletta ex
director of cia who was also talking
about this and of course a bunch of
journalists who are on it
so when things like this happen
when there is
political tensions around the globe when
there is even that's picked up by media
what does the management or the the
security head of security organization
does it can reach to the to the
intelligence team
and can
ask them to to provide provide analysis
find out what's going on assess how it
will how it will
affect our organizations and what can
happen is that we end up in the danger
zone
why
because while the
while the it's normal that intelligence
team is in an advised advisory role the
what threat intelligence is is can be
quite quite moody let's say quite mixed
like you might be familiar with the
company jains they are most known for
their military reference chains fighting
ships but they also have threat
intelligence service but data
intelligence is around
insurgency activity military posture of
countries proliferation of weapons of
mass destruction and so on so if you are
a board intelligence analyst and just
applying to various linkedin jobs and
you would apply to threat intelligence
and jains and your cyber threat
intelligence analyst they might be quite
a surprise at the job interview so on
the other hand we've got like our own
let's say cyber threat intelligence as
here represented by the sanskros
4578 cyber threat intelligence that
teaches you how to analyze the
tradecraft of the adversary so is the
one threat intelligence more correct
than one than another of course not but
the issue comes when the when there is a
mix of expectation from the
from those who enacted and support the
threat intelligence server service so it
might be
so it might be quite expected that the
the expectation will be that not only
the intelligence team will be
will have expertise in technical
analysis of threats
and in
and in following the infrastructure
following the malware implants but also
when something something some let's say
adversarial actions happens they will
analyze the geopolitical landscape
provide the sound analysis of what will
happen whether we will be cyber attacked
and so on and so on so for example at my
company at intelligence we have folks
from both the cyber side and the
political side and we work together but
we are a specialized out outlet and als
and of course this might not happen if
you are in the organization you might be
the only threat intelligence analyst you
might be a threat intelligence that's
working with the with the incident
response team for example a support so
so how to approach it what to do
so first of all we need to establish
some assumptions and and like deal with
the reality regardless if you are a
small company or if you are
a big company like amazon or microsoft
your field of view will be limited and
especially in terms of the
of the analysis that
that extends beyond the beyond disciple
landscape
so
this combined with the fact that you
will kind of instinctively think that
the the
or central management can
think that the early world event affects
you can lead to biases on your side so
you will start to create the
intelligence requirements and
intelligence collections plan and so on
based around the fact that you're like
at the center of these
activities even if they do not happen so
you might be familiar with the with the
kevin bacon
which is the relationship between kevin
bacon and other actors counted by how
many there are links of separation
separation
in terms of movies so for example
michael emerson's
kevin become number is two because he
acted in movies with the with these
folks from movie loverboy and they acted
with with kevin bacon and in the same
example of course you can draw an
arbitrary relationship between your
organization and basically any event in
the world and this is something that we
should strive to avoid
because what can happen and what can
exacerbate this problem is that when
high profile event happens like conflict
starts like there is a tension between
the country where your company is
located in and so some other country
that is active in terms of cyber space
operation you can
you may want to move your collection so
so what you're focusing on as an
intelligence team to things focused on
the
on this event and uh in the first first
look it looks it looks perfectly
reasonable because you want to you want
to find something about this event you
want to analyze the activity you want to
compare it with your infrastructure and
so on but
ultimately this may lead to like having
a tuna vision on on what what is
happening so of course if you if you for
example take the
the
invasion of ukraine as an example and
you will start looking for for
malware related to that you will read
the reports from microsoft and from
other companies from ukrainian set on
what's going on you will find something
and by extending this threat
relationship further and further you
might
find a link that's not necessarily
direct or really feasible to your threat
landscape so first question to ask is do
you have any direct visibility so so
when you are talking about when we are
talking about the analysis of those
those far-reaching events do we not just
based on the visibility provided by
others and what are the biases related
from it and if we talk about the
highly volatile situation do we have
this direct relationship which we'll be
talking about in our examples
or do we just have the impression of the
relationship so let's go with the first
case study that shows a kind of perfect
storm of events that lead to retaliatory
attack
so there was a certain gentleman in the
united states i think he passed away so
so he was not available for comment but
he thought that the best way to deter
iran from the from pursuing their
nuclear program uh was to detonate a
nuclear warhead in the desert in iran
and threaten the further nuclear strike
if the if the program will not subsidize
so this
after this the
his and his casino enterprise suffered a
wiper attack it was some visual basic
wiper nothing nothing like super special
but
it did a job and cost of recovery was as
it was as we see 40 million dollars and
we have attribution from stereo from the
us intelligence so we we have
confirmation that i run link groups were
responsible and what what happened
behind the scenes so the quotes was for
from sheldon adelson who was the ceo of
las vegas sandscorp some the saudi
uh this push towards retaliation and
this adversarial relationship happened
just at the top level so so like
straight the the first officer the first
representative of the company made this
kind of
implication of threat and of course from
the from the perspective of the iranian
groups that was treated as an as an
invitation to to this kind of u.s policy
and why i'm saying this was this was
kind of a perfect storm because
in case of the iran structure of cyber
operation there are many subtleties and
complexities so for example iran
bases heavily on the independent
contractor groups that are essentially
essentially competing for the government
contracts if we can call it like that
the the groups that that
have effects that that can provide
effects are getting paid and are getting
further contracts
the
competition makes the operations more
aggressive and so on
and the iran has a history of using the
retaliatory attacks so for example in
we had a so-called operation abba bill
which was ddos against multiple
u.s banks like
jp morgan chase bank of america and this
was the
this was caused by the
as this was a response as communicated
by the groups responsible uh to the
inflammatory inflammatory movie
published by the by the
radical fundamentalist
christian preacher from the united
states we also had deployment of shamoon
against the saudi aramco
which was highly destructive and was uh
was communicated as a retaliation to the
uh
to the acts of saudi arabia in the
region and if we look at the work of
those groups and then compare and
contrast it with the uh
let's say more pure espionage operation
like various those various kittens or
apt 33 34 45 that uh that are working we
will see that that clearly the iran goes
two ways in those terms and the
destructive attacks can be highly highly
likely given given these
retaliatory relationships so this is
actually actually what happened in the
in the saudi aramco case the saudi
aramco tried to try to deny the denied
the
that it had much effect but the
journalists linked this photo that
after the after the attack the
it the this flotilla of the tankers of
trucks could not could not get the oil
from the refinery due to the damage to
the systems
and another case study was the guardians
of peace
attack against sunny pictures
entertainment and what happened there
was the
this was a response to the to the movie
the interview if you haven't seen it
then then apologies but there will be
spoilers on how it ends then you can you
can leave or watch the presentation
later online
but
the movie was about two guys
tv reporters who were acting on behalf
of cia
and went to north korea to assassinate
kim jong koon
and it
caused quite a stir and it caused a
diplomatic tension and threats from the
north korea not only against only
directly but
also against the against the theaters
so that there will be terrorist acts
ahead
and
resulted in attack that was not only
just a hacker they released a lot of a
lot of stuff from sunny pictures
entertainment but also also disrupted
the it infrastructure used the
the employees who are who were
uh
who would turn down the pieces in the
morning so this uh this
red skeleton that they've been hacked by
the guardians of peace group and there
was threat to to
take down the interview before
before the
certain timeline or else and so on so
let's take a look on how how it relates
to on what could have happened in the in
the background so when we look at the
north korea state priorities this is
complied for the from the public u.s
intelligence reporting and
think tank reporting is that major
priorities are development of nuclear
capabilities ensuring the role of kim
family and being having this dominant
position in korea and peninsula and
especially especially
if you look at the at the second point
the ensuring the the rule of king family
like how this can be threatened and and
what could happen so what happened in
the movie and now that there is a
spoiler ahead is that at the end of the
movie kim jong-un
is traveling in a helicopter and it gets
shot down by by a tank nonetheless and
he he dies in a fireball so why this is
so significant because i mean this is
not the perfect picture because this is
actually the cia protecting the uh then
afghanistan president hamid karzai but i
could not find a picture of cia killing
a foreign leader but the point is that
the being involved in foreign policy
matters meddling in politics of other
states is exactly what cia does
so what from the perspective of north
korea what happened is that the movie
was the depiction of what could have
happened of what will happen like the
pers like the the declaration of threat
from the
from the united states now it is
debatable what
happened in terms of the tasking so
whether it were overzealous elements of
the of the north korean intelligence
cyber groups or was this order from the
top but this relationship of of like
kicking the hornet's nest in terms of uh
digging right into the into what makes
north korea the state it is so the rule
of the kim family was what the what
caused this mess this attack and against
the private company threats of violence
response from the president of the
united states who who said that sony
made a mistake because because they
should not have taken down the picture
because
it's essentially
for instance sensoring us artists and so
on and all this
mess so next let's move on to
wada so world anti-doping agency and the
uh and events that surrounded the 2018
winter olympic games so as we as we know
uh
now russia is quite
proficient in
providing illegal support to the atleast
they were running a doping program
that's run by the
fsb and sbr and the officers were
involved in faking the
the urine tests opening the containers
and so on so there were two distinct
operations that happened as a as let's
say relation to that in response to that
first was leaking of
uh documentation from from other world
anti-doping agency and it was openly
advertised by the by the group as the
fancy beer hacked him so fancy beer was
the moniker used by the crowdstrike to
describe the activities of russian gru
or well one of the teams and they said
yeah yeah this is us it was also
almost like in the face but what
happened then during olympics was that
there was another attack and here as we
were talking about the direct
relationship and direct victims here the
it's it's not so easy so the attack was
uh
it was against the olympic
infrastructure that was involved in
uh
in
vp access for journalists in the ticket
distribution so so if you wanted to buy
a ticket during olympics like last
minute you could not do it and the
collateral victim was not the well
collateral direct victim was the
olympian games but the collateral victim
was it provider as here we can see
in the indictment issue but the united
states department of justice the i.t
company one whose infrastructure has
been breached and because they were pro
iit providers to the olympian gays there
it was essentially a supply chain
attacks
and
they were used to to disrupt the
olympics to they had the infrastructure
and of course it does not matter if it
would be company it company one or it
company one two three four five six or
any other
the company that was here responsible
for the for the olympian case got like
got tackled because of the relationship
and if we compare those two
we can see quite a quite a shift in the
tactics procedures
because while the
defensible hacking team and their leaks
leaks
were openly
advertised like this is us in case of
the attack against uh direct attack
against the olympian games uh the
malware attribution was heavily thwarted
or there were attempts to toward the
attribution
uh the using false flags trying to make
malware look like the like the work of
the lazarus team and so on also the
russian government officially denied
responsibility here as we are reading
the indictment but
by the department of justice the those
actions were actually attributed to the
to the actors of russian state so as we
see when there was a hack and league
operation that was it was quite open but
once we moved to this this destructive
operation that could be considered in
various different terms for just a
cyber sabotage to perhaps an armed
attack depending on on the
on how you look at it
and the level of the of admittance let's
say dropped significantly but the effect
of those
did not
so those were the those were the
case studies that
showed how the
uh showed how
attacks can happen as a result of
geopolitical tension but what if
analysts are bit over sellers in terms
of analysis and sometimes sometimes the
there are many roadblocks
for the analysis so
china's policy is well not based but
there is major document of china policy
the five-year plan
which shapes the economic and national
priorities for the next five years
and especially interesting for analysts
and prominent since the 13th
13th plan five years plan
so which
was supposed to to cover the the period
between 2016 and 2020. and included for
example the made in china policy so the
so the move to the to manufacturing of
components in
china and getting the intellectual
property
on site
innovation strength strengthening the
industrial base and so on and if we take
a look at the reporting from the
reporting from the period
we can see that everything is five years
planned like we have at the top uh the
report from mandiant
lower is the report about the the
accident this is the report that's known
in this
cyber threat intelligence community
report operation smn so it was combined
effort of microsoft cisco fire eye then
multiple multiple companies did that
made the effort to to describe this
axiom protector
and here is the on the right side is the
document from the united states
government department of health and
human services which also describes uh
china threats and you can see here all
over the the references to the five
years plans in terms of the threat actor
relationships so i i took a look at what
actually in the fight it's in this fight
years plan actually that's a lie because
i knew what was there because i was
dealing with the with the china related
protectors but for the narrative site
let's say we take a look now and if we
if we
those are public documents no no need
for some advanced collection so if we
take a look we can see that the
technologies name in china are aerospace
equipment so maybe something related to
jet fighters to flight transport
marine engineering so
naval shipbuilding
rail transit manufacturing to cnc
some computer numerical control machine
tooling used in
using production and precise
manufacturing robotics is so common now
in
in production lines
agriculture medical equipment
chemical machinery next generation
information and technically biotech
industry and that's nice for them but
that's not the end
the
special information
processing and so on
advanced materials and
new energy vehicles so quite an
extensive list and if we look at the at
the other two attackers that were
supposedly active before this five year
plans like here described by the
uh
by crowdstrike the puter panda activity
they targeted aerospace industry apt-1
both of these groups related to
people's liberation army activity the
targeted i.t transportation anglic
agriculture or if we look at divinity in
its various groups that
targeted chemical companies high-tech
companies machine equipment companies
we may ask like what's going on did
those groups miss the memo that there
will be a next next 2016 plan that they
should refer to in terms of their
targeting
we can also like scroll back and if you
now take a look at the
uh at the department of human and health
services presentation you can see that
they also actually describe the activity
that took place between 2006 and 2014
and is also somehow related to this 2016
five years plan so what happened in the
in the end from my perspective is that
because this plan was so so extensive
and and covered so many different
industries
there was no no relation there was it
was it had no
significant diagnostic value what
happened is that because of those
those threat actors activities were
geared and pointed towards the
uh towards supporting china's national
priorities or any country's priorities
like defense strengthening industrial
base and so on the
use of firefighters plan in reporting
was not all about correct let's say
methodologically was not always about
the
uh it was not all about the
using additional factor for analysis but
rather a case of confirmation by us
where the analysts
saw the fighter's plans like pick and
choose if it fits to the activity and
then it was
it was used as a as a supporting
argument as something something like
supporting their thesis and if we look
actually at the 14th five year plan we
can see that those uh
those priorities that we
saw earlier especially strengthening
technological advantage uh developing
national security boosting domestic
housing demands also manufacturing and
having materials to create them are
still present so we cannot take out of
context like one single piece of
document and there are there are
multiple for the china
and and take it just try to apply it but
instead we have to fortunately or
unfortunately take a look at bigger
picture and make sure that when we are
taking in evidence they are not here to
support our costs but actually to make
sure make check on us if the if the
causes are in fact correct
so now comes the comes the the moment
that the presentation presentation was
supposed to look a bit different
because when when i was submitting the
call for papers in march the the
russian invasion of ukraine was was
still let's say quite in its early phase
so i
kind of tried to i kind of thought that
by the by the time the
uh the zip code will happen we will be
in a bit different place but but it's
still a stalemate so i would like not to
comment on the
only its consequences yet but we can see
on what happened already and what did
not happen so definitely what did not
happen and was to kind of let's say in
air quotes a bit of disappointment of
many cyber third analysts is that there
was no no expected massive cyber
armageddon let's say massive destructive
attacks and for various reasons so we
had these various activists these
activities groups like kilnet or
religion attacking ddosing targets in
the in europe and in ukraine
we had the
ddos attacks against the latvian
lithuania after the announcement of
sanctions against royal transport in
kaliningrad
and we had the activity in so so we're
doing very early phase like days
that followed the invasion and days
before
we had again attack against the
satellite communication provider which
cripples like internet access we had the
ddos attacks against banks and
government sides which you know when the
when the country is getting invaded it's
the it's natural that cities and look
for them to secure their belongings and
microsoft described the describe the
activity in the report and they
mentioned that wipers were being
deployed and so on but because of the of
the preparation of ukrainian computer
emergency teams
and other factors they were not as
successful
but what again what did not happen and
what many companies and this is this is
what's the inspiration for the for this
presentation is that many companies were
were kind of
they were upset to say list i mean
because they felt like this was a major
geopolitical event so this will this
will like fall back on us but of course
this the here we are going back to this
to this dilemma of of the kevin bank on
effect and and main character syndrome
so it's natural for the for such
situation to make you overestimate your
your threat landscape
but it is the job of the analysts to
to make sure that this overestimation
does not happen so here we can break
down the cases of of what was the
breaking down case studies into into
what were the motivations method and
relationship so basically if we look at
the at the methods of attack in case of
this this where we saw this relationship
there were either destructive or
hackanthic activities so
so the
response to the geopolitical event in
each case was proportional in a way that
is it was not a covert operation it was
not concealed it was supposed to have
this
this effect that will that will kind of
bounce back on the target
and
of course as we mentioned the
relationship is not always directly
directly adversarial so in case of
las vegas casinos
and in case of the sunny pictures we had
this dislike
seemingly direct threat but in
in fact sorry in case of las vegas
casinos and olympic games we had this
seemingly uh seemingly direct
relationship
but what happened was
in other cases is that the there were
some companies were just collaterals so
sony pictures of course have no
intention of starting a war in north
korea or or deploying cia operatives to
to kill the leader they just were doing
hard the i.t services provider attacked
during winter olympics
was not involved in the in the
assessment of
russian russian doping scandal and so on
but because they could establish this
second-year relationship
they were they were attacked so how to
how to deal with those and how to how to
remain sane
so i think that the worst thing that can
happen when these things
when these things happen is trying to
establish threat intelligence program
like right now so
if you if you are in situation of
heightened tensions and you will want to
have analyst new analyst new service and
so on it will be always by us toward
collection of this of the information
around these threats so having the
preparations and making sure that you've
got intelligence requirements you know
you know this relationship with the
vendors and supply chains and threats
can make sure that that you will not
actually be
can not will not be actually
alert fatigue a security operation folks
might say
and and will have clear-headed analysis
so in terms of the intelligence
requirements and expectations of
management
we have these we have to manage we have
to know if we have event capability to
assess the geopolitical situation of you
know if we are more on the
if we are more on the cyber threat side
so we can only provide information of
that we have to fight against like
putting additional priorities if we are
making sure that uh that what we do is
and that what we do is is
sound methodologically and
and provides adequate information and i
like models and i like methodologies
that
that because they provide a repeatable
sequence of steps for different
situations and one of those known in the
cyber threat intelligence is the diamond
model so it's i mean it's here it's
arrows model but it's you can imagine
the diamond that connects the vertexes
and it pops it has two main axises and
in maps the relationship between
adversary and victim so like social
political access and the infrastructure
and capability so technical access and
uh this diamond model made by sergio
caltagirona others highly recommend
reading about it it's got it axioms and
one there is always relationship between
the adversary and victim it causes the
the action to happen but my axiom is it
is that if you try hard enough you will
find a relationship between anything so
it's important to when assessing the
uh this social political axis to ask
what
exactly relationship you have in mind is
it direct or is it direct after after
many many steps is there
goals that will be achieved if you will
be targeted by the by the
adversary and for in case of destructive
i think there will be some
some goals to be to be achieved and of
course as we if we step back the
assessment of those goals does require
the expertise to have a political
situation from my perspective it's
better for it's often better for the
threat intelligence team to to kind of
push back on the on the expectation to
uh to provide those like recently in my
company in my team we had we had a short
discussion on uh what is easier is cyber
threat intelligence easier or is this
geopolitical
and one might think that you know in
terms of geopolitical you can collect
information you this open source you
have these think tanks reports this open
source intelligence reporting from
various government agencies and
in terms of technical intelligence you
need to have some malware reverse
engineering knowledge d5r knowledge and
so on so it's it might be considered
more difficult but i do not think that's
the case and that's because the adequate
collection of information that will not
be biased will not be
just public reporting but instead will
feed you
like on the ground view on what is going
on is at least equally challenging you
need to know the culture you need to
know the language in most cases you need
to know which sources are are biased and
so on so this all contributes into
sometimes like easy ways of relying on
on associated praise reuters
cables which might be great but will
always be biased towards how we
how we perceive the situation so what
how to how to counteract it
i would say that technical threat
intelligence team might want to focus on
the technical threat intelligence so we
do not necessarily have to have a
knowledge of what is going on in terms
of the
geopolitical events but we can be
prepared towards certain deployment of
certain tactics and procedures that will
that we
observe from our analysis on the threat
landscape that are used to
achieve those goals so as we've seen
here the wipers and denial of service
attacks are very common in case of those
in case of those operations but we've
only like scratched the surface of
course if you have threat intelligence
team you should pull more data
and see exactly how these dos attacks
were provided if the such thing would
happen what how it would translate into
your monitoring and response so we have
a procedures for that and in this case
you can kind of mitigate the need to
mitigate the need to have very in-depth
geopolitical reporting which might not
be available to you and instead try to
try to raise the
bar for your organization
in terms of the in terms of the
specific attack
so and finally finally assessing those
ttps and so on would give you ideally
ideally a line of defense on how to
how to prevent those intrusions
okay so i guess that's kind of what i
wanted to conclude with essentially with
this
with these points on how to how to
counteract the biases and so on so thank
you for coming to xivcon thank you very
much for your time