[Music]
welcome to my talk i'm dominic one of
the uh the red teamers from dusek
um so my talk today is
um how i met your
beacons excellent that worked
it i had to get some guy on fiverr to
make that for me
um
so
um so today i'm we'll be more focused on
the blue side really um so i'm going to
be looking at some effective strategies
for detecting beacons on windows um
including detections for behavior
in-memory analysis network interaction
and that kind of stuff
i guess my interest in this topic is
really three-fold and so firstly it's no
secret that we've got some skin in the
game um because we you know produce a
framework ourselves um so i'm interested
in this kind of stuff because obviously
i want to improve our talk
secondly from a red team perspective um
i'm interested in it because i want to
improve my craft and make sure that we
avoid doing certain actions that might
end up kind of leaving dangling iocs
behind
and then finally
um yeah i do get involved with threat
hunting exercises that kind of stuff at
md sex so it is useful for me to have a
good understanding on how to kind of
spot beacons
and i guess i've always been in the
mindset
in order to hide you kind of really need
to understand all the different ways
that you can be found
i'll also kind of demo a tool that i've
been working on that we're going to open
source called beacon hunter which
implements some of the strategies that
i'm going to talk about today
and then we'll look at some real world
examples from some popular c2 frameworks
so
the c2 frameworks that we're going to
focus on is probably going to make gene
sweat a little bit over there
the first one will be cobot strike
i'm sure everybody's you know kind of
familiar with this doesn't really need
any introduction um yeah it's as popular
with red teams as it is with threat
actors
and so having kind of an understanding
on how to detect cobalt strike is really
beneficial for defenders
i guess like one of the great things
about cobalt though
at least from the red team perspective
is that it's it's highly customizable so
and there's a lot of flexibility for the
operator to to kind of mix up how it
behaves and that can make um pinning
down generic detections quite tricky
and so all the analysis that we did was
on cable strike 4.6.1 which is the
latest version
the other c2 framework that we're going
to talk about will be brute retell um
this is another commercial framework
developed by a company called dart
vortex um it's a little bit less popular
but it seems to be growing um in
popularity amongst other actors at least
um unit 42 and dropped a blog post
recently talking about how it was being
abused by apt 29
and then i think maybe last week the
week before i'm so fast dropped a blog
post uh documenting on how the black cat
ransomware group were using it
um
i guess um they kind of like stole some
of my content actually because i wrote
this talk a while ago and then people
started like focusing on it and blogging
about some of the stuff that i'd already
knew about
but hopefully you know a few things will
still be quite unique
um one of the interesting things i guess
about um detections for boot retell is
that the agent is not particularly
customizable so um outside of the c2 you
can't really change how it behaves and
so for example there's no real way to
kind of customize the obfuscate and
sleep strategies um or it's loading
process that kind of stuff so if you
start to build detections for it they
can be quite powerful
um
and then you know i saw this image on uh
on twitter i think it's like vx
underground put it up there and they you
can see they've gone to the effort of
obscuring all this kind of stuff but you
probably can't see it's not too clear
but there's actually an ip address in
there that's not been obfuscated and i
just randomly who is there and it
pointed to moscow so um it kind of gives
you an indication of who might be using
this framework
um
all the analysis that we did was on the
latest version which was one zero seven
as of today
so
let's start from the beginning and look
at how a beacon might actually begin its
life
um firstly there'd be some kind of
loader
that load has probably got an encrypted
copy of the beacon inside it um the
loader then will probably perform some
kind of process injection and maybe to a
remote process maybe in a local thread
um then the shell code will probably
unlock itself and
and
it will then go on to load any
dependencies that required by the beacon
um and then the reflective loader will
be executing the reflective dll will be
executing in memory doing it's all at c2
from a thread
and that's a pretty standard way for a
beacon to kind of initialize itself and
kind of get itself running in memory um
what we're going to look at is um kind
of like through each step of this this
process
oh
what is going on here
through each step of this process
where's my thing yeah for each one of
these steps we're going to look at
basically um different iocs that can
kind of trigger
and where we can build detections around
them
so the first one that i'm going to focus
on is behavior
and i think behavior is quite
interesting
particularly when you look at
commercial products because you can't
necessarily change the behavior if it's
a behavior that is built into the
architecture
okay that's back
having some technical difficulties today
um
so
some good examples of behaviors that we
might be interested in and that could
leave dangling iocs
are things like image loads things like
name pipes they might not necessarily be
customizable by the operator
so
let's look at image loads to start off
with um
i guess so in order for a beacon to kind
of remain small
i'm not gonna change this it's just not
working it's not working great
okay that's better
and so in order for the beacon to remain
small it usually relies on functionality
from the operating system um using dll
dependencies
so for example rather than building your
own http client it kind of makes much
more sense to use something like win
http or win inept
um now when the beacon loads these dlls
we can obviously capture this telemetry
if we're um
you know collecting image load events um
so for example here we can see we're
capturing our notepad loading loading
kernel base um.dll um with sysmol and
event seven
um so image load telemetry is kind of
interesting for us because it gives us
hunting opportunities
um so some of the things that we can
focus on are
um beacon frameworks loading all its
dependencies on at the start
um
we can start to build signatures on that
and if we're hunting for egress beacons
um we can see that they'll typically
load things like win http or when inet
and if we kind of create baselines of um
dll loads from specific processes and we
can look for anomalies so for example if
we saw something like notepad loading
dbg help that would probably be
irregular
um so how do we go about hunting for
these kind of things um well usually
most ddrs have this built into them you
can you can build like hunt rules within
your edr um but for for my examples i'm
just going to use elastic um so if
you're not familiar um with eql it's
basically a sql like language that
elastic provides you
allows you to query the event database
and so in this example all i'm basically
saying is
um
give me all the processes that have
loaded um cred ui.dll win http.dll
within the space of a minute and we can
just pump that into our events database
and find all those processes so let's
look at a real example
so
i took brute retail um and i injected it
into notepad i'm using the built-in pc
and jet command and then i just watched
for dll loads
and as you can see when the reflective
loader executes um it loads all the
dependencies for the dll effect for the
reflective dll
and there's quite a lot of stuff in
there it kind of pretty much loads the
kitchen sync
so and there's some quite unique stuff
that you wouldn't necessarily expect to
see in all processes so for example um
you know we can see cred ui here which
is probably
um wherever it is um it's probably down
to his you know credential prompt
phishing thing tool that he's got built
into the c2
um so what can we do with this um we're
using eql we can trivially um build um
you know signatures to detect brute
retell when it's loading and when it's
injected into beacons
so for example if we took this eql rule
we're basically saying give me all the
processes where cred ui dbg help and win
http are all loaded within the space of
a minute
and as we can see here i just pumped it
into my events database and i was able
to trivially find all the injected
notepad processors
and this is cool because we can use this
um
retrospectively so we can actually hunt
for all injections that have occurred in
our environment over time
assuming we've got the telemetry
so let's look at in memory stuff
so once the beacon is injected it will
typically remain memory resident really
to avoid any undis detections
um the beacon as i mentioned before is
usually injected into memory using a
loader which will like create a thread
or hijack a thread
um and then it will typically be
operating from virtual memory or from a
stomped module um so there's various
kind of like things that we can look at
and for in-memory detections
the first one is probably the most
straightforward and the most simple but
is also possibly one of the most
effective for detecting no malware which
is using previous pre-built signatures
essentially this involves um scanning
memory with a tool something like yara
or through your edr for known signatures
of a beacon these could be like strings
that might be in the reflective dll or
they could be specific op codes from the
text section of the implant
so if you've not played with yara before
it's pretty straightforward um a simple
yar rule probably the most simple url
might look something like this all we're
basically saying is um
scan this process memory um and if you
spot two of these strings that are in
blue this hello and thiefcon 2022. if
you spot two of those um then then tell
me about it
so let's look
at how this might apply to cobalt strike
so
cobblestrike has got some evasion
configurations built into it for
avoiding in-memory detections so the
first one is the
rep malleable config option and this
basically allows the operator to replace
strings that might exist within the
beacon's reflective dll with whatever
they want
um
now i think in-memory detections are
probably a bit of a problem for cobalt
strike at the moment because of its
popularity
and it's gained much more focus from edr
and av companies and so what they did
was in the 4.4 release they basically
introduced a um something called the
sleep mask kit
which effectively allows the operator to
provide their own custom code for
sleeping and obfuscating the beacon in
memory
there's three kind of configurations
that you can go with for this um for
sleep masking obviously there's no sleep
mask um in this kind of scenario the
strings the code that will all remain in
plain text and the beacon can trivially
be picked out of memory through memory
scanning
we can enable sneak the sleep mask with
sleep mask equals true in the marble
profile and so when this is turned on um
basically it will coax right will mask
the beacon in memory and it will use xor
to obfuscate the strings and data
um and but this can still be
fingerprinted because it's basically
using like a pre-built um
a pre-pre-built obfuscate and sleep
strategy
and you can you can build your rules for
it on the uh on the on the actual code
that does the sleeping
and then finally which is probably the
preferred option and you've got the
user-defined sleep mask
and this basically exposes the sleep
mass functionality to the operator
it provides them with pointers to be
conceit memory and it basically allows
you to kind of walk through it and
obfuscate the text section and obfuscate
all the heat records for the beacon
which is pretty cool
so if we look at how this actually works
so using the user-defined sleep mask and
there are a couple of things you need to
be aware of a couple of trade-offs
so notably
if you're operating from
kind of read execute memory only then it
the beacon doesn't actually obfuscate
the text section because it can't write
to it
so um
in essence it's not actually adding
anything
so you can still build your rules for
the text section of the beacon um so you
can see in this example um we've got
like userwx equals false
and we're still able to pick up cobalt
strike um with a url
and that as i said that's basically
because the text section is not
modifiable
if we
if we wanted to obfuscate the text
section
we can do that
but i guess the trade-off is we have to
operate from
read write execute memory um so i think
it's probably a case of you know pick
your poison what do you think is the
bigger ioc
how about brute retell does that fair
any better um
so if we took a look at the
documentation for brute retell
it basically says something along the
lines of it's got a pretty complex sleep
and obfuscate mechanism
it uses a mixture of windows event
creation
weight objects timers in addition to
kind of rock gadgets and apcs
so you would think
it would be pretty complex to detect the
beacon right
um so what we did was uh we injected a
badger as he calls it to
process put the badger to sleep
on quite a high sleep and then just
did a strings dump over the um all the
strings that were in memory
and i was a little bit surprised to see
some stuff like this sitting around
um
so as i said all i did was use process
hacker and don't dump to the strings and
we can see randomly there's things like
ansi ecw patched that kind of stuff i
mean it sounds totally legit
and basically that was because the the
obvious gate and sleep mechanism is only
only protecting the tech section
um
so what i did was i was kind of curious
about how this was working so i wanted
to reverse engineer it um so i threw it
into either and i wanted to kind of
start to build some some more reliable
detections
um
so when i threw it into ida one of the
things that i kind of spotted initially
was um
brute loader that's basically the export
for the entry point for the reflective
dll
and so i searched memory for
the string brute loader and we spotted
it inside the sleeping badger
and so what can we do with this well we
can build a very simple url and to
search for all instances of brute retell
that might be running in any process in
memory
and pluck them out quite trivially
um
but can we take this one step further
and we can so i plugged into virustotal
and we can find all the other samples of
brute retell that are sitting around in
there and pull them down
and have a look what they're doing as
well
and i'll come back to this because
actually what we did was um we wrote a
tool to extract all the configurations
from the artifacts on disk and from the
artifacts in memory and so you can get
all the c2 information all that kind of
stuff
um so kind of moving on from signatures
and what else can we use to spot the
beacon
well once the beacon's up and running
in memory it will typically operate from
as i said virtual memory or from like a
stomp dll
it's operating from virtual memory
there's a few kind of like telltale
indicators
that we can use or we can focus on to
build detections and so perhaps one of
the most obvious things is is the page
permissions as i kind of touched on with
um with cobalt strike already
um so outside of the the clr outside of
clr jits it's pretty irregular to see
executable pages that are not not backed
by a dll
so if we saw something like this where
we've got
the read execute page permission set and
it's not
backed against a physical dll on disk
then it's probably a little bit
suspicious
um so if we can start to hunt for these
um and you know if we kind of maybe
disregard the cll modules for a moment
um you know we can start to build kind
of relatively high signal detections
around them um obviously there are um
there are ways around this um so some
beacons have strategies built into them
within their obfuscate and sleep to
basically modify the page permissions
and so basically when the beacon goes to
sleep it removes the execute bit from
that page
and these strategies they typically
leverage um some form of event driven
execution within its sleep and wake
and when it re-engages execution or use
something like rob gadgets to call um
virtual protect and we set the beacon's
page permissions back to executable
um so there is like some um you know
blog posts out there detailing some of
the techniques that we just that we
discovered and we're using in our
product and one of my colleagues peter
wintersmith
built a technique that uses um windows
timers
and this technique basically works by
cueing a number of timers using queue
time eq
crate timer queue timer
which then when it triggers um ends up
returning to some previously defined
context records which um call empty
continue and end up calling virtual
protect acting like a form of rop to
engage the um execute bit back on the
page
so it might look something like this
where when the beacon's awake and it's
doing its tasking and the um the execute
bit is set on that page
um and then when the beacon goes to
sleep it might be reset back to um we'd
write
so how does this work within cobalt
strike um
the well the page permissions were
always executable in cobalt strike it
doesn't have a strategy to um to remove
them on on sleep um so the page
permissions will typically remain um
read execute or read write execute and
without module stomping um this will
always um
you know run from virtual memory won't
have a dll packed against it so that's
that's pretty straightforward to pick up
brute retail does have um a of the skate
and sleep strategy that modifies the
page permissions so you can see here
it's um read execute and then when the
beacon's asleep it's um it's really
right
um so i was kind of like curious um to
see you know kind of how this works and
one of the interesting things about this
strategy within brute retell is you know
it's kind of cool that it's like
flipping the page permissions because it
does make it harder to set when it's
sleeping
that is unless you've got a badger
linked to peer-to-peer um because
obviously those two need to communicate
so if you've got a pivot enabled within
brute retell um you know all bets are
off it just doesn't encrypt itself and
it remains executable all the time so if
you've got a egress beacon link to
appear to be become
there's no obfuscating sleep um so i was
kind of like curious again at how this
um how this worked
so what i did was um
while i was reversing brute retell um i
had to look at the obfuscate skating
sleep inside either
and
i guess like basically the way it works
is or what it does the first thing it
does is it creates a new thread
and it splits the start address of that
thread to be tp release
clean up group members plus 55 hex
and then once it creates that thread it
sets up a number of context structures
and so these context structures are
basically used to call things like
anti-wave single object to delay
execution um nt virtual memory to change
page permissions system function uh 32
to do rt4 that kind of stuff
and these are basically the different
steps within its um it's encrypt
obfuscate and sleep strategy
and then once it's set up the context
structures it basically queues a bunch
of apcs against nt continue
and these will end up proxying calls um
to those contact structures as i kind of
mentioned
um so by the time i'd kind of like put a
couple of hours into into reversing this
um it kind of like clicked on me um i've
seen this before
um and it basically it's just the um the
open source implementation of foliage
that austin hudson's got on his github
repo
um i like interestingly you know based
on the description about the timers and
all that kind of like stuff that was in
the blog post i was expecting to see a
little bit more but um actually i
couldn't find any imports for any of the
timer apis or anything like that so um
maybe i missed something
um
so moving on um there are other kind of
like in-memory iocs that can can be left
around dangling around
that threat hunters can use to build
detections
um
so these might be deplored by the
operator they might be deployed by the
beacon um so some good examples of these
are um patches like memory hooks um so
things that might be um applied to
things like etw or ramsey i mean maybe
to disabled telemetry or to avoid
scanning from antivirus engines
um so hunting for these can give us a
really high signal um that something
suspicious is going on inside a beacon
um so in this example and these are
taken from um the sliver armory um so
basically patching ecw you can see all
it's doing is finding the address of et
um
etw event right and it's patching it
with the ret
um
and then we've got an amd scan buffer
bypass down here um so if we can
actually hunt for these in processes we
um looking for these patches then we
know that there's something suspicious
going on
um the only kind of like problem with
this of course is that some of those
patches might be reverted so they could
be temporary so for example maybe you've
got like a clr harness that's used to
run an assembly in memory um you might
pack gtw and amse do the post
exploitation um assembly execution and
then remove those patches so um hunting
for the patches alone is not necessarily
the best thing to do
but there are some kind of like dangling
iocs that do get left around
and so the way windows works is it will
back common dlls to physical memory and
these are shared across different
processes on the host now if a beacon
patches
a dll something like
ntdll um in our previous example like
etw and that triggers what's known as a
copy on white operation so that
basically means that that
that process gets its own copy of the
dll
and that page gets marked as private and
when the page gets marked as private um
it basically clears a specific bit known
as the shared bit on that page so what
we can do is we can hunt four processes
and hunt for pages with the shared bit
cleared and then we can resolve all the
exports in those pages and we can get a
good indicator um if something that has
been um has been hooked on the on that
page
so if we took a look at an example of
this from from brook retail and so
brutal's got a shop in line um command
um and
you can see here when we run shop in
line with an assembly um it says on the
console you know patch dtw event right
and patch ramsey and now these patches
are permanent so what i did was um i
just ran sharp in line let it run the
assembly and then i attached when dbg to
the process
and i just um disassembled etw event
right and amazing scan buffer and you
can see even after the assemblies um
finished executing the the function
remains patched so if we're threat
hunting that we can trivially detect
brute retell um based on some of the
post exploitation actions of the
operator when they're running clr
assemblies
by looking for these patches
um
in addition to this um threads can give
us a
a relatively kind of good hunting
opportunity as well
so threads as i kind of mentioned before
will typically um be operating virtual
memory or from from storm dll and there
may be one or more threads depending on
whether the beacon is synchronous or
asynchronous and so looking for
anomalies in these threads um can be
extremely useful to us
um so you can see in this example we've
got uh we've got cobalt strike um um we
could we can tell it's like one of the
kerbal strike threads because it just it
just looks entirely suspicious um so
we've got this kind of like null start
address and then if we look at the call
stack for the thread we can see there's
a bunch of calls to virtual memory
um
but kind of like what else can we look
for um
well
at some point when the beacon goes to
sleep it needs to delay execution it
needs to wait so um if we examine the
call stack of different threads um
and we see um some of the functions that
are typically used to delay execution so
things like sleep x and sleep x ends up
calling the nt api into nt delay
execution
if we hunt for these threads and we
combine them with other iocs like the
virtual memory and then you know that's
a pretty good indicator that this is a
sleeping beacon
obviously there are kind of like ways to
kind of get around this um
you know to kind of mask these
suspicious goals within your call stack
um and it seems to be quite a popular
thing at the moment
so some of the techniques are um
to kind of like spoof the call stack um
there's a few different ways we can do
this and so we can
could truncate the stack and so
basically we end it before some of these
suspicious calls
and this is pretty easy to do and you
can basically
just um set the return address of the
frame that you where you want to end to
null um and that will effectively kind
of match that stack for us or end it
early
another approach might be to actually
clone the context of the legitimate
thread um so we can find a a legitimate
thread that is running in the process
um and then when the beacon goes to
sleep we copy the context of it um and
we overwrite our own context with it and
then we update the tib to make sure that
the tip values match for that thread
that's pretty effective
or another approach this is the one
that's used by kebab strike um is to
switch the thread to a fiber um so when
the beacon goes to sleep it changes it
changes to a fiber and calling crate
fiber x um and that effectively creates
a new stack um so what you actually look
at when you retrieve the stack is is the
stack for the fiber rather than the
thread and it looks a lot less
suspicious because it hides the kind of
calls to virtual memory
so
they might look something like this so
the first one up here is uh is brute
retell
now the the bit stop highlighted um are
the bits that are suspicious so we can
see the start address um of the boot
retail thread is i'm tp release cleanup
group members plus
5550 hex
um now
every brute retell thread gets this as a
start address and this is not a common
start address like i i scanned my host
and i couldn't find any other processes
other than the retail ones that are
using this as a start address i'm not
sure why why this one was picked but it
becomes quite a trivial way to actually
pluck these beacons out of memory
if we looked at the call stack for it we
can see we've got some calls to delay
execution and then at the end we've got
this nt terminate job object now that is
actually just a rop gadget um so if if
you look at this in one dbg you can
actually see it's a rock gadget for
anti-test alert and he basically just
uses it to make the um the the uh to
execute the abcs that are cued on the
thread
um if we look at cobalt strikes um
thread stack spoofing and this is quite
a new thing um it's only actually
available like in the artifact kit um
which was kind of quite surprising so
only the um the dll and the xc artifacts
that you produce
are able to spoof the call stack it
doesn't work for shell code or the
reflective dll
um so if you are i don't know don't know
who uses the the the artifacts but if
you do then you can spoof the call stack
and it might look something like this
and again um
i think that's a i think it still looks
a bit suspicious because i'm not sure
how popular fibers actually are um but
we can we can spot the fiber just by the
call to rtl user fiber start as the um
the first in the first frame in the call
stack
um so like some suspicious indicators um
for stack spoofing um that we can use to
kind of build hunt rules
um so i guess um firstly um at least in
most of the threads that i've looked at
and they tend to have a common start
address so if the start address of the
um
the thread is rtl user thread start uh
sorry it's not rtl user that's start and
the second frame is not base um thread
and it thunk then it's possibly that the
call stack has been truncated in some
way
um in terms of like looking for clone
context and what we can do is recover
the tib for each thread
and
we just look for duplicated values so if
we saw something like um stack base and
stat limit attributes and that
within the tip that i duplicated across
different threads then um that's
probably irregular and it means that
that thread has been spoofed or cloned
in some way
and then finally kind of as i mentioned
it's not not too common to see fibers um
anymore so scanner my own system i
didn't didn't find any examples of them
but basically we could potentially build
um hunt rules looking for um for fibers
so things with thread stacks with the
start address of rtl
use a fiber start
um
so one one kind of approach for avoiding
threads running from virtual memory is
to use module stomping
so this technique basically involves
loading a legitimate module and then we
stomp a copy of the beacon over it um
either over the text section or over the
whole dll itself a thread is then
created that is backed by the module
so we can see in this example um for
cobalt strike we're using like net shell
as um as our stomp dll and then if we
look in the call stack we can see uh
like the thread coming from that shell
so there's a few different like
approaches for detecting module stomping
we've got a few different options um so
firstly the most simple one is probably
comparing the copy of the module that's
in memory with one that's on disk
um
and but i don't think this is
particularly feasible to do at scale
because
it kind of means reading a copy of every
single dll so it can be quite resource
incentive
um another option might be to look at
the modified working set so as i
mentioned before we look we basically
hunt for these copy on right operations
and we can tell tell that that dll has
been modified because it doesn't have
the um the shared bits up
um or we can look for indicators that
might actually be associated with that
specific module stomping technique
so if we look at how cobalt strike
implements its module stomping and we'll
find it does leave some dangling iocs
within the peb
so the way the cobalt strike module
stomping works is
it will
effectively
load a new dll with load library x and
with these arguments so null and do not
resolve dlr references um and that all
that is doing is basically telling the
loader um not to call the entry point
and not to resolve any the import table
for for the dll because we don't want to
load all the dlls dependencies um
so this ends up leaving like um some
iocs in the peb as i kind of mentioned
um so this is there's a structure which
is this ldr data table entry structure
and if we look at that what we'll see is
the entry point attribute will be null
um and the image bit will be set to
false and that will basically is a good
strong indicator that that module has
been stomped using cobalt strikes and
module stumping technique
how about like um kind of moving away
from the endpoint how about um like
network level detections
because if we're actually able to
fingerprint the c2 server then that
might give us sufficient intelligence to
detect beaconing coming from the network
um
so some of the things that we might be
interested in are you know any any kind
of bugs that might be in the the c2
server that might allow us to
fingerprint it so foxit and fox it did
some good research on this a couple
years ago
and they did a census and found a bunch
of kerbal strike servers that were on
the internet based on the response
containing an extra space at the end
um if we can hunt staging uris you know
we can pull down the beacons as well
because they're there in a predictable
format
um or otherwise you know any kind of
like default content that might be
exposed so things like the default
landing page or default ssl certs that
are exposed by the c2 servers we can use
these to hunt for the c2 infrastructure
so let's look at some examples
so cobalt strike um sql strike is um
based on nano httpd
um and nano http is um basically an open
source like java web server um i think
like i think it's built by some
university student
um
now
one of the things that in the fox here
fox city census and they basically
showed that there's probably more cobalt
strike servers on the internet than
there were nano http servers
um so if you do find one of these
there's probably a good chance it's
cobalt
um so let's look at some ways to kind of
fingerprint this so the first one is in
the range header and so if you send a
request with a range header um where
you've got bytes equals and then you've
got an invalid um integer as one of the
values um you get no response back from
the from the team server so you can use
this to kind of like fingerprint for
scan for cobalt strike right so i built
a nuclei template to scan the internet
for this this stuff
and now you might wonder like why do we
get no response um well if we look on
the um the team server the reason we get
no response is because we get an
unhandled exception in the team server
and it crashes the thread
um
so you get something printed like this
which basically says um you know invalid
like number format
um so if we want to dig deeper and see
what's going on here we can jump into
the source code um
and we can see basically what it's doing
when it's processing the range header
is it's trying to convert the string
read from from the header into an
integer and there's no exception
handling around this um so when you send
an invalid um
an invalid integer it ends up throwing
this unhandled exception
um other ways we can fingerprint code
strike again with the range header so um
this is this this ioc is shared with
nano httpd
um but we can figure out whether it's
cobalt strike or nano httpd
um based on the server header because if
you don't expect ies and apache to
behave like this we're turning these
responses so basically if you send a
range
um like back from byte one to zero if
you're asking for the content in byte
one to zero that's a range that the
server can't um facilitate so it ends up
providing this
fixed response of range not satisfied
and so again we can scan the internet
for these and use it to plug out cobalt
strike servers
another fingerprint within the um the
kerbal strike team server is um
is when we send an invalid byte
um so what i spotted this in the source
code and we get this like fixed response
um so if you send um an invalid url
encoded and by so percent zero like
obviously it needs to be two bytes for
it to be to be available um we end up
getting a fixed response back um which
is this uh bad percent encoding so again
we can use this just to scan to scan for
cable stripe
um
how about brute retell um so we can
fingerprint the brutal c2 server um so
if you send a post request um with some
base64 and valid base64 but the base64
does not um
unpack to the c2 traffic um again that
triggles triggers um a unhandled
exception and you get no response back
from the from the team server so again
we can use this to um to scan for retail
servers
now i'm pretty confident people are
scanning for group retail servers
because
i had got a brute retail server um
sitting in aws and then i wasn't
actually using it at the time but i got
a takedown notice from um from amazon
and at first i thought it was like one
of our red team gigs and you know
someone had been busted um and then when
i took a look at the instance id it was
basically the test but retail instance
that we got so i think you know some
internet hero is like scanning the
internet and reporting all the retail
instances
now these are pretty trivial to pick up
with um like showdown so if the default
landing page is exposed um we can
basically just take the hash for it pump
it into showdown uh and find out where
some of these are
and we can see you know
there's a few of them out there like the
majority of them seem to be in the u.s
there's a couple in russia i don't know
what they might be
um
and then i saw this tweet from this guy
and was basically saying you know
russians obviously you know they don't
discriminate against any specific c2
they like to host both cobalt strike
amber at retail on their infrastructure
um so once we found uh once we found one
of these um we found a badger you know
what can we do with it um so as i kind
of mentioned before
we built a little tool to um
scan artifacts um so dlls xes that i've
got brute telling them and extract all
the configuration information um so we
can get the c2 uris we can get the
secrets for the the team server
that kind of stuff um we can also scan
these in memory so you can see i'm just
giving a pid here uh and basically it's
like
like looking for the the badges config
structure in memory and then when it
finds it just prints it out so we can we
can actually extract all these from any
kind of processes too
so i guess you know we put all this
together like what can we do with it
like what was the point of all this
research um well what i did was um i
basically used it to to build a tool and
i called beacon hunter
which i'm going to open source there's
also like a whole bunch of blog posts
then we've got like four or five blog
posts we did look at like other c2s um
but like when i was putting this
together for the presentation i just had
way too much material so i just picked
the two that were probably the most
popular um
but some of the things that the beacon
hunter will currently do
is it will look for things like um it
will analyze call stacks it will look
for um beacons that are running in a map
memory and look for suspicious start
addresses it will um look for suspicious
execute pages um it will detect cobalt
strikes module stomping it will detect
in-memory hooks even if they've been
reverted that kind of stuff
so let me give you a quick demo of this
um now i have cheated and i have
recorded the demo so it cannot go wrong
i've given talks before so you know this
is the the safest way to operate
um okay
so
we're going to start off with brute
retell
so basically i've got brute retell here
i've injected it into notepad and what
we're going to take a look at is now you
might not have seen that but the start
address of this this thread this uh
thread is it was null
and if we took a look at the call stack
for it we can see it's got our way for
single object and so it's just a thread
that's delaying execution
um
and then
if we take a look at the next thread
uh what we can do
i'm just gonna pause that we can tell
this is brutal and i might not
necessarily be clear but the start
address of this one is um tp release
cleanup group members plus um 550x
whereas all the other ones you can see
are 450 hex so that one's 550x so we
know immediately that that one's brick
retail
and then if we took a look at the call
stack for it and we can see as i kind of
mentioned before we've got the um
the calls to delay execution and then at
the end we've got the the rop gadget for
nt tesla to execute the apcs that are
queued on the thread
now what i'm going to do is i'm just
going to run
beacon hunter over this pid
so i'm just going to pause this um so
what we're doing is i'm telling it to um
it supports filters so you can say you
know scan 4 processors that i've got win
http.dll loaded and i'm giving it a pid
just so i don't have to scan all of them
and i'm basically saying um so m is for
memory t is for threads um h
i can't remember p is for page
permissions
um so i'm just going to scan
this brute retail process i'm just going
to pause i think i highlight them um so
some of the stuff that we pick up um or
the beacon hunter picks up is we've got
the suspicious start address and then it
tells us that it's brute retell
because we know it's brute retell
because brutal tell's the only thing
that has that that fixed start address
so we found both of the brute retail
threads um so thread id 102 36 thread od
2900 uh and uh we know that with that
one is group retail as well and we can
see that they're delaying execution
because we've got the call to wait for
single object
um so that's the
first one
i'm gonna have to speed up because he's
telling me well i've got five minutes
um what i'm going to do next is um
to show you how we can detect the memory
hooks um so what i'll do is i'm just
going to run shop in line in boot retell
and just run any old assembly i think i
run seat belt
now if you remember when i was talking i
said that um the in the shop in line
command basically does leave these
dangling ircs so it patches um etw and
it patches amazing scan buffer and it
leaves them sitting in memory
so we're going to run seat belt
and then
if we run beacon hunter over the process
so same thing again same process
um but what we get this time is
um it actually tells us
that um
there's a bunch of hooks that have been
applied now this is not looking for the
op codes on the hooks it's basically
doing it by um looking if the shared bit
has been cleared on those pages and then
it resolves all the exports in those
pages so we don't know exactly which
function has been hooked but all the
exports that are on that page might have
been so we can see it's probably ecw
event right and we can see here on this
page that it's probably the um the
amazing scan buffer
um so again that gives us a good way to
detect these hooks in memory
the next one i'm going to do is um is
cobalt strike
so i've got a couple of beacons here um
both injected into notepad and one of
them is using module stumping and one of
them is running from virtual memory
so i think i'll look at the virtual
memory one first
let's find the pid
so if we took a look at this one here
just pause it for a second
um
we can see that the um basically in this
thread we've got a call in the stack of
the thread we've got a call from virtual
memory and we can see it's calling sleep
x and then nt delay execution so we know
that is um a pretty good candidate for
being a sleeping beacon
so i'll just run our beacon hunter over
this one as well
i did mess up here i gave it the i tried
to cut it out but i gave it the wrong
piece initially um so if we scan it with
um beacon hunter we can see some of the
stuff that's picked up um so it's picked
up the sleeping beacon it's telling me
it's got calls to um sleep x and
anti-delay execution in the stack um
it's basically telling me uh that it's
running from unmapped and unmapped image
um
and we can see the suspicious looking
like start address of null
so again those are pretty good um iocs
to
to flag that something suspicious is
going on in this process
the next one we're going to look at is
uh the module stomped one um so just to
prove it's module stumping um we will
have a look at the call stack for this
one and you can see we're stomping from
uh ww
i know whatever that deal i was
uh and then i'm just going to run beacon
hunter over it again
and what we should see
is um it picks up the same stuff with
the threads but um like down here you
can see it basically says checking for
module stomping and it says found stomp
dll and that is um it's able to detect
cobalt strikes and module stomping
functionality basically down to um the
specific dll that's been stomped because
of those dangling iocs that get left in
the pub
cool all right
where's my mouse
okay not too much more
that that's pretty much it really um but
just a quick thank you to um
some of the other guys from dc
um particularly peter who gave me lots
of advice when like doing some of this
stuff give me some example code and
things to look at um and also uh mod exp
uh who helped me with some of the
reversing the brit retell
there's a bunch of like really good uh
like references i'm here to different
techniques um both for detection and for
building um you know evasion strategies
um which i would kind of like recommend
going and reading
foreign