[Music]
hi
cool so thanks everybody for coming
this talk is called morpheus malware
and yeah my name is sebastian
i'm working as a red team operator at a
company called codewide
we're basically doing all sorts of red
teaming purple teaming
also regular pen tests but we
specialized on red and purple teaming
my main part in the team is the creation
of offensive tools and
probably most importantly the creation
of a custom c2 which we are using in our
assessments
and this talk is about the execution and
the hiding of malware in the
context of another process
we will be taking a look at techniques
which are typically used by adversaries
to avoid detection either by security
products or by analysts which are
manually taking a look at
processes which might be infected
and we will be trying to finger
fingerprint infected processes
simply by looking at the memory
the states of certain threads
and by taking a look at the call stack
of certain threads
i then show you
i will try to give you an idea of how to
avoid being fingerprinted
by blending by blending in with false
positives or by using a bit more
advanced techniques
so two slides of
general talk
why does it actually matter
for us red teams
protecting and hiding our tools
definitely has priority for two reasons
the first reason is that we obviously do
not want to get caught if we get caught
um then the operation is pretty much
ruined we didn't fulfill the goal
the second reason is that custom tooling
is quite complex and also precious
those of you who are developing their
own c2 know that it's a quite painful
task and it might take ages
to to achieve it
um dropping tools on disk is obviously
considered an upset fail
operators
tend to forget their tools on disk which
is a big problem
because security solutions are really
good at analyzing stuff that you ever
put on disk
um but even more important like before
real operators forget what they stored
on disk at some point
the thing with the memory malware is
that it needs a host process otherwise
it wouldn't work
you cannot simply choose any process
that you like notepad.exe for example it
doesn't make any sense why
because usually the process that you're
injecting your tool into
um the behavior of this process should
be as similar as um as possible compared
to the tool that you're injecting
for example it doesn't make any sense to
inject the cobalt beaking into notepad
why because notepad usually doesn't have
any internet connections right
so you will
have to carefully choose the host
process um based on does it make any
internet or internet connections is it
making use of dp api or is it even
probably known to legitimately access
elders
i personally like to target browsers
because they're doing pretty much all of
this
um so and the thing with process
injection is that it's nowadays quite
heavily monitored and this is what this
talk is going to be about so how does it
work basically it works in three steps
the first step being that you kind of
need to open a handle on the process
that you're trying to inject into
a handle basically allows you to perform
certain operations on the process that
you're trying to fiddle with
the second step is then to kind of
somehow inject the payload that you're
trying to execute so you need to write
code into the context of another process
and the last step is that you somehow
need to make the process into which
you're injecting to actually execute the
payload
so once again first step handle creation
um
the most obvious way to do this is to
simply make use of an api call called
open process you specify a pid you
specify a process access mask
and depending on if you have the right x
the right um
permissions on the process that you're
trying to access you will be given a
handle
there are a bunch of problems with this
approach then the first or the big
problem is that
upon process access there's a there's a
kernel callback
meaning that um the kernel is going to
notify every single driver which is
subscribing to this kernel callback
about this process
is actually opening another process with
this access mask
which makes
the creation of a new handle quite easy
to observe for security products because
of this kernel callback
and this is why you have the the swiss
mount event
um which is letting you know that
scratchpad xc is opening node.xc in this
case
a probably better way would be to make
use of a concept called hand duplication
and it basically works as follows the
observation is that there are multiple
processes on windows and there might
even be a process which is already
holding a handle on the process that
you're trying to inject into
uh that means that
everything you need to do is you need to
open the other process which already
holds a handle to the process that
you're trying to inject into
um duplicate or steal this toke this
handle from the other process and then
reuse it in another context like this
you're kind of shifting the problem away
from opening the target process but
you're opening another process
last year i released the tool which is
called handlecads it leverages this
exact technique to obtain a handle to
elsa's and it went pretty well by uh
bypassing a bunch of security products
because there is no process access event
anymore on azure right
um there's a big problem with this
approach however and this approach is
that
there is not always a suitable handle
pre-existing on the system that you
infected so it's not really reliable
what is probably a bit less known is
that existing handles can also be
upgraded this means that you can
basically create a new handle on the
target process with a very limited
access mask which doesn't show your your
real intent
and before you actually use it you
duplicate it once again and when you
duplicate it you say well the duplicated
version of this handle it would be nice
if it had another process another axis
mask
this is really cool because
there is no suspicious process access
event there is only process the
duplication of a pre-existing handle
with another access mask
this is quite cool because there is
there are kernel callbacks for handle
duplication but system for example is
not
subscribing to this
kernel callback you can still observe
observe this
in the windows security lock
but the problem with this is that it
must actually be configured per process
and it's not enabled by default so i
really like to go with this approach in
order to get a handle to another process
the thing is that obtaining a handle was
only the first step right i showed you
three steps that we need to need to do
um the first step was actually not that
difficult
um the real problem starts we need to we
now need to use our newly created handle
in order to inject the payload into
another process how do we do this and
the problem with this is that there are
a bunch of
security
techniques um trying to make your life
more difficult so for example you guys
might have heard of a concept called
user land hooks there are even more
kernel callbacks and there's also event
tracing for windows
um
let us first talk about a bit about user
land hooks and system calls
this is a quite old concept and it's
being widely used and exploited in the
security scene but for those of you who
might have never heard of are two slides
of
of theory
um the thing is that antivirus really
like to redirect the execution flow of
suspicious api calls
they do so so that they understand when
a certain api call was used by a process
and with which parameters it was used
um they do so because
they
do not really have any other chance to
understand when a certain api call is
used
there are not there's not a kernel
callback for every single system call
this this used to be true we will later
get
to how it is nowadays
and the thing is that system calls which
are usually used for process injection
are obviously hooked because the
antivirus product is quite interested in
why this api is actually used and how it
is used
so basically
basically um if you're making use of if
you're trying to
create a remote thread the mower is
going to
go through the abstraction layer in the
kernel 32 dll which is then calling um
something in the entity dll and the
entity is then going to perform the
system call for you
yeah
um
if there's a user lent hook in place
the first steps are similar you still go
through kernel dll you you then go to
entity layer
and last but not least you end up in the
antivirus dll which is then doing
some analysis for you
there are some obvious ways to bypass
user networks and they are i don't know
they are a hundred thousand ways
probably um the most obvious way to
bypass this is uh to directly conduct
the system call and this is doable by
simply
embedding the code uh snippets of the
ntdl into your own malware
and then
um doing
letting your moorway actually do with
the
the system call for you which directly
which effectively bypasses current32
ntdl and the other antivirus data
however
i mean it does bypass user lane hooks
but there are some very obvious problems
with this approach
the obvious problem is that all system
calls should go through anti-dll
if any other module then ntdl is doing a
system call then this is quite
suspicious because this should actually
never be the case
and
if we take a look at sysmon
in the first in the upper screenshot we
see the usage of the windows api and we
see that the last module in the call
trace is actually ntdla but if we make
use of direct system calls uh here i use
the tool by by outflank uh hello
we see that the last module in the call
trace is actually not anti-dll but it's
outflanked dumped which is a
big indicator of compromise i'm assuming
um the problem however is that yes you
can sometimes observe direct system
calls using sysmon
but there are not kernel callbacks for
every single single system called there
is there's one for anti-open process but
there are way more
system calls you guys might be
interested in
um
and since there is no kernel callback
for every single system call you might
want to use an additional framework
um and an additional framework which you
might be leveraging is called novana
which is an instrumentation engine used
by microsoft it's present in windows
since vista
it's a quite complicated thing and i'm
not going to get into too many details
here but it can actually be used to
monitor and control user-made processes
without recompiling the target
more importantly it even allows us to
define callbacks for system calls upon
return from kernel mode
and what that means is that we can
basically specify if
a system call returns from kernel mode
um it should
before it continues execution in user
mode
it should execute our user specified
callback
and this actually allows us to hook
basically every single system call
and perform some additional code before
it transitions back to user mode
more importantly it allows us to check
where the system call is returning in
user mode if it's not returning to
somewhere in ntdl then this is obviously
an ioc
and there's a really cool sample
implementation by wind turner and if we
make use of
this implementation
again against outflank dumper
the
implementation by internal i call i
think it's called syscall detect is
immediately complaining that
the kernel returns to an unverified
module and it's going to
to exit
so this can actually potentially be used
by security products in order to
identify direct system calls uh it's
just that the performance overhead might
actually be a big issue here
um so okay so what can we do against
this um obviously we need to make sure
that our system calls go through ntdl
and bypass user land hooks at the same
time
and the cool observation is that an
enterprise product does of course not
hook every single system call there is
otherwise it would also run into
performance problems
it only hooks those system calls it's
actually interested in
um this leaves us to the observation or
this brings us to the observation that
some system call stops are simply not
hooked because
the api calls are simply not interesting
enough
um yet all system coil stops do pretty
much the same thing but they use a
different system call number so
basically they move the system call
number to eax and then perform the
system call by syscall red
what can we do um the idea could be to
first resolve the system call number um
by using a technique called taylorsgate
which is by sector seven and then we
initialize the system call manually and
then we reuse uh existing syscall web
instructions from a clean system call
stop in order to perform the system call
so we basically jump um to a very
certain
location of a clean system called stop
which is the system called retrospection
we basically we use these instructions
from a clean system crosstab
so
i'm a paint master
we first set up the vegas
then we kind of reuse the stub once
again meaning that we choose a clean
system called stub which is not hooked
and then we use the system callback
instructions from there which
effectively bypasses the user land hooks
and we're going through entity delay at
the same time
i wrote a small implementation for this
you can find it on my github and if i
make use of this
and i let i use the syscall detect tool
at the same time it's not complaining
why is it not complaining because the
system calls they all returned to ncdl
um
and
you see on
in this month the last module in the
call stack is anti-dla
there are still some iucs though um
because usually system calls go through
kernel-based dll and then to anti-dla
this is the first ic
the second ioc is that yeah the system
call returns to ntdl but it does not
return to the correct step which is
associated with the executed system call
and by leveraging hooking nirvana this
might be an idea in order to leverage
this
cool so
user land hooks are still a thing in
2022 actually and i was quite surprised
about this um because i thought it's
like a relic from the past but that's
not the case many antivirus security
products still rely heavily on them and
the question is why
the first reason is that monitoring from
kernel only can cause stability issues
because if you
up your kernel driver then your
client won't be protected but have a
blue screen
and the second problem was this is not
the case anymore but it was that
missing telemetry because there was no
other no no other way for an antivirus
to understand
if and how a certain api call was used
so it was used kind of a patch to under
to get to get more telemetry
what matters from the attacker's
perspective is basically that user and
hooks
are not a problem they can always be
efficiently and stealthy bypass and
github is full of user into bypassing
techniques
cool so now we should be able to conduct
memory operations on the remote process
with the handle we gained earlier in a
very stealth way so we should be able to
inject our payload using every single
api call we want
is that true and the thing is we still
need to keep some some effects in mind
because some system calls trigger a
kernel callback as i was saying before
and others can actually be observed by
etw because there's a etw provider which
many security solutions have begun
subscribing on
and it's called the microsoft windows
web intelligence
dtw provider the provider sits in
kernels so there's not a lot you can do
against this from user mode
and
for us it's kind of a problem because um
it delivers uh events for everything
that might be used for process injection
you know apc's suspending threats
resuming that and so on and so on
um so it should provide enough telemetry
in order to observe typical process
injection techniques and there are a
bunch of device
event action types you can use
um
i tried to write rules for this
for for a client for a very big client
in a purple teaming assessment
and
yeah
you can see the process injection it's
just that these api calls are often are
so often used in a legitimate context
that it's almost impossible to write a
working detection for this without
having any first positives
so what actually matters in my in my
opinion is which process and injects
into which other process and more
importantly what is actually being
ejected if you inject a plain cobalt
stock beaking into another process in
the most stealth way it will still be it
will still be picked up simply because
it's cobia strike so our next problem is
actually static signatures and we need
to think about how to avoid static
signatures
or evade static signatures
um okay once again we successfully
injected our payload into the target
process and obviously now uh jaga rules
are applied by security products in
order to identify if it is something
they already know and there might be
ways to bypass this some are better than
others but let us take a look at this um
the first concept is called polymorphism
it's a very old concept what you're
doing is basically you encrypt your
payload and you glue it together with a
decryption step uh the decryption slab
decrypts the payload and then actually
executes it cool um so here we have a
hello world.pin which basically pops up
the message box and we remember it
starts with ascii vh something something
if we if you put it into executable
memory
it pops the message box and we see the
vh something something in an executable
memory page cool
now if we make use of the category which
is a polymorph encoder we see that yeah
it looks really different it doesn't
start with vh and there's no vh
something something anymore because it's
encrypted
but what happens if we actually actually
execute it in memory we see that the
first bytes are different but at some
point uh our vh something something pops
up once again
and we wanted to avoid this wasn't it
um so there are a bunch of problems with
polymorphism
first it needs rwx which is an indicator
as such second thing the decryption step
as such can be fingerprinted and after
decryption your malware or your tool or
whatever is not protected in plain
memory so it might help to bypass the
initial memory scan but
uh at some point if memory scan happens
like i don't know 20 minutes later your
codes are peaking or whatever is going
to be playing the memory
copy strike makes use of or tackles this
problem with a concept called sleep mask
it was introduced in version four the
three is wrong it's four or something
and the core idea is actually quite
simple
the observation is that a beacon
basically spends most of the time
sleeping and waiting for new commands so
what you can do is while sleeping
sleeping the beaking actually obvious
skates and encrypts itself in memory
while it is sleeping
and you must be quite unlucky if um the
memory scanner hits you right in the in
the situation where your beacon is
active because usually a beacon is
active only for i don't know a fraction
of a second or something like that
there are some limitations with this
however because the first limitation
might be that the sleep mask itself can
be fingerprinted you can customize this
in cobblestock and we also have other
memory artifacts which we will which we
will take a look at later i however like
to use another concept
and the idea is to change the appearance
of a program on instruction level
if we change the appearance of a program
on instruction level uh we do not need
any encoding or encryption or whatever
and we do also not need any rwx because
we're not encrypting anything
there might be ways to achieve this
one way to achieve this is to substitute
instructions with a sequence of
instructions
which lead to the same result yet these
are other instructions what you got what
you could also be doing is add useless
instructions or add trash and jump over
the trash or you shuffle the basic
blocks or whatever
the terminology for this is quite
unclear for me if you google this some
actually call it a variant of
polymorphism other called metamorphism
in this talk we call it keyless
polymorphism
so some ideas for substitutions if you
want to null out a register either you
can write xor i i x or you move 0 to i x
or you store another register on the
stack
null out this register move this
register to ix and then restore this
register
if you want to jump to rcx you could
also write push rcx and then return
where push rcx could also be written
like this so there are a bunch of ideas
or
instructions which can be substituted
with an equivalent of other instructions
by adding trash as i said basically you
add complete trash bytes or instructions
which don't make any sense at all and
you add a jump over the trash
and however you do it in the end of the
day
so on the left side we see our actual
program
which is not
obfuscated or whatever and on the right
side we see that the first instruction
was substituted with another instruction
second one is also substituted then we
have a jump over the trash then probably
an instruction which could not be
substituted and last but not least
another substitution
i really like to leverage this technique
to protect my tools from automated
memory scanners and it's quite powerful
if enough instructions are substituted
you obviously need the source code for
this because otherwise you would be
breaking relative gems
and if you consider this to be a problem
it makes your payload obviously
significantly larger
um also you need to take into
consideration that strings and constants
need to be encrypted and obfuscated
additionally because this is not part of
the polymorph process
i'm doing this by hand it's really
really annoying and you should automate
this i'll get i will later get back to
how to automate this
cool so once again we remember our vh
something something shellcode
it pops a message box
and here if we use this keyless
polymorph concept we see that it
actually doesn't start with vh anymore
actually you don't find these constants
anymore
in an executable memory page
yet the method box still pops up if
there's someone really uh
careful you see that this is actually in
an rwx page i earlier said you don't
need rwx it's because i forgot to change
the page permissions
um
cool so now we gained a handle in a very
stealthy way uh we defended user land
hooks while still we go
through ntdl and we defeated scanners
using some kind of polymorphism
the problem now is that in fact the
processes leave a lot of other iocs so
even if you managed to infect a process
that you wanted to infect you still have
a lot of other iocs
let us take a look look at suspicious
artifacts
to understand this some
some basics windows roughly has three
types of memory there's private
committed memory which is reserved for
heap and stack there's map memory which
is used for file mapping and ipc and
there's also image committed memory
which is basically used by pe files and
executable executables
and the thing is that usually only um
image-committed memory should be marked
as executable
um there are some false positives or
some some exceptions for example managed
code like c-sharp because it's a
bytecode which is compiled interpreted
at
runtime but as we see on the screenshot
actually only or normally only image
converted memory should be marked as
executable
and this
gives us a big problem because
somehow we need to gain
executable memory uh while injecting
into remote process and the problem is
how do we actually get or we execute a
memory in a remote process
and there are a bunch of memory scanners
which are really really good at
finding
memories or abnormal memory allocations
the one by monitor is
really popular and they're really good
at detecting optimal memory allocations
so for example if you make use of
virtual alloc or anti-map view of
section or whatever
monitor is quickly complaining about hey
there are two
pages which are marked as executable yet
they are marked as private commit what
the is this that doesn't make any
sense
the next next try could be to make use
of dll hollowing where we load an unused
dll into the remote process and then
replace the text segment
with our own code
problem monitor is complaining again why
for two reasons first monitor is asking
why did this process load this dll it's
not declared in the peb or anywhere why
did it decide to load this dlr second
problem
the text segment of the dll on disk is
not the same as the text segment of the
dll in memory it's also a big problem
for monitor
and
there are a bunch of ways to bypass
memory scanners
and they basically all boil down to
changing the page permission of the
beacon
while it's actually sleeping
because memory scanners only check for
executable memory regions in order to
find known better
this leaves us this brings us a big
problem because how do you mark your own
code as not executable while you're
executing this should not actually
happen this note should not work
but it does work with a bit of black
magic and i like to you leverage a
concept used by exploit coders which is
called return origami programming
which leverages stack pivoting and
existing small code snippets
from any ntdl or other executable memory
which is there legitimately
so the idea is before the beacon goes to
sleep uh we set up a robbed chain which
first calls virtual protect marking our
beacon as not executable then it drops
itself to sleep and then it robs itself
again to page execute read
this is
nothing new as such um the original idea
was called gargoyle i'm assuming it was
first implemented by f-secure but i'm
not sure about this
um
and the core idea here is that before we
go to sleep we set up the stack and we
set up the stack as follows
the first return address on the stack
points to a gadget which sets up the
registers
or which pop which pops
the other values on the stack in a
certain way and in such a way that on
the next return when woodward protect
happens um the address of the beacon is
not marked or the page of the beating is
not marked as executable anymore so upon
the next return our beacon looks like
this it's not executed anymore and the
stack looks like this and now the first
gadget on the stack points to a pop rc
uh gadget which effectively puts the
5000 on the stack um
to rcx which is the first parameter for
sleep and then it pops the return
address of sleep and goes to sleep for
5000 milliseconds now the beacon is not
executable and it's sleeping at the same
time
and
when the beacon returns obviously it
takes the first return address from the
stack
again
setting up the registers for virtual
protect which then upon returning
makes or beacon resuming
i released the
small proof of concept for this which i
call deep sleep it's also on my github
while it is active it's actually popping
a message box and monitor complains why
because there is private executable
memory or something
um
but while sleeping we see that the page
of deep sleep is actually marked as not
available or execute
read only yeah we'd only make sense
so we bypass memory scanners looking for
executable memory
there are a bunch of other
implementations
they all boil down once again to the to
the same idea which is changing the page
permissions while sleeping
um there's one by a cracked spider
there's one by sec idiot called foliage
um yeah but they are all pretty much
boiled down to the same idea
now the question is actually this was
quite complicated and the question is is
that actually necessary and i would say
no because if you run moneta on firefox
for example you see a bunch of forced
positives once again so you also see in
firefox there's that there is a bunch of
private and executive memory and it even
modified it on its own dla its own entry
dla
so i believe that memory artifacts alone
are quite good first indicator
but they have way way too many false
positives
for example why did firefox change its
own anti-dll it's because it likes to
hook its own create thread as a matter
of an anti-exploit mechanism
memory scanners can also be bypassed
using gargoyle-like techniques and so
the problem is that we definitely more
need more metrics in order to identify
infected processes
once again the um observation is that we
can spend most of the time waiting for
new commands
and what developers really like to do
to make the beating sleep is to simply
call sleep this is really obvious right
but there's a big problem with sleep and
the problem with this api call is that
it sets this threat which is calling
sleep to a very special state it's
called anti it's called delay execution
and on my machine i had 1 500 threats
out of these 1 500 threats and only 20
were in the state delay execution so we
boil down from 1 500 to 20 threads which
might be a beacon
20 are still too many to check so we
need another metric
the net next metric could be a call
stack on the left side we see a normal
call stack we see that that it starts
somewhere in user thread start
and it can map every return address on
the stack to a
to a module on disk
on the right side we see the one of the
cobblestock beacon and we see that it
does not start where it's supposed to
start and at the same time there is this
hex 1a
what is this this cannot be associated
with a file on this because this is
quite abnormal
and if you take a look at the
implementation of gargoyle also of the
deep sleep thing um the call stack looks
even more broken because there are a
bunch of pointers which cannot be mapped
to a file on disk and it looks like
virtual protect is calling sleep if you
show me a developer who does this
legitimately i want to talk to him
um
so yeah call stacks are also a thing and
now the question is out of the 1500
threads i have on my machine how many of
these are in delay execution and have a
stack trace to delay execution which
contains unknown or tempered regions the
answer is only one and it's a beacon
so also for this i created a small tool
to automate these steps it's called hans
sleeping beacons and it first enumerates
threads which are in delay execution and
then it checks the call stack for
unknown regions and also for
text segments which
do differ
compared from the
in memory compared to the version on
disk
yeah it picks up deep sleep because
um
this the threat is called is in delay
execution and the stack is really really
broken
i had some false positives with this
approach um i had positive false
positives with updaters which are trying
to protect itself because they're
actually behaving like a beacon you know
they're also trying to obfuscate
themselves in memory because you don't
they don't want you to reverse it
at the same time they're also sleeping
between their intervals
um
and i also had some false positives with
very crappy c-sharp applications
there are some other very easy bypasses
for hand sleeping beacons the first idea
could be to simply spoof the call stack
which is actually not very easy if you
want to do it correctly
but the more easy way would even be to
simply don't use sleep to weight between
your callbacks you can also make use of
weightable timers in order to have a bit
of delay
this then sets the thread in a state
called weight user request which is way
more common than delay execution
cool so call stacks definitely leave
significant iocs and this does not only
apply to end delay execution but it also
applies to other system calls
memory scanners can actually fully be
bypassed using gargoyle or gargoyle-like
techniques
and the
c2 coders should definitely avoid using
sleep
internally from ic2 i use a modified
version of deep sleep which is using
weightable timers
cool um this is almost the end of my
presentation um i have some tools to
release
uh because earlier we were talking about
keyless polymorphism i created a tool to
automate the step which i call spider
pick
um and it actually
does the objection on assembly level so
what you do is
um you first compile it using gcc or
whatever
to
and you make the compiler output
assembly then you make
that spider pic do its job it's doing
the obfuscation and then you compile it
just as normal
and in order to show how greatly this
actually works we're also releasing a
sox proxy which is implemented as
position independent code the client
makes user web sockets and is
implemented as pic and the spyder pick
is integrated into makefile so it looks
differently every single time you
compile
the
the client version the backend is
written by my colleague and good friend
christian
and yeah you can find it on our github
so
if every time you compile lessons you
see that the fuzzy hash is completely
different
yet
they are all the same program
you can find it here on our github i
think my boss clicked on release right
now
and you simply type make to build it
okay that's it