[Music]
thank you
how the are you disobey
oh man it's been a rough two days uh
I've had fun have you had fun
for Real uh well that's brilliant I have
some thoughts though
just a few I won't bore you with too
much ranting and rambling but
this year we've had mental health as one
of our spearhead topics
had a really courageous moment very
warnable moment on stage and I think
that deserves a special mention at this
point
it's it's incredible that we can have
this
sessions that we can have these talks
that we can have this community uh where
this is possible where people feel safe
on stage to share something so personal
with a huge amount of people
I I was moved I hope some of you were
moved
we've had a lot of technical talks we
had visitors from other
countries we've had amazing connections
we met friends
people we haven't seen for a really long
time
and
I'm I'm getting emotional thinking about
it twice we had to cancel
twice we were this close to being here
again
but now we are and it's coming to an end
and I almost kinda don't want it to but
I also have really tired feet and I kind
of get around and get my
toes in the sand right
so
I hope you feel a sense of
belonging a sense of accomplishment a
sense of
finding your people
as uh closely as I do
if not then let's drink some more and
maybe we will become better friends
some statistics from this year
1714 participants
that's a new record for us
228 CTF players that's also a new record
for us
[Applause]
57 Flags in the CTF now how many of you
here participated in the CTF
that's so amazing to see I applaud you
brilliant
many many many minutes of talks many
many minutes of workshops
a lot of hacking a lot of lock picking
a lot of laughs
we have
as usual
some awards that we want to give out
this year
we're gonna start with handing out uh
the stealthiest solve
from the Elisa and varzilla
OT Village
I want to welcome to Stage uh Elisa
people I'm gonna jump off because this
stage is too small for all of us
gonna grab my beer okay greetings
everybody uh greeting from upstairs so
we have a privilege of hosting the
OT delays challenge together with
varachilla so I would say it has been
quite a success a lot of attendees a lot
of happy people trying out their skills
uh
if you try to attend it you might know
that the end goal was to basically print
out the batch that gives you access
behind the closed doors on your way
there you might have maybe set off a
fire alarm on a factory level uh maybe
misuse the robotic arm to kill a Barbie
doll somebody might have made it happen
but uh
kind of like the special Source 47 was
that we had a pool demo also from LS
side trying to see how what the hawk is
doing and and how stealthy they might be
and we had interesting learning and and
so we wanna give a a small price to the
one particular team that from our
perspective uh
beat the things right so what go what
was the end result
the end result was it was amazing
obviously it wasn't the fastest team
that did the challenge
but it was indeed this stealthiest and
um
they did things in a way that based on
running on memory so
they left
very minimal tracks for us to monitor
and if um
the automation wasn't able to track them
and the sock should have done manual
operations in order to just basically
stop them
so um
as Ben said
me as well my feet are very sore at the
moment so um we would like to hand this
price over to the team that is called
Sask 69.
[Applause]
thank you congratulations thank you
congrats thank you
how did you do it how did you do it
laughs
so
um yeah we started enumerating the
machines
but we try not to use so much like these
automatic tools because we knew that
this will be like very noisy
um
after some point we start to do maybe to
try
we noticed that there were some specific
uh oh it's called extension using the in
application and we start to do some very
like easier or maybe common uh buff and
we got the first flag
then the next ones require a little less
noise in general so
I don't know okay we just I mean we just
went with a flow with a bit of our noise
yeah yeah so
yeah I think nothing really fancier
particular we just yep
is a bit of our knowledge but nothing
super special for you
excellent hey uh kudos to Sask 69 and as
a final remarks upstairs we still have
beer welcome
[Applause]
okay uh so one down one to go nixo also
had a scavenger hunt
now I'm not 100 sure where the
here
guys are uh this year they actually
asked for permission last year
they had me uh and because no in 2020 uh
they had me amiko hupman and as part of
the scavenger hunt without asking our
permission which was a lot more in line
with the spirit of the event to be
honest
a lot more fun so I kind of feel like
you dropped the ball on that one I'm
sorry but you kind of did
I don't know where the uh
yeah I don't know where the Elisa guys
went with the mic but that's what
happens
maybe they're really trying to get
people to drink their beer
cool okay
all right thanks Benjamin
uh hey good evening all of you uh yeah
we are uh Kim and James uh
[Music]
um yeah this year we we came with the
big bang and and uh for those who who
was here I want to let you know that
nobody was physically hurt so all all
good on that side
[Applause]
um yeah we had the honor to be the
judges of the traditional scavenger hunt
this year and and for those who don't
know what it is please
thank you very much I don't know if I'm
Matthew pepper but I think I'll do it so
for the ones who don't know what
scavenger hunt is we we had
this competition uh the main point is to
do this task they might be funny and and
sometimes even a bit embarrassing you
collect points and and compete each
against the charger as teams
uh just a couple ones of the task where
like uh get a selfie with Benjamin we
did ask permission and bennyman's
comment was that it would have been
funnier if we wouldn't have done that uh
one was make a human pyramid and post it
on on social media and uh do some kind
of singing and dancing and and be
embarrassing basically
yeah and the price of course is um what
every Finn appreciates
um plastic bucket
um yep
we want to thank all the participants it
was really fun fun being a judge we were
a lot bribed as well
um
but there can be only one winner and um
this year's winner is this was your
winner is give a big hand to team Europe
ish please come up on stage
[Applause]
and when you are climbing here we want
to thank the sponsors of this year which
is Red Bull and papa miss and
well please do the honors
a big hand young guys
[Applause]
what
and the big prize
and before we let you go
I really want to want you to know that
uh this team went all in and not only
doing funny games but also collecting
the first prize of Nexus ETF so a big
hunt for that as well
[Applause]
thank you very much see you at the beach
so
that was the sponsored part of the
presentation done
now let's get back to our regularly
scheduled programming
uh the community aspect
so
we have some really fun Awards in this
event one of them is the unauthorized
access award it works as following
you need to a not have a valid entry to
the event a bought ticket
two you need to find me inside the event
three you need to avoid everyone else
who is trying to throw you out
if you manage to accomplish those three
Feats you win a badge and a bracelet
so
this year we had a winner uh
we also had some
happy participants
the winner is our very own this
[Applause]
are you still here software
no
yeah but
but I want to give kudos to Christina
are you somewhere
[Applause]
she found me uh without using her
bracelet and badge but because there was
no risk I can't award her the win
the same is true for energy are you here
somewhere
now he's probably left and a special
mansion
to T2 or Tommy tubing and
who managed to get inside the event five
minutes before the opening of The Doors
dressed as a vault delivery person
requiring a signature from The Av team
because he was delivering medicine
now if that isn't social engineering
just for shits and giggles I don't know
what is
on top of it he actually bought a
support pass which is the ticket price
uh which this event could cost without
sponsors so big up to T2 I really
appreciate the selfie it was an amazing
start to the event
and we found this as well
[Laughter]
[Applause]
for
I guess you could call it the main
competition the main challenge or the
main event
the capture the flag
now
as always this is what we really want to
do well which we really hope you've
enjoyed this year as well
and in reverse order let's start with
the Bronze award I would like to
ask for the prices to be brought out
no
so
have a wonderful third place winner
burning cops
[Applause]
hello hello
congratulations
at least this will help us stay afloat
and I mean yeah thank you and
we really enjoyed the competition I I'd
say that the flags were really fun this
year there were a lot of different
things to figure out and
yeah anyone else want to say something
apparently let's hack the planet
[Applause]
so
for those of you confused about our
prize policy there's usually one
criteria it can't fit
carry on baggage on an airplane
our silver team
again
I would ask for the prices to be brought
out
[Music]
[Applause]
the silver price winner
this year is
two of them four Ops
[Applause]
well this this is quite unexpected by
all of us
there you are
um yeah
um
this is
oh thank you uh it was very fun
um this was my first time in like a live
CTF event so this was extra surprising
now
um but yeah uh thank you to everyone who
made Flags thank you to all the other
teams especially
um
whose competition Spirits kept us going
even when we had no idea what to do
anymore
um anything else we want to say
is the best city in Finland
[Applause]
and let them move back
all right
whoa
it's my first beer
in an hour
[Applause]
I hope these aren't too expensive uh
gold
I would again ask my wonderful
assistance
to bring out the first prize first place
price for the capture the flag
competition for disobey 2023
give a big hand for makeup
or delic
[Music]
ate
[Applause]
[Music]
congratulations
team Europe is
[Applause]
now even your mom can fit on one of
these
I guess
thank you thank you everybody thank you
thank you team Europe ish and thank you
for the flux they were great fun and I
think the real uh capture TF was the
friends we made along the way
we like as a team I I still don't know
your name I guess like we've we've met
today like yesterday for the first time
so it was nice to meet you
foreign
come on you can make a bit more noise
they're the winners
[Applause]
all right so
on top of
these aforementioned competitions
we also have something called the badge
challenge
all of you have it around your neck all
of you could get started on it
since 2017
this challenge has not been solved
there has not been a winner presented
this challenge takes place in the
fictional city of coaster
in the fictional nation of coeostalita
is a state where
we see police brutality
overreaching governmental
insight and spying
corruption on the highest levels
and a telecom provider that provides
Concrete service
this year
in the badge challenge
we had
4032 transactions now unfortunately for
the central bank
of call hostelito they had made a small
problem by buying their banking software
from the
bidder with the lowest price
they also forgot
to do input validation which led to
a overdraft
or a possibility for anybody who sent a
negative amount of money to another
account of actually getting that same
amount of money into their own account
now it seems
our friends at kuha
the call was the underground hacking
Alliance
took some liberties with this
vulnerability
and managed to well
completely tank the entire economy of
goldostalita
because they are now minus uh let's see
if I can read this right one trillion
billion 800 wide not one million 1011
416 coaster box in that
I think they need financial regulation
the highest amount of money any one
account
well most of it was stolen by one
has almost the same number
the account with the most transactions
uh has 1553 and
they are some of you figured out that
there was a leak Market where you could
buy hints to the puzzle you could do
well purchases on the system
1268 of you actually created an account
whether or not you realized it by
initializing your card at the automated
ATM machines
and 17 of you
got burned you were caught by the
co-host or intelligence agency
I needed to re-initialize your batch
this year
we actually do have a winner
[Applause]
again I would like
for tapio to bring out
the award
[Applause]
may I please have to the stage for the
first time
in six years
the winner of the disobey badge
challenge
competition is that tautologists
[Applause]
so thank you very much I I want to say
that I really enjoy the batch challenge
this is I guess this is mostly the third
time we participate this the first time
was
2018. this year and that was the year I
first time attended the diesel Bay and
the batch challenge really challenged us
and I still remember and it still does
what it does it did then it makes you
socialize with other people it makes you
to walk around talk to people you do not
know but you share something common you
shared uh to say the
you want to challenge yourself and you
want to solve the patch Challenge and it
really makes me tick so thank you thank
you for the organizations and the badge
challenge creators very much this really
was a joy
[Applause]
on behalf of the CTF organizing team
I would like to thank from the bottom of
a heart all the participants of the CTF
all the people who gave to the community
by providing challenges and getting
people to learn new things
you can give back to the community and
teach people stuff without standing here
I want to thank all the participants all
the people who brought challenges I love
you all
so
as we usually do as this at this part of
the show I would humbly ask every single
volunteer to join me not on stage but at
the proximity of the stage
I couldn't do well we can try to fit on
the stage I suppose I couldn't do any of
this without any of you this is a group
effort
yeah let's try to get as many on the
stage as possible this will be
impossible very quickly
these people deserve your thanks
they make this happen
[Applause]
all right
so thank you from the bottom of our
hearts this isn't any one person this is
all of us from all of us to all of you
thank you disobey loves you see you next
year there's an after party at BTC where
you can get your feet in the sand the
joke is to put the hackers in the
sandbox so
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you so much