hello everyone and yeah today we're
talking about something that a lot of
people don't really like to talk about
um when you up
so today uh the topic is we up
and we broke the internet well for some
people for a while
uh briefly to tell you who they are uh
We've with doing networking since a
couple of years we started
more than a decade ago we've moved to
Finland in the pandemic we're now a
Finnish company
and we speak a lot of languages
and
um yeah so we run the network we run an
ISP Network across Europe we are with
our team across Europe so all of those
locations have data center connectivity
backbone connectivity
so we do routing we run our own network
since 2014 we have become earlier
Lear means a local internet Rich history
it means that you're part of one of the
five global
Registries be that right
we started with hey we want our own IP
space we want our own routing let's put
some servers there let's have our own
little stuff it was fun them people came
like hey can you put that server online
she was like hmm actually I would like
to have my internet in my office from
myself as well so of course we started
doing a bit of DSL
and then it's like um
now I have to buy all this capacity we
had to pay like
a couple hundred couple thousands of
bucks just for a couple of uh gigabits
of Transit
we should sell the Trotters it's going
to be cheaper so we started providing IP
Transit
and eventually this went into something
called sponsorships when uh students and
other organizations want to do some
research be that for example small ID
company that's like hey we also need our
lab equipment
and when we have our own lab equipment
we might not want to have that on the
production Network so they come to us
yeah someone clicked the link
congratulations
so
um back to the sponsorships so again
we're trying to educate people so if
anyone in this room has ever wanted to
do some bgp some background running come
to us
we do this resource sponging you can get
IPv6 based from us you can get an ASN
from us we normally only give you as
32-bit ASN because 16 bit is ends are in
limited Supply
and we have a lot of them not not many
it's it's hundreds it exploded when
Hurricane Electric one of the most
predominant uh providers in this field
which gives out free resources and free
Transit as we say I don't know we don't
do tunnels anymore so we picked up quite
a bit of like
quite a bit of of organization
so an asset what's an as set when you
run a network when you run a vgp network
you have routes that you announced to
other networks
a stop net is what you know a subnet is
a route in backbone terminology that
route belongs to a so-called out num and
a uh in ASN
in common terms
when you're an upstream provider so
you're a trendy provider
you want to filter that your customer
doesn't announce it to you because it's
not 2005 anymore we're Pakistan Telecom
I think did one of the most famous route
leaks when they were like hmm we want to
block access to YouTube let's put into
more routes though block the YouTube
traffic into nowhere
but I accidentally published it globally
and then everyone believed that YouTube
was hosted in Pakistan and yeah then
Pakistan Telecom was overwhelmed with
the traffic because there of course are
not YouTube
why we're referring to this well it's
one of the most famous cases where
filtering was not done
um so
the common way to do that is the
so-called as said it's basically
yeah it includes our paying customers
and includes our free customers
so
things we started to do to prevent that
stuff goes wrong is I was like hmm this
this is an array and this array can
contain other stuff so
no we don't do that to to free customers
we don't we don't we don't accept that
because people has been doing stuff like
oh we we include our Upstream providers
so suddenly you have like recursive
includes
who here believes that recursion and the
recursion is the same thing in internet
routing I think nobody it leads to Route
loops
so we started doing preventive stuff we
don't accept that from free customers so
they cannot include garbage
but we have a few Legacy customers we
can't change what's already been
deployed people will be angry people
will stuff will break so hey maybe maybe
you're a small lab Network you probably
shouldn't announce a hundred thousand
routes to us because that's like the
size of the global routing table so we
we maybe set you a little bit to five
well you can announce one route maybe
two but not a thousand not a hundred
thousand
we still have if we run the numbers I
checked about a week ago 25 000 routes
the IPv6 table is at the moment 169 500
routes so
we're still like a major chunk of the
global V6 internet if everyone announces
their routes to us that's scary
and one of the things for people who
have run networks if you have static
filters and your client stops announcing
any routes to you but you still allow
those routes through you end up doing a
redistribution so you have a tier one
provider tier one provider gives you a
full table
and that's a customer route who's
currently not your customer you
re-announce it to your other Upstream
provider so you're suddenly becoming an
upstream provider for a big Upstream
provider that's not good like company
like Hurricane Electric level three all
those so-called tier one providers you
should not actually become
their service provider
this is a bit of groundwork for
what's going to happen now so
we have an incident
we get a phone call hey
we can't do phone calls anymore it's all
bad I had to call you from my mobile
phone because we don't hear and
understand anyone on our VoIP calls
that's odd we don't have that here so
when we go to investigate Hmm this
router in Frankfurt is really high CPU
load that's bad
we go on again it's an S flow demon
which runs wild s flow for who doesn't
know is a
one of the standards to export traffic
metadata so this is doing in order to
actually know what's going on in your
network you normally just get automata
data you don't get or the entire packets
as an ISP it's like every 2000 packet I
want to know hey this is traffic going
on this way if you only get two thousand
one two thousandth header samples
you can extrapolate what traffic levels
you have so you know like this customer
is causing issues or this customer is
getting 500 000 packets per second these
customers under details maybe we should
do something about it so it's like this
after runs wild okay let's kill it
standard operation process process runs
file is it Mission Creator no
kill it customers happy
well and then that's where the actual
incident starts because we get a ticket
from a company called salesforce.com I
don't think anyone ever used that I
don't think that's a really a relevant
service
and it is oh a subnet League out of D
kicks Munich
I think the dumpster starts smoldering
here
that's how we feel like stay smoke just
something weird
smells like smoke
so
uh what went wrong so we we talked to
the knock from Salesforce and they're
like we announced them around to
cloudflare hey last time I reject
cloudflare doesn't pay any routing bills
to us they're not a clients of ours also
they're fairly big so makes no sense
awesome
we don't have a session with Salesforce
so
we're not doing anything why does this
go through uh so with bgp you either
have a session with
another Network for your exchange routes
so this is also just metadata where you
exchange routes or you have a metadata
mediation server it's called a router a
route server and an internet exchange
point just facilitates that because if
we have 10 member
on an ixp and I actually just a bit big
fancy switch you have to maintain 100
sessions if you have a hundred members
suddenly you have to maintain across all
of them 10 000 sessions so at one point
if you have a thousand members on ixp it
just becomes absolutely unmaintainable
so you need a router to facilitate also
a route server should perform the
filtering for you so you announce your
routes the route server everyone else
knows
what's available on a route service
so there's a central point of filtering
well D kicks should filter that
so we send a ticket to dkicks hey guys
something's wrong here why are you guys
not filtering
well the answer that came back was like
this because yeah we clearly up
and that was the answer so
sorry we we're starting to run a query
on our as set
and hey actually we are a client a
customer uh there are customer of ours
that should not be what happened
there's a nice tool called IR Explorer
from nlnoc because if you have to search
for content in an array in an array in
an array in an array in a database
you're actually going to get crazy so
this thing does that to you and we find
out that
a customer of a customer of a customer
of a customer claims that there are
an ispf cloudflare well that
that's not a good idea
so
again briefly what's an AI set contains
an array of objects that can be either
another area is that or
a bunch of asns
and this is here that you can generate a
list of routes to filter to say which
are the legit routes that this network
can announce to you this ASN
and because there's a route object and
the route object gets searched reversely
so our es set is garbage that's what we
know now it's like okay fair enough but
but but but but
we have a route from cloudflare that has
been announced to us from Hurricane
Electric and we now announced that
to cloudflare which then doesn't work
because the uh sorry to Salesforce which
then cannot announce anything anymore so
this this
is for that it's not that just our
customers in the right and the get
filtered routes and our upstreams get
filtered out both sites have to filter
the ISP filters
and
they're a client-filled this
so
in order to have a filter macro which
processes what you announce because you
might have different policies you run
something called a route map
uh yeah well
we only announced stuff that we take as
customers this doesn't come out of a
customer route so what's what's wrong
here
we haven't updated anything so we also
don't generate automated filter updates
because exactly kind of issues like this
where stuff blows up
well
the dumpster Fire gets bigger
so we were running a routing OS at that
time which is called iOS and iOS at that
version was query fairly fairly limited
I mean if you have to to save your
configuration and every time you change
something you wait 20 minutes it's
really really fun I tell you I mean
that's more like drinking coffee or code
is compiling everyone knows this this
XKCD of slacking off no the code is
compiling this was worse
uh so we've reached the configuration
size where it's so bad that sometimes
the config just gets corrupted and we
have to fix it underneath on the disk by
hand and exactly that's where where we
where we up so up number one
kind of a kind that's fine up
safety net of ours well we
we copied this allow allow allow allow
deny
oh there's no deny here so we allow a
bunch of stuff
and then the rest also gets a lot well
it worked nothing broke you don't notice
that you don't break anything you don't
notice that you don't filter out
anything if you don't announce garbage
until you announce garbage and you've
realized that your filter doesn't work
yeah it's like
it's great
uh well it was it was done by a junior I
don't blame my junior I wasn't doing the
break myself and I wasn't breaking it
myself I mean
but I wasn't personally doing it so I
had no idea this was repaired
and in my opinion there is a third
up
how you can do a route map because we
have this this route server so what
happens is this this route so
two Salesforce we announced that we're
the ISP of Hurricane Electric which is
the ISP of cloudflare
and in my opinion a route server should
start doing plausibility check that like
small isps are not like the the service
provider of a large ISP
but
yeah it hasn't it hasn't worked so yeah
three layers of security none of them
worked and also we announced a lot of
routes not just that one route
so we were like well shouldn't like
we announced a hundred thousand routes
to you
should that shut we have leaked every
single world ever
so what happens is we send an entire
table like the entire internet routing
table to with the Upstream of the entire
internet now where the service provider
of the entire internet now nobody should
announce that nobody should tell that
the route service or route server should
tell us like you know what you're idiots
session shot
that didn't happen so we had a third
up
I mean only the Salesforce route went
through but still we announced the
entire internet to them so yeah in the
meantime it's like okay we we really
need to clean our fire
so in the meantime this is one of the
topics I'm working on is how do you fix
this that the internet doesn't break
whenever someone does a simple type of
like
oh there's no deny one line that gets
lost and the internet breaks
um
so essentially in my opinion the
route filtering with ASX is is
completely broken which means yes the
internet is broken and yes the internet
works on a broken
system of trust
and probably there should be some
possibility
checks I don't know how to do it other
people know don't know how to do it
there's approaches for it and this with
everything on the internet I mean IPv6
has not been rolled out since 24 years
of age of IPv6
I would assume it takes another 10 to 15
years to fix this problem in the
internet our approaches are PSL for
who's who's interested in it or
historical data to start saying hey this
network has never been an upstream of
this other network maybe that should
that is not plausible because the
service provider of cloudflare have
always been hurricane and a few others
so so these random Smalls this Finnish
company probably should not
you can do is you can do machine
learning on historical data you can do
Declaration of data to do that so
yeah this is this is a master thesis on
one of my co-workers who's also running
around here to to bring up proposals
but yeah triple fail and rebroke the
internet for Salesforce and uh
I would say this is how it felt then
so and in order to give proper picture
credit uh this this was found that it's
only time to occur I still love this
because yeah everyone who has been to to
talk who knows what this is about
um
we have five minutes if someone has
questions
find me here but we're anyway at the end
of this
of this day
thank you
okay so the question is how long it took
things to become normal again after this
happened I think the moment we we found
the issue Salesforce has already
filtered the route from us so the issue
has already stopped at a point in time
they have opened the ticket because they
were like
you're getting you're getting this the
the cloudflare traffic and that's not
right
we just filter the route because they
can also just say uh no no we don't take
open Factory as an ISP to that so they
just block the path and everything went
back to normal because we have a one
geek port and say it's four centers five
gigabytes of traffic that's by the way
why everything broke
otherwise it would have worked but
Salesforce has five five gigabit of
traffic to cloudflare I didn't know that
now I know
more questions