okay hello everybody
talking about operational operational
technology and in particular device
security there
and there are lots of standards in the
area so
they create sometimes quite a moments to
remember the numbers
my content is first I introduce
operational technology so if you know it
you are great very you are going to get
very bored
sorry then I'm a little bit talking
about the standard itself it's a big
thing I'm not going to go at to any
depth in the standard itself and then
I'm going to talk about a little bit a
bit about the device part of the
standard and process part
and finally we end up with missing parts
because these standards really don't
cover everything there is in security
my background is I started with smart
cards so I have started all my life I
have been doing Security in a way or
another
doing Hardware software
and processes even some business
development and lately I have been doing
industrial device security Enterprise
so
I didn't actually make any pictures
about industrial devices because they
are gray boxes and they are put into
three cabinets
if you want to see them go downstairs
there is a corner Department there are
some kind of Standards some of them and
if you really want to see something go
towards vertical so the they stand and
solve the capture the flag and see even
more of them
I don't think I don't want to show you
10 different gray boxes doing different
things I wouldn't make the difference
only colorful thing is the manufacturer
logo even if the if that is even colored
one
what is important in operational
technology typically availability you
have to work
if you stop working people are either
highly annoyed like in elevator or then
you lose a lot of money like in Factory
because factories if they stop working
they are fixing some things of money
and
even more lots of people will get
annoyed when you don't have electricity
of course electricity may have some
other problems like in Ukraine they are
having but uh
during peaceful times
Industrial Automation is the most risky
thing in the in the electronics in the
in the electric grid
an electric techniquely handling big
Eminence of energy it's easy to forget
there are
even one wind mile is 10 megawatt
compared to home electronics Home
Electrics doesn't consume anything so if
something starts to go wrong it may go
wrong the big way
and even worse it can go if you are
having a let's say a big containers if
it has
10 times four magnitudes of more energy
in its motion compared to car in Highway
so when it hits some some solid object
there is really a mess
and maybe environmental problems if it's
oil you are going to have big problems
and in mining side if things go wrong
you will get people killed that easily
and going to extremes some kind of oil
refinery there is a hot stuff there I
know very little about those but there
are some hot stuff and if you don't shut
it down correctly
it will make a lot of problems there is
in oil refinery contents about the
energy of atomic bomb at the refinery
site of course it doesn't explode as
quickly as atomic bomb but still when
it's burning it's better to go the other
way it's not going deep you are not
going to go closer to it
that is what operates all these are
operational technology things so they
basically follow same pattern
and I'm going to present it from Network
point of view just to give you the idea
what are the real problems in
operational technology
at the lowest level you have
actual things that are doing something
or moving something Motors
conveyor belt
pumps and things that are measuring
the connections are typically analog or
serial port or proprietary there is all
kind of weird stuff going there it's not
really
uh standardized or anything when vendors
do really different things and of course
there it's enough to have a physical
access to be able to do evil things you
can't really attack those connections
remotely because they don't wrote anyway
or you just have to go into place to do
some evil things Hammer is pretty good
there of course you could leave some
nice things they are also doing later
something active but that's a different
thing
then there is some field Network it's
typically real time
soft or hard so it's controlling that
things are going right if it's not
controlling then things are not going
right and uh
it doesn't really do anything like TLS
today it it's it is highly unsecure if
you can connect to it
usually it's only beginning to get TLS
like things
then there is a plant Network this is
now looking already a bit more like
ethernet it's not typically ethernet and
connecting whole stuff together
firewalls in between they are typically
application firewalls they could be also
normal firewalls but often they really
inspect what he's going through
and of course as tuknik told us good way
to attack this kind of system is USB
when you don't have any connections
outside
I mean you have to somehow bring in your
Malabar
also you can have supply chain attacks
so you obtain the device is going in the
facility I don't know how much this
really today happen but at least in
electric grid they are considerable risk
I think
and then of course today vendors are
bringing their laptops their phones
in order to serve the thing you have
some problem there so vendor wants to
debug it so they're bringing their
laptop they connect they need something
from the corporate networks how they
connect it through their phones to that
and suddenly this whole thing is in the
internet in the worst case I mean it
almost anything can happen at that point
then
it Network
every every I think almost everywhere
and
operational network is nowadays
connected to some bigger network with
through a Gateway and then the bigger
network is of course called go into
Cloud our internet
and of course there are random or
they're running in the ID Network so
only question is when these guys making
ransomware will go to the operational
side and start to stress that also
because it might be good business I
don't know if it's good business for
ransomware because if a ransomware would
attack the plant Network and field
Network I don't think most
factories would recover by getting the
keys from the ransomware vendor they
would buy new devices the device is
associative compared to rest of the
stuff they are running so they probably
throw out all the stuff and buy new one
of course they might have trouble
getting those stuff so
then it's a different story
then
for a reason another many of these two
stems actually connect through VPN to
some place it might be vendor that is
offering them some automation or
collecting some data or then it might be
a second
plant where they
where they have where they want to
coordinate things
and well
we have already seen attacks coming
through these vpns VPN is something so
it doesn't itself protect that much you
can go through with an attack
and then final and most recent funny
thing is this iot devices that uh
sometimes bypassing all of these nice
layers that try to offer security
uh this uh
this kind of uh
connection is really confusing that
think about in this model
so we have plenty of standards
this is only random set I did look at
the actual product but then I realized
that if I put the actual product list
here you will you can work out what
product it is so I didn't want to do
that
standard Dairy standard for almost
everything there is even standard for
markings in the device that what kind of
marking symbols did you use there
and of and for example there is security
standard for grid there that tells how
TCP uh who have TLS should be used in
that context what kind of things and all
kind of details pretty much everything
is standardized
by standards
for example electric many many interface
you want to have this kind of basic Hue
again just not to have anything too
awful there
you may have safety
so you want to know that safety is
properly reliable then it's not about
liability when you can say that I follow
with this standard I'm not liable
and the guy who buys your device can
also say that this was made according to
standards so we made it good care of it
we are not liable either
and then there is this funny places like
explosive environments where you can
have Sparks which where you actually
want to prepare this year that it's not
going to have any Sparks so this at x114
is I think that kind of thing
there are different levels of mandatory
and it's not very clear yet what the
role of this kind of security standards
will have here
for example Maritime Insurance costs
will go up if you don't certify so there
they will definitely use certified
devices
in critical infrastructure there is also
it's coming
that you need to certify the device it's
very likely that you need to certify the
devices that make electric work
but other than that I don't know what
will happen
customers might buy the certified
devices because they must be more better
than the non-certified but they don't
think they actually don't certify the
plant at all which makes it pretty much
useless
but I don't know that time been so
so what kind of thing is this standard
itself
okay
not working okay we have their
uh in the asset owner is the guy who
owns the stuff
they said policies how the things would
behave
how it what kind of things are done and
how how are they done then and they
seldom know what they are buying what
they are running they want to get system
integrators who can pull together the
stuff others otherwise it doesn't really
make sense
them it doesn't work and this system
integrators have already
kind of making all these configurations
that you need to do to make the thing
work
but actual products they are not they
are much much manufactured so they are
not configurated yet and product
supplier produces this kind of general
purpose devices that can be used they
can be applications embedded devices
Network or host but they are anyway kind
of general purpose they are not made for
specifically this case it might be made
for some general use case like wind
turbine but still it's uh
uh for many kinds of winter events in a
way
and
there are two standards here that are
now getting I would say that companies
are competing to implement them right
now the first companies have them
certifications for some products some
companies have pretty have all only
started the road to certify them
and they're when creating certified
product you need to also certify your
development process
so you must have process that is also
validated
that it seems to work
there are multiple significance themes
multiple certifiers so it's
that side is
uh
pretty much mess I would say
there is probably situation that some
certifiers are better than others and
here we go
the standard specifies security levels
what it what the device can resist
SL1 is lowest you can't hack it
accidentally but if you intend to hack
it you are allowed to it it doesn't have
to resist that anymore
okay good pretty secure then SL2 is it's
the most common level I have seen
companies certifying devices now is
Hackers with
simple means and Furious this is General
skills a lot of motivation
so
everybody here has high motivation
has more uh and some industry specific
knowledge probably after this
presentation and they have high
motivation so it can't stop you sorry
according to standard
well tough luck and these
goals are really interesting because
they don't really tell what the standard
is aiming at they don't reflect really
content of the standard but still
standard says that these are the levels
that are being aimed at
I don't think any I haven't yet seen SL
for highest level
uh project myself but I doubt this
this certification model will work very
well there
it won't really give guarantees that
nation state attacker wouldn't be able
to compromise something
no way
and on the other hand starting point in
industrial
security is pretty low lots of devices
are really such that you can
accidentally hack them if you run animap
scan to network the network will go down
sorry
so maybe these goals are not so wrong
after all maybe they are reasonable
goals as a first step
and in actual product security is there
is also a huge variation Linux devices
tend to be reasonably okay the closer
you go to the up real-time operation
system that is custom fit by company the
more likely it is that it fails pretty
miserably
about the requirements the actual tech
device security requirements are
actually mostly functional requirements
so these are telling what kind of
functionality device implements so you
can verify them by functional testing
pretty easy to verify that yes it is
very implementing TLS it doesn't say how
many bugs TLS implementation has
and security level changes what exact
functionality you need to implement
but funny thing this is in the standard
this is pretty much the only thing that
changes with the security level
so in sl3 I think you need to implement
multi-factor out indication or was it
tesl for the exactly remember but these
kind of things pop up more and more
there when you write them
and then when you don't can't do
something or don't want to do something
for example you don't want to do CQ boot
then you document that you didn't do it
and customer needs to protect against it
and that's I think really valuable thing
because now you should know what vendor
has Triad to do what they what is the
best they even think they could have
done
and do they call most common challenges
well encrypted communication or lack of
encryption
it is there or then it's not it's very
slot then the standard at SL2 at least
requires per user accounts
but I don't know how sensibility is to
have a user per user accounts on motor
control that is controlling some motor
it doesn't make sense to me but it
standard requires that
it's a little bit flat in it thinking
that everything is similar
maybe third one is that it requires
secure boot pretty much everywhere but I
don't think absolutely every device
requires that
the process thing is
complex
I mean I try try to draw this kind of
simple and it this is simplified version
this is heavily simplified version of it
there is threat modeling security
requirements
that's okay that modeling is driving
security requirements and then we have
verification validation with lots of
different kind of tests and then
implementation
many thing for third-party components
and check your pie design and coding
standard stuff
we have plenty of reviews
I would say everything is reviewed and
preferable once a year
so there will be this it cannot be
implemented very lightly or then you
have to explain away a lot of stuff
so if you are making this kind of device
that is secure against accidental misuse
it might make it doesn't really adapt
that you have heavy process to make
rather insecure device
but when when going higher second levels
it makes a lot of sense
there is a traceability of requirements
I have heard that this is one of the
tricky parts for development teams that
they don't
they can't really make
this kind of security test traceable to
security requirements well yes I
understand it and uh
in many parts it's a document in pretty
obvious things that are not not really
adding value but
but the main problem is probably that
well there's the tested Independence
test that is really good thing to have
you can put your development team to do
pen testing of your device that just
doesn't fly you have to get maybe not
some external but at least different
department in your
company to do it
but then there is comes the negative
side I mean nothing really verifies in
the standard or puts any kind of quality
requirements for this so as soon as you
have threat model it's pretty much okay
and I can promise to you that the pro
direct modules are so complex that no
accessories ever going to read them
through
they are they are way too big
lots of stuff and lots of this kind of
details that
that make really difficult to read of
course you can make simple threat model
out of it but then it doesn't really add
much value either
also requirements and testing is kind of
thing that
there is not really way to handle them
very well and there is for example there
is no feedback to developers nothing
says that you have to tell to fit
developers how did did they do did they
Implement city code or did they do it
correctly
and of course there is no weird culture
in whole documentation why there should
be because cultures don't make software
right
and even worse security level is not
impacting the process
so this process is pretty good if you
aim at
some kind of SL2 sl3 but if you aim at
SL1 it's complete Overkill and if you
aim at sl4 it's not sufficient I would
say it's not nearly sufficient
it's lacking too much Human Side
so it really one of the cool things it
standard really does though it enables
organizations to spend money these
companies can't use money to security
unless it has standard that's impossible
I mean if it's requirement it has to
have standard
that's the way thinking goes
I'm really surprised by that myself
because I have been working in
completely different environments before
but it's the way it is
and it addressed this worst of the
current problems you won't see any more
this kind of device that crashes when
you do any map after this
and it helps users they will know what
they get a little bit better than before
right now they have no glue but ticket
and security levels do not really really
reflect the work needed or this kind of
thing that that Gap is there that it it
has at least it has at most two meaning
at most two meaningful security levels
the first and last are not that
meaningful in the standard at all
I know Nick at this nixo has tried to
apply this outside industrial sector
car for evaluating car but they reported
that it's awfully tied to Industrial
things it wouldn't it didn't work very
well
things in future
there will be race to put them people
will try to implement the standard as
cheaply and simply as they can and they
will be good at that
they will be good
environment will change so what is now
industrial environment it's not famous
today it wasn't famous yesterday either
and there are huge differences between
evaluators I'm already hearing that how
on Earth these guys did get this
evaluated
well it was evaluator evaluators take so
much different stand and problem is that
this standard doesn't say how cool you
have to do things
so real standard evil what do you think
will there be revisions of standard to
match the changing things
I don't think so
so we will see more and more different
interpretations and certification teams
will start to interpret things
differently
this doesn't make standard failed but it
makes it that you have to pay for
certifying the stuff
if it was somebody known to make very
strict certifications then it's probably
high security if it was somebody from
somewhere you don't know about then it
might not be as good
it might be not good at all
typical discuss an inside company goes
this way when starting this kind of
where customers want to have secure
devices
they really want to have okay let's make
so secret devices that we can make it
competitive Advantage I have heard this
mirror several times
yeah good idea but actually customers
want to have certified devices
they don't know what the secular device
they can misery they can taste it they
just don't know what they secure device
I actually made a test with the daily I
asked edit to draw security
secure devices it made a lock on top of
the devices or something like that okay
good I ask Eddie to draw insecure device
well it gave the same as with with the
devices only so that thinks that every
device is in Secure device well might be
can't make difference
unfortunately pictures were so boring
that I didn't take them here
the fight between compliance and
security you need both of them you need
to have compliance to make customers
happy and you need to have security to
make customers happy after five years
once they go because compliance doesn't
really protect you against hackers
particularly does but customers can buy
security they can only buy compliance so
vendors should really do both of them
but they are a little bit different
things
compliance is about measurable things
easy to measure things typically
valuable things have for example this
fit these secret features resourcing
documentation then whether the process
actually works exactly it as it should
maybe not that important it's nice to
have but
not always so important whereas getting
things to be secure you need motivation
people must be motivated without that
they will fake it because it's so much
easier
also they must get feedback
and in general they they are quite
different things
and you need to think which one is
driving company
many process oriented companies are
really driving by compliance and then
they do the compliance and then they
want their why disagree wasn't that good
after all
when you have certified your device
is it secure does your Emperor have the
clothes
you actually cannot really get know
the things that I really need to pay
that instance deal is the feedback
and also motivating the team in other
ways though the other willing to tell
the problems they know most of the teams
no problems
are they talking about those
and I have heard some disobey conference
that talks about this kind of things
have you heard about it maybe maybe
because
even if you are individual developer
inside this kind of making this kind of
iot devices or or or or industrial
devices you still can apply these nice
things
you really still can apply
go on look at what your product does do
and tell about it within company
and share information and don't be
because that will kill your
effort but I have heard from one manager
of uh industrial device manufacturer
that why on Earth we can't have more
this kind of hacker people
they would love having more of them but
their culture is killing it
so maybe we should have this kind of
hacker inside sticker after all that
corporate would tell that we have these
hackers inside the company maybe I don't
know
and that's it thank you any questions
[Applause]