foreign
[Music]
hello everybody Welcome to my talk about
locked Sky boats try to make a joke here
I don't know if anybody recognizes but
it's from XKCD so the thing explained
are using only 1 000 words so if they're
like the most common 1000 words of the
English language
I'm not gonna do the talk in that way
don't worry I'm gonna use normal words
and it's gonna be all normal English
language I hope
so
I'm Ben I'm going to introduce myself in
a little bit like a little bit more
detail but
um basically to start off with
I have this quote about Aviation
um
I guess somebody might recognize who did
it
um
is there anybody who knows can you raise
your hand maybe just you don't have to
or you can shout the name of the person
nobody
um so basically electric supersonic
vital heart problem was set by Elon Musk
and
Vito I try to not use abbreviations in
this talk but just on the first slide I
had to because it's a quote so we told
vertical takeoff and Landing basically
is this next generation of aircraft and
as you can see here
people find this not too easy like
people find that building a veto seems
to be like a really hard problem
um
a year later same person
said this no I think it's incredible
difficult to bring an aircraft to
production and meet all the regulatory
requirements worldwide it's a very
difficult thing
so you can see there's like this person
who basically made electrically Vehicles
like cars available for everybody who
introduce space flight and reintroduce
space flight in the US as a really big
thing
but he is saying the aircraft no I won't
touch and over the next years there were
more quotes but I just want to keep it
like that and like yes it is difficult
it seems to be difficult for most of the
people it seems to be not approach
approachable it seems to be like an
problem which is really really hard to
solve
so
everybody knows this car
that's a Delorean from Back to the
Future
it literally was a vital in that sense
it was a car which could fly at some
point a vertical attack of a landing so
it didn't need any Runway or you don't
need roads where you're going
um yes it was a time machine as well but
let's not talk about this like this is a
different topic so
looking back at what Elon Musk says and
like this quote this seems to be like
some some dream some unsolvable thing
um but is it actually is Aviation so
hard and like is it such a difficult
topic to address or like to deal with or
to work in
um it all comes back to the dream of
flying so coming back to XKCD I mean
what else would you expect
it's the dream of everybody to like at
some point like you know you keep
running and at some point you just take
off and you can go wherever you want and
it's like getting from point A to B like
the direct route like you can go like
directly from here to Oslo to Copenhagen
like you don't need to like take the car
somewhere like up Norway or down again
or stuff like that you don't have to
cross water in that sense so you just
like go from A to B
um it's three-dimensional that sounds
fun I mean like going up and down and
not just like left and right or straight
um they seem to be quite unreachable for
a lot of people as well like it's you
know like this it's a little bit like
gazing at the stars and thinking like
how do I get there like how can I reach
it and planes I mean they are closer you
can see them at airports you can get on
them on airports you can fly with them
but still like how do they work what is
it behind it why do they fly that's all
like kind of for most people Mysteries
and obviously it's fun I don't know like
the feeling of freedom and I mean there
is the simulator upstairs I haven't
flown it yet I was considering to skip
my talk just to take a chance but here I
am
um but I guess it's worthwhile to check
it out upstairs
um probably it's fun and some adrenaline
considering it's like a military
aircraft
um but who am I actually like why do I
talk about Aviation why didn't I
actually mention cyber security yet like
and why am I called cyberband
um
so that's me
or maybe that was me a while ago like 30
plus years maybe I don't know you see I
grew up in a time where you didn't
really have a computer at hand all the
time so there was still analog things
um I've been running from away from
reality since the late 90s 80s sorry
that was when I born um you can see I've
been living in a few countries and I
across the globe you could say I mean
New Zealand was the first I was getting
and that's just living in in these
countries um I've been traveling much
more than that
um I claim to be educated in Flight
controls guy board computers and
security what does that mean
um basically
um I studied avionics so
I have like a degree in how to actually
build aircraft systems I I have
developed my uh my own like uh
navigation system for like artificial
aircraft like in a whole group project
with like 90 students and Engineers
um
I know flight controls um yeah I I know
how to fly a plane I've been flying a
few types of planes I have a few like
eight or ten flight lessons on a
helicopter don't try this that's just
crazy it just wants to crash immediately
um and yeah I I also studied security I
started off like studying embedded
security and specializing in this area
kind of merging the topic of
the computers on an aircraft as well as
like them being a better system the
security of them
um
probably not the right phrasing but role
playing experience in a corporate
environment
um
I've been Consulting a lot of Aviation
companies I've done things on a
technical side I've certain risk
assessments I have managed a team of
aircraft security Engineers as an ad
manufacturer like I've been around quite
a bit and I can tell you I haven't seen
the talk before about Mental Health
uh Aviation and security is not a
healthy Thing by itself but it's
manageable if you just start focusing on
the right things
and nowadays
um living close by I mean
there's somebody from Thailand I guess
uh some more yeah but I moved to
Thailand um because Finland was a little
bit too much of people around me like
the first row kind of
and somewhere over there some more
people like I've been living in Finland
before working for this company called
fcq at that time but now yeah I'm I'm
living in Thailand and I'm actually
having my own company so nowadays I'm
Consulting for like aerospace companies
by myself
because
it is a challenging topic there's a lot
of companies around and the best way to
do it is to just go ahead and build up
your network and like do it by yourself
so yeah I I kind of claim I know this
this world of Aviation and also like the
security world so I've been working in
this domains like both of them for a
while and I have seen a lot of things in
a lot of companies countries
um some of the stuff you don't even want
to know potentially but
if you ask me nicely and I can talk
about it I'm happy to share any insights
or experience
um so the news you always have to kind
of like make draw a picture on like what
is actually Aviation and cyber security
and what is actually like publicly known
what are people talking about there's
the usual news is about like plain
hacked
airport hacked
Airline hacked
the new one really like fancy is
pictures sent via airdrop like
passengers sitting on the aircraft just
looking for like iPhones which are open
to receive images and just sending them
out they have been like normal pictures
being sent selfies there might have been
some pictures about bombs being on the
aircraft or stuff like that which you
don't want to have on an aircraft which
is about to take off because passengers
don't like that
um
then there's this usual statement like
which comes from a lot of people
regulations are changing too slow it's
like
why is there no security or old aircraft
why don't we see what is being done in
security Aviation but if you actually
like working in this area you know
what's going on and what is being done
but the news are the news
and then this usual ransomware at tier 2
supplier like some supplier from the
aviation world having being attacked by
some sophisticated hackers who've
encrypted all the hard drives which was
at the end just a simple mail
attachments and somebody clicked it and
then it just happened
so
today to actually help you a little bit
to understand what this Aviation cyber
security is what is Aviation how does it
work how do we get from a drawing of an
aircraft to an actual aircraft and how
does security actually fit in there so
basically the the engineering
perspective like the cyber security
engineering perspective I try to bring
it to you like open it up for you and
give you an idea what this actually is
about
so we're going to talk about Sky boats
like the aircraft like
why they fly how they fly how they
exchange after a while or like how
they're being improved and yes we're
going to talk about crush it but it
sounds bad to actually put it out so
it's not that official that we're
talking about crashing aircraft but
there might be some information about it
then
we have like building the sky board so
basically building the aircraft like
what components do you need what kind of
systems are being involved in like
building the sky boat and like how do
you test it how do you break it things
like that so basically end to end like
where does it come from where where does
it end up and then there's like some
security around like how is it actually
being isolated secured how do you
actually test on an aircraft from a
security perspective as well as how do
you when you operate the aircraft how do
you manage it
so drafted Builder tested break it again
a quote from a random person from the
internet
um I have a QR code later for him I
think
um it's a nice YouTube channel about a
person from America who's building
aircraft but uh fasten your seat belts
nobody has them but literally let's go
into the like more technical more
interesting part of it
um
abbreviations my day-to-day
um I would assume most of you people
recognize maybe a few abbreviations
um I'm gonna have now like 15 slides
with abbreviation of explaining like the
terms so bear with me no just kidding um
it's crazy if you know security
abbreviations and then you go into
Innovation you have three times the
amount of abbreviations and every
manufacturer every supplier is naming
the the system in a different way even
though it's the same system so
don't want to scare you with this I'm
not going to talk about it but this is a
reality this is where it is this is what
I deal with on my day-to-day talking to
manufacturers suppliers Airlines
whatever
um but yeah there's not going to be 15
slides species like the veto was the
only abbreviation I hope in the slides
so let's start with the first point fly
it so again just to reconfirm with you
trust me I'm an engineer
I've been working for a certain
manufacturer before I started my own
business so I've been working actually
on vital aircraft I've been the manager
for cyber security there I've been
running the whole team setting up
everything which is needed for security
uh so yes I've been around there
so
referring to those talk which was coming
after me about the maritime world
boats float on the water that's the fact
I mean if you look at a boat it floats
it doesn't sink so same applies for
aircraft they float on the air literally
it's just another liquid so there we
have Imperial evidence if you're
wondering why planes fly I'm not going
to explain it to you that sort of
physics about it
um this is just how we have to deal with
it right now that should be enough for
us if somebody wants to know more about
it uh that probably would be one of the
points where I would say please don't
ask me to explain it to you
I've even I studied avionics the flight
Dynamics and everything behind it
depending on the aircraft I don't even
want to know why they fly and if you
look at these big Beluga aircraft from
Airbus like the ones which can open up
on the front
even the engineers at Airbus sometimes
said like yeah we don't even know why it
flies
it's
just flies we are lucky
and obviously aircraft are not alone
there's a lot of network communication
between the aircraft so you can assume
that these nowadays are well connected
and that's necessary so
maybe if you take a little bit of the
magic out of it while they fly this
image you see there's a lot of magic
involved that's if you ask me how they
fly this is how I would explain to you
why they fly and how they fly
um how do they change over time so kind
of the first aircraft first flight
ride buses so we have moved on from
there we have changed the aircraft quite
a bit I mean I don't even know if this
had an engine I think there were like
two propellers that's about it and I
wouldn't argue that this is flying in a
sense of nowadays because it's more like
yeah you're gliding above the ground
you're just lucky that you're not
touching it anymore
um so you see nowadays the aircraft like
I said they have to communicate so
there's a lot of increase in
connectivity we've gone from where you
actually
ping the aircraft and based on the reply
the aircraft knows where it is
that's how it started nowadays there's
GPS there's Galileo for Europe there's
internal sensors who calculate your
position pretty precisely for quite a
long time
it all improved and it all connected you
I think in Europe or at least in Germany
as far as I know like nowadays you don't
even have to turn off your phone anymore
on the aircraft
so flight mode
is it still necessary so we are changing
constantly we are increasing the
connectivity we are connecting more and
more systems
this comes as well with automation
usually I would put this picture of like
an old
um Concord aircraft where you can see
you have two pilots and then you have
the flight engineer and then potentially
you have the radio Engineers so you used
to have a lot of people in the cockpit
responsible for a lot of
activities so not a single person was
responsible for at all that changed
um
then we're just directly related to the
flight code reduction so basically we
are nowadays at this point in theory so
just one person sitting in front we
trust him to handle any situation and I
mean to be honest most of the time
who's flying the aircraft
like I mean the pilot is doing takeoff
and landing and besides that there's
like one knob he maybe has to turn
um
and that's about it is it still like
this big job and then
look at incidents who are which are
happening or look at things which might
happen in aircraft so what happens if a
system fails so the pilots they're
supposed to know their aircraft really
well because if the system fails they
have they have a checklist how to react
to that
but that's like quite a challenging
situation to be in if you're like close
to landing and like it says oh the
landing gear doesn't go down
would you be able to manage like saying
okay I have to keep flying I guess oh I
have to tell somebody that I keep flying
uh and where do I actually go now
because I was supposed to stop at this
end of the runway like
how do I do this so even though I say as
a title improve it is it actually
Improvement or is it just like putting
all this Automation in it that actually
the human factor kind of is being
removed or neglected like we will maybe
see
um digitalization uh a big word can mean
a lot and like every other industry
it's happening in aviation as well
like you have your phone app with your
boarding pass when you go to the airport
you don't print anything out like
the flight plan is being transmitted
automatically to the aircraft like it's
just a matter of sending some bits over
um Pilots used to have this big
Tully like with all the handbooks and
all the paper which was like 20 25
kilograms they had to carry it around
but as you can see in this bottom
picture as well maybe like on the left
hand side basically
that's the tablet and all the
information is on a tablet It's All
Digital nowadays there's like barely any
paperwork being done
um I think the most likely thing for
like a plane on the airport with paper
is transferred is when the pilot gets
the weight and balance information so
basically how many passengers do we have
on board how many luggage do we have on
board to calculate
what do we need to take off at the point
where we need to take off because if you
are too heavy on the front and you try
to take off your aircraft doesn't want
to go up uh that can be quite bad
and then the fancy word of e-enablement
so basically and I'm gonna go a little
bit more into detail when I go more on
the engineering perspective is that the
entity systems on the aircraft are
getting more and more integrated so it
used to be this really random boxes or
like a lot of boxes with different
systems that look like a mess it took a
lot of space and nowadays this e
enablement is kind of more integrated
and also again the e and e and
enablement doesn't stand for security
but for
connectivity
I don't even know what it stands for to
be honest
um so let's not talk about crashing an
aircraft
um
crashes are definitely not anticipated
in aviation I mean there's they put
numbers on it like there's this nice
number of 10 to the minus nine there's
talking about catastrophic so
like I don't want to say it's
anticipated but based on like the
calculations
at some point in our field crash and we
have seen that but it should be so low
that like whenever you're doing your
maintenance activities and follow the
processes that at the end like it's
really really unlikely that the plane
will crash because a system fails and
this is like really about the systems on
board this doesn't calculate human
factors into account like so it doesn't
anticipate a pilot going crazy on an
aircraft or things like that
but yeah it's like I say I'm not going
to call it anticipated but there's
numbers which are used to actually
like yeah to accept it in a way
and also
not about talking crashing it
necessarily but you would be surprised
if you fly especially like on the
regional flights in Europe like when you
fly with an Airbus A320 1921 whatever
it's the same aircraft at the end just
different size
and then you fly with an A320 Neo
um it's actually it the same aircraft
even on the A320 new you could find
floppy disks
because what did they do they just used
the old aircraft put new engines on gave
it a new name it's more efficient here
we go
there might be some more changes than
just the engine but it's literally
says next engine option which is like
yes or new engine option so it's a new
one the same is Boeing
um 737 727 Max 727 Ng
um and I mean it's sadly fitting on this
slide when I say crash it but
the max incident on the boring topic
that's kind of like where all this
engineering plays a role and maybe you
might understand more later how the
Boeing incident if you're aware of that
like the 727 Max issue actually really
relates to the Engineering Process which
is being used in aviation
and obviously like I said like you're
you're learning a lot from these kind of
events and this picture from World War
II is kind of like
also showing like what you might not
learn because this is about like
aircraft returning from from the war and
like you can see the red dots uh like
the positions where the aircraft were
hit
and basically the first idea was like oh
we make we have to make it stronger
where the aircraft actually was hit so
actually where the red dots are this is
where we would improve the structure of
the aircraft
but at some point they realized wait a
second
so we only have aircraft returning this
like
dots at these positions but we don't
have aircraft returning this actually
hits on the other positions so what
happens to them yeah they literally
don't come back they crash so instead of
improving where the dots are you
actually go at the things you don't see
because you have to like put it in in
the context
and
that's also like how safety work like I
mean you learn a lot like from what you
see but you also have to anticipate what
you don't see or what might not be
reported so when a pilot reports I'm
saying like it really needs to be
investigated and looked at and like
understood like what's the root cause of
this and how can we improve this
so let's go into like a little bit more
engineering
um actually building an aircraft
um so basically let's just use a Lego
aircraft as an example
um just imagine like each brick is like
one component of an aircraft and to make
it really sound simple you just put them
together and at the end you have an
aircraft flying
easy
but you have to find the right blocks
because
you also have to be able to fly
it has to like work together it has to
communicate so basically interfaces have
to fit
and yeah it's
if it doesn't fit maybe you have to
build some new blocks so I mean in the
Lego example just get a 3D printer and
print the part but um in like
engineering perspective like you have to
potentially develop a new system to meet
your needs or you like your concept
and yeah you can do it the fun way if
your Skunk Works and you don't care
about
Pilots returning so that used to be like
the really fun engineering part when you
just start playing and put people on a
plane and yeah they don't return okay
move on next one
um and then and like I said before like
pilots carry a lot of material when it
comes to manuals
you have to put it all together
according according to how we want to
put it together so you basically have a
build manual and operation manual like
to actually like build it and operate it
and
it's not rocket science it's aerospace
engineering so I mean that's difficult
maybe easier who knows
um
so how do you start like with these
buildings blocks and like where do you
take them from
so you start with an idea so you say I
want to have an aircraft I need a
massage supersonic vital aircraft so
what do you need it needs to be able to
fly it needs to go fly supersonic
oh and yeah probably it should be sheep
and electric so let's just put it
together it's gonna be fine or you say
like Boeing in Airbus okay
um that was as a new aircraft ours is
not as efficient so maybe we have to put
new engines on our aircraft as well and
if you want to do it fast you just put a
building block on the aircraft and
you say it fits
um the 7 C7 Max
this definition of it fits was um
find a gray area to do to put it lightly
um at the end like it didn't fit in the
same manner as it should be so like
there was not mature enough evaluation
of that
um surely this supersonic electric vital
is definitely not realistic so obviously
like a product should have
a market it should be
being done in a certain time frame you
should have the right resources the
right money stuff like that and
it's not just a one-person job so it
wouldn't be like that one person sits
there and says like oh this is my idea
now I have an aircraft it's basically a
lot of competing engineering teams and
um as like I said I studied avionics
um actually the avionics group is if you
go to the middle of the second but last
that's basically the how an aircraft
would look like from my perspective if
you can see it but it has a lot of
antennas a lot of like technology to
connect and like to compute things but
if you then look at other things like
the maintenance group you just have a
lot of letters attached to the aircraft
so people can actually work on the
aircraft so it's not a matter of like
there's just one person or one team
wanting to have a solution it's like a
really big group of people and sadly
this picture doesn't have cyber security
yet because that would be funny as well
I guess I would just put the aircraft in
a final decade and I would be fine
um
so yeah it's a lot of teams working
together and
the thing is from my perspective
you don't you don't need to know it all
like it's not like you need to know why
Network flies it doesn't need to know
like why we choose this engine like if
you do cyber security it's important
that you know where your area is where
you need to have an impact and where you
need to be involved
building it like I said before take the
right Bridge like put it together and um
oops again doesn't fit
um we do start again like it's an
iterative process and you will see at
some points that things not fit or
doesn't work out so you go back a step
and do it again but that's like the
process it's not just like a straight
line and going from one end to the other
it should be for yourself like we talked
about this crash in 10 to the minus nine
like it needs to be a safe design so we
need to trust it that it goes from A to
B in a way which is accepted by by the
industry
um how do you do that
um a little bit of Avionics FCC damn I
have another abbreviation
I didn't want that FCC is flight control
computer basically the system which is
controlling the engines as well as the
actuators and make sure that like you
fly level or you turn right and left go
up and down as you can see
um if you want to be in the wet area I
was like your failure rate like having
a 10 to the minus three or whatever with
like errors or failures of a system you
put one flight control computer and it
will be pretty sure that it fails quite
quickly in a sense of like flying arrows
so what if you put three oh that looks
better that's like this orange part
where like it's acceptable in a certain
way but it's actually not enough
variation like you have to be in the
queen area so
you can see you have redundancy again
you have three systems but you can also
see that one box is green
um in this sense like if you can't read
the text it's basically about like this
similarity and like actually having a
different system being built so you're
not just building a flight called
computer three times and put it on the
aircraft
you're actually building the flight
called computer twice so you put
different engineering teams and say ah
you're building this by control computer
there's this software and you're
building it with that software and then
you have this decimal energy so like if
one system fails it's unlikely that all
three fail because the same error will
not might not be present in one of the
other flight control computers and yes
this can be done by code this can be
done by Hardware as well I mean just put
a different CPU things like that
and I don't see this picture actually on
my laptop but this shows the evolution
of this avionics like I said before you
had like this boxes before which like
just were one system
and they represented what's the
Justified control computer for example
or just the flight management system or
just the navigation system and like this
time the evolution of these things or
like these systems is that actually you
start to put them in one box so you have
multi-core computers
that's kind of still the future of
Aviation multicore computers but there's
approaches to actually say we have one
box multi-core we can run two squeeze
systems on it one might be safety
critical and then we have two S3 systems
which are just providing entertainment
with the passengers or something like
that
and some people who have done Aviation
might think now oh you're putting the
flight control computer next to the
entertainment system this is where all
the passengers connect
interesting so
security people would be like oh yeah I
can just jump over from here to there
and uh that's not gonna be fun
and again
human factors
all these designs is like from
perspective that oh we trust the people
who are involved in this processes we
trust the pilots we trust the engineers
we trust the maintenance teams We Trust
The Operators to do the right things for
security
um
but if you come from security well you
probably know that like
humans trusting
maybe not so much so it's something
which from my perspective like the
industry is still catching up on like
because for them it's like oh yeah we
just trust the human and then
just ask them like okay but if I would
like hack your software development
environment and like put code in there
what do you see that
maybe okay what if not hmm maybe not so
good so it's something like which
there's a lot of trust boot on humans
right now and that's kind of like a
challenge by itself
um security a bit
like I said before putting file control
computer together with an Ife or in fact
Entertainment System
um
you don't want to do that and this is
where this isolation comes into play so
basically what you're doing is you build
trusted environments where your safety
critical systems are and all the other
stuff like the open domain basically is
far away from that oh not that far away
securely segregated from The Trusted
environment and yes that's going to be
boring for some people considering
there's mostly technical people here you
do risk and threaten risk assessments
you go through a whole Loop of like
seeing what could be done who could do
it when could they do it what does the
risk related to that but this is how you
actually evaluate it from security
perspective like at the end you want to
have
Queen colors for security in a way
and yes the Cheese model
also is being used in aviation like most
people know that properly but don't have
a single point of failure don't have a
single security vulnerability which
could bring you to the trusted system so
just really basic if you would like go
from left to right on the right hand
side you would have the flight control
computer and on the left you would have
the public domain like the inside
Entertainment System the Wi-Fi of the
aircraft and if you look on the aircraft
you would see that actually like there
are several security controls in place
between these so-called domains
and yes don't don't overdo security
um
it's already challenging enough to
integrate it with safety and not impact
the safety but if you're doing too much
we're still talking about real-time
Computing systems so the aircraft wants
to have the information quickly like if
you're turning banking right whatever
and there would be some miscalculation
you want to know or like if you're like
realizing oh I might flip over you want
to know it early enough and not like
three seconds later when you actually
can't control the aircraft anymore
um so yeah don't don't build a Swiss
Army knife
build an aircraft
um
yeah just to summarize these a little
bit like safe design is not equal to
secure design but you could imagine
talking about this this similarity and
flight control computers that this also
actually helps security perspective
because the same applies for
vulnerabilities if I have a
vulnerability in one system or one
computer but I know the other two are
actually different
this gives me some leverage to work with
this is something I can use for security
you want to have it end to end you don't
want to have like some points where it's
like oh we're getting our software
updates on a floppy disk
thanks not anymore that doesn't work
you need to improve it constantly I mean
with time the sweat landscape changes so
you need to have something in place to
actually improve your systems or like
make them secure again I don't want to
open that box about changing a system
because that's
a long process it's not fun better have
defense and depth is one vulnerability
shows up once one layer of security
fails you can still rely on the rest of
it and the most boring part obviously
documented
a lot of paperwork being evolved a lot
of like assessments a lot of
test plans things like that
it's fun
but hey
at the end you might get to fly an
aircraft
um try it above upstairs there you
probably can do something like that and
you don't feel the same as he does
um
security testing on a flight testing
actually for now it's extensive like I
said like you need to actually have test
plans which like I've seen them at
errors they can be hundreds of pages
easily for a single system a single
functionality and you test all the
things through when it comes from safety
perspective and the same nowadays
obviously for security
you need to exploit the limits of the
product so
I mean you shouldn't do that with an
aircraft you're building but you
actually do this kind of tests so this
is how you test a wing
have you ever seen an aircraft when
bending that much probably not but this
is what they can actually do so if you
ever fly an aircraft and you see the
wing doing a little bit like this
uh don't be scared that's what they can
do
and
I put it on the wrong side actually like
I mentioned like this tested build it
break it repeat before like that's
actually YouTube channel about the
person who's building his own short
takeoff and Landing aircraft he's doing
fun stuff he is over engineering a lot
but it's a nice perspective into like
how do you actually build an aircraft
from scratch and he is actually building
them from scratch scratch he's building
all the parts of the aircraft from
carbon fiber by himself
and it's crazy like what he does that
definitely recommend it if you want to
know more about like how to build an
aircraft from scratch unlike and more
human level than what the big aircraft
look like and security testing is fun
good can you please not
thank you
um
but is it really
is it even fun if you're sitting in a
faraday cage or like spending a whole
night on an aircraft
um without AC on somewhere in the desert
yes keep nodding thank you
um
I mean like how do you actually approach
security testing for an aircraft it's
kind of challenging
um
if the aircraft is already operational
that's a challenge by itself if you just
have a prototype or like a development
aircraft it's actually easier
the biggest challenge is what do I need
to test and how do I test it the Pharaoh
take age is there for a reason because
this connectivity comes systems which
you don't want to expose or like you
don't want to do the security in public
because you don't want to do GPS jamming
at an airport
it's not I mean it's fun but not for
everybody
um so yeah it's really depends on like
what you need to test and how you can
test it but it's like getting more and
more complex and yeah get the right
environment and get the time in like
engineering follows a strict time plan
so if you don't allocate the time early
enough no
and like I said time is a factor so
you need to manage an aircraft while
it's being operational so you have these
hours interface always until
vulnerability so like that's the
operational perspective into like use
flying in an aircraft and how to
actually deal with security and you have
to react and there's ways to react
um I don't want to mention regulations
whatever but there's a new European
regulation about like Information
Security Management so part is is
actually bringing all these stakeholders
together to react coordinated to
security incidents and about sharing
these kind of insights because you
haven't seen many talks about Aviation I
guess that's probably for a reason I
mean
I'm not really aware of any security
vulnerability that would impact the
safety of an aircraft like a real one
but there could be one even I don't know
everything
um and yeah like it's not risky to smoke
next to gas and
I guess nobody's watching this anymore
like the safety briefings I used to
listen to them and I watch them because
it is important and sometimes I realize
oh this aircraft is not like I was
expecting it to be when it comes to
leaving it so yeah just can recommend it
and
yeah it's not a unique product
development lifecycle
um
at the end you start at the draft you
assess like what you need to do
you consider what is being like required
by regulations but I mean it's just
developing another system in that sense
it's like this is an aircraft It's Gonna
Fly and it's hard in a sense but it's
not like rocket science
maybe
um and the good thing about Aviation
cyber security especially engineering is
security is not necessarily a cost
center because
yes we want to do it but also we have to
do it because if we don't do it we can't
fly
and like I mentioned before security
support safety or safety support
security so they're not the same but
they are helping each other out if
required and for the sake of time
because I also want to do some q a
um just shortly looking at like the
product development lifecycle you can
see I mean this is the aviation one this
is based on a standard but does it
really look different for like other
development life cycles
I would argue that you do the same you
have a concept you do requirements the
detail design implementation and then
all the validation activity is
interesting I mean not not a big
difference
and I'm gonna skip this part this is
more about like the operational side and
like I said before like this
Community there is things happening
there's people talking there is exchange
of information about security events and
people actually are helping each other
so it's not like a private community
um yeah it's a regular regulatory twist
the certification always scares people
off or companies of like Elon Musk
doesn't do it because of certification
requirements
um but it's manageable like you just
have to approach it in the right way and
you have to talk to these people as well
they are really helpful
um and yeah obviously it's not just
about aircraft like I've mostly tried to
focus on aircraft in my presentation but
there's a whole environment around it
and they all need to do security at the
end because like I mentioned before
aircraft communicate so there's
connectivity and also you get parts from
suppliers and end-to-end security should
be implemented like you don't want to
have a software coming from a floppy
disk and then you copy it to some
windows
XP computer maybe if you still have one
and then you connect that to the network
of your company and then like it all
goes crazy so end to end is also really
important
so how to get started my recommendation
is like exploit the opportunities
whenever you get a chance to talk to
somebody or network or find an
opportunity go for it if you're
interested in aviation just go go ahead
try out there's nothing to do wrong
understand and be understood listen to
the people who try to tell you how
Aviation is being done
but also explain Security in a way which
they can understand and not scare them
off I have had situations where I was
trying to explain a solution and
suddenly the next day the engineering
team said oh we're not doing this
anymore we don't want to do security for
it so literally they just by me talking
to them were too scared to do security
and just skip the whole system
and stay calm stay focused stay safe I
mean don't don't go crazy don't burn
yourself out doing that it's a
challenging domain to be in like with
all the abbreviations especially but
it's doable
and it's not just engineering yes I'm an
engineer but security stuff you don't
necessarily need this kind of
engineering background I have
and yeah
that's about it
um
if you want to talk to me just approach
me after the talk you can ask me
anything about building your own
aircraft I haven't done it yet but if
somebody is interested
um sure and anything else Aviation just
approach me
thank you
any questions
so if you have some questions could you
please just raise your hand or stand up
and wait for the microphone so that
everybody can hear it and I I anticipate
if you would just like ask it back
quickly if you have a question to me
right now because then everybody can
hear about it and like we can share the
answer
was it that simple everybody understood
everything
thank you for the presentation so where
does the magic come from
just disappears okay actually I had a
question about this Automation and the
security of what the pilots actually do
I think there was recently a case I
think in Spain where this pilot just
decided to fly a plane into a mountain
just killing off everybody they think
like automation or like this kind of so
you mean the the incident where like it
wasn't a German airline um like with the
pilot one of the pilots was outside and
the other one just crashed into a
mountain Yeah so basically
um this is like where this iterative
like evolution of the aircraft comes
into play because nowadays if you have a
new aircraft or a new aircraft they
actually have a system which is called
Ground proximity warning system gpws
basically it would warn you if you are
attempting to crash the aircraft and
actually it would at some point start to
react automatically so it would just go
up so it's it was an aircraft which
didn't have the system so the pilot was
able to do it
um and I wouldn't guarantee you that the
pilot is still able to do it even though
the system exists because he still has
to a certain level the power to overrule
the system so if you now also to turn it
off
doesn't matter now this is a matter of
like how much should the pilot still
know and with the Boeing 77 Max it was
the opposite the pilots didn't know
enough to react to that and this is like
well it's like a really challenging
balancing act with like reducing more
and more flight crew from the aircraft
like the single pilot operation which
was shown in the picture
10 years 15 maybe not before it's gonna
be like too challenging to actually not
have two people on board anymore
uh in a not so complex aircraft how do
you prevent somebody of actually sending
an ILS client slope that is like 10
meters away and making the airplane
crash
sorry can you repeat the first part of
it in a not so complex aircraft very
different nav AIDS are not compared to
each other let's say like an old King
here how do you prevent somebody with a
transmitter actually not crashing the
plane or something a faulty Clyde slope
the these stupid answer I could give you
is like nobody would get on the on the
airport to actually tamper with the ILS
system
but that would be the wrong answer
um so it's kind of a challenging
question because I think you can't
prevent it I mean it depends also on the
like situation of the flight because if
it's a clear sky or like the night and
you see the runway lights and stuff like
that the pilots would see it
if it's like the visibility visibility
is really low no and if you come back to
me later there's actually a research
paper from the ASA where they actually
did this kind of simulation on a flight
simulator with screen Pilots tampering
with ILS and all these things and
there's really interesting findings in
there but I can't summarize it like in
one sentence
hi thank you for the talk
um I was thinking what is a
vulnerability assessment or a
penetration test for an airline or for
an airplane look like
it really depends what you're looking at
like there's no simple answer to that
like for like if you like the easiest
example I guess to explain to you is
like when you look at an infinite
entertainment system or the Wi-Fi on
board
it potentially is just like yeah Wi-Fi
security there's a website a web app a
web server and this is like pretty basic
security testing but if you actually
have some avionics or safety critical
system it really depends on the system
and like what your threads are and what
you need to look at it can be a simple
code review
it will also be especially like nowadays
and with a move on like the more
connectivity you would actually have a
test aircraft where you actually would
tamper with a system on the aircraft in
an isolated environment and this could
like the testing like did
it's probably too much for me like to
just summarize it in that sense but
anything you can think of basically I
mean there's web apps there's Hardware
there's anything like from technology
perspective you can test
this hello uh great talk thank you so
much thank you uh I have a question that
uh
it's a bit of fun maybe uh every time
when you happen to be on the airplane
and you have you know the interactive
interface in front of you how often it
is or How likely it is that you can
actually do any harm to the system
because I guess the networks are
segmented so I mean I shouldn't be able
to mean the system the entertainment
system itself I mean you can make it
crash I guess easily but going then to
the safety critical part no because they
are isolated nowadays they have
basically data diet in it so basically
it's just unidirectional Network traffic
going from avionics to the infinite
entertainment system and an old aircraft
basically it's actually good to have old
boxes in there which are all isolated
only have only directional communication
so you actually couldn't even
communicate with it in that direction so
it's unlikely but but yes you could
crash it but it doesn't affect the
flight
like but do you think there are any uh
Planes in use that don't have the
separation
unlikely
I wouldn't say no 100
if there's nothing else nobody else
thank you of course somebody else please
yeah just a quick question like I know
like I have some background in aviation
more background in security but like uh
how much penetration testing or testing
of for example the data links the eight
cars and and the others are being done
since some of them is not much that they
send or that they receive on the plane
are kind of getting quite close to the
like more critical avionics Parts yeah
and there is not much being done and I
think that's something like where it's
challenging for the aviation industry
like being in that sense like slow with
developing the technology because acres
and all this stuff or adsb for Aviation
it's new and it hasn't been designed for
security in mind so not not too much fun
yeah and there's The Duality that you
kind of especially of all areasb you
kind of want everybody to be able to
receive it at the same time you would
want to kind of prevent everybody from
receiving so yeah it's a challenging
thing and like it really also depends
like
if you talk about Acres it's again the
argument about human factors and you
would have the pilot to actually check
the message it would be a process to
actually say the pilot has to check the
message that everything is correct from
his perspective but
how much does he actually understand it
nowadays and like how much time does he
spend on that so it's a challenging area
to be in
there's one more at the back
Mr Henry
hi Ben hi
nice to meet you again so considering
the efb's irrigating connectivity you
get the updates and uh gate link as as a
concept is quite difficult
to handle the global connective or all
the airlines in all of the airports how
do you see the security of it going
forward how do you secure a gate link so
first of all for everybody who doesn't
know efb that's electronic flight back
that's basically the handbook thanks for
using the abbreviation seems like you
know your stuff
um
so
I might be wrong but actually gate link
isn't used as much as you would assume
not a lot of airlines actually use it
and I mean the thing is like
it's like any other Wi-Fi you shouldn't
trust it in that sense that whatever
information comes over it is trustworthy
by default so there's and I don't know
how many companies or airlines are
actually doing that but the Integrity
check should be independent from the
interface
in that sense and I know company is
doing that and also they're having their
own Wi-Fi and stuff like that so gate
link is not the single solution actually
for that use case but yeah don't don't
trust the interface but make sure that
you have end-to-end security
in place
it seems like that's it
thank you everybody
enjoy the maritime talk
um I hope it's more grounded than mine
[Applause]