[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
hi everyone I hope for the mics working
yep sounds like it good
thanks for joining us this afternoon I'm
here to talk about cloud in general but
more specifically what we're seeing
happen in the wild to some degree and
some interesting attack paths and things
that we've been exploiting and trying to
defend against for a while now
so
um first off I'm sure why this stuff
matters probably isn't a surprise to
many but there's a few uh interesting
bits there too some common weak spots
things organizations don't think about
and where things tend to break down
common breach scenarios both what we're
seeing in the wild but also a lot of the
more uh red team style things that we
don't think the real world attackers
have gotten onto yet expect to see that
coming through in the next couple of
years some bits on detection and that's
always been my main focus historically
so we'll dig into that too and lastly
some tips on a few things to take away
uh go check out for your own
environments and make sure that you've
got them down
as to why I'm here and talking I'm a
principal consultant and the cloud
security lead at with secure just over
there
um AWS Community Builder when I'm not
doing that I do a lot of stuff with AWS
you might also see me at citysec Mayhem
back in 2021 or or Tita a few years back
as well
had a good time there it was great
um
so I'll do a fair amount of cloud this
is mostly going to focus on AWS just
because that's what I know but a lot of
what I'm talking about will apply
equally to your Azure Estates your gcp I
hope no one here is using IBM or Oracle
but if you are my condolences
um
actually it's a show of hands who's got
some AWS in their environments let's see
how much
all right so we've got quite a few
people have poked at that azure
okay
smaller show of hands probably for the
best given their record with o days
lately
but let's get started
so I don't think it's a surprise to
anyone that obviously this Cloud stuff's
getting pretty big and I pulled some
stats and some predictions on where this
is going
um the market this year they reckon's
worth a half a trillion dollars now AWS
themselves are probably going to
generate about 100 billion in Revenue
um
the various parts of the market are
changing at different rates though I'm
mostly going to be focusing in on the
cloud infrastructure end of things
there's going to be a little bit of the
software as a service stuff your
Microsoft 365 and things but that's not
really where my interests are expertise
lie
um
obviously a lot of this data is
predictive but AWS have been hitting
about a 30 growth rate for the last 10
years pretty reliably so it's probably
not far off the problem though comes
from a security perspective right a lot
of the old pen testers look at it like
this right the amount of times I've
heard oh there is no Cloud it's someone
else's computer
it's not wrong but it does also
completely miss the point and most of
the attack paths rely on Technologies
tricks things that didn't exist back in
the old DC world and equally the other
entertaining one when it comes to attack
detection
um you get organizations rolling out
their EDR across their virtual machines
in the cloud and you should you
absolutely should do that but most Cloud
attacks are only going to touch on that
slightly or it's going to be a component
of the attack path and if that's all the
data you've got you're going to miss the
vast majority of what's going on in your
average Cloud attack there's a lot of
other data sources and we'll get into
that later on
so when I say a lot of stuff's changed
one of the big ones really is that when
you start getting into kubernetes and
serverless functions like Lambda on AWS
there's no direct operating system
access all of the the old tricks we used
to use for inspecting what was going on
most of that goes away
um a lot of the networking change is
really quite drastically you can't ask
spoof in AWS because there is no op and
so you often also lose visibility from a
logging perspective because you can't
intercept the traffic and monitor what's
going into an S3 bucket there are
alternative options but you've got to
adapt for them
application security is broadly still
the same but vulnerability class is sort
of changing importance a fair bit server
side request forgery is the big one for
stealing credentials
um but there's a few others as well
and from both an offensive and defensive
perspective the way that organizations
work with all this technology really
affects how we can do security on them
both from an offensive and a defensive
perspective right
um if you've got an organization who's
set up really well with uh continuous
integration and deployment it's easy to
deploy lots of changes very rapidly so
Netflix say they do hundreds of
thousands of deployments a day Amazon
reckon they push every 11.7 seconds into
production on average so this stuff
changes constantly doing a point in time
pen test sort of pointless to a large
degree right and from a persistence
mechanism perspective how do you persist
in a Lambda function that's only going
to last for 10 minutes before it dies
you can sit there and repeatedly exploit
it every 10 minutes but that seems a
little pointless and very noisy what
we're seeing people do more instead is
you look to immediately pivot out of the
compute into the control plane layer the
administrative functions of the cloud
rather than stay inside the VMS or
inside your kubernetes clusters and on
that note a lot of your detection
strategies change as I say and the big
one is um a lot of the old monitoring
say they support kubernetes in some way
um I'm not going to name vendors but at
least a couple of them their kubernetes
support is their Linux agent that's
completely unaware of kubernetes or
containerization or anything else and
marketing has just re-badged it right
um equally incident response let's say
you've identified a bunch of data's been
stolen you're trying to do forensics and
work out what actually happened and the
initial breach Point turns out to be a
virtual machine that was destroyed in a
new deployment two weeks ago how do you
do any forensics on that how do you
maintain forensic artifacts for long
enough that they can be useful should an
investigation be necessary right the
industry is starting to settle on some
of these questions EDR supports getting
better things like that but there's a
lot of work still to do here
common weak spots some of these will be
familiar some of this might be might be
new broadly speaking though when I work
with organizations a lot of them think
about their Cloud security inside
specific boxes you've got a workload
you're deploying we've got an
application so someone's threat models
the little box in which that application
lives and it's one of 150 applications
they've got running in AWS right
um sometimes if they're thinking about
these things in the right way that might
also be including things like their
source code Management Systems whatever
deployment pipelines they've got going
on that's less common than I'd like but
some do
um but generally the bigger picture
isn't considered and even if we're only
talking about a single cloud provider
there's probably a bunch of other stuff
to think about too
in reality I don't think I've ever
worked with a not startup that was only
using one cloud provider does anyone
here think they've only got one cloud
provider in their organization
we got one very brave hand down the
front here
um I would be surprised but hopefully
for your sake that's true it's really
really common to see either AWS or Azure
is the primary
um Google Cloud often hangs around as a
secondary one because everyone wants
kubernetes and their kubernetes supports
better
um then you'll have some poor sod who's
got to deal with China and so there's a
an Ali cloud or Huawei or something
sitting in the corner that no one really
knows what to do with and then your
source code lives in GitHub you're
pulling images down from Docker Hub uh
all your stuff lives on Slack
trying to adequately strap model and
secure all of this stuff
most organizations don't have the budget
so you have to get better at
prioritizing and the prioritization
decisions I often see people make
make some degree of sense but probably
aren't the best ones they could be
making they often Focus very heavily on
the internet-facing public presence of
the organization and not on all the
places where the important stuff
actually lives
and to go along with that I'm sure this
mostly won't be news to people but it's
really common to see attackers pivoting
around between environments right so
um particularly common you start off
with a phishing email to steal some
credentials or to land some some malware
as a foothold on an endpoint and then
use that to Pivot up and compromise
Cloud assets loads of people use active
directory to authenticate to the cloud
most people's active directory Estates
probably aren't as well hardened as
they'd like and so ad admin means Cloud
admin off we go from there equally
people put stupid stuff in S3 buckets
and we did actually find a bunch of SSH
private keys in in one bucket on an
assessment and we use that to then jump
into a bunch of servers in the cloud and
then also actually
um that allowed us to SSH into a box on
their perimeter which then got us back
down into their on-premises estate too
um so attackers will try and pivot
between environments like that and we're
not seeing as much of it going from the
cloud to on-premise the other way around
um but that I expect to increase over
the next few years
so then common breach scenarios
what are attackers really doing
um good question and the blunt answer is
I'm not convinced we know
there are various breaches that get
reported in the news but that's reliant
on the attackers being noisy enough or
the impact being severe enough that it
gets reported and the organization
wanting to report it or having to
because gdpr or what have you and the
providers hate talking about it with a
passion if you go back to about 18
months ago you wouldn't find a single
mention of the word security incident in
the AWS documentation or blog posts or
anything because they were banned from
using that expression
thankfully they've gotten on board with
it and you know things are changing
attitudes are improving but it doesn't
benefit the providers to publicize
security incidents or to help people
learn from them because it risks them
scaring less mature organizations that
oh you know hackers are breaking into
the cloud it's all bad
um equally there's a big focus on
low-hanging fruit organizations look for
the lowest common denominator the easy
stuff to spot and so my expectation is
that what we see is biased towards the
simpler end of the spectrum and a lot of
the cool stuff the interesting attacks
isn't being spotted at present
speaking of cool stuff though Cloud zero
days this has really taken off over the
last probably 12 months or so maybe 18
months
um there's a vulnerability database
specifically for vulnerabilities in the
cloud service providers AWS is here and
the like
um they're tracking over 120 that have
been found of that that I'm aware of
one's been exploited in the wild and no
actual breaches or significant impact
has been reported off that
um you'll see the Israeli firms being
the big names in this space whiz in
particular are the 800 pound gorilla
they've got a team of about 15 really
really good researchers doing very
interesting stuff and but like Spin and
awkward have got some great people too
and if this is a space you're interested
in if you want to learn more about
breaking Cloud providers
um forward Cloud SEC 2022 the keynote
from whiz there is all about how they go
find all these o days and given their
processes been producing probably one or
two a month for about the last 12 months
worth a watch
that said
not worth worrying about a present I
expect that to change now that people
are looking
um but I just wouldn't worry about it
really it's not worth including in the
threat model for your average
organization
equally I'm not gonna spend any time
talking about this really we've all seen
all the news about all the open S3
buckets over the years AWS is doing a
lot to improve this situation things are
private by default there's nice switches
to turn on uh you know block Public
Access for for all buckets in an account
um if you're working in AWS double check
that
um block public bucket setting is turned
on uh and then forget about this and
move on to the interesting stuff really
uh Rami McCarthy out in the US did a
really interesting talk at Bayside San
Francisco where he pulled together all
the data he could from AWS based
security incidents over the last 10
years
um and I'm going to shamelessly steal a
bunch of his data and in fact his uh his
graph here to talk about this
um what we're seeing is uh so abusive
stolen abuse of valid is referring to
credentials the majority of attacks are
somehow tied into credentials that have
been compromised or abused in some
fashion there's a reasonable amount of
application exploitation going on
um the other interesting one there is S3
Global right access
um so this is being used for major cart
style attacks to embed malicious
JavaScript into websites to either
crypto mine or steal credit card info or
all these kinds of things
that's happening more than I would
expect you've got to screw things up
quite bad before you have Global right
on an S3 bucket
um so yeah that's a bit of an
achievement in in some ways
but then in terms of what we've been
doing on our engagements um what I'm
starting to hear some of the red teams
doing this sort of thing
um credential abuse much like real world
attackers that's the the big one
um pivoting in from on-premises as I
talked about if you're working in an
organization that's still very hybrid
there's a lot of Legacy windows and
active directory and things
um the usual play on a red team is do
all of the old stuff on premises steal
the administrative access and then pivot
into the cloud from there
um source code management GitHub Etc
continuous delivery
um that is my personal favorite and what
I'll be spending a bunch of time talking
about
um and then people still build
vulnerable applications those still get
popped people still exploit
infrastructure in much the same way
there
so then for those who are perhaps less
familiar with um the source code
management and continuous delivery
attack path the core of this is you have
a setup where you've got some production
workloads in the cloud or maybe
on-premises even
um and we have something storing all the
source code and then automatically
building and deploying changes out into
production as developers make them now
the key thing here is as an attacker if
I have right access to your code
repositories or I can manipulate what's
going on in those pipelines or in fact
just steal the credentials straight out
of them then it doesn't matter what
you've got in production doesn't matter
how well hardened that is because if I
can compromise everything that's
deploying to production then it's
usually game over those pipelines
usually have an incredible level of
privilege and so if I can get in there
that's it
so
example attack pass and some tips and
tricks the tips and tricks I'm mostly
going to focus on on AWS but these broad
attack paths apply everywhere pretty
equally and most of what we're talking
about here will apply in some fashion
tweet to Azure just as well right so as
I say credential theft's the big one
um Verizon's data breach reports for the
last several years have been guessing
about the sort of 70 Mark and so that
backs up ramy's data from before
um the usual options here credentials in
public repositories if you're pushing
stuff up to GitHub with credentials in
GitHub actually had to introduce a delay
on the open source fire hose feed where
you see all the the public commits
because a lot of crypto mining
organizations were monitoring that feed
scanning every single commit that was
being made into repositories for things
that looked like AWS Keys then they had
their own cicd pipelines that took those
keys and immediately deployed crypto
miners so the time between those
credentials being spotted and an active
crypto Miner being put in an account in
a lot of cases was down to under a
minute
so GitHub now have a five minute delay
on that feed and they've also worked
with AWS to build a bunch of AWS
specific tooling so that AWS Auto
revoked credentials that are found in
public GitHub repositories you get a
nice email saying please don't do that
again but
that's only for AWS right um a lot of
other credential types aren't being
monitored for like that
um if you can break a web app and start
sealing the credentials that that's
using to talk to all the other Cloud
assets that's a great way to get some
credentials too pretty much everything
you run in the cloud as an application
is somehow talking to S3 buckets or some
managed queue somewhere or a managed
database server and those credential
Management systems are pretty well built
by the cloud providers but obviously if
the application can get to them and you
compromise the application you've got
them to and lastly obviously phishing
still happens it still works I'll get
into some interesting more Cloud native
phishing stuff a little bit later on
um
all of these attack paths I'm going to
talk about they're Composites of things
we've done for specific clients are very
deliberately chopped and changed and
move things around so that we're not um
you know not releasing anything we
shouldn't be and but this is all stuff
from The Real World right so
some kind of initial credential
compromise let's say access keys in this
case from a GitHub repository
um but there are a lot of different
things that would work here
um
from there obviously we've got some
creds what are they what do they work
with uh how do we work out what we can
do with them ideally without getting
spotted by the sock
from that then a reconnaissance
perspective there's a lot of things you
can do a lot of it's quite noisy
um by default or other Cloud stuff's
quite locked down
um so a lot of the old school Recon
techniques don't really apply Much
Anymore
um but there's then a bunch of ways to
use those Cloud credentials to start
running your shells on on Virtual
machines and at that point let's say for
the sake of this
um our end of our attack pass is uh
route on an ec2 instance that's uh
running some kind of database full of
sensitive data Etc
so we've got these access keys
first off which AWS account are we in
now
my favorite way of doing this is with
the STS get access key info command if
you have your own AWS account configured
and you pass it the ID of another access
key AWS will tell you what account that
belongs to in a way that doesn't record
that to the account you're asking about
right it logs into your cloudtrail which
is the AWS audit logging system not the
target accounts
so there are a number of public lists on
the internet as to what account IDs are
owned by what organization it's unlikely
you'll find the account ID in there but
at least if you're on a security
engagement where you're testing this
stuff you've got an idea if you're still
in scope or not right it allows us to
rule things out
then what are the credentials or who are
the credentials for rather and the
classic one with this is AWS STS get
caller identity you can't block this
it's a inherently granted permission
effectively uh inside AWS so this will
always work
and what you get back is uh the user's
ID the account in AWS that it's tied to
and uh the arm the Amazon resource name
uh for the user but
this might well get you caught it logs
to their cloud trail it's pretty noisy
just purely monitoring on this so a lot
of organizations discard all those
events by default but depending on the
nature of your environment it's often
possible to whitelist out the noisy ones
so that actually you can get a
reasonable amount of fidelity off this
and this is the classic like you know
hackerel security consultant gets his
hands on some keys what do we do we run
that
the better option is
AWS by default with cloudtrail logs
management events so
um create red destroy that sort of thing
on the resources themselves it doesn't
monitor for data level events where
you're reading and writing to and from
S3 buckets or cues or things like that
you have to specifically enable those
and as of December last year at least
um the publish uh command for SNS didn't
actually log to Cloud trial if it didn't
work so what you can do is you can write
to a topic that doesn't exist with the
credentials that you've just found and
what AWS gives you back is the on from
the previous screen of the credentials
that you've got tells you that you're
not authorized to perform it and so that
tells you who you are but in a way that
isn't logged anywhere so that's my
preferred go-to for that it's a nice
little trick there
and so now we've got some credentials we
think they work because it's tied into
something we've not got a a message back
saying these creds aren't valid anymore
um what do we do next we could start
poking around from the perspective of
those credentials but it's usually
something I avoid doing and the main
reason for that is anything you do from
that point forward if the blue team is
paying attention to their cloud trail
logs they're going to see it any get
list described you know what S3 buckets
have I got what ec2 instances are
running that all gets logged and if
someone's paying attention could get you
spotted so to start with
we want to do what we can from an
unauthenticated perspective so that it
doesn't turn up in their logs
it turns out there are actually some
ways to find
AWS users and roles in ways that don't
log
um you can do that without any AWS
credentials at all quite often but in
this particular case the trick is
basically when you try and save an AWS
policy of some sort on a resource or on
an iron entity and you have that
principle field you can see there in the
middle
AWS won't let you save it if the
principal is invalid so you can
essentially Brute Force the AWS apis
brute forcing a bunch of different role
names and usernames and see what comes
back as uh you know a successful save
obviously doing that manually is pretty
bloody tedious so instead um Quiet Riot
is something that someone built to do
that at scale with a ton of threads
against a bunch of different AWS
services at once
um and equally paku which is sort of the
Metasploit ish for AWS has some modules
for doing it too that said both of these
take forever generally
um it's not somewhere I'd usually start
or I'd leave it running in the
background while I went poking around in
whatever code repositories I've got
access to to look at the infrastructure
as code definitions that have built all
this Cloud stuff it'll have loads of
role names and things in probably so you
can get an idea of of what you might be
looking at
the other trick with AWS here is that
while it's really hard for us to work
out what resources specifically belong
to which accounts from the outside right
you can't do that with S3 buckets
unauthenticated and we can work out
probably what services are being run in
the account because the role names from
the previous step a lot of AWS Services
have what's called a service link role
which is created when you create the
first resource in that service so if you
brute force for the list of AWS service
link role names you can get an idea of
what services are deployed in a given
account
um so that's that's often how we we
guess this stuff right
for Azure you don't actually have to
worry about any of this sneaky sneaky
stuff because they don't currently log
read-only events to their audit logs
it's only things that change stuff or at
least last silence
um so we know they've got the data at
least a couple of my clients have seen
them working with it internally but they
don't expose it through their audit logs
certainly didn't last I looked
um so more of a problem in AWS than
azure
but in the case of this particular
attack path
um one of the service link roles that
we're going to discover is for AWS
systems manager which is an agent-based
thing that runs on your virtual machines
in AWS and allows you to do things like
um automated patching Inventory
management all of these good things so
it's pretty common to see it used it
also provides the wonderfully named AWS
systems manager session manager that are
what they were drinking when they came
up with that one that allows you to
execute commands directly on the box
through the agent this is actually quite
common to see these days because it
allows you to execute commands through
the AWS apis without having to expose a
jump box or anything like that to the
outside world downside is obviously if
you get AWS creds that have got these
rights you've got code exec everywhere
so you can either execute arbitrary
commands through it or there's a start
session command and you give it the
instance you want to talk to and and you
get a usually a root Shell through that
by by default I think you've got to have
certain roles configured on the ec2
instances in order for all of this to
work but if an administrator's gone to
the trouble of deploying the agents and
is using this service you've got about a
95 chance that these commands are going
to work for you
so that's the first one
um now looking more at the sort of
devops tooling end of things
um
for this one we're going to say that we
fish the developer
um and we're in a position to steal the
single sign-on cookie that they've got
saved in their browser right
um from there that gives us default
developer access to their GitHub
repositories obviously developers are
going to do their work they're going to
have some access here
um we open a malicious pull request from
that point
um because a lot of the tools used with
terraform in particular which is a
really popular infrastructure as code
language for those not familiar
um they work in a way that allows us to
essentially gain code execution without
anything ever being approved or merged
in and we'll get to how that works in a
second and so from there that gets us a
bunch of credentials
um and in the case of the client
engagement the last time I pulled this
off
um we ended up with administrative
access over their production AWS account
uh sort of almost by accident I'd ask
them what this uh AWS account ID was for
and got some very nervous responses back
um so first up Cloud native phishing
for a lot of smaller organizations or
newer organizations there's no active
director anymore right there's no point
in running all of that if you don't need
to and these days sometimes you'll see a
zero ad because people want Microsoft
365. it's really common to see people
using OCTA or ping or One login or all
xero or one of these other Cloud native
identity management single sign-on
platforms
they're usually a single point of access
into everything that the organization
works with from their HR systems to
GitHub to their emails to everything
right
um interesting supply chain risk there
really you know we all saw OCTA get
breached a while back thankfully it
turned out not very much came of it but
I think a lot of people woke up to the
idea that if Octor did get breached
their organizations were going to be in
for a world of pain
a lot of these have quite interesting
security properties too though when you
first authenticate they'll enforce
multi-factor authentication they'll have
a bunch of risk-based modeling that
decides whether or not you're actually
allowed to authenticate based on the
devices that you're logging in from and
the IP ranges you're connecting from and
all of these other things right
but in many cases once you have that
initial authentication and a session
token's been issued you can use that
session token from everywhere uh we were
messing around with this with One log in
a while back and once you have that
session token you can spin up a box in
digital ocean and start doing things
Against One log in with it and it all
just works fine and so once you've got
that session token you've got all the
access that that user has to all the
corporate systems basically
and so from there we can usually get
into your GitHub or gitlab or whatever
else it is that you're working with and
some kind of authentication into well
hopefully not Jenkins but probably
Jenkins
um or some other CI CD system
all this stuff is built with the idea of
allowing developers to do their work
efficiently and quickly less attention
than I'd like often gets paid to these
security models around all of these
tools and in a lot of cases once some
changes have been approved they're
automatically merged in and deployed
straight out into production and that's
all done with a variety of tooling and
things that people have built for this
there's a few standard models and we're
going to look at terraform's usual one
here and you'll either see it with
terraform cloud or there's an open
source tool called Atlantis it operates
on pretty much the same principle
right so in this case uh we are a
developer we've stolen the the session
token we got into GitHub
um we are now in a position to start
looking at their infrastructure as code
repositories uh and maybe we can't make
direct edits to the repository that's
fine I've been smart enough to require
um a second set of eyes for all merge
requests that are going in or or pull
requests but if you're using terraform
Cloud on Atlantis the model they work on
is that they review the merge request
they run terraform in it and terraform
plan to understand what's changed versus
what's currently in the cloud and then
they post back to the original GitHub
pull request thread saying here's what's
going to change helps the developers
understand what a given merge request is
going to change in their environment
brilliant idea in theory makes the
developers lives a lot easier but when
you execute terraform plan it executes
every single line of terraform that
you've got in order to compare it to
what's going on in the cloud
now there's two or three different ways
of doing this you can have a custom
terraform
um provider they call it like you have
the AWS provider and the Azure provider
you can write your own and get code
exactly that way or my usual favorite
because it's much easier there's an
external resource type that essentially
allows you to supply A bash script uh
that runs as part of the terraform
so terraform Cloud will take your merge
request there's been no other
interaction required on the developers
part here we've opened this merge
request and terraform Cloud goes and
executes all of this stuff
and in order for it to go into the cloud
and understand what's currently there
and be able to do the right diffs
there's usually some credentials in
there and it's very rare that I see
people try and differentiate the
credentials that are used for terraform
plan versus what's used to actually
deploy all the stuff so these
credentials that your script is
executing in the context of are almost
certainly going to have administrative
access over whatever AWS or Azure
workloads they're working on so usually
you'll find some environment variables
or if they're deploying custom Runners
it'll be the instance metadata service
in AWS or Azure and you can just pull
these credentials they're using straight
out uh very very rarely do I see people
properly lock down where those
credentials can be used from it's often
a pretty manual process so you grab
those you put them on your laptop off we
go
this is quite a hard thing to harden
against though people are still trying
to work out how to do it for this
specific thing with terraform the best
thing to do is basically be scanning
terraform as part of that merge request
to look for the two or three types of
resources or the custom providers that
allow you to do that attack path right
and even just some simple bash scripts
grappling for the right stuff is an
improvement and you can set that as part
of the merge request workflow to trigger
before all of the terraform stuff and
then basically not proceed any further
if you find stuff that looks like it
might be nasty
in a broader sense I don't see a lot of
organizations actually doing proper Four
Eyes checks on their their merge
requests so you definitely want to make
sure that whatever's getting merged in
requires two people to be bad before
um
before we accept any of those merges
it's not going to stop all attackers
obviously but it's a step in the right
direction
um a lot of people don't treat their
pipelines as a core part of their
security model it's seen as a supporting
system as something that we can think
about but not necessarily uh work too
hard with right
um we focus on the production workloads
instead that is a big mistake in my
opinion the more Cloud native you get so
threat model Forum pen test them all the
rest of it give them a good hard kicking
and you'll be surprised at what falls
out I bet
um and equally a lot of organizations
it's seen as a benefit to the developers
to allow them to use whatever tooling
they want and do whatever kinds of
things they want however they want the
more you can do to reduce down the
number of CI CD systems and the number
of tools and things people are using as
part of that pipeline uh the better a
time you'll have as a security team
trying to keep all of this secure
um Jenkins is a bit of a dumpster fire
here and unfortunately there's not
really a huge amount you can do to
prevent most of the common issues with
Jenkins like all the old plugins that no
one maintains anymore
um but for most of the good CI CD
platforms you can also disable at an
administrative level what components of
the tool are available to your
developers all of these kinds of things
so well worth looking at that the less
there is there to abuse you know the
harder time an attacker is going to have
so that gets us to the end of the attack
paths I wanted to talk about
um
from a detection perspective the Cloud's
a bit of an interesting Beast
um I've been talking about this now
since T2 in 2019
um but a lot of things are still being
worked out right
um
there's a few key places where it
differs from what we're used to dealing
with on premises one of the big ones is
what we've taken to calling uncertainty
of malicious intent there are very few
things in the cloud that scream
someone's trying to hack you like mini
cat's executing on a box right there's
not really much of an equivalent for
that in the cloud space
um in a lot of workloads you'll find
that something that is very obviously
bad in most places is perfectly normal
that might even differ between workloads
and the same application same
organization sorry depending on how much
Freedom developers get so everything
becomes about context is this thing
normal in the context of this workload
is this something this developer usually
does
we're getting better at that and
obviously everyone's trying to apply as
much ml and Ai and probably chat GPT
this week too to trying to work out how
to do that better
I still think we're a long way away from
that being good
on the plus side
visibility is generally easier to get
you can turn on most data sources and
have it automatically apply to a hundred
percent of what is in that bit of the
cloud we've moved away from the old
problem of oh we've got 10 boxes in the
corner that our crowdstrike deployments
don't support and so we've got no EDR
coverage there or boxes that you weren't
aware on your network because we can
just query AWS or Azure and get a
complete list of everything we've got
make sure everything's deployed properly
right
now on the flip side I mentioned earlier
on about attackers stealing keys and
auto deploying crypto miners
we've not seen them do much more of that
in the automation space yet but my
expectation is with how easy it is to
automate things in the cloud we're going
to start seeing more and more automated
Smash and grab
um so that's easier to do in the cloud
world than it was on premises so I'm
expecting to see a lot more of that
we're starting to see targeted attacks
against uh S3 buckets in particular
looking to ransomware the Daylight's out
of them basically there's a lot of that
going on now to the point where AWS have
finally had to admit it's a problem
um so for that S3 bucket versioning is
your best friend for now because you can
then just roll back
um but watch this space I expect we'll
see more automated attacks coming in the
future
then
when we think about Cloud we've got a
pretty good idea of what sort of log
sources apply at the infrastructure as a
service end of things this is your uh
sort of virtual machines your old school
networks all of that in the cloud right
and we run EDR on our virtual machines
we grab VPC flow logs or NSG flow logs
and Azure and that gives us the network
visibility you can have cloudtrail or
audit log to get a lot of the
administrative actions out between all
of that you get a pretty good picture
maybe some of your application logs are
useful too
once you start working up towards the
platform as the service workloads manage
databases Lambda functions S3 all that
sort of thing we lose a bunch of the
visibility that you had with the
infrastructure as a service the further
to the top you get on this pyramid the
the worse that gets
um we still have pretty good visibility
cloudtrail does a lot of stuff as
there's Azure audit logs
um Amazon lets you do object level data
events as they call it so you can see
when a KMS encryption key has been used
or who's reading and writing from your
S3 buckets if you really want it
um once we get to the top though your
GitHub boxer you have CI platforms these
kinds of things
well yeah we're still really working out
what that looks like the quality of the
logs you get out of those platforms
varies enormously some of them are
really quite good if you pay enough for
GitHub and you can actually ship the
logs out of it they're pretty effective
um oxal likewise fairly decent the
closer you get to Niche sash platforms
that often becomes more of a problem in
smaller countries running like specific
tax or HR systems and that that sort of
thing and the worse that problem gets
um and we tend to find that no one's
really worked out what to do with those
logs what to be hunting around for so
every organization who's trying to do
effective detection at that end of the
spectrum with all their SAS platforms
outside of Microsoft 365 they're all
working out for themselves as they go
the infrastructure end of things I would
say the two big ones to go for are your
control plane audit logs so Cloud trial
audit log the things that log the
administrative actions
um if you have only got one Cloud log
Source go turn that one on now the
providers make it fairly easy to do
across your entire organization so
that's priority number one and then you
have the service specific logs so if
you're doing a lot of like uh serverless
development with Lambda for instance
it's probably worth looking at the
Lambda specific logs likewise if you've
got a lot of stuff that's encrypted with
specific KMS keys that might be a good
option too
I got yelled at a few conference talks
ago for calling some of the cloud native
detection Services essentially antivirus
for cloud
but it's not really a inaccurate
description at this stage they're pretty
good for catching really obvious bad
stuff right
um for instance don't ever use Kali
Linux if you're pen testing an AWS
environment guard Duty lights up like a
Christmas tree but it's specifically
signaturing on the user agent that
Cali's using for its requests right
really easy thing to bypass equally um
it's Port scanning detection is pretty
bad in my experience too a lot of this
stuff is improving and guard duty is a
hell of a lot better than it was the
first time I put this up on on screen at
T2 I still wouldn't rely on it it's a
lot better than nothing but if you want
an effective detective capability in the
cloud you need your own logs you need to
be doing your own analysis and your own
alerting
then the closer we get to the sus end of
the spectrum the worse the format
variations get
all the SAS providers have their own log
formats totally unstandardized a lot of
the scene providers will have ingesters
for your Microsoft 365 and Google
workspaces Salesforce things like that
but the closer you get to weird Niche
SAS platforms the more you're on your
own
um
in theory there's this great thing
called the opening open cyber security
schema framework that a loaded the scene
vendors and Cloud providers are getting
behind but I think they only announced
that about six months back so it's going
to be a solid two or three years I think
probably before we're in a position
where SAS providers are really
standardizing their formats
the other Silver Lining from a detection
point of view
patient infrastructures in the cloud
tend to be very micro service based lots
of small pieces and so any given request
from a user is probably going to hit a
whole bunch of different points where
you have a way to monitor for it in some
fashion so your average attackers
requests and whatever they're doing is
going to pass through a bunch of
different places where you can pull log
sources out and put it in your scene the
problem ends up being a problem of cost
uh you know if you're running Splunk for
instance my condolences to your credit
card because this will utterly ruin it
but it's worth Gathering up a few bits
of uh the key bits especially uh
wafflogs maybe probably not but things
inside the the containers in your
kubernetes clusters like we've got going
on here
um or like the kubernetes API server
audit logs
um there's a number of places where
depending on your specific workloads and
how you've built them you can pull out
some quite interesting uh Telemetry
there
all right so lastly key security
controls
um what are the big things to put on uh
to try and stop the worst of uh the
attacks in the cloud these days right no
surprise number one multi-factor
authentication preaching to the crowd
I'm sure but you'd be amazed at how
often I still don't see that in use in
all the places it probably should be
the industry's been banging on about
principle of least privilege for I don't
know how long I see that in about half
the pen test reports that people write
realistically no one's ever going to get
there but you can probably get about 80
of the way with 20 of the effort work
out where the key resources the key
administrative users those kinds of
things are make sure they're nicely
locked down and try and standardize
where you can so your developers aren't
trying to write their own ion policies
all the time as a reasonable amount you
can do there
equally
um reducing or eliminating long-lived
credentials I've got a bit of a personal
Crusade against AWS I am users because
you generate the API Keys once and they
live forever until you delete them and
inevitably they get checked into GitHub
or uploaded to paste bin or something
about how bad happens with them so
single sign-on temporary credentials you
know AWS is single sign-on workflows
give you credits for a maximum of 12
hours at a time so that's a much safer
way of doing things than having these
credentials Live Forever on your hard
drive
provide a back to authentication so what
I mean by this is if you're running a
Lambda function you can assign a role to
it and then AWS handles all the
credential rotation and supply to the
function for you the sdks know how all
that works you don't have to do anything
you just give it the right permissions
and off it goes right so don't be hard
coding credentials into things in the
cloud where you don't have to they've
deliberately put a lot of engineering
effort into making it fairly easy for
you to supply the right access to your
workloads without having to actually
manage the credentials yourself
obviously that doesn't apply for things
like your workstations and your virtual
machines
um you know vdi is often a classic issue
here for for this where you can automate
credential management and rotation you
know a bunch of the
um privileged access Management
Solutions and things like that will
provide means for doing some of this
that said there's a reason it's at the
bottom of the list it's generally a lot
of effort and comparatively low uh low
value in the grand scheme of things so
I'd get to that once you've done all the
rest
avoiding people in production
um this one usually pisses the devs off
pretty bad they don't want to be told
that they can't have access to
production anymore
so what you have to do is get to the
point where they don't need access right
um robust logging for an operational
level for everything that's going on in
their production accounts
um having a CI CD system that allows
them to push changes so fast that if
there's an incident they can just follow
the proper workflows instead of having
to go poke around manually that said
most places are never going to get there
so you need some kind of production
Access Control mechanism I've seen quite
a few organizations now building things
that provide a jump box on a per use
case basis uh with you know a single-use
user and the requests for those are then
logged and audited and the security
people can pay attention to that
if you get to that stage and you've
still got some budget left this year
then the logs from your production
access control system feed all of those
straight into your scene so that your
security teams can monitor what the devs
are doing once they do get into
production right most of your devs
aren't going to be doing anything bad
but if something should happen or if a
Dev gets compromised what have you being
able to see exactly what they did in
production because you've got the bash
logs from what they did in the jump box
is really really useful
blast radius is a bit of a pithy term
but what I mean by this is break out
your Cloud infrastructure please for the
love of God don't just shove everything
in the same AWS account I still see
people doing that occasionally but
thankfully it's happening less have
separate AWS accounts or Google Cloud
projects or I can't remember what Azure
calls them for each of your workloads
ideally
um even if you can't get that far even
just having Devon prod in separate
things is a is a pretty good starting
point
um that applies at the network level two
I still see a lot of people like joining
things at the network level with their
their vpcs VPC peering
um even saw one case where a client was
VPC peering with a network owned by a
third-party provider uh who they had no
visibility into whatever and they just
open the open the gates right up at the
network level the other common problem
Point here is what I'm calling shared
services so it's common to see a single
Jenkins box that deploys everything
across an organizations in entire estate
or having a single Secrets management
box somewhere that everything connects
back to
um if that's not handled properly then
that's a key pivot point that attackers
will use to bounce around
um where you can use separate pipelines
and all that sort of thing at least one
for Devon one for prod ideally per
environment
and to the surprise of absolutely no one
I'm sure Secrets management is still one
of the big problems in the cloud
um so it's well worth paying very close
attention to where are the application
teams storing the secrets their
application use are they hard coding
those in are they fetching them from
somewhere sensible the providers give
you a lot of good options on that front
you've got Secrets manager you've got a
key Vault for Azure there's a there's a
few good options there
um checking in on how they're shared and
rotated you know it's no good having
them up there and in theory secure but
the devs have still got them on their
laptop and they don't ever get rotated
and
um lastly how do you know when secrets
are leaked right one of the really
valuable things I've seen a few
organizations do now is just have a
security guy run truffle hog or one of
these other secret scanners over all of
our repositories are like a quarterly
basis just to make sure nothing's been
checked in that they've uh they've not
spotted you'd be amazed at how much
stuff that turns up especially in larger
organizations and that at least then
means you know that you've got to rotate
all this stuff right Better to Know Than
not
and lastly
with the amount of cloud stuff that's
going on in most organizations this idea
that you had a Central Security team
that did security and and uh you know
that was that
that has to go we don't have enough
people who know what they're doing uh
there's a general lack of knowledge and
skills and all this stuff still in the
security world and so those people who
do know about it tend to cost quite a
lot so if you want to Career trajectory
this is quite uh quite a profitable one
right now
um and there's usually two wider spread
of Technologies you know multiple Cloud
providers a whole lot different stack of
devops tooling uh kubernetes is his own
Beast that I don't even want to touch
really
um you have to push all this down into
the engineering teams right we've been
trying to get them threat modeling and
shifting left and devsecops and all the
rest of it for a while now
um but at the concrete end of things
having them do some of their own threat
modeling helps them get better at
security anyway so definitely try and
help them out with that
um leaning on them to build a lot of
your security automation for the cloud
is a really good idea they're generally
better devs than the people in security
teams for a start and the carrot you can
use is we're going to build all this
security tooling anyway it's in your
interest to help us build it so that it
works in a way that you actually can
live with and that you don't hate
yourself for right it's also a really
really good place to hire people from or
poach into your own teams uh to help
with the cloud security stuff I found it
much much easier generally to hire a
x-cloud engineer and teach them to do
Cloud security then to take someone
who's been doing like old school
networks and Mainframe stuff for 20
years and and get them thinking in the
cloud
so well worth thinking about that if
you're struggling to hire for these
sorts of security roles
um and obviously the sooner you fix
security issues the cheaper it is and
the more you can automate the more you
can do so all the stuff everyone's been
saying for ages about um putting stuff
in your pipelines to
um scan for bad things in your your
source code all that still applies
um check off worth checking out for
infrastructure as code uh really
powerful open source just take it and
put it in your Jenkins pipelines and it
will find a lot of the more common Cloud
security problems for you
so
to wrap things up
well Cloud's a bit of a different ball
game the broad security principles that
we've all used for years all still
applies uh the way that it works and the
way the organizations are building and
maintaining this stuff means that the
Practical applications of a lot of the
security stuff we used to do change
quite significantly in many cases right
in theory if you know what you're doing
I would argue the Cloud's probably
easier to defend and monitor than a lot
of our old school on-premises stuff in
theory it's built for it in practice
most organizations are struggling to get
a handle on how much of it they've got
and where it is and who knows about it
and having enough people who understand
it well enough so I don't think we're
going to get to that for most
organizations for a while yet but I
think we're moving in the right
direction
key security controls to take away no
surprise as I say MFA all the things is
the first thing you want to check for
and segregating and hardening your
individual environments so that it's
hard for an attacker to jump from one to
another it's really valuable
um given that the cloud is by default
obviously out on the internet
um and put a particular focus in on your
your code management platforms your CI
CD pipelines these sorts of things and
treat them as the crown jewels that they
really are actually for your your Cloud
security
and with that I think we've got time for
some questions
potentially and we've got a microphone
there if we've got a got any questions
or I just stunned the whole room into
silence because it can't have been that
good there we go we've got one down the
front here
sorry there's a microphone just just
coming okay
should be separated but uh in a sense
student therapy one concrete quality a
sermon pipeline that goes through the
development anti-guality assurance and
the products and so how do you how would
you separate them from Etc
right so the question is how do you
separate separate Dev and production
when really you should have a single
pipeline for the lot
I would run both off the same source
code repositories it's just that you
want to make sure that whatever's doing
the deployment that particular step
there is separated for your Dev accounts
from your production so that if an
attacker gets into one they don't also
have the other and so the way that I've
seen organizations do this so far is as
I say you run it all off the same
repository and then once it's been
promoted out of the development stages
and all that pipelines run fine it's
then merged into a branch that is
approved to go run through production so
all the steps that happen in the dev
pipeline are all assured before it gets
merged into the branch that then runs
down the second one hopefully that makes
sense
good
any other questions
all right in which case I'll be around
for a while down here and if not and
you'll probably see me elsewhere in the
conference the rest of the day thank you
for joining me today I hope you've
enjoyed it
um and I'll see you all over a beer