alright let's get started
how's everybody doing out there having a
good Saint calm all right we have some
booze that sounds good too here instead
of dead silence so I'm Chris Mader and
my presentation is on quantum cryptology
Armageddon now don't worry I'm not gonna
get too technical I am NOT a quantum
physicist so you should all be able to
keep up these are the topics we're going
to be going over we're gonna give you
some quantum basics so you can kind of
know what we're talking about a little
bit understand the molecular level of
things then we'll get into quantum
cryptanalysis the offensive side quantum
cryptography the defensive side and then
we've got some some goodies some things
that you can play around with and I've
got references so you guys can check
this out later I don't have these slides
of this per se posted on the the st.
Conn repository at of slide deck but I'm
getting trying to get a URL there that
you guys can go and check this
presentation out later and also for the
the references the links to things so
you can check that out so let's dive
right in
Armageddon so quantum computers they are
people have been talking about the
threat of those they're gonna be able to
crack all of our codes and the internet
will just you know fall apart because
nothing will be secure anymore so we're
gonna start out with a little video to
get us in the mood
what about this Federal Reserve transfer
node Culpepper Virginia cashiers good
luck nine hundred billion and day goes
through there
that'll do punch it in it's encrypted
see
Bobby that last contact
anybody want to shut down the Federal
Reserve hmm hey don't screw around with
that thing please Carl what else you got
national power grid
we come
rolling
anybody want to blackout New England
Carl what else air traffic control
system
okay mother
oh my god cryptography systems are based
on mathematical problems so complex they
cannot be solved without a key Janek
must have figured out a way to solve
those problems without the key and he
hardwired it into that so it's a code
breaker
no it's the code no more so that is the
threat that quantum computers are
bringing or that's what a lot of people
believe that quantum computers will be
this supercomputer that can just break
through all the codes without any
problem because they will be so fast
that is called there's something called
quantum supremacy and that is the point
at which quantum computers will have the
processing power and ability more than
what our conventional systems have right
now and they're kind of measuring that
in qubits you know how many bits there
quantum computers have there's
estimations between 60 to 100 qubits is
what quantum computers are going to need
to reach that quantum supremacy there
also but it's it's kind of a moving
target of the traditional computer
scientists are increasing their
algorithms and things to kind of raise
the bar for the quantum computers to
reach and so it's kind of a fuzzy line
but it's soon approaching so there's a
concept called hacking wait so we've got
these quantum computers that aren't here
yet
but there are nation states ours
included and others that have collected
our encrypted information and there are
just storing it so they know that even
at the time they collected it the
computers they had couldn't crack it
they know technology is increasing and
increasing we're getting better GPUs and
those will enable them in the future to
crack those codes and we switch over to
just the microphone yeah darn thing
doesn't want to stay
all right they're still good all right a
little less distraction so yeah so
nation-states and other people have
collected these they've hacked into
systems collected passwords and such
information that they can't crack but
they're just holding on to it and
waiting for the day when either there
are traditional computer resources or
quantum computers will be able to break
those open and get to the secrets inside
so along with that the United States
just recently Congress I think was just
this month has the National quantum
initiative Act they are setting aside a
1 billion two hundred eighty million
dollars over a five year period to
invest in quantum technology quantum
research and into the quantum realm
they're realizing that this is a big
thing and we need to get involved in it
they've been involved in it but not as
much and China is investing a lot of
money we're behind them so the United
States is trying to up their game a bit
and catch up I think it's kind of
interesting that the budget number was
starts with 128 I think a computer guy
kind of had something to do with the
financing on that so that's the the doom
and gloom that's coming so let's look at
some of the basics of quantum mechanics
so we're going to talk about quantum
particles what they are and then three
concepts that are important to
understand quantum computers and the
things that we were talking about those
are superposition particle spin and
entanglement so jumping in if you all
remember from school your your physics
class atoms have particles within them
those will be the electrons the neutrons
and the protons and we've also learned
that the protons and neutrons have
quarks as well or that's another
particle so the
quantum mechanics is the study of these
smallest particles and their behaviors
and how they interact
most of the stuff the the deal with in
quantum physics is the electrons
manipulating and working with electrons
they don't use protons neutrons or
quarks so much the electron seems to be
the one they like but there's also
photons now it was traditionally the
idea of the you know light is a wave
it's not a not a physical particle like
you know things we have but they've
learned that photons actually have a
physical component there are light
particles and also that the other one
particles matter exhibit behavior like
waves just like they figure light did so
they're a little bit of a blend but kind
of the big takeaway is there's two kind
of particles that you'll encounter if
you read about quantum mechanics some
system uses the electrons but others
actually use photons to do the things
they do and we've got a couple examples
of that so those are kind of that the
basic ground level components we need to
work with superposition this is kind of
what gives quantum computers their power
or their magic
so traditionally in computers we have
ones and zeros our bits we can turn them
on and off and that's how we create our
numbers and do our calculations quantum
particles can behave as if they have
multiple states at the same time so they
can be a 1 or a 0 or that can be a 1 and
a 0 at the same time this is kind of due
to the the positioning you see your
little diagram here the kind of the
coordinates were the spin of a particle
so it can exhibit multiple values at the
same time and that's one of the
important things for qubits and quantum
computers is how they can be so fast
particle spin
so these particles if you sustained an
electron in a magnetic field it'll have
a spin and scientists have learned to
control that spin and and read it if
it's spinning with the magnetic field
they call it spin up state if it's
spinning against the magnetic field it
spin down state they use lasers to read
and change the spinning states of these
quantum particles and we'll see later on
how that gets used in quantum computing
but that's another one of the concepts
you need to understand entanglement you
may have heard about this one it's where
you take two electrons or two particles
the coupie photons and you and tangle
them together they are joined by some
kind of force and you can move them
apart and separate them and when you
change or read one the other one will
react as well and that's cavil that call
information
teleportation so yes we have discovered
teleportation yay and it used to be when
they started this the the particles were
very close together they weren't very
far apart they were like first couple
experiments was like millimeters apart
and then they were able to increase it
to centimeters and it they just keep
growing that distance that they can keep
those particles separated and transfer
that information and so that's called
entanglement I don't know if they've
figured out exactly what that force is
that joins the two sometimes they call
it spooky physics or magic but those
particles can be entwined and read and
send information to the other so those
are physics basics that we cannot need
to know so let's jump into crypt
analysis this is the attacking side
we're going to talk about the qubits
quantum computers and then some
information from NIST and the NSA on how
they feel about this and their
recommendations and the rest of the
industry where they're at
so we know classical bits are one or
zero qubits can be a 1 and a 0 at the
same time like we talked about if you
can see the little picture here this is
a quantum computer CPU or chip and each
of these little square boxes with the
equal signs in them is where an electron
qubit is being suspended and used so
this right here we've got 2 4 6 7 qubit
CPU now the way the computations work on
it is you can have 2 to the N
computations per qubit simultaneously so
number of key bits is to end so let's
say we have a hundred qubits you could
do 2 to the N or 2 to the hundredth
power of calculations in one step and
that's that number there at the bottom
which if you spread out that is pretty
darn big I mean we talked about you know
our our GPUs that we have are 10 a TTI's
can do you know some of the millions of
hashes in a second
this is exponentially bigger than that
now this is just kind of one one
calculation one CPU cycle so you'd still
need to develop your quantum computing
algorithm to process you know do
something like hash cat or like that but
that shows the power of quantum
computers that is the the threatens
threatening scary part but it's also the
cool part uses quantum computers aren't
just gonna be used for you know hacking
passwords even though it's what we're
talking about today they're looking for
them to do artificial intelligence
things look into chemical modeling
giving us new materials and all sorts of
applications so quantum computers are
not bad but there's a side we have to
deal with all right this right here is a
quantum computer it's what they look
like
these must be supercooled so I don't
know all the wires and things but the
little electrons that they use have to
be in a supercooled state for them to
work with them a lot of degrees below
zero I don't think it has to be absolute
Kelvin zero level and the quantum
computers isn't just a computer all by
itself they have to work in tandem with
a normal computing infrastructure kind
of like our current GPUs they'll have
the traditional computer where you kind
of set up the things and you pass your
quantum algorithm over to the quantum
computer it does its faste calculations
in math and brings you back the result
and you continue on with your your
project so kind of in that respect
quantum computers will never become
personal computers we won't have a
quantum computer sitting on our desk or
carry one around in our pocket I know we
think about technology well you know our
traditional computers used to be like a
mainframe in a room and then they you
know it came to the Apple computer that
we can put on my desk and now they're on
our phones and on our watches but just
count the the physics behind quantum
computers will prevent that from
happening
they'll I'm sure they'll get smaller but
yeah we'll never have one at home unless
you count cloud computing so there are
quantum cloud computing services that
you can sign up for and play with and
that will probably be the methodology
that most of us will have to interact
with cloud computers or quantum
computers will be able to access them
through the clouds send them our
calculations and get results back and
we've got some examples of those at the
end
so NIST has come out with a report that
calls a report on post quantum
cryptography and they basically assess
the threat of quantum computers now this
was back in April of 2016 I haven't been
able to find any kind of updated
references or Marceau but kind of like I
guess our top 10 2013 existed for like
the longest time until just last year
they finally did it top 10 2017 so the
as you can see zoom in a little bit
they've given some about recommendations
but what they see the quantum computing
will do to our current algorithms near
the bottom you can see all of our public
key algorithms are totally threatened by
quantum computing they will no longer be
secure to use RSA elliptic curve and DSA
those are very vulnerable to quantum
computers and the speed of the
calculations they can do our other
encryption stuff like a EES and the the
shah's or encryption in your hashing are
a little more resistant to quantum
computers and the power that they bring
we can increase our key sizes and make
them resistant to quantum computers so
we'll move on to what the NSA recommends
and again this is a report from 2015
kind of the latest I could find that
they've recommended but they give some
recommendations that you can do right
now if you've got a system that you're
doing encryption with your files for
your company or something look at
bumping up your encryption levels
because can quantum computers may not
totally be here right yet but like I
said there's the problem of the hack and
wait if you get breached now that would
just wait a couple years till quantum
computers are there and then they can
open up your stuff so as we will see the
NSA recommends like for example AES use
256-bit keys and they say that is
enough to protect top-secret this is
government stuff so if you feel your
company's files or top secret level bump
your stuff up to 256 bit encryption even
if they're not bump it up anyway we've
got the references for the different
publications like the NIST and the
Phipps if you wanted to read more on
those and what to do with them they've
got some so we've got the RSA we've got
some elliptic curve in there and they
recommend bumping up to a p3 84 and down
on the RSA minimum of 3,000 72 bit
modules so you can protect yourself
right now from quantum computers when
they get here these will be in the
slides you can get later on and also
I've got the reference links to these
documents so you can read more about
these the NSA and the NIST
recommendations so that's kind of what
we can do right now to help prevent us
prevent things or data from being
breached by quantum computers this is
where the industry is right now in their
progress on developing quantum systems
d-wave was one of the first companies
that really got into quantum computers
improved yeah we can do this this is
this is real stuff not just theory as we
mentioned quantum supremacy is estimator
for between 60 and 100 cubits and as you
can see where we're in the zone where
we're closing in on that Google recently
this year bumped their quantum computer
up to 72 qubits of processing power
before that IBM held the title at 50
cubits I'm sure they're working on
bumping that up further as well I don't
know as of today where things are but
that's the latest I've been able to find
now d-wave you look at them you go whoa
they've got 2048 qubits they've like
totally surpassed quantum supremacy it's
a little different their system is an
annealer now I don't know exactly what
an annealer does I've read about it
several times I still totally grasp it
but it's kind of a specialized quantum
computer those specialized tasks so it's
a little different than the Google and
IBM ones that could be used for like
quantum cryptography there's another
company called Righetti they are
predicting they're estimating in a year
they will have 128 qubit computer and
this was just a month ago he's the one
they made that estimation so it's at the
doorstep it's coming China has
definitely seen that this is coming zoom
into that and they are putting resources
and money into the quantum field here's
a chart compared to China versus the
u.s. the u.s. is the black line chai
need the red and they are putting a lot
of money into quantum technology getting
patents and developing their quantum
infrastructure and the u.s. not so much
now this chart doesn't include the
initiative that was just recently signed
so hopefully we're bumping thing up
things up a little bit
we do have some catch up to do and
that's what the industry sits there's
other companies out there but these are
the ones I was able to research and
present to you I'm kind of the leaders
all right
let's dig into what we can do about this
to defend ourselves in cryptography so
they're working on new algorithms that
are resistant to quantum computers and
we'll also go over some other
technologies particle key generation and
how that is like totally unhackable know
not everything is hackable right
you can always hack something and then
we'll go over applications of
entanglement so here's a list of some of
the new algorithms they're working on
one of them is called lattice based and
see the picture over there with the it's
kind of like a layer of grids and using
that to perform different calculations
that is resistant to quantum computer
power also multivariate polynomial
cryptography
that's all this algebraic math over here
that I don't understand that's another
one super singular elliptic curve I
sahjhan II then that one sounds fun
that one's all these little squiggles
here those are different elliptic curves
and doing calculations between multiple
curves so some of these algorithms
they've figured well we'll just fight
fire with fire
well if you're gonna crack our codes
with a supercomputer will use a
supercomputer to calculate them and so
it just brings it up to that level and
some of these these algorithms are
planned for that usage your standard
normal computer would not be able to
crank through these and and be useful so
some of these already they're being
designed to be used on supercomputers
we'll skip down hash-based is using
hashes to do digital signatures and
code-based is using error code
correction values some how to create
encryption the middle one here symmetric
key quantum resistance is what we talked
about previously using our current
encryption systems like AES and stuff
and just bumping up the level of bits we
use that has proven effective against
the power of quantum computers and so we
can use some of the algorithms we
currently have in a quantum world
so we're gonna give you an example here
of generating a key using quantum
particles so in this case we're going to
be using photons as I mentioned earlier
the the quantum computers and the chip I
showed that one used electrons to do the
quantum mechanics in this case I'll use
photons so what we have here is these
photons are gonna have spin remember
spin we talked about that in this case
we have rectilinear spin which would be
up and down or left and right and then
we have diagonal spin which would be to
the upper right or the upper left now
we're gonna have Alice and Bob and Alice
is gonna send Bob a key and she's gonna
do that by firing photons at Bob and so
she's gonna generate a whole bunch of
these photons and basically create a
bunch of ones and zeros a key and she's
gonna do that at random and she's gonna
use four different filters here so we've
gotta up and down and left and right and
her two diagonals and she'll swap
between the two different schemes and
the and the two different values just
randomly firing photons over it at Bob
now Bob is going to use filters to read
those photons coming at him now his
filters look like the ones here on the
bottom so he's combined the up-down
left-right into one filter and then the
two diagonals are combined into the
filter so he's gonna pass that photon
through his filter and read it so if
it's a rectilinear filter if it's up
he's gonna get a one if it's sideways
he's gonna 0 he uses a diagonal filter
he'll read the the diagonal spins and
get his 1 or 0 that way however he
doesn't know which filter to use whether
to use the rectilinear or the diagonal
so let's say Alice sends
and up and down spin photon and Bob uses
the diagonal filter he is not going to
read that photon correctly and it will
change the spin of the photon as he
reads it
so basically half of his reads are going
to be wrong the Heisenberg uncertainty
principle kind of dictates that that the
particle he's going to read he's not
gonna know which filter to use and when
he reads them he's either gonna get it
right or it's gonna be screwed up so
half the values are gonna be bad but
that's okay so the way they've worked
around that is now once bob has received
the bits he calls up Allison says hey
what was our filter scheme and she'll
say oh I used a rectilinear a
rectilinear a diagonal a diagonal a
diagonal or at Alinea a diagonal and
that way you can go all right now I know
which of my bits are good and they can
both agree on all right here is our
encryption key that we're gonna use and
that's how that works
there's a great video online the kind of
walks through it now I went through
several of them bunch them didn't kind
of really make sense until I found one
the like oh it clicked it was like yeah
that one's good I've got that in the
references for you guys so you're gonna
walk go through this now we're gonna
throw Eve into the equation here and
we're gonna kind of show how this is
impervious to eavesdropping or a
man-in-the-middle attack so let's say
we've got Eve
sitting in the middle and she's seeing
these photons passed by - now if she
measures one with a bad filter she's
gonna get the wrong result and it's
gonna change the spin of it that Bob's
gonna get so half of her guesses will
also be wrong because she doesn't know
which filter to use she's going to do
the same thing that Bob did swap between
rectilinear diagonal and just take a
guess and like I'll try this one so -
we're gonna be wrong now you say all
right but she can listen in on the
covers
stationed between Alice and Bob
afterwards and get the schemer right
which she can but it won't help because
she will get a different set of filters
that she used compared to Bob and so
even if she listens in on the filter
scheme of the rectilinear rectilinear
diagonal diagonal rectilinear
it's not gonna help her because she did
different measurements that Bob did and
so her scheme that she would come up
with like oh here's the key is gonna be
different than Alice and Bob really
agreed upon part of the trick of it is
doing that measurement beforehand and
then afterwards okay here's the the
filter scheme that we used so this is a
way that they're using quantum particles
to generate keys that are impervious to
eavesdropping there is a company here in
the States
called quantum exchange that is using
this technology they have a system for
that they have a an endpoint and they
send a key to another endpoint using
this technology and so any
man-in-the-middle attacks are useless
one of the problems though is is that
distance thing remember the particles
can only go so far the problem with that
is when they shoot the particles there's
the chance that particle will hit
another particle in space or in the
fiber-optic cable or whatever medium
they're transmitting these particles and
bounce off or get wiped out so that
distance thing has been a problem and
kind of all the the particles that just
exist in the medium they're using and so
to send a message you have to send to
one really point get the message Rhian
cryptid send it to another relay point
and down that way
so I know all the hackers are going on
there's the target hit the relay points
right you know I can't figure you out
figure out what the message is in
transition but if I can you know get
some code in there the relay point
that's where I can read
and that's true that's one of the where
the weak spots are China has done a
similar thing they actually have a
network between several of their cities
that uses this technology and they are
increasing the distance that they can
send things so they're starting to
reduce those endpoints those nodes and
increase their security level they're
also using another scheme which is
pretty cool
they are starting to use satellites so
they've got a satellite called the the
mightiest satellite and this has helped
them with that distance problem so they
figured well if you know we're
transmitting these particles and it's
hitting you know all the air and
whatever particles we have here let's
throw it up into space where space is
empty right there's hardly any particles
there that are going to interfere with
ours reaching its destination and they
originally did this between a couple of
cities in China and this is a little bit
different schema than what we went
before but kind of same principle so
they have the satellite and the
satellite creates two entangled
particles shoots one down in one city
shoots the other down to the other city
and now these two cities have entangled
particles the one city will read the one
and it'll change the value of the other
and they read the value of its paired
particle on the other side and we have
just sent a message between those two
particle bits and once again this is
entanglement there's no medium between
there's no way to you know guess what
that change was it's just there so
teleporting information I've read some
more and China has increased their
ability for that they've actually set up
a system a receiving station in Vienna
near Vienna so yeah they can send a
message between Beijing and Europe using
their quantum satellite and these
entangled particles so they're learning
to increase that distance and if you
think about like the technology it takes
to do that you've got a satellite
orbiting the Earth miles above the earth
and you're shooting a subatomic particle
down to a receiver station and hitting
their receiver and measuring that it's
yeah it's pretty amazing and right now
the United States we don't have anything
like that
you just have kind of the land
ground-based systems but I'm sure we're
working on it so those are some of the
things the methodologies we're using
quantum computers and particles in
defense so we're gonna jump into some of
the quantum Goody's things you guys can
actually play with so Microsoft has
developed a quantum computer language
they call it Q sharp you can actually go
to their website and download the
development package and install it into
Visual Studio and I'm sure you can
install it in kind of other development
systems they've got a link there for
Windows and also Mac OS and Linux and
you can start learning quantum computer
programming language and I don't know if
you can use it on a quantum computer
yeah but you can get a feel for how the
the mindset of programming a quantum
chip works it's it's a little different
with the whole superposition structure
and things can have a 1 and a 0 state at
the same time but that will give you an
introduction into that if you're
interested in going into the quantum
field and getting a future job as a
quantum software developer sounds cool
to me IBM they have a quantum computer
you can go and play with right now they
called their IBM Q experience they used
to have three bits they've bumped it up
to 5 but you can go to their website and
you can log in they've got tutorials
they're a bunch of things that'll walk
you through how to program a quantum
computer and it's and it's an actual
quantum computer they have right here to
kind of show you you got your ear this
one's a 5 bit quantum computer is your
bits their values and down here is where
your program will be you add these
different gate structures and things and
and create your calculations and you
send it over and it actually runs on
their quantum computer
get back the results so you can actually
go and play around with a quantum
computer now it sounds pretty cool I've
read some of things there's a guy he
created a little game that you that he
plays on the IBM quantum computer a
little quantum computer game so the
technology is here right now and you can
be using it Righetti they have a similar
system
I haven't dug into it too much but they
have a quantum cloud service that is in
beta right now and you can sign up for
the beta and play around with their
quantum computer and tangly on now this
is a game that was actually kind of
developed by the IBM people and it's a
board game that teaches quantum
computing concepts and things so you can
learn kind of a in an easy way the ideas
and concepts of quantum computers and
how they work it's shown here kind of a
nice little boxed set but it's actually
an open source thing you can down
download from github we've got the link
there and I guess you can like print it
out and play it at home and it's a kind
of a low enough level I got the hash tag
there checked out some tweets and one
lady said oh yeah I played this game my
10 year old loved it so it's not a high
level complet complicated game you know
if 10 year-olds can grasp it it's got to
be good and I haven't downloaded it yet
but I want to check it out and play that
so that'll help teach you some of the
concepts of quantum computers in an easy
way or get your kids involved get them a
jump on technology so those were all the
goodies that was my presentation here's
the references I don't expect you to try
and write these down right now I do have
them posted online so you can download
you can't download this presentation but
you can go to and check it out and get
those so up here I've got some links for
the quantum basics get you
quantum physics there's a lot of stuff
out there to read if you want to learn
more
the quantum cryptanalysis I've got the
links for the the NIST publication and
then also the NSA recommendations and
some other things on defense one and
Cuong computers where they're at
cryptography wikipedia has a good
article on those different algorithms
like the lattice and a super singular
aside genuine there's the youtube video
on that particle key generation
technique and some information on the
misuse satellite and links to the
goodies so down here at the bottom white
cap Cybercom slash 2018 saint khan
that's where you'll want to go and
that'll bump you over to the
presentation and you can flip through
these slides on your own and get the
references and check things out that's
my presentation any questions yeah no so
they started ground-based like I said
they were able to entangled particles
but they were only like you know a
centimeter apart and they've learned to
you know get those particles further and
further apart the problem was as they
got them further apart that kept bumping
into other particles right and so they
do have a ground-based system that works
but they figured hey let's throw it up
in space and that way there's not all
those other particles we're gonna bump
into we can get our distance further
away so you don't have to use a
satellite for that but they've figured
out that works really good and helps
them overcome that distance problem yeah
right but until you get kind of down the
lower levels of the air and atmosphere
is where you might bump into particles
and stuff that will throw off your
good question any others Yeah right
um I'm sure we'll still use passwords I
mean we keep trying to get away from
them but you know they're still there
the the quantum computers I'm sure
somebody
I'm sure the NSA and I'm sure China and
Russia are looking at those going to hey
we need to you know these are gonna be
our methods to break the other guy's
passwords and stuff so I'm not sure how
much it's gonna be you know Armageddon
or not as you noticed the encryption
methodologies weren't too vulnerable
blocked our public key encryption
schemes we're really vulnerable to the
quantum computers I'm not sure how much
our passwords will change we may have to
bump them up to more characters your
passwords will have 60 characters in
them now instead of 20 does that answer
your question
enough so any others the speed
instantaneous yeah so I mean you send
the particles once you get them there
yeah and then when I read this one that
one changes if we could build a particle
receiving station on the moon to receive
it maybe I don't know but yeah they're
working on that distance thing yeah it's
magic they call it spooky physics you
just changed the one particle and the
other one over here just changes
instantaneously I don't think I don't
know if they know what is connecting
them what force but there's some kind of
force they're able to entangle the two
together split them apart you changed
one the other one changes I think to the
opposite value that you did the other
one no they're doing it they are do yeah
that's satellite the China uses does
that it does that entanglement and
information teleportation
anybody else
yeah the back there
right
right yeah yeah you know anything's
possible but the science that are doing
right now they they don't even know the
force that's between them right so I
would say there's nothing in between you
could do to affect these but thinking
like a hacker
I would attack the receiver station
right attack them they're not you can't
man in the middle of that but I can
attack the receiver station and find out
what they read there yeah maybe we'll
find out and and maybe there's nothing
we can do about it it's like well we
know what the force is but it just is we
can't do anything with it
any other questions all right that looks
like it thanks a lot
[Applause]