okay so that everybody awake testing
testing
does that work for everybody get to
listen to myself talk not disorienting
at all how's everybody doing we awake
after that turkey lunch that I made a
executive decision on passing on so that
you all wouldn't have to watch me sleep
up here all right well one more question
so how many signed up for this session
using the using the online the online
interface and got a good look at Brian
cantos okay
if you did then I know what you're
thinking
Brian spent some time tanning over the
last few days right so I am NOT Brian
cantos my name is Dana Porter I am a
sales engineer with Vera dhin we are a
provider of a of an up-and-coming
security instrumentation platform and I
want to spend a little bit of time
talking to you about what Brian had
originally intended to explore with you
a little bit and that is the idea of
industrializing red and blue teaming now
by a quick way of background I have
worked in and around InfoSec in cyber
security for about the last 20 wall of
last 20 plus years I spent a lot of time
as a security practitioner working in
and out of enterprise and then I went
into sales back out of sales back into
engineering and so on but the reason I
the reason I say all this is because I
am here now because I really at some
point along the way I like to tell
myself that I like the idea of
protecting multiple and missions helping
multiple organizations fostering
relationships and helping multiple teams
be able to achieve their whatever their
security goals are
as opposed to just the mission of
whoever happened to be my employer at
the time I also I'm standing up here in
front of you today through a
conversation that I had with one of my
colleagues I'm actually from the Dallas
Fort Worth Texas area and one of my
colleagues in the Houston area was
telling me about some cool stuff that
somebody was doing with having systems
that basically run attacks against each
other and you know of course to somebody
you know to an audience like you I'm
sure that you can appreciate the novelty
of that sort of thing at least at a high
level so anyway enough about me
let's talk about why I'm standing here
today so Bryan if you know Bryan you
know that he has a way with with word
usage with word selection so when he
decided he was going to title this
industrialization of red and blue
teaming I thought you know that's pretty
cool
but why industrialization why if you
know of all things that red teamers and
blue teamers think about why are we
talking about industrialization and i
don't know if this thing is going to
stay on we'll get through this together
right all right let's try this again so
I'm talking about industrialization I am
one of those people that I believe that
words have meaning specific words have
specific meaning and I thought that I
immediately zeroed in on the use of the
word industrialization know Bryan's
choice not my choice but then I started
to explore this a little bit and I
thought you know there's there's
definitely something here and I'm going
to have a little bit of fun exploring
this and then hopefully we all get to
have some fun together as I communicate
some of my findings to you so words on
the screen right you may or may not be
able to read them if you cannot I
apologize but essentially we have a
couple of definitions up here right so
industry merriam-webster defines
industry as or has in its definition of
industry systemic labor especially for
some useful purpose or the creation of
something of value and then also
diligence in an employment or pursue
especially steady or habitual effort so
maybe you can see where I'm going with
this
and then industrialization is of course
pertaining to industry or the act or
process of making something industrial
but what we are going to explore
specifically today is going
to be in and around automation
automation automation automation of
specialized using specialized tools and
processes so let's do a quick exercise
when you think of industrialization what
are some modern-day maybe not so
modern-day examples of industrialization
that you have just thrown at me okay any
others Hubbell phones okay so can
anybody tell me what this is can you see
it okay Wikipedia a stock photo of the
cotton gin all right how about this one
INRI Ford's moving assembly line I
should in the Industrial Revolution I
believe it's widely accepted that the
moving assembly line was where the where
we officially started to see the
Industrial Revolution so these are good
examples historical examples I grant
granted how about something that is
maybe more near and dear to the world
that you and I live in who can tell me
what this graphic represents DevOps
anybody here familiar with DevOps the
cultural slash arguably philosophical
pairing or wedding if you will of
development and operations in the
pursuit of a common business objective
the ability to to rapidly and reliably
deploy systems in an iterative and
cyclical fashion or repetitive fashion I
think DevOps is a really good example of
modern-day industrialization wouldn't
you agree
okay these are all great examples but
what I would like to explore with you
with the time that I have left is
industrialization in the context of
information security assessment and
defense or right and blue teaming so
first let's look at some of the
challenges around offensive efforts they
tend to be time and resource intensive
and they don't always translate to
or even long-term defensive value and
what I mean by this is that we have I'm
sure that many of you have seen or
hopefully you've seen some of the
challenges around Red Team exercises and
you determine the rules of engagement
you determine the scope you determine
the parameters and you run you perform
an assessment or series of assessments
and then you have some output and then
that that output gets if it's at
depending on its action ability if you
will that output gets triage then and it
gets prioritized along with other with
other security operations or business
efforts right the problem with that is
at the best-case scenario there is that
these findings actually do get
remediated and even what we're finding
is when when once the findings do get
remediated there's no guarantee that
something is not going to happen between
the point in time of the initial
assessment and then whenever the next
assessment comes around that something
is not going to happen to reintroduce
risk into that environment through some
sort of a change so that is what I mean
when I say that offensive efforts Red
Team efforts don't always translate to
immediate business value and we'll
explore this more in just a moment but
let's talk about the defenders for just
a second has anybody had any experience
with or faced I guess dealt with the
challenge of defenders not really
working with an attackers mindset well
the challenge there is the obvious
challenge there is not being able to
operate within the attackers mindset
means that you're going to be somewhat
of a loss as far as being able to
actually tune the the defensive controls
the processes and the technology and I
have as a quick aside I've actually seen
firsthand some really good some really
promising efforts around a there's a the
area of the of the of the country that I
live in up in North Texas a see so
friend of mine is actually responsible
he actually built out he's part of the
DFW hacker underground community if you
will and he actually built out his a red
and blue program where he rotates his
staff like his staff will be build build
build you all there red for a month or
two and then and then and then the blue
will do a response for a month or two
and then they'll switch and a lot of
that is because of
his passion for cybersecurity you know
the guy is a bonafide
if I through it if I through his hand a
lot to you you've probably heard of them
but I'm not going to do that but he his
passion is what drives that you know
many organizations don't have that level
of that level of drive or that level of
expertise but that is really how you
start to crack the nut of the defenders
being able to really adequately and
efficiently tune the controls and
because they're able to operate within
that that attackers mindset so what we
really need to see and what what we are
starting to see more and more are
starting to drive the I guess champion
the message you know more and more is
how about the red teamers really start
we start looking at offensive efforts
and we start judging the value of those
efforts on their ability to measurably
improve defenses and as opposed to just
scanning finding an exploit validating
the exploit riding up the findings and
then lather rinse repeat and do it again
when we start to do this when we really
start to judge take the take the offense
take offenses efforts and marry that
with a real desire to measurably not
just improve but to measurably improve
defensive efforts then that's when we
have a concept that maybe you have heard
of that we're starting to hear more and
more of a purple teaming which is
essentially some some degree of
symbiosis between a symbiotic mutualism
between between red and blue where both
are working to establish use their
knowledge their their their respective
knowledge and establishing the own good
and then figure out how to measure
manage improve and communicate against
that known good or that baseline okay
so speaking of measuring managing
improving and communicating
cybersecurity effectiveness this is a
good place for me to to dovetail to
segue for just a second if you will and
I just want to say that cyber security I
mean one of the reasons that were so
we're so gung-ho about what we do is
because cybersecurity has historically
been but not being not been managed as
as you would manage any other business
unit you know business risk
as managing in in much a different way
business business risk is managed
differently from cybersecurity risk in
that cybersecurity tends to get money
just thrown at it right Cyrus especially
after after a after a serious incident
after a major breach or whatever there's
there's that whole that old adage the
checkbook opens up after a major breach
right well that's that's not sound
that's if we're honest with ourselves
it's not really sound business principle
you know if we look at some of the
others up here finance performance some
of the other KPIs up here
patient mortality rate you know these
things are these are measurables and in
measurables are what business by and
large makes its makes its decisions on
and the problem with cybersecurity is
yeah we have metrics we have I'm sure
that means some of you have built out
metrics programs I've built out metrics
programs you honestly could make metrics
tell whatever story you want them to
tell in pursuit of whatever it is you're
in pursuit of but it's not really and up
until recently it hasn't really been
measurement driven and this this whole
this whole idea of figuring out how to
get quantifiable data how to get how to
get empirical evidence out of the
systems out of the people out of the
processes in order to start making key
sound security or business driven
security driven business decisions is
really why I'm up here standing in front
of you so I'll just leave you with one
quick note for 2018 Gartner forecasts
that organizations by the end of 2018
will have spent in excess of 96b billion
dollars on security tools and services
to protect against to protect against
them recover from cyberattacks and as
such I have seen personally by my
colleague down here in the corner we we
go into organizations all the time and
we're starting to see with some of these
larger organizations we're starting to
see head counts created for secure
security program validation operations
basically people who were who were
charged with coming in and making heads
or tails of this security fiscal black
hole so with that I'm going to talk a
little bit about security
instrumentation and how it relates to
industrialization
now before I go any further security
instrumentation is first on the list
here I want to make it very clear that
there are other ways of cracking this
nut each has its place each has its
unique positioning and each has the each
has its own set of capabilities its own
set of pros and cons if you will I'm up
here as no obviously I'm a baron and
employee so I talked a little bit about
what I know I can do this without you
know I'm not you're not here to be
pitched to and I am NOT here to pitch to
you I'm here to share my knowledge with
the space with you and how and and what
security instrumentation what what value
security instrumentation in general lens
to the automating red and blue teaming
synergy with specialized tools and
processes so here we go what you see in
front of you is a graphic a graphic
representation of the of a security
instrumentation platform or sip and sips
in general are the are the I'm just
gonna put my head this is it distract
anybody if I just keep my hand up here
come on who's awake anybody still awake
anybody still with me awesome all right
if I get too loud just tell me anyway so
security instrumentation platforms are
the first business platforms for
security and they are designed to
provide empirical data to power
decision-making now we call this a
business platform I call this a business
platform because yes it is doing
security things which we will explore a
little bit more obviously but while
we're doing things in and around
security while we're all we're
performing security related actions
we're driving a business discussion
because the the the outcome of this is
designed to be that which is actionable
from a business perspective we're all
about providing or producing empiric
data or evidence and that enables the
organization that the security
organization does finally start to
govern itself as a sound business unit
not as a security Enclave but as a
business unit and this is important
because the ability of the security
program to function in this way means
that you really start to drive that that
the organization really starts to drive
drive a conversation with the business
worry it basically it gives the security
organization a seat at the table and and
and further drives home the messaging
that you know security that security
leadership gets that the business is not
there for security right it's the other
way around security exists solely for
the safe enablement of the business in
pursuit of its objective of pursuit of
its objectives all right so the SIP or
the security instrumentation platform
exists to provide provide evidence for
decision-making right well what kind of
evidence are we talking about and what
kind of decision-making are we talking
about well so again quantitative
analysis I haven't really explained that
in depth at this point but through
quantitative analysis provided through
security instrumentation you really
start to these things will really start
to make sense and when we're going to
explore these next but you're probably
thinking or I hope you're thinking okay
he's kind of I'm I'm kind of smelling
what he's cooking you know we'll start
to talk about security in a much bigger
business and a much bigger business
light business uses the business at
large uses evidence driven KPI is
evidence driven metrics to make its
decisions so we should probably be doing
the same thing with security what has
any of this Dayna not Brian what does
any of this got to do with red and blue
teaming we're gonna go into that next I
think this is the part all of you have
been waiting for hopefully all right so
here is one example of security
instrumentation and when I say that I'm
talking about one basically one this is
one approach granted it's our approach
but this is a approach to getting metric
getting evidence out of the systems
getting empirical data out of the doubt
of your systems out of your processes
that you can use to really start driving
this conversation so what you see in
front of you essentially what you want
to do is you want to start figuring out
ways and again you can do this through
multiple multiple different ways right
but you want to start figuring out ways
to do real things like real real real
malicious behaviors right
but you want to do these in an
environment that is as representative to
the real environment as possible
well how about production how about the
production environment okay they know
how the heck are you gonna do that how
you just how do I do that and not you
know basically generate a what is it
called a resume generating event I think
is what it's called how do I do that
well in varied ins case you're looking
at you have a you have a management
engine if you will or a director and
then you got we have a director actor
architecture we call it this I think of
think of like bit players in a in a and
a movie in a motion picture or whatever
right you have the actors who basically
they they take on a role on the screen
and then you have the director that
basically orchestrates how things are
supposed to happen sample sample network
environment sample environment right
sample production environment broken up
into logical broken up with logical
points of delineation where you have we
call these zones and these are points of
these these are basically choke points
in the environment that agree to be
broken up by either by process or by
technology for the sake of this
discussion we're talking about breaking
breaking them up by technology and those
then the actors which I mentioned before
you have your security controls across
the bottom these are and these are
representative these can be pretty much
anything but the actors actually get
deployed in these individual zones and
then what the director is going to do
based upon the configuration is based
upon your goals based upon the things
that you want to achieve based upon the
the real-world scenarios that you want
to simulate right the director is going
to reach out and in accordance with the
scenario that you want to play out the
director is going to start doing a
couple of things first it's going to
tell the actors involved in accordance
with the test that you want to run it's
going to tell the actors involved where
they need to be what they need to be
doing as far as what types of tests need
to be run and essentially where they're
you know which which actors at what
points of the network need to be you
need to start doing things so what's
going to happen next actor a on the
right and the internet takes on in this
scenario actor a takes on the role of
being the attacker actor B and a
high-value target appearances business
zone takes on the role of
being a target right there actors
attacker actor target actor the actor
the target the attacker actor is going
to do what its gonna start attacking
he's not attacking your network he's
attacking his counterpart at the other
end at the other end of the network
right real live fire malicious
activities happening across the
environment and what do you think
happens next what how do you think
interaction time what do you think the
tools that you see across the bottom
there what are those tools going to do
yes they're going to fire in accordance
I like to say with their capabilities
and their configurations they don't know
if this isn't real true this they don't
know if this isn't real life real
malicious traffic folks they as far as
they're concerned and attack is actually
in progress but wait it gets better
for security instrumentation for you to
be able to have this this is fine and
good right this is this is this right
here is called reaching attack
simulation but as far as getting
evidence actionable evidence out of your
systems and being able to use that to to
to start driving those conversations
that we talked about a couple of other
things need to happen at the at at a
management level you need to be able to
reach into these tools to find out what
they know about that attack right it's
not enough just to perform the attacks
for security instrumentation you really
need to be able to look into the tools
to find out what the tools had to say
and to take it one step further this is
where the real challenge is you need to
be able to reach into your aggregation
platform your collection platform your
security information and event
management platform your sim you need to
be able to reach into those tools to
find out what actually made it to made
it to the sim and why is that because we
all know that sim is expensive sim is
time-consuming sim is difficult sim is
very specialized and sim probably 75
maybe more than that percent of the time
does not get efficiently tool to tune
and we'll actually see some some numbers
to back that back up that assertion here
in just a minute sim is very difficult
and in order to to real really be able
to start to tune your analysts so to
speak you need to start tuning yourself
all right so that was a little
architecture not so much a very dim but
architecture of what instrumentation
looks like and how you can really start
to automate some of these things and
make your make your your attack and
response teams a little bit more
efficient let's dig into the read just a
little bit and I am going to at this
point I'm going to throw up here a quick
little video that I made and I'm just
going to explain it along the way so
that you can actually see what this
would look like if you were basically
hands on keyboard it's not okay with
everybody all right I'll put this down
and I'm going to with this hand alright
so what you see in front of you this is
another representation of the map that I
showed you the the end from the
architecture diagram just a little bit
ago you have your yeah if these locks
represent those zones that we talked
about the there goes you know your zones
and then you have your little actors
explain the actors just a little bit we
actually have in this example you see
that you there are network actors which
are in the in the other example and then
you have some then you know you want you
want to be able to do endpoint
assessments as well so that you can do
those as well now where I'm going to go
next is so actions are basically the
building blocks of of all this right
when we talk about actions we're talking
about basically these represent the
theoretical the real and theoretical bad
things that can happen in the
environment what you see here is an
action library and the point of this is
this is something that needs to be not
only I mean it's all great that we have
threat feeds and everything else
behavior research teams internally but
you also want to be able to ingest your
own data as well basically your own
samples your own pcaps
post Incident Response teeps pcaps and
so on and so forth I've now moved into
the into what we call
evaluations and evaluations are really
where the rubber is gonna meet the road
from a from a from a red team
perspective because red teams have their
playbooks right you have your playbooks
that you maintain you ever play books
that you add to so on and so forth the
as a matter of fact I'm sorry I have not
moved into that you haven't gone to that
next right now I'm demonstrating the
some some detail around what a
particular action looks like whether it
be behavior detection alerts which is
what you're seeing right now things that
might actually make it things that you
can expect to see in your analysis
platforms and so on and so forth but now
we're looking at the now we're looking
at the evaluations which are iterative
basically iterations on a specific
action case in point you might if you if
you map to the mitre attack framework
like we do you can actually start to
iterate your actions in multiple in many
different ways you can do this from a
DLP's perspective where you might encode
a particular piece of PII multiple
different ways zip it one times if the
two times it but ten times see how your
DLP controls respond to that you want to
be able to do that and then another
example may be an obvious example of
this is the multiple variants of the of
whatever malware du jour you have out
there find my semantics my SEP 11 SEP 14
think it's at 14 my sep 14 responds just
fine to this version of wanna cry but
what about this other variant that just
basically hit the wild how do i how do i
guard against that well rather than
creating individual actions you want to
be able to create evaluations and then
build upon those evaluations and then
add those to your run books make sense
what we're looking at now I think is
we've moved on into sequences and
sequences think of a sequence as an inn
to end campaign right what we're looking
at right here I don't know if you can
see it okay but there are multiple
essentially multiple groups of actions
here and we've got what's represented
here is a standard post fishing watering
hole attack compromise website
downloaded a particular I downloaded a
components and we just pause this for a
second so I can catch up downloaded a
malware component now my desktop is
owned I'm going to start moving
laterally looking for looking
something as I start to get to a target
of opportunity or a high-value target if
you will now I've gotten to this target
I've I've gained access to this target
of a gained access to something
interesting in this target's file in the
file system now I want to exfiltrate
that data well with the concept of
taking an action and building it into a
sequence you can start to do these
things you can start to build out into
end attack campaigns so when any of you
if you have a colleague that just got
hit by something nasty and it was a
multi-stage attack you can actually
rebuild an instrumentation platform you
can rebuild that attack in your own
environment and then safely run that
attack in your production environment so
that you can start to start to determine
where your gaps are and we'll talk here
in just a moment about how we expose
those gaps so I think we're all caught
up and essentially what I'm doing here I
may just go ahead and fast forward here
yeah I think we're okay what's happening
right here is building out that attack
basically what that looks like selecting
the actors involved it's multi stage so
it's multiple actors first stage would
be desktop to the internet second stage
will be desktop of server and then third
stage would obviously be server out to
the Internet's build that start to put
it together run it and then fast forward
to the end we start to see as we're
running this job we start to see some
things pop up real-time as far as what
was blocked but wasn't blocked what was
detected what wasn't detected in
accordance with those actions being run
which you'll see here in just a moment
think I'm actually talking a little bit
faster than I planned to but let's see
yeah here we go so here it's running
here the job is actually running now I'm
going to pop over because this is this
is an action in progress it takes a few
minutes to run obviously because you
want to start to get some data out of
your out of your protection platforms
but what's going to happen here is going
to move over to a to a job status screen
where this job has already been run so
you actually have the historic you
basically have the job history and
clicking into this one is basically what
that former screen looked like all
wrapped up all completed and that's
where we're going now so what you can
see here is this is what the once you
have run this campaign once you've
finished executing this campaign just
to see where you have things that have
been blocked as the left as the left set
of the left column if you will of a
green red and then an event generated
it's going to be the right hand side
clicking into one of these will
basically just show you where you have
where you have alerts what type of
alerts were fired by your technologies
and essentially if you can see this you
can see scrolling down you see in this
example for instance Palo Alto had its
own set of alerts no surprise there Palo
Alto generates logs for everything and
then if you look further down you can
see that we actually have two sims in
this lab if you will cue radar and
Splunk and then looking down at the
bottom you can actually see that you
have rules that actually bubbled up fire
that matched a correlation item within
Splunk and then or I'm sorry not rules
but alerts that masticore elided
correlation item in Splunk and then
alerts that did not so again it's that
whole soon sim tuning conversation that
we talked about getting getting more
bang for the buck out of the sim
figuring out where the sim is not
providing value and then actually being
able to start working toward driving
that conversation so that's pretty much
that I won't belabor that points so from
a red team perspective using
instrumentation platforms or any of the
any of the open source tools out there
open source action simulation tools
breaching attack simulation platforms
all of these are designed to be able to
basically add some real power to your
ability to to run run really good
assessments really accurate assessments
within your environments obviously each
of the each of the tools have their own
limited scope and they have their
individual use cases but this is just
one example so let's look at a let's
look at instrumenting and were
industrial izing if you will
blue for just a moment here so going
back to that job completion screen and
basically this is going to be a
conversation about measuring drift well
how are we going to measure drift
well you measure drift is defined as a
deviation from a baseline right so once
you have run the actions and in this
example
once you have run the actions in your
environment the way that in accordance
with your your objectives then you need
to be able to have some sort of a way to
go in and set the system up and this is
where automation is really going to come
into play you want to be able to set up
these jobs to be able to run on their
own but not only that to be able to
alert you whenever something deviates
from your known good if you will so run
the actions get the results to the place
where basically pass/fail is what you
define it to be and that's the other
thing that's that's very important to
note here is security instrumentation
platforms should not tell you what
pass/fail is you know you in your own
environments determine pass/fail the
example that I like to use the comment
vulnerability scoring system if any of
you have done have managed a
vulnerability management program you
know it's there's a lot of subjectivity
to something being dumped out of your
Qualis or your a rapid7 or whatever that
says this has a cbss of eight right well
you've got to take in to account some
environmental factors and so on and so
forth and then you've really got to
determine whether that is a
vulnerability that is real in your
environment so what we like to say is a
security instrumentation platform is
going to add some objectivity to your
environments subjectivity and what I
mean by that is you determine what's
pass/fail right DLP quick DLP example
might have a business use case where you
have to have PII flying around your
environment but you need to be able to
learn on it so blocked would be a fail
or not blocked would be a pass but not a
learning would be a fail and if you have
a developer that wants to work from home
and they siphon a bunch of data up to
their Dropbox
well not blocking that would obviously
be a fail right so different use cases
you define pass/fail within the context
of your objectives and then varied in is
just going to as an example measure
basically in any security program
security instrumentation platform needs
to be able to do this is going to grade
you based upon what you have spent what
you have defined for your environment
not on what that platform thinks is
right wrong okay so getting back to this
real quick when we talk about now that
we've now that we know what defining the
defining pass/fail means then where we
want to start being
we want to start measuring drift and
we'll do that through setting up
repetitive actions that basically
whenever those actions results in a
deviation from from whatever your
baseline is you should be alerted
accordingly and that's what's happening
here okay
now this is really where the symbiosis
if you will is really going to come into
play all of this to this point has
really been in a in an effort to provide
something provide some evidence provide
something that is going to be actionable
for the security team actionable for the
business as a whole act actionable for
senior leadership to really start making
decisions as to know what controls need
to be reproved upon where do we have
people or process gaps and so on and so
forth so it's all a bit about evidence
evidence evidence well how would a
security instrumentation platform
demonstrate evidence what does that
evidence look like so what's happening
here is this is a set of gauges we call
these our effectiveness gauges and the
the purpose of this being up on the
screen in front of you is to essentially
communicate that you need to be able to
drill down you now that you're actually
doing things in your environment
whatever platform you use now that
you're actually doing things in your
environment to be able to start to
figure out where where you have gaps
things that are getting through things
that are not getting through things that
are being alerted and adequately alerts
that are actually reaching the sim so on
and so forth now it's you actually are
doing these things you need to be able
to see where those gaps are and
basically all these all these gauges are
designed to represent is some immediate
drill down into where the gaps are from
a technology perspective right so in the
example that we have here that that
highlighted gauge if you will represents
malicious file transfer so what you can
see is that you have 200 investors 227
actions that were run that correspond to
malicious file transfer and these aren't
the only four in our case there are
others but we use these by default and
you can see right away that of those 227
actions
224 were not blocked and you can see
that in this case three were blocked and
Palo Alto blocked them but let's move to
the next column right we've got 220 to
220 detection and this is this is the
kind of information that is not so
readily available if you're not doing
something similar to this right because
again this is what this is designed for
it's it's fine that we had 2220
detection x' but we have two detection
technologies in this environment and and
Palo Alto actually detected near
everything but we had some gaps in
snorts detection how about we fast
forward over to the event the event
management over at the far right for a
correlated events or noddle notable
events right we can see that in our lab
environment and lab environments do or
can and I've seen them firsthand
translate to real world production
environments but this is what you want
right you want to know that you have and
not so much most people don't have
multiple Sims deployed but it's not so
much a conversation about the fact that
we're stacking up two sims against each
other as it is that you have a lot of
detections that were not acted upon and
that is what that last column represents
so again sim tuning the thousands
sometimes tens hundreds of thousands
alerts so that make it into the sim
depending on the size of the
organization they don't do you a whole
lot of good if you cannot correlate
those into something that a human
analyst can see
all right so again the purpose of
everything that I have thrown at you
today has been the production of
evidence evidence evidence evidence
powered decision-making one of the
things that this is kind of a rubber
meets the road moment for me I hope it
is for you too this is a sample output
from one of our own engagements and it's
not this is not a selling tool so much
as it is illustrating that this is a
this is a common this is a real problem
so what you see here and it may be hard
to see again if if it is I apologize but
what's your sit what you're looking at
here is that less than 1/4 1/4 of the
attack patterns that were run in this
sample engagement and this is a real
engagement obviously sanitized but less
than 1/4 of the attack patterns that
were run in this environment actually
were blocked and then less than half of
what was actually blocked had a
detection event that actually reached
the sim so again it's that's a not only
do we not have a have an enforcement
problem with with the lack of blocking
but we have a visibility problem as well
and then we also see a scenarios where
we see a lot of situations where actions
do get blocked but corresponding alerts
don't reach the sim or reach the log
management solution whatever that may be
and in that case you have a situation
where yeah it's good that you're doing
blocking but you know it may be
something that you want to know about
there may be an attack in progress that
yes it was blocked but maybe there's
something correlate able there that you
could take some sort of action on and
then finally for the actions that do
reach the sim again I think I've
believed at this point but for the
actions that actually do make the alerts
that represent actions or for the
actions that have alerts that represent
them actually make it into the sim we
have seen that less than half of the
correlation rules now these are the
rules that are actually configured in
the sim this is this is a this is a
different way to look at sim tuning
you've actually done the work of putting
those rules into the management platform
putting those rules into the aggregation
and correlation platform but the rules
aren't firing so that in this engagement
and this is representative
of many more I think you actually have
rules that are there but they don't fire
so what good is that
so again sim tuning discussion alright
so that's pretty much all I had for you
I don't know how I am on time Yeah right
about 40 minutes I guess I just want to
close with a couple of thoughts so when
you industrialize is that word again
right when you industrialize red and
blue through security instrumentation
you start to do a couple of things you
have the ability to obviously to start
tuning your security technologies right
you can figure out where security
technologies are missing things entirely
or maybe they're doing things or they're
maybe they're sending alerts but they're
not tuned to actually do a perform
blocking a lot of the detection
platforms actually are very good at
blocking as well and this presents you
with an opportunity to start to do so
that we can start to apply some
configuration assurance to our
environment and this is huge this is
that holdest this is that hole drift
discussion again how many of your
organizations have some sort of a change
advisory board or change management
change management organization how many
of you have had those clencher moments
where you have a question of will change
this about to be introduced and you're
like okay well we approve this but I
have a feeling we'll be right back here
tomorrow anybody ever seen that a couple
of hands so what Automation in this
regard really allows you to do and this
is near and dear to me because I did sit
on a cab in my last my last Enterprise
job before I moved back over here a few
years ago but what other thing I used to
see this all the time and in in
developments in shops especially agile
shops where where things are happening
in and and very compressed Sprint's I
used to all the time I would I'd like to
think of myself as I'm a security guy I
understand I have a background in
systems and network engineering before
moving only over into security so I
understand system architecture so on and
so forth these guys are doing things
that I just flat-out doesn't understand
problem is they have to happen right
these again security is there to safely
enable the business not the other way
around so we would approve these things
and we didn't get bitten a lot but I
would have loved to have had something
orchestrate able something automated in
hand to be able to help me determine
right away where my key points of drift
from a known good baseline work
especially with rapid development cycles
like what we were dealing with in some
of you are no doubt dealing with as well
so I will just close with saying this
and actually have this have this thought
hearing from I'm not I'm not ashamed to
read to you we've so you essentially
need to readjust so that we are focusing
on the secure on we need to think about
things a different way let's focus on
the effectiveness of our controls and as
opposed to just figuring just you know
point and shoot and then pray right and
with the regard to red and blue team and
let's just keep in mind that there
really needs to be more of a that we can
all work together at least in our own
environments within the context of our
environments we can really start to work
together to start to drive that that
synergy right that that symbiotic
mutualism where both teams are actually
working together where the red team is
working for the improvement of the blue
team and everything that the blue team
represents from a people process and
technology perspective where the blue
team is getting better through looking
at looking at some of the things that
are available through something like a
security instrumentation platform they
start to get a better understanding of
the things that the red team is doing
and then they can use that knowledge to
not only better tune security controls
but then the red and blue can come
together to start to establish using
their requisite knowledge knowledge
silos if you will to start to establish
and maintain that working baseline all
right so that's all I have for you what
questions questions comments concerns
Dana never come back here again turkey I
get it
yes ma'am I'm sorry I didn't see the
lights murder up here
yeah so if I understand the question
it's that that's a very good question
your your ask was you know in doing
something like this and move into
something like this or implementing a
I'm obviously rephrasing your question
right let me know if I'm off base but in
doing something like this
it's somewhat of a paradigm shift you
know what is this what is the impact to
the employee community okay so with
regard to security instrumentation if we
go back to looking at the architecture
we are talking about and and these in
our case these actors think of these as
sensors these are sensors throughout the
network and they only attack one another
so the user community never comes into
play here even in the case of when we're
talking about like an endpoint by
positioning this from an endpoint
perspective we're talking about using a
endpoint that is dedicated to that where
we're validating the controls on the
endpoint we're not so much doing
anything to the user the user themselves
does that answer your question okay
anybody else
all right well if you you're gonna have
to yell at me because I can't see you
but if I don't have any other questions
thank you for your time