would close it out and move on is that
the right thing to do hmm
so it was the analysts actually wrong
they follow their procedural steps they
followed the rinse and repeat cut and
dry copy-paste style of analysis they
probably follow for every investigation
because their organization says these
are the steps you must follow so is the
analyst to blame or are the box
checking styles of analysis the root
cause I mean maybe it's organization
like I mentioned locking them into
procedural methods these analytical
methodologies should be able to be
dynamic they shouldn't be cut and dry
like this so why we lock them in these
analytical procedural boxes shouldn't we
empower them to think just a little bit
differently so let's kind of run it
again with a without the limiting
factors of a checkbox style of
methodology so we'll empower the
analysts to think a little bit freely a
little bit more freely and approach each
data point in the investigation in a
dynamic way so let's get our Sherlock
Holmes hat our thinking hat on and get
to it alright so imagine that the first
run-through is actually fairly accurate
they followed the steps that they were
told to follow they verified none of the
data was actually malicious right except
for maybe that code so not exactly based
on the code if you were actually to
perform analysis on the blob of data you
found on the pcap you might actually
find something so taking a step outside
the old methodology we can come to the
conclusion that there may be some level
of encoding at play so maybe it's hex or
base64 encoding if you were able to see
a little more clear clearly you could
see that the letters actually go beyond
what's allowed for hexadecimal base 16
we know that ends at the character F so
we can see there's actually a key there
so we could probably assume it's some
other level
coding so we'll run it through some
tools maybe base64 decoder simple one
online or cyber chef which is my
favorite if you don't know about that
website it's a great resource for when
you're doing analysis allows you to
decode in code sometimes decrypt if you
have the keys available etc so maybe
your security devices actually have some
type of decoding feature in them I know
a lot of them do like blue code proxy
and etc have stuff like that but are
they gonna actually do it to the level
you need in order to solve the problem
that's in front of you so now we're
cooking this code starts to become
apparent after we base64 decoded it and
we can assume that this triggered from
web traffic and as you can see on here
it's definitely a JavaScript file so
could it be malicious or could it just
be simply just a random javascript file
like there is on every single web page
out there today but I do think raagh
does something here as you can see
there's still some level of encoding at
play as we can see there's two variables
here with random digit numbers along
with long strings and if you look really
closely you can see that these don't go
beyond F so we can assume that's
probably base 16 or hexadecimal so of
course the plot thickens because there's
a lot more at play than we thought so
after using a tool such as cyber chef or
your base 16 decoder we can actually
figure out what's going on in the script
now for simplicity sake for the
presentation the first variable is
actually a link to malicious domain calm
slash backdoor Exe if it's ever that
clear in the real world I think you're
doing great so it looks like there's
also a target destination com we can
assume that a user probably assumed that
a user probably clicked on a link they
thought they're going to target
destination com and if an analyst
doesn't really know anything about
JavaScript if it's really a few skated
to a certain extent they may be
wondering what the heck to do
and of course that's where we break out
our own Google foo or google skills to
figure out what's actually going on in
this script but it's in plain English we
can see that there is some level of
redirection at play here and the
location diagraph if you're familiar
with JavaScript at all but if not that's
what Google is for so using Google we
can actually figure out that it's
attempting to redirect the user so it
may not have been obvious in the
beginning to most analysts are most tier
1 analysts in the beginning but a
certain level of obfuscation was being
used in the script so obfuscation what
is obfuscation how should we deal with
it as analysts or how should we approach
these types of problems so according to
tech target com if their reliable source
obfuscation is the practice of making
something difficult to understand
programming code is often obfuscated to
protect intellectual property and
prevent an attacker from reverse
engineering a proprietary software so
like with every piece of technology
developed for a good purpose
someone has probably weaponized it right
so let's go over a few examples of good
things that are actually turned and used
for bad purposes so DNS being used for
command and control I can't even count
the number of times I came across a an
alert or an event that was triggered on
a malicious DNS query because the first
part of the DNS query was actually
basics t4 encoded and once decoded you
could see that I was going out to
several foreign nations our known
command and control servers operated by
certain apts I won't say too many for
classified purposes and there's what's
called inter protocol exploitation this
wasn't actually really cool and I
learned about during my web at Penn test
training basically in a protocol
exploitation is you're exploiting one
protocol through the means of another so
for example let's say that you're doing
a Whois search on a potentially
malicious domain and you want to get all
the records the text
records etc and so you select text
record and all of a sudden a script pops
up or a window pops up what's going on
well it turns out that I was discovered
a few years ago that if you embed a link
or a URL address to a script inside your
DNS text record you could actually
trigger some form of cross-site
scripting on the individual who searched
your text record so basically you're
using DNS means to exploit on HTTP and
of course there are tons of examples out
there of good things being used for
nefarious purposes
so given enough time an analyst could
attempt to reverse-engineer a piece of
obfuscated code but to be honest a Tier
one analyst isn't gonna have time for
that because the organization is most
likely having them work X number of
alerts per hour or when it comes down to
it's really just a numbers game but it
is possible they could it's not simple
but they could follow the breadcrumbs
depending on the level of complexity it
may take time but I've seen certain
levels of education where each each
random every other character was
replaced with a period or a slash and
that really takes some time to
reverse-engineer things like that so on
the initial run through the first part
of the investigation it was it was
fairly straightforward the analyst was
limited to some very restrictive
guidelines as far as their procedural
methods go and a simple methodology was
at play it wasn't really anything
detailed they didn't dive in each data
point like they should have so this
approach really operates along the lines
of assuming that the malicious actions
are going to jump right out at it at you
which is rarely the case and if it is
you've you've gotten pretty lucky in
your analysis game so a simple
analytical methodology may work
sometimes I'm not gonna say as we're
gonna work a harpist all the time and
may may be for your organization
it works 50 percent of time maybe it
works 80 percent of time but it's
probably not the case when it comes down
to the real deal stuff such as apts
attempting to conduct lateral movement
on
network and stuff like that but of
course that's putting a lot of faith in
the tuning of your security devices
unless you're running some fancy AI
machine learning behavioral analytics
device or network on your actual scene
that's taking in all that data from
secure devices you're probably not going
to be able to find stuff like this
that's multiple levels of obfuscation
conducting the farías actions against
your network so the final run-through it
started the same way as our first
run-through right the answer wasn't
blatantly obvious as we solve multiple
levels of eustachian at play so we had
to apply a different methodology now
there's not going to be one methodology
that fits all types of investigations
but we followed the breadcrumbs which
led to our final result the way I think
about it an investigation each data
point is what I like to call stepping
off points basically the stepping off
point should be anything any piece of
data that comes up in an investigation
and that data should of course spawn
more questions and the data analyzed
from answering those questions should
lead to analysis driven results and of
course this should feed back into that
starting point to see if it needs to be
run through again or if it simply just
needs to be added back to the
investigation or if it was a waste of
time but you won't know until you
actually perform detailed analysis on
each data point allowed so the question
is can you follow the breadcrumbs it's
going to be rare that an advanced
attacker such as an apt or some type of
hacking group is going to leave behind
simple breadcrumbs that's of course
unless they're wanting to see one I'm
wanting you to see those things so the
threats facing your organization in my
organization they aren't adhering to
limiting guidelines sure every military
operation has guidelines that they have
to follow but they're going to try
whatever possible to complete their
objectives and they aren't locking
themselves in to a procedural box or as
procedural thinking method so the
question is why should we allowing our
analysts to think outside the box can
greatly increase the odds of identifying
nefarious actions
so putting the puzzle together as
analysts or investigators we're often
tasked with putting pieces of various
types and amounts of data together to
create an understandable picture of the
events that led to an alert this often
can be time-consuming and require you to
think a certain way as we mentioned
thinking a little bit more outside the
box so an example of what really drove
this presentation was I was working as
an analyst when I first started and a
fellow analyst comes over asked me to
help out he says you know I it's it's
flagging but I can't figure out what's
going on so I followed my procedural
steps I checked IPs URLs nothing seems
odd here I looked through correlated
events to see if there's anything
flagged nothing in our historical
records but in the pcap just later our
investigation earlier there was some
type of obfuscated code at play
so after base64 decoding it I found out
it was JavaScript which fortunately I
knew a little bit of JavaScript at a
time and you could see there were URLs
encoded in hex just like in our early
investigation decoded those and running
through the code and really analyzing
what's going on it turned out to be some
form of crypto jacking malware and
what's funny of all places it was on a
baking site for a bread crumb recipe and
so I I never thought as an analyst I
would be doing analyzing malware on a
baking site I'm especially working like
for the airforce like you think our
focus would be on you know military
websites but turns out we have users
just like in every other organization
that browse to random websites so the
end game what have we actually learned
here I know we didn't really go into too
much detail on these investigations but
that was really on purpose it was really
to help you think that or realized that
you need to approach every investigation
in a dynamic manner our methods of
course should be adaptable to the
information that we have available to us
just with our stepping off points and
each point in the data there are each
point in the investigation and of course
there's no way our security devices are
going to detect everything unless you
know of course you got that crazy AI
machine learning if you use behavior
analytics machine which probably cost
billions of dollars so that's where we
as the analysts come in or the
investigators that incident responders
it's truly up to us to drill down and
find out if this alert was actually
malicious or if it was simply just noise
in the scene so the question is are you
employing the correct analytical
methodology like I said before the best
methodology is the one that is fluid and
can be implemented into every step in an
investigation and there's not gonna be a
one-size-fits-all here and that's that's
really what it comes down to is what
works for your organization alright so
in the spirit of sync on what's called
the bread crumb challenge so you may
have noticed that there may have do is
hex on each slide the challenge is of
course can you figure out what is
actually going on with that hex and the
first individual to contact me on
Twitter will actually get a copy of the
blue team field manual which is a really
fun book it's a great starting point for
investigations and such especially on
the host level so that's 200 stores it's
going to be at 5 special so special in
five underscore underscore capital K via
Twitter so any questions all right
perfect if you want to talk after this
come on up I'll leave this up for a
second so if you want to write it down
you want to send me the results to the
quiz probably give you guys until the
end of the day I'll be in the area
around the conference so feel free to
tweet me thank you
[Applause]
yes