keep to loud is that better
can everyone hear me okay awesome
alright well thank you everyone for
coming today my name is Spencer Haywood
I'm a security analyst with the u taja
keishon network my twitter handle is at
underscore bin underscore sh the slides
that I have presenting here today will
be our I posted that I showed them on my
Twitter feed so if you want to just
check it out I don't care if you follow
me or whatever just feel free to grab
the slides and look at it whenever you
need to my other handle is Heywood LH if
you are in the Utah st. slack channel
you'll see me in there I am pretty
active in there and yeah so I guess now
that it's 11 o'clock I can get started
so today I'm going to be talking about
port scanning and I I know that a lot of
people here at st. Conn will know how to
do port scanning they'll know what port
scanning is they know what ports are but
I think there's also a lot of
misunderstanding behind it and I think
port scanning is also widely underused
and so I'm gonna present some tools not
only for a newbie but also for more
experienced security admins or network
admins and so on that hopefully you'll
be able to take away from this con this
talk today but yeah if you have any
questions please feel free to raise your
hand during during my presentation and
I'd love to answer them otherwise I will
leave a section open at the end for
questions so if you want to wait for
then that's fine yeah so let's get
started so first we'll go into what a
port is so when I was trying to define
this it's kind of difficult especially
if you're trying to do you know my mom
would ask me what this presentation was
about that I'm giving and trying to even
describe what a port is is a little bit
difficult but Wikipedia has a pretty
good a pretty good article on it if you
check that link out it has more
information but a port is a number
representing a virtual interface that
enables software to interact with
services running on a single computer
due to the limitations of networking the
possible port ranges that we have our
ports numbers zero through six five five
three five can't go any higher than that
well-known port numbers that systems
often use for widely used services are
ports 0 through 1024 often your most
interesting port scans will be in those
port ranges but you can often change
services to run on different ports so
they are not limited to port 0 through
1024 service is running on specific
ports often broadcast banners that
provide information about the services
so if you do a port scan and you're able
to snatch banners you can often identify
really interesting information about
your targets so here's some common ports
you should be familiar with a lot of
them so 21 FTP 22 SSH ones that we all
use on a daily basis our port 80 in port
443 both for HTTP and HTTPS but you can
check this list out these are some
interesting ports that you'd want to
scan if you're doing a port scan
especially during an audit or if you're
just trying to inventory what's on your
systems so talking more about banners I
went into it a little bit but banners
advertise relevant information about
network accessible services on a
computer this is also from a Wikipedia
article about banner grabbing
administrators can use banners to take
inventory of the systems and services on
their network however an intruder can
use banners to find Network hosts that
are running on running versions of
applications and operating systems with
known exploits so if you do port
scanning correctly using banners you can
identify versions of systems that are
running and you can correlate those with
known exploits and therefore run those
exploits on those systems and get into
the system so here's an example of a
banner I grabbed I blurt out the host
names but I just used telnet to to grab
the banner so I tell them edit into this
host using
port 80 and you can see here what the
output looks like and then you see the
command that I ran under under escape
character is control and then that
bracket you see the command I ran which
was get slash HTML 1.1 that get command
is just meaning I'm trying to grab the
root directory of the web server using
HTML version 11.1
and to dissect that response a little
bit you get all sorts of really
interesting information so you can see
one the version you see 200 on there
that's the response code so that means
that my connection was successful and
you see okay the meaning that the the
connection was okay you see the date
that I did the connection you see what
what kind of server is running so this
is an Ubuntu server running Apache 2.4
dot 18 so just that information alone
that server portion if we found some
vulnerabilities specific to Apache
version 2.4 dot 18 you could use that
easily against this server I believe at
the time that I did it I had patched
this machine or I might have just
scanned a random host I don't really
remember but obviously as you can see
there's lots of information that you can
grab from these banners
so who does port scanning like why would
anyone care there's a lot of different
entities that do port scanning and we'll
go over a couple of them so shoten is a
great service I'm gonna be talking a
little more about them and later in the
presentation and how to use them but
showdown is a service where you can go
online and see what kind of ports have
been scanned on different servers so
let's say you want to check out your
home IP address and what's been scanned
on it you could type in your home IP
address and show it in and it would
return results if it had been scanned
before if it hadn't been scanned the
results will come back with nothing or
if you're not running anything
interesting it might not have any useful
information
Simon is another service similar to
showed an same with senses zoom I rapid7
and then of course
you know postulating here there's
probably three-letter agencies doing it
you know they're probably trying to find
all sorts of interesting stuff on the
internet for whatever reasons and then
most importantly hackers are trying to
do port scanning so if you've ever set
up a server and you just watch so let's
say you set up a server on the internet
that's completely accessible almost
immediately once it's set up if it's
publicly facing it will immediately
start getting scans hackers are just
always doing automated scans and they
somehow automate the harvesting of those
results and they automate attacks on
those but this is really important
because do you know what hackers see on
your network like have you done a port
scan of your network and and see what
what they see because if you don't know
what you're advertising you don't know
what what your attack surface is
obviously there's lots of different
attack surfaces that someone could take
but this is a pretty significant one
because if you don't know what you're
advertising and someone connects to it
and and it's a vulnerable machine they
they could completely exploit your
system remotely that's why port scanning
is so important is because it's a
completely remote attack that you can do
someone in India if you have a
vulnerable server that's completely
accessible to the web someone in an
India could hack it get into it and boom
you're now your network is pwned and so
that's why this is important youyou got
to know what you're advertising so what
are the benefits of port scanning so the
first like that Wikipedia article says
inventory and network accessible
services is really important even if you
don't use it for security it's really
helpful to inventory what devices are
broadcasting what you can use that for
troubleshooting servers you can use that
for all sorts of things inventory is so
important the second thing that I found
interesting once I started doing port
scanning on a massive scale is that you
can identify misconfigured network and
fire firewall rules so for example at my
at my job we do a port scan of our
network and we've seen multiple hosts
running port 389
completely accessible externally port
389 is an LDAP port and LDAP is commonly
used for services like Active Directory
that's what Active Directory is it's an
LDAP service and so if that's accessible
externally someone may be able to
potentially remotely exploit your Active
Directory server and start collecting
information on users passwords and so on
and then most importantly I think for
security of professionals is identifying
vulnerable devices and services through
banners like like I showed earlier if
you find a version or server that's
version of a server that's vulnerable
you can easily use port scanning to do
recon on what what services are
vulnerable and then again just just to
emphasize you can always use more
inventory in your network inventory is
so important you need to establish
what's normal and what's irregular and
you also need to establish what
shouldn't be externally exposed and what
should be so now we're going to go into
some useful tools all of these are open
source and so if you wanted to you could
start you could download all of these
tools and start using them today you
could the these are really really
incredible tools that security
professionals use everywhere so just
going over some of them so the ones I'm
going to go over today are going to be
netcat telnet a telnet and map mask an
and shodhan some others that a co-worker
recommended that I look at are these
others unicorn scan one-two punch flash
scan cannon they're all really awesome I
would recommend you check them out
because they are really sweet tools for
automating a lot of this scanning and
also exploiting the results that are
found so I would definitely check those
other ones out although I'm going to be
hitting more of the basics so first
we're gonna go into show Dan so show Dan
is a port scanning search engine so like
I said earlier let's say you wanted to
see what what results show Dan has
indexed on your IP address on you could
go to showed an i/o type in your IP
address
and see all of the ports that are
externally exposed so there's three
different ways to explore showed and
search results so the first one is
through the web interface which I would
recommend the second is through their
command line and their command line tool
is very well documented
John Maithili the the creator of show
den he he releases little snippets of
videos every I think every week to show
how to use show dance command line more
effectively so I would definitely
recommend using their command line as
well and then they also have an API in
which you could write your own tools to
interact with it if you're if you're a
developer I would definitely recommend
doing that you could easily build some
security integrations using their API
it's a really awesome tool
so first we'll go into show dens web
interface so shoten provides an easy to
use web interface for retrieving
showdowns search results similar to
Google showed n has dorks that can be
used to return more specific research
results that link if you find this slide
I'll actually show you what it looks
like but this link is a Twitter post
with a whole bunch of helpful showed and
dorks you can't really see but in the in
the image there's the search results or
the search that they've done and the
results that have come back so I would
definitely recommend checking out this
this Twitter post because it's really
helpful for knowing what dorks to use
and what examples and then some example
searches that I've done you can see here
so this dork I'm using is org Comcast
cable and then I'm scanning port 80 so
any any showed end result that has come
over an IP of Comcast cable with port 80
externally exposed will be available in
the search result show den has some nice
features where you can export all of
these results into a PDF or CSV and then
you can start chopping the results up as
you need to
another one is city salt
city/country us these these showed and
orcs are really helpful for they're
really helpful for narrowing down your
searches so if you're a large ISP like
where I work
it's really helpful to be able to use
these showed and orcs to see what other
people are looking at because most
likely if the results are publicly
accessible on showed an a hackers found
it and they're trying to exploit your
system they're probably trying to do
something malicious on it so I
definitely recommend if you haven't
checked out show den I would definitely
recommend checking it out it's probably
the most popular port scanning online
port scanning service that's available
right now I would definitely recommend
checking it out and see what other
people are looking at on your network so
here's some examples with their CLI tool
so it's written in Python so if you have
pip installed you can just use pip three
install shoten well I prefer Python
three so you could just use pip install
shoten if you want to do the Python 2
version and then some other useful
examples in order to use showed ends
command line you have to have an API
which if you sign up with a free account
you can get a free API education gets a
large discount on the features that are
available and then there there's some
other helpful shoten command line tools
again John math really releases helpful
hints on how to use showed in so I would
recommend checking that out as well one
thing on the last on the last section
that I would recommend doing is you can
create alerts in show 10 so when an IP
address in your in a specific subnet
shows up in show Dan you can have an
alert generated and sent to you which is
only accessible via the command line so
you have to if you want to create an
alert you have to use the command line
tool but I would recommend creating
alerts one of the first things that I
did at my previous job was creating
alerts in show Dan so that way if if
some funky results came up I'd know
about it immediately and again because
hackers are going to be looking at this
as well you're gonna want to know if
something in your eye
space comes up so now we're gonna go
over some funny examples that I've seen
on show Dan so this first one is so I
you can't really tell sorry about the
resolution but what I did is I searched
for a hacked
that's all I searched for in short and I
just looked for hacked and then it
returned a whole bunch of machines with
banners containing the word hacked in it
so a great example the first one is the
hostname is hacked router help
SOS default password the second one is
hacked FTP server the third one is
hacked router SOS was MF worm infected
the the last one is hacked router help
SOS had do passwords so there's all
sorts of funny things that you can find
on the web and what I've what I really
like about show Dan is that there's all
sorts of interesting things that that no
one has ever looked for there's all
sorts of combinations of dorks that you
can use and using those dorks you can
really find some weird stuff out there
on the Internet
so this was a good one I just did a
search for a camera a specific type of
camera I blurred it out though but if
you look here this guy's living room is
completely accessible to the Internet
and it's like super creepy I went to
that I went to the link as well and it's
totally live this this person's living
room is just totally open to them to the
internet which like totally awesome I
was super happy about this when I saw
that I was like men like this guy's
living room is on fire and then this
last one was the funniest one I found so
I actually didn't find it I I was
following someone on Twitter and they
posted this and I was like this is
amazing so if you don't know what this
is this is a hardware device that
contains two-factor authentication keys
and what this person did so one of the
big reasons behind two-factor
authentication is that you log in and
you generate or you log in using your
password and then a random code is
generated that you know would be pretty
hard to guess even if it's six six
characters it
you know it time times out after 30
seconds typically so after 30 seconds
that six digit code is completely
useless if you found out this person's
username and password there's their
second factor authentication key it's
completely accessible to the web I
thought it was really awesome I was like
man this is effective two-factor
authentication right here so yeah
there's all sorts of weird stuff that
people put on the internet even if you
don't want to do it for security reasons
if you want to just lurk like show it
ends a great place for that it's awesome
all right so now we're gonna get into
some more command line based tools and
they're they're pretty simple again a
lot of you will know how to use them and
what they're used for as well as their
syntax I'm just going to go into them on
a pretty surface level for port scanning
so the first one is netcat so if you
look here netcat on certain systems the
full command is sometimes netcat
sometimes it's just NC it's available on
a I think all UNIX systems come with it
by default but if not on a bone - you
could just do like sudo apt-get install
netcat and so on but if you look here I
did a netcat on one of my home home
servers on port 1024 and as you can see
so netcat and then the IP address and
then the port number that you're trying
to scan and the output as you see is SSH
to OpenSSH 7.2 P - bun - for Ubuntu 2.4
so you know it's an Ubuntu server
running OpenSSH on port 1024 really
useful information and then I did the
same thing with telnet I prefer when it
comes to scripting stuff I prefer netcat
because as you can see here in net cats
man page it says unlike telnet netcat
scripts nicely and separates error
messages on to standard error instead of
sending them to standard output as
telnet does with some so if you use
netcat it's a lot more scriptable so I
would definitely recommend just using
that if you haven't used either of these
two out of habit I just use telnet so I
as you can see I tell NetID to that same
host on that port as well and it came up
with the same
output telnet is no longer pre-installed
on Mac OS just just so you know it's
actually not pre-installed on a lot
anymore just because telnet was a
unencrypted protocol so nmap is a really
awesome tool again a lot of people here
at st. khan will already know how to use
nmap but it's it's a really cool tool
there's all sorts of really interesting
functionality that nmap has for example
there's vulnerability scanner plugins
there's all sorts of different plugins
that you can use for it but I'm just
going to go over the basics so the first
is man and map that's how you look at
the man page I would definitely
recommend checking that out
the second is n map - lowercase s
uppercase P and then the IP range that I
want to when I do a sweep on so s is
scan P is for paying so I'll do a ping
sweep on this slash 24 in this example
and then another one is you can use n
map to detect operating systems
so what n map does is it connects to a
host then the host responds with
specific information and map will use
that information oftentimes to
fingerprint the host typically on more
well-known systems like Windows Linux
Mac typically n map will come back with
pretty accurate results but sometimes
depending on how you have your network
configured as well as depending on the
device sometimes it'll come back with
inaccurate results but overall it's
still really useful to use that flag
this next command is n map lowercase s
capital S and this does a silent scan so
it does a TCP connection test on all
default ports there's a - P flag that
you can pass to n map to scan more than
just 0 through 10 24-hour the default
ports but if you do this silent scan
it'll come back with all of the ports on
0 through 1024 it'll come back with what
they're running if they're open or if
they're filtered that means that it's
probably firewalled off and then on this
last example just that same command
using but we're doing a port scan on
that single host
doing port zeros through 6 5 5 3 5 so
every possible port will respond in this
command there's also some really nice
flags for nmap to increase speed as well
as like lower speeds so that way you
know you'll want to use lower speeds if
you want to be you know more quiet on a
network whereas if you don't really care
you can do capital - capital t-55 is the
fastest speed and it'll just it'll run
all the scans that you've told it to
yeah so those are some of the the
commands some useful commands that I use
on a pretty regular basis with nmap so
here's an example of nmap so I just did
the scan on all the ports all the
default ports so if you look here this
is a linux server that i set up
specifically for this so port 22 is ssh
you see a that the state is closed port
443 which is HTTP is open port 5 1 4 is
open port 1024 which I'm running SSH on
in this example is open but it
inaccurately identified the service but
still it's useful to know what is open
and then 6 7 8 9 and 8 1 8 1 or some
other services that I was running as
well but you can see an map comes back
with a lot of really useful results in
port scanning to identify what kind of
systems are you're targeting so I like
masscan so masscan is similar to n map
in a lot of ways but I like masscan 4
this is just a personal preference but I
like masscan for huge swaths of IP
address IP address ranges one thing that
I would recommend is if you install
masscan especially on linux build it
from source because the repositories
don't have updated versions of masscan
and mask n has had some nice new
features come out and it's no it's
really not that hard to build if you
just check out the mass can read me by a
Robert David Graham on github if you
check that out he has to build
instructions in the read man it's it's
pretty straightforward to build but you
see here I have a basic usage so you
look here
we have the mask and command invoked and
then - P with the port ranges that I
want to target and then after that the
IP addresses slash ranges that I want to
target the syntax by default is pretty
simple but it can get really complex and
mask n has some really cool feature so I
would definitely recommend checking out
the man page or actually the help page
for mask n because it doesn't have a man
page currently but yeah I would
definitely recommend using that tool for
mass gaining of large ranges of IP
addresses according to the readme of
like it says here this is the fastest
Internet port scanner it can scan the
entire Internet in under six minutes
transmitting 10 million packets per
second so it's really fast it's an
awesome really low really well developed
tool so here's an example of here's an
example of what I used mask scan for so
we invoked mask an and we're doing ports
0 through 10 24 and we're scanning a
192.168.1.0 slash 24 range and then you
can specify the rate in which you want
mask and to run at so if you don't have
a really big network or a really robust
network I've seen masks and like make
like when I run mask an on my home
network it just like totally makes
everything super slow so just just be
aware of that if you do a faster rate it
might slow down your bandwidth if you
don't have a really robust network and
then I just specified the interface that
I'm using on that specific Linux server
yeah again I would recommend checking
out the the github repo because the
readme has a lot of useful information
so port crawler is a tool that I wrote
that is a wrapper around masscan and
essentially what this port crawler
script does is it creates almost like a
self-hosted showed an instance so if you
have a server that you can spare for
port scanning this would be a really
great time to use it and the project
that I made you can see the URL there
it's github.com slash Heywood LH slash
port
- crawler - PI all capitalized I would
recommend checking it out I have a
simple and
stall script it installs elasticsearch
Cubano and mask an for you
currently the install script is limited
to a bun - and CentOS so if you want
another distribution or operating system
supported please just open a github
issue request and then just tell me what
you need and I'll try to get it ready
but I'll go over some examples so if you
want to check it out I have a demo setup
the URL is HTTP scanner hey woody me
port 9000 and it's got a username and
password and you can see it here so the
username is PC 2018 admin PC uppercase a
and admin uppercase and the password is
port crawler P and C and port crawler
are capitalized port crawler 2018 and
then the hosting costs were provided by
a gray well design so I'd recommend
checking them out they're great web
hosting - web design firm but I'll show
you a little demo of what it looks like
but this is this is an example of a
project you could set up in your
internal network to start doing
inventory
port scanning on a really large scale so
this is an example I have set up so you
see here there's all sorts of really
useful information sorry that the fields
are a little small let me see if I can
so you you can see here in this
dashboard that I have set up you can see
all the different ports that are running
so the port's the hosts that I'm
scanning are three honey pots that I set
up so if you want to scan these IP
addresses I don't really care I'm going
to destroy them in a few days anyway
but you can see this this cubano
dashboard really makes it super easy for
me to parse through the results so let's
say so we can look down here we can see
all the different IP addresses that
we're scanning and so let's say we want
to filter by this one IP address we can
filter for this value and boom we can
see all the specific results for it here
we have a daily histogram if we go to
this last day
which I think was a I think I have it
scanning at 1:00 in the morning every
day so this will be today's results if
we hit on that filters are even further
down to the results that it picked up
per day well this day and so this is a
really useful tool so on I work at an
ISP and we have millions of IP addresses
and so using this we can find all sorts
of really interesting information on
what's on our network more importantly I
think again for inventories sake it's
really important for you to know if an
attacker we're if an attacker we're
scanning you externally or internally
what they would see so yeah feel free to
check out the the github repo that I
have posted if if you need help getting
it set up feel free to open up an issue
or talk to me on Utah sane or just talk
to me after this presentation I don't
really care I'm fairly approachable but
I'm out of time so I'm not going to be
going out for any questions but thank
you so much for coming and hopefully you
were able to learn something useful from
this thank you