great how's everybody doing yeah so I'm
the last talk so that means I can go
over maybe maybe a little bit I just
thank you yeah so a little bit about me
I was stationed here I was in what was
called first radio battalion back in the
90s
I'm battled yes and it was an amazing
experience in fact first ray of
battalion is now in California so I'm
glad I had that opportunity while it
lasted
I really enjoyed a lot manalo Beach and
I think I spent too much time at dukes
and mousses and World Cafe and Zanzibar
and Pure Barre and yeah these old places
right all right so it's been eight years
since I've been back to Oahu so I was
wondering if there are any new
transportation options so caillou bird
it was a long trip I actually did
confirm and did try to pay and I
cancelled at the last minute because it
was unknown amount and I was like this
could be bad so after the Marines I went
to the University of Florida and I later
worked for government contractors such
as PwC Booz Allen and then I went into
commercial world with Leviathan security
now I met octa who hears heard of octa a
couple of you okay so we do identity
access management and I'm the lead
researcher on the internal research and
exploitation team or otherwise known as
Rex a nice little dinosaur I also write
code and I like to flip bits for fun
that's my github no sig ant work in that
background at all with the secret
squirrel being the name right I wrote
something called backdoor factory which
will do file infection on elf mock oh
and PE files and the files still work
normally it does it on the fly it's
automatic it's doesn't statically there
were this in 2013 and then I wrote
BDF proxy which will infect binaries
during download over HTTP it's kind of
fun so this led to me finding a sabre
cybercrime group infecting Windows
applications over tor and this was back
and like October 2014 yeah so enough
about me today we're going to talk about
some code signing basics I'm gonna give
you a demo I'm flipping the script I'm
gonna do the demo upfront to show you
impact then I'll talk about the details
and do some what about isms with
gatekeeper and then we'll talk about the
disclosure process how to do these
things correctly and how I found the
vulnerability so so code signing is a
security construct that allows for
consumer end-users to verify who signed
the code and also to verify that the
code in question has not been modified
any failure either at the OS level or a
third party developed tools can have
disastrous side effects especially for
security practitioners that do defense
and Incident Response now
both Windows and Mac OS or Mac OS
support the concept of portable sign
code there have been issues in code
signing in the past however we're
focusing on issues in and Mac OS
third-party developed code so I'm gonna
go ahead and do the demo excuse me while
I try to fix everything here okay in
this demo we have Google Santa in full
lockdown mode and Google Santa is a
white listing - who knows what white
listing is a lot of you okay so this is
developed by Google and they use it
internally by default only native apple
code and Mac OS app store code can run
and I'm in this in this demo the concept
is that I was able to get onto the box
via phishing social engineering
is USB devices or post exploitation and
I dropped a executable on the machine
and I'm going to bypass whitelisting and
this also will show that this can allow
for persistence in plain sight so let's
go ahead and do the demo so you
everybody see that it's kind of small
so on the Left we have there's so
there's two VMs here or or two there's a
VM on the left and in this VM it is High
Sierra fully patched there's two
terminals open the top one is a root
shell just just I'm going to show you a
privilege privilege escalation
bug in homebrew if you install it
default and then also in the lower
terminal is just the regular admin user
and so on the right we just have netcat
listening on a port and i'm going to get
some shells back so I'm going to open
calculator to show that regular
applications run and then I'm showing
that Santa control is indeed in or
Santa's in lockdown mode okay I'm going
to try to actually execute netcat from
in map suite and it does not execute
Santa blocked it as it should have
because it's not signed
so I'm gonna show you right here LS so
LS this is the malicious binary and I'm
going to execute that you'll notice that
it's an user local Bend all four routes
and the normal user user local bin is
what is first in the path okay so if an
attacker gets on your machine and drops
a executable into use or local bin and
if you have homebrew that means that if
the any attacker that gets on your
machine can write to this directory so
we're gonna go ahead and execute LS and
you'll see I get a connect back shell
okay and notice that whitelisting isn't
is installed on this machine and i
bypassed it so here we go
now so we had the connection back I am
the tester user and now I'm going to
show you that the same path exists in
for the root user okay so now execute LS
and then I get a connection back for
root
yep pretty easy so that I'm going to
disable Santa lockdown mode and I'm
going to use objective sees what's your
sign tool to show that it also thinks
that assigned by Apple now this is not
signed by Apple
so I does everybody get the impact of
this bug so now I'm going to use Apple's
own code sign tool to show that this is
signed by Apple and that just shows who
is signed now I'm gonna do what we call
strict checking to show that it is
validly signed all right so that's the
demo so how does this uh yes thank you
thank you let me change your arrangement
all right all right so this bug was
published a month ago exactly a month
ago and it kind of hit a lot of
different news outlets it motherboard
ours Gizmodo Washington Post and so
there's a couple conditions for this bug
it takes advantage of the fad or a
universal binary format and we'll go
into that the first mock oh and the fat
file must be signed by Apple and the
second one must be i386 and it doesn't
necessarily have to be signed or it can
be self signed and one way to way it's
malicious is that basically you use a
CPU type in the fat header that is not
native to that chipset I mean we'll
discuss this so in the vulnerability
exists in the difference between how the
Mokka load or load sign code versus how
it properly use cosine and api's check
sign code and is exploited via a
malformed universe
fad binary and we'll talk about that
right now so I'm just gonna run this is
just a file command on bin sink and
you'll see that there are two
architectures and one is 64-bit and one
is I 386 and that's basically you see
the diagram below that and that's
basically what a fat or universal binary
is it's the same program compiled for
different chipsets so that is portable
between between different computers now
and the fat file really became in a
prominence with OS X leopard because it
was PPC to Intel chipset and I think
that was like two thousand seven so this
bug it could have existed in third-party
tools since 2007 so and there's no
signing on the fat header or the file
itself so you can modify these and no
signature shets checks are in place and
so the devote and also the the want
ability exists in the difference between
how the maka loader loads code versus
how and properly use cosign api used to
check the code so it's a bit of a
bait-and-switch and i'll explain that so
- so you can see this i we're using a
command that actually comes with xcode
developer tools called lipo I'm not
kidding it's actually called lipo it's
for working with fat files and you can
create a fat file just by using create
then later on there's a thin so you can
thin a fat file obviously this was
written before everybody was very
sensitive on the subject maybe they
should change it we can get it we can
get a position a petition started so
what I'm doing here is I'm gonna create
this Frankenstein binary and yeah so
this is what this will look like this
tool the header will look like in mock
Oh view you can download mock Oh view
there's a I think it's on one of these
downloads stuff for free sites that are
totally trustworthy so you can see that
the Python x86 64 bit code is first and
then you have
right after that and if I run code sign
on this you'll see that the that it says
that so I'm running on Python first and
there's no team identify right and then
I run on net cat next and you'll see
that the signature is ad-hoc self-signed
and there's also no team identify err
okay so if if I want to execute the
Python code Python has this interesting
bug that probably could be abused it has
to be named Python so if you renamed
Python to something else so look for
loaded libraries that are not are the
same name as executable it's kind of
kind of fun so it has to be named Python
and so I just copied it the attempt and
I execute it and you see that Python
executes now how can we get netcat to
execute without messing up the
signatures well what we need to do is is
set the CPU type for the first binary
slice and the fat file to an invalid
type for the native operating system so
basically I just flipped a bet a bit by
setting the CPU type to an invalid type
or in a non-native type you could also
you can set it to PowerPC or whatever
the maka over loader will skip over the
validly signed maka binary and execute
the malicious non-apple signed code it
just skipped right over because it's
can't execute so in this example you see
that after I made that change netcat
execute still called python but netcat
execute and then you'll see if i run
code sign on it it still has the same
team identifier and it's still valid so
that's that's pretty pretty awesome so
what vendors were affected everyone that
I could get my hands on and test
everyone everyone that had the code
signing feature as part of their their
their feature set product feature set
and part of each bug report we provided
four samples to the vendor so that they
can fully test it let me go over these
so the first one
is it's not signed that means the
malicious code is not signed and it
wasn't really malicious I wasn't sending
vendors malicious code
it was just examples and the header is
malformed the next one is actually a
PowerPC Apple PowerPC signed binary that
I took off a OS X leopard ISO that I
found it was dusty and the headers so
it's not it's a non malformed header
it's a normal header and the malicious
code is ad hoc sign the next one is ad
hoc sign malformed header and then I
actually took the terminal application
that comes with apple and I was able to
create a malicious terminal application
that came back assigned so the first
vendor is a f-secure little flock er X
fence so it came back this is the what I
would call the weakest sample it came
back as signed as Apple and so
objective-c tools if if the tool had
code signing as part of the feature set
it if my samples would come back
assigned by Apple so this is a what's
your sign and then this is TAS Explorer
but I think all the tools are effect I
think block block Lulu a knock knock I
think they're they're all affected so
then we have Google Santa's whitelisting
tool you see that comes back is
whitelisted it's okay
greens good and then it shows a full
chain as being apple and then yelp OSX
collector so OSX collector would only
return an error if there was a failure
so I had to modify the code to get get
everything to print zeros if everything
was okay so this shows that everything
is okay then carbon black I don't if you
can see it but it says it's valid and
it's signed by Apple and the virustotal
on it they by heard of irish total
that's a joke so this everything came
back signed by Apple you're getting kind
of the picture here oh it's query maybe
a couple people have heard of those
query and they had a pretty good fix and
then Little Snitch so Little Snitch
actually did the best they actually they
actually would tell you so I'm gonna
read it because internal differs from
the version on disk it has no code
signature but the dispersion does this
means that the running process was
probably maliciously modified it's half
true the reason they do this check is
because your code can be modified at
runtime so this is a pretty good check
all they're doing is just checking the
the runtime executable but if you were
to go into the settings and you'll see
bottom right-hand quarter corner it says
signed by Apple and then you look at the
certificate and it shows that it's
signed by Apple and so if all your other
tools are saying that it's signed by
Apple you you might think that it's a
bug and Little Snitch versus everything
else or vice versa but most I think most
people would run the code based on my
experience so that's the list of known
vendors I feel like I have a runs
Rumsfeld problem of unknown knowns or
known unknowns I can remember how that
goes but yeah so after this came out
there was some comments on ours and like
oh thank God for gatekeeper and so gate
gatekeeper who knows about gatekeeper
everybody knows about gatekeeper a
couple of you so gate keeper is a
security feature that enforces code
signing and verifies downloaded
applications before allowing them to run
and that's only a one-time verification
so if you modify it after the fact
gatekeepers not going to check or
doesn't do anything but this is how
Apple sees gatekeeper and this is how I
see gatekeeper
and there's a reason I think this and
I'm not the only one so this is a slide
from Patrick waddles 2016 gatekeeper
exposed talk and I'll talk about some of
the details of why many people that do
red teaming and pen testing fill this
way so if you're targeted you know
you'll get the picture after this so if
you follow the standard method of
getting app bundles and DM G's and you
download them through a browser
gatekeeper will protect you gatekeeper
does not look at standalone mokou
binaries and that is the executable
format right so this is what I tend to
use when I'm setting up a persistence
method I just use a mock oh there's no
need to use an app bundle if somebody's
using that bundle there either they've
infected the supply chain tool chain of
a developer we've seen that with Mac OS
or they have a signing certificate or
they're not very sophisticated now if
you download a zip file a zip
application bundle for press application
bundle via zip format you're protected
unless you use 7-zip and then you're not
protected if you if your application
bundle is been compressed with 7-zip
you're not protected if the application
is Todd you're protected unless they use
7-zip to uncompress it then you're not
protected if the user uses curl or W get
you're not protected or if that bundles
on USB you're not protected so yeah it's
a very I don't consider it a security
boundary but Apple does so I initially
when I I found this bug I decided to
contact Apple directly and this started
let's say it will the con we'll just
talk about contacting them first so I
sent the initial sample it's a Apple
where the malicious code was not signed
and I already knew what they're going to
tell me so it's kind of a setup because
I've been down this path before on
code-signing issues and products
security you know provided a
recommendation and I turn around and
provide a bypass to their
recommendations and then they provide
another recommendation that doesn't
solve the issue and I respond with a
workflow to solve the issue and I hope
that they'll address it because my goal
with the entire problem was for them to
fix it on the back end so that
developers didn't have to do anything in
their code so they'd be frictionless
however they let me know that
third-party developers we're gonna have
to work it out and they were gonna
update some documentation so I guess
you're asking your next question is
Apple vulnerable to any of this and I
tested a number of scenarios and they
are not in a security sense for example
I could not access key chain from
unsigned code directly without entering
a password so there's really I haven't
found any instances maybe they are maybe
I just haven't looked at it fully but
this is kind of an interesting bug so
this is the system information app and
my terminal POC is there and it comes
back assigned by Apple but I don't
consider this a security bug because I
hope you're not making security
decisions off the security information
out but if it was if this was built in
as a security feature into Mac then I'll
consider a security issue but as of
right now I don't if somebody else wants
to report it go ahead good luck with
that
so the developers were really excited
about this book as you can probably see
this is some of the reactions this was
very common yeah god help anyone using
these API so I like that and this was
somebody sent me this offline
it was great I just leave this in the
background sometimes I'm having a bad
day so how did we go so yeah April 9th I
was able to tell all everyone we were
able to find the other that we knew were
affected and then at the same time I was
in contact with CMU sir and their
recommendation was a blog post to get
this information out because because of
the code signing aspect a lot of people
could have developed their own internal
tools to check code signing and we just
you know back to the Rumsfeld question
unknown knowns no known unknowns you
know so on June 12th we did the public
disclosure and yeah yeah so here we are
so this was Apple's documentation on
June 9th thank you Google Google cache
this is the sec static code check
validity API documentation
sometime after June 12th
we got updated and I'll read it out when
checking in your universal binary
include the Kasich CS check all
architectures flag otherwise the method
verifies only one slice of the binary
potentially indicating success without
testing all slices be aware that the
slices of a universal binary don't have
to be signed by the same signer for the
test do to pass one slice might be ad
hoc signed thank you but the validity
check doesn't know which slice you're
going to run for example the user might
be using the arch command-line utility
to pick a 32-bit architecture even
though a 64-bit architecture is
available in fact that flag alone is not
good enough they that is also not
correct but whatever so how do we do it
correctly well so let's say your non
developer or you're just doing things
via the command line you got a bunch of
bash scripts that are you know helping
you out that's what your everybody just
uses bash scripts I guess so there's a
couple ways you can do it
code sign you can use four V's you can
use two V's it's about the same if you
look at the source and then you got to
pass this what was called the
requirement flag and you just pass
anchor Apple and then some app or you
can do a PID an actual running process
and that's a pretty good check if you
want to see what's going on in your
current process list now this that
anchor Apple only checks for native
Apple applications okay so if you want
to check to see if it comes from a Apple
cert assign cert or you know Apple sign
developer cert you do anchor Apple
generic same concept and then if you
want an if the application is failing
and you want to kind of figure out why
you can use lipo and then you have the
thin command so you can thin out your
fat file and then you just check the
output of that simple right so on the
developer side it depends how you want
to do is on what you want to see so
you're going to use the sec requirement
create with string and you're gonna pass
anchor Apple or Anchor Apple generic and
you're going to take the output of that
and pass it to sec static check code
validity with all of these flags enabled
all of them
I think that's every flag may be
possible for this and then then you may
have to break it out even further to see
words where it fails and I think OS
query actually implemented that so they
actually strip out every architecture in
the fat file to make sure that
everything is ok so yeah so it's a
pretty simple process as far as
discovery I've been wrestling around
with fat files for or signing for a
little while
reported this issue back in 2015 this
was I think June
it was a resource error kind of fun but
then I did a talk
schmuck on in 2016 called hiding from
the investigator you could actually at
the time I think iOS 9 you could take an
append like a gig of data to an iOS
application uploaded to the phone via
iTunes walk around with all that data
your app works fine and then you know
let's say you're crossing borders then
you could just pull the file down back
through iTunes and you have your data
you're able to smuggle the data right so
that's kind of fun kind of a fun talk
but what there was during that during
that talk I noticed that while doing
research on the talk I noticed that if
you were to put a single knot in between
Macha binaries in the padding area of
the fat file you would get a error it
just just something wrong right wouldn't
tell you what it's just an inter
internal error occurred great so that
made me want to look more into Universal
binaries or fat binaries to see you know
what else I could find and so I got
right on that and almost two years later
I decided to look at this again I was it
was you know Christmas season everything
was slower and yeah so I took a Perl
binary used backdoor factory to infect
it and then I all I think all I did was
append data to the end and you see that
it fails code signing strict checking
and yeah I just I uploaded it to
virustotal and it came back as valid and
I knew at that moment that I number one
shouldn't have uploaded at the
virustotal because then everybody has it
but I realized at that point that I'm
kind of on the right track so being that
this was really important I put it off
until February 13th most who must I know
what happened is I had a kid and just
life got busy so I finally got around to
it around February 13th and so
I'm back using lipo and I tried to put
two I want to see what I could do with a
fat file format and so I tried to put
two architectures in the same fat binary
and I failed gloriously it wouldn't let
me do it now
generally if I see something like this
like a safety feature in a program it
makes me question well what if I did it
what happened
so I manually created the fat file and a
hex editor and and then it goes it goes
execute and it failed so I'm like well
that's not good so then I started
playing around like I started reading
source code and I figured out that if I
could flip a bit on the CPU types that
it might execute and then I was able to
solve that problem so then at that point
I knew that I was on to something and
didn't take after after that it didn't
take long to actually start by passing
through third-party code signing checks
and after that happened you you all saw
the results of that at the start of the
talk so if that is my conclusion to this
talk or at least at least that's the how
I discovered the bug in conclusion I
really encourage people to take a look
if you're into reading source code and
and reading see I encourage people to
take more of a look at code signing I
think that you could actually find a lot
of bugs in the api's themselves those
that probably need to be fuzz a little
bit more and I believe that these bugs
are going to continue to happen over and
over and over because it's not being
fully addressed by the operating system
maker and so I think that if you have a
product that you run across that does go
to signing checks you should take these
binaries and test it test it for sure
and there's the blog post if you just
search I can be Apple you should be able
to find it but any questions
anything at all no because iOS so I it
has I forgot the there's a there's a sis
control that you can use on Mac that
actually enforces its its OS wide
co-signing checks and if this is
automatically compiled into the kernel
on iOS so it doesn't work on iOS I
forgot that I just can't remember this -
scoffs off my head any other questions
all right well thank you for your time
yep actually I don't think so I think
PCs are better actually the mitigation I
did a talk on a met last summer DEFCON
and I was bypassing he met and and they
fixed it and I bypass their fixes and
they map Windows 10 is gone is blown
back out of the water as far as security
mitigations it's not even they're not
even the same realm anymore
any other questions all right well thank
you for your time thanks for thanks for
Chaka Khan putting this on