[Applause]
okay so Active Directory that's a bit
awkward because I actually put together
some stuff on x86 instruction set since
that was the talk that was going to be
up here before but I'm guessing that's
not what I'm actually going to do so let
me just go through these and this and
that
oh sorry that was actually really cool
that's something you should look at
later pack bits are awesome definitely
check those out yeah we got that
sure bitwise logical Xers anyway anyway
yeah okay there we go all right so let's
talk act by Curie security I'm Sean
Metcalfe I'm the founder Trimark
security company I work with a number of
company a number of organizations around
the world to help them better secure
their environment Microsoft Certified
Master in Active Directory there's about
a hundred in the world I've spoken in a
number of conferences including Chaka
Khan here three years ago so I'm very
excited back and I'm an eightieth
enthusiast I'm very much excited about
Active Directory I'm excited to talk to
companies and customers about what
they're doing and their challenges so
we're going to go over the current
threat landscape cloud Active Directory
what does that actually mean
the typical security issues that I've
seen at customer sites and organizations
and how to fix those clean them up the
ever evolving and expanding set of
permissions that tend to just take over
Active Directory over time some cool
attack detection and then wrap it up
with some recommendations so breach I
love doing searches on Google that are
just very simple like this and
apparently there's like four million
breaches out there according to the
googles but the state of security is
good right though we got some good
better security awareness we're able to
see what's going on better than we have
before we're getting some logging we're
flowing it in sometimes we miss the
benefit in the room but that happens we
have better security testing pen testers
red teamers have really evolved and are
looking at what some of the more
advanced persistent threats are actually
doing out there and better PowerShell
security so if you haven't already
rolled out version 5 please rolled out
version 5
it's awesome and apparently the same
thing in Python is coming to Python v3
we're looking at similar types of
logging and security capability there
that we already have in PowerShell
that's pretty great we also have some
grumpy cat news unfortunately going from
a user to an admin is still way too easy
in most environments all someone has to
do is basically put on the outfit and
then there the admin legacy really
reduces security legacy is probably one
of the biggest issues that we have today
the flood that's associated with it you
have the service count it has the main
admin it doesn't need that well this is
how it's always been and Joe set that up
well where's Joe he left five years ago
ok
PowerShell logging not enabled so we've
got all these great new features in
PowerShell 4 + v5 but the logging is
just not enabled it's a pretty basic
simple group policy configuration and
there's still too many blind spots one
of the great things about having a pen
tester or a red team come in is to
identify those blind spots those areas
you can't see if you can't already see
those they're just going to come in to
confirm your suspicions and of course we
got to talk about the ugly email gets
users to click why is this we have
trained users to click for years by
sending them internal email click here
to update this click here to update that
we have performance reviews that we have
to do click here to get to that click
here to get to this click here to see
the dancing chickens and from email the
breach it's way too easy we end up with
a situation where we have predator
hiding on our network and we can't see
it and a year ago there was an article
so the nearly half of firms had a cyber
attack or breach which is pretty bad and
this was in a year that about 80 billion
dollars is spent on cyber security so
how does that make me feel as a person
who works at a company that works with
other companies I kind of feel like when
you're talking about 80 billion dollars
you're talking about taking a dollar
stacked and to end and then going 16
times back and forth that's a lot of
money and then in 2018 how much money
are we burning through this year for the
blankey box
it's a challenge and so now we have this
whole cloud thing where it's rainbows
and unicorns and everything's happy and
wonderful right there's a lot of
challenges though because we have our
on-prem environment which we're very
familiar with probably and certainly
more familiar than a cloud environment
we know how to how to control how to
control egress ingress in our own
environment we know what things look
like we know what the problems are we
know we can see hopefully we we know we
can't see but it's always changing in
the cloud world I go and read documents
there's six months old and then I've got
to go and read new documents because a
lot of things have updated and change
this means that learning curve is a lot
steeper than it used to be and certainly
steeper than it was for other
technologies and the security
capabilities and the ability of that
cloud environment is very much dependent
on the provider so if you're with Amazon
or Microsoft or Google there's gonna be
differences in how you can how you can
secure different things how you can
control access and there's even
different names for different things
across those different cloud
environments which makes it even more
difficult and then of course it's not
always obvious what you're sharing
versus what you're not or if you're
sharing it internally versus public I
think most people here know what the
word are the term s3 means right because
we've seen it in the news all the time
the one thing that I've heard a lot
though is I'm going to migrate my
on-prem ad to azure ad and it doesn't
quite work like that Azure ad despite
the fact that it's a j''r Active
Directory is not Active Directory at
least not the way that we're used to or
the way that we're used to thinking of
it as we're not going to just shift and
forklift what we have on Prem up into
the cloud it's not as your ad at least
not today we have our on Prem ad which
we're very familiar with we have
authentication directory management
services we have authentication Kerberos
and ntlm we know that pretty well
certainly the attackers these pretty
well we can use LDAP to period we can
use group policy to help manage our
systems Azure ad is quite a bit
different it's an identity multi-tenant
cloud directory and it's cloud web
focused which means that the
authentication is very different as well
we're looking at Oh our Open ID Connect
based authentication and protocols
we're not looking at ntlm we're not
looking at Kerberos oh those things
don't exist in Azure ad and if you want
to use LDAP to look at Azure ad you can
you have to use the app directory graft
API and if you're looking at doing some
sort of management of devices sure I can
join my computer to Azure ad where's a
group policy
there's no group policy I've got to then
get it configured with an MDM something
like into which isn't quite group policy
doesn't have the same exact feature set
today I can't go into Intune and
configure the security settings for
Windows 10 like I can in group policy so
this is what Active Directory using
computers looks like we're very familiar
with this we have used this we've seen
this with Azure ad it's so webpage or
PowerShell very very different we have
to think about this differently it's not
a situation where we're just going to
push all of our systems into the cloud
now moving email and data and in order
to share and in order to collaborate
better that makes a lot of sense in the
cloud but these workloads that we have
that use ntlm kerberos for off
we can't just ship those over to Azure
ad so there's some key points here that
Azure ad is cloud authentication that's
what it's primarily for and as I
mentioned there's a number of things
that are differences between Active
Directory and Azure ad and there's a
reason why I say asher ad and not Azure
Active Directory because it's not
exactly Active Directory if you want an
Active Directory in the cloud that's
quite a bit different you have to go
with something like Azure Active
Directory domain services from Microsoft
or Amazon's managed Microsoft Active
Directory in the AWS cloud I had to make
sure I read that correctly because
that's a mouthful but Microsoft's Azure
Active Directory domain services is your
cloud hosted Active Directory it has
some interesting OU's here like a a DD C
computers a DD C users a DD C domain
admins these are delegated OU's you're
not going to be a domain admin in this
hosted environment and there's some
differences with it but this is the 80
as a service if you're looking for that
sort of thing
but again this is a little bit different
than what most people think it is Azure
ad domain services is not meant for you
to set this up and then use it to in
order to configure a forest trust from
your on-prem ad it doesn't support truss
this is primarily for managing your as
your workload your cloud workload you
group policy and all the other things
but you're not a domain or enterprise
admin and you're not going to have
direct access to those demand
controllers so again even with AD in the
cloud it's a little bit different than
what we're used to now when we're
talking about Active Directory and the
connectivity with the cloud 80 provides
a single sign-on services and there's
sync tools that enable you to take users
and user data and then sync it up to
whatever that cloud service is a lot of
people have probably gone to a company
and have the ly pad you touch the
information it has the information about
who you check in with well guess what
that information gets synced from that
on-prem ad to that cloud provider
there's a lot of others that do the same
thing and these rights that are required
in order to do this or just user rights
an ad so the real question is how many
of these sync tools that you have in
your organization then you're aware of
well there's a 3d Kinect which if you
have office 365 you probably have azure
ad Kinect because that's how you
synchronize your user in groups up into
office 365 in the azure ad tenant that's
spun up automatically for office 365 and
primarily what this is used for is order
to make sure that the user accounts that
exists on your on-prem ad are also an
azure ad and you have group membership
that gets updated as well and you have
the ability to do what Microsoft is
calling here password synchronization
which is not entirely accurate it was
called password synchronization it's
been called password hash
synchronization which isn't entirely
accurate either basically it's an Active
Directory password hash hash so they
take the password hash of the user
account the hash it again do some
additional crypto on it and that's
what's actually sent up to Azure ad and
there's also the capability to do write
back so that way when a user off to
Azure ad and their password is expired
they can update their password nazzer ad
and then have it sink back down to their
on prem ad environment
and if you have as rady predict connect
and you've gone through and hit the easy
button and panicked do the Express
settings it would set up all of these
different permissions for you
automatically but there's something
interesting about this here and I talked
about this at Def Con last year with
Gerald that there's two rights here that
are provided to the service account for
a JD connect replicate directory changes
and replicate directory changes all
these two rights provide the ability to
pull password hashes what makes a lot of
sets under the context of as Rainey
connect when you're actually
synchronizing that password hash
component up to Azure ad but what if
you're not well that's not necessary
right and there's this little thing
called DC sync that's part of many cats
now that provides an attacker with the
ability to take over this account or to
have these two rights without domain
admin rights or enterprise admin rights
to actually synchronize and pull
password hashes from the environment so
we want to make sure that if we have as
rady connect and we have sirs count for
that we're really well protecting it
because effectively it's like being in
being an administrator an ad admin with
access to the crown jewels so custom
permissions would be definitely the way
to go if you're not planning on
synchronizing the password data and
certainly a few months after that
December last year Microsoft put out a
security bulletins highlighting the fact
that account operators has the ability
to take over that account based on the
base the default install of azure ad
Connect hopefully no one in here is
using account operators and we'll talk a
little bit about why that's not a good
idea actually to have that configured so
the azure ad connects server is at about
every two minutes it's requesting the
stored password hashes from Active
Directory and taking that onto the
server and then doing some crypto on it
so it's taking that md4 it's then doing
an 8-bit binary hash which is converted
to a 64-bit binary to a 10 bytes salt
and then creating a 64-bit hash which is
then input into sha 256 which is pretty
strong so that's sent up to Azure ad and
that's what is
used to compare to when a user actually
authenticate saturating so that way they
don't have to come back into the on-prem
ad in order to off and then get to
federation other things that they have
through as your ad so there's certainly
some very strong recommendations that i
have here basically if you have ad your
ad connect in your environment and you
have that server and you are
synchronizing that the password data you
want to protect it like it a domain
controller the other thing that's
interesting in a lot of environments
that have multiple forests will actually
have one azure ad connect server for it
so this server is not just like a junior
domain controller it's a junior to main
controller for like all of the Active
Directory environment so we want to
firewall this off we're going to protect
it and keep the account operators group
empty there's also another thing that's
pretty interesting that I talked about
at Def Con last year and that was that
Federation is kind of like a cloud
Kerberos and so just like how you have
to protect your curb TDT password hash
in Active Directory you also have to
protect your certificates that are
installed on your Federation server like
a DFS so you'll definitely want to look
at your ad FS server if you have a TF as
servers or other Federation servers on
Prem you want to check to see who has
admin rights to those check the local
administrators group you want to look to
see who has access to those on the
network certainly not everyone on your
network should be able to connect to
that server because the token and
signing certificates are effectively
what are used to create those tokens or
those tickets when you're dealing with
Federation and then a few months after
this talk certainly someone figured out
how to actually weaponize this and made
what they call the golden sam'l attack
where if they had these certificates
they could go ahead and create their own
tickets and say I am whoever I want to
be in this environment through
Federation etc so we find some really
interesting things when we do Active
Directory security assessments for
customers what are the things that
attackers really require well they need
accounts the credentials they need the
rights the privileges associated with
those credentials and they need access
the connectivity to the resources if
you're able to disrupt any one of these
things the attacker is unable to do what
they want to do in your environment and
one of the things that is very important
to understand is even if you feel like I
always have to be right
have to be read a hundred percent of
time the attacker only has to be right
once
well that's true for the initial
foothold once they get onto the network
but at that point that entire paradigm
shifts and turns around because now is
the defender you have the ability to
configure and control your environment
jessyca pain calls this building the
attackers playground you can set it up
and force these traps and tripwires
for when the attacker gets into your
environment they have to go through
these things and you can get alerted on
that and at that point the attacker has
to be right a hundred percent of the
time you just have to catch them doing
something once so one big thing is an
attacker do I need two main admin no hey
not there's rights all over the place
there's lots of things in your common
everyday Active Directory environment
that provides escalation paths for
attackers there's a number of them
here's a few of what we find regularly
and we go through and analyze these and
talk to customers about how to tighten
these up and I'm going to dig into a few
of these in more detail in just a second
local administrator password not managed
on workstations or servers a lot of
times the workstation builds sets a
standard and it stays that way
so we compromised one workstation to
compromised them all well you can use
mini cats or something similar to dump
the credentials off that local account
database and once we have that admin
account password hash we can then try it
against all the other workstations and a
lot of organizations that so works so
you definitely want to use something
like Microsoft lapse are similar to make
sure that those passwords actually get
rotated changed on are unique in the
environment but we also find the flip
side with organizations that have lapse
often times they will over delegate who
has access to view these lapse password
so certainly once you're changing them
you want to make sure that you restrict
who has access to these passwords
because the delegation of this axis is
critical and we don't want to find a
situation where there's ends up being a
hundred people that have access to the
local admin passwords across all
workstations or even across servers the
main password policy by default looks
like this it's seven characters I'm sure
everyone agrees that that's a great
really strong
yeah so we're gonna change that we're
gonna make it better and make it eight
one better obviously that's not a great
great setting we've got a great way to
do it ten is much better I've set it to
twelve perfectly something more like
fifteen Microsoft did an update in April
so now using Windows 10 or 2016 you can
actually set this within the GUI to 20
so that's a huge improvement from 14 to
20 so now we can actually start cracking
that up to to force longer passwords if
you have a situation where you have a
subset of users in your environment that
just can't have 15 or 16 character
passwords because of legacy requirements
you can also use fine-grained password
policies to apply to a group that you
put those users in and they will still
have a character password for 10
character passwords or whatever's
required so certainly a user in a domain
admin group would be bad but that still
happens oftentimes organizations have
gone through the process of cleaning up
and of shifting their old single account
to a user account and a day an admin
account but a lot of times forgets the
process of cleaning up those old user
accounts no name account standard I
don't really know what the admin account
standard is but I know absolutely know
who the admins are because I know how to
enumerate admin groups it is not full
attackers it's best to have a very
standardized admin standard or naming
standard because that way you can
programmatically identify who supposed
to be in admin groups and who isn't
so designators that clearly identify
admin rights like something - a TA for
Active Directory admin default domain
administrator account so the default
domain administrator account is it
should really be a break class account
like only used if you really need it in
an emergency but I regularly find that
organizations have set this as their
sequel service account which doesn't
seem to make a whole lot of sense but
it's the admin account for the domain
and so it has a service principle name
and if the password hasn't been changing
in years it's probably very weak and
there's an attack method called Kerberos
thing which enables attackers to request
a service ticket
for this account because it has a
service principle name and then attempt
to crack it offline and there's all the
password crackers now support this and
then of course service counts of domain
admins so service counts rarely need
domain admin rights despite what vendors
say much better to delegate exactly
what's required and if your vendors say
that their their service account
requires domain admins to ask them what
the specific rights are that leads them
to that statement push back on your
vendors as the customer before you sign
the contract you have that ability you
have that power a little more difficult
once the contracts been signed but we
see this all the time where the
vulnerability scanner is the account
that's a member of domain admins because
it's got a scan workstation the server's
domain admin a domain controllers etc
it's much better to split this out into
separate accounts because what if this
vulnerability scanners pickups what if
someone does a code update to it and the
hiccups and at least credentials behind
on one percent of systems these are
domain admin credentials that end up
getting left on a workstation so we want
to segment these off we want to isolate
and have an account for scanning
workstations one for scanning servers
and then a totally different one for
domain controllers if we even want to
have that same system scanning to make
charge server GPOs link to the bank's
rollers happens all the time we have a
GPO that has a servers policy we link it
to the domain controllers are you it
does many things that's the security
baseline but one of the things that
actually also does is adds the server
admins group to the local administrators
group well guess what happens when we
applies to the main controller it takes
that server admins group and adds it to
the domain controllers local
administrators group which happens to be
the built-in administrators group for
the domain so now our server admins are
our Active Directory admins so even if
this configuring fee configuration is
not in place we can also have a
situation where there's a baseline
security policy that someone's created
NIC is a great guy he's this up for
servers domain admins are like alright
we got to set up some sort of baseline
security policy for our domain
controllers so what are we going to do
we're going to take what Nick did we're
gonna link it to the main controllers
problem is that Nick still has modify
rights of that GPO
since he still has modified right to
that GPO he can change a group policy
that links and applies to domain
controllers which means that he can link
a script that can install or run code or
rollback security settings or had admins
to the administrators group or maybe
someone taking control of his count can
do the same so we want to make sure that
only your act directory admins have
modify rights on these GPOs and then
cross force administration gets really
tricky we regularly see that there's
production and there's external to
different force it could be production
lab it could be production and then
something in the DMZ it doesn't matter
there's a one-way trust where our
external environment trusts our
production which is the standard
Microsoft recommendation because then
our accounts in production can
authenticate to the systems and external
the problem is that a lot of times when
this configuration is in place the
production forced 80 admins manage the
external force well that just makes
sense but it gets how they typically do
that via RDP so when you already pea
into a system you put the credentials on
that system and when we RDP from a
production 80 environment using our
production 80 admin account and we RDP
into a domain controller or something
else in this external forest environment
we are leaving those production ad admin
credentials into that external untrusted
environment we don't want to do that
because all an attacker needs to do is
compromise that lower trusted forest in
order to compromise the production force
so definitely we want to either manage
our external environment with external
accounts or we want to use non
privileged production forest accounts
with admin rights in our external
environment as long as we're not using
the exact same admin account from
production so account operators I
mentioned this earlier account operators
are a carryover from the NT for days
we do not want to use account of theirs
they kind of have outdoor rights to user
accounts and groups and a bunch of other
things that we don't need to do anymore
it's much better to custom delegate a
custom group to give it the access it
needs Microsoft even says don't don't
use account operators they say that it's
a service administrator group because it
can modify server server operators
leave this group empty do not use it so
I plead with you do not use account
operators one action you can take when
you get back to work
enumerate the membership of count
operators if there's accounts in it
figure out how to get them out and then
one of the other big problems is admin
group nesting where one group is another
group is another group another group it
is very difficult to determine who is
really an act directory admin through
this method and we have incidental or
unintended admins that end up in these
in these groups because of this and then
one thing to see a lot of the time is
the default domain controllers policy is
default the same security policy that
Microsoft is configured and identified
from Windows 2000 is still configured
today and no one has changed it or maybe
they change it and for some reason they
had two main users to have the ability
to log on locally to two main
controllers the user rights assignment
component on GPOs that are linked to
domain controllers is an untapped bounty
for attackers admins very rarely look at
user rights assignments that are
configured on domain controllers I know
this because I look at them it's one of
the first things I look at and then I
can identify what other accounts and
groups have admin rights on domain
controllers or the ability to log on to
the main controllers because if I have
this configured on a GPO that's linked
to the domain controller show you where
server admins can log on locally or log
on through our RDP and there's ODS is
also configured where domain users can
log on locally this means that server
admins any server admin can already pee
into the domain controller and
administer it or at least manage it that
way so we want to make sure that only
our 80 admins are the ones that can
manage our domain controllers here's a
fun one exchange requires manage
auditing and security log rights on
domain controllers and sometimes other
groups get put in there as well just
because like server admins well anyone
with the manage auditing a security log
right can clear the security but this is
not something we want just anyone to be
able to have
and if you've moved to office 365 and
you've cleaned up your environment you
definitely want to talk to Microsoft to
see if this rights still required for
your exchange servers but in the real
world rights are everywhere workstation
admins have full control on workstations
server admins have full control on
servers server admins our exchange admin
sometimes server admins are condemned
and controller admins help this admins
have local admin rights on all the
workstations there's local admin
accounts and passwords that are same
across multiple systems and then we have
temporary admin accounts we need Mike to
be able to do something so we add Mike
to this account this group and he's
doing stuff and we move on because we've
got 10 priority once we move on to
something else and then we don't clean
that up again and I went through and
looked at a lot of the third-party part
product permission requirements across a
large number of products and I came up
with these are this seem to be the
common ones across all of them and as I
kept looking at these and looking at
them my eyes just glazed over but a
pattern emerged and hopefully a pattern
emerges for you as well because as I
started looking at it I saw that over
and over and over again these products
were requiring domain admins why because
it makes it easier it makes it easier
from a development perspective when they
develop the product domain admins this
works for everything from a sales
perspective here install it this way it
takes five minutes from a post sales
perspective you have all the rights
everything's configured for the product
to work there's never going to be a
problem with permissions probably so
everything just works but this makes it
easy for the vendor it is way too easy
for the vendor I had a friend who was
working at a customer site and the VPN
vendor said that they are VPN service
account needed domain admin rights
I said why that doesn't make sense so we
asked the VPN provider and the VPN
provider said well if a user's password
expires they can't VPN we provide them
the ability to change their password so
we need to be able to change the
password said okay well that's pretty
easy that's like one of the most basic
things you do in Active Directory is
deling they delegating the ability to
change password
but there's also over permission
delegation where we use the built-in
groups for delegation or we click the
easy button so we do full control at the
domain root we just want to make it work
and the delegation tools and Active
Directory are very challenging I don't
know if anyone has ever tried to use
this to figure out what permissions are
in their environment but it's my
impossible because just looking at this
right now there's a major security issue
and no one's seen it yet
this is illustrating my point perfectly
here I'll highlight for you
domain computers for some reason was
delegated full control on this oh you
wherever the so us that means compromise
of one computer anywhere in the
organization would have full control on
the so you and all the objects in it so
this is vou that contains all the user
accounts or computers or workstations or
servers that can be quite problematic so
there are ways to get oh you permissions
report we can use PowerShell
which is my favorite because I love
PowerShell and so in the slides which
I'll put up on 80 security later I have
a PowerShell link on how to use
PowerShell to develop and and put
together the so you permission report
and we can filter off of this in Excel
because it just outputs to a CSV what
those rights are and what those identity
references are those groups those
accounts that have our custom the ones
that are not the built-in ones just by
looking at those we can highlight and go
well that looks weird that shouldn't be
that way why is that configured that how
come has helped us here to one and tier
to have those full control rights
generic all those full control and then
there's a tool that was released called
ac-lite by cyber-ark
and it goes through and does a lot of us
work for you which is great now ac-lite
leverages invoke ACL scanner which is a
function written by will Schrader it is
part of Power View and so invoke ACL
scanner will scan through the y-o-u
or the domain or OU's and look at the
permissions and depending I you can
figure it it'll give you information on
what the o'you permissions are and how
things are delegated ac-lite
speeds this up and makes it much easier
because it leverages info KCl scanner
and then spits out a bunch of reports
like accounts with extra permissions or
all entities with extra permissions so
oops accounts computers and then there's
CSV reports that show up so it's a batch
file you run that it does some
PowerShell gets the information and
gives you report makes it easy and then
there's also bloodhound it's a little
more complex but if you use bloodhound
before it gathers the same sort of
information it used invoke a CL scanner
as part of the powershell and gesture
now it uses a c-sharp and gesture and i
have the links here and again those will
be in the slides and there's also the ad
ACL white paper that was written by
Annie Robbins well Schrader who spoke at
blackhat last year more about if you're
interested in eighty ackles and how they
work so if you want to effectively
detect attacks on your network there's a
few different things you can do first of
all you want to make sure the logging is
appropriate way too often I found domain
controllers don't have the best logging
or are not configured appropriately with
logging for Active Directory so there's
this attack method called Kerberos sting
which I mentioned earlier which is very
simply you look for all of the accounts
and Active Directory all the user
accounts with service principle names
which is required for Kerberos to work
for authentication and once we identify
all those user accounts that have
associated service principle names
we're going to request service tickets
for every one of those once we get those
service tickets well first of all we
need to make sure that they're encrypted
with our chief or what's special about
our chief or well the ntlm password hash
is what's used to actually encrypt that
service ticket so if you take that
service ticket that's encrypted with the
ntlm password hash we take that line and
we can attempt to crack it so Tim Medina
this out a few years ago and spoke about
at Derby con released the Kerberos tool
and in this very simple basic powershell
script i effectively did this i went
through and identified what those
accounts are with service principle
names and then requested service tickets
for each of these and got a service
ticket for every one of those accounts
then i just take those offline
I run a dictionary word list hybrid
password cracker against it it's going
to create an ntl and password hash and
then attempt to open that service ticket
once it opens it I'm golden I know what
the password is and for service counts
that were created and have had passwords
that haven't changed and I don't know
three years four years five years ten
years
I don't know about you but passwords I
created ten years ago we're awful
pastors I created five years ago we're
slightly better a little better today
course staple of battery it's the horse
battery staple yeah something like that
don't use that okay so I figured out how
to detect kerberos ting by looking at of
NIT 4769 which is when a user request a
service ticket with specific ticket
options and specific ticket encryption 0
by 17 is our c4 so we filter out some
things we identify that there's other
types of tickets that actually use our
c4 regularly so we can filter those out
in our environment and then once we do
that we can identify that someone like
Joe here at nine o'clock is kerberos
ting the environment at least he's
requesting service tickets for all these
different services okay Shawn but what
if the attacker doesn't do it all at
once
that looks really suspicious I see that
that's obvious but what if they do it
over days or weeks or months because
they've got plenty of time and these
service count passers don't change
anyway so it doesn't it doesn't matter
okay so I figured out that we could
actually honeypot this we can create an
account I call it here Kerberos honeypot
I recommend that you use something
different
I said admin council one which makes it
interesting any account with admin
counselor to one is a probable active
directory admin account because of the
way that act directory works in
protecting domain admins administrators
enterprise admin schema admins etc and
so I create a service principle named I
created the service principle name it
does not exist it is not valid on the
network it does nothing so there's no
reason for anyone to ever request it so
of course someone does we look for a
user account with admin counts that's a
one service principle name set and then
we go ahead and go through in Kerberos
step and hopefully they didn't look
don't look too closely at what my
service principle name is because then
they figure out it's actually a trap but
you can see at the bottom it's the this
session key type is Archie 4h max so
it's Archie for its encrypted with that
ntlm password option and so now I run
the same detection and look there's the
honeypot account well that's obvious
that something malicious is going on and
if we take that one step forward I don't
even have to look for
all the 4769 I just have to look for
that one once I get that one I know that
someone's doing something they shouldn't
be doing well and then I went and took
this one step further I was like what if
I could prevent this what if I set these
two options on the service count that
say supports aes-128 supports is 256 so
I did that and guess what happened now I
get a an Aes Kerberos ticket now this
isn't going to break everything there
are still ways to request an RFC for
ticket but the standard method of
Kerberos ting breaks and most of the
tools that use Kerberos it breaks so if
you're able to set your service
principle your service counts that
obviously user accounts that have spins
if you're able to set them for AES I
highly recommend you do because it does
break the attackers normal playbook so
password spraying is something that is
very popular and attackers absolutely
love doing this red teamers pen testers
the whole concept of an account lockout
for user accounts was built around the
concept that you can only guess this
many accounts and then I'm gonna lock
out that account
well what ends up happening with
lockouts I lock out my account because I
only realized on the fourth attempt that
my caps lock was enabled and then the
next one I flubbed it because someone
said my name now I have to wait 30
minutes okay long coffee break all right
well attackers figured out that they
could use something it's either called
horizontal password spraying or just
password spraying where we take a list
of possible passwords like summer - 2018
and we attempt that one password against
every user account and the odds are
we're going to find one user account
that has a bad password in an ad
environment of 5,000 10,000 users and so
it goes through it and does this and
it's easy enough to look at the lockout
threshold it's five so guess what I'm
going to do and my n - 1 5 - 1 4 so I'm
only gonna do 4 and then I'm gonna wait
and I can also enumerate the
fine-grained password policies because
those might have different policies for
lockouts
so I can look at those also and then
pick lowest common denominator and then
I know how many passwords I can tempt in
the
this works this works well in my lab my
fake users are horrible at picking
passwords let me tell you I'm a fire all
of them terrible I told them not to use
password so they're like password one
needs an ampersand but through my lab
environment of 1892 users perfectly
random number connect to an SMB share or
a network service and then so I just
decided to target the PDC's and that
logon chair to do this and it didn't
take me long to write this PowerShell
I'm not a great person at writing power
so I do okay but I'm not a developer it
took me a couple hours to write this so
that means anyone can go ahead and do
this it's not that difficult but when I
go ahead and run this pasture spraying
script that I wrote there's a bunch of
4625 bad password attempt account that
password attempt against this account
and so this happens across all of them
but I also figured there's an attribute
in active directory called labs last bad
password attempt at least that's what
it's called in PowerShell when you use
the active directory powershell
commandlets so I looked at that I'm like
that's pretty obvious that someone is
doing something odd so we have a couple
different ways to detect this 46:25
which most organizations are logging on
their domain controllers and we can look
at the attributes and ad which any user
can do okay that's great but then I
switch to LDAP and when I password spray
against the LDAP service on the domain
controller guess what happened all those
46:25 is just disappeared okay so this
means that organizations that are
looking at 46 25 s or a password
spraying are completely missing a huge
attack vector okay but there's got to be
a way to figure out that this is
happening right well there is so I ran
through again environm environmentally
fake users about their bad passwords and
saw that the Kerberos authentication
service event got logged 47 71 this
one's pretty boring so I went back to my
attributes and I saw yeah last bad
password attempt was definitely flagged
there great bad password count by the
way is per domain controller so if you
have an environment with a ton of domain
controllers this isn't as
because you'd have to parse all of them
to figure out that password count but I
show it here as an example so I looked
at that 47 71 and Kerberos pre
authentication failed well most people
don't care about pre authentication
failed and then I looked closer and saw
this failure code which is 0 by 18 and
when I look this up guess what it meant
bad password attempt so now we have a
way to detect its passer spraying no
matter what's being done in our
environment which is great the other
thing I identified is that on endpoints
on our workstations if someone's doing
password sprang from that we can look
for 46 48 event IDs and we can see that
there was a you a logon was attempted
using explicit credentials so Jo is
doing some very shady stuff because he's
attempting to authenticate as all these
other users Jo is another fake user that
I need to talk to because he should not
be doing that so what's the next step
what do we need to do and I have a bunch
of recommendations here and it's a very
busy slide but this encapsulate all the
some of the primary recommendations that
that I make to customers when we're
looking at their Active Directory
environment some of the keys to this are
limiting who your act directory admins
are and making sure that they're using
some protected method to ensure that
their credential is well protected and
not leaked on the in the environment if
they're using a regular workstation and
then already peeing to a domain
controller that's not the best way to do
it it's much better to use an admin
system like an admin workstation to move
it over to isolate that credential from
the standard workstation so there are
things that matter making sure the local
admin passwords change host firewall on
your workstations is one of the most
positive things you can do in your
environment if you get a host-based
firewall like the Windows Firewall
enabled with default inbound rule
blocking on all your workstations
this will incredibly frustrated ackers
it will have much more impact than
buying the the security tool with the
blinky box sorry people out there
it has tremendously positive impact and
guess what the ransomware that uses want
to cry or any of the the new names of
the month how SMB worms are
or being alder how they're working it
blocks that too because they could just
can't jump from workstation to
workstation which is what they've been
doing it has a huge positive impact
there is no need for workstations to
talk to each other and workstations also
don't need the ability to have a demand
controller reach directly to them it has
a stateful firewall the Windows Firewall
is stateful which means that when the
workstation reaches out to the domain
controller then makes troller responds
to it so you can have the Windows
Firewall enabled you can't have a
host-based firewall enable in Active
Directory the things that you'll have to
look at as exceptions are your
management products your patch
management products administration much
better to have an admin subnet that
those are going to come from so that way
when they reach down they're allowed
through that firewall rule so we want to
make sure that we are firewalling and
protecting lemon lemon limiting the
communication between systems that need
to be have communication between them
and restricting and preventing
communication from other systems that
don't need it
and then disabling old and uncommon
features and protocols really matter
things like getting rid of LM ntlm
shifting up to ntlm v2 turning office
and vv1 in the environment L element R
is usually not required so disable that
things like responder which I call the
easy button for for pen testers and
attackers will just siphon and suck up
the credentials in the environment on
the network when these things are
enabled so that's been my time thank you
so much for yours
I do have a few minutes for questions if
anyone has questions otherwise I'll be
over here if you want to follow up
questions yes
group managed service counts are
fantastic because 80 manages the
password for it and that changes about
every 30 days great one of the
challenges with that is there's certain
applications that don't work with GM SAS
or MSAs but yeah I would absolutely love
to see more service counts using using
that because the passwords automatically
get managed and rotated and are long
complex absolutely anyone else okay
great thank you very much for having me
at Chuck kaan again
[Applause]