(upbeat music)
(Applause)
- Thank you Heather.
All right welcome to
the iOS of Sauron,
nerdy referenced there, right.
How iOS tracks
everything that you do.
A little bit about
myself like Heather said,
I really like Mac stuff.
I do like to test it.
If it has a piece of fruit on it
I'm going to buy it it.
It doesn't matter what it is,
I will put all the money I
have towards Apple products
in the name of research,
as I like to say.
I am author instructor
of Forensics 518
which is gonna be
held this next week
so if you want to hang
out for this summit
a little bit longer go
ahead and take the class
but I do have a few other
classes up there as well.
And I have my
contact information
which will also be
on the last slide.
Just a word of note here,
the slides are
already available.
This is a condensed version
of this presentation
because I do have to do
within 20 25 minutes.
So the slides that are
available on my website
or my Github are
quite a bit more.
A little bit more lengthy.
So it's got a little
bit more stuff to it.
So what I want to
talk about here
is pattern of life.
So we use our iPhones.
We use them all the time.
I'm looking at information.
I'm looking at
files and databases
that can tell a lot about
a certain person's usage.
Of how they use applications.
where are they at a given time.
Even down to the nitty
gritty little bits
about their life like
their health you know.
What is their heart
rate at a specific time.
Really creepy stuff.
Very interesting stuff as well
that I hope that you
guys can possibly use
in many of your investigations.
So I do have this caveat page.
So I do like to put out
some information in here.
This is a work in progress
type of presentation.
I will be doing more
review of these files.
Looking at different devices
looking at different
iOS versions
because they all do tend to be
a little bit different
here and there.
Before the purpose
of this presentation,
this is on my iPhone
6 and my Apple watch.
So these are my devices.
This is my data
that you're seeing.
I'd also like to say that
this is a jailbroken.
jailbroken files.
So most of these files,
minus maybe one database
is only accessible on
a jailbroken device.
your cellebrites your xoys
your whatever other
mobile device tools
are not going to pull
this information.
These are fairly
very protected files
that is not.
They are not backed up with
like an iTunes style backup.
So just be aware of that.
The timestamps I've learned
with doing the research
for this presentation,
do not implicitly
trust the timestamps.
Some of them are way
off and I'll show you
a few examples of those.
Always always test.
Data retention for some
of these databases,
it could be anything
from an hour to a day
to a month to a week you know.
All these things different.
I try to mark it in
here as best as I can.
So for the documentation
portion of this,
I do have these file
paths and files on here.
I'd like to say that this
is only an introduction
to a fraction of the data
that's actually available
in most of these databases a
tiny tiny tiny little subset.
There's so much information
that hasn't been reported on
that are stored in
these databases.
So I encourage you to
take a look at these
on some of your own devices
or your test devices
to get more
information from there.
The ones highlighted in
pink are some of the ones
I'm going to be
talking about today
and you'll notice
the table counts
specifically current power log
down there at the bottom.
There are 257 tables
within this one database.
There is a crazy amount
of information to be had.
and another slide here just
for documentation purposes.
So let's get into it let's talk
about some application usage
How are the users using
their various applications.
Are there third-party
applications, let's say.
So if we go into this
battery settings page,
it'll take a few minutes
but you'll finally get this
other screen that pops up
showing the percentage of usage.
Now you can get it on
a last 24 hour basis
or a last 7 day basis.
Now if you're
looking at this GUI
you're saying okay this
information has to be stored
on the device somewhere.
So I went ahead and
found that information.
That information is being stored
in the current power
log pl/sql database.
This is a very very
large database.
This is the over 250
table type database.
So this one is
storing information
about the background and
screen time of an application.
So how long was the user
looking at this application for.
How long was it
on the screen for.
So it stores it for
about two weeks.
Power log has
archive files as well
so you get about two
weeks and five days
worth of information
and the time stamps
do tend to be accurate
for this particular one.
So on the left or the
right hand side here
got your time stamp,
a background and screen time
and the bundle ID.
Bundle ID is basically
which application
or which process
is actually running
for this particular one here.
So I can take this information
and I can correlate it and
do some analysis on it.
So on the left hand
side here I have this
PLAppTimeService_Aggregate_AppRe
they're all named these very
strange names for these tables
but I'm sorting
it by screen time.
So I do a lot of twittering.
A crazy amount of Twitter.
I'm always on it.
So you can see the screen
time is right at the top there
for the Twitter application
comm that 8 bits that Tweety2
and then overdrive anybody
know what overdrive is?
It's like audible
for library books.
I have a lengthy commute,
so I like to listen to
a lot of audiobooks.
mobile mail,
SMS, Facebook so
on and so forth.
I also did the same
thing for background time
on the other side.
so background time
is just you know
which application is taking
the most background
time usage here.
It was kind of
interesting to see
they call that Apple
Safari view service
taking up most of that time.
It's kind of this weird
obscure process for Safari.
So I thought that was
kind of interesting.
Now my favorite
or one of my favorite analysis
is this app by app or excuse me
app usage by hour or by app.
So on the left hand side here
I was curious to see you
know which time of day
so say April 10th at 10 o'clock
that particular hour of the day
which application was
being used the most
and of course for
me it's Twitter.
So at 10 o'clock in the morning
on any given day you know
I tend to be using Twitter
especially on the weekends
on the right-hand side
you can do it on a
per application basis.
So if I want to look at
how when did I use Twitter
for any particular day
an hour I can sort it by
just that bundle ID for
that Twitter application
or Facebook or what-have-you
to see what hours of
the day I was using
this particular application.
Now we can also take this
and kind of graph it.
So I take this
we saw the screenshot on the
left hand side here before
it's showing the screen time
for a particular application
Now if we put it into
a graphical sense
you can see that
I really do spend
way too much time on Twitter.
It is much larger
than most of the other
applications on there.
Now I just took this out
and threw it into numbers
and just did a nice graph there.
You could do a lot
of interesting...
a lot of different
visualizations I think
with this data if you were
if you wanted to do so.
You've got my commute there.
Apple fit call that
Apple Fitness health.
This is when I was
doing some research,
so I had that screen
open quite a bit
and of course you
have to procrastinate
when you're putting a
presentation together.
So of course on Twitter
looking at my RSS feeds on
Feedly and Facebook of course.
Now one of my favorites is what
I call the app play-by-play
This is tracking for about a day
each application that
the user has opened
one after another after another.
So you get this information for
about one day's worth of data.
So if I'm looking
at say April 11th
which applications
was I using you know.
Basically you're
going back and forth
between apps and
the home screen.
This is part of my testing.
Now this is where the
timestamps were really weird
and I can't quite
explain why they were
but they were a solid nine
minutes and 20 seconds
off of the actual time.
I was watching these entries
being created in the database
you know with my watch
I'm like what's going on here.
So do not implicitly
trust your timestamps.
Always test to make sure.
It's kind of strange.
I just want to put
that out there.
some are quite accurate
some are not.
So the next topic I'd
like to talk about
is device state.
Now device state,
I'm gonna be talking about
some of the more physical
attributes of this device.
So lock state.
when the device was
locked versus unlocked
and it's a simple binary value
0 is unlocked 1 is locked.
So you can see when the user
was potentially using the device
versus maybe when it was just
locked and in their pocket.
I took out two different
time stamps here.
So with these tables you get
the time stamps are stored
in a couple of
different formats.
You usually see UNIX epoch but
you might also see mac epoch
which is why I have
an example of it here.
So just be aware of
the time stamp format
when you're looking at these.
Now this one is kind of neat
because it actually
stores the time zone.
So if you're interested in
when the user is traveling
maybe across time zones
it's a potential way to also
view that data in here as well
This is quite sensitive
I'll be on yeah
Troy was quite right with that.
So battery level.
so battery level
can be indicative
of usage throughout
the day right.
So if I take this
battery level and we got
PL battery agent event
backward battery table,
it's storing the level
at certain frequencies.
Or at certain time periods.
But you see it's it's
storing it with a level
and a raw level.
Which is kind of interesting.
The level is actually what's
being presented to the user
you know in the upper
right hand corner
while the raw level
can sometimes be
quite a bit different
than what's actually
presented to the user.
So I found that to
be quite interesting.
Now I can graph this out.
And this is one of my days.
I start at about
looks like about
midnight to about
it's about a day's and
a half worth of data.
'til about 11:00
o'clock the next day.
So I wake up in the
middle of the night
I can't sleep right you know
what do I do I get on Twitter
I check Twitter
and see what's up.
check Facebook.
So you can see a
little blip there.
I took it off the charger
and actually see a little
little battery usage there.
I used a little
bit in the morning.
I did finally get some sleep.
So I used it in the
morning and then I used it
plugged it back into the charger
because I knew I was
gonna have a fairly
phone intensive day.
I used to quite
heavily that day.
You can actually just see it
drop to about almost 50% there
and then I finally put
it back on the charger
and charge it for the
rest of the evening.
So you can see when the
user is really using it.
It does get to be
quite interesting.
Now another one that I like
to show you is plugins state.
plugins state might
not be that interesting
but it still shows a pattern
of life detail to it.
So this is a little story
of my one of my normal days.
you know, commuting from work.
So a plug in state basically
0 is unplugged 1 is plugged in
and this is through
the Lightning port
on the bottom of the phone.
So I'm right in the
beginning of the day
about 7:42 in the morning,
I unplugged it from my charger.
My bedside charger.
So I'm eventually
going to go to work.
I commute and I listened
to those library books.
So I plug it into my car
into the little car charger
and it shows up in here.
It's what about 7:52 I got
in my car and plugged it in.
Got to work unplugged it.
I got a long commute home,
so at about 17:43 so 5:43
I started my commute home.
So this is a daily
pattern that you can see
over and over and over.
You get multiple
entries sometimes
when it doesn't quite take
and then finally you
can see I plugged it in
at about 7:46 to do some more
research for this presentation
so you can correlate
this over you know
at least a month's worth of data
and get this person's
pattern of life you know.
When are they home,
when are they in their car.
You can correlate this with
other information as well.
So I like to talk
about health now.
This is where it kind
of gets really creepy.
There's health
applications, you know.
An Apple person
gets an Apple watch.
It's recording your heart rate,
it's recording different steps
different other
exercise related items.
So you also get this
activity application as well
and this comes with Apple watch.
Those who don't have an Apple
watch paired will not get this
but you'll still
have that fitness,
the health app as well
that you can look at
and it's storing
information like you know
how many times you know are
you active during the day.
How many times did you stand up
and walk around for a little bit
as well as your
exercise minutes.
You can sort of see in
the third panel there
you have a couple of
different workouts
if you want to do workouts.
So a lot of health-related
data is stored
in these little
health databases.
Now these this data
is actually stored
persistently because it wants to
the user wants to
have access to this
for as long as they can
so they can track their activity
levels and things like that
which means this is
a gigantic database.
I think I extract in
mine and it was about
90 Megs worth of data.
So it is very very large.
Now this is one of the tables
and this is the activity cache.
So this is what's storing
your your brisk minutes
or your energy burned.
Your stand hours goal and
your steps and your distance.
You know your major
health activities
with the little rings.
This walk distance and I'm
I don't know how to
get the thing here
but this walk distance
this column here
I was curious I'm like okay
I know it's this distance
but what is it actually
being stored as.
So I went to one of my
favorite websites WolframAlpha
and started just
plugging in random things
that would make sense
and I know how long like how
long it's a reporting back
to me using the
actual application
I said okay you've
walked seven miles.
it was a good day right.
I got to impress people
with my my walking.
That's not normal
for me obviously.
So I walked seven miles,
so I plugged in meters and
miles and finally got something
that represented the
actual information
that was being presented to
me through the GUI itself.
So you got to know how your
data is being stored as well
sometimes you have to do
a little bit of guessing
and that WolframAlpha
helps out quite a bit.
Next one is this
activity samples.
Now if you look at the
seque lite query here
it can be a little daunting.
I think I'm putting together
four or five different tables
because this data is spread
across many many many places
to actually get this big old
data base worth of information
and to make it have some sense.
Now we have this data types
on the right hand side here.
So data types is what's storing
the various bits of data.
So the weight is being tracked
if they're in
putting their weight.
Nutrition.
If you have certain applications
like dietary applications
hooked up with your
health application.
it'll track you know
how much vitamin C
how many carbohydrates I have.
All that good stuff.
The steps is represented,
the heart rate is represented.
So a lot of different details
and they're all being stored
in this huge huge
sequel lite query.
Which means you get
thousands and thousands
of rows in this
particular query output.
So a lot of information in here
but it can be
potentially useful.
Now one of my favorites
topics to talk about
is location.
I have been kind of obsessed
with looking for locations
on different iPhones
and i devices
to see where can I pull this
location information from.
You know I get asked where was
this person at a certain time
I don't know.
Let me go find some
some areas on the drive
where that can pull
that information from.
So the first one and if nobody
has actually looked at their own
I highly recommend that you do.
First what is called
frequent locations.
So this started I believe iOS
7 or iOS 8 I can't recall.
It's basically tracking where
you're going at any given time
So I like to call it frequent
and recent locations.
It basically has a some sort
of algorithm that's unknown
at this time to bubble
up this information
and I'll show you an
example in just a bit.
This is kind of a
big creep factor
when you actually
look at your own.
On that left hand
screenshot there
it says 31 minutes to Arlington
traffic is unusually
heavy right now.
I did not request
this information.
It knew that I was leaving work
and it popped this
information up because
it knew I was going
to commute home.
It's called routine D,
the process is actually
called routine.
It knows your routine.
It knows your pattern of life.
Anybody think that might
be a little bit creepy.
Yeah it's good stuff though.
So an example of one of mine.
I go to my frequent locations
and it's really hidden
deep down into the GUI.
So it's really hard
for people to find.
but I do have that path up
there so you can find it.
You can see I've been to
Arlington to DC Stafford
Florida, California
and Washington.
You know it gives you
a broad range here.
So if I click
through Washington,
California and Washington,
I've been on South
Disneyland Drive,
176 Street and Airport way.
I can go even further and
get more specific information
like how long was I there
and how many times
was I actually
at that particular location.
It's doing all this
in the background.
So these locations
are being stored
and some of these
encrypted databases.
I use the air quotes because
if you have a jailbroken device
you can get access to
these fairly easily.
You just have to get
that physical access.
So these locations
are being stored
in this cache
encrypted B database.
Now you get this for
about about a day
before it gets rolled into
the actual frequent locations
files I'll talk about
in just a second.
You get lats you get longs
altitude and so on.
I can import this information.
I can import this information
into whatever mapping
application you might want.
I chose to Google my
maps for the screenshot
because it just makes
a nice presentation.
so I have a day's
worth of Lat and longs
and I started in the beginning.
I live in Arlington and I
commute down to Stafford
every single day.
So I can actually
plot out my commute
with this application here.
So you see that first
part of my commute.
I go by Arlington Cemetery,
I go on 395 and eventually
head down not to 95
which is a very fun drive.
If you're in the DC area you
know how awesome that can be.
I'm opposite traffic though.
Yeah it's still not great.
Now the frequent locations.
So you get these data
points that are stored
in this encrypted
cached b database.
You get them for about a day.
Whatever algorithm
that Apple is using,
it's going to push some
of this information
into these state model one
or two dot archive files
dot archive files,
like what is that?
It's actually a plist file
You don't have to have a you
know a plist file extension
to have a plist file.
They're just binary XML files
but these are a
little bit different.
These are NS keyed
archiver plist files.
Has anybody look
at these before?
They are absolutely
awful to look at.
So you think XML you
think key and value
but these NS keyed archiver
property list files
are kind of a serialized
version of that.
I have a whole blog
article about it.
How much of a pain
it is to actually
interpret this information
for the analyst itself
but instead of
doing that for these
I actually wrote a script to
parse some of this information
so I can actually pull
it out much quicker
than doing it manually.
So got it up there on my Github
and what it does is it
extracts a CSV or a KML file
and throws it into you
know you could throw it
into whatever mapping
application you want.
The screenshot here I have
an example of Google Earth
and you can see which
locations and where I've been.
I also have a text out
I also have a text output
for this particular one
which just parses the
information in the database.
So the geolocation data blobs
you can sort of see on
the information in there
location data, the visits
the entries, the transitions.
All that information is being
stored within that plist file
which is where the actual GUI
is pulling that
information from.
Now we also have cell locations.
So cell locations
is basically looking
for the locations for
all the cellular towers
through various different
you know different protocols.
So CDMA will have one.
LTE so on and so forth.
So it's storing this
information in these tables
lat and longs as well
as the cellular tower
information as well.
Now the one thing with
the cellular information
that is much less accurate.
So I was only at the
the yellow spot in DC
on this map here but I
was getting the locations
for all the cellular
towers all around my area.
So it's a lot more general.
You also get Wi-Fi.
It's doing more driving for you.
How cool is that
So it's storing the
MAC address channels
lat and longs.
That MAC address looks
kind of weird, right?
It's actually storing it in
base 10 which is strange.
So in the calculator app
you can take one of these
or you can do it in any
other format you want
and change it to base 16
throw colons in there and
then you're good to go.
You have a have a a MAC address
that looks familiar to you.
I can plug this into
a site called wiggle
and actually plot
the information and
find more information
about you know how long this
access point was around for
so on and so forth.
And of course I just
released a script
called location scraper that
takes a lot of these databases
that I just talked about and
stores all this information
or outputs all the information
in XML and KML or CSV.
So you can rip all
these databases out,
run the script on it,
throw it into Google Earth
and look at all this
information out there.
So if that one's already out.
I know the slides say it's
not but it is out now.
I thank you for coming
to the presentation.
If you do have
questions you know,
please I'll be here
pretty much all week.
So feel free to ask
questions whenever you like.
I am looking for
somebody to work with me.
If you do a lot of
Android forensics
come talk to me.
My class my information
is up there.
All my presentations and
scripts that were presented here
are up on the Github.
So thank you very much.
So any questions?
- [Man] Do you know
if the the phones
will ever do location
services just by GPS
without relying on
assisted cell tower
or the Wi-Fi.
for example if I'm
in airplane mode
or just try and passively
receive GPS signals.
- Yeah so I've been
meaning to research that
and get a little bit
more detail on it.
I believe even if
you have airport
or what's it called,
airplane mode turned on,
it still does GPS I believe.
But I'd like to test that
across multiple devices
just to be sure
because it might change
on per device per iOS.
So more research to be sure.
- [Man] I noticed when you
brought up the the screenshot
of the power management
application on the iOS
it's very very similar to
the one that's on Android.
Do you know if the
backends are similar
and do any of these other
applications have backends
that are very similar
on the Android side?
- Yes so I get
that question a lot
when I do this presentation.
I do Android forensics.
I don't do it as
much as I do iOS.
I mean iOS is my
I love Apple stuff
but I have been looking at
some of the Android versions
of these databases.
They still have a
health database.
location databases.
They're not quite
the same format
but if they're the databases
are here for a purpose right.
So the purpose is to
be useful to the user.
So on the Android side it's
doing a lot of the same thing.
I don't know if it has
like a frequent locations
type of aspect to it
but a lot of the information
or a lot of the usage
could potentially be
found on Android devices.
I just haven't done the
research for that specifically.
One thing I also like to
point out is third-party apps.
So your Fitbit application.
That stores a lot of these
very similar health-related
information in here.
So it's not just
native applications.
It could potentially
be third-party
applications as well.
Anyone else?
- [Man] So in situations
where you turn off
location services,
how much is that honored?
- As far as I know it's
honored quite well.
Again it's one of those
things I'd like to research
is just have a phone
completely brand new,
turn off location services.
Never have it on and see
what's actually being stored
in those location databases.
I won't even guess to how
much would actually be stored
until I actually do it.
Again like Heather said,
I'd like to test things
before I actually tell you
whether it's yes or no right.
I know crazy, right?
- [Woman] But then you
can barely use your phone
when you turn the location off.
- I know.
I hate.
It kills me to
turn off locations
but it makes you
paranoid that you
probably actually should
turn off locations
from an OPSEC point of view
and I'm getting the cut off
so thank you.
If you do have other
questions you know
I'll be here all week.
Thank you.
(applause)
(upbeat music)