(epic music)
- [Robert] I also want to
give Erick a quick chance
to introduce himself.
I met Erick actually
at Utica College,
so I teach at a Masters program
in my spare time as well,
and Erick was one of the
folks that came through there.
He was incredible
and so I asked him,
said "hey man, you're really
sharp with this stuff,
"if you ever wanna
collaborate, let me know."
As an instructor, both
at Sans and elsewhere,
you say that to people,
you would be surprised
at how many people don't
ever wanna do some
just something extra.
I imagine most people
in this audience do,
you're here, which is great.
But there's so many people
who don't just wanna go
that little extra distance.
He took me up on it, he did
most of the work for this,
so I'll give you a second
just to introduce yourself.
- Cool, thank you,
good afternoon.
When I first saw that we
were gonna be presenting
on the second day, the
last day of the summit,
and the last presentation of
the last day of the summit,
I was a little worried
about the turnout,
but I'm glad to see you're here
and I want to
thank you for that.
My name is Erick
Mandt. I currently work
for the Air Force Office
of Special Investigations
as an open source
intelligence analyst.
Worked with them
since October 2009.
Prior to that, I spent
roughly 20 years, one month,
and eight days in the
United States Navy
as a cryptologic linguist,
kind of like Rebecca
Brown earlier.
Just a different service,
kinda the parent service,
I will point out to her.
(laughter)
and I did Russian
instead of Chinese,
so with that back
over to you, Rob.
- Alright, perfect.
So I really like his
background on intel intel
because that's what we want
to talk about today as well,
is not just the let's
throw the word cyber in it.
The beautiful thing about
intelligence analysis
is it's been around a lot
longer than the word cyber.
So it's interesting to see
the over focus of indicators
try to sort of skew
what we see with intel.
So I wanna talk a little
bit about it today.
We're really gonna
cover three points.
We're gonna cover the
just quick lexicon
of what cyber threat
intelligence is,
but we'll jump right into
the Platinum Intrusion,
which I think that campaign is
actually really
really interesting,
Microsoft having done some
really good work on that.
We'll go through
threat intelligence
specifically in an
act of cyber defense.
And then Richard
Heuer and Sherman Kent
because it's hard
to do a presentation
without doing a hat tip
to those two fellas.
And we'll go forward with that.
So, I also couldn't
get through this
without putting up a
Little Bobby comic strip.
So threat intelligence,
when I see threat intelligence
in the community today,
there is an over
focus on two points.
You either see a lot
of organizations trying
to get better indicators faster,
or you see a large
push to share more.
And the problem
around sharing more is
most of you have
probably experienced
at one point in your
day to day lives,
is if it's just filth,
you don't want more of it.
I rather not rate things on
we have a million indicators,
I would love to validate and
rate things on we have 10
really good ones with context
and reports to go with it,
that you can actually
know what's going on
in your network if you see it.
So more is not necessarily
better when we talk indicators,
but also threat
intelligence itself
is actually that
intelligence focus, right,
so it's actually the
analysis of information.
IOC's can just be the
byproduct of that.
And most importantly, and this
is where I think most people
trip up, you have to
know what a threat is.
And threat has three
key components;
intent, opportunity,
and capability.
You don't have one of
those three things,
you're not a threat to
any given organization.
That still requires
organizations to understand
what their opportunities are.
So just to phrase
this going forward,
I want to tell you as the author
of the class here at Sans,
that most people shouldn't
be doing threat intel.
Oh man, that's probably
a horrible thing to say
trying to sell a class, no,
most people shouldn't actually
be doing large scale threat
intelligence generation.
We'll talk today about how
everybody can do consumption,
but really there's a
"you must be this high
to ride the ride" kinda
discussion when looking a intel.
It's that five percent
secret sauce you put
on top of a good organization,
not just something you
jump to immediately
expecting to satisfy all
of your requirements.
Also, when we talk
about Active Defense,
this is the one that
gets sort of mixed up
in the community a lot,
Active Defense was a
strategy for militaries
long before the
word cyber as well,
and it was always about
monitoring your environment,
being able to take action
based off the adversary,
and being able to
adapt over time.
It never has anything
to do with going
into somebody else's territory,
not hack-back, not
geolocation, not honey tokens,
none of that stuff.
The whole process of
Active Defense is a lot
of what you guys do
on a day to day basis,
responding to adversaries and
securing your environments.
So, with that, we'll jump right
into the cyber threat
intelligence portion with
the Platinum case, which I'll
turn it over to Erick for.
- So, a month, two months
ago, somewhere around that
Microsoft released a report
where they characterize
an intrusion campaign they
identified as Platinum.
You can read on the slide
several details of that.
It's really the work, you
think about Microsoft,
large company, they've got a
lot of collection capability,
they bring in a
lot of information,
so they're able to accurately
correlate a lot of information
and give meaning to that,
accurately describe TTP's,
and put out a pretty
decent product.
So you can see some of
the characteristics,
this really is an effort
against Southeast,
South or Southeast
Asian governments
and telecommunication
providers that might
give you an indication
of the type of actor
that's behind it.
You can see some of the
TTP's, the tactics, techniques
and procedures that they use
and the interesting point is
it has been active since 2009.
So we're gonna look at this
information that Microsoft
put out in this report
through the lens
of a couple structured
analytic techniques,
the Diamond Model of
intrusion analysis,
which you've heard referenced
and the intrusion kill chain.
In the last couple of days
I've heard it
mentioned a few times,
I've never seen, no one's
really walked through that,
so it's one of the things
we're going to do today.
There we go.
- There we go.
- So this is the Diamond
Model of Intrusion analysis.
It's a pretty basic
looking thing,
it's based on four
core features,
adversary, victim,
infrastructure, and capability.
And it's really a
way to characterize
an event with inner intrusion,
it does not focus on the
entirety of an intrusion,
it focuses on an
individual event.
And you see the meta features
in the top, I guess,
left, yes left side,
that you can use to
enrich the information
and tell about that.
- I can actually add
onto this as well.
First time saw the Diamond
Model, good ol' Sergio,
for those of you who
haven't met him before,
Sergio's the man.
There's a white paper
that we'll link at the end
that talks about this.
The first time Sergio
talked about this to us
I was working in one of
the intelligence agencies
specifically responsible for
identifying nations-states
breaking into Kirk Lumber
Structures, that was our job,
figuring out attribution
and things around it.
And he comes up, Sergio, all
excited as he is off to be,
like I've got this model, it's
going to change everything.
I'm like oh, I'm so
hyped up, what is it.
And I see this wire drawing,
I'm like you gotta
be kidding me man,
like this is it, the big
like model we're gonna use.
But as he walks
you through this,
I want you to keep in context
the amount of information
that should go into this
'cause when we start actually
structuring our
analysis differently
based off of something
as simple as this
little wire drawing,
we actually started
identifying nation-states
we never even thought were
going to be in our data sets,
and we started identifying
threat actors that
we though were three years
off from actually being able
to target the kind of
infrastructure we were guarding.
So, I just wanna give a quick
hat-tip to it in a sense,
that it actually ends up being
a very, very useful model.
- Just to build on that,
it looks very kinda
basic and simple,
but it's actually
a pretty flexible
and a powerful model to use.
Here you can, you've heard
pivoting referenced multiple
times throughout the
last couple of days,
this is what pivoting looks
like in the Diamond Model.
You can start with any
one of the core features,
and pivot and look at one
of the other core features,
and begin asking
yourself questions
and answering those
questions about say
start with a capability,
take a given capability,
it doesn't matter which one,
start asking yourself,
who uses that capability.
We might not know the
specific person, organization,
or individual, but you can
begin characterizing them.
Look at the infrastructure,
what do we know about
the infrastructure,
what IP addresses, do they fully
control the infrastructure,
is it exploited boxes that
they just happen to be using
and they know it might
now be a permanent thing,
and then also, perhaps
most importantly,
looking at the victim, who
is being targeted on that,
because that can feed into a
lot of really important things,
and you can tell a lot
about the adversary.
So let's take a look at
the Platinum Intrusion,
we'll run through
three slides really,
to just walk you through
what it looks like.
Here's the very basic
one, it's weaponization.
In this case the
adversary, unidentified,
embeds an Active X control
in a Word document.
So they've developed
a capability.
This is a way just
to characterize that.
Not a lot of
information in this one.
You see in the next slide
the delivery aspect of it
can feel a little
bit more information.
It's very concise, it's a
good balance between being
concise but also very clear.
The weaponized
document is delivered
through a spear phishing
email to a personal,
a non-official email account.
If you look at step
two, it's accessed
that personal web mail
account is accessed
on a government computer,
obviously there was some
reconnaissance that went in
that indicated this is
the likely viable method
for delivering that.
And then, you know obviously
spear phishing works,
they open a document and it
delivers a capability to them.
So to go on to one more,
exploitation phase.
Here, you can see,
again as Rob mentioned,
the amount of data that you
can really fit into this
Diamond Model in a good
easy to understand way.
Again, just a little
bit of overlap,
the victim opens a
trojanized Word document,
that Active X control then
reaches out and downloads
to and adversary
controlled infrastructure,
downloads a JavaScript,
executes a JavaScript,
it fingerprints the
browser, and the reaches out
and grabs a PNG that has
a second zero day in it,
and then that one is executed,
provides a capability
to execute remote code
to a memory corruption
vulnerability.
So, I've walked through these
three slides really quickly,
but hopefully you can see
that it's a very flexible tool
where you can get a
lot of information
in about individual events
and that's really the,
with inner intrusion, that's
really one of the strengths
of the Diamond Model.
Now, I'll turn it over to Rob
and he'll talk a little bit
about the intrusion kill chain
which really focuses on the
entirety of the intrusion.
- Perfect, so, this is
actually where I wanna note,
so if we look through any
of these slides as
we flip through,
how much of that looks to you
like almost every campaign ever?
When we say like oh, spear
phishing, zero day, drops,
Active X, congratulations right?
So that first view we look
at and go why, who cares,
like what's the point?
The whole point with
Diamond Model, Kill Chain,
all these different models
that you've heard about,
are just to put data
in different buckets.
It's just to structure data
so that when analysts are
actually going through and they
start identifying patterns,
that's everything we wanna do
in terms of
intelligence analysis.
So the Kill Chain, I
always love talking
about the Kill Chain
because the first thing
that I can sense is
when I say that word,
there's definitely a side
of the audience before
that's seen the Lockheed
marketing that takes place,
and you just sink in your chair
and go "kill chain oh my gosh,"
but the reason I like
that is 'cause I get a lot
of folks come up to me
and go "kill chain's dead,
"kill chain doesn't work."
I go, "oh, cool, 100%
totally agree with you.
"Why doesn't it work?"
"Ah, well, somebody on
Twitter was telling me,"
I go, "okay."
Until you can figure
out why it doesn't work,
it's probably a good
model to use anyways,
but all models are broken.
All models break down over time.
The entire purpose
behind them is being able
to structure data and
use it for your purpose.
It's not this mythical,
magical cure-all.
So when we look
along the Kill Chain
around reconnaissance,
weaponizations,
all of the things you know.
Think of it not as
from where do I disrupt
the Kill Chain
defender perspective,
but think of it from
the analyst perspective.
Where do I start seeing
indicators that are popping up
in multiple intrusions across
these different data sets
that are matching the same
phase of the Kill Chain.
Why am I starting to see
the same memory corruption
vulnerability being exploited
in different campaigns.
Then you add in the
victim analysis piece
in the Diamond Model, which
I think is probably one
of the strongest
attributes of it.
Who even has the motivation
to go after this target?
So the Guccifer
presentation that you had,
you know there's a lot of
different things we can talk
about attribution, but it
probably wasn't somebody
scraping off credit cards.
Probably wasn't a
cyber crime type actor.
We can start ruling out just
based off victim analysis
what we think it
may or may not be.
And as we start
structuring that data along
is when we'll see
those patterns.
So that's what I
wanted to hit on here.
The first thing I'll do is talk
about the Active Defense piece,
is the Active Cyber Defense
Cycle, it's one of my models,
I'll admit to you that I only
threw the word cyber in there
because it makes
the acronym ACDC
and I just thought
that was clever,
but the whole structure of this
and the reason I want to
show this to you here,
is when most organizations
say I want threat intel,
what they really mean
is I want somebody smart
in my organization who
understands my organization
well enough to go out
into the larger field
and collect whatever's available
and apply it to my organization.
That is threat
intelligence consumption.
That's a model like
that, using intelligence
to drive your
processes for hunting
inside the environment,
doing instant response,
doing threat analysis
on the back end,
and competing in that loop.
That's what most organizations
want to be doing.
When we start talking about
threat intelligence generation,
which is analysis of lots
of intrusions over time,
Kill Chain analysis matched
with the Diamond Model,
Diamond Model for each
phase of the Kill Chain,
when I start saying
all these things
there's probably some of you
who are just tuning it out
and going that looks like a
lot of work, 'cause it is.
There's a lot of
organizations on this planet
that shouldn't even be thinking
about trying to
generate intelligence
'cause they don't have the
right amount of data for it.
Which I don't want
to put of anybody,
I don't wanna say
like you two can't,
I wanna say that there's
organizations that need
to take a look at
their security maturity
and validate the
return on investment
they're getting out
of any given process.
'Cause when you actually
combine the two,
and you start matching
up with organizations
that do generate
intelligence very well,
whether it's in information
sharing at an analysis center,
whether it's Microsoft
getting lots of data,
whether it's the government
as if they're gonna help,
but whether it's anybody
that's actually sharing this
side of intelligence with you,
you've gotta know how to use it
and how it winds up with you,
or it's ultimately
going to be meaningless.
How many of you have heard
actionable intelligence?
Oh my gosh, yes, I heard
the grunts and groans.
I hate that term, probably
for different reasons
than most of you,
but I hate that term
because if you look at what
intelligence really is,
it must satisfy a requirement
or you're not
doing intelligence.
So by the very definition
of what intelligence is,
there's no such thing as
un-actionable or in-actionable
intelligence so there's not
actionable intelligence.
You are creating requirements
that you are mapping
and actually doing the
process or you're not.
Just an AV feed with
a bunch of indicators
is not intelligence, its
actual information analysis.
So when you see
this process here
going back and forth between
that generation consumption,
this is what we wanna
get the community to.
I like when folks
come into my class
on the threat intelligence
side and go wow,
I realize that we're
not the group that wants
to create intelligence,
we wanna use it.
Wow, we just saved
20 million dollars
in threat intelligence to
make sure we didn't split
up a team for nothing, I'm like,
great job guys, that's
a good ROI to take.
But it's try to be defeatists,
it's trying not to
push people down,
the whole point is saying
what do you actually wanna do,
what's your big requirement?
So we look at it from
this perspective,
which is, I'll let
Erick cover it a lot,
but what I wanna say
about this perspective,
is you need to know, looking
at the Diamond Model,
looking at any given
structure analysis set,
what side you fall on,
and the big pitch here
is your organization with all
the things you have to do,
whether you're in the military
and you've got all
the CBT's to do,
whether you're on a regulation
and compliance side,
maybe you're with the
electric sector and you've got
nerc cip regulations
you've got to acquire,
you've got stuff
to do all day long.
You will probably only get to
focus on one of these sides
of the ply, right,
you will either say
I'm gonna be
operational using it,
or I'm going to be generating
it and be an analyst.
The problem I see is when
most folks try to do both,
they fail at both.
You've got to figure
out where you are
and try to take advantage
of those models.
Why don't I let you
walk this through it.
- So jumping onto that,
whichever side that you're on,
whether you're on the consumer
or the generation side,
it's good to understand the
relationship between the two
so that you can effectively
manage that relationship.
Going back to the Diamond Model,
one of the things I really
like about it is it really
provides a natural divide in
how you can understand that.
The top model is really
an intelligence of you
where you're externally focused,
you're looking at the adversary.
What is the adversary doing?
What infrastructure
does the adversary have?
What type is it, you can see
the different ways you can
characterize it on right
above infrastructure.
You also look at what type of
adversary you're encountering
and the tactics,
techniques, and procedures.
So it gives the focuses
on the external actor.
The bottom part to me is that's
where we have the control,
that's our network, where
the network defenders--
I kinda wish I'd changed the
word victim to network defender
because the victim is kind of
a defeatist approach there,
but the network defender,
that's where you have
your action on this.
What network security monitoring
and asset identification
processes do you have?
What ability do you have
to manipulate threat
and the environment?
On the capabilities side, do
you have instant response plans
fully developed and practiced?
Again the threat
environment manipulation,
and then getting down to,
as Robert's talked about,
the victim side of this.
You know, looking at
who is being attacked,
that tells a lot
about the adversary.
Are you dealing with
critical infrastructure
that you're trying to protect?
Are you protecting
financial data,
customer data,
proprietary information?
Understanding both
sides of the diamond,
both the external and the
internal of what you're doing.
- [Robert] Wait, if you
could go back one real quick.
- Sure.
- So here's one thing I
also want to leave you with
on this discussion of
which side you're on,
how many defenders
on a regular basis,
want to know if it's
China, Russia, whatever,
watch, right, that's the
topic, we always see it.
Well was it China,
was it Russia?
If you're doing the
operational side
of consuming intelligence,
if you're on the side
that's actually doing
network security,
I actually think that it hurts
you to even think about that.
So lets run through
a little quick drill.
China's on you network,
what are they looking for?
- IP.
- IP, intellectual property.
Russia's on you network,
and other than the DNC,
what are they looking for?
(audience members speaking)
They could be doing that,
but are they doing any sort
of military preparations,
maybe a little bit
of reconnaissance
for a larger
intelligence apparatus.
Iran is on your network,
what might they be doing?
- [Audience Member] Nuclear.
- Nuclear environment,
that's always a good one.
I always hear things
like data deletion.
Same thing with North Korea.
If North Korea's on
your network and you're,
unfortunately, you're
Sony, anybody else though,
same thing, data deletion right.
This is where
defenders mindsets go,
all of that is bias.
All of that is you have seen
one or two campaigns before
about adversary X and it
focuses how you look at it.
Every single team out
there across the world
has every one of those teams.
And when I go in
places across the world
I still have to include US
and their threat landscapes.
I'm like, yeah the US has
IP teams and military teams
and intelligence teams,
same thing with Russia,
China, and Iran,
everybody has them.
So if you're only starting
to think about attribution
at that tactical level,
you're going to bias the way
that you look at the data
and you're gonna miss things.
That's one of the key
points I wanna draw out
of this model here.
Is if you're on the
operational side,
it's not about who
the adversary is,
it's about threat groups.
Can we call it sparkling pander,
or whatever else you wanna
call it to group them together,
great, can we call it
some level of actor
that we can view all the
intrusions to see patterns
across them, good job.
But until you start talking
at the strategic level,
you may not care.
Your board of
directors might care.
If you dealing in
the government,
the policy makers might care.
But you're not gonna patch
the network differently,
respond differently, look for
sim cash or PSX differently,
you're not gonna do different
instant response tactics
if you think it's China
versus Russia, and if you are,
I'm gonna tell you that
you're doing it based of bias,
and you will get caught with
your proverbial pants down
and it will not be
a fun time, alright.
So we've got to figure
out how to look at this
from either side of the angle.
Continue on.
- So, just one more slide,
kind of putting the
two sides together.
If you use this view to
understand relationship,
kinda gives us a red
force, blue force approach.
And it's a good way, a
mental way, at least for me,
hopefully it is for you, to
understand the relationship
between the
intelligence production
and the intelligence
consumption.
Now we've gone through a
lot of semi pretty pictures
up here, little diagrams,
- [Robert] This one's
for you Rebecca.
You're not even
looking, you're texting.
- I'm eating!
- Okay.
- All lot of this is just
not us coming up with,
or the people who came up
with these models just kind of
come up with something
on their own,
it's really built on the
work of some other people.
Richard Heuer, very well-known
with the intelligence community,
career CIN employee,
started out on the
case officer side
and switched over to
intelligence analysis,
and as he was developing
his careers as an analyst,
he started thinking
about how he did it.
He started thinking
about how he thinks.
And that led him
to kinda going off
into a little bit
of esoteric stuff.
He started talking about looking
into cognitive psychology,
how does the brain work?
And he identified a
couple key issues,
one is he was convinced
that good intelligence is
in the head, it's
not in the numbers,
it's not an automated
process, it's not in tools,
it's in the head, it's the
application of human intellect.
A couple of areas
that he focused on
were perception and memory.
As all of you guys are
out there listening to me,
you're all perceiving
me different.
You're going to take different
things away from this talk
as you listen to Rob and myself,
because you come from
different places,
you have different experiences,
you might have different
levels of interest in
what you're hearing,
you might have differing
levels of understanding of it.
That will frame what
you take away from this.
Memory is not like the camera
in the back of the room
where it just
records everything,
your brain kinda
creates a story,
and that's how it
stores the information.
On the memory side, there's
some limitations there as well.
There's this kinda
magic rule of seven,
that your brain can really
handle in active memory,
about seven pieces
of information.
Some people a little bit
less, some a little more.
But if you start
getting above that,
you're gonna start
forgetting things,
you're gonna undervalue
different things,
so these were weaknesses,
you know our brain is a tool.
So we've heard talked about
all the different tools
for forensics, some of
them are good in one thing
and not good in the other,
same thing for our brain.
So Mr. Heuer came up
with a couple things
that you can do to address that.
One is decomposition,
one's externalization.
Decomposition's just
really breaking things
down into the basics.
If you think about
the Diamond Model,
that's broken down into
four basic components,
that's really, it's
Richard Heuer's thought
put out in application
and it's externalized,
that means it's documented,
put together down on paper,
so that you're able to
recall these information
or have some reference
material to go back to.
He also in his book
the Psychology of
Intelligence Analysis,
which I really
encourage you to read,
he's come up with an analysis
of competing hypothesis,
I heard it talked about
briefly in the previous talk.
Again, it flows very well from
the victim's side of things
because if you know something
about who's being target,
that tells you a bit
about who the actor is
and what the capabilities are
that they might be employing.
One of the very interesting
things about analysis
of competing hypothesis that
I found it's a very good
kinda control on bias that
Rob was talking about,
is it requires you to
generate multiple biases,
or multiple hypothesis, and
then you're not seeking to prove
one of the hypothesis, you're
seeking to identify the one
that has the least chance
of being incorrect.
So it's a little bit different
turning things on the head,
from my perspective.
And he also recognized that
intelligence, like Robert said,
it's only intelligence
if someone wants it.
Intelligence for
intelligence sake
is really kinda worthless.
Anything you'd like
to add on that?
- [Robert] Nope, go ahead.
- So one other
individual, Sherman Kent,
he's really kinda the godfather
of American
intelligence analysis,
although he started
out in the 30's
as a history professor at Yale,
and then moved into the
intelligence community
in the Central
Intelligence Agency.
He still kinda anticipated
the advent of the computers
and he understood that
automated processes are aids
to human thinking but that
didn't change the fact
that the human, well-trained
analyst is really
remains the intelligence
device supreme.
That's really, the human
element comes in on that.
His work has resulted
in analytic doctrine.
It's really, well you can
see all nine points there,
the one that's most
applicable here,
and hopefully you've
seen this come through,
is the relationship that focuses
on policy-maker concerns,
what's that really talking
about is the relationship
between intelligence producers
and intelligence consumers.
They both have to be there.
I think in the
Intrusion Kill Chain,
the title of the paper is
Intelligence Driven Defense,
so that's all fine and good,
but I would argue
that you need to
take it a step farther back,
and start with the policy-maker,
the consumer of that,
'cause that's what
really kicks off
and defines what the
intelligence producers
are going to do for you.
So I took a little
bit of liberty
with the statement he made.
Network defense,
it's kinda like love,
it really takes two to make it.
You gotta have the intel and
you gotta have the consumers.
And they gotta get along
and be kinda intimate.
- Yeah, I wanna note as we
start rounding this out.
Look at just that
nine list right there.
Just take a quick look at it,
and if you can map this
intelligence framework,
the old-school intelligence,
and just think about
how this applies to
our day to day basis
with what we see and
are inundated with now.
Number nine, candid
admission of mistakes.
I really like our vendor
community and all the
threat intelligence
analysis stuff that happens,
but when's the last time
you've ever seen anybody
come out and go,
"oh, we got it wrong,
"the attribution was off, we
had some different indicators
"that took us down
the wrong path,
"and here's the
new information."
Anybody's ever seen that?
I know I haven't.
And the problem with
that is attribution,
we have this whole
discussion earlier,
attribution changes over time.
Toolkits, indicators,
things like that,
they fade in and out,
different people use them.
Keys that the Russians
might of used at one point
are now attributable and
relevant to everyone else.
We as a community, if I
look at where we really need
to take a step forward,
as we're going and moving.
Number one, with have to
understand the difference
between intelligence
consumption generation.
Number two, we need to
start getting better
at going back classical
intel and realizing
it's gotta address
concerns upfront,
and the very end of it,
we gotta make sure we're
ready to admit our mistakes
or changes over time.
Until we can do that,
policy-makers will
never listen to us.
Unfortunately sometimes
intelligence analysis
gets to that level.
I've seen a lot of reports
go to national policy-makers.
I deal out with a bunch
of congress critters now
out in the think tank
that I work when in DC.
And you'd be surprised at how
much they listen to people
in the community that I would
imagine most of us dislike.
There are certain key figures
that all of us sort of like
rally around and go,
"ah, he's a jerk."
and then yet they get
the ear of congress
because they're a cyber
security whatever expert.
So a lot of this intelligence
stuff that goes on
based off the data that you
collect and produce, right,
so a lot of instant
response data
is really where threat
intel comes from.
That level of data
is what's required.
When it goes up
to national policy
or tactical level defense,
things can change drastically.
And we have to be aware
of how it's gonna be used
or we're going to end up
being the suckers instead
of the people who are actually
contributing to anything.
So we'll go ahead and
go to the next one here,
as we start rounding it out.
I just put some references
and readings for you.
There is no way to do a good
"here's everything about intel"
in like a 30 minute
kinda presentation.
You need to do some reading.
I love my class,
don't get me wrong,
that's why I like teaching it,
and we try to give
on the class side
20 years of intelligence
work in five days
and just water hose it.
But the only way you're
really really gonna get good
after that, is you gotta read.
A lot of the intelligence
analysis stuff isn't
"here's how you run this tool,"
it not, "here's the man file,"
it's what were people
thinking about working through
hard challenges in
Operation Bodyguard.
How are they doing
things in Vietnam
compared to Desert Shield.
How are the Chinese in the
second sino Japanese war
dealing with the
Japanese Imperial Army?
Think about the intelligence
analysis of those folks,
and then try to map it
over to what we're doing.
So I put the references up,
some of the ones that I enjoy,
Diamond Model, Sliding
Scale, Phycology Analysis,
the threat intelligence poster
that you've probably gotten
multiple copies of
by now I'm sure.
So those exist as well.
And then the last
slide, of course,
Little Bobby to roll it out.
I write these things so of
course I'll include them.
"We need more
scalable cloud based
"threat intelligence analytics,
"and automated big data end
point security solutions,"
Little Bobby says.
Matt says, "You have no idea
what you just said, do you?"
He says, "Nope, I just read
off a list of words out loud
"and got invited to
speak at a conference.
"I figured if I
told two more people
I'd be a security expert."
Matt says, "Yeah,
sounds about right."
So as you go forward,
looking at these things,
as you go forward thinking
about different ways
to do analysis, be that voice
of change in the community,
when somebody,
attribution case, says,
"oh well that C2 server
could've been reused."
Be like, "Well, did you
look at the actual data
"that went into
creating that analysis,
"or are you just being that
pain point in the community?"
How many of you have worked an
instant response case before?
Do you feel that I could
come in after reading one
of you reports and tell
you all the same things
about your instant
response case?
Do you feel that if I wasn't
on your instant response team
dealing with that case,
that I would be an
expert on that case?
Probably not, but it's
funny to me that when people
come up with analysis
along intelligence,
everybody's automatically
an expert and can dime out
and tear down every
bit of analysis.
There's a lot of stuff
that goes into it.
Try to be that force of change,
go to figure out where
those references are,
and be mindful of where
your data's gonna go
'cause it makes a
huge difference.
Erick, any last thoughts?
- Nope, I'm good.
- Perfect.
Thank you so much
for your time today.
I guess I'm supposed to ask
questions now, too, right?
I'm supposed to ask
questions of you,
we're reversing here at Sans.
- Hold up, it's a--
- Not now?
- [Announcer] Yeah hold up.
- Oh, I'm supposed
to wait for those.
- [Announcer]
Audience questions.
- Alright, we'll wait for that,
but you have a question good
sir, up front, go for it.
- [Audience Member] Go ahead?
- Yeah, yeah, go ahead.
- You got a microphone
coming there.
- Alright, I'll
just yell at him.
- [Audience Member] So you
showed the Diamond Model,
which is very valuable
and have been able
to use it a few times,
question I have is if you've
seen it used more successfully
at the beginning as
you're doing the analysis,
or most often at
the final analysis,
post mortem phase of things,
and then anything automated
that you've seen to actually
take your IOC's and
populate them out
based upon what you know.
- Oh yeah, good question,
so I'll speak up,
I'll repeat him because I think
it was a little bit quiet.
Really good
questions, number one,
where have I seen it
most successfully used,
the back end or the front end
of the analysis being done,
and number two, is
there any sort of tools
that can help us out here.
So it completely depends
on your vantage point,
and I'm not gonna give you
a it depends answer alone,
I'll answer the question,
but it depends on
your vantage point
and what you're trying to do.
When I was on a team that,
and nowadays it's
called threat hunting,
when I was on a team
doing the kind of stuff
that we call threat hunting now,
we used it on the front end.
We used it on, you know what,
I've got some data from
our different data sets,
I've got a bunch
of data related to,
we'll call them honey pots,
hydroelectric
facilities in Africa
and people targeting them.
Hmm, who would even be
interested in going after
hydroelectric facilities in
Africa and sub setting contracts
for big construction projects
in Sub-Saharan Africa?
I wonder if any of this data
relates to the indicators
that I've had before based
on Chinese intrusion groups.
Oh look, we found new teams
that we didn't even realize
because we see the
real world events,
not just the cyber ones where
certain Chinese companies
are starting to win
all the contracts
in all the areas that
we saw getting targeted.
And that's where you
would use the diamond
on the front model more
victim analysis focused.
On the back end, when you're
actually creating intelligence
products and actual reference
guides or big analysis sets,
you'll still use it, and you'll
structure that data along,
and you'll go okay,
did I do it correctly?
But on that Diamond
Model on the back end,
that's really where
you gotta bring in ACH.
'Cause we all have biases.
I'm a Sans instructor, I'm
from Alabama, I'm white,
and I'm married to a Dutch girl.
I've got some biases that
may affect me, alright,
just a couple and so
I've gotta figure out how
to defeat those so that
they don't bleed over
into my analysis, especially
when we're talking to either
policy-makers or the people
that are on the networks
that we expect to use it.
So we use those models
on both sides really,
but there's different
ways that you would
use them to your point.
As far as tools
go, I haven't seen,
I mean there's all your
different, name your platform,
that will do some
different aspects of this.
One of the ones that I
actually liked is Threat_Notes,
so Scott and them
folks have been doing
some really good work with that.
So Threat_Note will allow
you to take indicators
that you have, it's just
a free GitHub script
to get started with
and stuff if you want,
then if you realize you like it,
go talk to vendors
about platforms.
It's usually my big push,
and I don't wanna down play
any vendor support here,
but my big push is usually
max out open source,
figure what the value is of
that professional product,
then go to the
professional product,
'cause eventually someone's
gonna ask why do we need that,
and if you have them references
and metrics backing it up
of what you did before
the professional product,
you can keep that nice
shiny toy you got,
if you don't, you're
losing it first time
there's a budget cut.
So Threat_Note on GitHub is
actually a really good one,
where you take key indicators,
you classify 'em based on
the Diamond Model structure,
and there's even a
visual analysis component
of indicators that overlap.
- [Announcer] Last question.
- [Audience Member] You said
generally speaking that people
should not both produce
and consume intelligence,
I wanna clarify a little bit.
If you primarily
consume, but you also
generate information internally
from attacks that you see
and you document that and
you fit it into the context
of the threat intelligence
that you're consuming,
can you be said
to generate that,
or is that just a
part of consuming?
- I would say that
you're giving off--
so if we go back to that
slide, as we go through here,
alright as we go back
to that slide with that
consume to generate process,
where there's the actual line
that goes back between 'em.
That's what I'm
trying to say here.
We are always involved
in the process.
So all the stuff you do
is going to be coming off
into that generation
of consumption side,
so in my opinion,
you gotta know both.
If you're gonna be
dealing with intel,
you're gonna get swindled
if you don't know
how the hotdogs are made, right?
You gotta understand the
ingredients in the package.
Same way if you're creating
intel and you have no idea how
to do instant response in
security networking monitoring,
you're not gonna
help out your folks.
You gotta actually have
both set of skills.
My point in that, so
thank you for allowing me
the opportunity to clarify.
My point in this, is you really
get to specialize in one.
You're going to be
the team of one.
If you try to be
the team of both,
you're the team that's actually
producing the intelligence
and you think you're
going to consume it,
you also introduce
another bias loop,
where there's no
outside expertise
really looking at that.
So you can get
yourself in a problem
where you run your entire
organization down a lap
that they shouldn't
be going down.
And on that point
I'll also note,
that I think generally speaking,
for non-specialized teams, too.
If I go around to most
companies in the world,
the security operations
center, if they have one,
which most don't, is also
doing patch management,
architecture discussions,
the PowerPoint briefings,
three o'clock phone calls,
you can't do all
of that and this.
You've gotta figure out
what your priorities are.
I find most people, if
you go and ask them,
what are your priorities,
they'll give you about 10.
If you've got more than three,
you don't have priorities.
Right, so you gotta figure
out where you wanna play in.
Good point though.
- [Announcer] Alright, that's
gonna do it for questions.
Big round of applause
for Robert and Erick.
(audience applauding)
(epic music)