(Synth music)
(crowd applause)
- So, this is our
general marching orders.
We're going to talk very
briefly because of the room.
Our building blocks...
What are the things
we have to deal with
that make a registry hive?
If you've never looked at
it from like a hex level.
And then from there
we're going to dive into
what's in those building
blocks a little bit deeper,
just at a high level,
and just because of the
nature of the time frame,
we can't get into
super low-level
with each of the record types.
I want to spend the
majority of the time
getting into deleted recovery,
because that's the most
important part out of this,
so people that have seen
any of my stuff on the
forensic launcher
or my blog posts,
this is kind of how
I like to explain
what a registry hive looks like.
It's basically we have our file,
and then inside that we
have of course our header
and then hbins are buckets
that you put other things in.
So, it's very straightforward
from a high level
and you can see we've got
our header chunk, 40 96 bytes
and then these hbins are
going to be different sizes
typically 40 96 bytes as well,
and then you have
cells, lists, and data,
that live in there and are
related based on pointers
to offsets, relative
offsets, to other structures.
And so here's the important
stuff that's in the header.
This isn't everything,
but these are the things
that we're typically
going to look for.
So where the signature
is, why do we want that?
We can do file analysis to
determine if something's
a registry hive or not.
Last write timestamp, the
major and minor versions.
Those will become
important if you are going
to get into parsing
because of big data
and some other
structures only are...
They work differently depending
on what version of
a hive you have.
So if you just assume, "oh,
I'll just do it the old way
in a new hive.", it's
not going to work,
so you have to take into account
the major and the minor version
numbers for some things.
Root cell offset,
that is going to be
basically where we
start at the top.
So if you've ever opened
up a hive in any tool,
the very first key,
that's our root cell,
so it's basically
the header points us
to where we need to
go to get started.
The length of course,
that's going to be how long
the hive should be, how
long the header thinks
it is anyway, but
you cannot trust it.
If you just always assume
that the length is valid,
you will miss stuff.
It's not always accurate,
so take that in mind.
You basically just have
to run out the whole
file and look for
your hbin headers
to see where things
actually stop, okay?
And then internal file
name, that can be changed,
but typically that is
going to allow us to know
if we have a system
hive, or an NT User hive,
or a user class hive.
Now a better way would be
to go look for the presence
of keys in there just in
case the name got changed
and if you mount a hive
it can change in Regedit
and things like that.
But those are all
important things.
This is what those key fields
look like, and where they are.
So I've got it color-coded here,
and throughout this
presentation there will be
a lot of references
to other resources
throughout the slide deck
and you can really dive down
into any of these beginning
parts here as well.
So there's just where our
important things are here
and color-coded so we
can see our file name
and all the different pieces.
This is what registry
explorer takes the header,
this thing, and
pulls everything out
so that it's actually in
a much more usable format,
so we have our sequence
numbers, we have our check sums,
you can see the version,
our embedded file name,
all of that gets extracted
out in a nice format
so that we can make sense
of it without having to
do a bunch of
manual, conversion.
As far as how we
want to parse a hive,
for people that are
interested in this.
There's some
programmers in here,
I know Willy's tool is going
to take a similar approach,
but anything like this,
this is just the general way
that you would
want to look at it.
At least the way
when I designed it,
I wanted to do it this way.
We open it up, we find
the header, is it a hive?
Yes.
We know where the root
cell is now, then we
start looking for hbins.
Those are our buckets, and
we're only going to find records
that we want to try
and use in those hbins,
and so once we find an
hbin, now we can start...
We can get the length,
and then we can start
pulling these
different records out,
and then we do stuff, right?
The magic, that's where
the magic happens.
As far as building
our tree, our key,
relationships, keys and sub-keys
and then sticking the values
inside each of the keys,
and then once we've
finished with that hbin
we just go back up and do
it until we run out of 'em.
So and that's it
and when you're done
you close it and
you're good to go.
Now one thing to note here
if you have a root cell,
typically it'll be
hex20, that's the
relative offsets
so you have to..
If you're going to look at
something in a hex editor
you have to add the
size of the header
or everything will
not work, right?
So you have to add 4096 bites
which is going to be this.
So throughout you'll
hear the relative
offset or absolute offset...
Keep that in mind if it's
relative you have to add in the
size of the header or things
will not line up right.
So basically this
is a little bit
more information about hbin.
So we've got, our buckets
and some more size stuff,
most of them are 40 96
but the thing to take in
you can't just say,
"I'm just gonna read 40
96 every single time."
In part of the header
of an hbin is the size.
So you take that and then
you multiply it by 40 96
and that's the size of the hbin,
and again if you don't do
that, if you just assume 40 96
and you get a 8mg or an 8k hbin,
when you jump down to
that second section
you're not gonna find
what you're expecting,
things are gonna
go sideways, okay?
So offset, again that's
going to be relative.
So the first one would be zero,
one, two, things like that,
and then our records
are gonna start
at that relative offset.
Okay, again, we
have to add that...
Header size or things
aren't gonna work right.
So this is what an
hbin would look like.
So of the four properties
that we just talked about,
you can see we've
got out signature,
our relative offset,
our size and then
where actual data starts, okay?
And on that particular
one it's and NK,
that would be our root, right?
And this should look familiar
if you've seen enough hives,
that's pretty common
for certain things.
Inside our hbins now we can
start actually pulling things
out that make up our
hives, the things
that we're actually
interested in.
So we've got our NKs,
which are our keys,
VKs, values and then SK which
is our security key stuff.
Okay, general concepts.
In use records have a negative
size, so when you're going
through it and you read
the front part of a record
and you convert it
a sign imager, it's
going to be negative
if it's in use, which
is a bit strange, right?
Why not do it the other way?
So when a record gets deleted
or freed in the registry, the
size just becomes positive.
So keep that in mind when
we get to the second part.
That's how we can
identify things that are,
not being actively used.
Set them aside as far as
where they live and the size,
and then go back and
start carving out
the details that we're
interested in, 'kay?
So you never wanna trust,
the last point there
is really important,
you wanna never trust
the side of free records.
You can from the point of
"I know that there's
this much data"
but you don't wanna just assume
if you see an NK signature
that that's going to be
one NK and that's it,
and tools have run
into this problem,
commercial tools have run
into this problem where,
they have this big blob
of data, they see one NK
and then they just extract
one key, and they move on,
and things don't work.
You have to take the padding
and you have to take the slack
into account when you're
dealing with that.
So NK records.
These are our keys, right?
We have our last write
timestamp, a name,
a subkey and a value
count and some flags,
and the pointers that we are
going to be interested in
is basically where
are our subkeys?
It points to a list,
that points to other NKs.
How many values do we have?
And then our value pointer
would be where is
the list that points
to the other VK structures.
And then we have a pointer
to our security key. Okay?
So those are the things that we
would wanna extract
from an NK record.
This is what an NK record would
look like if you went into
the technical details
of registry explorer,
and if you go in here and
you click on any of these
properties, the bites that
correspond to that property,
will be highlighted down here,
and you could use the tool to
validate itself, or other
tools, or just to do research
and get a better understanding
of what we're talking about.
So our values.
If you're thinking of it
like a file system
perspective, our keys are our
directory structure, values
are files that live inside
of a folder, so we've
got, things of interest
and this certainly isn't
all of 'em, but our name...
And one thing I'll ask
you guys at the end,
what if the name length is zero?
What happens then?
We have a type.
D word, Reg binary,
string, multistring,
those kind of things, a
length and then different
flags that control
stuff about the values.
And then again,
we have pointers.
So if, depending on
the size of the data
that the value represents,
it may point to another
data structure or a list of
pointers in the case of big data
for you to be able to go out
and then build the
contents of that VK record.
Okay, so this is just
what one looks like,
now similar to how the MFT
works you can have data
that's resident in a VK, if
it's equal to or smaller than
four bites, because
our pointer to where
our data would normally
live is four bites long.
So I'll finally have a
number, a small number too.
I could just save space
and stick that value
right inside the
VK record itself.
Okay, and if I have a...
And you can just
see examples here.
It says it's resident because
it knows what the size is,
and here's an example where
we would have one isn't.
So we have bites.
It's pointing to where our
data is, and then you can see
the length is going to match
here, and then that's how many
bites we have and the
range down there so...
The tool will go out and
do all that stuff for you
to show you what it's
actually sitting at on disk.
But you can then
validate it with those
different properties
that are in there.
The SK record is by far the
most complicated and dense
so, we're not gonna spend
a ton of time on here
but you can see on the screen
a lot of the different pieces
that exist in there, and that
bottom link will be really
important and it's a rather
long post if you're interested
to really get an understanding
of how all the bits
work as we break things down.
This is what one
would look like.
There's the bites at the bottom,
and then this is the beginning
part of the property, so
I just break down a
couple of these things.
We have our descriptors
for the Sacls and the Dacls
and all the different things
that would control auditing
and who can access it.
So it just basically explains
all of those and then
we get into things like
how big each sub component is
and then how many ACE records
which, that would define,
who can access it,
and you can see, we have
our identifiers down here,
and then the tool
also reverse back
to the common keys, what it is.
So you don't have to go
Google and look at MSDN,
like what is this key?
What is this identifier?
The security identifier.
Oh that's the built in
administrator.
That's the this.
And if you get one
that it doesn't know,
it'll point you to that as well.
The next part we
wanna talk about
which is our glue, is lists.
And I've mentioned lists as
far as keys pointed to keys
or keys pointing to values.
They're all held together
by these list structures, okay?
And again there's a
very long post down here
about what we wanna do
when it comes to lists.
So I would suggest that
you go look at that
if you're interested in
the mechanics of these
but basically they're just
pointers to other things.
Okay and our data, that's
kind of everything else.
It's just a blob with a
size, and then stuff in it.
And this is typically
where our values will live.
The data that makes
up our values.
We've got the normal
and I mentioned before
the big data case if it's over
a certain size 16344 bites.
And again, that's where
our version number
starts to come into play.
So you have to
treat it differently
if it's greater
than one dot three.
All that stuff we
just talked about,
can get summarized
in this slide.
So we have our root
and then we go here
and you can see we've got our
sub-key list it's a pointer.
We get a list, it points to NKs.
Same thing with our values.
So theses are all the
different types of ways
that you can navigate
through, a hive.
And if you get to the
NK and their sub-keys,
you just would go
back to the beginning,
and then walk down
again until you
have no sub-keys or no values.
So this is just a general
high level overview
of all of these structures
that we just talked about.
Okay, so the real thing I
wanted to talk about today,
we have to have a
little bit of framework
which is what we just talked
about, is how can we recover
deleted keys and values
from the registry?
And this is what we're going
to do with the remaining time.
So basic way we wanna do is,
I talked about we look for
those free records, the
free chunks of data,
once we find that we wanna
look for signatures NK, VK,
those signatures for those
two critical components,
and then once we find
those signatures,
we can start extracting
chunks of data,
and then applying rules
to see if they're valid
and then relating them back
to other keys and values.
Okay and that's this
last point here.
This is what a free
record would look like,
I know it's small, but I
wanted to pick a big one
so we had a lot of
offsets to work with.
So here you can see you have
a size that's a positive size.
And because of that now we
can say this entire page,
this chunk of data, is not being
referenced by anything else.
So we can basically now
start walking bite by bite,
looking for, and the way I
implemented it was I lookfor K.
And I'm going down the list
and list and if I see a K
I look at the bite before
it, and if it's a V or an N,
I record that offset, okay?
And a the end of that process,
I get a list of offsets
that would look something
like this, okay?
So the next thing we would
do is then go to that offset
and you can see it's
highlighted here.
We would have a VK record.
And we can look at the size
and all that stuff so you
have to take where we started,
where did we start this whole
process with the free record?
Then we have our offset and
when we add 'em together we get
the relative offset of
our recoverable record.
Once we have that we
can take those bites
'cause we know the
offset that we're at.
We know where the
next offset is,
where the next signature was.
So now we have a range
that we can take,
and then based on that,
we can recover it,
if it meets certain
critera, right?
We have to have at least
the minimum amount of bites
to do certain things
with an NK or a VK
or there's just not
enough data to recover.
So once we do that,
this is the example
that we have highlighted here.
You can see this is
some of our properties.
We can see the name.
We can see the length,
and those things are all going
to match up to what we saw
when we recovered things
on the previous slide;
the range of data and all that.
So, we would
automate that through
all the free
records in the hive.
Everywhere that's not in use.
We would go through
and carve out all
these NKs and VKs
and then to re-associate
them, we basically want to now
look at that parent
cell in the NK record.
There's a parent cell index.
It points to who owns
this particular key.
So we go through
all of our deleted, and we
can say, "is there any other
deleted keys that
have that offset of a
deleted key that points to it?"
And if they do, we can associate
it to say this deleted key
lives underneath
this deleted key,
and then we can keep doing that
and build up an entire tree,
until the point where
we get to the top part,
the top of the deleted stuff,
that would point back maybe
to a key that's active.
Okay, we look at
the parent offset,
we go to that parent offset.
Now we know is it in use?
Yes or no?
And if it is,
we know that we can
reattatch it to that parent
and we've recovered that
particular NK record
to where it belonged
before it was deleted.
Okay, similarly, we would
start with our NK record
and then go down
through our lists
to pull all the values in, but
you have to take into account
checking of where
those values...
Where those things point
to, because you don't wanna
take a list from an
NK record that says,
"Here's where my
values are", and just
blindly associate them
with the deleted key.
You have to check whether
or not they're in use.
You'll never have, it's not
valid, rather, for an NK record
to point to an in use value.
You just wouldn't have that.
So you have to check, of
the deleted key values,
each of those offsets.
Are they in use or not?
And if they're not in use,
if they're not active,
they you can associate
that value to that key,
and if not, throw a warning.
This is not, "I
can't associate this
because that offset's being
used by something else."
Okay?
So, if you wanna get
into the code, as to the part
that actually does this part
it's a multi step process,
there's a reference there to
get help on how to do
that, and then again,
once we're all done, we're
going to have two groups,
we have ones that we were
able to associate back
to an active record into our
stuff that's not deleted,
and if we...
Once we have that list
established, anything that
falls outside of that,
anything that doesn't
have a valid parent index,
it's unassociated, but it's
still going to have potentially
structure, keys and
sub-keys with values
and things like that, there's
just not any way to relate it
back to where it came from
because that particular offset
has been re-used
for something else
other than an NK record, okay?
So you do all that really,
really fast and then you get
all this stuff basically
out and we can use it,
and then there's
also another one,
would be unassociated
values, and there's nothing
in a VK record that tells
you what key it came from.
So unassociated values
while we have access to them
are less than helpful because
we can't say with certainty
where they came
from, you may find
some interesting
string in there,
but you wouldn't be able
to say where it came from.
We've talked a little bit
about some of these things
when just going through
the process here.
You can't stop processing
after the first signature
and this is where I mentioned,
"don't trust the size",
because if we go through and
I look at a free chunk of data
and I see an NK record
and it's 12000 bites long,
I can't treat that as one NK
record or I'm going to miss
potentially hundreds of values
and keys that I could recover.
Now some tools will do that
and go, "Oh, well this whole
free structure must
only point to one thing
and everything else
is slack or padding."
You can't do it that
way or you're going
to miss a significant
amount of stuff.
And commercial tools, this
is where they've fallen over.
They're fixed now, but that's
where the second part is.
You have to look for signatures
and then, follow the rules
to build these out like
you would if it was in use,
and then contruct the ones
that you successfully
recovered, okay?
And then that bottom
part is the one
I just was talking about.
You can't just assume,
"Oh I'm always just going to
associate up reguardless."
You have to check whether
the things that are being
referenced in a deleted record,
point to an active record.
There's only one valid exception
to that and that's when
we're taking an NK key and
trying to associate it back
to the active parent,
that's the only time
you would violate that rule.
Here's some other
resources, that outline
a lot of the process
just as I went through
and did this,
basically from scratch.
My philosophy on how to do
it, a lot of these basics...
My basics series on the hives
are really going to unpack
a lot of the sub-levels
that we talked about.
The NKs and the VKs.
Oh, okay.
So if you want more
information on this the...
My primary source
when I built my tool
and validated what
we were dealing with
was this bottom one,
Matt's documentation, which
he seems to have figure out
and written stuff
for every single
conceivable artifact everywhere.
So that was my starting point,
this second list here is
a newer one, and it's very
good and it goes even a lot
further than Matt's stuff
does so just another list
of resources to dive
further into these things
and start pulling stuff apart
and I think, right about,
a little, what five
or 10 minutes left?
We'll do questions?
- [Man In Audience] Alright.
My question is, I get a
lot of questions in class,
specifically about
anti-forensics
when it comes to the registry.
Based on what you've discovered
during your research,
with deleted records and you
know, the overall structure.
Question one is: Are you
currently aware of any actual
anti-forensics tool that's
useful against the registry
and two is: With this
information you know here,
could one be built?
- I think there's registry
de-fragmenters, I haven't like
actually run them
against the hive
to see if they're basically
wiping free space.
That would be the way
to really mess it up,
is to go through and
look through things
and look for those
positive size records
and then just zero 'em out.
- [Troy] I think
what they do is, I think
they re-write the hive.
So they'll re-write
the hive compressed,
- Okay.
- [Troy] Basically
get rid of the (mumbles)
- So Troy's saying
one technique that
the de-fragmenters
will do is basically
go through the hive, read
all the valid stuff out
and basically make a copy of it.
So that would be one
technique, another one would be
if you could open up
that hive is to just look
for the free records, you'd
have to leave the size,
when windows tries to
look for the free space,
it wouldn't know what to do.
So if you just
left the size alone
and zeroed out all the
bites of that length.
I'm not aware of anything
that's doing that,
it would not be terribly
difficult to write,
you just would need to be
able to open a locked file,
but that's not,
difficult to implement.
But I'm not aware of any tool
out there doing it write now.
The other thing that makes
it easier for that technique
is there's not
gonna be any holes.
So if we have an hbin,
you're not going to have,
like active, active,
deleted, deleted, active.
Windows when it
frees things, copies
and shoves everything
to the left so to speak.
So all of our free stuff will
be more toward the right side
for lack of a
better illustration.
So just go out there until you
start seeing those free areas.
Padding's gonna be different
of course like slack,
but for the free stuff
it's typically going
to be out at the end
of the structures.
One over here and one over here.
- [Troy] Go.
- [Audience Member] Yes.
Have you used any tools or
found any way to utilize the
anti-user that log files or any
of the registry that log files?
I haven't ever really seen
a great methodology to parts
to them or figure out what's
in there and if so do you know
if they have useful
information of, you know,
maybe registry keys where
deleted and you could help,
- Right
- [Audience Member] Validate,
you know your findings
and find other evidence?
- Those are like the transaction
laws while things are happening.
I've discussed this
with Dave and with Willy
and the length of
time that the stuff
sits in the logs is
relatively short.
So, while it's possible, we
know what the format looks like
I could come up with something
but the chances of you
running into something
where it's like within
that very short window, to
actually need the log files
to overlay on top of the
original hive, it's pretty rare
and I think from
talkin' to Dave...
Have you guys ever
run into that?
Where you actually have
needed it or seen it, useful?
- [Dave] You could definitely
use Registry Recon.
- Registry Recon, like,
a more specialized tool
to pull those things in and
recover those individual items.
So Registry Recon'll do that.
I mean it'll carve a
completely formatted disk
and find all kind
of crazy stuff.
Think there's one over here?
- [Man] So you've been talking
about recovering deleted
registry values and keys
from unallocated portions
of an actual registry hive.
What about chunks of random
registry hives that you
find in unallocated space?
Have you worked on
trying to actually
recover pieces of
structure from that?
- Not with my tools.
That would be more like...
Registry Recon does that.
X-Ways would do that,
where is would find, "Oh
I see a regeff header.
I see the header
length, I can read
that out and potentially
recover some stuff."
Registry recon you point
it at an EZR one or a DD
and it's going to find every
single sliver of everything
and attempt to put
it back together
and it does a very
good job at it.
- [Man] I'm thinking more of
situations where you don't have
the header, you've just got
random chunks of registry
(voice gets drowned out)
- You certainly could find
the NKs and the VKs.
It would be rather difficult
unless they were
relatively close together
and even then you may be...
If you're missing the
first 20% of the hive,
all you relative offsets
are useless at that point.
So really if you have the header
and then down at that point
you'd be much better off than
if you found stuff toward
the middle of the tail, just
because of the nature of...
I don't know how much
stuff came before
and you could figure it
out maybe to a degree
if you have an hbin because
you're gonna have a position
but you don't know how big
all the other sizes were,
it would be very complicated.
You'd have to do it
individually and then try
to just glean something out
of key names or value names,
time stamps, things like that.
Is there one over here too?
- [Troy] Anybody else?
Questions.
Okay.
- Alright
- [Troy] Former special
agent Zimmerman
(audience applaud)
thank you very much!
That was outstanding.
Well done.
(synth music)