(dramatic instrumental music)
- So, for those that don't
know, I'm not Kyle Maxwell.
So if you were looking in
your handy dandy guide there,
Kyle was gonna give
an outstanding talk
on analytic biases and proper
thinking and proper analysis.
And I tried to keep something
that's along the analysis line.
Little known fact, I actually
submitted this paper,
or submitted this presentation
about 4 1/2 months
ago, during the CFP.
They said, "That's ridiculous,
the DNC hasn't been hacked.
"We're definitely not
accepting this paper."
And so, lo and behold,
Kyle ended up not
being able to make it,
due to some death in the family,
as you may have seen on Twitter.
And I went ahead
and pinch-hit it.
Again, good thing this is ready.
I had the foresight to
know this was gonna happen
and we were all ready to go.
Of course, that's obviously BS.
Who am I?
You don't care about
any of this, right?
I love coming to
conferences, though.
That's why I'm out here
and I just happen to
be out here for the...
(beeping)
Okay, well, look,
bottom line here,
the only thing we can conclude
is that the Russians
do not want you
to see this presentation,
right (audience laughs)?
If there's anything that I know,
it's the Russians don't
want you to see this.
So, okay, look.
- [Man On PA] False alarm,
no evacuation is required.
- No evacuation's required,
thank goodness, okay.
So, you can sit in your seats.
Nobody will spontaneously
combust, we are set.
Okay, so look, the agenda.
Why do we care?
What are we doing here?
Yeah, this is neat
to talk about,
but do we really have any
business implications here?
Overview of the hack.
Some of you may not have
read about this yet.
It's still fairly new.
TTPs that we know
to have been used,
talk about some of
the final metadata
from the exfiltrated documents,
'cause it's, to be
fair, it's pretty cool.
Then we're gonna
talk a little bit
about false flag opportunities.
I'm not saying this
is a false flag,
but if you wanted to conduct
a false flag operation,
meaning you wanted to
blame it on somebody else,
could you do it?
And, before we're done,
I'm gonna reveal to you
my super secret,
never-before-known,
by anybody in the room, I
think, my APT hacker handle.
So you guys will be
the first to see it.
So, again, why do we care?
Suppose your organization's
concerned with politics?
And I deal with
this a lot with my,
I deal with this a lot
with a lot of my clients,
whether they're
concerned with politics,
or foreign policy,
or you name it.
They see something in
the news and they say,
"Look, could this happen to us?
"How does this apply to us?
"How sure are we about this
particular attribution?"
Let's say we have some
business dealings in Russia
and we believe
Russia's trying to,
I don't know, influence the
outcome of the election,
they wanna know how
strong is the link.
And so, and then the whole
Guccifer 2.0 thing comes out.
If you guys haven't
heard of Guccifer 2.0,
essentially, he's, he, she,
some individual on the net
essentially is claiming
credit for, lone credit,
for hacking the DNC
and stealing documents.
And so, we'll talk a
little bit about that,
but leadership sees this
Guccifer 2.0 character
and they're worried
about these lone actors.
They're like, look, you know,
if a single actor, not
a state-sponsored actor,
but a single guy in
his mom's basement,
'cause that's what we
all picture, right?
Some 30-something
dude in underwear, in
his mom's basement,
chugging away on
Pepsi and Cheetos.
If he can do this, are
we worried as well?
Should we be worried as well?
So, again, this is where we
come in and threat intel,
and take a look at, overall,
what's been reported,
what can we confirm,
what do we look and go,
(screeches) that's a
little suspicious, right?
And then we come to
our own conclusions,
as we talk about in 5784, which
I'm proud to be a part of.
So, again, they're looking at,
Leadership's asking what can
we find out about the hack?
So, the attack timeline.
14 June, DNC hack was announced
more or less by Crowdstrike.
Guccifer 2.0 takes
credit on 15 June,
and Russia publicly denies
involvement at the same time.
They famously proclaimed,
"Maybe somebody
forgot the password."
To the DNC?
I'm not quite sure how
that works, but cool.
So, the DNC had a password,
maybe somebody forgot it.
Guccifer 2.0 releases more
documents on 18 and 21 June.
20 June, Threatgeek
posts some findings
from some of their
malware analysis.
On 20 June, Guccifer 2.0 opens
up DMs for media inquiries.
He's like, "Hey, I'm on Twitter.
"You wanna talk to me,
you got questions."
"I'm not a Russian puppet.
"You got questions, just DM me."
He's like, "I'm not
gonna answer everybody,
"I'm only gonna answer
real media contact.
"But if you got questions,
you just let me know."
This is kind of a
little bit brazen
for somebody who's
hacked the DNC and all,
but hey, rock on, right?
So, that's our timeline,
the timeline of the attack
as we know it so far.
As you read the
Crowdstrike post,
and I certainly
recommend that you do,
it's well put together,
take a look there and you'll
see that they've been hit for,
the DNC, has been
hit for some time.
And, as you know, in
these, I say some time,
meaning more than a year.
And if you do forensics,
you already know that, as
that timeline increases,
it gets harder and harder to
pin down an exact zero date,
or an exact zero patient
and time of infection,
and it gets harder and
harder to pin down.
So, I think details
will continue to
emerge here over time.
Guccifer comes out, he says,
"Look, I really, really
dislike Crowdstrike."
Says something about
sophisticated hacker groups.
When was the last time
it wasn't a sophisticated
hacker group?
Does anybody ever say,
"Hey, we were hacked
by total skiddies
"because we left the password
posted on our website.
"Totally shouldn't
have done that!"
Nope, it's always
sophisticated, right?
And so, again,
sophisticated, good to go.
Yep, he says, very pleased
they value my skills so highly.
It was easy, and
shame on Crowdstrike,
and wow, okay, he's really
mad at Crowdstrike, right?
Look, Crowdstrike kinda
comes back and says,
"Hey, we get it, all right?
"We have evidence that there's
two separate Russian groups
"in the network,
"and this Guccifer 2.0 guy
may be a Russian puppet.
"We don't know, but we
stand by our analysis,"
essentially is the gist of this.
And this really is
where executives get in,
and this isn't a
hypothetical call.
I actually have two
emails already about this
from different clients that
I work with at Rendition,
the company or small
consultancy that we own,
asking us, hey, what's
the impact on this
and how strongly do we believe
this attribution and analysis?
And so, it's not a hypothetical
that your execs might
actually care about this.
Depending on the
industry that they're in,
they definitely do.
As we begin talking
about the attribution.
First off, attribution's hard.
And I tried to make it a little
bit easier earlier this year
when I launched whohackedus.com.
Sadly, I forgot a
screenshot here.
But if you're ever having
an attribution problem,
just go out to whohackedus.com,
and you'll get a
random attribution,
complete with a random
state-sponsored group
that is clearly made up.
Despite this, however,
I've had three,
count them, three
offers to buy API keys
to this particular
service, right?
Again, I didn't use that here,
but some other attribution
considerations.
TTPs used by the attacker.
We look at the specific
malware that's used,
certainly malware
characteristics.
There's no substitute for
a good reverse engineer.
And then we look at command
and control domains,
IP addresses, and
other infrastructure,
and certainly there's
a bunch more stuff
that we can throw in here,
but I only have 30 minutes,
so we gotta pick it up here.
Talking about
validating attribution,
because in this case, I'm
not starting from scratch.
We're not the
starting attribution,
we're valuating another
analyst's attribution.
We have observable facts,
and then we have analyses.
And any time you
have the two of those
when you're trying to
validate the attribution,
you put more weight on the
things that you can observe,
the things that you can confirm,
versus the actual analysis.
And we saw this going
into the Gulf War.
There was some postmortem
done on the Gulf War,
where, goodness, Colin
Powell got up in the UN,
got in front of the UN and
said, "Definitely DWMD!"
And they went back and looked
at some of the analysis.
And in some cases,
people that were making
these analytical judgments,
were five, six, and in
one case, seven steps,
removed from actual
intelligence.
So there were people
building analytic conclusions
on nothing other than
others' analytic conclusions.
This is like playing
the telephone game
in the fourth grade, right?
So, not a good place to be.
You don't know what went into
those analytic conclusions.
And so, observable facts,
always better than
others' analyses.
Look, of course,
of course it's always
experts that build these,
but you may or may not wanna
always place blind trust.
Does everybody know this guy?
He's the Ancient Aliens
guy on History Channel.
He's an expert too,
but some of his conclusions
we might call into question.
Okay, so the diamond model.
If you're not familiar
with the diamond model,
you should absolutely be
familiar with the diamond model.
We use it all the time
in threat intelligence.
What we do here, essentially,
is break out how our
indicators are being used.
We've got the
adversary, capability,
infrastructure, and victim.
What do we know?
As far as the adversary,
Russia, maybe some other actor.
Getting into the capabilities,
we know that they do a lot
of living off of the land
but as far as malware goes
heavily using PowerShell,
We also see the SeaDaddy
implant, X-Agent and X-tunnel.
And these have previously
been identified
to be other Russian groups.
We take a look at IP addresses
and we've got a litany of them.
Number of IP addresses
that were passed over by
the CrowdStrike folks.
Definitely appreciate
that no domain name is
passed over by the way,
just IP addresses in the report.
And then we know that they
compromised an email server,
as well as an IRC
or a chat server.
Because they talk about
being able to see both email
as well as their private
messages being sent.
So maybe a link server.
We don't have that level
of detail to understand.
But this is kind of where
we sit in our diamond model.
I always find this
interesting to plot one,
because it's a great one
slider for your executives,
executives love pictures,
they love pictures.
Give them a picture, right?
And we separated
out our IOCs here
and what do we know
about the actual event?
I'm not using any
conclusions here,
just simply pulling stuff
out of the actual report,
and plotting against
the diamond model.
So what do we know?
Capabilities, we know they
used credential theft.
We know they did
living off of the land.
Again, didn't deploy
a lot of malware,
tried to use things that were
already there on the machine.
We know from infrastructure,
they had multiple IP
addresses in the malware.
Domains weren't specified
though in CrowdStrike reporting.
Victims, we know DNC
email and chat servers.
Certainly there
were other servers
and other machines
compromised during the event.
You know I picked a
couple of IP addresses
to start playing with this.
And the one that was great,
probably the best here,
we went into RecordedFuture.
And if you're not
using RecordedFuture
you're missing out.
It is an outstanding tool.
If you haven't used it
before, we teach it.
In fact, you get a free
license, free demo license,
fully functional for 30
days in the 578 course.
The RecordedFuture
immediately tells me,
"Hey, inside of the slash
24 with 255 IP addresses,
"there are 13 other IP addresses
"that have a weird
reputation score."
Meaning a high risk score.
And so, now I'm not necessarily
saying that that means
that this IP address is bad
or that confirms the CrowdStrike
reporting or any of that.
But it's kinda like,
we occasionally do SANS
in Baltimore right?
Anybody been in Baltimore?
I'm sorry, do you live
there fresh hands?
- No.
- Okay.
Then I would be
extra sorry right?
So that you've been
to Baltimore, right?
And occasionally go to one
of those places in Baltimore.
This is one of those places
I could've been to Baltimore
and people are like,
"Do I admit to that?"
And anyway, you go to
some places in Baltimore
and it's good, but there's
other areas of Baltimore
that look a lot like a show
I saw on HBO called The Wire.
And it's true to form.
So I look here, and this subnet
looks a lot like The Wire.
Because I'm not necessarily
saying that it's all bad,
but again there's a
lot going on here.
And again, one of
our IP addresses,
again immediately
pivoting over here,
this saves me a ton
of searching here.
And again, this isn't some
super advanced query I did.
I just popped it in, and bam!
I'm starting to believe here
that we've got some
other reporting.
The good thing to know
is that this
particular .134 address
didn't have any reporting on it
prior to the CrowdStrike report.
But these other IP addresses
have lots of reporting on them,
lots of reporting on them prior
to the CrowdStrike report.
That gives us some level of
who is using these IP
addresses previously
and in a number of cases
where there have been
attributions done,
several these IP
addresses have been seen
used by Russian actors.
Now does this mean that
that's a Russian
actor that's using it?
No, not necessarily right?
It turns out that
this is out in Romania
and you can go, I'm sure,
buy some virtual
server out in Romania
and use one of these
IPv4 addresses.
But it's starting to fit right?
We're looking at
alignment of TTPs.
And again, if we've
seen Russian actors
coming out of this
net block before,
might they also
continue to come out?
Does that lend some credence
to that .134 address?
And I come back to Domain
Tools, another outstanding tool.
I say, "Hey, tell me about
maybe domains that we've seen
"parked on .134, no passive
DNS either by the way."
Domain tool says, "No Bueno,
I got nothing for you."
And this is a pretty rare thing
with domain tools at this
point for reverse IP.
Most often, I've
got something pinned
to that particular IP
address at some point.
Some domains been
assigned there.
I've got nothing here,
so nothing that I can
pivot off of there.
Look, being from Romania
isn't necessarily bad,
but it's certainly not one
of my top 10 countries,
where I like good
legitimate IP traffic from,
or expect good legitimate
IP traffic from.
I kinda like do
a lot of teaching
a couple times a
year, over in India.
I know where I can eat, I
know where I can't eat, right?
So eat in the
western restaurants,
don't eat at that food
cart down the way.
Chad Tolbert tried this
a couple of years ago.
Was not a success.
Likewise here, I know
about good IP traffic
and maybe questionable
IP traffic.
Again, questionable IP traffic
(groans) I'm not profiling here,
but tends to come from
places like Romania.
We start talking
about TTP's earlier.
We started looking at Seaduke.
I pulled up some old
reporting on Seaduke,
actually pivoted off of
this from RecordedFuture,
and Seaduke was using
compromised websites
for command and control.
So the attackers
weren't registering
any of their own IPS,
they weren't registering
any of their own domains.
They were using IP addresses
that have been
previously compromised
or had compromised sites on them
for their command and control.
This is actually really
smart from their perspective,
because I can't do any
reverse who is at this point.
Renders that useless.
I'm looking for things like,
hoping to find things like,
email addresses or names, or,
you guys know about
the San Diego affair?
You may hear about
this a couple years.
It's actually more than a
couple years ago, five or six.
We had a particular
group of attackers
who was misspelling
the word San Diego.
And they were consistently
misspelling the word San Diego.
And they were misspelling it
San Digu, instead of San Diego.
And so, as new domain
registrations came in,
from San Digu,
California, right,
they were immediately
known to be bad.
And that's the kind of stuff
we're looking for here.
People are creatures of habit.
Your attackers are
creatures of habit,
as well as they're
trained for good opsec,
they're gonna screw it up.
That's just the
reality of the game.
And so, took a look
here and I said,
"Well what else is Seaduke
fencing using before?"
Primarily compromised servers.
"Okay, well, good!"
I don't have that
level of detail on the
CrowdStrike report,
but pivoting off here,
trying to understand
some more about the TTPs
of the supposed adversaries,
this certainly helps.
And pull another IP address.
Great, it's in China.
I talked a minute
ago about Romania
and that being like
bad food poisoning.
I think this is like guaranteed
salmonella here, right?
At the end of the day,
I'm not necessarily
profiling China here,
I'm totally profiling
China right?
It's almost the
blame-it-on-China
kinda complex here.
So, a great run on the
web server, outstanding!
You know I go back to
mnemonic trying to get,
so sorry virustotal first,
trying to get some passive DNS
and I even bouncing mnemonic
with a couple API keys
punched in and I got nothing.
And that makes me a sad panda.
But okay, moving forward right?
Why am I focusing on
the command and control?
Because if the attackers
are purchasing the
command and control,
there may be some kind
of thing I can follow.
Whether it's a
registration email,
where is the domain parked,
do they tend to buy servers
from a particular location?
I think we know the
answer to that by the way.
We saw that big net block
full of servers in Romania.
Looks pretty promising there.
If we see compromised, only
compromised servers being used,
if there's something in common,
we may be able to identify
a particular capability.
Perhaps all the compromised
domains are running Drupal
or WordPress.
Oh, was anybody out
here, a few years ago,
the DFIR summit when DrupalCon
was going on next door?
So, like DrupalCon was going on,
I think you were in
the elevator with me.
Were you not, when
this happened?
You know yeah, anyway.
So a couple developers
there from DrupalCon
and I see that one's wearing
like big DrupalCon badge
and I've been down on
music row, and anyway,
you guys know how
that goes right?
I'm coming back up to the hotel
and sure enough I say,
"Hey, hey you, you,
"Are you one of the
devs for Drupal?"
She's like, "I am a core
developer for Drupal."
I'm like, "Ah, that's awesome!
"I got a thank you
for what you do."
She's like, "Are you a fan?"
I'm like, "As a
matter of fact, I am."
She's like, "Do you
use our software?"
I'm like, "I do not."
She's like, "What do you mean?"
I said, "Well,
"I'm running an incident
response consultancy."
I said, "You're putting
my kid through college."
(everyone laughing)
Anyway, and then I
arrived at my door.
The little (dings), and I
was like, "You know anyway."
So it was one of those
wonderful moments
just too good to pass up.
Last, maybe they're all
running something like Drupal
or WordPress, or something
where we can kind of identify
a capability that the
the attackers might have.
This gives us some
insight into TTPs.
But if they are
all running Drupal,
it's not like I'm gonna
go scan the internet
for all Drupal
servers and assume
that those are all C2 domains.
Still, gives me some insight
into the attackers capabilities.
One of the malware artifacts.
So these may say something
about the attacker as well,
they're easy to fake.
We do it all the
time at rendition.
Black Hills does it.
They actually had a tool
that used to put
APT related strings
into their existing binaries.
Ed Skoudis has been
talking about for years
that connections to
the Stuxnet code.
They just can't be trusted,
it's too easy to
false flag this stuff.
PowerShell is just text, too
easy to copy coding styles.
But as we talk about some of
these artifacts of interest,
there's a fairly unique OpenSSL
library that's being used.
It's actually
Heartbleed-vulnerable.
In one of the X-Tunnel
samples, it's been identified.
It was also
identified being seen.
On one of the IP
addresses hard-coded in
was used in the German
parliament attack, in 2015.
FireEye reported that
that was linked to Russia.
So must be good.
What about document metadata?
Some of that doesn't
seem quite right.
Something seems just
a little bit off.
'Cause Guccifer 2.0 has
been releasing documents.
Can we take a look
at some of this,
last modified by, I'm sure
that's in the DNC, no problem.
It's total at a time at
two minutes with 231 pages
totally makes sense.
And then the company is GSA,
which I'm told is
an abbreviation for,
and I can't remember the
pronunciation of this,
but basically one of the
Russian intelligence services.
So rock on there.
What are some other
document metadata?
I love that Ernesto Che has
been involved in editing
or modifying some
of these documents.
You guys know Che right,
good old revolutionary dude.
Again, here we see the code
page being Windows Cyrillic.
Also doesn't quite
grok with a DNC there.
I don't even know
what that spells
'cause I don't read Cyrillic.
As far as false
flag opportunities,
look, PowerShell is easy.
We could be copying
that from other reports,
we could plant
malware artifacts.
We could plant
document metadata.
We could even use a social
media puppet account
with broken English kind
of like Guccifer 2.0.
We could try and
publicly discredit the
work of researchers.
Step back and think about
how difficult any
of that would be.
From where I sit, all
actually sounds pretty easy.
Actually let's talk about that.
How are false-flag
PowerShell right?
One of the things
that we identified,
or the CrowdStrike identified,
they said, "Hey look, we took
a look at this PowerShell,
"and the key, the
encryption key,
"has been seen
being used before."
And I'm not necessarily
knocking CrowdStrike's analysis.
When we have good TTP
alignment, we should map that.
But let's keep in the
front of our minds
that you too could use this key.
This key, this one
right here, this key,
and I'm not saying like
a random key, this key,
and you two then
could be attributed,
based on that same logic,
to a Russian APT group.
Just throwing that out there.
What about false
flag puppet blogs?
I thought, "Man somebody
could go register
"the WordPress blog guccifer3."
I thought about that.
Turns out somebody
already had that idea.
So I had to register guccifer4.
(audience laughs) So that's
my new secret APT hacker name,
guccifer4.
Totally wasn't Russia,
death to polio, right?
And Putin guaranteed me
that if I convinced you guys
that it wasn't Russia, that
it was totally not Russia,
he'd let me ride a shark, right?
And so guccifer4.wordpress.com.
The original site that's
leaking all the documents
is guccifer2.wordpress.com.
I figure guccifer4 is at least
twice as cool as guccifer2,
math right?
And so, how hard would it be
to create a false-flag
puppet blog?
I did it during the Hadoop
forensics presentation,
which, by the way was awesome.
When that thing is released
on video, go watch that.
So what about Alternative
Competing Hypotheses, ACH?
We don't have time to
cover the full ACH.
By the way, if you're
not doing ACH, do ACH.
If you don't know how to do
ACH, come to Forensics578,
we teach Alternative
Competing Hypotheses.
This keeps me out
of so much trouble
when I'm presenting
to the board,
board, boards, the board,
whoever, right, the management.
Because they ask, "Did you
think about...", whatever it is,
and the answer is nine
times out of ten, yes.
But only because we did ACH.
And not only did
I think about it,
but I have the good mathematical
evidence to show you.
Say mathematical,
of course, we're assigning
some qualitative pieces there.
But I can say, "No,
"that particular theory
doesn't really line up as well.
"The evidence doesn't
support it as well
"as the particular theory
that we want with."
And so I can throw out
a couple of theories.
Russia, it was Russia.
Guccifer 2.0 was a puppet.
Maybe there's another
unknown state actor.
I've got a null hypothesis
says there was never any
compromise at the DNC.
I find that highly unlikely,
but we throw it up there
as the null hypothesis.
Maybe the docs leaked by
Guccifer 2.0 are all fake.
Guccifer 2 is real,
and the Russians hacked
the DNC independently.
So the question really
is at the end of the day,
'cause I talked about the
possibility for false flags,
and I said clearly
this is easy to do.
We even talked about how you
can write your own PowerShell
Russian malware today and be
attributed by CrowdStrike too.
And I'm not knocking CrowdStrike
let me be clear on this,
but be attributed by
CrowdStrike as a Russian actor,
maybe a fancy bear, or cosy
bear, whichever bear you want.
You know the question
is, who did it?
I certainly don't know.
We don't have enough evidence
to say with any certainty.
But based on the publicly
available evidence,
I have to say probably
that guy, right?
Well good, that's all I've got.
Any questions before we break?
None?
Nobody has any questions about?
Awesome I like it.
Okay, well, hey I
appreciate your time.
Thank you very much.
(audience applause)