[Music]
[Applause]
my name is Mark
people call me pipes I work for insomnia
security over in New Zealand if you
don't know who we are look us up in
something you seek calm and this is this
is kind of a real quick whirlwind tour
on certificate transparency so we ended
up here as long as that crack on last
year and Fraser gave an excellent tour
cord controlling the dumpster fire look
into CAS it's on YouTube is really great
it effectively covered like what's the
deal with CAS and what are the
technologies that we're currently going
in on them to sort of help make them
more trustworthy and whether or not we
can bring back trust into the root of
arm stuff gets and he had one little
touch on near the end of his talk around
certificate transparency now I have
already sort of seen some stuff around
CT but I decided that it was probably
time there I mean I had a look at them
and this is kind of the result of that
as well as in depth if as I'd like just
due to some family stuff last year late
last year but hopefully you'll walk away
at the end of stay with a bit more of an
understanding about like what does
difficut transparency what does it mean
how can you use it
so stiphu katha thora t's are important
to understand before we go into it the
problem with stiphu katha thora T's are
really boring right like if you read the
Wikipedia article you'll be asleep by
about the third paragraph they say stuff
like you know electronic documents and
slamming and PKI and everything else so
I asked around the office am I good
coworker middle storm said well
certificate authorities are like toast
that's great man what do you mean you
guys know I got nothing
[Laughter]
so certificate authorities are like
toast but as a quick whirlwind for those
who aren't familiar with certificate
authorities effectively if you have a
browser which you'll see on the on the
screen is presented as a blue box
somewhere in there if you have a browser
browser visits a website it gets handed
a certificate and that's typical as
effectively the web site presenting its
identity to the browser the problem is
is that how does the browser know that
that certificate is the right
certificate that has trusted that it's
been presented in the Krait format and
the answer is you have your certificates
signed by a certificate authority right
and so effectively what it is you
effectively generate a certificate
signing request which is a base
certificate you submit it to the
certificate authority say hey bro you
please sign this for me
they say yep give us some money we'll
sign it for you they sign it for you
they hand it back you put on your web
server and then when people visit the
browser goes actually is this signed by
annoyance difficut Authority that I
trust right as effectively the base part
of it there are multiple authorities
there are over 200 if you have a look at
a modern operating system to get your
see a sign generally cost money right
that's changed a lot in the last two to
three years with let's encrypt which is
a more community driven project and one
that a social good with the idea of we
want to take the power away from these
fat cats that are taken on the money
just to have trust on the internet and
you can have different levels of trust
right so how you're sniffing it is
signed can have different levels of
trust and that's usually determined
again by how much money you're willing
to pay a very stupid Authority and
there's a bunch of additional
functionality that certificate
authorities provide such as revocation
right so if the certificates compromised
and gets I guess taken offline or
end-of-life before it's due to be end of
life then there's a cheap process and a
protocol that runs in the background
that says yo what's up but a lot of the
stuff that certificate authorities deal
with that really important for us today
the main problem we have is that in any
modern operating system there are as I
say hundreds of certificate authorities
which means any certificate that's been
issued
why are those certificate authorities
are trusted in a sense within the
operating system and ID we've been
mostly talking about within the browser
here and there's a lot they just don't
make sense at first glance why I'm not
entirely sure why my work laptop trust
hong kong post
and it turned out that that authority
exists because Hong Kong had the idea
that they were going to do their own CA
infrastructure related to identities for
their citizens right similar to Estonia
with the way that Estonia has a digital
identity for every citizen anyway so
that complex is many of them how do we
know that we trust them and everyone sit
around for pretty much the last 20 years
until a few years ago living in a
certificate utopia right late there was
the enterprise flying through the sky
the Federation existed Disneyland was
awesome and we were like you know this
is trustworthy right this is what it
goes for
the reality in this utopia is that we
had significant trust issues with
certificate parties right and this is
because of a number of reasons like
things like their across multiple
jurisdictions right what goes for trust
and understanding in China does not
necessarily relate to what goes and
trust our understanding in the United
States and neither of those go with what
goes on in Europe a lot of the time
right so our standards that we hold them
to sort of vary greatly and some of them
have really poor standards some of them
are it is the government-run certificate
authority you will trust it and there's
no auditing of actual value there's no
audibility in any of this right and this
is one of the if you talk to people who
spend a lot of time in the certificate
space this is the number one issue
that's going around at the moment which
is well an order become a certificate
authority you have to go through the
engineering workgroups you have to show
that you've done a lot of work and that
you're getting regular audits and the
standing over and if you actually go
request any of their information they go
well it's India we're a corporate entity
you're a corporate entity we're not
going to share that information with you
so getting some transparency on what's
going on it's not that easy when I
initially started looking at this I was
aware of two or three major certificate
authority incidents it turns out there
has been dozens over the last ten years
way more than I could have ever
anticipated to be honest I'm a really
good starting list on the more
significant incidents has been put into
the skip repo which is linked on the
slide and if you haven't read it I
highly recommend you go and read it
because it gives you an idea of just how
blind our trust has been over the last
sort of 20 years with this
infrastructure and given us criticality
is kind of a little bit concerning
so what are the some of the issues that
we're seeing with CAS right what's some
of the trust breaches well we're seeing
issues for stuff gets to just straight
up and on bad actors wait they know this
person is bad like well we know this
person is bad but there's no actual
checking on going on and who's
requesting the certificates literally
like a request validation so me just
creating CSR's for various other
organizations putting them through
reseller accounts with lease
verification that would probably go
through on them issuance of wildcard
certificate so if you have a CA that
issues a wildcards to forget that
certificate can present itself is
trusting for as trustworthy for any site
of their choosing so that can lead to
man-in-the-middle and is quite often
what interception appliances rely on
issuing a test certificates so one of
the examples we'll look at in a minute
is you know issue situations where
tested SH like some shell scripts
actually generating certificates that
could be valid in the wild for millions
of browsers and a compromised of the CA
itself right we like to think that
certificate authority means they are
authoritative therefore they are secure
and that is not necessarily the case so
some examples now where issuance so in
2011 comodo got put out I'm caught out
issuing suits for malware so it turned
out the Iranians had owned one of their
reseller accounts which is log and until
then it's facing being way taken over
certificate for login yahoo.com k thanks
and they're like yeah sure no worries
and it was like you know pretty much a
target list that that you kind of want
people not to be able to unset at that
time on the internet right right
did you note how everyone's probably
heard of did you note how if you
followed any major incident and breaches
in the last 10 years they had this
wonderful thing where they got caught
out issuing wild-card certificates for
google calm so start on google calm
which could be used for a whole bunch of
stuff on that it turned out their
hardware security modules so the but
that has all the cryptographic keys that
does the sliding was just sitting around
on the land it was unpatched the Windows
servers were compromised for months that
they could verify and the forensics that
they did but they assumed years because
they had suspicions that they actors
have been in there for years as a net
result of this compromise basically
DigiNotar no longer exists right they
were never going to get their trust back
CA all the browser's blacklisted and
said any certificate they came through
DigiNotar we don't want to know about a
great trust only example was actually
Symantec they got busted issuing
intermediates difficut Authority certs
to blue coat so the ideas is that when
you're an intermediate you can slide on
behalf of the CIA itself and they gave
it to blue coat which is notorious and
being caught out a number of times
selling appliances to like recursive
regimes to man-in-the-middle all
Internet traffic for entire countries so
a intermediate stuff get being issued
there would actually be quite useful for
them when they were caught on it they
were like no no no no no we were trying
to find man-in-the-middle attempts in
Saudi Arabia and we asked how they kind
of just went quiet and disappeared into
the night backdating so we were in the
middle of a shower one depreciation
force lining of certificates recently
and were signed got caught out basically
they're showing certificates with
identical serial numbers and x.509
extensions and the only exception was
the nopper for field so basically they
were issuing certificates that would be
valid with sha-1 signing for a longer
period than what would have been
acceptable under the deadlines for the
sha-1 depreciation period and the most
recent example which has been
fascinating to follow if you if you have
a chance to go dig up the the mailing
list archives that are in group stock
Google come around this one but
effectively yeah Symantec got caught I
think issuing about initially 13 or 15
certificates for Google comm and Google
away yeah it's not on we have bit more
of an audit please and they weren't sure
I actually it was 30,000 and this was
developers and test scripts and like
continuous integration systems doing
testing against production CA
infrastructure right so and the
interesting thing about this one is it's
my understanding this was actually
caught out through certificate
transparency and yeah so we we end up as
basically in a position where we know
the CAS affair cats you trust them as
much as you trust Tony Soprano right
they love to shake your hand take your
money but they'll stab you in the back
and they do all sorts of crazy stuff in
the background and they have goons
running around doing stuff so do got
pretty grumpy about this and in 2013
proposed a new RFC it was 69 62 the idea
of stuff
transparency and in a nutshell it
basically says we want a way to be able
to have a public audible log of any
certificate that's being signed and
issued out of a certificate authority
the interesting point here is actually
highlighted in bold which people are
only just sort of catching on to now and
the intent is their clients ie your
browser chrome will then be in a
position where they can opt not to trust
your certificate if it hasn't been put
out into the log right and we're
actually at this point now if you look
at certificate transparency data volume
it has exponentially growing over the
last civil sort of six to twelve months
and that's because Chrome I think in
July are actually gonna start bringing
the son with I like if you're not
logging we're not going to trust you so
the two too long didn't read of the RFC
as effectively it's it's down a process
on how we should build these effectively
immutable logs so it means they can't be
tempted tampered with that face so
they've got their own cryptographic
integrity checks in them you should have
to log to one or more instances so
multiple instances the log should be
public which as a result means the log
should be auditable which is a key point
and the rest of it kind of just gives
specifications on how log should be
stored how they should be accessed how
they should be duplicated for redundancy
as well as other stuff like if you're
lagging behind by more than 24 hours you
should drop yourself off and lock that
log and bring in a new log and stuff
like that so it's kind of just
specification around that it's really
well thought out in Russian but at the
same time you can tell but it's been
kind of rushed and there's a new
revision of the RFC there's effectively
certificate transparency to that's
currently in draft and coming out
shortly that basically addresses the
limitations with the Karen OSI and the
most of those limitations are I don't
think they expected the volume and
exponential growth that they got with
this solution there's very experimental
at the time and it turned out to be
super useful so my question to myself
after watching the talk last year and
after having a bit of bit of think about
it was if there's a public log of every
certificate that's been issued via a CA
that is logging to CT logs Kim can I go
query it
and the answer was yes and there's
several logon phases that exist that you
can use to do this right there's the
Google sort of ticket train certificate
transparency report there's Facebook
developer tools they have really good
interface and there's certain SH there
are other ones as well but they were the
ones that when I first started this in
sort of February sort of March last year
so for example with Facebook if you're a
Facebook user you can just go to the
developers dot facebook.com/ there's two
interfaces there's an API that you can
arm sort of do search queries off you
can also do subscriptions to say hey if
there's a new log entry that matches
this domain that I'm interested in to
actually send you an email or a web hook
notification or you can just punch it in
on the web interface subscribe to your
email and away you go it's all good
the problem is I like to do things at
scale like usually country scale for New
Zealand because I care about New Zealand
and I had a number of issues with these
solutions they're slow and buggy and
even the Facebook one can be kind of
weird on however it into the data and
we're dealing with big data and I don't
know exactly how much resource and
engineering they've put into these
solutions had still been treated
experimental until very recently limited
coverage so status age for example I'm
pretty sure there was instances where
they were only reading probably two or
three logs and there's 14 logs and title
approximately at the moment so coverage
was a bit of an issue right side search
limitations so sure I could look up
anything to do with insomnia comm for
example but if I wanted to find anything
with insomnia on the sort of right-hand
side it was a bit of an issue I did
learn just last week that City SH be on
the web interface you can actually just
point a post Chris client to it and do
straight up raw sequel queries on the
data set which includes the right side
search so that that wasn't I don't even
think that was really was around when
it's doing this it's still buggy global
buggy and they all have API rate
limiting they arm do not like you
throwing very very very much domain
let's set them so I decided that I hang
kiwifruit approach it we'll just
take the lot so for those of you unaware
lohank who fruit is the system that
middle storm built we operate internally
had insomnia that basically allows us to
scan dot NZ has a whole white New
Zealand internet as a whole and keep a
massive database of records on services
and ports and domains and stuff like
that
so I thought what I'll do is I'll write
some Python to download some logs
I'll pass those logs with a bit of
Python and I'll match based on a really
basic filter I want anything with
donning zit in the name and then I'll
save the certificate into a data set
that I can play with later now an or
profit right yeah so my initial job was
like I went to hit snow on line I
grabbed one of the auction servers it
was like 32 gig two terabytes of disk
eight cores I downloaded a series of
logs which took a while I used all the
process procs to filter through darlings
eard with a bunch of hacked up proof of
concept code and Python and it took
seven days to execute across basically a
log the logs themselves are Merkel hash
trees that are compressed and zip right
so the final data set that I was playing
with at the time was around nine hundred
gigs compressed sorry nine hundred gigs
uncompressed and it turns out that's
actually a whole bunch of data and if
you've ever actually tried to pass
certificates right X 5 and 9 and 8 in
one is a nightmare like if you do it at
small scale and when you go big scale
you find super weird and interesting
things and because it's an immutable log
any certificate that was mr. xu door
issued with invalid fields as in the
lock right so open SSL for example did
not handle this very well like I have
many many crashes that have open SSL so
yeah and attend out like if I wanted to
take this to more scale if I wanted to
go across all the logs late disk is
cheap ramen sheet is cheap in the cloud
but CPU ISM CPU starts getting expensive
and when you're doing zip operations CPU
is intensive part of that like it's CPU
intensive work but I ended up with this
data set I don't know how well it was
sharp on the slides there but
effectively it was a massive sort of
tree of flat files
header index sort of CSV that's said if
you've swapped this name it's in this
hash and then you can basically just
kept the certificate out until open SSL
and go through and work through and so
most of my initial analysis on all of
the data was basically sit and walk over
a file system
which wasn't too successful so I decided
to come back for round two and around
the time that I was sort of throwing my
hands and flipping the table and trying
to figure out how to make
multi-processing and fight them be more
efficient
Ryan Sears drops this platform called
suit string right and suit stream is
effectively a real-time consumable API
of all new logging trees so that's cool
when he has his clients for Python and
go but he also dropped an interesting
open source project called Axman right
an Axman is effectively a usable version
of my Python download code and so what
it will do is it'll go through it'll
download using Python 3 async i/o or
download the zip files from the logs and
actually pass them out and save them
into a more usable CSV format and stuff
like that so I was like alright I'm done
with the cloudy I can get cloudy with it
I'm gonna take all of the certificates
I'm going to shove them into Google
storage I'm going to shove them into
bigquery then I'll just query the
bigquery and profit right and the answer
is yes you can so the process worked
really well and after I went through
this and went through all the drivers
are figuring out Ryan actually posted a
blog post I think it's called how to
post his 250 million plus sets like a
boss and he took the exact same approach
and he had a data set that already
existed that he's willing to share with
anyone so I'm like but anyway so I end
up effectively with a set of CSV files
or JSON documents depending on how you
want to export them that effectively has
here's the alternative subject name so
here's all the domain names or host name
so this stuff gets associated with and
we can work through with that I wanted
to have more time to analyze the data
and I didn't so if you hit the QR code
you'll get a 10 gig TARP easy to of
Australian certificates up until last
Wednesday so if you want to have clothes
that are straight up CSV files they're
about 900 mix of CSV file and I hope
you're really good at awk
he's an interesting caveat to this as
I've been using search stream for a
bunch of the other stuff that we're
going to talk about in just a minute
it disappeared I mean when I was tidying
up some slides last week and I was
really curious as to why so I went to
his tweet Twitter's and he got $1,000
traffic bill after migrating to Google
compute and just turned it off right so
there is always a lesson here and using
a free service you get what you pay for
I really hope he starts a patreon or
saying and just it's a slight throw
money at them because everyone's using
seed stream at the moment but it came
back online just before the talk so
that's all good and if you want to go
through with it all right so what is all
this good for right I'm on the red team
for the most part so for me all I
actually wanted to know was being able
to find host names associated with
targets right having for example a
massive data set where I can say give me
anything that's associated with insomnia
and NZD from a host name point of view
it's super useful and goes a long way
it's really good for if you've ever been
on a red team you've had say you've
fished some credentials you've got some
credentials that's great you've got RDS
in point or remote access in point and
you know what it is and it's expecting
the format domain name backslash user
name right if you don't know what the
domain name is and that hasn't leaked it
can be a really frustrating place to be
thankfully we've already had a couple of
instances where they've issued
certificates for say insomnia dr. Danes
eared insomnia DeLand and insomnia LAN
within the alternative subject name so
those so sharing the certificates with
both the internal and external DNS
horizons reviewing data for a geographic
region by you right like it'd be really
interested in see what are the shower
algorithms and Uslan sliding and pulling
out some stats around on by that sort of
stuff
understanding extensions and use within
certificates so one of the things I've
already found looking through the data
is especially when it comes to looking
at wireless networks and how
certificates being issued across
wireless networks and stuff is there are
dozens of x.509 extensions I didn't know
existed let alone I knew they were in
use and they're in use by appliances and
various other useful things so there's
already one appliance for example that I
know an x.509 extension then if you
query across the data set you'll find
their endpoints for their customers
everywhere so that's pretty useful and I
also think it will actually eventually
make a pretty decent assistant and you
know
writing a corpus for fuzzing right
anyone who's ever fuzz SSL knows like
the hardest thing is actually figuring
out a code branch that hasn't been fuzz
5,000 times before and we saw that with
heartbleed right like we saw that where
and they came out with heartbleed it was
just sitting a strange code part that no
one else it had before it was super
obvious but nonage lee taken that time
to sort of fuzzy and go through so for
the blue team visibility Facebook have a
really great post where they point out
that this security team got alerts that
someone was on the FBI calm domain which
is their corporate domain issuing valid
certificate for something in there and
they were sitting there going but but
not through our CA and our process in
our security team doesn't know anything
about it and by they got a heads-up on
that through CT logs it's really good
for determining of phishing sites or
incoming for targets any decent Fisher's
nowadays generally spinning up the mains
that sort of match with the keywords
they all had stuff gets so there's a
bunch of hosting providers and cPanel
solutions now that will automatically
issue a let's encrypt stiphu k't for
every domain that's been added to the
shared hosting box or whatever or via
the cPanel but also understanding how
certificates being used within malware
I'm pretty sure that there's a couple of
blue teams out there getting I guess
bitter bitter understanding of now
malware slamming and stuff off domains
that's coming through that as well so so
because I'm in a big sort of thing at
the moment where people keep saying look
the routine keeps running you guys keep
kicking everyone's ass I decided that
for any research that I do other than
sort of next couple of years I'm going
to produce the blue team solution with
it so I took the time to build a blue
team example that effectively says you
know alright let's tap into the seed
stream let's monitor it and they'd see
if there's any domain that sort of
matches out with the keyword that I'm
interested in can we do some recon
generate an alert go through it it kind
of looks like this almost slack bot for
PayPal for example but I've been looking
at PayPal Apple ID stuff like that this
was I don't know a couple of hundred
lines of Python for the initial proof of
concept
probably the current version which does
a few more smarts is probably somewhere
around four or five hundred lines
right there's nothing major to it so you
can get a heads up on what's going on
out there
pretty pretty easy bonus you can steal
the fishing kits because you had them so
fast they haven't deployed yet so one of
the things that I found is that they
would set up the slide through
compromise see panels that would upload
the zip file and before they unpacked it
and set up the index dot PHP to redirect
and everything else there be a zip file
there and I'll seen this in the
screenshots for everything else taken
and by the time I'd go back and revisit
it there's a fire would have been
deleted although it's configured the
site correctly so I just automated that
with a little bit of Python and you can
still a lot of fun fishing kits out of
that fun fact for most of them pretty
much 90% of the backdoored and it's a
great great game to go through figuring
out how did the fish get authored
backdoor them to send the credentials as
well so getting started so as I
mentioned way I did the blue team
example it was really straightforward if
you have a look at bounty monitor which
is around bug bounties sort of
monitoring it's a really great basic
example it's basically taps into says
stream sets up a sequel wipe database
goes ahead and figures out have I seen
the certificate before you saw R no have
I seen it recently do I need to recheck
it should I look at the slide or not
should I log it this is just dozens of
projects if you go looking for seed
stream on github code search so to
conclude so that we can get out of here
and go to the pub before Glen and their
kill me yes so CAS can't be trusted we
know this we've got dozens of incidents
they show they can't be trusted and
certificate transparency really has open
that up to be publicly audible it is
freely accessible like if you've got
enough time and a little bit of patience
and some Python you can go download them
all you need a bit of disk in a bit of
bandwidth why the day.you data set that
I put on the slide earlier that was
generated from one point five seven
terabytes of data something like 800
million rows and it took a hundred and
seventy seconds on Google bigquery so
that's all good and it's also possible
to incrementally monitor the log with
free and open source tools right like I
think suit stream needs to either
formalize as a project a little bit or
you know maybe a bit more of a
if it around how we can tap into
streamable api's to do with the set logs
be greater Facebook open that up a
little bit more on this lotta something
I don't know but there just has to be
something a little bit more redundancy
and reliability there then then just
Ryan as much as I really appreciate Ryan
Zephyr it's pretty awesome and there's a
bunch of awesome started projects to
explore and there's a bunch of ideas to
explore right like the more you go
looking at certificates the mortal make
your head hurt like frankly because
there's mentioned there are just dozens
of extensions and people use Tiffa ckets
for things that I'd never actually
considered so that's well worth checking
out there as well and that's it worth 13
seconds to spare
[Applause]
[Music]