hello sexy area are you ready so I do
want to start my talk just as they do at
DEFCON with a disclaimer but not for
some business but because i might not
see the whole picture i'll talk about a
problem that I see as new in the game
with fresh eyes
therefore if there is a solution to this
matter then please come talk to me later
so who am i and what am I doing here
well my name is lava or outer as I'm
called in the student work as you might
have noticed i'm at my last year's
studies of Milan's have school on are
slowly becoming an engineer in computer
networks and I'm here because I heard
something about a spring pub when
listening two seconds for kaustubh well
at the spring pub I met mother has
bought who said if you have a child who
is student or if you know someone who's
charlie is a student then please tell
them that we would love someone to come
talk at our community night at sector in
September I late reply to that with hey
I don't have children but I just might
have a solution and for the opportunity
that gave me i'm very thankful before we
start I would like to mention that i'm
looking for somewhere to do my thesis
this spring
so if you have a company and a code
project or if you have a company or if
he know someone who has a company then
hit me up afterwards so my talk is about
best practice and the inconsistency of
doing it the right way to understand
what i mean i'll show you an example so
let's say we have and imaginary business
someone starts a business and as all
other businesses this business needs
email but it also needs a web server we
are hired to get this to work and as all
job details there's a sentence and find
writing at the bottom saying do all of
the above following best practices
this so we'll need to understand what
that is
wikipedia SS a best practice is a method
or technique that has been generally
accepted as superior to any alternatives
because it produces results that are
superior to those achieved by other
means or because it has become standard
way of doing things
IG the standard way of complying with
legal or ethical requirements so how
hard can this be
well let's look at this network will
need a DM said since we're going to have
a web server and since we have a team
said we might as well place our emails
there since an attacker might get access
to it somehow
now with this in itself isn't a problem
to the long axis is only given if the
connection is established permanent site
this is when a client contacts to grab
person new emails so far so good now
let's say that there will be enough
people are enough employees working
there that the company wants our old
favorite active directory to maintain
these passwords and usernames this
server is of course not placed in the DM
said but in the local area network but
now there is a problem when a user
connects to the evening server his
credentials needs to be confirmed and
for that to happen a curry needs to be
sent from the main server to Active
Directory server
however this connection is not
established from the inside but from the
DM said and therefore the packet gets
dropped for this problem there are
solutions the best way I found was to
rank special firewall rules that is
exactly what is and what is not to be
sent this can get complicated but for
now it's fine but now we have a bigger
problem our contracts us to follow best
practice and this practice for Team
census that no connections are to be
established from within the DM said so
what else could we do
well we could move the email servers
from the DM said but that is again
against the best practice of DM said so
we could move the active directory to
its own and have like a semi p.m. said
but that would kind of defeat its own
purpose we could of course move the
active directory to the DM said if we
never ever want to work with security
again the reasonable thing would of
course be to speak to the company and
percent the problem and whatever
solution seems best but we never really
got around the real problem you see best
practices something that gets thrown in
you know with the right way but doesn't
help much
it should be the way it's generally
accepted as stated and it should also be
superior to any other alternatives but
today it's more like no one cares
because no one uses it anyway because
all of the standards of best practice
and network collide
so what would only like to be done about
this well you know how programmers have
a community with a sure code and tips
and tricks and ask questions
stack exchange is a great place for
solutions if code where the objective
however this does not apply to have
relatives and switches and servers and
firewalls are configured them connected
some companies would argue that they
don't want to share this information
because they think that security lines
and no one knowing how your network is
built to be honest
one mistake and then map will screw you
over so bad
so let's let security line good
algorithms being up-to-date not using
char one or god forbid md5 the objective
is of course not to give out all your
configuration and network scheme but
rather have a discussion of why you
chose one configuration over another and
why you built something one way and not
the other
it's in some way to take back best
practice to something that will actually
be helpful to have somewhere to talk
about problems that you run into and
i'll give you another example of this
this is part of a network that we built
just before summer see how it got quite
complicated
well the company wanted extremely low
down time so we basically put into of
everything but let's focus on this
strange part of the network which is
actually RDM said this consists of two
edge router is connected to two late two
switches going to do servers and this is
set up this way because we wanted to use
a protocol called vrp app road called
for two devices to share one IP address
if one of them would figure the other
one would take over the problem with
this is that this protocol only runs
through later too
therefore the network looks like this of
course we could have used another
standard like GBP which runs through
later three but then the two servers
have to be at the same subnet and since
we want them connected to different
routers that wasn't an option
this in itself might not breach best
practice even though i highly doubt it
doesn't in some way but this is an
example of a problem that could be
helped because i know that this can't be
the best solution network engineers
system admins and other network
maintenance people plus security IT
security experts should have its own
forum where we can help not only the new
guys but also each others because from
what I've learned the last few years is
that you will never ever have the best
solution
no matter how smart you are there will
always be someone's market figured
something out in the beginning of
computer networks back at ARPANET we all
helped each other's from what I've
understood no one held secrets but was
very open with new ideas and therefore
my questions must be why did we on the
pier
what are we willing to do to get those
good old times back
what are we willing to do to get the
platform where we can speak to each
other no matter what level you're at or
what company you work for
thank you