if i'm going to welcome Felix at the
moment you walk in stone by some cattle
in thank you thank you thank you know
hi welcome nice to have you all here
hopefully we can get drunk afterwards so
we're going to talk and we're going to
tell you a little about the story
regarding an audit we did actually quite
some time ago but it has a lot of
lessons that you can learn from it
ok next slide please
yeah this is me yeah York it's always on
I work as embedded security consultant
in Gothenburg and I do a lot of crypto
stuff for embedded devices and that's
about it
next slide please my name is Frederick
so all my work for XD we are a small
heightened security company operating
out of Sweden doing mainly work in the
European Community and and in the US
yep exploit we had is interesting
customer they had deployed a very large
new system which was literally thousands
of sites that was actually organized in
a star topology it was a fairly new
installation it was you graphically
dispersed and what they wanted was they
wanted a security review of the system
so they contacted Ross and and we
started to work on it and the scope was
basically doing an IT audit trying to
identify any weakness as we could find
within the different communication links
the three primary communication links
that we're looking at was data which is
basically we were expecting to see all
of the problems
the alarm systems and the video link and
each site and we're talking several
hundreds of sites had these three
different communication links calling
out to them
next slide please
data traffic obviously flows and and
this customer has that at a very typical
are not typical but rather old setup so
it's truly a star topology you have
traffic that's meant to flow from a
central site out to the branches and
it's not supposed to be branch to branch
communication everything is meant to go
to the central site its sensitive
traffic it's from many different
perspectives clearly not a good thing if
you can enter altered data or eavesdrop
on the data the alarm system the second
communication link is well yeah it's
used for the alarm system it's basically
an alarm system that sits on every of
these multiple hundreds of sites alarm
system has a lot of features one of the
features are obviously that can give an
alarm to the Central security central if
someone tries to break in but it can
also open doors and etc and others
another funny stuff that actually makes
it kind of scary if if we find any type
of all things within the system and as
icing on the cake the alarm system
actually had a GPRS based backup which
made this even more interesting but to
be honest we didn't expect to see
anything out of the ordinary from the
alarm system we were expecting to see
troubles on the data communication link
this is where also the customer had
focused us to believe that there could
be some problems on the data site
and lastly we also had a video
communication channel of the RF that was
meant to stream video ip-based video
from each branch into the central sites
yeah that'll work yeah okay so i missed
introduction i'm peter from XP as well
just gave you to give you a lay of the
land so they're from a network
perspective this is just a sample sites
is going to be hundreds or even
thousands of these installations all
over and typically they buy from
provider dividing it into three
different GRFs based on mpls which is
kinda normal setup I mean you buy a
private virtual network from a provider
now like Frederick said this is like a
hour you call it the hope and hub and
spoke kind of thing but lessons learned
from this is that when you buy the vr
af-s vr s and mpls networks you really
need to actually I mean you delegate the
security of your protocols and so on to
your provider now I worked at a provider
and I know for a fact that for instance
in order to accomplish sls and stuff
like that you actually tap DVR efforts
at one point to measure inside of the FC
for instance so what you need to do is
actually protect the transport or
otherwise you have to delegate the
security down to the protocols that are
actually communicating in this setup
it's a full mesh so everyone can talk to
everyone and the security or the virtual
network private network is mpls which is
basically kind of the same thing like
you would expect from a regular VLAN
it's just a label tag what
however it's still going to be clear
text so the conclusion from the overview
is basically once you're in your room
and that's it so yeah the next
so there you have a rough overview of
how complicated this is
and based from the fact that this is yes
the mpls it's going to be a flat network
alright so like I said the network is
operated by third party it's not the
actual customer is not their main site
it's actually like it what you would
expect like one of the big operators in
town and this is lesson I think a lot of
companies that really doesn't know this
technology that's often referred as like
an IP VPN so it's secured two began
encrypted but yeah it's labeled yeah you
can go to the next one and the
difference between every meal and the
MPLS label switching is basically that
you are have your own routing tables and
one thing to take away from this as well
i mean if you buy this from a big
operator in Sweden like Kelly RTC or tea
party or whatever it's going to be the
same infrastructure that runs the
internet or whatever so potentially so I
reached there and you're you're done
so you have to do something else on top
of this and also the provider is going
to be at every site so you have
excellent spot for men and mill and yet
again delegating this purity down to the
protocol level which is going to be the
more and more interesting part of this
discussion I think ya can
so
so like I previously said more or less
they have three bf's not directly
connected to each other so basically
what you do with a BF in that labeling
in that VLAN it's not a villain but I'm
just trying to use that as like it's
something you probably more familiar
with but in in that segment or that
network you have your own routing table
for instance so this is three separate
networks that doesn't really connect to
each other but they're still transfer
all the same equipment so they have one
for the video and one for the critical
data transport of their main application
and the alarms of course and and the
video to suit have this available of
this high-security areas so yeah and
this is kind of the essence of what I've
said all along
keep this in mind when we go further on
onto the protocol analysis and stuff
like that and and this was also a big
surprise for the customer because they
they weren't aware of this
yeah it and that's true as well because
the customer just bought a big network
we want to have a thousand sites or 500
whatever the number is and they have no
technical perspective today they assume
of course that they going to get what
they want what they want but they don't
expect the side benefits of having the
the fully mesh each site is connected to
each other instead of they actually
required communication pattern which is
from the sides to a central hub in the
in terms of the data is the center site
for their main system for alarms it's to
the alarm central and for video probably
alarm central as well right but this is
mean
so you can you can see where this is
going if you have a breach
I one side and I mean if you have a
thousand side's chances are some of them
going to have issues right so everyone
is directly connected to each other's
right and like I said it's more or less
industry-standard i would say or not
understand about best practice to
actually do like an ipsec tunnel or
something over the transport network in
this case it's not done so it's just up
up to the actual providers and the
encryption here
I mean the providers is not gonna you're
gonna have a lot of issues because if
the provider when you're debating this
with your provider because as long as
you start doing in the tunnels and stuff
like that you're gonna not be able to
Duke us you're not going to see the
actual traffic flowing is going to see I
to take tunnels and stuff like that so
what you're going to prioritize here and
also this was also a typical salesman
type of problem because the customer
thought they bought an IP VPN that's a
virtual private network while big
surprise for them there's not there's no
privacy in this network it's just an
MPLS cloud general ipsec tunnel is
deployed whatsoever and also I when you
deploy this who's going to be
responsible for your actual their
encryption keys and and the endpoints
doing the encryption I mean if you do
that at the CP which the provider
provides them well what's the point of
course it's going to be an additional
cost to place yet another CP after the
actual CP right so it probably comes
down to what kind of agreement you have
and also some sort of risk analysis and
stuff like that in this case though they
didn't have a clue
and while presented by this they were
kinda shocked i would say yeah
absolutely so the customer was under the
impression that were actually having to
encryption from the central site RG of
every function just by examining the the
basic apology and the configuration we
could tell them well everything is going
in clear text here and you could
provider can read an altar and data
basically transmitted on all the tree
communication links so we have the usual
suspects when we did this when we
started this sordid and as a wise man
once told me you should never assume
anything because that will make an ass
out of you and me and basically we found
some issues with the data link they were
not as grave or serious as the things we
found on the alarm system examining the
traffic some of it was clear text some
of it was encrypted we found self-signed
cas that's obviously not quite good
might be okay to pentagon on the
policies we found see as CAS using keys
that were way too short
we found clients trying to negotiate as
a Cell version 3 the server insisted
insisted on TLS version 1 which was kind
of good
these issues being in the port of being
in the report was actually mitigated so
proper cas now until last version one .
two is probably worth mentioning also
that this is not really like any normal
system it's a critical infrastructure
with this cannot be down at any time or
less so yeah yeah it's kind of tough top
cranium
so the video link well how hard is it to
do video one would expect that's also
one of those things you shouldn't do
well the video is is transported over
HTTP why on God's DNA
why didn't they use https no one else so
basically we could capture all the video
and images going back and forth between
the IP cameras and the central station
yep that this is where we got it get it
actually to start to get interesting and
they were this close to get away with it
and so we said okay
the alarm system so we shot off a couple
of questions to the security provider
and we awesome stuff like well the alarm
system obviously it's ok isn't it yeah
they said yeah well it's it's encrypted
you don't have to worry about it for
your audit you can market as with a big
check mark its fine everything is
encrypted
ok are using encryption what kind of
encryption are using our using heck what
is it called
I think we're using AES 256 actually so
you don't need to bother
okay so is that ok that sounds
interesting and and we were basically
almost ready to okay the alarm system
seems fine but is that ok
they seemed a little bit not to
knowingly about the object about the
subject so let's just shoot a couple of
more questions just to get some more
information to make sure that we're not
out on deepwater here so we bombard them
with some questions which is kind of
very normal question when it comes to
cryptography okay sounds great you're
using AES 256 that sounds just great but
one modes are using are using all FPC
fbgm TX whatever and most importantly
how are you storing the keys for the
encryption and what sorts of entropy are
using when you're doing the encryption
and we got all kind of all the answers
back and forth we got we got answers
back like well what modes with just told
you were using AES and so we ok so we oh
I think we found something here we said
okay and by basically pushing their arm
we finally managed them to send out over
all the year or not all but some
internal documentation describing the
protocol between the actual alarm system
which is the box that sits on a branch
and talks to the alarm central and you
have to notice so it's not yes the alarm
is the key to the door
this is religiously yeah you can turn
off the alarm and turn on the alarm but
you can also open the doors to to the
branch external yeah and this is
basically what we're talking about in
this case it's typical embedded systems
where you have microcontrollers sitting
on a min a PCB that you put into some
put into a cabinet somewhere it leaves a
very lonely life for 25-30 years doing
important stuff and I said in this case
it actually it detects when somebody
breaks a window or open something and it
can also receive comments say that you
open this door or whatnot and and these
kind of things you find everywhere and
they're doing a lot of important
security and this is a system that is
made for highly sensitive sites
basically and we don't we know that it's
doing aes-256 really really good stuff
and as freaking and Peter said we
finally got some design documents and
and I was brought into this project and
i started reading documents and and
looking at this board and and discovered
something interesting things and and
normally talking about a couple things
in this case to have to have
authentication that they want to ensure
that the when a one is machines sense of
the command to sit to Center
it actually comes from the right place
you can't change a message you can
substitute the message and then also you
can optionally add confidentiality to it
you can actually read the contents of
the message so they looked really good
in that case but then when I start
reading the documentation and and
looking at the rapture doing I'm
starting to realize that well this is
not really working is it
I started finally using a random number
generator for keys and four challenges
there is not based on the random number
generator that is actually safe and I
realize that they are not using cipher
modes block cipher modes that are
actually working to invent their own
they're there are there is a whole
family of of great really working and
some quite a few bad cipher modes block
ciphers but hey we can make our own and
then they use all kind of short fields
and numbered stuff that you can actually
brute force stuff a-and and it turns out
that actually are are doing stuff that
cancels out you can actually in this
case you can actually buy license to get
confidentiality but if you enable
license than the authentication doesn't
work so you get worse performance and
that's kinda bad and then it's a whole
kind of this and a typical you see this
a lot of magic constants and trying to
obfuscate code we're very late
aight aks for example a great cipher and
then I try to be
I don't know anything about encryption
but I'm think I'm smart
cited do stuff with it to beat make a
little better so security security
that's actually decreases the security
now okay and we look at first one is the
and i was asked what where is your
source for entropy where the witness you
where is the runner numbers and keys
come from interest that they have
actually selected what's called a linear
congruential generator it's a very nice
Randall generator can generate very nice
uniform random numbers it's very common
for non cryptographic epic
options the problem is that if i can
look at a couple of of numbers for it
that means i can actually in identify
the state of there is a surrounding
areas I if I can figure out the start
value then I can figure out all the
other values before it and after and
coming after it and so you're not
supposed to use this as something for
security and it's been known from the
seafood seventies and this thing was
designing in nineties so they shouldn't
but anyway and they're seeing a random
generator has 16 bits state you cannot
have 2 216 values of ribbon of values
and at best but they're not using one
that it's much worse and we're actually
still selling this piece-of-junk of
hardware
yeah in 2014 yeah so just do it just do
it if you could make someone this next
one
yeah this is typically if you take some
data from a right good run and prolly
this is what you look like something
like that and if you take it out there
once if you did you put in the liner
that's what you get if you can see it
actually predicted works pretty well you
can see that there's these lines going
like that of using that that means that
actually this pattern repeating over and
over again so they have much much less
than 2 216 values in their data and this
is the basis for the key speciality this
is scary stuff
yeah so I just took it there there's a
program called I harder which you can
use to test run generators and this is
the result of took the one that they're
using this application and is it mostly
fail it's a good with this
this one is at least just week is pretty
good i right but it actually failed
every test except for the one that's
weak
yeah i think is so it said it's not
totally worth it melanoma ok you know
and and then I said they're using AES
256-bit turns out that actually using a
tooth is AAS 128 well who is to have 128
bits among friends to their
yeah a few bits here and there and and
if you know what a is a block cipher is
a pure function if i take a key and a
block of data 16 bytes of data and put
in there i get an encrypted with block
out of it i'm going to get the same
block out every time and that has
consequences
this is a good example from wikipedia
everybody seeing this month at the
penguin and basically if you look at the
upper left corner you got white
background there and you get this stripe
patterns and this is why we have cipher
modes feedback most like for example CBC
you actually basic take the the the
incoming message block and you take the
previous message box and you combine
them with an ex or for example in this
case because you have to do that and
then you get a state in there so
actually if you send in the same block
many many times it will be encrypted not
only next week not only with itself but
the the state of previous of blocks and
and but hey there's this a lot of modes
but these guys decided let's invent our
own one not feedback but if feed-forward
instead it's nobody's done this before
this is this is really interesting
this is a unique they should have paid
inside and probably sew-in they say that
they're actually four instead of this
actually they forward the clear text to
modify the the ciphertext instead so if
you take know her now so it's so you see
this on and and this one that really
scared me because the point is that that
it's okay if you take a sensitive
message and you put it through a cipher
then when you have something that is you
can get that you this secure and then
you can bring it back and you can do
stuff but in this case you have actually
have clear tech stuff going passing by
the cipher like this which is scaring
itself so you're going was so pissed
when I actually call us at this can't be
real late they must be doing this on
purpose yeah you're came forth we were
unfounded cameras that this is so bad it
can't be true
so and everything is that if you
actually think about this if it takes
like it's not doing that in analysis
actually don't have any state if you
send in multiple blocks the same one
that actually won't be able to actually
modify things so but the cool thing is
that all this doesn't matter at all if
you go back to the previous slide
because the mix function there is
actually so bad and it depends on a
magic number from that random generator
we talked about so the whole s thingy
doesn't even keep matter how they react
because they invented their own mixing
function instead of using X or which is
very strange and hard and complicated
they invented their own which sort of my
together the whole s thing so yeah and
then they have the message
authentication which and domestication
for embedded system is really really
important i usually say that if you are
designing embedded system
confidentiality is probably not your
most important concern authentication is
that you actually know that for example
if you have a power meter that the
amount of power do you consume is
actually correct and comes from the
right meter and we have a whole bunch of
really good algorithms h Mac cbc-mac
gmac all doesn't pull it 30 30 30 45 for
example really nice anything is that the
Mac the Mac targets is a number as a
signature for for the data there it has
to be big enough so that you can
actually brute force it and typically 64
96 128 for example express so basically
this is what we what you see that you
have your message and then you have a
key security that both the sender
receiver knows and you process something
like hmx sort of takes to get you get a
mac a tag that you add to your message
and send it over to the receiver and
trust that they're using 32-bit Mac I
can from the bruce that pretty fast
yeah and and it's based on
one of those feedback for things so it
turns out that actually can reduce to a
single constant that is like eight bits
so EAS is totally irrelevant in this
case so so there you are seeing as2
physics LASP not funded not latex the
key is generated from a 224 bit master
code so so the key is introduced my cat
most 24 base and and that is seeded into
that . we talked about but I was only
sixteen me too . the 16-bit and then you
can you can actually get access stores
old master codes so you can actually
force an old master code so you actually
can't do rekey know it
this is so broken but hey it's sold to a
sensitive applications many yeah so this
is yeah this was basically this is taken
from from the the report to the
customary oh we're basically saying that
we do not recommend relying on the
security of the features in this system
should be viewed as an unprotected
system if the system is to be used
separate communication security
mechanism should be used to be added so
basically the customer absolutely need
to have something like an ipsec tunnel
going from the alarm system to the
Lauren central and the really casual it
is basically it is not ready for
production use this is basically the
worst crap we ever seen is yeah but
expensive and and think about this
sentence for a while these guys
manufacture alarm system that spread
globally all over the world
it's probably where others are probably
one of those controllers sitting here
protecting this
yeah you can actually walk around in the
stores or whatever and you can actually
see these boxes read them all over all
over
we were crying after a long long
difficult with that with PACOM the
manufacturer from Australia we finally
got a minute to admit well and then
finally they said okay seriously guys we
we surrender your correct it is utterly
crap
however we will not issue in patch we
won't fix this so we will tell the
customers to start using our new base
station and they will have to download
the new firmware that can make it
possible to use the new base station and
they will have to pay for it so
affectionate and so that's that's really
good as a good player so I i assume we
wrote the first report that the these
are the findings and there was a suspect
this epic some sort of discussion with
unless it yet everything is true
yeah that's basically what they're
telling the customers yeah instead of
using windows 7 you could upgrade to
Windows 10 but we are setting yourself
window seven
yeah but you can also a graph the
magnitude of this I mean this was one
client and they have the several
hundreds if not thousands of sites and
imagine all the other big companies or
all the other organizations and each one
of these when you're going to flash the
firmware you need to have someone how to
decide someone from a security company
basically to to provide for the security
so it's kind of a very expensive process
to reflash the farmer yeah so a little
lessons learned I i think is that don't
use several nominated dinner is not
designed for for security there are some
really really good ones that you can use
an example based on only yes and and
they shouldn't have been known bad for
more than 10 years yeah is that it's you
can actually you can you can grab for
example Bruce is all the classic red
book and apply crypto and you can
actually turn up and and look at linear
kana don't use this for for crypto stuff
and that was published 20 years before
the design system so and and don't
invent your own ciphers and cipher
mouths there's so many good
once the shoes from so why spend the
time for it
yeah yeah my favorite in this was
basically they were neutering AAS 128
down to 24 bits so it was a s24 that's
three characters and you think that's
hard to brute-force yeah yeah and if you
think that feedback is backwards and and
old school and you want to go forward
instead don't do that either dockside
relax it doesn't work and and a set of
brute forcing a short maxfields 32-bit
is not the way to go suite 320 ya next
year this is actually a picture i took
it when i was skiing down in Italy so
it's my picture it's this is an Italian
we're thinking of a secure lock and it
reminded me so much of this alarm system
so i just had to take the picture
ok questions and the best question gets
this very very nice book by the way
about honor burling Swedish cryptic
giant so come on asking questions
the question was if we look at the next
version i guess you're assuming the
updated firmware yeah we were actually
graciously allowed to examine the
protocol of the the updated former that
goes to the there
Paycom is solution which is this fixed
solution we found some problems they're
not a major and not any showstoppers
they had some issues I think they fixed
couple of them they still have a few on
the backlog but there's nothing that's
basically says there's no shot
showstoppers around but what it is like
cannot just what we basically the
internal crypto that they sort of their
throughout all of the homegrown invented
stuff and it just basically follow
standard stuff which makes it easier
just also to see
you to sell to customers to explain you
can actually look at this stuff and it's
easy to implement so that's a good
lesson that don't do this it there's so
many good stuff to use and that's what
it was really good
yeah yeah absolutely that's a really
good lessons to learn don't you don't
invent your own Krypton our hash
functions yeah but also a one lesson is
also to be curious i mean if we didn't
have asked all the questions we could
have a accepted the answer of the AAS
256 right and good move on
how many times do you do that probably
quite often because you don't have the
time or the resources to actually go
down and down in this kind of stuff so
be curious
yeah and that's a good point Peter to
make because you know what it's like
this you have like hundreds and hundreds
of questions that you ask your customer
and this is just one of them so it was
this close actually that we miss this
one so oh well you'll just have to stick
there and go for your gut feeling
we have a question
ok how the question is how difficult was
it for us to explain to the customer
that an IP VPN isn't really private
yeah it was a bit challenging but but it
finally worked any other questions
we're like but it's a good question
because i'd say $OPERAND ninety-nine
percent of the customer that we meet
when we're doing audits they saying we
have mpls we have an ID pen we are
secure
yep i freaking hate the guy that makes
it I pvp am just call it mpls or
whatever
sorry questions get here let's test
yeah yeah how you ever seen or heard of
anyone doing this feed for the thing it
seems like an original invention or hood
to me to me I've never seen before or
after have any doing this ingenious
thing no it was unique as I said your
camo see he was furious when i call them
after the initial discovery and he was
really mad when someone is actually
trying purposely trying to do this make
this bad
yeah so all the question what did they
get the patent I'm sure they did have
you looked at other allow vendors the
big ones at least you have seen some
sister other systems
yeah yeah well this is unique and in
this case
listen for we need for in india in the
forward since it's kind of scary because
as if you read on pay concert on paper
homepage it's basically says that we
spread these systems all over the world
there are thousands and thousands of
installations and I guess at least now
we're not the only one knowing about
these stuff and it's kind of convenient
to you if you want to shut down the
alarm system or open the door if you
want to do a burglary somewhere so yeah
and like we said it's not like a small
companies spread all over the world and
you can find installations everywhere
else we don't know if you just go around
go around looking not necessarily this
board but probably some of them but yeah
and there's a cv out
yeah yeah yeah there is a CV and we
should and the
we actually this was 2014 but due to
responsible disclosure and stuff like
that we had to sit on it for like almost
two years younger have here is something
like that but finally it's out here and
this is the first time we're telling
anyone about this except we've done it
before on NBA to legal authorities in
Europe and obviously to customers on the
partners
any other questions okay no okay
the this units a are the Wi-Fi connected
with this protocol enabled now they are
connected through either GPRS as a
backup link or the actual their internet
or less we should probably mention the
the the board is so on the picture we
bought out of ebay for how much was it
we've got it from Israel for 600 swedish
crowns
yeah so by one go nuts
yeah and then everybody else at like
Peter said they are connected through
normal infinite so the ethernet cable
from the alarm system alarm internet
cables from the video links from the
data goes in and then get split up in
the difference you're so in that same
sense the same ghost I mean if the
ethernet would be down and you can argue
okay about what about GPRS and stuff
like that and the same issues going to
be there with the you're a PM or
whatever it's not going to be that
private either probably and also to stop
the course they know i think he showed
at CC two years ago so GPRS might even
be a worse solution that actually going
on with if the protocol actually being
totally broken and other questions
ipsec to achieve confidentiality I guess
from the carrier understand but did you
suggest anything to kind of segments the
different sites from each other well and
that was actually yeah the question is
did we talk about the customer using
IPSec from the site site to site or from
any point one point and then also
segment decides off from each other
yeah that's what yeah yeah i think that
the question is twofold there of course
you should
when you have a growing for protocol
like this ok they didn't know but still
when you're using a carrier like the
mpls stuff even though you don't know
what the protocol or it should probably
use IPSec to protect your data because
one of these days some guys going to
implement something new that you don't
know when that way you have a secure
channel but are also recommendation here
would also be too like segment and look
at traffic patterns in this case it's
very simple because it's a store
configuration everyone talks in it's
never any any ever need for to talk from
one side to another side so that would
be extremely easy to implement in the
firewall or yesterday she routing or
whatever so it's a kind of two things in
one and yeah both of them both of more
recommendations to do to decline
customer that now that was that was this
is a good question because it basically
what it ended up was doing being a soft
recommendation of the customer that you
need to look over your procurement
process because the reason they didn't
have any isolation between the sides
which our customers thought they had is
because the procurement was bad that
didn't give the right demands when they
purchased the impellers cloud they
probably didn't know so that providers
said well there's no demands for
separate separating the sites so why
should we spend money on doing it
because the customer didn't have any
demands from it so that was a feedback
to the customer that you need to be
better in on procurement you need to
better
22 to have your demands better your what
you need actually from both our business
perspective but also from a security
perspective was an answer to your
questions
yeah but i think that this bro broken
protocol is a perfect example to as to
why that the SEC would be needed because
you assume and you don't know and when
you start poking at it
well so any more questions
say again please sorry so the question
is was it the consultant helping this
company out or was it someone in-house
that they remember this
you mean from a account hoodie the
they're forwarding dependent at judging
from the documentation and the
communication we had with the finally
when we got hold of the engineers in
Australia its invented in house we we
don't really know but we don't we
probably any more questions we should we
drink beer here
yeah thank you thank you thank you