[Music]
welcome to the rice con studio i'm
melissa chan and we're in conversation
the next 30 minutes with jawad fairoos
as usual post your questions in the chat
box and we'll get to as many questions
as possible now jawad fairus is chairman
and founder of salaam for democracy and
human rights he's a former bahraini
member of parliament who resigned in
2011 over the government's violent
response to protesters during the arab
spring he was later detained and
tortured and while overseas he was
stripped of his citizenship
and essentially he's become stateless
and been living in exile ever since so
statelessness is an issue that he very
much advocates for some of you may
already have seen him he presented a
lightning talk entitled are human rights
linked to good governance bahrain and
the 2022 parliamentary elections and uh
his short film was also shown in that
session
jawad fairus
welcome
thanks a lot michelle and good to be
with you and with the rest of our
audience today
um i'd like to start with
your status statelessness this is
something that happens to a lot of
people
certainly in my personal experience i've
interviewed uyghurs overseas uh they
hold a chinese passport uh they were
living and working overseas and you can
well imagine that there was no desire to
go back to china uh where they would
inevitably be a put in detention camp so
many uyghurs have stayed overseas uh and
their passport has uh their passports
have expired or even when they go to the
chinese embassy the chinese embassy has
you know
essentially ripped their passport apart
so can you give people a sense of what
it means to be stateless and
the limits of how you can live
unfortunately one of the biggest grave
humanized violation which is ongoing in
this planet that uh
there are stateless people
and the most great part of it that
if you already have a nationality and by
sudden your nationality will be revoked
and you become statements like my case
and the clear sequence of it that you're
going to be unknown person at the same
time all your basic rights you it will
be deprived and and saying that that
you don't have an official document you
cannot travel you cannot have the basic
services either way state you are living
in or your own country and even all your
civil political rights will be deprived
usually i call it it's like a social
death
that it's look like you are not existing
and the whole entire your day-to-day
life will be so complicated that you
cannot be engaged we have this
phenomenon on this planet unfortunately
although unhcr they launched a campaign
i belong since 2014 and there are a huge
international campaigns with so many
international ngos and you and uh
humanized buddies that try to challenge
it but as i can see and
especially when someone like me that
already had a nationality been elected
member and by sudden his nationality
will be uh
revoked due to the political decisions
without any judicial
process without any clear evidence just
due to
uh wish and the demand of the political
authorities to uh target and
revenge from their political opinions
even if they are being elected members
like my case i've been elected as a
counselor for four years and elected
member of the parliament for five to six
years yet i could find the buy sudan and
my case is being built by the
authorities
as an opponent and then they revoked my
nationality it started in november 2012
and they gradually increased the
revoking nationality of the citizens uh
till it reached almost 909
so
i think now the time comes that
international committee should have all
joint effort to either to to solve
gradually the issue of the statedness or
to prevent any states revoke the
nationality of their citizens
thank you so much for sharing that now
can you tell me a little bit about your
organization salaam for democracy and
human rights
yes
we mainly focus over three main issue
human rights sustainable development and
political reforms through
adopting uh democratic principles
measures and so on we believe that
the security and stability in this final
planet can be maintained if each state
adopted
this comprehensive package
of
evaluation through first of all they
have to have a continuous political
reform by adapting democratic value
then they should have a sustainable
developments
a program part of the governmental
programs all that should be based on the
human rights principles which is going
to be a part of the international human
rights convention and so on so we are
encouraging a lot this type of the
adaptation and we are engaged on a lot
of activities campaigns and so on and
meantime we focus in general in the mena
and then the gulf region and in in
general and specifically in in bahrain
where we are in contact with the victims
we are asking for
that accountability and we try to spread
as much as we can the awareness about
the human rights values and we believe
that more people and especially the
victims and their family they are in
contact with the
different u.n treaty bodies and they are
aware of their basic human rights more
there can and
make a good campaign and and and reduce
whatever harassment and targeting is
being opposed to them but at the end it
showed all that uh to be related to the
local legislation which we are fighting
for to
amend and upgrade the the the local
legislation to be the standard of
international conventions of the human
rights
you know you mentioned the work that you
do
in the mena region i want to go back to
about 10 years ago this is when access
now
started out during that period of the
arab spring and the organization as you
know has hosted wright's con
in tunisia in 2019 i'm curious what you
think where do things stand in the
middle east particularly the gulf a
decade later after the arab spring and
seems really grim
first of all we can see due to the
likeness of the any adaptation of the
continuous political reform as i
indicated due to
uh
on on
unrealistic measures where the
authorities they deal with opposition in
general and absence of freedom of speech
freedom of assembly
absence of the basic political rights
and civil rights we can see such
uprising is continuing uh occasionally
if we can take bahrain as example since
a century
and we can see this each decade we are
facing uh an uprising because
the basic citizenship right is in
absence and
people are demanding that
they want to have their basic rights
with regard to the better income
political rights uh
their human rights to be respected and
so on so um
after the arab spring uh sparked and
tunisia and in december 2010 as everyone
knows that as has been spreaded in an
arab war
uh and in in in egypt and in yemen in
syria and it continued in bahrain
bahrain was part of it although bahrain
and being in in so much
type of the political crisis sin is a
long long time back but it was a chance
that for the people to be in the street
and demand their their basic rights and
demand that their reform and power share
in the government as we can
realize that bahrain unfortunately it is
an absolute monarchy or entire power in
the hand of the ruling family all three
bodies
legislative body executive body and
judiciary body in the hand of the ruling
family and the people demanded their
rights and at the beginning it was a
good turnout and i believe that it was a
good chance for some uh a positive
change on that region in a region in
general in the gulf and part with
bahrain but unfortunately due to what
been called the counter revolutionary
governments and and states all that
being collapsed
and
with the with the let me say silence of
the western government and maybe
sometimes is being looked at the type of
the conspiracy with these
governments
that the counter-revolutionary uh uh
succeeded to suppress and
to crash all these type of the political
uprising and now we can see that
entire control is in the hand of these
governments uh it's been controlled has
been called uh by a security iron fist
and the basics rights are being
suppressed
there is no chance for any type of the
freedom of expression freedom of
assembly and the rest and as i indicated
many many human grave human rights
violations have been acted starting with
the continuous of death penalty
systematic torture revocation of
nationality and the
forcible deportation of the country
which we have it like in bahrain after
your nationality will be revoked you
will be expelled out of the country
forcibly and the same with time whenever
you are active and you could be targeted
your family could be targeted uh and and
and and a lot of type of the
discrimination is being been imposed now
the question is that is this going to be
like a continuous way of the government
that they can have control i believe it
is going to be very very short term
because it is
opposing what
we can believe that
the security and the stability will be
only maintained through
a power share through the the human
rights respects and the continuous
political reforms in absence on these
three
continuous demands of the basic rights i
think the stability will not be there so
i'm expecting that uh after a while
maybe we're gonna uh uh facing another
wave of arab spring uh
more or less because uh the people still
they think that their basic right as a
citizen is not being demanded we have a
lot of
financial
service type of the demand has not been
provided by the government and and
and
considering that even they are not
elected government
so uh i believe that in your future we
can
face another wave of the arab spring
now you mentioned um in
that there are parliamentary elections
later this year
i'm assuming that uh you're not quite
hopeful of the results of that given
what you've just told us about the way
the government is structured
unfortunately we can hear a lot of
high quality type of the democratic
values or names like election
municipality election parliamentary
election even we can see some human
rights uh bodies within these
governments but it is only only being
used as a tool to
a
uh
whitewash these governments uh for
example in bahrain uh when it comes to
the parliamentary election the the
national assembly bahrain consists of
two houses the upper one uh which is
elected body they have the all power
which is elected and appointed it is
appointed house appointed by the king
they have the same number and the same
power as elected house elected house the
constituency has been drawn by the uh
king himself and
all the political oppositions groups has
been banned by law after they pass a law
and then their members and the leaders
are banned from any political
participation they cannot candidate
themselves they extended that one to
included over
of any civil society's election that
they have been banned to be part of it
so they cannot be even part of any sport
club or
charity funds or even any type of the of
of the of the unions labor unions or
women union and so on so totally they
have been banned to
their basic political rights so in such
conditions
are you expecting to have free and fair
election are you expecting to have a for
a representative of the people through
elected house and and even if we can
have a few individuals but with the
limitation of their power what they
don't have and they left the full power
right to either to
monitor or to pass legislation in favor
of the rights of the people so it will
be end up like a a decorative type
prismatic type of the election cosmetic
type of the parliament i believe that
without agreement through a national
dialogue to reach to the um
consolidation on having a free election
and independent uh judicionary
uh and and and and the legislation uh
bodies and and elected or uh uh directly
or indirectly governments with that and
they were ensuring that the full power
of the parliament to be and and service
based on the one man one vote uh and and
for sure security for all without that
one we will not get uh a right track
toward stability security and continuous
reform so once again for sure the coming
election in bahrain in the absence of
good governors and without any
accountability and without adaptation of
transitional justice it will be really
cosmetic
once again like it's been in
2012 2014
2018 and coming one in november this
year
now rights khan is at the intersection
of human rights and technology so i want
to pivot to
talk a little bit about that during the
arab spring as as you know
um it was discovered that bahraini
pro-government hackers
targeted human rights activists during
that time with the software created by a
german company uh finfisher
to try to spy on them nowadays we have
the israeli company pegasus another
software that many state actors have
used including states in the global
south and there's been a lot of media
outcry both during finfisher and the
case
of pegasus the use of surveillance
software by states
not for ostensibly law enforcement
reasons but to target activists how do
you think we can stop this there's been
so much media outrage and outrage among
the activist communities but it doesn't
seem to stop these software surveillance
companies from selling to states and
from states from abusing them
unfortunately this is one of the shame
act
by the uh some authorities in the in the
mena region and it is so clear that
bahrain used the the the
this uh type of the the spywares
either in 2010 and with this uh german
type of the software uh for fine
pressure and
many bahraini activists uh
during that time they've been abroad
they've been targeted and their
emails and
other software that they used to use has
been targeted and
actively whatever they used to
communicate has been monitored and once
again as you indicated the the biggest
one the recent one uh clear evidence
being given and
many international media covered during
that time that many bahraini
human rights defenders and not for once
even some of them their mobile has been
hacked for eight times like episode
assayer some other lawyers in bahrain
and some were activists abroad
it is shown that it is like a systematic
tactic and
systematic
mythology by these authorities to how to
hack and uh try to penetrate
all the electronic stuff or or software
of the activists and i believe that now
right time comes that internationally we
have to pass
international convention to prevent it
and prohibit all the states to use such
software it is totally should be now
illegal act and
our country will use it there should be
certain sequences
and and some type of the punishment to
be applied without that one i'm i'm
afraid that such bad act and and roman
act will be continued by these
authorities and governments
thank you so much i want to turn to
questions now
someone is asking what your message is
to governments that claim that
protecting human rights goes against
national security this is something that
i suspect is often repeated by many uh
leaders of gulf states you've heard this
one before
yes i think unfortunately it is a claim
not seriously there is willing to
protect the basic rights of the human
being i think the main principle of any
legislation which we passed would
related to the security should be based
on the human rights value we cannot
penetrate our basic rights due to the
claim that because we want to protect
the security all that one should be
within the international conventions
that all of us who agreed to be within
the mechanism of the united nations
without that one and without
international agreement which should be
part of our basic human rights i think
this type of the legislations or the
accusations who shouldn't be accepted
and should be rejected unfortunately we
know that so many governments like
bahraini governments they use a lot
terminology of
fighting the the terrorism uh
to to to target and and and limit
the activities of the human rights
defenders so what they do they try to
amend
so many local legislation to say that it
is going to be targeted to to to to to
to fight against the terrorist
act but actually this target against the
activists and prevent them to
practice their basic rights so in short
most important that it should be within
the boundary of the human rights any
legislation going to be passed and
within the boundary of international
conventions within the the u.n
conventions
thank you
now um
a participant by the name of abeer wants
you to comment on the situation with
tunisia
and the status of the democracy there i
know there's um
sort of a problem with the parliament
right now i don't know how closely you
follow tunisia but any thoughts on
that
country as a general rules is that
any particular individuals either he is
a president or he is a king or whatever
being called you shouldn't have the full
power
to freeze the constitution or to
dissolve the parliament and i believe
that the democratic process are so clear
on this regard the basic thing that if
there is any dispute there should be
either through a clear dialogue with all
political parties and all the activists
and here emphasize the role of the ngos
secondly the referendum they're they're
the going to to the poll stations to the
elections that should solve the problem
not to depend on the military not to the
end on dissolving
a role of the parliament not to depend
on freezing the any article of the
constitution constitution should
continue as active as all the time and
we should take
any type of the military intervention
away from any our political disputes
only through the dialogue and then
agreeing to go to the early election all
that could be solved but unfortunately
yet in tunisia that is not being
practiced and and we believe on that uh
that the tunisian political activities
and
the role of the ngo is so so long and i
hope that all of them can get together
and try to practice peacefully whatever
pressure they can to maintain the
democracy and and to be as a model for
the rest of the arab world to have a
transitional of power in the same time a
very
democratic process to any changes
occurring in this
country
great thank you another question is
asking about how civil society around
the world can support activists
especially those expressing themselves
online especially
since activists are being targeted by
their governments
yes for sure we need to enhance the role
of the ngos i believe that any
democratic process without the role of
the ngos is going to be a
a
a short one and going to be uncomplete
we need to enhance the role of the ngos
and we knew we need to have a unity and
more cooperation
and contacts with with ngos
internationally as i can see now it is
good step and good indication that even
you and buddies they try to give a
bigger room or more room for the ngos
they are involving vietnam as an
advisory board they are giving them more
in their campaigns which is good
indications and uh we watch event that
will be extended to the human right
council which is unfortunately here the
human rights council is representing the
states which we believe that the
consultative status of the ngos should
be easier than it is and more role of
the ngos
as much as we can we have to engage ngos
in all u.n mechanism and we should
demand the states that they should give
for the room for the power of the ngos
and any process they do
there's a question here that goes back
to the issue of statelessness which was
at the start of our uh conversation
they're asking could you unpack the
impact of statelessness in the gulf a
bit more they talk about kuwait and also
the fact that qatar has deprived
citizenship of a clan there's also the
uae that has its own stateless
population
comment a little bit about that
unfortunately the issue of the
nationality in the gulf a little bit
sensitive for the states they locate
totally as a sovereignty of the state
and without any type of the uh state of
law without any type of the
let me say
away from international conventions it
states
they feel they have all the full rights
either to
refuse the nationality of the people who
already live their centuries back like
we don't in kuwait they have been
deprived
their rights we have
more than 200 thousands
equations are stateless in kuwait
imagine you are living in kuwait your
father your grandfather lived in kuwait
and they are been there so so long time
centuries back but you don't have any
basic right of as a citizenship as
being kuwaitis you've been deprived of
your basic services by the government
and so on you don't have official
documents you cannot travel you cannot
have education you're going to have
birth certificate you cannot get
marriage
so so easily as i said it's totally like
a social death or in another time
whenever there's a political dispute
your nationality will be revoked and
you'll be expect out of country this is
so clear now in the kuwait as a bedouin
and now we could see
it's happened in bahrain
by revoking nationality and
unfortunately in qatar when some tribe
they're being banned of their basic uh
qatari citizenship
joad faires we have time for um just a
final remarks do you have any final
thoughts um before we wrap up
i encourage all the activists once again
sorry my throat yeah have a drink of
water i'll have a drink of water as well
yeah thank you
i think uh with the digital sphere and
shrinking and then the distance among us
as activists and as a ngos
and and all those who are demanding the
change in this planet
uh we have to engage ourselves with all
international
events related to the
human rights democratic change and so on
and once again i emphasize a lot that we
have to
depends on the
civil civil movement and away
from any type of their violence and we
have to be
managing all our
act on the very peaceful manners
the change is coming we have to be
more patient but active in the same time
we should have clear vision that to
maintain
a a peaceful planet through adaptation
of
democratic process and exchange of our
all experience toward
further establishing
a stability and exchanging or our vision
toward sustainable developments and once
again i believe all that cannot be
achieved without the human rights and
basic rights which being so clear by the
united nation and
with our coordination i think that we
can manage it so for sure
thank you so much and for ending on a
hopeful message jawad fairuz
thank you we're very grateful for your
time
thank you thank you very much and good
luck
and for the rest of the rights con
community as always enjoy your sessions
and stay engaged see you later
[Music]
you