welcome back to the studio and we're in
conversation the next 30 minutes with
nick allardyce ceo of change.org
nick you started out as an activist then
you went to change to help with its
global expansion and then you also i
know worked on the campaign's team and
the product team so
know many aspects of the organization
welcome to the program i'm so excited to
talk to you because we're here to
celebrate
the 10th anniversary of the global
expansion of the organization right yeah
we are it's uh it's a really special
year for us actually because it was 10
years ago that change.org went from
being this very u.s centric uh petition
platform to really expanding globally
and
most people may not realize but signing
petitions is the most popular civic
action second only to voting
and so in the 10 years since then we've
seen more than 500 million people use
change.org around the world to sign
petitions on the things that they care
about
so much so that in a bunch of countries
whether it's the us or the uk or spain
we have almost as many people using
change.org as voters like more than 50
of the voting population are using
change.org on a regular basis
um and then just in the last couple of
years we expanded to africa and um right
now actually there's this massive
campaign that's taken off in south
africa
about energy and the energy crisis
that's happening there
and so all around the world we've seen
this explosion of activity of people
using this simple accessible tool to
take action on issues they care about
and we're taking this year as 10 years
since we started that process to just
celebrate that
awesome now with petitions i think um
how do you take a petition and and see
the impact you know beyond the online
signing i mean some people can be quite
critical it's just signing
you know putting your signature on
something and then nothing happens after
that but what are you seeing yeah so i
think there's a little bit of a
misconception that petitions don't work
and that's not at all our experience um
literally every hour there are campaigns
winning on the platform just through
people adding their voice telling their
story through this very simple tool now
i think in some ways the advent of
online organizing came from the simple
insight that signing a petition could
also act as a sign up form for further
action
and so what we see is that petitions are
they're kind of containers they're a way
in which a group of people who have a
shared set of values or a shared goal
can come together but then organize
together on what additional actions are
going to make the most difference
and so frequently we see
thousands of people come together within
a petition but then using that as a
forum to identify what's the next action
to take where are we meeting up in
person who are we calling
um how are we lobbying the decision
makers and they're the campaigns that
are most successful
now i think the problem is
activism as a whole and i've been
working in activism and i guess
volunteering and activism for uh pretty
much all of my life at this point i
think the same barriers exist today as
have for a really long time which is
it takes a lot of time
it takes a lot of money
you've got to have the like
privilege to be able to invest time in
activism and organize it often happens
outside of somebody's job absolutely
and
and it requires a you know it's not
clear how it works it's very
inaccessible
it's not clear how to be successful
requires education knowledge various
things and so
we are constantly looking at well how
can we make this more accessible what
are the barriers that we can lower by
taking all of what we learn about what
makes for effective campaigning making
that accessible to people through
personal coaches through
training and education but also
exploring ways for people to be able to
like earn money to be sustainable in
their activism as well so the petition
is really very much a starting point
it's like a gateway drug
a nice gateway drug exactly um so what
has changed over the last 10 years in
terms of how you're seeing this process
play out
what was it like 10 years ago when
people signed up for a petition and what
happened versus now and how are they
using technology to leverage things yeah
so i think
there's never been a better moment
in time for people to have more agency
and voice through using technology
whether petitions or actually social
media and other
technology evolutions to organize
quickly and
i think that like covert actually
provides a really good example of this
so
on change.org we saw this explosion of
campaigns like hundreds thousands of
campaigns looking
at the advent of covert like how to
protect and support different industries
hundreds thousands of campaigns how to
make sure that healthcare workers had
access to ppe and other forms of
security hundreds thousands of campaigns
around vaccine access and things like
that
and that was a moment in time in which i
think institutions
were struggling to react fast enough
like that the centralized coordinated
approach to that rapidly changing
environment simply couldn't keep up with
the set of needs and so on change we saw
people like breaking that problem down
into all of these different micro
solutions and then organizing around
those and we saw that happen off change
as well like
mutual aid groups springing up
and other forms of collective organizing
that involve individuals and communities
self self-organizing to identify
solutions and improve things so super
busy period the last two years not much
uh bread baking for you definitely
definitely vein a busy figures
amazing and so um
can you talk about what is uh happening
right now
something that's coming up a lot in the
last 24 hours of this summit is of
course uh russia's invasion of ukraine
um how are you seeing
that play out on your platform yeah so i
don't know about you but certainly
around when that first happened i felt
this incredible sense of like
powerlessness frustration anger like
yeah absolutely how can we do something
like what an awful situation you know
you're just sitting there watching the
tanks roll towards kiev and you're
concerned that
i mean there was a moment when everyone
was concerned that the president of
ukraine was just going to be killed and
we're all just watching absolutely and
so we saw this like explosion of people
like trying to find a way to
constructively challenge their like fear
and hope in that situation
so constructively channel
challenge
and
uh
that led to a mixture of things so
you have these like
one-off big breakout moments so one
example in russia an anti-war activist
started a petition
that really ended up being a central
focal point for anti-war
expression in russia at the time more
than 1.2 million russians signed that
campaign
and it became a
mechanism and voice for people inside
russia to express their
their kind of frustration in this
situation and oppose the war
but outside of that we also saw this
phenomenon of these like thousands of
micro actions that people might take so
we saw thousands of campaigns that were
about
how can we
make it easier for refugees to get into
this particular country um we saw
thousands of campaigns that were about
welcoming those refugees or about
ensuring that there was aid going to
different groups and so
um what we're seeing in response to
moments like that is not one silver
bullet campaign where people think that
one particular movement or one
particular petition or any one thing is
going to solve that problem i don't
think people are that naive right but
what they are doing is they're trying to
take that big problem break it down into
a whole bunch of smaller component
bite-sized pieces that you can then make
a difference on in your local community
and that honestly is the thing that
gives me the most hope in those
situations
i actually want to go back to one of the
examples you gave of russians signing a
petition against the war here's a
question what about protecting those
people in the security i'm sure you guys
think about about it people sign their
names onto list at the time
it
made sense and
if they're in a semi-authoritarian state
that decides to start going after people
on that list how does change deal with
that yeah it's a great question so
uh we operate
across a bunch of different contexts
both democratic as well as
semi-democratic as well as kind of
authoritarian and so we
have a set of protections in place in
those
markets where we anonymize and make
secure a bunch of personal information
so whereas in a us market what you might
see is you see all the list of names and
like that people putting their public
persona against a campaign in russia
what you would say is just the aggregate
like you see the number of people taking
action but um we kind of strip away the
ability to identify any one person
within it
super interesting
the other thing that i'm wondering is um
since a decade ago my own observation is
that
activism happens in different countries
but there's a transnational thing going
on like point of reference is um in asia
with the milk tea alliance a funny name
but it was a way for young protesters a
lot of them students in hong kong
myanmar thailand indonesia to start
communicating with each other
to try to
you know it's a strength and numbers
thing that people were recognizing are
you seeing more of that um through
change.org as well yeah absolutely and i
think it's a really good example because
i think looking 10 years ago i think
there may have been a
optimism that there was the potential
for these unifying transnational
movements that would be like you know
put pressure on international
governments to see climate action and
you know one big campaign might be a um
a global cry to
force a change of some kind and that's
not really how we're seeing it play out
we see transnational movements that
share values
and goals
but which
take those values and goals and
customize them for their local context
and figure out what the right expression
is for those contexts and that are
inspired by each other and support each
other with lessons with learnings with
things like that but which are not
working on fundamentally the same
specific campaign
an example of this would be in 2020
we saw thousands of campaigns in the u.s
focused on uh representation around
racial justice monuments so
thousands of monuments to slave owners
in the u.s that were kind of held up and
glorified in different local communities
and so we saw hundreds and thousands of
campaigns that were about changing that
representation and taking those down
that inspired a set of similar campaigns
that basically started copycatting
copycatting and learning from what was
happening that we saw spread across the
world in the uk i remember and
absolutely and the same thing happened
another example uh in many uh in many
contexts
um women's sanitary products are taxed
in a way so tampon taxes as an example
and so we saw this big campaign in the
uk where um there was this huge movement
that was about getting the tampon tax
removed that started before the united
states that did start before the united
states that's right and that campaign
very much inspired
copycat campaigns across first across
rest of europe and then on a
state-by-state basis in the us
and
those campaigners were talking to each
other right there's like literally a
whatsapp group in which folks are
sharing lessons celebrating each other's
victories and being inspired by what's
working in different context contexts
and countries and that i think is the
future of like transnational activism
it's not about one unifying big campaign
that everyone is working on it's about
shared goals and shared values and then
sharing lessons and being inspired by
that and supporting each other in the
way that it gets taken forwards how is
that different than like i'm just as
you're talking i'm thinking about like
the arab spring where there was also
transnational communication how is it
different now than
back then i mean you answered it a
little bit about you know each group
understanding that they have to focus on
their own theme and their shared values
but are you seeing
anything else in terms of like how they
implement technology or
so on yeah i mean i think the themes are
still there from the arab spring which
is that like
uh decentralization of communication
enables that sharing of information and
that inspiration
um from each other but the mechanisms
through which that happens are changing
and so
uh you know these days rather than
necessarily twitter being the thing in
which the arab spring is like sharing
that information now you have the rise
of like tick-tock communicators who are
telling stories and figuring out how to
make information about the ukraine like
digestible
easily accessible and distributable to a
really large audience and so i think the
mechanisms are changing i think things
like whatsapp things like whether it's
discord or slack that are enabling
um coordination across context and
sharing of lessons
is new and evolving as well great uh
we're gonna go to questions very soon so
if you haven't um you've been shy in the
chat box definitely start submitting
your questions and we'll get to as many
as possible but i want to
maybe wrap up this part of the segment
with a couple of big picture questions
um
it's been a little depressing sometimes
to see
uh people power movements essentially
not work out we see this with hong kong
we saw that there was such an
expectation from the people of belarus
that the world would stand with them and
to an extent they have um but
they didn't get perhaps the kind of help
they needed or
in any case the movement was crushed
you see this it's just slightly
different but in kazakhstan earlier this
year um
i can go on and on right
in southeast asia the thai students came
out during covid and kept coming out and
so i mean it feels sometimes like none
of it is working as someone who
sits there and deals with all this looks
at the petitions look at all the
activism in all these different
countries what would you say
i mean
unfortunately advocacy activism
campaigning it's just not a linear
process
my experience i think back to one of the
first big kind of organizing efforts
that i worked and volunteered on which
was about trying to increase australia's
aid and development budget
and after this blood sweat and tears of
nine months of campaign working on this
we secured a commitment to increase
australia's development budget by about
three billion dollars which felt like
this huge win right and then three years
later new government comes in cuts it
immediately right and so it was just
this devastating moment and and
constantly i think advocacy and
campaigning is very much two steps
forward one steps back and you can never
know when a
when the groundwork that a campaign has
laid
can find fertile
ground when context changes yeah it
often feels like it's happening very
quickly but actually a lot of people
have been investing decades totally i
mean i think you see in a bunch of
countries right now what has felt like
zero progress at all on climate
suddenly context changes and something
new is possible the same is true
actually on covert where
for decades people had been working on
mental health issues
and then covert put a focus on that that
meant a huge number of national
governments um invested in mental health
in a way that they had never done done
before and the only reason that was
possible was because there'd been
decades of pre-work that had felt like
it wasn't going anywhere right and then
suddenly it was possible and there was
this huge leak forwards excellent okay
so let's go to questions uh we have one
from carolyn
how have you seen people use change.org
to innovate beyond the traditional
petition format
yeah so this is a great question um
one thing that we're seeing at the
moment is the rise of what i will call
the like individual civic leader
influencer type and what i mean by this
is
if we go back a few decades
most organizing and activism was
much of it was led from within
institutions organizations non-profits
that were
kind of building durable power and
organizing that or organizing on that
over time
and what we're seeing now is these
individuals who are have powerful
personal stories
who
are compelling communicators
and who have like really innovative
theories of change and diverse ways of
looking at a problem building audiences
and brands almost like as individuals
that are then being very compelling
public communicators around it like the
most
obvious example is like greta at a at an
international level but
i think across every issue you're seeing
more and more of these people who are
building an audience as an individual
finding their voice
um and having an incredibly important
impact on the way that the public is
perceiving an issue and so petitions are
like one way to build that audience and
to start to
cut through um but people are then
leveraging that audience into
things like additional actions that
their supporters can take one thing that
we're working on is how people can take
that and turn that into having durable
income actually because the biggest um
barrier to being able to do more of that
work is time and money to what you said
at the very beginning exactly so that's
something that we're working on as well
and that's something we're very excited
about cool awesome so next question
uh what has change.org learned um
and shared about the impact of petitions
and other advocacy tools have in
persuading dece okay so yeah and if you
can provide some examples of when um
petitions have persuaded decision makers
to change course
so i think that there's a couple of
ways in which this happens so the first
is
um
a petition can spotlight an issue that a
decision maker just simply wasn't aware
of this happens surprisingly frequently
decision makers have a hard job right
they're balancing all sorts of different
things
and so by simply calling attention to an
issue and spotlighting it that's enough
to kind of lead to some sort of change
often though it's the addition of two
things that make the most difference so
the first is the personal stories behind
the person who organized the petition
and the signatures behind it as well
it's kind of not enough just to be like
oh there's a nameless one person who
added their name to this instead it's
about hearing about the personal story
of like why this matters
and that
turning abstract numbers of petition
signatures into real stories
of how people are affected by different
issues is extremely compelling to
decision makers the second thing is to
help focus the activities of those
signatures into additional actions like
calling the decision maker showing up to
events right those are the additional
things that also make petitions really
powerful cool all right well
um
colin asks can you talk about trust and
safety at change.org what's the main
trend of user-generated content you are
fighting against
that's a good question it's a great
question and it varies it changes a lot
over time and changes a lot by different
national context
we
try to balance three things um we want
our community to be empowering
open and safe
in the way that we
uh essentially protect our safe space
for people to have a voice
the biggest trend um
over the last few years was obviously
covered yep
where
we had to
react really fast honestly to try and
make sure that things weren't that
wasn't misinformation spreading through
the platform
and
i'm really proud of the way that our
trust and safety team worked on that
actually we acted much faster than many
of the other like tech platforms on this
um can you give an example i mean just
like what kind of misinformation
somebody was trying to petition yeah so
like uh
vaccine safety is a good example of this
right
where um there was a bunch of
misinformation or i don't know 5g bill
gate like there's all sorts of
conspiracy theories out there that um
were that we had to act really fast on
to try and make sure that we were not
being a kind of platform for them
excellent
uh cool so lots of questions this is
awesome i think this is the most we've
had for in in conversation donna is
asking is email still a functional and
worthwhile channel for digital activism
i mean
people have been predicting the death of
email for like 15 20 years right exactly
i still find it useful exactly
so
a huge amount of number of our community
regularly find out about um the
campaigns that they can support through
the email channel so um we kind of have
somewhere in the range of a billion
recommendations a month going out to
different members of our community um
with email as a primary channel
it's definitely
not as effective as it used to be
but there's not a better alternative
like the alternative is to try and be is
to kind of put yourself at the whims of
the algorithms of various social media
platforms
you know some people are building up sms
platforms um but that's expensive and it
costs a lot of money to distribute so
even though email has declined in
absolute value it's still i think
one of the best channels for any
organization um organizing community of
people to be investing in yeah and
there's a second life now with the
popularity of newsletters yeah
absolutely are you guys involved in that
kind of um yeah i mean that's it kind of
goes to this uh
uh
trend that i that i was talking about
before of these individual like leaders
who are
kind of building up profiles by
themselves not not associated with
organizations often they're doing that
by building up audiences through email
newsletters we see them using platforms
like sub stack or patreon or things like
that
so that's very much something that we're
looking to enable as well very cool
okay next question let's see
laura says after 10 years of emails and
petitions emails again
what trends will we be talking about in
organizing technology 10 years from now
and i think that's kind of like what's
the future of change.org right yeah so i
couldn't be more excited about this
um that the new voices that are coming
to the table as a result of this
of this disaggregation and
decentralization of the the new civic
leaders that are finding their voice
these are the greta's the malalas
parkland
students um
again and again we're seeing these kind
of new leaders emerging and i think that
that's something that is incredibly
um exciting it's bringing a more diverse
set of voices to the table it is
bringing a more diverse set of like
theories of change for how you create
change in the world it's not about using
the same old tactics that like a small
set of organizations have used forever
um and i think that trend is only going
to continue i think that
in the same way
we are seeing in media
this trend of
journalists essentially
becoming
production companies themselves
individuals they become brands they
become brands we're going to see that in
in activism and organizing and i think
that that's going to lead to a much more
diverse set of voices at the table and a
much more diverse set of theories of
change for how um different issues get
taken forwards that's something that i'm
incredibly excited about
the other um
kind of big trend i think is
in 10 years time
i don't know about you but i'm i'm
overwhelmed when i think about how can i
personally take action on climate change
yes yes
like there are a thousand petitions
signed there are 100 000 organizations
to donate to
and there's a lot of noise
and that is
both exciting because
i can look through everything and i can
go here is an organization doing
something i'm incredibly inspired by
they're based in africa they've
organized organizing on the ground and i
can back them directly and be connected
to them directly in a way that wasn't
possible before so that's like the
exciting part the hard part is that's
really overwhelming there's a lot of
noise to cut through and do you think
that's the big challenge for for
change.org i mean it's something that
we're definitely thinking about how we
can help our users with which is out of
all of the opportunities that are out
there which one is like most relevant
for you and how do you cut through and
identify the things that are most
impactful
um and i think there's a lot of other
really interesting organizations doing
similar things that are essentially
solving the problem of identifying the
most impactful action that you can take
givewell i think is actually a really
good example i don't know if your the
audience knows about this but they do
really great work looking through all of
the organizations that are doing work to
fight extreme poverty essentially
and
saying out of all of the possible
opportunities to donate
what has the highest impact
right and saying like here are the top
three here's where we think your money
should go and as a result of their
recommendations literally hundreds of
millions of dollars get channeled
towards these highly effective
organizations and i think we're going to
see more of that over time not just for
donations but also for advocacy actions
also for volunteering right but it's
about helping people cut through the
noise and identify what is most
impactful for them personally got it
i think we have time for just one
question so let me check and um
and you know what i'm gonna end on on
asking you about the biggest challenge
that you think change.org is going to be
facing in the next decade what's the
thing that really kind of worries you
and say oh we need to really work on
that and make sure that this works yeah
so
this might be a slightly wonky answer
but we have increasing amounts of
attention
and
time
being captured and utilized by
essentially monopoly technology
platforms that are very closed gardens i
mean you mentioned tick-tock i mean
tick-tock is a great great activist
uh you know communicating there but you
can also just spend six hours watching
watching
i don't know people dancing which is
great but and they're very closed
ecosystems right like i think if we go
back to a previous iteration of the
internet and the technology
um
people would coordinate but they would
also post links they would share
opportunities for action and it was very
possible to go out and take action
somewhere else as a result
instagram tick tock some of the most
popular technology platforms these days
snapchat is another good example are
very focused around keeping you within
the ecosystem
um which can be great for education
content and so on but makes it really
hard to
inspire people to take action elsewhere
and i think that's something both for us
but also the industry more broadly we
need to be really careful of
because it's going to be increasingly
hard on those platforms to get people to
take action outside of them
and that i think is a challenge for us
and for everyone to overcome
well on that note nick thank you so much
for joining us in the studio i hope
everyone out there thought that was a
fantastic talk i certainly learned a lot
have a good day and stay engaged