the end the new laws and %um it is your
home
I
I will now go to English which is much
easier for me
how many views this your first time here
while a lotta newcomers Sastry puts on
an incredible
show you're going to have a lot of
interesting people to talk to a lot of
great presentations
and please we have a lot of sponsors
that have helped out
to make this all possible this is the
new facility
what do you think this new facility is
in a great yeah I mean I absolutely love
it I think this is yeah
not scared for so without out getting my
we're gonna be running on little
behind schedule today as you can tell
and that's okay we will try to make up
some time
Aug and during the first break and
during lunch time
keep in mind that around five o'clock
we will have a debate very hot debate
on vigilantism and strike back
active defense in cyberspace
so please make sure your here we will
have
alcohol for that and make it all the
more interesting
but I have the honour OVR beginning
this conference and we're going to talk
about something that perhaps is new to
you
and
and I have talked a little bit about it
in the last a couple of months in
mostly in Europe and I'm gonna mess with
your minds a little bit
on a present an idea a series of ideas
that may be right they may be wrong
but whatever hopefully they can give us
a new perspective
a new view of information security
because certainly some other things that
we've been doing over the last few years
have not been working
so let's keep in mind
APT news people were only for hundreds
and hundreds of days
the concept of digital is something that
we live with something that we breathe
in our world and I wanna change that a
little bit
and get you to think about the concept
up analog with a few fundamental
concepts that
why does digital have to be binary
why do we treat security
as though it's one thing only that its
static where are the measurements a
security I don't know if there is any
vendors here
but how many times do we get a product
from a vendor that has a
guarantee love performance that it will
work
not very often if it all
and we're going to present some ideas I
have stripped out most of the
mathematics
is that it is things I do would be sides
that are four
5-6 hours long to give you a high-level
view
so right now securities keeping the good
guys on us
that's about it wrong button
there legislation and laws about
security
how do those work for us those work well
all the laws in compliance
now we're building I O T
we already have a mass and in the next
10 years we're gonna add
$20 billion $30 billion $40 billion new
devices
on to something that's already broken
something has to change
so I grew up
doing the stuff I was a TV repairman at
five years old which
was very very easy back in those days
you take everything out with the TV go
to the drugstore
find out what bro replace it
and almost anybody could do this but I
had a deficiency
I'm colorblind I don't see collar very
well
and as we go through this you're gonna
see how those
influenced my thinking when it comes to
analog processing and the differences
between
analog and digital I grew up in
rock-and-roll
I was an audio engineer and I worked
with all the great guys did you see the
console
on the right there hundreds and hundreds
and hundreds of
analog control devices in
order to make music that's
thing with the three dials that isn't
analog computer
from nineteen 62 63
yet it kinda worked but it was a
different approach
that i'm gonna suggest we start
revisiting again
so analog WTF
and what is it well I don't can you read
those
it's kind of difficult these are some
questions and the slides I will make
them available to everybody
what is at all
is analog always a yes-or-no question
one lawyer asks a question did you kill
that person
isn't always a yes or no answer or
is there something that balances when we
look at balance
its analog it's not yes or no
analog mean something very simple
continuously variable changing
all of the time and
in the analog world we take digital
signals
and we split smoothing functions on them
to make them look better and ultimately
sound better when you watch a movie
is a data logger digital anybody
is an analog or digital 30 frames per
second
to digital function that our eyes
and our brain processing turned him to
an analog signal
to make it look continuously variable
when we talk about things like Aspergers
Syndrome he has Aspergers
well there is a spectrum
it's not a yes or a No answer
and I started to approach security with
the same kind of approach
trying to look at it and see are there
new answers that we can come up with
if we just look at the universe
completely differently
I also have a thing called sinners
feature and when I was in the record
business
ice so long music so we were recording
concerts or recording an album in the
studio
I would see collars and this is often
the kinda image that I would see
while we were making the music and
it some help helped me do it and can
also suggest that the
internet has become analog when we look
at one end point that might be digital
might be binary but be Internet as a
whole
including was coming with I O T it's a
constantly changing blog
do we really have perimeters anymore
that we can say hard to find the digital
points and I'm arguing that when we
step back and look at large networks
look at how everything is connected that
it is really much more than
an award function when we want to think
about
how to make things different than they
are now the brain is analog
the brain is not big computer the brain
is a great averaging machine
it averages every phone when you see
something in your looking and it's very
very clear
less than three percent all your brain
and your
I are used to do the focus everything
else is fuzzy
but the brain average is this
and we're treating the world how do we
interface with that from a human
standpoint
so now we're getting the bio implants
and the prosthetics norrell implants
where we have to connect the digital
world
that were growing up in and we now know
with the analog
human element and more and more of this
is coming I think
deal on mars is leading now saying we
have to be very very careful how we
become
the board as we put all these things
together
so let's step back and see how did we
get into this mess that we're in right
now
and the fundamental security model
that we use two day was developed
in the nineteen seventies we still use
it
and it was based upon mainframe
computers
and the mainframe computers had a box
one wire
and a green screen and that's how we did
security
security was done with a static mindset
because the military are the ones who
developed it
so when we look at military history the
match in a line
did not work the Great Wall of China did
not work
Berlin Wall anything that is a static
defence
in the military world has never worked
but that's how we chose
forty-some years ago to actually build
security
into our computing infrastructures such
as they work
and it's based upon the concept of risk
avoids
I want no rest so the concept was
bill the walls higher and that'll keep
the bad guys out
in what we do today we say let's add
more firewalls more controls more
defensive technology news
and that'll keep the bad guys out that
works right
week month you are getting to know from
everybody here this is what we have
chosen to do
and the fundamental mechanism is called
the reference monitor
and there were several people involved
in development up
Anderson BB bellum a partial back in the
seventies and it was very simple 11
directional communication called a
synchronous
and what we did is a system request for
comment
stop the process go to the side
make a decision come back and I had a
yes or no answer
a binary answer now this worked
in a mainframe environment what
killed at all the concept of network
because the network is synchronous it
goes in two directions
and this wasn't a synchronous model the
only worked in one direction
yet we have stuck with this model
because we started building technologies
around a concept and that's why
every vendor today has a next generation
thing that is really gonna picture
problems
where stock in this mindset
so numbered years ago
a friend of mine who will be in the
debate hopefully this evening
gave me an idea I started working with
and it was called protect the tech
respond and he developed for the %um
United States Department of Defense so
what are the questions that we began
with his here's a fault
is that vault secure
is it secure jason is that ball secure
know why not because the doors open
if the doors closed as the vault secured
Jason
no why not he's gonna get somebody
that's get the combination
so he's gonna do the social engineering
thing but technically
in the physical world we have something
we do something for security
we don't do in our world Jer a safe
a vault has a raiding and the rating is
temperature and time-based how long will
that metal sustain
a torch trying to break through it so
when you ask your vendor
your firewall looks
really nice how many hours will it
protect me against the Chinese
are you gonna get an answer
in the physical world we have the answer
but in our world we don't have it yet
and I'm gonna are you it's about time
and we're going to use time throughout
and time
isn't analog function it's continuously
variable
until you get them to quantum mechanics
and we're not gonna do quantum mechanics
here today
all about time so we can
radar firewall nobody knows all the
vendors
law I no offense to vendors or
supporters
course but that's what sales and
marketing guys do
ours is the best ours is the best but
they all operate on the same fundamental
principle
when we look at firewalls and access
control mechanisms
mechanisms and protection devices
ultimately
do the bad guys go through the front
door trying to be did
they do what was done around the
National I'm
to go around it the go over us
building under a protection devices is
where we have invested
invested hundreds of billions of dollars
in the last 25 years
and it doesn't work for all of these
sorts reasons
so we need to take another approach what
can we actually measure
internet works and what we can measure
are two things
one is detection
and a detection could be a in the
physical world
Osama alarm are
you it could be are the tape on a window
noticing that the glass has been broken
we know how to measure
be amount of time it takes
to be able to detect something I know a
lot of folks and I don't know if any
have you have
actually built in ones and cold in your
networks
hostile cold is a test the sea
number one can your detection mechanisms
pick it up at number two
how long does it take a but the texan's
only half the battle
we have to be able to react and in the
physical world
maybe a jewelry store is getting rocked
the alarm
goes off right away very very very
quickly how long does it take police to
show up to actually
do something we can measure that
in a new york networks you have the same
capability
depending upon how your reaction 28
detection works
do send somebody email they get an SMS
they get a telephone call what if the
guy is on holiday
what if it's the weekend other five
people to react
how long does it take you have the
capability
right now to be able to do some very
simple code
and test your own networks to begin to
get a matter
a measurement love how secure you are
never going to get a little more refined
amiss
and ultimately what happens I'm not
gonna go crazy math with you
is it turns out that we can measure
and quantify security with a simple
formula if
my firewall for example is strong enough
to be able to take somebody hacking
but bad amount of time is greater than
the amount of time it takes
my detection and reaction mechanisms
to find out what's going on and do
something about it
I then can have a secure environment and
I music exclusively
the time domain to be able to do this
so this is something you can do right
now to find out
where you are because something very
interesting happens
in the cold war we did exactly the same
thing
if United States
or allies detected in the cold war
a soviet missile launch we had
eighteen and a half minutes to make a
decision
as to whether the shoot back or not a
time base function
in the physical world which gives us a
lot I hope for what we're trying to do
in our world so when we're looking at
our detection reaction
there's little components other that
mean work in one way if you have a
manual operation with a human has to get
involved
or even go much faster
if you haven't automated process because
you have planned out
things in advance and my experience
the number of companies that have
actually planned out responses to
security
he vents are very very rare
they like to call in the lawyers they
like to call in the police the wanna
call in management to make a decision
which makes the detection time in
reaction time
much bigger which means that my
protection
metric is bad much
smaller some very very simple concepts
that were gonna play with but with this
gives you
is an opportunity to measure your
exposure time
the exposure time what is your detection
time plus your reaction time
because we know the protection cannot be
measured
so we put on a risk management had
and look at it that way and then we can
do some
math and let the guys overnight and
security but the coroner's the financial
people
you can now we go home
measure your network and determine your
exposure time to find out
how much damage could be done in five
minutes ten minutes to hours
or in cases
China and the PT's four hundred days
six hundred days we are missing the
entire point of work
protection really means and part of the
problem is obviously people do not know
what they have on their networks
and we tend to look at our networks is
one the single
being that all briefing wonder the hood
past
to be protected everything has to be
protected
because that's the technology that we
have been given thus far to be able to
use
but is it everything above the same
value
within your network and obviously it's
not some things are much much more
important than others
but we're still seeing the same security
problems
regardless of how sensitive but data may
be
now we can also apply the concert though
defense in depth
with the simple concept we go to the
movies in which to the big house on the
hill
and the bad guys are going to rob so as
they wanna robbing notice that their
views
alarm system so what do they do
they wanted disconnect the alarm system
obviously
however with defense in depth
using this model I can add an additional
layer of protection and detection and
reaction
to me the primary detection mechanisms
which will give us increased levels of
protection
with some defense and a but I am not at
all convinced any more than I believe in
defense in depth and I'm gonna show you
how that works out and why the things
you can do with the exposure time
is to determine the file size is that
could be
actually targeted and it's fairly simple
math to figure out
where's my weakness what is susceptible
and with padding solutions with
adding additional bits and bytes two
files
through obfuscation I love them
to encryption et cetera we convince a
certain files have a higher level
probability up being attacked
being actual traded and then we can
start mitigating in handling this
in a slightly different way but this is
only the very beginning
where we go the circularly
top there is an analog circuit that
dim the light bulb at all it does very
very simple sir
but what we don't do
is how come we don't dim
all the data when we noticed something
we have the ability
current to add what is called a band
with limiter
so simple Analog concept that came from
the music industry
that we can apply to when
in the band is occurring cuz pet we tend
to these days say
something's bad happening turn it off
then we'll fix it
i'm saying there's a middle ground
by dimming the amount of data and again
at a time
base function analog function and
something really interesting happens
and hopefully you can read some about
that have I restrict the band with my
band which is normally one gigabyte
and I sense something going on through
the detection mechanism
but I don't wanna shut down my company I
don't wanna shut down accounting I don't
wanna shut down
my transactions what about band with
construction
the numbers turn out very very
interesting with a little bit a bad with
construction
my exposure time will remain the same
but Mike data exposure will go down
orders %uh magnitude with a simple
instead of turning it on and off just
restricting the amount of data that goes
through
now the bad guys no map these guys are
not getting its
may understand just as well as we do
just because they work for the bad guys
doesn't mean they're idiots
but they're also understanding that some
was a lotta math that's coming up and we
are redefining what security is so
one of the things that really bothers me
in our technologies today
is the concept of loot anybody hate
group controls much as me
and getting some head the room its one
person
withhold all binary control
over a system one person wonders
and I have a problem with that and
whether you look at this
note in a van to look at them insider
gone bad
and administrator overriding a man
manager whatever it is route control
gives us
how do we get reserve route all right
now
little billion algebra right now we have
multiple administrators and single
processes which after because one
person's
not gonna work 24/7 so we end up
with the Boolean or and the bullion or
says
either administrator a or be can do
whatever it is
this is the way we do things now
now when we have multiple administrators
having access to Route what happens
store security
years ago up or down it goes
down and there's a lot again math fell
far be happy to share all the map with
everybody
the security goes down significantly and
we use probabilistic
amassed simple calculus to do it to
determine the hard numbers
so this is where we are today and
we know it doesn't work in the
enterprise how many are there
I don't know the there's a plunge in
every companies gonna be slightly
different
so this comes into the factor of trust
him we're gonna look across the little
bit more
because currently we have a trusted
employee
but when you have a trusted employee do
you trust him
100 percent again a binary function that
word
using I trust him I don't trust him so I
give him
complete control or no control how do we
begin to solve this
well in a safety deposit box to use a
thing called a two-man rule
to different people with two different
keys after unlock
the contest and the two men rule works
pretty well
well now for a logic standpoint the two
men rule
isn't and Kate in Boolean speak and on
the topic
Rovers two levels of control
so in this case both administrator a
and administrator be have to both
approved whatever
the action is and it doesn't have to be
that mean it could be
anywhere from hold his work at the cold
level all the way up to BGP
the problem with this though is time
because while administrator a may say
okay I want this done administrator be
maybe out the launch he may be on
vacation he may not agree
there may be a dispute am
suddenly be attempted
make control change is not a fight it
does not work
so we have to find a way around this so
this gets back into trust trusting your
partner
you trust your partner with your life do
you trust your partner to write a check
without your approval banks use this as
well
the two men rule for fun major financial
services
and this is the world we live in today
so how do we getting around this by
looking at ross factors
currently most
human resources and hiring departments
and managers
do not use a matrix to look at how
trustworthy is somebody and this becomes
very important
when they're hiring if your gonna hire
somebody who is going to do some
really deep deep analytical holding but
he may not have access
to administrative controls does the
he need the same level of trust in the
system is somebody else
again we look at a binary yes or no
with out coming up with some of these
numbers
and these numbers can change throughout
the life cycle
that's why we had Robert Hansen and
aldridge ames
spies in the United States because being
security services in the FBI and the CIA
never really checked these guys as to
why they were spending millions of
dollars
so again they approached it from a
binary
static standpoint with no change at all
now we're gonna introduce a nother
concept before we start gluing this
together
and it's called feedback and in the
military its Colby Lulu
very simple observed koreans
make a decision and then
act and this was developed by Colonel
John Boyd in the nineteen eighties in
the United States
and it was done for aerial combat
the same thing applies to marketing
and sales I have a product idea
I'm in a test that out I'm gonna make a
decision to make
blue widgets and then I'm going to
really observe look again see how the
market likes
and changer and we call it squeezing the
loop
work I want that loop time
to shrink can get very very very very
small
the same way that I want my detection
time
and my reaction time to get very very
small
and in calculus terms it all this is is
a
limit function very very simple to be
able to work with
soul to squeeze the loop with what ever
process I'm doing
and if you want to apply defense in
depth concepts
there are some links that can be applied
and this is where it gets very
interesting with fractal analysis
and understanding the dimensions a pure
networks in again I'll help you with the
matter later on
now feedback is inherently analog
in the world I grew up in on the upper
left we've all heard squeals
when the microphone on the speakers in
any its feedback the device on the right
that as a mechanical governor to control
and regulate
the speed have been injured in this case
from steam engine from the 18th century
in the lower left it's an electrical
circuit
the fundamental circuit for all
analog circuits is negative feedback
controlled
in order to keep things from going what
we call
a runaway condition where things get
chaotic
when they do lose complete control
love the system sounds like
vigils networks that we're living in
today but in the analog world we solved
many many many years ago back in the
nineteen twenties
ICS industrial control systems
many of them users are sure how that
works in a little bit
the other component of feedback is
haptics
and we hear the new phones to that blows
their tactical you get it keyboard
Eagles click
you feel it on the new smartphones
sometimes they'll
vibrate a little too let you know what's
going on
we as humans require feedback and was
built into
every aspect nature builds and
every industrial control system every
piece 'em
analog electronics on the earth and it
works
but we don't do within networks
we don't do it in our world at all so
what we're gonna do here's take a very
simple example in this case
are we're gonna people use a password
forgot login
to something in all I'm saying at this
point is let's introduce
and analog feedback Lubinda my digital
processing so when
I make a decision I taken action whether
it's again a cold level administrative
level doesn't matter
all I'm doing is starting a flock a Mac
clock could be
3 milliseconds 3 microseconds
two days it doesn't matter it's a
decision
that has to be designed into the system
how long
do I require the time to be be four
somebody else
actually approves that primary control
choice
and this is the first step of making all
analog work in this case
we've got administrator a making a
decision
in the construction of the system
they've said a number
to be one hour where administrator be
tax to finally made the approval if he
does not do the approval
the original decision is taken back
and completely rescinded so
when we move this forward even into
greater levels we can do this at the
access control level we can do with the
cold choice level
we can do it in virtually any
environment now so you may notice in the
physical world
you go to your office open the door
but you have a security system see if
the 1 like hell to the closet open the
door and
entering the code within 30 seconds
perhaps
again we do it in the physical world
we know that it works but we don't do in
our world yet in all we're trying to do
is the look at it from perhaps an eye in
a mechanism standpoint it's the exactly
the same process
any access control mechanism will do the
same phone
and what we do is take this
and apply a fundamental did now the
fundamental bit
unit im Boolean logic
and indeed Electronix is how do I store
one believe information
either a0 or one the way it's done is to
the circus and it's called
are s flip-flop and there is the logic
tables for how it
works and very very simple concept ice
admin a zip-top he does the reset
or admin be can do with that and it
changes the output
digital this is the way we're doing
things right now
but why do if I take that same circuit
and I play a feedback loop that analog
to it what do I have
behind now have a new set of truth
tables serve truth tables that are
digital logic with the time base
component to it that it can be preset
in any environment we're living we're
dealing with in our digital world
that's the logic symbol for
that has been developed and there's the
truth tables for that gives us more
conditions and we had before because
certainly looked a little more complex
but all the enabling of this
is just part of setting up the risk
that you're willing to have in your
network based upon
exposure time and your detection and
reaction from
early on now how do we launch a new
again something we've been very used to
in many countries over the years and as
the two men rule
the circuit for the two men rule and how
that works
is this it's very very simple and
supplying how much do I trust
administrator a forces administrator be
to initiate a launch sequence
before the second guy can go yes I
approval no I don't approve
this is the fundamental circuits that
will
do this and we're having it coated now
and we're going to be giving it away for
free
for any woody to be able to apply for us
the next thing I want to do is a ticket
concept we used in the audio world
when digital audio began in the nineteen
seventies
traditionally as you saw on that earlier
circuit i'd have a volume control that
is correct
we in the circuit that matches what we
do today with TCP IP
my single level of communication the
TCPIP channel
goes over one physical transport level
and that same communication channel is
synchronous
but it has both data and the control
signal
back in the seventies we realized that
we already a world that's not gonna work
anymore when we're doing automation
so what we created was 'em our room
band mechanism to be able to very
the amount of signal that went through
any particular circuit
and an award function part of the great
part that occurs here
is that if my data
might audio signal dies okay I have lost
my audio
have lost my data that's fine bustle of
my control
if I lose my control signal because
is a fixed I would have banned control
into that circuit
I will not go into chaos it will remain
the same will not change until the
control signal
has come up and this is talking about
going
out-of-band Hanway get outer bands
circuitry to be able to work
and communicate where I don't have to
rely upon the TCPIP channel
to Dubai detection and reaction a
specially when we have hostile bad guys
wielding a de dos the tax somebody's
Aug major level defense that are
occurring
how do i do something about this well we
want to have
sometime based escalation and what you
notice in this very simple network here
is that there's some routing channels
but then you notice
there's a lot of sensors lotta sensors
anybody know how many sensors are
inside of a jet engine today
about 4,000
four thousand of them but
generate constant feedback i've
information
and generate between one and two
terabytes love
data sensor-based engine performance
data
every hour we keep the planes flying
using a very simple analog feedback
technique
and we use a concept that I said I
disagree
more and more with the concept the
defense in depth I am getting very
impressed with the idea of
detection in Dept we need
Bowl load more sensors in our networks
at all levels a all layers of the stack
all the way down and all the way up
through everything we're doing
and insight about the occasions as well
but order to do that as I mentioned
earlier we have to have a reaction
we have to know what we're doing if this
is gonna work
people have to be willing to plan out
and understand
how bad things can be and what should
occur
if we don't take this step and we allow
management to continue doing it the way
it's being done today we're going to
continue to fail
so there's lots of small elements to
make this all work we have a single
reaction channel
that's certainly possible we've got
detection and depth with multiple
reaction channels the same kind concept
and we take the same out a bank on Sep
and let's say we're doing this at BGP if
the ISP level
creating a out-of-band network
just for security just for security
will allow less than 2 have ISP's
talking to their peers in its peer to
peer conversations are not that many of
them
and be able to do honest to god
hacking back to the source and
mitigation
I love spam and hostile attacks at the
slow
it looks fundamentally like this I've
got my primary channel
data communication I'm using TCP API can
use it as a control signal
but when something goes wrong each one
of those points at the sensors
is gonna need to have a texan module
reaction module and then back to
but back-channel communication to out a
band
the other thing that we can do with our
circuits is something that back in my
day
we called negative time what if I
introduce a negative time
into some of my circuits when decisions
are being made
the negative time factor there's the
schematics for
these are not things that have to be
invented that these are things that have
to be
re fought and it's called introducing
intentional the ladies in the circuits
a few nanoseconds for the processing and
decision-making to be done
because if I know my detection and I
know my reaction time
that becomes exposure time if my
exposure time
is very very small because I've done it
right and I
had a little bit of negative time delay
what happens mathematically provable
security
mathematically provable security
and I'm very very much enjoyed being
able to talk to any view about this over
the next couple of days
the thing that reason I put this up the
math that's here
is very very close to the matter that
we've developed and
this is math for load balancing on
existing circuits are already doing
we do this for load balancing we do it
for traffic stability
in order to avoid chaos on certain or
circuits
we already have it we have just never
looked at it from a pure security stamp
so analog network security for me has
been an eye-opener
it allows me to look at the world in a
wholly different way
every time I have a discussion with
somebody I don't know what about the
time factor
what about time how was that he fit into
the equation
is up automatically brings in an an
award function
and not any longer looking for a purely
by Mary answer
these are the tenets these are the rules
these are the fundamental pieces though
I find to be exceedingly valuable
and I know that in 45 minutes I have not
done this justice
but I hope to have got you think maybe a
little bit that looking at the world in
a completely different way than we have
in the past
will offer us something up a path
forward
and I really hope to have an opportunity
to speak with the many have you
and for you to challenge me and for us
to discuss
how well some of these may work so I
want to thank you very much
welcome to hack in Paris and but all
have a ball this week