goodnight everybody
and me and my calling Alex are going to
tell you how to get full access to your
3G or 4G devices and do it only by SMS
so we are part of the estranged wife
team and
this research they took many many times
have we here and there were many people
who involved into this research not only
we there on the site and gas and in this
research we speak about 3G 4G network 3G
4G network is really very very complex
and big theme
that's why in this research we speak
only about taxes low and about
explosive devices these devices like
phones smartphones femtocells USB modems
use bureau tours of course about the SIM
cards and will speak not only about the
traditional radio access but also multi
IP access and IP access problems and
this research is done not only because
we use 3G 4G networks everyday for
social network for hiking staff and so
on but also been king
government
industrial companies used 3G 4G networks
every day and it is this Kara sparked so
radio part is really well research at
this moment there were very Koo research
of this people like alexander to missus
song they research a great
you guys and we will speak about their
IP network IP access and
about this device just sent you just
send is something like final point which
provide access to the internet from
their telecom and if this final point
and butyl internet also can be accessed
from the internet and they are if you
look in four wards like Jess and or
words like justice and model names like
alcatel-lucent you can found really many
many devices which can be accessed from
the internet
next possibility is to look for specific
GDP parts TCP or UDP and send the
specific GDP requests and wait for
specific responses and that's how we
found these devices on them all over the
world
from russia and China to USA and Canada
what's problem can problem is about if
you get IP address of judges and device
first of all you can look for their
specific management boards like SSH
Telnet get access to them and getting
side of telecom network next problem if
you compromised one judges you can
attack others just sense and other
telecoms with her parents home in
exchange protocol you can attack
UDP protocols due to be applications and
get the denial of service or still some
private information or still some money
and get the fraud or you can get inside
the private APMC here is an example of a
tech very similar to GDP since to
disperse include in our service but only
at the deeper level since millions and
millions PDP context activation requests
to the judges and in some moment of
requests is finished and the next
customers which
try to get access to the internet from
their phones simply cannot get access to
them next summer face of attack is when
you are inside the telecoms network for
example if you are simple subscriber
list of all you can get the internet
tried to use traceroute tour some
external board see some internal IP
addresses interests or table and try to
get access to them by some management
boards HTTP or ipv6 or UDP or some
specific telecoms protocols like GDP and
song and that's how we found this device
also just sayin also very big also very
expensive problem of this device was
that it gave us without any appreciation
private gibbons names what does it mean
means that if you know their private a
pen name you can change your APN name in
your phone and get access inside of
getting side of some private network
like banking network and or government
and something like a call from nineties
when your balance is negative you still
can get access to the Internet
by UD period class with Dennis to know
and song
internet providers pics dishonorable it
is maybe ten twenty years ago but they
are still present in mobile telecoms so
what can you recommend for telecoms of
course you should know what your devices
could be accessed from the internet you
should not forget that your subscribers
network are not your own trusted network
for auditors if you check oldest age
when you are is negative balance when
you enroll me when you are different
subscriber plan some song results may
surprise you but you should not forget
you cannot hide other subscribers it's
illegal
next fire is about the devices about 3G
and 4G USB modems 3G 4G modem it is not
only black box that you plug into your
computer to get the Internet it is
small computer of these operations
system file system arrays Linux or
Android on board which support many
interfaces like is the cards
management comports and so on and of
course part like remote network devices
and sometimes wifi this parts are also
really will research first of all
people research
feeling better result from this point of
view like how to update the firmware how
to change
customized if you wear or baseboard how
to unlock the device and so on and so on
but there were also some security
researchers in last day last year like
last year was found to be a decent
quality modems there were presentations
of regular account of how the four-way
modems problems and so on but most of
them were
have on the local impact and
we tried to get the remote impact and
here is the developers of Muslims we are
looked into but you should understand
that not all winner abilities along
store these firms because every telecom
company write their own
dashboards with their own
vulnerabilities and so on and they
security pass are also well known for
its disabled all the interfaces or
diagnostic parts leave only one web
dashboard with one button connect to the
internet but you'll see great enough to
have no matter what happens when I plug
in the device is that working to face to
the computer gives me new interface and
your IP address which by the city center
on the muslim side right some DNS
records open web is more than web rest
connect to the internet
maker old from my computer though there
internet through their telecoms network
and when i see UI be addressed first of
all I will stand for or concurrence
that's how sometimes you may find
something interesting like open
diagnostic Donaire and if you like it
you can also find the root password 10
get full access to the device but it's
not so funny
first of all because sometimes you found
nothing is modern was not so popular and
next problem is about that you cannot
exploit
melatonin abilities remotely
his brows are disclaimed browser this
why we decided to look into the web
service when their abilities that we can
exploit remotely first of all because
almost nothing or almost all web
services simply do not have some
protection like CSRF stockings and so on
and next to me will tell you also about
how to
how to attack the broadband part
communities we found many many in every
Muslims from the information leakage of
current base station I D to the
client-side client side burner abilities
like cross-site scripting cross-site
request forgery and so on
also willing to police about
authentication bypass like when you use
when you are being called is on and open
page recenter enough been called you
still can fight this window just and get
access for example to file system to
wifi then of course we will review this
you can change the
Dennis Ferrer to intercept the traffic
you can read and write the essay masses
and uses the requests read the contacts
and also look around they devised with
white rice can you mix the interesting
part was about how to get access to
self-service portal is SMS you send
success SMS found the browser of
subscriber
then sent uses the request to reset the
pass or intercept the music success and
get access to cell service portal also
very simply very simple denial of
service attack when you send requests
with invalid for this window then you
sent down invalid unlock codes and my
break from the SIM card or you simply
can't change the IP settings and also
bridge the device and finally last
couple of months we use the devices and
execution of these devices to turn them
to the spy devices here is first
about how to get full access or how to
get access to the software is part of my
ass mess here is winnable page as masses
here is my phone I sent by SMS and
receives sorry you need to update the
page to inject the code if you see the
source code found clinging to our
injected coat next we have some hikers
consul in another browser which
get the comment received the data about
modern section moment then we reset the
password by using request getting your
password
of course this semester we can hide and
send the password to the hacker to get
access to self-service portal it works
transparently to the client
ground and then they can delete this
message sent to all the data again next
problem is about all Muslims have fire
feel we're updating page some just hide
them in comments
some modems
have some protection like Syria c16 some
Muslims have some Muslims have
protection we scooped the functions but
we still can delete this crypt function
script and bypass their checking next
problem you need to get their original
theory to upload your purple coat and
but
you should not forget that most of all
web service on the muslims it's simple
CJI which get the video from the HTTP
requests and send them directly to the
shower without any checking this way you
can find the diffusion almost everywhere
in content land
heater in Austin GATT and song and of
course if you cannot exploit exploit
remotely content-length had you still
can exploit data platforms and those
parameters now we get access to the
modern
get the remote code execution what's
next
here is an example as I said how to get
your own make your own space device from
you can
there were 12 in russia they give us a
modern for 1 week for testing then we
can take them to the store you can get
the money you can
used for the collection remotely or
in fact the local in fact the system and
we script which sounds
current cellular base station by DNS
every minute or two to five minutes then
you can intercept HTTP HTTPS with Dennis
pushing and interests and SMSs if you
have a remote code execution and that's
how I walk in from from my home to
my work in moscow is the packet switched
on but you should not forget once again
do not like other subscribers I was
South how many modems
able and used the script on some
security portal in Russia to gather the
data research image recognizing for one
week we found more than 4,000 syllable
devices and for one or two requests we
can switch this statistics just basic
statistics to active vulnerable and
remote remote in Section muslims
ok we can change the fuel bears we can
attack the client's my SMSs by UCSD with
precise script increase aid request
forgery and so on
then we decide to pound subscriber first
better was if you have remote code
execution you can update their but also
come down and in fact the cost with and
installing the malware
recent study indigenous 22 but more
obvious fire is about making from your
USB modem USB modem like Carson said we
have as you may know use be have mister
safe architecture drivers are also split
two day device driver us and to the
house basis drivers they were not so
much problems which caused by the
drivers they are
standardized and you are so speak about
the device drivers or gadgets in Linux
terminology one device may have
different
interfaces and there is competition
driver framework for these devices as I
said many modems work on Android Android
kernel we have Android get the driver
very interesting gadget
driver something like a wrapper around
composition driver framework which
provide you interfaces and deals to
change their behavior of the modern in
runtime without restarting and general
budget that's how your phone can became
is the card or out the source and so on
here is proof of funds are available on
the Google Play it makes use became more
from your template but he's worried said
proof of concept first of all it meets
Hudak says then it needs some parts two
and a half maybe devices this white said
we decide to make our own
with USB driver for more than all you
need is to find supported functions
arranged
runtime find my by adding new human
interface device function to this array
restart the device and get the profit
but in real world
your first met some problems
first of all it's Carol do not have to
face device
gadgets by default that's why we need to
take them on board down there were
problems creating universal
human interface device driver of 44
every three modern problems with person
signatures with changing prototypes and
structures of expert functions and
problems of course with different
hardware it just means that you need to
fingerprint device before invasion it is
very big and
hard work but if you were good enough
you will get something like that
already infected vulnerable is modem
plug into the computer
get the new remote network device which
opens their browser by default then its
height or Abboud
and carries human interface device
keyboard appears and then some magic
without any fans entering the comments
like or you can reach the viewers for
loading from the USB stick then you can
restart the computer
wise
network interface
after restarting and predefined comments
once they reach their later the device
and load booting from USB storage to
infect the computer
reduce the next best thing about the
device in the device and get the company
and last couple of months we interested
in this device its way modern piece high
silicon chips served on board which have
some different one day we'll abilities
it's not the latest firmware maybe
but we found also take over flow and
possibility to blow to their February
motive but not the point point is about
someday my colleagues found some
interesting stuff about Linux on our way
below two weeks works a brain system
which works on base been brought to us
and work with radio parked there were
many many problems like a scene 12
commendations to GBP documentations
problems faced working in real time
operation system all the bargain was
correct but resumed that Linux
operations system load week's work
suppression system image by well-known
basil dress
you can update this way you can
update the bike and so on
weeks works weeks works have seen
something like operation system shelf
for some comments have well-documented
objects and functions this way again
weeks works quote almost to the white
coat and these possibilities we get the
rector attack to take baseband recalls
for poor people so for everybody do not
plug in the device into your mother and
your questions
some problem because so we're told this
is no time for the last part of the
presentation then I shall continue if I
make every device that are already
mentioned by tomorrow
small piece of plastic mould SIM card is
essential for the customer is something
that is used for just connecting to the
network and that's it but for sure its
own device controller with braking
system with its own file system with
application which allows you to access
network to manage keys and do very
different things on our SIM cards there
are applications for example when you're
buggin SIM card in your phone
there is there is a manual where can
access different products from the
from your operator for example different
different applications for managing your
contract and so every such applications
have its own ticket application
reference or tire for all applications
secure for example applications that
allow you to form your SIM card is
protected more thoroughly them
occasionally which follows your talk on
the to send us a message for for some
numbers so if you ever applications
predicted by its own key and if you're
lucky enough you can find something to
force it because these SIM cards are
made from nineteen nineties they have
this encryption to protect their
different opportunities for brute
forcing for example you have rainbow
tables for British friend applications
but actually some of the keys if you
have no time for all all different
applications on the SIM cards so you can
just build something YouTube workforces
reader comments you have CPUs and after
their planes of devices that will render
their former forcing its refugees so we
bought from the eBay some of them if he
sees that cost you for about two
thousand euros we managed to make it in
turn forcing device and opportunities to
give to us for example
22 1903 million or 33 thousand troops
process and our device is about 100
times faster for the patient but
actually you want to see in this sim
card you can send different comments
well where you say something and get
some different replies but there are
actually three different applications
for example cut manager that allows you
to reprogram your sim card on file
system applications that come our way to
access information manager is the holy
grail if you can have a program you can
get access to a graphic tees you can
cloning device do whatever you want but
there is actually no successful concept
for this so we mentioned to access file
system on the filesystem you have
difficulties but only session once they
are protected with pink coat four-digit
number that allows you to access it most
of the SIM cards iPhones are not
protected with it because the two you
can protected by swiping the iPhone
Unlock Code Red Code and so there is no
need for another protection but forces
in from the telecom network for the SIM
card you should have a bigger keys open
coat there is no fun with singing
locally so you can take home phone
and the masses to overturn number on the
telecom therefore if you don't have to
have you with us most centers that
allows you to send such minor s masses
to any number of miners message can be
fewer children but actually it's not the
keys for different operators there is
different opportunities for example
Internet communications internet for
communications and everything wrong you
can just use figured out some of the
cells to gain access to the phone
directly coat and operator said the PIN
code with 40 and easy to work for us
many number of phones with the four pin
code them to workforce one device with
many girls obvious way to block all
devices so we can just 30 mins masses
and to enter the PIN code and block
device but there is different you can
access current difficulties or and
current education number to call me
device from all over the world and
they're great problem is that operators
are
that all craters I think that it's too
hard to do and just ignore you I will
show small video that will be off
with this console access mobile and
access and connection to it on the right
we have not lost my phone iPhone we are
sending a sms from iPhone to see that
it's it's then we sent a 3-2
Nokia phone that gives us from it and
we're sending and resending burners mass
to get information number from it so
it's obvious that if all the devices are
not protected from these attacks are
also protected because these miners
masses are not protected with operating
system but directly connected to the
basement of the
the phone so we're sending from us
McComb ms to the iPhone and see that
it's not from the previous number but
from the one that's it