slow public always was and still is very
much in favor of the european union
membership so it did not change so much
after the break seat and i can call the
very recent public opinion poll which
said that more than sixty percent of
those of executions would vote for
remain and only something more than
twenty would vote for leaving the
european union so that means that still
european project is very popular and
failure going slovakia in spite of the
fact that of course within last three
four years we saw certain decline but as
I said still inside maybe majority of
public key sir for yes staying remaining
within the EU maybe to be more specific
about public opinion it's necessary to
add that today the support is Morgan for
more qualified but on the other hand
it's still a subject or based mostly on
a coma
and social benefits which European Union
brings to Sobek citizen so that means
these are earphones these are labor
market opportunities and jobs outside
the country much less it's it is based
on values on solidarity and on feeling
of solving common European problems
together it's one of the factors which
are responsible for that I see or among
the factors I see also the way how the
national political elites communicate
the agenda so that means that there are
pointing and you when something is
wrong and are taking the ownership if
there are some successes and maybe this
is not open euro skeptical rhetoric but
the increase in placentia accent or
implicit great line in the communication
is undermining support