thank you very much for inviting me
thank you for having me thank you for
coming to my talk I was wondering I mean
I'm very happy I'm not upstairs because
quantum encryption is far beyond my
capabilities
if French is beyond your capabilities
then you're in the right track
that's your P okay so usually I really
try to keep the ball flat and have
reasonable and modest titles now my wife
tells me I didn't succeed this time so
this is this might be a bit exaggerating
so probably not that a reasonable title
at all can we make a deal you hear me
out and at the end I'll ask you again if
it was reasonable and modest or not if
that's okay good
let's get formalities behind us boring
bio few people know that I have a
background in medieval history and as it
happens I used to run a medieval
reenactment company which was founded
exactly 30 years ago in Graz all very
close from evil but as it happens I
somehow ended up from this middle-age
thing into the IT security industry and
Here I am talking about denial of
service attacks now honestly I as you
see with this pack I don't have much
clue what I'm talking about so if I
don't really know why I ended up in this
program first place but if you could
just keep my background to yourself and
we'll see how this works
table of contents I'm going to do an
introduction to denial of service
attacks there are two reasons for this
first we need to be on the same page so
everybody should be on the same page
everybody should really have a clear
understanding with denial of service
attack so distributed denial of service
attacks is all about be the second
probably more honest reason is my slot
is 50 minutes and that's an awful lot of
time so by filling the time with an
introduction I can steal a bit of your
time sorry about that but please bear
with me I'm going to look into denial of
service trends
three of these strands that we have been
seeing up last few years are fairly
obvious others are not so obvious
actually not at all and I think there is
a game changer that few people have
noticed so far I'm going to explain this
and prove a point
traditional defense methods against
massive large-scale denial of service
attacks are hitting a limit I think so
we're kind of heading into a dead end
somehow and we need alternatives and
what I'm going to propose is an
alternative method to defend against
massive large-scale denial of service
attacks and of course such defense comes
with a few strings attached and as it
happens with this method that I'm
proposing one of the strings attached
could lead to the end of the internet so
so yeah it's a bold statement it's a
bold prediction and for your convenience
I added a craziness ohmmeter on the
right so you're an attentive crowds you
might have noticed this this talk is
starting in a fairly reasonable insane
level and it's getting more and more
crazy tomorrow at once I think there is
certain it's really building up there is
a certain line of argument in this but
maybe I'll leave you drop off along the
way and if you brought along Tomatoes
rotten eggs I propose you keep them for
the end of my talk where they're more
suitable then for the beginning but I
still hope you will follow my
organization you also maybe want to
follow me on Twitter because during the
talk I'm going I have scheduled a few
tweets that reference document documents
which I'm talking about in the talk and
I'm retreating one or two things during
the talk just so follow me on Twitter so
you catch those I'm not going to display
the URLs good when you when you take it
stock photos then the hackers always
wear hoodies if you do Creative Commons
photos you have a hard time finding a
hacker with a hoodie Creative Commons
but I I really searched long and I hope
you appreciate that he is actually
wearing a hoodie took me a long time to
find a Creative Commons photo with a
hacker with the reviews but what a slide
is all about it is CIA
now CIA is not only American Secret
Service Foreign Secret Service it also
refers to an acronym which you certainly
know it's confidentiality integrity
availability this is what security boils
down to in the inner core what we do in
security is we try to guarantee
confidentiality integrity and
availability there is this saying that
you can only have two so there are three
in this acronym but you can have two
lucky enough denial of service attacks
are only about availability so we take
confidentiality integrity granted and
the attackers will only attack
availability do you do I have you with
me do you agree on that denial of
service attack is about availability of
a service I see a few nodding hats now
let's assume that everybody is in the
boat good so what is the denial of
service attack targeting it's generally
targeting three targets in a very broad
sense first you have bandwidth on the
right so it targets bandwidth basically
bang with is the pipe that runs into
your server it runs into your service
into your cloud now the cloud may sound
like an endless supply of bandwidth but
actually that's not quite the case
bandwidth in the cloud isn't closely
rate-related or it maps one-to-one to
your bank account so filling the pipe
running into your cloud means taking out
money of your bank account so even if
you're in the cloud under the line at a
certain moment you will need to
push to stop up which is you can no
longer support or finance the
denial-of-service attack it's my
reasoning here somehow proving that
you're able to serve the content that
you're able to respond to the requests
or the packets that flow into your
network is somehow related to a
proof-of-work I mean the attacker
attacks you and you're proving him yes I
can respond I can respond I'm still
available
I maintain availabilities I'm still
serving my service you cannot kill me
somehow this is a proof of work with a
lot of friction there is a lot of heat
there is a lot of data flowing around
without serving a purpose somehow it's a
proof-of-work like crypto money just you
prove that you're able to do something
and you attack or you affect global
warming somehow so this is DDoS defense
men and it a bandwidth or CPU attack
hits you is like crypto money without
the coins somehow just extremely
expensive to defend against the second
target so outside of the network is CPU
often it's very hard to distinguish
instance now a band with the tag or is
this GPU attack in in practical world
doesn't really matter too much just they
try to kill you and you try to stay
alive somehow
so CPU is a is always involved - very
often involves and it's involved in
places and very small bits of CPU where
you're not really expecting it so a
threeway a tcp/ip handshake involves cpu
maintaining a TCP session or an
application session for its end is
involving CPU a firewall doing stateful
inspection of incoming track traffic is
cpu-based and the Web Application
Firewall that's my domain that's what I
usually work on when I'm at doing
medieval stuff for not doing data
Theodore's defense a Web Application
Firewall is filtering based on regular
expressions and that involves a lot of
CPU so that's all CPU ice swimming pans
extremely X
pensive and least if not all a TLS
handshake an encryption handshake is a
lot of CPU a lot of calculation so
that's a lot of work and then finally we
have storage with storage I'm not only
referring to this I will refer to
storage in a very broad sense so we have
bandwidth that's the pipe we have the
brain of the computer CPU and we have
the memory the storage the ROM the disk
space but this in a broader sense the
TCP connections are a form of storage
because you need to keep them up it's a
resource that you have a limited
resource port numbers are limited on a
server threats processes are limited on
a server I'm working with web servers
mutexes semaphores are resources namely
of the Apache web server that's all nd
are limited you don't have an endless
supply of these a DDoS attack tries to
eat them up so an attacker can try to
eat up resources from his part he can
try out all the resources where you have
a certain limit and where he is able to
directly consume them or indirectly
that's what this is all about in a
denial of service attack you have a
single client it's staggering how much
mayhem that a single client can actually
provoke or cause but in a distributed
setting you just have hundreds of
thousands of them doesn't make things
much easier when you face an army of
hundreds of thousands good let's look
back at DDoS attacks in Switzerland in
the early years we had online shops so
around 2000 2005 online shops in
Switzerland would attack each other they
would DDoS each other to bomb the
competition out of the business CEO of
one of the early online shops told me
that and that was affecting business
like like for everybody and they said we
finally we met into a bar we drank a few
beers in the sidewalk look let's stop
this madness
let's stop killing each other and this
is off the table now and he said that
actually succeeded it stopped
immediately when they all
let's stop the dancing each other of
course this was years before a law
enforcement criminal prosecution found
out what details even exist so if they
would went to the police completely
sensible no point
so they sorted this out amongst
themselves blue in chat servers were
famous for being DDoS constantly in the
holidays
World of Warcraft clients very nice
target if you'd battling with your
friends or enemies and then you DDoS
their client then you win the battle
that's a lot of fun
I'm sure online poker sites wonderful
during a poker game high stage you DDoS
the server and you don't lose stuff like
that happened a lot in Switzerland it
came to public attention or details came
to public attention in 2010 with so
called Operation Payback
though is not familiar with that attack
there was one Swiss pose or riposte
financed to be honest announced publicly
that they're stopping doing business
with Julian Assad from WikiLeaks
immediately I did not of service attacks
today as it happened I used to be on a
server during that moment I used to be
in the server being under attack there a
couple of videos where I talk about this
at security conferences what happened
and yeah of course it was a huge snail
of service attack they had Swiss Post
that anonymous come after them
like literally minutes after the press
release and I think post fan has learned
it the hard way that it's not a smart
very smart business move to talk to the
media about your customer relations
especially not if the customer is very
close to anonymous or his WikiLeaks
system so this this was immediate attack
a couple of years ago the attacks on
proto mail started I think this is still
ongoing 2018 protomans law Mourad in all
of service attacks and 2016 we have a
campaign targeting big attack
coop shop the online shop I think
targeted Swiss trains as well this was
an extortion attack and probably a few
other shops I don't really remember
Celeste that has been a bigger campaign
targeting several businesses and
everything it's been mostly silent
Switzerland why is it being silent I
think in 2016 and 2017 we have learned
that extortion is much more effective
via ransomware so organized crime
interested in gaining money online
we are criminal activities they resort
to ransomware now this is a direct link
and this is easier than sending an email
to somebody a look we're going to take
down your business unless you pay just
prove your point by encrypting all their
files that's a lot easier I think that's
why we haven't seen denial of service
attacks for the last two years but
looking back at this you'll see post
fine has been a vandalism attack this
wasn't extorted this was just your
assholes and you mess with Julian
Assange and we're coming after you
so vandalism is not interested in
gaining money they're just in for the
destruction we protonmail the case is
not as clear as that this might have
been a random attack yet there were
rumors about extortion as well maybe
it's just a teenage kid that did is for
the first time what is a huge attack and
what protonmail did they they went under
the umbrella of a denial-of-service
defense company and that's very typical
so they had somebody who supports them
with their online availability post
finance on your hand when I was on the
server we defended differently yeah the
first leverage was talking to the
management and tell them what is
happening tell them don't go to press
ever again and then let's do geoip let's
say we're only talking to Swiss IP
addresses anymore because this is a
global anonymous attack and to moment we
start to to only talk to Swiss customers
yep thank you we only started siscon the
attack will be over immediately and of
course with Swiss pose or space was fine
and said no we cannot do this we cannot
cut international customers they look
it's like the only thing we can do and
let's do this and after 10 minutes the
attack will be over and talking to
management took like a day and then they
finally agreed and then after 10 minutes
the attack was over because the attacker
would say yeah it is still down and then
somebody in the chat room we've been in
with the attackers in the chat room
that's IRC that's moderate so you're in
the chat room with the attackers the FBI
is probably there CIA and whatnot and
and they say yeah they're still down and
then somebody says with a very Swiss
name no they're up and then they go
how's that oh that's very stupid the
attack is no longer effective let's go
to Sweden and attack somebody there
that's what happened then it was over
so that's how sue suppose defended in
pro team element under your umbrella big
attacks with trains etc I think they
went under an umbrella as well generally
these umbrellas that's a very customer
oriented business you don't have to
prepare anything's then you're under
attack you pick up your phone could you
help me and say yeah just fill out this
form and we protect you and after 15
minutes the attack is over and afterward
you get a little small bill and usually
that's an annual renewed service yeah so
so that's how this dead noodles defense
business works nowadays and generally
you see extortion and you see vandalism
and the texts usually either of the two
important to notice probably it's
extremely hard to do criminal
prosecution here why is that
and the person interested in attacking
you is not hurting its own botnet to
attack you of course they don't do that
there is denial of service as a service
denial of service and sorry service fee
so do s as a service you go that you
fill out an IP address
and hit attack them and then you enter
your Visa card and they have very good
customer relationship management well
they're really interested in your as
satisfaction so they bomb somebody until
it really goes down if they have the
capabilities and the criminal
prosecution is extremely hard because
the person running the botnet is not
residing within Switzerland and the
person who runs the botnet and online
server is there all not in Switzerland
probably and unless you you're able to
just dump somebody with a smoking gun
because he has written the stupid email
send me money to my Swiss bank account
it's very hard to keep wholesome of an
attacker
I think and somebody correct me if I'm
wrong there hasn't been a conviction in
Switzerland outside of the few cases
where there really identified himself in
the emails and they made stupid mistakes
and then they call them really if you do
this properly nobody will ever find you
good there is a report or a document and
explanation from the Federal Office of
Civil Protection Switzerland they did a
scenario on denial of service attacks
around 2012-13 the report is published
and I just treated to link it to that
one that is fairly interesting because
the Swiss offices for protect Civil
Protection they're really thought it
through into detail what happens if
Switzerland as a country becomes under
attack that's a really good and
interesting document Melanie as so the
federal reporting now analysis center
for information assurance they're doing
annual reports are think two reports per
year and they're always covering denial
of service attacks so if you want to
learn about the history of denial of
service attack the size of them within
Switzerland
these reports are really important are
really good in 2017 Melanie also a
Shinto warning that several financial
Institute's were being extorted with
denial of service exhort
and unlike ransomware it should be noted
it with ransomware it makes sense to pay
I mean your files are lost you pay a few
bitcoins you can be quite expensive
nowadays you pay a couple of bitcoins
and then you get your files back and
then you finally fix your backup and the
next time you're no longer victim to it
extortion we have ransomware with the
Nile of service attack is different when
you pay then you've just proven the
point that you're willing to pay to stay
online I mean that's like an invitation
to ask for more money the next time so
there is more to say about a night of
service attacks in in Switzerland the a
voting is an important topic and now in
Switzerland I don't know if you follow
the news but the fierce critics of a
voting have made it very clear that they
see denial-of-service attack as an
interesting proof of point that Evo ting
is weak and should be abandoned there
shouldn't be a vote in Switzerland and
they've called for attack if somebody do
a denial-of-service attack of a voting
I've just retweeted a tweet where they
proofed is you can search for the
hashtags DDoS and e-voting so it's all
you find dozens of teachers good so we
haven't seen much DDoS recent one to
three years in Switzerland but it could
be back at any time either for vandalism
or for extortion
trends growth is the first trend it's
it's a no-brainer
you can you can call it Moore's law
whatever DDoS is on the rise it's
getting bigger nowadays we see massive
DDoS attacks above one terabit per
second of data and that that's like
really a lot unless you're a global
player you're not swallowing a terabit
i'll spend with my suppose maybe you do
in your basement limbs are probably not
botnet botnets
rely on IOT devices nowadays I mean
Damir I bought there two years ago was
running on
vulnerable webcams sounds very stupid
build it up 200,000 webcams attacking
you and they haven't even been very
sophisticated which is good enough to do
several hundred gigabit per second of
data and it's been two years ago there
are more more IOT devices nowadays in
fact the growth of the network capacity
of the carriers is much slower than the
tremendous growth of IOT devices so
they're sold like candy or given away
like handy nowadays and carriers really
have to invest into infrastructure so
this this is these two lines are no
lying a meeting think it deals attack is
getting more fierce all the time and
carriers have a hard time catching up
with the development and I think this
effects the biggest of carriers now and
if it's not now it's in a couple of
years
IOT is a major driver for large he
doesn't pass and I mean imagine the
situation it would be extremely
embarrassing for a Swiss bank to fall
weak to him to a denial-of-service
attack carried out with the help of wife
where wireless enabled toasters for
example I feel like I mean it could
happen anytime the question is why is it
actually not happening I mean the
various options my personal idea is know
was interested in vandalizing Swiss
banks and if you do then you're probably
really having a law enforcement behind
your back but then you are only
extorting victims that are likely to pay
and I don't think that a Swiss bank is
going to pay you to stay online they
will try everything but they're not
going to pay I mean a bank paying a
robber is out of question I think that's
why we're not seeing posters attacking
Swiss banks and I think that's the only
reason we're not seeing posters
attacking suspects
good second friend application-level
and traditionally that tradition we've
seen the denial of service attacks on
the network
two months in fluids ICMP floods famous
teardrop attack on Windows servers
reflection attacks carried out via UDP
is like I attack him and with his IP
address and then the victim he attacks
him and he goes down in a reflection
attack and this can be combined with
amplification where I do a very small
package and then as the victim gets
thousands of packages returned so that
that's extremely dangerous but its
inherent built into these protocols and
it's not always clear if this is really
Network base anymore of its if it's
application base it's hard to tell
sometimes but it practical it doesn't
really matter it's just it's an attack
and somebody's supposed to die in this
so the the largest amount of attacks are
still network based traditionally their
network based and application level
attacks are slowly growing it's an
extremely slow trend that's been growing
like ten years and I think maybe it's a
fifth or a quarter of the text or
nowadays application level the rest is
still network base why is that there are
two reasons I think it's extremely
simple to do in our network base it an
idiot can really do this because it's
inherent to the protocol you just fire
and you guns and it's also very very
simple to do the OS as a service because
the customer forms is just an IP address
and if your customers don't know with an
IP addresses then you can have them fill
in the domain name a host name and then
press attack that's all it takes with
application attack it's also extremely
simple to do this but let's say it takes
five minutes of research because you
need to tailor the attack a wee bit to
hit the application service you want to
attack so that would demand a huge
change in the customer interfaces of
denial of service providers and that's
not happening why it's not happening
it's not necessary network based denial
of service attack still work so why
would they change the game
that's why application level attacks are
very slowly rising
but let's say we face such a an
application-level attack and we need to
defend it I'd like to play this through
with you for a couple of minutes because
I think it's important to understand you
understand what really happens so I have
here a request
this goes to example that come I don't
know if you read it at the back that's
an envelope an IPM lab whatever going to
example come I have my Swiss Army knife
with me and I can open the ml up now and
look inside Network attack would be one
of the outer envelopes and the envelopes
wrap around the payload what do we have
in here oh we have TCP session yeah TCP
session yeah that makes sense on the
Internet well let's open the TCP session
what do we have inside TCP session
bloody hell
oh we have an IP packet yeah of course
him this was I had this coming
we have an IP package okay we're now in
the domain of stateful inspection that's
what a firewall is doing it has to look
inside this somehow so oh no no no this
is marios car this is an audit this
Russian doll veronik SSL TLS encryption
oh no fuck let's take rip this traffic
we need to look into this see what we
have in here oh yeah we have an HTTP
request it supposed to log in do with
the hostname example that come yeah yeah
if you know by HTTP that's how it looks
like but it's still no payload yeah so
let's see if we're at the final stage
open this one as well yeah we have a
payload yes we have a login we have a
username Christian and the funny
password so if you want to inspect
application level levels denial of
service attack you have to open all
these packages you need to look inside
and then decide I don't know if we have
a user called Christian we need to look
it up in the directory and that's an
awful lot of work to do and if you want
to defend an ends denial of service
attack you want to do this in the edge
of your network so suddenly the edge of
the network needs to know all the user
in the directory and
that's really annoying you need to take
denial-of-service into the consideration
when you construct your architecture
because once you've filled your network
then it's too late
and this means denial of service is
really important for all of you even if
you're only hitting and I are being hit
with a lot of service every couple of
years you need to think about this from
the beginning and of course it's not a
single letter it is coming with a the
problem the problems there are lots of
these packages I mean they're probably
ten thousand hundreds I've brought a few
of them and it's read an avalanche
that's coming after you and attacking
you and you need to open all these
packages to defend against and that's a
huge amount of work and that's really an
issue and if we continue with the third
trend like six eight years ago SSL EPS
was created and this made encryption
available for the rest of us
Alice dumped medievalists we don't know
encryption they were we learned how to
defend with this and then let's encrypt
came and gave us certificates for free
wonderful but as you've to see if we
want to defend against encryption
encrypted application layered defense
then the device doing the protection for
the device Phil thing for us needs to
decrypt the service so the device needs
to be unknown it needs access to the
keys and that is I think the game
changer here when clear text traffic
anybody can filter with encrypted
traffic the device filtering needs to be
in the known about the encryption and
that's making this extremely dangerous
this plays together all these trends
play together this is the rise of the
content delivery networks content
delivery networks are global they're
decentralized somehow so
you used to run your server in your
basement for your friends or in your
local company in your institution and
that was kind of centralized you had one
server to run or a little server farm
and and nowadays this globalized the
content delivery networks they put your
server in a global context and then
Japanese customers they're no longer
coming to your server directly they're
being served in Japan so this works
thanks to anycast Network technology
this is a decentralization of traffic
and it reduces latency it's really very
good and it increases bandwidth because
these networks are specialized to serve
on the quick so they're extremely fast
and you don't have to mess with static
on thing anymore because they are
hosting the static content for you
globally and your customers will love it
because it's a lot faster so that's
great unfortunately this also comes with
a few strings attached let's look at
this quote from Matthew Prince's hero of
CloudFlare one of the CDN services in a
not so distant future if we're not there
already it may be that if you're going
to put content on the Internet you'll
need to use a company with a giant
network like cloud frere that's him
Google Microsoft Facebook Amazon or
Alibaba
are you scared because this shit this
scares the shit out of me it says you're
no longer able to host the web server
yourself you need me to deliver content
on the Internet
I think that's really scary let's
continue this is damien mentioned from
google he's one of the person running
DDoS defense for google and when i
talked to him at usenix enema conference
two years ago almost two years ago here
we go
like within two three years that we only
be 2 to 3 players in the world are able
to withstand the biggest DDoS attacks
and protect websites on a global scale
so it's not the only six or eight
companies able to do this No
is actually a consolidation happening
and at the end of this consolidation he
thinks two or three down the road years
down the road he told me two years ago
so go figure there will be only two or
three players left who were able to
guarantee your service to remain online
and now let's connect the dots here and
this is what Paul vixie said in 2017 at
a public workshop in Zurich I think
we're going to see a future where people
will accept to pay money in X or ssin
they will accept to pay money when
they're extorted Alif service it will be
part of the cost of doing business as an
alternative there will be a handful
expensive services that can protect you
from DDoS attacks and these services
effectively control what new startups
will be allowed to operate on to the
Internet this falls down to if you're a
startup and you're targeting Google with
your service Google has the power to
shut you down when they push you out in
the rain away from the protection
umbrella that the modern Syrians are
guarantee meaning these networks have a
tremendous amount of power now with the
big big denial of service attacks
they're here to take you down and a
startup is not able to pay the extortion
money and it is unlikely to be able to
pay for the protection services and I
think that's very very dangerous city
and his limits you need to integrate
your service into the CDN I've given you
the example of a login request and
obviously CloudFlare does not have
access to your directory so if cloud
firm needs to understand if a certain
user is part of your directory somehow
they cannot do this that's very
difficult
they have means to tackle this they're
very good like dynamically put in a
CAPTCHA oh this is a login request
that's fair enough
but first fill out the CAPTCHA and the
toaster is unlikely to be able to fill
out the CAPTCHA so that that's actually
fairly effective it's an effective means
but one of limits obviously you need to
give decryption key to one or three five
seven global companies so if if the
attack is encrypted if you want
protection from CloudFlare you need to
keep your keys to CloudFlare there are
there are schemes for keyless SSL via
CloudFlare somehow know this limits the
exposure of your key but you still
handing them over the key you give them
control over the treci and let's go back
to CI a confidentiality integrity
availability ice at the beginning denial
of service only effects availability no
that's no longer the case the moment you
want global scale protection
confidentiality goes down the ditch
because you're handing over decryption
keys to global service provider and the
service provider is not a Swiss company
the jurisdiction is no longer schools I
think that's a huge thing there is an
alternative protection geoip like I said
it's wit post finance defended like this
it's extremely effective means of
defense if you have a local customer
base as it happens Switzerland there's a
local small country most companies have
only Swiss customers or 90% Swiss
customers and during an attack you say
yeah I'll concentrate on the Swiss IP
addresses ah there is collateral damage
or foreign customers too bad but this is
effective and in half an hour we'll be
right back to serve international
customers as well that's how do white
people's and devices are very well and
able to do geoip nowadays firewalls
routers you just go as a pull down menu
and if there is no pull down menu it's
easy to implement this yourself we are
an ACL and exit control list as it
happens in ipv4 they're like a couple of
thousand Swiss autonomous systems or in
the ripe database you can count solid
eight this with
of Excel if you need you and then fill
this interior router and Europe and
you're all so the kind of works and this
gives you total control over the traffic
and lets you it's really effective and
it's a way of retaining availability for
your local customers while maintaining
confidentiality and integrity you can
say you give up a international
availability for the duration of the
attacks whilst maintaining
confidentiality and integrity and this
is very important for certain businesses
I mean an online shop problem doesn't
care too much but banks will care about
this in government government services
ego will rely on keys remaining is
Whitson I think it's out of question
that Swiss government will hand over SSL
keys to a US company as to order a
passport personally think that's
unlikely so I think they will likely
have to work with a geoip scheme VoIP
has limits of course I would say if we
take you know this photo if you take the
inauguration of Donald Trump then there
was a large crowd of people gathering in
Washington but I'm sure that the Swiss
come would have been able to withstand
an attack by the Trump crowd but this is
the different image that's the Obama
crowd so that's the Obama inauguration
as we all know this has been more people
and I'm pretty sure evolve them
smartphones on this photo would wage an
attack on Swisscom Network far beyond
one terabyte of data switz on would go
down system would go down switch
carriers are not able to send gy p
doesn't work anymore because the tube
running into the first defense device
the core router on the access gateway
will go down the Delpy the pipe will be
clocked and this doesn't work anymore
so we need something new and this is
where my new proposal comes in local
route announcements BGP is the routing
protocol of the internet it's been
around for 20 30 years
it isn't extremely smart but it has a
few options which are
interesting and I'm not a network
engineer but I'm proposing I haven't
tried this out myself
I talked to quite a few network
engineers and they say yeah you that
could probably work but I haven't tried
this out myself and I don't know anybody
who has tried this out myself
but in the course of my talk I think
there is a certain and the way the
ability this has to come for somebody
will do this or will have to do this
maybe a voting providers will have to do
this one day our ego of sites will have
to this way how does it work what you do
is you based on the fact that the ISPs
in Switzerland they're peering with one
another like almost all Swiss IO ISPs
are peering with all the others with
ISPs let's say that's the community of
rel interlink the ISPs in Switzerland
and now the beach be a protocol has a
flag which says look here I'm giving you
a route to direct traffic to my a s to
my autonomous system but please don't
propagate this room this is only for you
this is only for your customers don't
propagate it beyond your network so this
would mean that the autonomous system is
route about from within the group of
fears
so Swiss ISPs will be able to route the
traffic to a Swiss service and everybody
outside like all the attackers and
unfortunately also a couple of
international customers or users are no
longer able to route it meaning the
attackers with their huge botnets are
not able to direct the traffic to
actually hit the victim residing within
Switzerland now this has as interesting
effect of course I still think the
attack would be over fairly quickly it's
no longer effective you might have a
couple of Swiss attackers Amanah botnet
zombies residing in swittel but that's
not so much of a problem because you
have a phone number for the ISP and you
you ring them up and say look you have a
few toasters attacking me could you stop
these toasters please I
think that would work fairly well
especially if you government and that
should be okay and solvable but other
strings attached have to do I mean you
you're dividing up the network somehow
aren't you I mean the Internet is a
global network and here you're
introducing gaps like like GU IP you you
you setting up borders on the Internet
some of you say I'm only peering or
routing friendly IP addresses of ISPs I
know ISPs under my own jurisdiction I
remember mark Haines our from the men on
the Secret Service branch of Melanie
saying or stating quite clearly IP
address space is not Swiss territory but
with the digitalization becoming more
and more important Switzerland and eGolf
being quite a thing and one day we'll
have an electronic air ID card then this
digital world this virtual world is
becoming more and more important and I
think Swiss government this common
services they will have to come back to
this statement and update it and state
yes IP address space Swiss online
services are part of our territory and
if they declare it is then they will
have to defend it and this will mean
that the Office of Civil Protection will
come up with contingency plans to
support Swiss companies to stay online
during the Nile of service attacks and
Switzerland and this mechanism I just
explained that it's the same borders and
this could be one of the means that
they're proposing and I don't know if
you've noticed but let's bring the
second national cyber strategy for
Switzerland was a was released or
confirmed by the federal government and
the first time the Army is now part of
the game so you see the national cyber
strategy used to be civil but now the
Army's at the table as well I mean it's
not they don't have the first seat at
the table but they're they start to talk
about this in the army too
so I think we need to pay attention to
this this is a big development and the
more important the utilization becomes
the more important defenses like this
will become and I think it is likely
that we might see it is maybe held even
Switzerland for a different government
trying this out one day or the other and
this will mean to cut off the National
autonomous systems the national IP
address is the national IP address space
from the rest of the internet for at
least a duration of an attack and
depending on the duration of the attack
that there is a widening crack between
this island off the internet and the
global Internet and this could lead or
one of the trends which might lead to
the so-called balkanization of the
internet so the division and cutting a
part of the global Internet and this I
think is one of the reason by
denial-of-service attack is extremely
dangerous and bloody interesting on top
of it
thank you for attendance
if you jump of tougher than I thought
she does on a little taller post you
know the kiss Giovanelli moly its
Jadakiss John yeah you talk about the
fact that in two and three year we all
need to use Google Alibaba to connect
when you serve a web service what can we
do to not do that
whoo I think it's extremely hard to come
back on the trend I think the content
livery networks are so strong now and
they really provide a service I mean
they do have a very strong business case
so I have a hard time seeing through
this have you heard of the Zion project
that's a Swiss alternative network
architecture this has been developed
within Switzerland's they're going out
now they want to make this into an
official RFC and they say they have
they've develop a protocol may you have
more control over the routing with PGP
you just control your peers and then
what the peers are doing is out of your
control with the Zion routing protocol
you get control who come who routes how
to use service and I've talked to this
guy or one of the these guys is is that
a response to this problem and he said
yeah he thinks Zion could be a solution
to this I'm not understanding nearly
enough should we see if that is a
solution outside of that I'm really
pessimistic I see the power of the CDN
is huge nowadays and denial of service
attacks I mean if the toaster is of the
world they're coming after you you have
a hard time with your local server sorry
about that
hey thank you oh the other question
here in front I just want to share and
see what you say you said like Swiss
banks are not being attacked today so
you saying I don't want to misquote you
this is the only thing yeah I can't
really tell okay because what is
happening here I was going in the wrong
direction okay just want to the sum up
we have done this you see the sources
contacts are yeah I think Swiss banks
but post finance was definitely attacked
back in the diamond ever not really a
bank yeah
others banks might have been attack or
they have been attack I'm not really up
to date anymore
certainly no big bang went down in the
US and it wasn't in the news I don't
think they went down a Sicily but I
think this might be underreported or not
report at all it's not as the interest
to report a thing anyway to the first
place and especially under certain
certain amounts they won't even report
to the police because you know it's just
is pocket money for some banks right for
a few thousand a few hundred thousand
yeah I mean you you have a point there
that they would have white getting to
the media but then who cares the moment
it is effective it will be in the medium
and we haven't seen this so maybe they
defend maybe they even pay something
they perish but I think payment I mean
if if they pay the sums are getting
bigger and bigger and bigger and at a
given moment is the market because it's
like this is a market like you criminals
they won't go into asking millions
because they know at this point you know
secret sources would be involved so they
asked for sons like Bank say yeah that's
it you know we next time we touch your
stuff and that's it you have a point but
why go after a bank when you can go get
by the Swiss online shop that's you yeah
yeah probably I think it's more likely I
know small businesses in shuttle getting
act actually yeah it's it is really
coming and when you depend 100% on
online business then you likely to pay
because they're going to kill you yeah
III think the Melanie reports are really
through and I'm really convinced that
Melanie would know if this would happen
and I think they would certainly not
name
the company but they would make it
transport that this is happening so it's
an to alarm everybody that this is
happening and they haven't reported on
that and their relationship as far as I
can see is fairly close with the core
infrastructure providers and so it's
alone so I think this is not happening
but what do I know I'm a medievalist in
yet let's take a final one there thank
you for a presentation I'm just trying
to making the dots between what you
mentioned regarding CDN right yes then
the recommendation on the BGP local yes
announcements okay yeah and the way that
Switzerland is doing business page it
basically Switzerland is making business
by export so yeah that is the problem
there yeah I mean it this has to play
into the architecture say does this
really need to be centralized this is
have to be the same website that's why I
said you Nene need to think about this
that was I released a tweet during the
talk where I have a guide what you could
think about when you set up your
architecture and then the defense
ideally it's only temporary like for
half an hour I mean important business
is not lost in half an hour and then the
attack usually goes away when you employ
typ other than that yeah that's a real
real problem I mean we're an export
oriented nation and cutting our foreign
traffic is painful but but then I see
this as a standard industry company they
don't have that much of a problem
handing out during trips keys but for
government it's out of way out of league
so and I think there is a distinction
and government first and foremost has
local citizens that they address if
through that with e-voting there is an
irony in the fact that the voting is
being proposed for international as with
voters and they might be cut off if this
scheme is being adopted of course but
then voting periods is one month and it
would say yeah we're down today we're
coming back tomorrow
it happens picking up for me that is the
solution the proposed solution is good
if you do business with the government
let's sort of say yeah that is a lot
easier yeah thank you oh no mercy Anka
Christian thank you very much