so thanks for having me if I'm not
talking clearly that's because my beard
is too big probably and its disturbs to
microphone so I'm gonna talk about nail
in the cello keystore coffin so those of
you who are already freight that I'm
going to show Java code don't worry
there is no Java code in my presentation
so everyone should be fine so um about
me and us
so I'm actually my name is Tobias Oswalt
and I'm working as a security analyst as
a pen tester at Mott zero
we're a small company but hopefully a
little bit known in Switzerland by now
we're doing it for quite a long time we
have a very specialized group of people
working at Mott zero I've been doing a
lot of different research so I love to
use a proxy a write extension for it I'm
also doing a lot of Android and AFL
fuzzing and Java fuzzing and my next
talks can probably going to be about
Java fuzzing but this one is about the
different topic so material as I said we
do security analysis what's a little bit
special is that we also do a lot of
hardware analysis not only software and
the content I'm going to talk about
today is the purpose of and mechanics of
key store files so why do we use key
store files at all and just to say it
already so Java key store that's
actually a name for the API in Java so
we have different kind of key store
types but the entire API is called Java
key store but one of the types the
oldest type is also called jks which is
the acronym so kks is the file type and
java key store is the entire API and
Java key store has more than just check
yes
so we talk about key store types as well
and the purpose and the mechanics of
java key store and and especially that
file type take s then we're gonna look
at the weaknesses sent cracking so i'm
where the security conference here can
only look at the file format i also
tried to break it and at the end i'm
going to talk a little bit about the
recommendations and what you can do so
to start with I hope you're a little bit
familiar with private keys and public
keys and how as a metric crypto works as
a small refresher so there's a private
key so you generate keys for yourself
you have a product private key and a
public key and the private key is called
private because you want to keep it
private and secret and not give it to
anybody else so not what adopt it so as
you see here in the middle of the
picture using you see beginning PGP
private key so other ones did a mistake
and publish their PGP private key on
their website so this is not how it
works you don't want to publish your
private keys you want to keep them
secret within your organization so a
symmetric crypto s set consists of a
public key and a private key and as a
user I want to store them somehow right
but I want to store them securely so I
put them into a keystore file so that's
just one file on our hard disk in the
end and put it on the hard disk now to
make it secure I want to encrypt this
data that is in that file and I do that
with the password so I I supply a
password it uses some encryption
mechanism and my private key and public
keys are safe so without knowing the
password you should be able to access
those keys now that's the use of you in
Java you have different options as said
before we have jks as a format which is
the oldest format but we also have an
entire list of other formats you can use
now I'm going to talk about the first
one today and the weaknesses of the
all this one to JK s now JK s is
actually used nearly everywhere where a
symmetric crypto is used so it's a
default format in Java before version 10
and it's also in all Android versions so
it's used a lot so just to tell you
where it's used for example that this is
just a very small list of examples
Oracle databases store their keyless
keys in J Case Files Apache Tomcat as
well
and when you do a new Android app you
also have to assign your app and that
you do with the key so whenever you have
to publish in a new Android app JK's
file will be created for you
so basically wherever there is public
key cryptography and Java you will find
these check s files now let's look at an
example Android studio so it allows us
to use a UI to generate this JK's files
the first thing it will ask is the
keystore Paso where on your hard disk
will you store this file so super simply
and easy then there is the keystore
password which is the password as we
said before then we have a Kealia so we
can give our key a name
fine with me and then there is also the
key password now now we should be a
little bit confused right I mean why are
they two different passwords there's the
keystore password and then there's also
a key password so now we have this
situation now let's take a small
shortcut and I will tell you what this
is about so actually this is what's the
first design mistake that it the
keystore password is not used for
encryption it's only used for integrity
checks so this password is incorporated
into a checksum to check if somebody
modified the keystore file but it
doesn't mean it will protect to your
private key or your public key so
nobody tells you that the first password
is super unimportant and the second one
is super important right so here here we
are we just get this UI and nobody tells
me what to do which password to to
choose securely and which one is not of
importance now this is actually the
first really strange design decision
right now okay let's go back let's
forget about this keystore password then
it's not used for encryption so we have
a key password but then well when I
looked at this there's another second
thing that they did design really not
according to best practices I would say
what they did is only encrypt the
private key so the public key is
actually stored in plain text so it
depends on what you do with these keys
but in general I would as a user I would
like to impose them because why should
anybody be able to extract the public
key from my keystore file but well okay
let's rename this key passwords to
private key password because it doesn't
protect public key right so now we have
this private key password used for
Krypton and we have an encrypted private
key so far so good but this is a really
strange design decision again now you
will probably already know what's coming
now we want to know what the black box
is in the middle because somehow the
Java developers design something here
and it all it is already a little bit
fishy
so let's look look at it in detail so
the encryption of the private key is
actually pretty simple it's a it's a
private key in clear text that is XOR
with something called key stream and
then you get the encrypted private key
now I hope every one of you knows what
XOR is XOR is just a simple operation
and I sorry I can't explain to you if
you don't know but the only thing you
need to know about XOR at the
is also that works the other way around
so instead of doing private key X or key
stream and get to encrypt private key
you can also do it the other way around
and take the encrypt the private key XOR
it with the key stream and then get the
decrypted private key now the question
is what is this key stream right that's
the only thing we don't know for now so
let's look at what what the Java
developers decided to design so the key
stream generation is pretty simple again
then invented the new password based
encryption scheme using sha-1 now you
will say well sha-1 this is so old
well Java is old so if if you were
talking about the primitives we have to
keep in mind that this was invented a
long time ago so using sha-1 was
probably a reasonable choice back then
the problem is more that it it is still
the default nowadays so why did we keep
it this long so they do a puzzle based
encryption and the generation of the key
stream is very simple again so we have
two sha-1 it's a it's a hash algorithm
and we take the password so that private
key password and we can concatenate the
IV now the IV it's just another
parameter stored in the file in
plaintext so we can take we can read out
his IV and then generate this first
block a now the next block is just
generated by using the private key
password plus a so we just calculate in
the last block and so on and so on with
all the blocks and in the end we
concatenate these blocks together so we
get a key stream of variable lengths if
that was too quick for you this is the
exact same thing inches limit
different pictures so we have a key
entry at the top which has an IV 20
bytes we can read it out we have a
variable lengths encrypted key it at the
top as well and we can generate the key
stream we take the password plus the IV
from the key entry at the top and we
generate the first block we can then use
the first block to generate the second
one and so on and we can XOR them
together to get decrypt the key now I
tell you that there is a not so obvious
weakness here can somebody see it so I
didn't see it either when I looked at it
but it's actually something you learn
probably in your IT security classes at
university I mean I learned it the least
so I searched around a little bit on the
internet what people say about this
about this mechanism and actually there
is a website called crypto cents and
they wrote only one sha-1 application is
required to derive the first key stream
byte since they're encoded keys contain
a lot of structure in their first bite
make it makes a dictionary based cracker
highly efficient so what they saying is
that we only need to do one shot one not
the entire block to in and to generate
the entire key stream so I thought wow
this is super cool but where's the proof
of concept so where's this implemented
and is that even feasible in practice so
I researched and researched but none of
the password crackers out there were
doing this and I didn't know back then
if this was feasible so I tried to do a
proof of concept just to show that I can
crack jks files easily and basically our
approach or our algorithm to crack
passwords is that we generate this first
block the very beginning with the
password candidate so we get a password
which is guess 1 and then we concatenate
it with the ie we generate the sha-1
and then we can explore it with first 20
bytes of the encrypted key that should
give us the first 20 bytes of the
decrypted key and then we can check
these first 20 bytes if they look like a
private key now what does it mean look
like a private key that's actually again
not a very simple question because these
guys of crypto sense a well it's pretty
obvious that you can do this but for me
it wasn't obvious
so the first 20 bytes of a decrypted
private key it's a pkcs 8 which is a
during coding which is a s + 1 so these
are different encodings or standards for
how this data is represented and in
theory it's actually pretty simple there
should be oh I D which is 9 bytes long
somewhere at the start now an OID
for example if we have an RSA key that
is stored then there should be this
hexadecimal value somewhere at the start
so what we can do is we search for this
Oh a key so when we get the first 20
bytes which we hopefully successfully
decrypt it then we can search for this o
ID and if we find it we can say okay I
think I guess the right password this
could be really what we're doing here is
really decrypting a private key now in
practice this is not a very nice idea
because searching for the OID is super
inefficient and as I'm not a math
student and I'm not a file format
specialist at it the usual IT approach
and I just brute force State so I
generated thousands and thousands of
private keys and just looked at them
what a private key in plain text how
does it look like the first 20 bytes and
at one point I realized there is a
pattern so I found out that 16 out of 20
bytes at the beginning of a clear text
private key are always static
so they always the same so for example
RSA all RSA keys in in clear-text
always start with hex 30 then we have 4
bytes we don't really know and always
vary in not different but then we have
another 16 bytes and there are always
the same at the end we can also see this
view o ID we saw before but now we even
get more values that are fixed and don't
change so for it is not so obvious
weakness let's do an example so for
those who haven't understood yet what
we're doing exactly so with what we do
is we guess a password we calculate this
sha-1 we XOR it with first 20 bytes of
the encrypted key get the first 20 bytes
of the decrypted key and then just check
if it looks something like this so this
is our cracking algorithm to crack
private keys of entries now there is
again an optimization here and it's the
same I told you before about X or we can
XOR number 1 with X or with 2 and then
get the decrypted keys and then check
number 3 or we can XOR number 3 with the
encrypted key bytes and we get something
we can compare directly to the sha-1
calculation so in the end we end up with
one shot one calculation and then just
check if these 20 bytes correspond
roughly to the pre calculated 16 bytes I
then went on and asked some guys who do
password cracking how should we do this
and we decided to implement it in GPU so
graphic cards which are much faster at
calculating sha-1 sums and enjoyably
from the haschke team excluded the
implementation so thank you for that and
the interesting thing is packet is
optimized and uses a weakness in sha-1
you can read about it here I didn't
understand the paper
I'm happy that it's faster than most
other crackers so we're super fast at
cracking jks files so this is again this
cert design decision I would say that
probably wasn't really meant to be like
this and this is the third mistake that
was in that code now for those of you
who think this was too much math or a
crypto there's also a more practical
approach so basically you can just
download my check has pretty prepared to
our file then use this JK's file
generate the hash file and then feed
that to hash cat so if you're doing a
pen test or something and you find a
check has filed you can start to crack
it and it actually surprised me how fast
we can do this so during this run we
have one nvidia geforce gtx 1080 that is
on this system and we're cracking with
that one the type is clear jks and we're
doing this with roughly eight thousand
million hashes per second which means
we're roughly cracking eight billion or
retrying eight billion passwords per
second on this one graphics card and
this is actually super fast so with one
graphics card we can try all
alphanumeric passwords of length 8 in 8
hours so this is super efficient
cracking and if you want to get more
details about the implementation and
well the benchmarking and how fast it is
and so on I wrote pork or tea TFO
article about it it's in number 15 and I
think if you read that you will get some
more ideas of how the cracker works so
my recommendations are very generic
nowadays we have better key derivation
function so in the 90s or even in the
80s I don't know exactly when it was
designed there was nothing like a PB
- or bcrypt or a script or anything for
key derivation so we have visa now and
you should obviously refactor your java
software so if you use jackass then it's
the time to change your code so I know
this is red really blunt recommendation
just out use jks but although good
password will keep you free
secret I mean even a password cracker
cannot do anything about passwords of
length 12 and above at the moment and
obviously you should also not publish
your JK as file so keep them secret even
if their password protected and the
prediction is that check s will stay for
a long time so this is not something I
said
but the Java maintain a set existing key
stores will not change so if you wrote
the java software with java 8 and you
generated key stores then they check s
and if you update Java now it will not
change nothing will ever change with
these cheeky store files until you
delete them and regenerate them so and
key stores tend to be long-lived so you
can imagine I mean a web server that has
keys in it will at least run with with
those JK as fellow check has files until
the keys expire so the alternatives
inside of Java if somebody is a chav a
developer just don't use jks that's the
rule of thumb you can use anything
really just don't use this default type
and probably the the wet dream of all
cryptographers is the new bc fks it's
called it uses everything which is
standard nowadays and you would like to
use so pbkdf2 more than fifty thousand
rounds of hmx sha-512 and it uses day a
year CCM mode so that's that's probably
really good for standards nowadays but
bouncy castle is an external library so
you will need fancy custody
if you cannot use an excellent library
you can use the pkcs12 which is using
1,000 rounds of shaman
so one round of sha-1 versus 1,000
rounds of shaman which is a lot better
although it's still Chauhan and Triple
DES so and then also as we as I told
this or I talked to two Oracle they
changed Java so they made updates and in
these updated Java versions
now the pkcs12 is fifty thousand rounds
although this part was not my research
so crypto sense did a lot of research in
other areas as well for example in
pkcs12 area and they changed and they
basically said well 1000 rounds is still
not enough so you should use more rounds
it's also the default key store type
since Java 9 so pkcs12 is now the new
type so when you when you write there
anything now in Java 9 or 10 then you
should be much better off so thank you
for attention this is the first round of
questions I would say and we'll see
after that so this is the basics about
kks and I would like to get any
questions in if they're questions so far
thank you for your talk hmm very
interesting can you tell more a bit
about how the integrity is checked yes I
will do that later any other questions
about I wanted to know how the IV is
generated start the IV is just randomly
generate 220 bytes random but I think
you're pretty solid on the topic right
so that's why because usually I know the
Swiss audience doesn't have too many
questions so
I prepared a couple of questions for you
so we have we're sorry sure the other
question was actually about your screen
shot on Android studio so when you uh
when you're developing an Android
application I'm not a very good
developer myself so I'm not sure can you
specify another another key store than
Jake yes for Android applications I
think it only comes with Jake yes yeah
so so far you think your luck yeah yeah
poor Android studio you were stuck you
can probably you might work around it by
signing it all in on the command line
you can do that yeah yeah let's see yeah
so so I prepared some questions for you
so how do you know which fingerprint to
expect so as we saw there different
fingerprints these 20 bytes however
private key starts it's different for
RSA and DSA and so on so how do we know
which one which one to expect when we
crack anybody an ID yeah so I'll repeat
it so everybody can understand that so
he said well but the public key is not
encrypted so that's actually one thing
that helped this research because they
didn't encrypt the public key I can just
check what algorithm is used in public
key and then I know which private key
fingerprint I have to expect otherwise
this will be a lot more guesswork and
and the effort to crack will probably be
a lot higher so we can just check in in
the public key which is not encrypted so
this was a really really easy question
to start and here comes the second one
so we only know 16 out of 20 bytes of a
fingerprint right so when we do cracking
the question marks are unknown so how do
we know we didn't get the wrong password
so he said we can just test it we can
decrypt the entire private key and then
check if that's fine yes that would be
an option but that wouldn't perform very
well they did would it because we had to
we would need to generate the entire key
stream first and then XOR you know I
think that probabilities are audio
celluloid yeah exactly
so although there are many question
marks the probability is not 100% that
we thought the password matches and
actually earlier implementations where I
did I didn't realize that 16 out of 20
bytes were fixed but less and we had to
check the entire key to decrypt properly
what what you said but then at one point
we realized that actually the
probability is 1 to 2 ^ 112 20 so this
will never happen in practice you will
never get such a password so we just
didn't implement anything afterwards so
this just works like it is so question
three starts with a new fact and this is
actually why this research took me so
long so if we don't specify a private
key password then the keystore password
is reused so we saw for Android that
it's just asking for both passwords but
most other tools so for example the key
tool of Java on the command line it will
only ask for one and then we'll just set
both passwords with the same value so if
we have this default case can we attack
the keystore password and if not why not
and if yes why don't we
opinions if if we could crack the other
password if they're the same so if the
two passwords here are the same key
password and keystore password and this
integrity check and both passwords are
the same well yes if the default case
applies the same passwords we can crank
any of these two algorithms so basically
it means we could crack with any of the
algorithms so we can track crack the
integrity protection or we can crack
what I just presented so the question is
more like in the default case which one
performs better well now here comes the
questions you have before can you say
something about integrity check this is
how the integrity check works so the
keystore password is actually used at
the top so the keystore password then
you concatenate it to the string mighty
Aphrodite and then you also concatenate
the entire key file so everything all
the keys so you have kilobytes of keys
and produce one sha-1 and then you check
it against the checksum which is stored
in the keystore file so this is how it
works mighty Aphrodite now you might ask
why mighty Aphrodite
well Aphrodite is the lady on the left
we yeah but it's more likely that the
Java developers were watching too many
movies and there was a movie called
mighty Aphrodite so it's probably why
they choose this random string so why
not crack the keystore password anyone I
guess
sorry can you repeat its long the
computation yeah yeah you don't have to
pattern but here we would just need to
we have to check some right so we could
also just crack on this so the question
is really which cracking protests better
performance and more data go into the
sha-1 calculation when you do the
checksum thing whereas the private key
password calculation only has password
an IV so that sha-1 is much quicker than
the other one and and what's especially
important is you don't know as an
attacker if it's default case you don't
know if the passwords are the same or
not and so the private key password
approach I showed also works in the non
default case and the worst thing
actually was that most other password
crackers they implemented this keystore
password cracker so you could end up
cracking and cracking and cracking
password for days and months and years
and once you found the password
it was super useless because you cracked
the keystore password which is only used
for integrity protection and in the non
default case it's not the same as the
keystore password sorry private key
password so basically you could crack
and they might not these password
crackers might not do anything useful so
and here's again a simple one to round
it off do I have time yeah so what was
the best alternative to check here's
again yeah pkcs12 that's default one so
any really just don't use check is VC VC
fks I hate these names anyway that's the
best one and if you cannot use next on
library use pkcs12 which is fixed now I
mean use more rounds if you have two
updates so if you generate keys after
the update
but if you generate them before then
they only have 1000 rounds so just get
everything a newly generated so thank
you for attention and if you have any
more questions thank you