hey andy i think it's time for us to
start doing this wrap-up talk
fabulous and wonderful well
welcome to the cloud native security day
ctf
outro uh oh he says outro and this is
the recap
let's go to bear instead there we are
welcome to the recap we will do a post
cap
recap decap uh walk through what we did
today
and go under the hood to explain some of
the attacks
peace indeed is never an option for a
naughty goose
and today we were off
hunting clusters in the wild
but actually it was not the public
internet we were using
it was uh far more whoops a lazy
a far more constrained environment
whereby we stood everything up in order
to
practice and learn in a safe place so
every cluster had a bastion host
and every cluster was inaccessible from
the public
internet so what were we trying to do
we were trying to avoid this kind of
thing
but you know a little bit of frustration
is a helpful learning tool
but by having a taskmaster available
and hopefully responsive enough we uh
we look to assuage some of those
concerns
so let's have a look
at the spoilers we do not have very long
to get through all of these so we're
going to try and do them as quickly as
possible
and do a pwn bipon demo of
uh well as you say everything that we
were doing
so we will start off
he says sorry
yeah so i think we're going to start off
with scenario 3 which is avalanche so
earlier on today we had
uh two separate twitch streams um in a
first twitch stream we went through
scenario one
and they'll be available for you to
review and then also in the afternoon
twitch stream
we went through scenario five so without
further ado i'll pass back to
mr andrew martin to uh show us a way
through the
uh scenario free which was called avalon
thank you very much so with the purpose
of this
excuse me the purpose of this is
uh we trust within our private networks
um our own container registers hold code
that we believe is safe to use
so we've deployed an image from our
private registry but the pirates captain
hash jack and the nefarious crew have
taken the registry down
so we can no longer get images from it
but there's a secret
in one of those deployed images so let's
have a look for the secret key
to uh unlock the plug in the bottom of
the captain's prize ship
and hopefully scuttle it so we're in the
hash jackpot
in the avalon namespace well what does
that mean
as usual let's just see what the
mount points look like let's check df
and see okay the
initial dual in any kubernetes
escalation is the service count
so let's see what we've got available so
we have queue control installed
so we're probably in a container that
was used internally by administrators to
do something useful
and we will try and use for something
that's less than useful
so let's see what access we've got well
we can hit the api server
we can see in the m that we've got
routing to these things
it is the bitnami cubecontrol app thank
you very much bitnami
that probably means it's relatively well
configured from a file system
perspective
what does that mean it means that we're
uid 1001
but group id zero does that uh
does that show us anything well actually
there is no
you at 1001 so that means that our file
system access is going to be difficult
it's also why we see i have no name
because
our username is pulled from etsy
password and we have no reconciliation
because we have no
entry no line in there
okay so we do have cube control and this
is probably a bad day for cluster
administrators
what pods do we have okay so we can see
already that we've
got uh three private earpods
and if we try and do this across all
name
excuse me that's not quite how you spell
spaces
then we can see here so we have a we
have a forbidden
and the api server has leaked our
um service count name and
the namespace back to us so we can't
list pods across all namespaces
fine but we do have access to our own
local namespace so what do we know about
the scenario well just going back to the
beginning
we can see there's a secret in one of
the deployed images
so we've got access to these pods
how do we find out what images they're
running we
examine them as yellow and we grep for
the
image tag or the image
key there we go
so that looks pretty hopeful
this container image is probably the one
that we want
so let's just see if we can exact
straight in
control exec interactive session
attached to sudo terminal let's go into
privateer
oh we don't have a completion which
we'll fix
and let's run sh okay so we
do not have pods exec that's not very
helpful when we want to read the
contents of the
image that the pod is running from but
we can do something slightly different
which is
run the thing instead
and then see if that works
okay so we've managed to do something
and in fact i've called pod sh which is
never a good look
let's call it test random
okay so we're able to run but we're not
able to attach to the pod
that's not very useful uh let's just
have a look again
and see what pods we have so here's the
erroneously named and here's the
recently named
so what can we do here well we're
looking for something in the file system
of a pod
of an image rather we can't get that
image
because it's from a private registry so
the only thing we can do here is to
execute something
inside the pod that will reveal unto us
the actual flag on the file system so
um
let us say pods is going to be called
uh test and we'll give it a random name
so that we can we can use the bash built
in random variable
so that we get excuse me so that we get
a different name every time
then that's our pod name and then the
command we want to run
is probably uh bash
and then let's just get our id and then
once we've done
that give it a few seconds for the pod
to start at the cube control logs
on the pod just see what happens
so three seconds pod starting hopefully
pod apparently not starting
i don't know if i need those in there
okay maybe we'll try a slightly
different approach to this
why would that not work
so andy the way that i did this earlier
was just
to uh in the sleeper command during it
is just to write out those logs as
you've done but then keep call logs
on the pod and then write it to a dump
so temp dump
and then to cut it out from there that's
how i
that's a good idea so let's just
so we've named the pod something the
other thing we can do here while we're
at
it is just to turn debug mode on and
bash to make sure that the command is as
i think it is
okay well mystically that worked
so let's just do uh
shell command id make sure that we have
something
um
okay we may have to come back to this
one because i would expect
this to reveal something to us at least
looks like we're just hanging with the
invocation
live demos hey joy joy of live demos
yeah
we spin up over well i've forgotten the
numbers
okay so it was because i tried to attach
terminal to it
so let's get back to where we were
uh command id and then we'll pull the
logs
as so
okay but we do need to leave a few
seconds for the pod to actually start
this is a kind of blind injection attack
against the pod
there we go so now we can execute
commands within this one shot container
in the interests of the time that i've
wasted that you will never get back uh
let's grab for the flag with my
favorites
one liner which looks a bit like this
so we're going to find something now we
happen to know
that it's in the temp directory to save
us a little bit of time
and that hopefully should now dump out
a flag if i'm being sensible
and as as people have pointed out before
we don't have to use find here
we do have to oh no that's not correct
sorry we do want to search this
we could just grep from the root of the
file system
um okay finally use a share never going
to make you
this smells of lewis denim paris cluster
perturbering
uh but there is our flag finally hidden
in some nefarious local coil system
and we've pulled that from inside the
container now that puts us
slightly behind time so let's see how
quickly we can get through the next so
whilst do you get that next one set up
yes um
value to my calling card to rick roll
whenever i get into a cluster or these
scenarios
um again we're tight on time today so
we're going to see if we can get
to the second but andy whenever you're
ready to go give me a shout
and for i think we're going to go on to
scenario four now
what is the name of that scenario when
it's home one second it is
escalates okay there we go
okay so what are we doing here the
supply chain is compromised
who would have thought such a thing
hashtag and the motley crew have managed
to get
code merged into the application library
that developers use the lobby runs in a
pod and attackers
have then escalated trying to find
secrets on the host
so what do we know here well we know
that we
have uh we have two
unknown containers from the starting
point in the process audit pod
so again we'll just do standards just
see what's uh what exists here
we have we have a service account we
don't have cube control
uh we could install it but let's look at
some other things first
the process table is interesting
so we can see here that we've got sleep
infinity twice
the reason for this is that there are
two containers in this pod
and for some reason the containers can
see each other's init
process that is generally a
bad day because once we share process
namespaces
we share proc and proc
gives us access to all the good stuff so
we can now see for example
uh how that process was invoked
uh and actually we need to do some uh
some null bytes
fixing so it's visible so we've got
sleep infinity in there so we know that
it's
process 11 here's 11. we've got the
right one
okay so what else could we look for in
here well we have access to the entire
root file system
of that process
uh which of course is is a joy for um
all to behold
let's just go back and do an ls
okay so there's some stuff in there but
that's not actually what we're looking
for
um got some stuff in temp
but what are we looking for here well
actually in this case we are looking for
perhaps something in the environment so
again we're looking in the environment
of the other container in the pod there
are two
containers in this pod and this one is
giving us
some useful information perhaps again
things are not bite delimited
and their joyful joys is something that
looks
suspiciously like a flag happy days
there we go um on to uh on to the next
in the last five minutes i'm sure we can
hear it so whilst you get set up for
that
some honorable mentions to today so we
had chris stuffed um
well d um noel mahey
uh we had you val all just
smashing through the scenarios uh thank
you to wallet as well who is
i feel is the community support officer
so thank you ever so much
for the channel uh lena thank you for
being the most eager person to request a
cluster 20 min
20 hours before the event starts but
it's totally awesome
and a safe as well but at this point
and you've got four minutes to do a hack
uh excellent
okay so the cluster is almost about to
die as well because it's an
old one so what are we going to do well
um
the environment doesn't give us much
cube control
has no local routing okay so in this
case
again i'd like to check the mount points
this is not something that we would
expect to see
so let's unmount whatever is bind mount
is
over root.cube have a look there's still
nothing there
why might that be because there are two
bind mounts
okay and then let's just double check
that the mounts are actually gone
yeah there's nothing there anymore bind
mounts are just a way of hiding things
on a file system you can hide processes
as well
but in this case we were hiding
root.cube
and now we've got cubecontrol access
and there we go we can route to the
master the api server
so what is the point of this exercise i
hear you ask
what's the point of this exercise andy
it is to find where hashtag has hidden
his ill-gotten treasure in a
hard-to-find
place okay so first of all
we probably want to uh get onto the
master but we don't know how we can do
that
easily let's see if we can get any
secrets
um irredeemable villainy and
pseudo-reminiscent uh are both potential
candidates
but of course if we have access to all
name spaces
let's just take that one down two down
uh
we can see there's a fair bit more in
here
so noticeably some of these controller
tokens are masquerading
so that suggests that it's a service
account token but it's not that is
created by
a human in the same way these default
tokens
that's not how it should be so
um subcompensatory super averageness
let's see if we can figure out which of
these uh
actually holds
the uh the token so what are we going to
do
let's uh let's get a secret
and i will be honest lewis i i'm not
actually sure which is what so
if you um so what i did andy when you
dropped
this one on me was to go all name spaces
get secrets hyphen
o yaml life
and then just grab from that because it
will give you everything so grab
um ssh i think yeah
and there we go is something that looks
like a private key
here's one that we made earlier
there we go so we've now got a private
key let's stick that
into ssh id i suppose
and
so maybe if we did an
nmap andy we would have found a certain
port open but again to save you from
doing it if you curled the master ip
um and port 5678
so if you've got the master ip node uh
if you have a master ip
from doing cube called get notice i have
no wide and
oh there you go you've already done that
so unfair so okay very nice information
thank you very much so it's a message
from our archetypal
arch adversary follow the 22 white
rabbits
so had we done this beforehand we may
have then
thought about trying to find ssh keys
which at this point we have done
anachronously but so we now have access
to this uh we also know
from running keep control version
what the master appears of course we can
get that from our local cube config as
well
which is probably that much easier there
we go
so let's follow
the captain onto the master node whoops
and you've got about a minute as well to
pull this up so i'm
going forward okay yes so that's
permission denied but that is because
we're not using the right key
there's the shid and we do a classic
trick
of not setting our permissions okay off
we go we're onto the master
so at this point what am i actually
doing here um we need
to we need to inspect we need to find
that there's an image on there control
plane i o
valiant effort and we want to inspect
that image
and we want to find uh where the diff is
so um nice and then
but we want to gain access to that diff
but to be able to do so um we don't have
pseudo access on this so if we remember
back to the first scenario of today we
showed you
how to get privileged access if you run
a privileged container so
let's if we could just loop back to
trying to do a docker run to run a
private uh
i can't say it a privileged container on
on our kubernetes master which would
then allow us
to mount the dev xv da1 mount the same
thing that we did in scenario one today
which then allows us to traverse to the
file system
that the docker image is within and
speed running it really is so it first
says this far live docker location is on
the hosts
um uh it's on the host file system which
we're on
but it's owned by root so that means
that we have to escalate
we can do that through a container or we
can just mount the file system as we're
about to do
here so we've mounted the so if we go
into host
there we go so now we should have access
to this
he says access
oh yeah thanks
okay yes it's the directory and then
proc self command line is the only
file hidden in the container image
and therein lies the flag that was a
speed run and a half
there are a couple more that you can see
that were on the live streams earlier
and i hope that's been at least vaguely
informative if not a little bit
too fast to follow thank you
that's a good question just to say for
thank yous
that's an excellent point and there are
the thank yous yes indeed
thank you to everybody who's uh helped
putting everything together
and also the organizers the work done to
get today
uh smooth and um speed bump free
and uh and control plane folks who've
been laboring on the back end
past and present thanks to you all
there is the the great passing of the
seas
uh some attendees enjoyed themselves
and yes of course don't put kubernetes
api servers on the public internet
control plane does this for a living if
you'd like us to run a ctf for you
um or indeed you'd like to attend some
of the sans training courses
then uh please do reach out to the
relevant channels
and thank you very much for playing have
a wonderful day