hey everyone i hope you have been having
a great experience
at the cloud native security day europe
virtual event
and i'm here to try and add to that
experience with this session
integrating security in the bill
pipeline
let me take a moment to introduce myself
my name is anirban
and i'm a member of the devops
engineering team
at allianz direct based in munich
islands direct
is the online insurance platform of
allianz operating
in a few countries in europe i have been
working with cloud native
infrastructures for almost 10 years
and tend to automate solutions to make
others and
my life easier also with so many
security incidents happening in our
daily lives
i sometimes tend to get a bit paranoid
about security
in my projects i should also mention
here that all the information
tools strategies opinions and
demonstration presented in this session
are entirely my own and they do not
represent the views of alias direct
or any other allianz entity although we
do a lot of cool stuff at alias direct
the contents of this session are not
really aligned with them
this session ends with a live
demonstration of a ci cd pipeline
with security tests enabled and involves
a cloud native setup i'll explain the
tools that have been used here
during the session and for the attendees
who are really interested in trying it
out themselves
i have added the configuration files in
a couple of github repositories
the build pipeline repository also has
general guidelines
about the base components that we are
using in the demo
and the commands to set them up i
understand that for some beginners
it might be a bit much to grasp but
unfortunately because of some time
constraints i'll not be able to
demonstrate setting up the base
components
such as the kubernetes cluster the auto
scaler
and the ingress controllers so we will
first look
at why we are here understand the
problem analyze it
find out reasons for them and look at
ways to mitigate them
we will look at how a vulnerability
scanning workflow works
how they plug into the build pipeline
the options that we have
in terms of tools analyze different
strategies
to integrate security scans into the
build pipeline
and finally we will watch one such
pipeline in live action
i know that we all hate staring at
powerpoint presentations
believe me i know i really know that
pain so i'm gonna finish up with the
presentation
as fast as possible and we'll dive into
the fun stuff
this is required as i really want to
keep this simple
and really want you to understand what
we are doing and why we are doing it
so why are we really here what is the
problem that we are trying to solve
in general terms we are trying to
implement software security
so how do we do it generally it starts
with the business goals
being defined resulting in products to
be launched which happens
at the management level the architect
designs the software
as per requirements developers get on
the same page with the architect
and they start creating some cool
software with modern life cycle
software life cycle processes testing
the software is very essential
we all we all know that once all of this
is achieved
the artifact is created and the product
is released
generally at this point a security or
penetration test
is scheduled where vulnerabilities are
detected
or sometimes unfortunately there's
really no security test done at all
as the software has never been scanned
before this list
is quite long now think about a cloud
native scenario
where we are talking about more than 50
to 60 micro services
and the amount of time it would require
to fix those problems
that's huge right now with product
priorities
and feature requests it is quite
difficult to devote dedicated time for
such fixes
as a result it gets postponed or greatly
neglected altogether
and before we know there is a breach
taking place
so how do we approach the problem you
might have come across the phase
shifting left on security this
very very simply means that in the left
to right process
progress of software development life
cycle
we need to move the security testing
towards the left
that is early on in the development
process
the basic idea is to detect and fix
security problems during development and
not after the service is released
so how do we actually go about
addressing the issue
the final objective of any business is
to create a trust relationship
with the customers the clients and
and the registered users to do this you
need to be able to convince them
that when they provide you with the data
it is not going to be compromised
under any circumstances at present
we are providing our financial insurance
medical and our personal data online
to service providers every day we would
definitely not want to be associated
with a service
who are not able to protect our data
to do this first and foremost thing to
be done
is to make each and every person
responsible for security
when you leave your office door open by
mistake you are responsible for the
safety of hundreds of your colleagues in
the office building
and you can compromise it by letting in
an intruder
this person can be an office
administrator
he can be an engineer a manager or even
the ceo of the company
similarly in the software product
lifecycle each person
needs to understand that they need to be
responsible for security
whether it is via software design code
creation
software deployment or really site
reliability
developers really understand features
and feature requests very well right
so start treating security fixes as
features
and integrate them in the development
process
in large development teams instead of
asking and expecting everyone to fix
their libraries
use a pre-built library repository which
only contains pre-approved
and vulnerability-free libraries to fix
problems
you need to detect them first and know
how to make it part of the process
so go for professional help in such
cases or
really hire dedicated security personnel
train the teams so that they first
understand what they are doing and why
they are doing it
it's not only important to decide to
shift left on security
but also to understand what to scan for
vulnerabilities are of different kinds
and there are different stages when they
can be detected
and fixed the first step in this
direction
is to look for package or dependency
vulnerabilities
they include base operating system
packages and also
application packages such as ruby python
java node or just any other programming
language dependencies
this is a stage where the code is not
involved yet
it's just the system on which the code
is supposed to run
next we need to scan for vulnerabilities
in code which has not been compiled yet
these are situations when problems in
the code can lead to unintended code
executions this is called static
application
security testing or sast
because the code is not running yet
another type of security scanning is the
dasd
or dynamic application security testing
in this stage the application needs to
be scanned
for vulnerabilities which exist when the
code has been executed
this need needs to be done against a
running web application
so we can really see that the attack
vector
is quite huge
next we will look at general
vulnerability scanning workflow
the ci cd tool is probably one of the
most important component
in the setup which orchestrates the
entire pipeline
the code repository is used as a source
for our code
and the image repository for image
artifact storage
the security tool is really not
mandatory
in most cases there is a central
solution security platform or tool
which coordinates the communication
between the build pipeline
and the vulnerability scanners it is
also used as a visibility tool
to visualize vulnerability reports
believe me when you look at the command
line and see all those vulnerabilities
it's not really that helpful a dashboard
can really help you here
pipelines can also direct commun
directly communicate
with the scanners the vulnerability
scanners
are the databases against which we
compare our image packages
if all goes well we can deploy our
artifact
on the container orchestration platform
for our demo we will use a similar setup
where we will use github as the code
repository
techton and argo cd as the cicd tool
harbour as a security tool and the image
repository
and kubernetes as a container
orchestration
platform there are few open source
vulnerability scanners
available such as clear and trivi which
are really really powerful tools
the default deployment of harbor ships
with trivi
as the default scanner we will fetch
our application code and dockerfile from
the app repository
build it and push it to a test image
repository
we will then scan the image from the
test repository
for vulnerabilities if there are none to
be found
then the image is promoted from the test
to a prod repository
finally we will deploy the app from the
prod repository
we definitely wouldn't want vulnerable
images to land up in plot repositories
right
if the image has vulnerabilities the
pipeline will stop
at that stage and we can visualize the
vulnerabilities in the harvard dashboard
for our demo our app is a simple nginx
container built from a debian or ubuntu
based
image nginx is installed on this image
and a test web page is added so really
really
simple stuff the debian image has high
and critical vulnerabilities which we
don't want to be in fraud
whereas the ubuntu image only has medium
and lower vulnerabilities which we
definitely want deployed
that that will actually be our
simulation
we will use techton to create a build
pipeline
an argo cd to run the pipeline and
deploy it on kubernetes
argo cd is a cloud native deployment
tool
based on the gitops methodology there
are some two specific terminologies
used in the session but if you feel
intimidated
please feel free to use any other ci
tool of your choice
it is also a cncf incubating project
however is also a cncf graduated project
which is an image registry and helm
repository
it can also add plugable vulnerability
scanners
to be able to scan the uploaded images
although we will demonstrate an
automated bill pipeline in this demo
this is quite far from a production
build setup
advanced features such as triggering
pipelines via events
and passing parameters are not part of
this demo
i have kept the app repo with helm chart
and the pipeline repo
different to help you understand this
better
however they can be modified to create a
more sophisticated workflow
okay so we will now start with our demo
this is the hardware dashboard that we
have already installed in our kubernetes
cluster
we have created two different projects
one for broad
and one for test each harbour project
acts as a docker image registry and
also a help chart repository we have
already gone to the configuration page
for both projects and enabled the option
to automatically scan
images on push
if we go to integration services we can
see that trivi is already installed
as the default scanner if we want
we can add a new scanner like claire
we have already set up claire in the
harbour
namespace in kubernetes if we check the
parts
we can see we have a clear part running
and a clear postgres board which is a
database
where it stores the vulnerabilities
we also have a clear scanner adapter
which helps clear to communicate with
hardware
if we add a new scanner
we name it claire
we put in the address which is the
service
for glare and the port
there you can see we have added glare as
a secondary
vulnerability scanner for our demo
we will still use trivi
for our demo we have created couple of
help charts which will help us
run our pipeline the first term chart is
called app deploy
which is actually a simple help chart
to deploy an application and create an
ingress for it
to expose it to the internet the second
helm chart
is called tecton build pipeline which
contains all the configurations to run a
tecton
build pipeline we have already built
both of these hunt charts
and we have already uploaded them to the
health charts repository
in the broad project in harbour
if we check the build pipeline
repository we will find a directory
called secrets
which are some kubernetes secret
manifests which are to be applied
to the combinator's namespaces before
our demo can be run
they are just basic authentication
credentials as some and some docker
registry credentials
next if we check our health charts
we will quickly go to the components
that we have added here
we have added some pipeline resources
which have our git repository
and the image registry
we have added some config maps which has
the metadata for our build pipeline like
docker tag the image name
the namespaces and the argo cd server
and the argosy application name
we also have a series of tasks that we
are going to run
in our pipeline which we have already
discussed which is the docker build task
the security scan task the image
promotion task
and finally the rocd up sync task
we also have a service account which is
attached to one of the docker
credentials
which helps us to provide authentication
for our pipeline
we have a pipeline definition which
integrates all the tasks that we have
already created
and finally we have a pipeline run
definition
which actually runs our pipeline
using tecton our second repository is
called example app
which has the configurations for the
application that we are going to deploy
the first directory is called app and it
contains the docker file
and the sample web page that we are
going to deploy we are going to start
with the debian image which is supposed
to have the high and critical
vulnerabilities
and will be breaking our pipeline
the second directory is called hell map
and it has
the helm chart specification to deploy
the
application and it uses the app
deployment chart as a dependency
the third directory is called helm
pipeline and it uses the tecton build
pipeline helm chart as a dependency and
will be used
to run a tecton pipeline
in the build pipeline repository there's
another directory called argo cd
resources
which has some manifests for our argo cd
application
the first one is used to add the
hardware registry information into argo
cd so that it can fetch
help charts
the example app manifest is used to
create the applique
the argo cd application to deploy to
actually deploy the application
and the third manifest is used to create
the argo city application
which will run our pill pipeline we will
now go to the command line
go to the argo city resources directory
and
we will apply each
of this manifests
if we now go to the argo cd dashboard
we will see both our applications have
been created
and if we go to the repositories page we
will see that our hardware
helmet repository has automatically been
added
and the connection is successful the
example lab build pipeline
gets its configuration from the helm
pipeline directory
of the example app repository the values
file
of the sun chart has the corresponding
values
which helps the pipeline determine its
status
if we go to the argo cd application we
will see
that all of these resources are ready to
be created
and it creates a dynamic name for the
pipeline run
with help of the tag
that we have added in the values file
in a more sophisticated workflow we will
not be adding this tag manually
but it will be created when our
automated build pipeline works
via triggers and events so finally
it's time for us to run our pipeline and
see
the output we will run the sync option
and we will select the prone parameter
here
and we will run synchronize this will
take some time so i will skip
the video here if we now check our
pipeline we will see that
it has stopped at the security scan step
and we will see the reason why because
it has found high
and critical vulnerabilities so in the
meantime
we have gone ahead and we have edited a
docker file to change the image from
debian
to ubuntu and we have
also bumped
the tag for the image if we go to argo
cd
we will see that the change has
automatically been detected
and the zero zero one pipeline run is to
be removed
and a new pipeline run with 002 will be
started
when we synchronize the pipeline so we
will go ahead
and run synchronize again and we will
select the prune option
so that the old pipeline's old tasks are
removed
and the new ones are created
if we now check our pipeline we will see
that it has completed successfully
because the security scan step was not
able to find
high or critical vulnerabilities
if we now quickly check our hardware
dashboard and check the test project
we will find our example have image here
and if we go into details we will see
each of our tags
with its corresponding vulnerabilities
here we can see
tag 001 has critical vulnerabilities and
0 0
2 has medium and lower ones which is why
it allowed us to perform our deployment
if we go further we can actually get
details about all the vulnerabilities
that were found if you're curious as to
what we did for the security scan step
just go to the tasks manifest file in
the tecton build pipeline head chart
go to the app docker security scan task
and there you will be able to see
that we used the trivi docker image
and we ran the trivi command to scan
our image from the test repository and
we
checked for high and critical
vulnerabilities
and we asked the command to fail if it
did find such vulnerabilities
so with that we have reached the end of
this session
i hope the session was able to help you
get some understanding
of how we can have better and secure
build pipelines
and optimize the software development
process
i have added some links about this topic
so be sure to check them out
i hope to see you in another awesome
event in the future
thank you