hey everybody welcome to cloud native
security days presentation from
checkpoint my name is hill
solo from checkpoint security and what i
want to talk to you today about is what
we call cloud native devsecops which is
a long word which i'll try to explain in
a minute
uh but first a little background about
myself and about checkpoint uh my name
is hillel solo
as i said i'm the cloud innovation
architect at checkpoint c
cloud cto office uh i've been in
checkpoint for about a year and a half
and it came there by way of an
acquisition the checkpoint made up a
company
that i was one of the co-founders of
called protego and we were focused in
protego
on cloud workload security so we looked
at things like lambda functions and
azure functions
trying to understand how cloud native
security changed in the new serverless
world and the
the world of functions and cloud-native
containers and things like that
and so we were purchased by checkpoint a
year and a half ago
and since then we've been part of the
cloudguard organization at checkpoint
really trying to drive forward how
checkpoint helps customers
solve cloud security challenges and
cloudguard is a big suite of products
from checkpoint that deals with
everything from
uh cloud posture workload security uh
analyzing logs and
and looking for anomalies and so on and
so forth and our serverless piece is now
part of that
environment uh so i've been uh in
checkpoint for about 18 months i've
actually been
in this room for about 13 months so i'm
really appreciative of the opportunity
to find a reason to put a shirt on today
so thank you um and if there are any
questions afterwards if you're looking
for me i'm hcello at checkpoint.com feel
free to reach out
so what i want to cover today in a
really short time slot and so i
apologize for how quickly i'll speak
is first of all what what is devsecops
why devsecops why is it my problem as
developer and i'm really primarily
talking to you
developers out there and trying to
convince you that security is your
problem it's not someone else's problem
so why is devsecops a thing what do we
mean by that and then why do i claim the
cloud native devsecops is a different
thing or an
evolution of that thing uh what's
different about it and then finally try
to give you some
uh tools and tips and technologies to
how you can try to solve that problem
and own it
so focusing on what devsecops is to me
devsecops is
it's the philosophy that as a developer
i own security just like i own any other
feature of my product security is just
another
important product feature making sure
that my product works securely
it's just as important as making sure my
product works at scale or any of the
other
non-functional requirements we tend to
think of when we think of a product and
the idea that
till now security was something else
that was someone else's problem
is kind of a silly thought really it
doesn't really work all that well and
particularly as we move into more modern
applications
it's really challenging to stick with
that paradigm so devsecops and really
i'd like to just call it devops to be
honest
is just saying security is yet another
part
of the functional and non-functional
requirements for our application that
means that we as developers
are responsible for deploying and
operating secure applications right once
once you own that once you say okay it's
me it's not somebody else's problem i'm
not helping them
it's my problem maybe they're helping me
well that changes a lot about what you
feel like you have to solve right
so security teams are still there
they're still there to help you they're
still there to provide
guidance and tools they're still to
there to look at the overall security
posture of the organization
they're going to worry about your
on-prem and cloud network security
postures and things like that but when
it comes to product and application
security
that's you that's part of your product
it's part of your application and you're
responsible for it and what that means
is things like making sure
that you do code scanning to look for
mistakes that your developers are making
and things like that and make sure make
sure your application is being deployed
securely
make sure you've got an operational
regime that gives you security
and protects you and so that that's
really devsecops is just saying
hey security is your problem mr
developer now let's see how you address
that
but i think that was last year's
revolution two years ago revolution
the thing i'm really trying to convince
you of today is that cloud native
devsecops
is equally your responsibility if not
more but also it's a slightly different
thing
and so why is it a different thing so
first of all when you move to cloud
native
you the developer you own controls for
security that you perhaps didn't own in
the past you are responsible for things
that make a huge impact on security that
were somebody else's problem several
years ago and are now your problem
things like network configuration vpcs i
am role configuration our back things
like that monitoring logging
all of those things are things that you
are operating and deploying
you're deciding on you're controlling
and they have a huge impact on security
and so it's really really crucial
that you're looking at that and saying
okay if i'm responsible for product
security if i'm responsible for making
sure
that my thing is going to work any hour
any scale
no matter what the attackers are doing
to it that means i'm responsible for
making sure that i am rules are
configured correctly that means i'm
responsible for making sure workloads
are in a vpc if they need to be
and that the security groups around
those things are correct that becomes my
responsibility so
part of it is is that you now own things
that you didn't own in the past
a big part of that is your
infrastructure is code revolution the
fact that all the infrastructure in the
cloud
can be managed as code and as part of
your code repository gives you
incredible velocity you love it
i know you i love it as a developer and
i'm sure you love it
yes it means you're responsible for more
things but it means you can change those
things as you need them to be
you don't have to call somebody and ask
them to provision a machine you just
provision a machine
you don't need to change around network
configuration you know what through
somebody else you could you can just go
do that in terraform script that's
really powerful
but it means that all of that
configuration is yours and i've seen
studies that claim
that up to 90 of cloud risk comes from
that misconfiguration
now that's really scary because it means
a mistake that you make can have a huge
impact but it also means you have
the opportunity to do it right so if you
plug those two things together it's my
responsibility
and i have the opportunity to do it
right well that really uh gives you a
path forward right
and the second thing is that there are
increasingly a large number of tools out
there
that can help you do that there are
tools to help you scan code their tools
to help you
scan infrastructure as code and
terraform scripts and confirmation
there are tools to help you scan
container images there are tools to help
you
with monitoring and logging etc and so
those things are at your disposal
to help you solve this problem but step
one again is identify that it is your
problem to solve
and that you're responsible to solve it
and so then what i want to finally uh
take
take to that is what are the pieces of
this that we need to do so the pieces
that you want to think of
first of all all the scanning things are
really important but now you need to
make sure
that i'm using tools to scan my
infrastructure and scan my code
for cloud problems so for example if i'm
scanning deployment scripts terraform
cloud formation those are cloud
constructs that i need to scan i need to
scan those things in the context of a
cloud environment how do i make sure
that my cloud formation template is
going to deploy something with the least
amount of risk how am i going to make
sure that my terraform plans
are all deploying things that minimize
my risk right so there are tools out
there to do that
and those are things you need to be
using the same is true for i am rules i
am role
least privilege is super important in
the cloud it's perhaps one of the most
important things you can achieve it
might
don't tell me don't tell anyone
checkpoint said this but it might be
more important than network security
getting i am roles properly configured
into cloud at least privilege
may make your risk diminish more quickly
than getting your network configuration
correct because
today increasingly we're talking about
sort of zero trust interactions between
resources
and workloads and things in the cloud
and the network is important but it's
not the most important thing
the cloud fabric is using things like
iam and rbac to ensure that
only the things that should communicate
do communicate in the way that they need
to and you doing that configuration
correctly
is going to make a huge impact on
security so getting those things right
are really important
and then of course making sure that all
of the operational parts of the
application are secure as well so making
sure your logging is
is connected to something that can
analyze it for anomalies and find
problems and you're looking at things in
runtime and not just relying on the fact
that you will i deployed it securely it
must be okay
it's not dev it's devops and make sure
that the operations piece of it
is really properly done for security as
well and then finally what i want to
leave you with
is a couple of things or a few more a
few things that checkpoint
provides today where we're starting to
really try to look at you the developer
as one of our customers and figure out
how we can help you
do your job better and again let's agree
three slides ago your job include
security now how do we help you do your
job better
traditionally things like cloudguard are
aimed at security people with their
dashboards and their integrations
and their jira notifications and their
slack and all that's great and you can
leverage some of that stuff
but you need to find tools that meet you
where you want to be so for example
checkpoint sourceguard product is a new
tool that helps you do source code
scanning in your repositories and
pipelines so that you can look for
things like
developer error you can look for
third-party components that provide risk
etc
the shift left component which is part
of the cloudguard suite allows you to do
that
through through the source card system
but also allows you to scan container
images
allows you to scan infrastructures code
templates scan your staging environments
if you have them to make sure
they're compliant before you deploy to
production allows you to do all sorts of
other useful things around security and
then the there's a serverless piece as
well within the cloud guard family
that allows you in ci cd again to
protect serverless functions and
workloads automatically
uh during uh deployment to uh aim for
lease privilege really
really tightly and automatically so that
as a developer i don't have to go try to
read through
you know hundreds of pages of
documentation to figure out what these
privileges but rather
i get to home in automatically on lease
privilege for my workloads
and then also what we call no code
runtime security so the ability to
deploy without having to modify code add
all sorts of
hooks inside my code deploy runtime
security in a way that is developer i
can understand and manage
but i can do it automatically in the
pipeline so that's again part of the
server's workload
capabilities of cloudguard so these
things and others from cloudguard and
again i know that i'm using
checkpoint as an example because that's
where i come from there are a ton of
things out there
there's open source and some other
products these things are all your
friends
and will help you drive to more secure
deployment in the cloud
something that is now your
responsibility so thank you very much
for the opportunity to present that
today hopefully i i got the message
through by saying enough times that
cloud security
and product security is your problem and
hopefully you see that there is a path
forward
to creating and deploying more secure
applications