[Music]
Patrizio congratulations for smaller
winning TV for support thank you very
much
was it a surprise for you oh yeah
actually receiving your install was
wonderful surprises having happy by life
I do that so many people who are being
considered and the whole thing worthy of
their or that has never imagined that I
was going to be one of their chosen I
when I learned that Kira Jota was the
other one I was even happier
what does the word mean to you I think
it's a recognition of contributed over
so many years which is not just my
contribution
somehow I've been able to channel the
the energy of many of my colleagues in
February gosh I shall get on board and
contribute to the accessibility so I
think it's a recognition of a long row
here
so much of the foundation of ICANN is
the work of volunteers who donate their
time their effort to what I can has
become is it difficult to get people
such as yourself and others engaged
I don't think it's difficult to get them
shelter get interested in contributing
but as I said there are many hurdles to
overcome one of them is languish not so
much easier with salvation and
everything at the beginning you just
have to be able to communicate in
English and many of my colleagues just
couldn't so i one of the things that I
did was helping with bridging of
subdivide nowadays mimicking obsession
and forget they are now very involved so
the multi-language support it will go
better than it used to be yes and also
through their years people are getting
better communicators in English too why
I can why do you want to be all tonight
I think we all understand that I can is
necessary for all this ecosystem to work
we realized that I can excel just one
company one corporation in the community
so through that community we join our
efforts before everything to work is
bolted together through CEO thank you
again for the time and again
congratulations thank you very much
[Music]