hi everybody thank you for showing up
and thanks for the organizers for
letting me speak here this is my second
year if you know me you know I speak
barefoot it's kind of nice it's a
gimmick makes me feel more comfortable
you can take your shoes off as well if
you want just you know well I'm gonna
talk today about research that we did at
Argus it's a work of more than one
person and these are the people this is
la CL the CL is the radio guy he's
actually on his way to Brazil now to
give the same talk we had colliding
events she was in charge of signals
analysis there was a lot of decoding and
analysis and trying to understand what
we see in radio signals this is me in
the back in this which we will meet
later is an Ikea clothes hanger why we
will see so who's familiar with TPMS who
knows what TPMS is okay not many people
TPMS tire pressure measurement system or
monitoring system is a little device
that sits inside of the wheel it has a
little battery and basically it just
transmits the tire pressure to the
vehicle many reasons to do that flat
tire you want to know about it if you
have a bad pressure then it affects the
way the vehicle behaves or your fuel
consumption and in some vehicles you can
auto inflate provided that you know you
have a pressure problem and this thing
has okay alright so this has been
extensively researched we're not the
first people to look at that there have
been talks about this in a number of
conferences people were researching that
analyzing the signal the signal is not
encrypted this is the number one problem
with it and many people reached the same
conclusion that you can analyze it you
can decode it you can spoof it and
basically what everybody said was this
is harmless there's almost nothing you
can do with it you can maybe cause
someone to pull over if they're driving
on the highway and all of a sudden they
think they have a low
sure they will like maybe pull over
right that can be a beginning scenario
of maybe hijacking someone or robbing
them or just taking their car whatever
or as I mentioned before if you have an
automatically inflating tire then you
could cause extra inflation that will
also cause damage but the general
consensus says the potential for damage
is very small and we saw that and we
said hmm this is very it's a very strong
saying to say this is useless because
when you say it's useless it's it's not
dangerous
then people stopped caring about that
they stopped looking at that and we
thought what if we can prove that it is
not as unimportant as everyone thinks
right
and we got our inspiration from this
you
what if we could cause that sort of this
distraction to many people at the same
time I mean if it's just one driver and
like we said before you get this little
light and maybe they pull over it has no
significance well what if we could make
it happen on a bigger scale so we start
with one car you need to receive the
signal you need to be able to analyze
and parse it
it has different fields of information
different cars have different standards
then you have to modify it we want to
change the tire pressure value to
something that will cause the alert
right this little sound and a little
light bulb on the dashboard and then we
want to retransmit it this is the
scenario for one car now let's try to
scale it up these are the fields that
you usually have okay every single tire
has their own ID so in order to be able
to talk to a specific car you need to
know the specific tire ID that the car
knows otherwise it's not gonna work this
is why you have to listen first you
can't just transmit stuff so you get all
the information you need now if you try
to scale it up then obviously you need
to be able to capture multiple vehicles
right so you need to do highway traffic
capture and of course this is a little
pun because the cap the traffic is both
radio and vehicles but you need to be
able to do that and analyze and parse
all of it in real time and if you look
at the entire scenario the whole setup
then you start by positioning multiple
receivers why because this TPMS signal
doesn't transmit all the time it can
transmit anything between once every 15
seconds and once every 60 seconds so if
I want to receive the TPMS of this guy I
don't know when it's gonna transmit if I
wait for him here and it just
transmitted 10 seconds ago it's only
going to transmit 50 seconds down the
road and I'm not gonna be there so we're
gonna spread a bunch of receivers and
which means that over this little piece
of road let's say 2 3 4 kilometers
I will definitely at one point catch his
car transmitting then you need to
collect them all and
and then extract the information you
need specifically tire ID and be able to
replace aggregate and sync why because
if you look at this little piece of road
every car transmitted at a different
point but when we transmit we want it to
happen to all the cars at the same time
all the cars that are in a certain area
so this is the challenge and let's look
at this who knows this bridge anybody
from Denmark or Sweden here hello gobby
this is the bridge between Denmark and
Sweden so let's look at that we take an
rtl-sdr this device is receiving only
but it costs about nine dollars you can
get it on eBay or anywhere else and we
position a bunch of them let's say eight
over this piece of road so any car
coming from here and driving towards the
tunnel at some point the TPMS will
transmit because it takes more than a
minute to cross through the bridge and
then I take another device this little
guy is called the yardstick one it is
made by someone who spoke here last year
and this device is also able to transmit
and very easily it has a Python
interface you just send it a Python
command with the parameters about $100
maybe 130 and then we transmit
everything here so right before the
vehicles enter the tunnel we transmit
the signal now imagine that you have 40
or 50 cars traveling at 100 kilometres
an hour and all of them get this little
one two maybe three of them will take
their eyes off the road and look at the
dashboard and when this happens at 100
kilometers an hour in a tunnel there
could be consequences now we're not
saying there will definitely be but this
thing only needs to succeed once in
order to cause real damage so status
report we're somewhere in the middle on
one hand we have a success on the other
one we have a lot of failure and this is
actually part of the talk many times
when you go to security conferences and
someone is standing on stage and telling
you what they did they give you the
solution they don't explain to you
they got to the solution what did they
try what worked what didn't work it's a
lot less teaching to get the textbook
answer but if someone tells you the
process that they took then you can
learn from that on how to do better
research in which directions to look how
to approach problems and we're going to
be or I I'm going to be sharing what we
did we chose to do that because we
wanted a learning experience as I
mentioned in the beginning this had been
researched before we could have just
taken all the work and continue from
there we didn't want to do that we
wanted to learn stuff that we hadn't
done before and that meant that we
reinvented the wheel right we went
through stuff that other people had
already gone through and posted the
results but we didn't know how they got
there
people just posted code and we didn't
know so we wanted to learn and of course
the meaning is that it took us a lot
longer than we had expected to the
extent that the first time that we
applied this talk to a conference we
applied with the abstract and then
started the research and we actually
didn't finish the research in time for
that conference so we showed up and said
well we wanted to talk about but we
failed and this is how we also got the
idea to insert that into the
presentation but now we're a little bit
better what have we learned during the
work it's not easy to find the signal
the TPMS signal is on two bandwidths 440
or 34 in Europe and 315 megahertz in the
US there are for public use there are
many many devices that transmit in this
range for example your car keys right
the remote keyless entry they transmit
in that frequency a lot of other devices
because you don't need to license
anything that works in that frequency
range so one of our problems when we
were listening to radio waves was to
determine which signal was in fact the
TPMS remember we started from scratch so
we didn't know what pattern to look for
we said okay we look for something that
is maybe cyclic or whatever so there was
a lot of signal and in the beginning we
didn't know what it was we were chasing
a lot of dead
and that's important we had a one
particular problem this is lazier and
this is my vehicle and this is the hack
RF and here is the yardstick one we had
such a hard time getting a good signal
so we said okay let's take the best
parameters we're gonna take the computer
and sit in front of the wheel what more
can you ask for
right the transmitter is one meter away
from the receiver not even okay and we
set this is the underground parking lot
okay it's not a nice air-conditioned
hole I hear we sat there for hours hours
and it didn't work sometimes we got a
signal sometimes we didn't get a signal
sometimes we got a signal but it wasn't
EPM s sometimes we got a signal that we
thought was TPMS but didn't have the
cyclic timing that we were expecting and
at some point after wasting many hours
said okay we got the point we accept our
failure we're going to take the shortcut
the shortcut is to take the wheel off
the car and then take the tire off the
rim and then look at the transmitter
itself because on these devices you have
the FCC ID code and the FCC ID website
will give you most of the information
that you need the frequency range and
the modulation used and this is a very
good source of information which we
didn't want to go to we wanted to figure
it out but we failed and then after
hours of sitting on the floor we
discovered that my car doesn't have that
TPMS transmitter
you mention our surprise so yeah that
was a little bit embarrassing
of course we immediately knew were gonna
talk about that that's why we took that
photo and then we found someone in the
company that did have a TPMS and this is
the device and here we were finally
getting a signal this scenario actually
helped us because one of the ways to
cause the TPMS sensor to start
transmitting more than once a minute is
if it detects a significant change in
the pressure and imagine that when you
take the tire off and then you put it
back on and you have to inflate the tire
the sensor is like whoo something's
going on let's party
and then he starts transmitting so that
was the first time we got a clear signal
in many bursts and that was a very big
step for us right so we started you know
reading the documents and determining
the signal and what we actually needed
the whole time was to find it you see
this is what it looks like it's very
similar to the ones that I've shown you
before it was hard to tell but here you
can see a clear modulation if you have
an experience with radio you can see
this is a clear modulation of bits and
this is what we were looking for and
these were the parameters if you know
anything about radio these will mean
something to you they describe the
signal how it is modulated what are the
parameters their merit many parameters
for modulating a signal and you need to
know them all if you want to be able to
demodulate
the signal so this is the mystery and
once we had that things started to work
for us this is a new radio companion
it's an open-source package Rossi is an
expert on that and it took him a very
long time to build this very
sophisticated graph that was supposed to
do everything automatically but even
that didn't work at the first start and
he had to rewrite a lot of stuff so like
I said we reinvented the will it was a
lot of work of course now he's a much
better expert but at the end this is an
open-source package each and every one
of you can do exactly the same doesn't
cost anything and then came
the analysis okay we have plenty of bits
let's see what well what to do with them
here I just changed it to dashes and
dot's because in when you look at zeros
and one they're the same size it's
harder to notice but when you do this
this the symbols are not the same size
so this is actually easier on the eye
now who recognizes this this is the city
of Manchester
there is Manchester coding here and we
kind of forgot about that
so that also took us sometimes you can
have Manchester encoding in two
different ways so we were stepping on
all the land mines during the research
until we finally managed to get
everything right and that helped us
because Manchester encoding also lets
you know when the packet starts and what
it ends because as you can see there's
there are a lot of bits here and you
really need to know which part of it is
relevant
we tried even recording the signal and
replaying it and to see if we can
analyze it as you can see this is again
Razzies work you can see the clear
signal and you can see the bits being
decoded and that worked very well in the
lab right it's a recorded real-world
signal being transmitted to our receiver
sort of a lab bench I guess you can call
it and it worked
however when you go to the car and you
start driving with the same setup all of
a sudden it's not as good it was a lot
harder to get a signal Razi was driving
around the city and they didn't work
this is the clothes hanger which we
mentioned before the reason we needed
that is because we had a directional
antenna which is perfect for this sort
of radio signal it's designed for this
frequency it's designed to look straight
forward and not in a wide beam and we
the office that we work at at Argos it's
right over the road the road is
literally down the building so we said
okay let's put the antenna on the closed
hangar looking
and record some signals and as you can
see or as you might be able to detect we
are not at ground level we were actually
on this 36th floor and we discovered
that that was too much for the signal
and the only way to actually get a good
signal was to go sit by the highway so
this is me sitting next to the highway
in the middle of the tel-aviv summer
recording bits okay
very easy same device same setup I just
had to sit close to the road after that
we said okay let's try to do the whole
thing let's get a signal analyze it
extract the tire pressure change the
tire pressure and transmit again we
built elapsed a lab setup in the lab
setup everything works fine really you
can see the bits going out you can check
the modulation but again when you try it
in real life it doesn't work the
benefits of this lab setup was that it
saved us a lot of time instead of
sitting outside waiting for signals and
then trying our stuff we were able to
use a recorded signal what you can see
here is a device transmitting the
recorded signal directly into the
yardstick one instead of connecting an
antenna we connected the receiver and
the transmitter with a cable so that
helped a lot and here came another
problem it was time to try the
transmission and this is again the
parking lot
the close hangar and the antenna and we
just couldn't get it work it worth in
the lab we went down to the parking lot
with the same device the same equipment
it did not work and remember there's not
a lot of work here it's a bunch of
Python commands going to a device and
all the modulation all the radio stuff
is happening on the device it's not even
on the computer and we tried my computer
which is the MacBook Air and it just
didn't work and then we tried the seals
computer which is also a MacBook Air and
it then it did work and everything else
is the same it's the same script it's
the same device literally the same
yardstick 1 and this is voodoo we we
don't have an explanation for that you
any of you guys have an explanation we
would love to hear nothing else work
other than me dropping my computer and
using lousy else computer which is
almost the same computer in fact it's a
little older so we don't know
so eventually where do we stand it was
time to see it was like that when we got
here don't worry it was time to see how
this is working so remember our
objective is to transmit a spoofed
signal that will cause the light to go
on okay and this is what it looks like
this is Rosie's vehicle and this is me
and we tried to sync the videos so let's
see what we try to do the vehicle is
parked outside the frame here and we
wanted to see whether if the antenna
which is here transmit the signal while
the vehicle goes by we can spoof the
signal that was from close range but
remember we wanted to cause the same
effect on a large highway a large
highway would have four five six
depending on your country lanes each one
is maybe two and a half three meters so
you want to get a bigger distance so
what we were gonna do is after clearing
this range we're gonna go over there
this is the Lowe's floor of the parking
lot we it was important to us to do it
in a relatively sterile environment we
didn't want to affect everybody anybody
else we were doing some driving we
needed no one to be there so this was
the perfect solution let's try again
yeah it's not gonna work we're gonna
skip this one so where we got I will so
let let me spoil you the it works right
the car drives we spoofed the signal and
it works and actually we got it to work
up to 30 meters away with this little
antenna the directional antenna without
an amplifier so imagine this setup can
cause the same effect in roughly let's
say the size of this hole
okay so cars driving here and car drive
a car driving at the back this will work
on all of them provided that we got all
the information from before okay this is
challenging so what did we get the
ranges that we got were up to 30 meters
which covers a lot as I mentioned and
then we started working on the setup now
the way to do the setup remember I
mentioned we wanted to position multiple
receivers and connect them all to a
central station then we'll later
transmit the way to do that we wanted to
go as simple as possible we had already
spent too much time and effort on
reinventing the wheel so we went with
raspberry PI's the Raspberry Pi can
easily support an internet connection
and this really nice rtl-sdr the little
dongle that I mentioned before that only
receives and costs $8 so we built an
open VPN setup where the main station is
the server and then each of the other
receiving stations is a client and when
you use that with certificates then this
setup is completely scalable all you
have to do if you want to add another
receiving station is just clone the
Raspberry Pi and change the certificate
and now we can add another one and once
they all connect to the VPN server then
they're all in the same subnet they can
talk to each other and they can talk to
the main system the main system will be
receiving the information from all the
raspberry PI's doing all the
calculations
and this is where the hard part is and
to be honest we're not there yet
we chose to stop the research I'll talk
about that in a minute but then you have
to do all the synchronizing when we
receive the signal we have to add a
timestamp to it because remember the
signals will be received in at different
times but the transmission must happen
at one time for everybody so why did we
choose to stop the point all right yes
all right so we talked about the
distance and we talked about the backend
setup and now what's next there are
challenges here first of all there are
many different modulations this
particular TPMS that we were working on
as it turns out transmits in two
different modulations one of them is
when the vehicle is static and one of
them is when the vehicle is moving so
obviously we didn't care about the
modulation when the vehicle is static
but that just shows you the different
TPMS sensors from different
manufacturers will be using different
modulations with different parameters so
it is a matter of scaling up but this is
just research it will not be creating
something that was not done before but
if you want to do this if you want to
create a setup that we mentioned then
yes we will need to go through more TPMS
sensors and there are many of them there
are many manufacturers and it's
challenging but this is what you have to
do in order to create the scenario and
the last thing is that synchronization
it's not easy we would have had to play
with that but we chose to stop why
because our objective was not to
actually carry out this attack this
could be dangerous we wanted to show
that it can be done so once we did it
for one vehicle then scaling it up is
not the big challenge and there was an
agenda here let's talk about mitigation
if I'm showing a problem then it's my
responsibility to offer a solution
otherwise I'm just giving bad people
ideas of course the trivial mitigation
that you can expect is someone to tell
you let's encrypt the transmission right
but here's a problem this little device
it's really small and it's using a coin
coin cell battery it doesn't have all
the computing power needed to execute
encryption right also what happens if
you
change the tire so you have four and
maybe a spare one but what happens if
you damage the rim so you get a new one
or and then what happens who is
synchronizing so this creates more
problems than it actually solves the
second option is to switch the operating
mode from listening to the wheel to
polling if the vehicle asks the wheel
what is your pressure instead of waiting
for the wheel to report then in order
for me to be able to spoof that signal I
would have to listen wait for that
question and then respond either quicker
or stronger than the wheel so this will
make this attack scenario a lot more
difficult not undoable but a lot more
difficult but this mitigation also has
its problems how how often do you do
that you can't do that
all the time because this device goes to
sleep when it's not transmitting if you
ask it every ten seconds then you're
gonna you know shorten the battery life
if you ask it every minute what happens
if there was a problem in between you
know two questions I asked it here and
then ten seconds later I have a flat
tire is it going to take me fifty
seconds to find out so this is not a
good idea
and the last mitigation is something
that can actually already be done and
relatively easy the vehicle has many
different sensors already inside it one
of them is measuring the rotation speed
of the wheel now when you take a wheel
and you take the air out of it the speed
at which the wheel is revolving will
change and vehicles know that okay this
is for example how the ABS works when
you brake and the ABS senses that the
wheels are not turning at the same speed
then it knows that you're starting to
skid and then all sorts of things start
happening so anti-skid and also abs so
the vehicle already knows that so
imagine if you get a low pressure signal
and then you correlate it with the
rotational speed and you see that the
speed hasn't changed then you know that
it is not
it's it's a false signal and this is
easy you can do this already with
existing vehicles no need for additional
hardware but of course the most
important mitigation is not even in the
vehicle it's as always in security it's
about the users and basically you have
to keep your eyes on the road and this
applies to all of us being distracted
while driving is one of the most
dangerous things that can happen and
this one actually started this whole
research the idea that we can cause
distraction to many drivers at the same
time now an important message it's
doable yes it's difficult it requires a
number of conditions maybe you need a
really busy highway with many lanes and
many may I don't know maybe a tunnel but
it's doable and as I mentioned before in
the beginning it only takes once the way
the world works
is that if something really bad happens
and then someone comes in claims
responsibility and says unless you pay
me 1 million dollars this will start
happening every other day there is
nothing people will do except pay
because there's nothing you can do
people get scared so it is a threat that
needs to be considered another thing
which is actually our agenda yes
everybody who looked at it said that it
was not dangerous but there's a saying
in English where there's a will there's
a way and in our case when we as hackers
as white hats and of course when black
hats do that when there's malice there's
a way a bad guy will always find a way
to make your system do something it
wasn't supposed to do and I think that
any of you who do actual security
research you know that most of the
problems that we find are because the
people who created the product were not
taking something into consideration
because people want to be good people
they want to think everybody else is
good so if the value
use of a variable or between 1 and 100
why would anyone put 200 or 1000 why
would they do that that's the sort of
question you get from people so we
wanted to show that even when everybody
looks at something and it looks harmless
if you really want to cause damage with
it there might be a solution or is
somebody else framed it if there is a
way to do anything there will be malice
because this is how the world works and
this is the most important thing scale
matters what I personally do at Argos is
threat analysis and risk assessment this
is hacking but on the earlier stages at
the design stages and this is the best
opportunity to find all the problems and
all the risk scenarios so they can later
decide what to deal with what to
mitigate and what not to mitigate and
this material case shows you that if I
do a threat analysis and risk assessment
on a vehicle and I look at the TPMS yes
the result will be this is a viable risk
scenario spoofing the TPMS signal but
the risk score will be very low because
the worst you can do to a single vehicle
if you spoofed the TPMS signal is maybe
make the driver pull over or as we're
starting to understand distracting the
driver can also have security
implications but that's it it's one
vehicle but if I do the same thing at
scale if the same scenario happens too
many vehicles at the same time at the
same place then the risk score is no
longer low it is actually very high
because in my best-case scenario as an
attacker I can actually cause a car
crash at 100 kilometres an hour inside
the tunnel this could be very bad so
scale matters things that look harmless
on a small scale could look very
differently when you go up the scale
another thing which is not said enough
failure is part of the work process for
me it's easy to say I'm Israeli in our
culture we fail all the time
we embrace failure we talk about failure
we share our failure of course we like
blaming
for their failure it's more fun
everybody does that but you cannot
succeed without failing and in fact the
most dangerous people are the people who
always succeed and never failed because
everything has always worked for them
and the first time that they're going to
you know encounter something really
really bad they will be unable to deal
with that like look at the computer that
thing was giving me trouble all the time
and I don't care because everything has
already happened to me I'm standing here
on stage being recorded and my computer
hangs okay so what happened to me before
and I survive to tell right in other
cultures failure is not accepted as such
now I'm not trying to change the culture
of other people but I am trying to
change the culture of the security
industry they're researchers people
think that if they share their failure
it's a bad sign which means that they're
going to lose their job people are not
going to think highly of them
professionally but in fact sharing your
failure helps other people and learning
from other people's failure teaches you
better and in fact in hack Lu two years
ago
Angelle Bertini which is an amazing
researcher the guy does things that
other people dream about he was giving a
complete talk about failures in InfoSec
and about impostor syndrome because
everybody has that everybody who's ever
been on a stage people that maybe you
and I look at them and say wow he's the
best in his field everybody makes
mistakes everybody fails
everybody has impostor syndrome so it's
okay it's part of our culture and we
need to accept that and this will make
us and our fellow researchers better at
what we do thank you
questions
[Applause]
is that the same question from last time
okay Gabi what do we have a microphone
further questions or is it gonna shout
we have a microphone all right so you
said that scaling it up is hard but how
do the manufacturers do it because when
I go to a service to replace the wheel
they what do they do they pull the TPMS
module out and install it in the new
wheel is it compatible with the new
wheel does every wheel that you buy have
a TPMS module inside like a brand new
one how'd they manage like all of the
different encodings and packets okay and
your car either has TPMS in its wheels
or it doesn't when you go to a shop
assuming it's a licensed shop and not
some somebody's backyard then they have
diagnostic equipment which they connect
to the vehicle through the obd2
connector they talk to the receiver ECU
and they can sync it with new receivers
and this is their responsibility when
you buy a new car ninh has four or five
tires they're all already synced it is
almost the same with the key some
sometimes we you when I was playing
around with SDR and I was doing replay
attacks on the key then I got the system
out of sync and my key stopped working
so I went to the shop and they just
connected to the port told the car
forget all the keys you know here are
two new keys and that's how it works but
this is done with that special
diagnostic equipment that most people
don't don't have or can't make and the
car shop they know how to do that
other questions also if you have any
questions I'll be around here today and
tomorrow feel free and remember failing
is an option no problem thank you okay
invar thank you very very much
[Applause]