hello everyone thank you for attending
this session this talk titled the red
square mapping the connections inside
Russia's apt echo system let me give you
a short introduction about his talk so
on in the last 15 years many Russian
operations and Malwa families in futures
were publicly exposed by different
security vendors and intelligence
organizations those publications focus
on specific Russian actors or operations
but the bigger picture remains unclear
which is the Russian apt ecosystem as a
whole and we wanted to get a better
understanding of how this ecosystem
looks like in terms of the connections
between the different components and
that is why we conducted this research
we really happy to be here today and to
show the results and we will also
present several open source tools that
we built during our research and now can
be used by by you guys the community for
further investigation but before we
start I would like to introduce
ourselves so my name is Ali Aten and I'm
the VP of research at integer hello I'm
a Thai Korean I'm a reverse engineering
checkpoint research I'm also one of the
developers of to the open-source reverse
engineering platform and maintainer of
the Qatar project so as you can see this
research is a result of a collaboration
made by checkpoint research group and
integers research team which was led by
ETA and on women basalt from outside and
in total we worked on this research for
a few months so let's start as I said we
wanted to detect connections between
different Russian entities such as a
pair of malicious samples whole families
or even between Russian actors
themselves now what is the connection
right a connection can be a shared
module tool or even a specific
implementation of a function
our research was very wide and we we
weren't limited to one type of of
connection well we had many questions in
mind that we wanted to answer for
example are the different Russian
government entities working alone or are
they sharing code and techniques with
each other and if so what artifacts
libraries and code are more likely to be
shared between two different actors to
different families can we support
unknown connection between two different
families or tools but from a technical
perspective and not from the
intelligence perspective and so on and
so forth I really had many questions and
all those questions led us to start
reading public information that was
shared by other vendors and researchers
regarding Russian attacks there is a lot
of information available out there in
many reports so that was the first step
that we took and it was a very important
one so first of all we would like to
thank all the amazing researchers who
published regarding Russian attacks it
was really helpful for us after days of
reading background materials and
publications it was quite clear to us
how we should proceed towards this goal
of mapping the Russian an ecosystem to
put it simply we split the research into
four steps the first step is to collect
samples that we know were attributed to
Russian actors then we need to classify
those samples which was a very
challenging step and I'll elaborate
about that after that we want to find
the code connections the similarities
between the different samples and lastly
analyze the interesting and relevant
connections right so let's start first
of all we collected the samples I told
you we we read many reports extracted
our seeds from them and then we had to
grab the actual samples the binaries
from many sources overall we had
approximately 2,000 unique
has to work with the next step was to
classify the samples and although it may
look easy since the name of the attack
or or campaign appears in the report
that we grab the i/o system classifying
the samples turned out we one of the
most complicated parts of this research
and I'll explain why first of all there
is no naming conventions for Mau
families and threat actors in the
InfoSec industry every mom or family in
every actor have more than one name
given to them by different researchers
or vendors some vendors will be used
different names to describe the same
family other mama families simply do not
have clear name so those issues and more
made us face one of the most painful
drawbacks of classification and required
us to be very careful when we classify a
specific piece of malware to a family or
or an actor but naming convention was
not the only problem and sometimes we
discovered problems with the IOC s there
were too generic or even wrong and since
we needed to know exactly what every
sample does we we had to dive in deeper
and we did we built the template for
pieces of information that we wanted to
collect for every sample of malware that
we had
first of all actor which actor is known
or likely to have written this malware
for example tearless officee a grey
energy and so on next family what is the
common family name that is associated
with this mower module many more files
are built in a modular way in which the
model can extract a specific module
embedded in it or downloaded from a c2
server
so when possible we wanted to know
whether the binary we have right now is
is a key logger module a communication
module and injection module log or
anything else
and lastly version some files have a
clear version stem better than them and
we wanted to differentiate between
earlier and recent versions of the same
module at this point we classified all
our samples into sixty families and 200
different modules so after collecting
the samples and classify classifying
them we were ready to get to the actual
thing which is finding the code
connections between the samples and for
that we used integers genetic malware
analysis technology we automatically
disassembled and dissected each binary
file into thousands of small fragments
of assembly also referred as genes then
we search in which other Marvel Zombies
Russian samples we have seen those genes
in the past using this genome database
made by interval now this database
contains binary genes from both
previously seen by Marvel files but also
from legitimate files this helps us to
focus only on the malicious and unique
code between the samples without wasting
time on shared library code like open
SSL for example eventually we were able
to connect different samples Russian
samples based on the pure assembly code
and every connection means that those
two samples shall code with each other
that was never seen before in any other
trusted software or malware which is not
Russian right so it's really powerful
actually it was a bit more complex than
that because some of the samples were
packed in order to stay basic probably
so we had to automatically unpack them
statically or
dynamic and the output of this process
was a list with pairs of samples that
share assembly code with each other the
next step was to make though this list
to a graph and it I will take it from
him thank you so as a reset intercepts
technology did its magic and now it got
a decent amount of data and connections
to analyze and so we search for a way to
visualize these connections and came
upon this open source software called
Gaffey and get free is a platform to
visualize and analyze graphs it was
exactly what we were looking for
so we downloaded Gaffey and loaded our
data to it and got this result now this
is of course useless we cannot work with
it so we had to apply some graph layout
algorithms to this thing in order to
make it usable so we did and we got a
much better graph with thousands of
samples thousands of node each node is a
sample of course with a lot of clusters
and a visible connections but still we
have a problem because all we see is
black know it's all over the place and
we don't have any context what are these
nodes so we added more information we
had labels to each to each node with
malware family with the name of the
family of the sample and we added colors
and each actor on the graph has its own
color so now it was much easier for us
to see things in a visual way we could
simply see connections between nodes of
different colors we can see clusters of
colors it was much easier to start
working so we had we have this graph and
we can start looking at the connections
and we have three types of connections
on the graph the first one is is the
first type of connection is when two
samples of the same actor and of the
same our family are sharing code with
each other and that means that these
samples belong to the same Mauro family
basically the same different versions of
different variants of the same family
the second type of connection that we
have is when two
samples of different actors or Shannon
code with each other and the but there
are of me of same actor but of different
families and this is very good for
attribution and the third type of
connection that we have is for us the
most important one and the most
interesting one is when two samples of
different actors and of different
families are sharing code with each
other
so before shall we do any results of the
analysis we did let me introduce you
with the first tool that we are showing
today we took this huge map from Gaffey
with the thousands of nodes and turned
it into the what we call the Russian apt
ecosystem up and this is a web-based map
interactive map that you can get a
better understanding of the old echo
system and the connections between the
different families so let's have a quick
demo ok so this is the map and unlike
the previous graph from Gaffey where
each node was a sample in this map each
node represents a Marvel family so we
can immediately start start seeing some
clusters and we can dig deeper and get
the names of each family and we can
hover for example Agent P T Z we can
over a cursor on it
and see the highlighted connection for
example comrade Andrew burrows and the
name of the actor behind it which is
Tula and and if I click on on the node I
see this sidebar on the left which I
have more information about the smaller
family such as the name of the family
the actor behind it when it was first
spotted in the wild other names for the
family where the short description and
references articles research papers that
we recommend to read about this family
and of course links to into the reports
down there and in which you can dig
deeper inside the connections themself
understand what pieces of assembly code
are shared between samples of this
family and samples of other families so
the the team this map and the hoe
Oh data that we walked in all open
source and available on our geetha page
so make sure you try it we invite you to
do your own analysis
using the map ok so now that we have
this huge graph from Gaffey and this map
we can start looking at the connections
themselves and try to understand what
are they are the interesting or the
false positive and for us as reverse
engineers this is where the fun part
began so we did we analyzed and analyzed
so many connections for days and we
really hope to find some groundbreaking
finding some new and interesting
connections that nobody mentioned before
but to our disappointment we could not
find any indication that two different
actors are sharing code with each other
we did find many examples of two samples
of different families but of the same
actor that shared code with each other
but we could not find two samples of
different actors that the shared
connection the shellcode between them
was meaningful enough to say that some
module or library of functions were
shared between a different organization
different Russian organizations so at
the beginning we were quite disappointed
but disappointed by these results ever
really hope to find something more than
that but later we figured that the fact
that no code was shared between these
these organizations is for itself an
interesting piece of information so we
started asking ourselves why why
different organizations do not share
code with each other and why we could
come up with some theories the truth is
that we really don't know and we have no
one to ask and if we did not sure it
will be wise but we have some theories
and maybe the first one and maybe the
strongest one is is that Russia is well
aware for the importance of a good OPSEC
and let away a quick pros and cons for
the decision not to share code in terms
of OPSEC Russia knows that if two
different organizations will share code
with each other in case were two
different operations which are called
with each other in case
one operation will get caught my
security researchers by security vendors
it will put the other operations at risk
so making sure the code is entirely
separate and we'll make sure that this
is not going to happen because nowadays
we use code attribution is a
Constabulary as a very good way to
detect new operations but it comes with
a cost and an expensive one because if
this theory is true that means that
Russia is willing to invest a lot of
money a lot of time a lot of man-hours
in having different teams of meroe
developers writing the exact same
functionality over and over again
instead of reusing the existing
knowledge existing models and this is
very expensive the second theory that we
have is that Russia is that the
different organization do not share code
due to internal politics and while this
might be the case we are not too
familiar with the internal relationships
between with different organizations
under the Russian government so we just
wanted to point it out as a possible
option but we don't have a lot of
information to support it so we did not
find the cross actor connections we
wanted to but we do have a lot of data
to work with we did enormous analysis of
so many samples and we can still use
this data and you already saw it in the
apt map that we showed but we we also
wrote another tool and even more
practical this time so having access to
thousands of samples and millions of
pieces of code that were shared between
these samples allowed us to understand
which pieces of code which genes are
more likely to be shared between the
Russian organizations so we took each
family and took all these samples of
this man of this family and found the
unique genes of these samples of this
family that were repeated over and over
again that were so popular so we
automatically automatically generated
garrison
just for them and we took all these
signatures for all these families put
them in a in a arable set wrap it up
together in a Python script and
executable and we are sharing with you
this tool you can scan your system your
files against known and unknown Russia
amputees and of course this tool and the
rule set and the other rules are all
open source and available on github so
you can simply take it and put it in
your favorite our scanners your favorite
systems and we invite you to give it a
try and give us your feedback about this
tool even contribute to the project just
few weeks ago we got we've got a very
nice contribution from an external user
and that made this tool cross-platform
so now it can run on Windows Linux and
Mac so please don't hesitate to to try
it and that's it thank you very much for
listening
[Applause]