so good afternoon everyone welcome back
after lunch
I hope that you are digesting well I'd
like you to take relax and I'm gonna
talk to you today about a syndrome that
I like to call facepalm and carry on
insecurity now before I get started I
need to tell you a little bit about
myself
I've worked on i.t for over 20 years and
about 10 years ago I took a few applied
cryptography courses and I learned
security is really cool so I decided to
make the switch and I've been working in
security for about six years now and
today I'm going to tell you a tale of
ice oats and teas now if you're sitting
in this audience you probably know what
that means I'm gonna be talking to you
about Star Trek The Next Generation and
the Starship Enterprise
using IOT to boldly go where no man has
gone before
so what I mean by this I started
watching Star Trek The Next Generation a
really old television show this summer
and I started noticing that the Star
Trek Enterprise uses a ton of internet
of things there are things like
replicators warp drives computer oh you
say computer and the computer listens
and then you tell it what to do there's
the transporter the holodeck there's
cloaking devices the medical bay where
dr. crusher just magically waves the
device over the patient and then you
instantly know what the diagnosis is
there is the ultimate interconnected
implant society called the Borg and
finally we have our very most favorite
Android in all of the world data now
when I say a Star Trek is there anyone
here who doesn't know what I'm talking
about okay I had I see absolutely no
hands in the audience so I'm going to go
on the assumption that we can assume we
all know about Star Trek and move on
and so I'm going to tell you about
Internet of Things now in your if you're
in this audience again I know you know
what IOT is but for the sake of this
presentation I'm going to cover
basically the architecture so that we're
all on the same
for this presentation essentially IOT is
comprised of three different levels you
have the bottom level which is basically
the dum level this is a level where you
have devices that are collecting
information about the environment or
giving commands in order to control the
environment in the middle level you have
your apps and you have your gateways and
you have your edge computing devices
these devices collect information
process the information maybe lightly
and ultimately they send that
information into the cloud in the cloud
there are three three responsibilities
there is a data analysis that can go on
their service configuration where you
can actually configure devices to work
the way that you want to and if you're
lucky you get over-the-air updates and
so this is IOT and the question is are
we building in security to a level such
that we can drive a starship through
there through the universe and actually
be confident that we're not going to be
hacked and so to talk about this I'm
going to talk about three security fails
that we've seen in the past year with
respect to IOT the first one has to do
with Captain jean-luc Picard he was
really into drinking tea when he was
thinking about problems on the Starship
Enterprise and in order to get that cup
of tea he would go to the computer
replicator and say tea Earl Grey hot and
then the replicator would create the cup
of tea and he would sip it now today we
don't have replicators to create our
cups of tea but we do have I Oh tea tea
kettles and in hackable podcast from
just a few months ago they pitted IOT
tea of kettles against IOT coffee makers
to see which would be the most hackable
I'm not going to tell you which one won
but what the hackers were able to do was
to disassociate the tea kettle from the
wireless network then they were able to
force the tea kettle to associate to
their rogue wireless network
they were they were able to connect to
the configuration interface of the tea
kettle steel the wireless password
wireless LAN password from the original
network and then connect to that Network
and be poised for further attack so in
this case in this hacking instance they
were able to be in a local area sort of
way use a typical hack and actually gain
access full access to the network which
is very bad my next example has to do
with warp drive
now when the Star Trek Enterprise goes
into warp drives but it goes really
really fast and it has the possibility
of warp 1 all the way up through warp 10
and once you get past warp 10 then you
run into problems with space-time
continuum but we're not going to talk
about that today we're just gonna talk
about regular warp if you think about it
if you go really really fast there's no
possible way a human can control a
starship that way you have to rely on
sensors and some sort of positioning in
order to make that work now naturally we
don't have warp yet but we do have
positioning systems and so the example
that I'm going to talk about today has
to do with vehicle trackers
so the pentest partner is a company in
the UK did their own research on three
different vehicle trackers now these are
add-ons that you put onto your vehicle
after you purchase it and what it does
is it allows you to track your vehicle
in the case that it's stolen well what
they did was they investigated the api's
that allowed the car to actually speak
with the cloud-based tracking software
and what they figured out was without
authentication and without authorization
they were able to track other people's
cars in one instance they were actually
able to without authentication and
without authorization immobilize a car
completely that's a problem so in this
case it's no longer a local attack this
is definitely a remote attack and you're
actually able to influence things in the
physical world
my third and final example has to do
with smart homes now if you think about
the Star Trek and start Starship
Enterprise it is the ultimate smart home
when you say computer the computer
listens to you and then it does what
you're supposed to do well we have that
today we have smart locks we have smart
thermostats we have smart baby monitors
we have security cameras we have smart
speakers everything is becoming super
smart
the problem with that is and the past
couple or in the past year there have
been more and more reports of attackers
actually connecting to people smart
homes and monitoring them in their homes
talking to them over there smart
speakers in some cases there have been
in some cases that have been reports of
attackers talking to babies and their
baby cribs and monitoring the babies and
their baby cribs another attack vector
is that domestic abusers are now using
these devices to control their victims
so they when the victims are not at home
they turn up the temperature of the
thermostat causing higher costs for
utilities and making it difficult for
people to financially make it they also
have there are also reports of they're
changing the codes for locks so that
people can't get in to their home when
they come home for work so in this case
it's no longer just security researchers
figuring out the vulnerabilities it's an
actual real-life attack interesting in
this case - the attacks are you're able
to make these attacks because of weak
passwords so default passwords were used
in those cases weak passwords were used
also passwords where people have reuse
passwords and other systems now these
are nice anecdotes but what if we have a
study that actually goes across just a
few IOT devices well a company called
cyber ITIL did this and they posted
their results in August 2009
they went online and they downloaded
4,000 plus firmwares
from 22 different vendors from over 15
years and what they did was they looked
for positive signs of security controls
in that software and what they found was
this there were no positive trends
across vendors and in fact security
vendors were removing security controls
in their software now when I see things
like this it makes me just want to
facepalm and then carry on IOT security
is never or IOT will never be secure IOT
vendors do not want to build security in
it's too expensive it takes too much
time they have to get things to market
but on the other hand we can't do that
IOT is coming it's here and it's only
going to get more complicated I haven't
talked to you about the botnets I
haven't talked to you about the new
implementations with artificial
intelligence the new implementations
with robotics and the potentialities of
human brain into our human brain
computer interface we need to get
onboard the Starship Enterprise and go
with our IOT friends or we're gonna get
left behind so I started thinking about
ok how can I approach this problem
because it's a big problem and for the
past couple of years I've worked in a
related field but not in IOT I've worked
in operational technology and to me
operational technology is like IOT but
on steroids and there are some
similarities here and I'm bear with me
as I explain what I'm talking about
so operational technology controls
really big things and what I mean by
that is manufacturing chemical
processing electricity generation
transmission and distribution which is
where I've worked water processing oil
and gas distribution
and at the very bottom layer kind of
like you know IOT there are some dumb
devices there are sensors that collect
information and there are field devices
that actually control things like
switches and relays in valves at the
second layer we have smarter devices but
not super smart devices these are PLC's
IEDs and are to use and they collect the
information from these sensors and they
send information down to the field
devices and then these devices in the
middle send the information up to the
smarter systems these are your SCADA
systems your distributed control systems
and these are the systems that prepare
the information and make it consumable
for the operators in the control room
now it used to be that operational
technology was air-gapped it was cut off
there was no connection in in order to
get into the control room you had to
walk into the control room but more and
more today it's moving towards i io t
industrial IOT and what that means is
there there are more and more
connections into the control room from
the outside so there are remote
connections with VPN for support
personnel there are mobile apps and web
applications so that the business people
can get up-to-date information about the
process network so that they can make
really good business decisions and then
you have cloud yes we're controlling
things with the cloud what could go
wrong well what can go wrong if ot is
breached is much much bigger than with
IOT you could have potential big
environmental impact death or injury and
if you damage equipment with an eye or
with an OT attack you're looking at
millions of dollars or euros with of
replacement I'm not the first person who
knows this in the early 2000s a bunch of
countries said this is a real problem so
we're going to put some legislation in
place to make sure that
we put security into these into the
operational technology networks so that
we're protected and so for example in
the USA the Energy Policy Act of 2005
was implemented and this required
electric companies in the United States
to adhere to Newark sip standards with
which have subsequently become more and
more stringent over time in Europe there
was the European program for critical
infrastructure protection in 2004 and
that was introduced in 2004 but really
countries has started getting on board
very recently and for example in Germany
in 2015 they had an amendment to their
energy sector law which required
companies to start implementing and I
SMS and start implementing security
controls and Singapore just introduced
something new just this year their
operational technology cyber security
master plan I love the name master plan
and I'm very curious to see how things
are forced to work in Singapore to
understand the legislation though you
need to understand the different roles
within ot and these roles are assets
owner system integrator and product
supplier now an asset owner is like The
Electric Company they use a bunch of
things to control their network on the
right hand side we have our product
suppliers these are people are companies
such as ABB Siemens GE these are the
companies that give you the devices that
you can use to control your processes in
your network and then in the middle we
have this funny group called system
integrators and these are people who
take requirements from the asset owners
and then they look for the product
suppliers who are going to fulfill the
process needs of the asset owner and so
where do you think the legislation
placed the responsibility for security
they placed it on the shoulders of the
asset owners and not on the product
suppliers which i think is very
interesting and this has led to a huge
growth of security of products and also
services within the security industry
targeted for ot there are security
audits there's new products for
monitoring new products for access
control and new services for managing
processes and keeping things up to date
now is this perfect no are there still
security problems in the area of ot yes
there are lots of things left behind but
we're seeing progress and this is what I
would like to see and what I'd like to
continue to see more of so if we map
these roles from ot the asset owner
system integrator and product supplier
on to IOT what can we learn and so I've
broken down IOT into three different
categories because these are categories
that come up over and over and over when
I'm doing research the first is medical
the second is connected vehicle yes our
cars are full of IOT too and consumer
IOT so in the first case we have medical
devices and the kinds of devices that
I'm talking about right now are
implanted devices that control
physiology in some way or the kinds of
devices that you use to measure your
physiology so you can make decisions
about your health and in the asset owner
category we have just regular old humans
in the system integrator category we
have hospital doctor doctors offices and
medical centers and in the product
suppliers category we have medical
device suppliers and component suppliers
and what's interesting in this case in
medical is that there's movement in the
area of security and for example in the
u.s. there is the Food and Drug
Administration they are able to recall
devices if there is a security
vulnerability that they think is
absolutely critical and they've done so
in the past they're also in the process
of putting together requirements for
medical device product suppliers
and that specifies exactly what security
controls need to be in place in order to
be able to sell in the United States now
this hasn't been put into place yet this
document is in review but the goal is to
give something to suppliers so that they
know what the expectations are with
respect to security in the EU there's
the medical devices regulation and that
was put into place in 2017 and it has
some cybersecurity components to it and
devices need to be compliant with these
requirements by 2020 so once again is it
perfect no but it's a start and we're
moving in the right direction so the
medical bay could potentially be a
reality so what about automotive so once
again we'll start with our three
different categories asset owner humans
system integrator you have auto dealers
service stations relatives and friends
who can actually fix things on your car
you also have product suppliers like
'omg and the ECU suppliers for the OEMs
an automotive is really interesting
they're not looking for legislation to
legislate them the Society of Automotive
Engineers has put together a work group
of representatives across the industry
and they're developing their own
cybersecurity standard so this is the
the proposed standard is Oh 2 1 4 3 4
and it is slated to be ratified in 2020
so it looks like the automotive people
have their stuff together and they're
moving in the direction of security now
it's not legislation so it's going to be
really interesting to see what happens
once this is actually read it ratified
and put into place what the automakers
are going to do and now we're back down
to the level of consumer IT these are
your smart homes these are the things
that you add on to your cars after you
purchase them these are your smart
teakettles what do we have here
in the asset owner once again we have
humans in system integrator there is no
formal system integrator here you have
package instructions you have YouTube
kora Stack Overflow people find
information to get things to work in
their homes in the most unconventional
ways and then you have your products of
layers which are your IOT device makers
your component suppliers and so let's
think about the different ways that we
could legislate the first thing that we
had within ot was legislating the asset
owners meet your asset owners this is
Sally and Jim Jim is retired he likes to
watch YouTube on his Roku device Sally
rooted her first tablet at the age of 65
and she has at least six devices
connected to her network at home at all
times by the way she's leading network
administrator of the house but really
what she likes to do is hang out with
her grand grand kids she doesn't really
like futzing with the technical things
are we going to force them to implement
an AI SMS are we going to find them if
they're not compliant No so we're gonna
move on what about legislation for
product suppliers like in the medical
IOT device rate realm
let's look we actually have an existing
piece of legislation people this is in
California in the United States they
passed a bill that the SB 327 and is
going to go into effect in 2020 is it
going to work my prediction is probably
not there's been a lot of criticism of
this bill and that has a lot of good
intention but it's not specific enough
for product suppliers to be of any use
and so if there is some sort of court
case that that goes on with this
particular law we're going to see the
courts struggle to enforce it we also
have some proposed legislation in the US
there's a House bill once
six-eight this is a bill that would
require any IOT product suppliers that
want to do business with the US
government to actually adhere to a set
of NIST standards which are currently
under construction in the UK they've put
together a code of practice for consumer
IOT security and it's a really explicit
nice list of security controls for IOT
product suppliers the problem is they
don't know exactly which controls they
want to make mandatory because of
reasons I'll talk about in a minute and
then in Germany after the Mirai botnet
problem which knocked out my telephone
for two full days the German government
or the BSI which is a part of the German
government put together about router
security security control lists and it
was really it's really nice so if you go
and read it you're like yeah you're
thinking about security here it's not or
it looks like it could be enforced but
over time talk about that has gone away
so I don't know what what is going to
happen here what's the problem with
legislation why is it so hard well the
four things that I've seen over and over
again by looking at the different pieces
of literature is that there's a lack of
perceived criticality for consumer IOT
now this is changing as real-life
attacks start occurring more and more
often and legislators are actually very
concerned about this but then there's
this lack of expertise they know it's a
problem but they don't know what to do
about it and actually there are several
governments that have put together tasks
forests task force's to try to figure
out okay how do we solve this problem
but it's still in process and so it's
taking some time the next problem is
that in the UK did a study to see okay
if we implement these things what is it
what impact is it going to have what
risks are we going to to suffer and the
first thing that they said is it's going
to negative negatively impact our small
and micro businesses so our startup
companies who are trying to get out the
next best things why security is
expensive and it's hard then there's the
next thing monitoring costs if I am a
government and I put out legislation it
has to be enforced in some way and so
with millions and millions of IOT
devices out there how are they going to
reasonably regulate and monitor and
enforce these regulations it's going to
cost a lot of money and so they have to
get their heads around that and figure
out what to do so we don't have
legislation for for our product
suppliers we don't have legislation for
our asset owners what about standards
let's write some standards and let's
give them to the to the IOT product
suppliers and then everything is going
to be great well I did a search online
to see ok what standards are out there
there lots every reputable organization
has put together their own set of
standards for IOT security so if I were
an IOT product supplier and I knew
nothing about security if I were to go
online and find all of these things I
would be overwhelmed I wouldn't know
where to start and then I just think I'm
going to wait for legislation and
they'll tell me exactly what I have to
do and so standards because there's no
de facto standard or no enforced
standard are out for the moments so what
do we do IOT product suppliers they're
under a lot of pressure to deliver and
so it's causing them to cut out security
and so what can we do as a security
group as a security community to help
out these IOT people so that we can see
security being built in so that we can
be on the Starship Enterprise where you
say computer and then things happen and
you know it's secure our first
opportunity is with
frameworks and the IOT application stack
so earlier in the put in this
presentation I showed you the general
architecture of IOT and the first place
that we can start is in cloud there are
already cloud frameworks out there for
IOT that's going to make building IOT
things much much easier
it has configuration tools it has data
processing tools and it has the ability
for you to actually do over-the-air
updates in a safe and secure way the
only challenge is we don't have a
blueprint way of how to do it
so if you have some time or if your
company wants to do some research and
get your name out there do some research
on how to build a secure implementation
within the cloud for an IOT develop
device and publish it developers are not
stupid they want to do the right things
in fact they're SuperDuper smart and
SuperDuper resourceful if you give them
the information on how to do it and how
to do it securely they will follow and
even more if you if you think about
cloud it's all code now so if you want
to build an infrastructure you write a
script and it builds the infrastructure
for you so rather than giving them
instructions write the code check it
into github and then let them download
it run build their environments and
they'll have something secure to start
with with respect to software
interestingly within the realm of IOT
there's some emerging real-time
operating systems and lightweight
operating systems that are used quite
often you have core OS Ubuntu for IOT
Amazon for free our TOS so on and so
forth if you want to help make a
reference implementation for an IOT
device and then give instructions on how
to harden the environment so that people
can start with a hardened hardened OS
core with respect to the protocols in
the the local area network or the
personal personal area network
you'll see if you start looking at I
ought to devices over and over and over
again the same components are being used
the same components are ble the same
composed for wireless get one of the the
test boards for these and tether creates
once again a mini application and then
test it and then report things that you
find back to the vendors so that they
can close the gaps so that we can have
more secure components and in the area
of hardware I'm still looking for ideas
every single time I open an IOT device
and look in I see a lot of similar
components but they're often configured
in different ways so really what we the
ideal is if you would have some sort of
reference architecture that IOT P
manufacturers can actually rely upon
that is safe and secure that somebody
has vetted and all they have to do is
build their functionality on top of it
there are other opportunities within the
secure development lifecycle one of the
cool things from the cyber ITL study
that we looked at earlier is that they
said there are a large number of
duplicate binaries across multiple
vendors indicating a common build system
or tool chain if we knew what these IOT
manufacturers who are using when they
were building their third devices we
could help them secure the process but
right now there's no large-scale study
across the different providers to see
what are they using so we can't really
help them so if you are a company that
has access to a lot of IOT providers and
you can get some sort of information to
help the broader community so that we
can start building the tools to make IOT
manufacturing more secure do it get the
information publish it and security will
follow
[Music]
and then we have our asset owners help
them so as we were talking about Sallie
and Jim Sally likes to look on YouTube
to figure out how to solve things if for
example her printer went on the fritz
she went into YouTube she found a
tutorial on how to solve the problem
with the printer
she took the printer apart replaced one
of the pieces put it back together again
voila printer works we need something
like that for you for security for all
of these devices that are being
introduced common devices in the homes
we need some sort of YouTube channel
that basically says this is how you set
up the device as securely as possible in
your home the next idea is to have a
consumer security review site this would
be a site that actually rates devices
based on security consumers want to know
what's secure and what's not secure
they love these kinds of sites because
they're getting feedback about what
they're about to put into their homes
there is a site already out there called
the Internet of Dex that kind of
does this this name would not fly with
Sally though she wouldn't trust this
site what we really need is some sort of
consumer site called consumer security
review something very boring but
reputable so that when she goes to the
site she can trust the information that
is being presented there and there's
also an opportunity for security tools
for humans there's a really cool tool
out there right now called Princeton IOT
inspector and what it does is it
monitors your network for for
communication that is strange for IOT
devices it also monitors common IOT
devices for weak passwords so if we can
build something that's going to help
Sally very very easily figure out what's
going on in her network that's a win for
us and then last but not least
in the situation with a smart home where
we had problems with weak passwords
reused passwords the default password we
need some better way for authentication
for these kinds of devices and services
I don't know what that solution is I
have absolutely no clue but we need
something like that so if you're a
security company or a security
individual who has an idea of how to
make this easier for Sally while she
administers her network please introduce
it bring it to the the table so that we
can get this problem solved
now so you're probably sitting in the
audience saying Jen has just told me to
do a whole bunch of stuff and it's not
for a customer and I'm not getting paid
to do it I have two answers to this one
do it as a research and development
opportunity in your company publish the
results and when legislation starts
rolling in for IOT devices you're going
to have evidence of your expertise in
the field and people want to hire your
company that's the first answer the
second answer is the EU has recognized
that this is a problem and so they've
actually put initiatives into place to
funds researchers and small companies
that are interested in doing work in IOT
security so take a look at the different
places or the offers in the you if
something matches what you you or your
company does go for it there are lots of
other ideas that I have for potential
solutions but ultimately what I want is
to make it a lot easier for our IOT
people who are the small businesses and
then startups to be able to deliver the
really cool things so that I can go onto
the Starship Enterprise and explore the
universe so that's all that I have for
you today with the one exception I would
like you to get out there
and engage thank you
[Applause]