hi everyone first of all I'm gonna start
by putting on my glasses because I never
have them on and people don't recognize
me with them on so I'm rather humbled to
be here because believe it or not this
is the 11th time I'm at activity and
this is the first presentation I were
submitted and it got accepted so I'm
forever grateful for the organizers so
um honestly I have so many friends
sitting here in the front row that kind
of feels like a bachelor party at this
point except my fiance is here as well
so okay ah
hacking games my budget so those of you
who don't know me I'm a penetration
tester slash red team lead at Vodafone
I'm a Buddhist University technology and
inside that the security team alumna I'm
enough abet soup enthusiast I like
collecting certificates and since my job
is pen testing my biggest hobbies
writing script I wrote one into all the
possible fields on web applications so
but when I'm not doing that I enjoy good
working building with Legos which I'm
not ashamed of and weight lifting
because let's go
but ah you're not about not here to hear
about me you're here to hear about
hacking ATMs and I'm gonna speak first a
little bit about the journey on how this
whole thing went and one of the reasons
is because one of the questions I get
all the time is hey how do you get into
hacking ATMs without going to jail and I
must speak a little bit about that and
the second reason is that a lot of
people helped me actually doing this and
a couple of thank yous are in order and
I really don't wanna miss that so yeah
story time it all started out and my
previous work place I used to work at
console r12 which is a small consultancy
here in Budapest and we actually offered
testing ATMs as a service we didn't have
too many customers but it gave me a
taste of this whole business and I found
it fascinating I mean an ATM is
essentially a big pile of cash
by a computer if that's not motivating I
don't know what is it also combines a
lot of areas of hacking I mean you get
hardware hacking you get software
reverse engineering malware Network
hacking all of that stuff in the single
package so I think it's fascinating
absolutely like all both my journeys I
think this started out with a conflict
and the conflict was that it was I had
to write my master's thesis and I didn't
want to and I figured the only way I'm
ever gonna finish this is if I pick a
topic that you know interesting and I
don't get tired of it
and my professor at the University dr.
Demento Bucheon was super helpful he
actually let me pick my own topic I mean
obviously they couldn't provide me an
actual ATM to heck that was on me to
solve but they were fully supportive of
me writing my thesis on this so I
started doing research and to avoid
getting into trouble the way I approach
this whole thing was that I started
first browsing open source intelligence
so I did a lot of google hacking I speak
very little Russian so I proposed on
Russian forums apparently legislation on
ATM security is a little bit different
in Russia so you have a somewhat more
information in Russian on ATMs than you
get in English so that was helpful and I
just tried to learn about the different
attack techniques on how you can
actually crack an ATM how do I read a
lot of articles police reports white
papers you name it and by that time I
started getting a picture of all the
different areas you can attack an ATM on
and it was interesting but the problem
was obviously to proceed I needed access
to an actual ATM and that's where it was
great that Bureau Gabriela and her
colleague chubby Shaggy Java who worked
at the bank at the time took me under
their wings
I actually got to test my first ATM in
their bank unfortunately I couldn't try
everything because this was this wasn't
a production ATM it was a test ATM but
they obviously couldn't rip it apart
and but it finally let a little glimpse
into how this whole thing works and I
could try a couple of things and after
this I gave us a really small talk to a
handful of people at the women in IT
security conference two years ago and
there was when I met dr. major Shimon
Bella who is a professor at the
university of public service and I just
treated my talk and the whole
conversation went something like this he
came up to me and he said hey I'm from
law enforcement are you the guy who acts
ATMs I was like yeah we have two ATMs do
you even hack them yeah yeah we just
started doing this and it was awesome
because obviously these were
decommissioned ATMs for disclosure these
are somewhat older models 2006 if but
they were still in use when I started
doing this whole thing in Hungary and I
believe ATMs have a tendency to wander
around from west to east so if something
gets thrown out in Germany that's
usually ends up in Hungary and what gets
thrown out to Hungary usually ends up
far east so yeah these models might
still be in use but they are officially
unsupported so I could do whatever I
want with them um obviously we had to
set some goals on what we wanted to
achieve and since I already knew the
different attack categories and you know
some I had some research on how to
actually do this we set out to be a
series of demos to demonstrate ATM
attacks against these systems and the
purpose for this was to show forensic
specialist police officers whatever how
actually this thing worked and
your life so as I said at this point I
knew quite a lot about ATMs so we're
gonna start by looking at how actually
an ATM is built so we can understand all
the different attack vectors that you
can have an on ATM yeah so forgive my
terrible terrible it's really design
skills but yeah this is where I could
cook up ah obviously everyone is
familiar with this this is the outside
of ATM but we're going to look how it
looks on the inside so an ATM actually
consists of two main parts if you rip
the outer cover off which is essentially
just sheet metal nothing it's it's not
armored on the outside if you go up to
an ATM and knock on the side you can
feel that it really really feels like a
PC case so it's just sheet metal plastic
you have a frame which holds all the
components and actually an ATM is
surprising modular and all these modules
are usually manufactured by different
companies so they have to have a common
interface to work together the lower
half of the whole thing is called the
safe area because that's where the safe
is and the top half is called the
service area and that woods actually all
the components that control the safe and
the whole operation that was the
computer and that holds obviously all
the components that are visible from the
outside the touchscreen the pin pad the
card reader the receipt printer stuff
like that but you can't see on the
outside obviously is that it has a
computer and you would be surprised so
this I've seen ATMs which actually had a
simple EDX IBM computer so it's nothing
special it's not like something fancy
flashy
I know industrial stuff it's usually
just a regular PC to make matters worse
it does
I mean you've all seen the screenshots I
suppose of ATMs crashing it does around
windows
these ones Ryan ran Windows XP newer
ones are much more secure they run in
those
but yeah it's windows what else so you
have a really massive power supply to
run all this an ATM throws a ridiculous
amount of power when it's powered on and
you usually have a hub it's either so it
depends on the manufacturer it's either
USB or some kind of serial hop 2 to
connect all these variants to the
computer so what else do you have in the
lower half you have something that's
really really interesting I mean the
safe itself is fascinating from a
mechanical engineering part but I am NOT
going to talk much about it from our
point of view the most interesting
component of the whole thing is the
dispenser this is like really really
massive this is electromechanical beast
of a machine housed inside the safe and
all it does is just delivers banknotes
to the to the slot on the top but it's
fascinating the complex
the only problem obvious is that it's
mostly controlled by the computer in the
in the top half of the ATM so yeah ok
so that's your crash course on how ATMs
work I think from this you can already
deduce a couple of potential problems
and potential attack vectors I mean as I
said obviously you can just attack it
from the outside so one of the most
common attack methods against ATMs is
the so called skimming attack I'm pretty
sure everyone this room heard about
these this is when they slap something
over the card slot a little gadget that
records the magnetic stripe card data
presented to the ATM and then they just
do this for code from the robot ever the
next one is network network attacks
these aren't that common I mean there
was a surge I think a year ago when they
actually didn't attack the ATMs but
instead attacked the back end through
these network connections sometimes
these are exposed I mean you can see it
on you
eighteens please just on the street but
sometimes Etienne's use wireless so you
don't even see this but if you can
access that you can try your luck with
that that can get some interesting
results as well but the actual
interesting technical attack methods
usually involves somehow getting into
the service area as I said this is
usually protected by weak materials so
you can just ask actually drill a hole
into it and access the wiring and this
is what most of the attacks that are
more advanced are based on so they first
reel a hole and they connect to some of
the components inside the ADM depending
on what you want to do you can either do
a Navarrete AK where you just plug in
the USB into the control contributor and
install them over on that it has two
interface obviously the ATM software and
drivers and stuff there to dispense cash
or you can do a black box attack which
is if you look at that way I mean it's
kind of like a hardware mall there you
plug it either on the dispenser or
between the dispenser and the computer
and just you you just do a man in the
middle attack against the traffic
between the computer and the dispenser I
mean you can see on this picture this is
so black boxes are supposed to be small
so you because you are supposed to put
it in the ATM then close it back this on
the picture this is a Russian black box
and it's massive so that card there
that's an is a bus and it's like this
long so it's it's really it's a backpack
size thing the whole point of this is
that it runs the driver that interfaces
with the ATM and just sends commands to
the dispenser so this is the basic
layout so and yeah so mal there mal
there is a really interesting because
you would think that all the ATM vendors
write their own software and that's true
to an extent but these now can actually
be
cross-platform because the financial
industry has something called
XFS protocol and that is basically a
common API that all the vendors software
have to call and most malware target
this directly so it doesn't matter of
each vendor the ATM was made by you can
install the malware on it and it's gonna
interface with the XSS API and just
dispense cash to that so it's kind of
amazing
so I set out to build try to be at all
of these things I choose first of all I
wanted to build myself a skimmer because
you know that seemed like something from
engineering perspective that could be
done doesn't didn't look too
sophisticated to be honest I set out to
get a mother sample that I can actually
run on my test ATMs and see if it works
or not so I just there are a lot of
different samples some of them are
really hard to get but event you're
going to see I went with a Russian
sample which was kind of advanced so I
chose that one
and I also set out to be a black box
attack which again I thought would be
interesting from engineering perspective
but turned out to be a real nightmare so
these are the three things I'm going to
talk about so let's start um
skimming to understand skimming you're
gonna know a little bit about how this
whole magnetic stripe thing works
basically I mean I ran into a lot of
misinformation on this topic when I
research it because people don't really
seem to realize what is actually
contained on the magnetic stripe and how
you decode that is it encrypt it not
encrypt it how it works yeah
so the thing is on a physical level the
magnetic stripe has something called an
NRC and arbiter to zero in coding and
basically just those binary data so if
you stripe it it's just a series of
chirps you can actually use a sound card
and the magnetic tape had to decode it
or yeah in theory the data
hold is I mean depends kind of on the
manufacturer but usually it is the card
number the expiration date and the name
of the cardholder so it doesn't have the
pink code or whatever but and this is
where most people in from Hungary ask
how do you use that because that's
usually enough for payment right I'm in
Europe because you either use a chip and
pin or tap your card or whatever the
thing is legislation in the banking
sector differs across countries so in
some countries you can actually pay just
swiping your card and they don't ask for
any code or anything and what happens is
they steal card data in Europe then
kinda export it to those countries I
mean you might ask what are those
countries there must be some
underdeveloped whatever kind of
countries yes so the biggest one is the
USA so in the US you can actually just
save it swiping your card so there you
go so yeah this is data you have to read
obviously there are some challenges
because it's not really a sterile
environment you know it's not like when
you actually swipe your card it goes
through the card slot it shakes whatever
you can actually by skimmer Hardware
online and as far as I observed the
price really depends on how obvious it
is that it's a skimmer so you can get
the skimmer for five thousand US dollars
you can get a portable small form-factor
card reader that this has advanced error
correction for incorrect reads and the
memory chip and bluetooth that goes
about for a thousand dollars or
something but I mean calling a skimmer a
portable small Fox or card reader is
just like you know calling a handgun
stainless table a dispenser so it yeah
but I didn't wanna do that reason a I
had about 100 dollars for this whole
project and that was a little bit
outside my budget and reason BAE I
didn't wanna get in trouble so I just
went on and design my own so since I was
an engineering student I approach it
from engineering perspective so I just
laid out in my head you I'm gonna need a
magnetic tape head
I'm gonna need an operational amplifier
I'm gonna need an ad convent go after
connected to microprocessor I'm gonna
need you Artie to connect to the
Bluetooth interface I'm gonna need see
view and I'm gonna write a custom
application to receive all the data from
the Bluetooth module I was like yeah no
I mean I had like one weekend for this
whole project so what I actually ended
up doing was I bought the Chinese in
card reader from eBay and sleddin
Arduino on it so tough luck but it
worked
I mentioned Bluetooth I really wanted
something with Bluetooth the reason is
because you know men love bluetooth no I
wanted it because actual card with
schemers and nowadays have Bluetooth and
the reason for that is it reduces the
risk of for the attacker I mean you know
if you just have a memory chip on it you
have to go to the ATM install it wait
for people to use their code hoping
doesn't get discovered and then go back
again and you know retrieve it with blue
services you can just drive-by download
the data and forget about the schemers
so that's also if you go on google play
you can download an application called
schemer scanner which is basically an
app for discovering Bluetooth modules
that are commonly used in skimmers I
believe it was written for the US market
they have card slots on gas pumps as
well so gas pump skimmers are really
really common and I want it to be as
something that could be detected by this
application so I choose a Bluetooth
module that was coming in in actual
skimmers so oh this is my schematic this
is the Chinese in card reader it is
absolutely amazing from an engineering
perspective so this is a card reader
that actually acts as a USB keyboard
when you plug it in so what happens if
you swipe your card it just type is your
card number into notepad so it's it's
lovely
ah so I use the USB shield
connected that to the Arduino said that
the card readers actually keyboard
slapped on Bluetooth module and wrote a
few lines of code and it worked this is
the housing I made
you can see my amazing craftsmanship
there I'm calling it the milk skimmer
but it actually works this isn't a
credit card it's my gym membership card
I almost photographed my own credit card
and that would be shameful but now and
yeah this is the application I mean this
is a standard USB USB bluetooth serial
terminal for Android I implemented a
couple of commands you can just dump the
core data from the from the machine and
yeah I mean it's not super reliable but
for demonstration purposes it works okay
let's move on now there again first I
approach this from the engineering
perspective so I actually tried writing
my malware from the bottom up carefully
reading the XFS API reverse engineering
software whatever but again you know I
had a deadline so what I ended up doing
was I actually required a sample of the
cube came all there I'm yeah I speak a
bit of Russian but I have no idea how to
pronounce this or what it means I hope
it's nothing dirty and this is a really
really famous I think you might have
heard about this is a really famous
mother it was it started its operation
around 2009 but it was at its peak in
2014 I believe and the reason why this
is still around is because it's cross
platform and it's awesome
how do you get them over samples so
apparently just go up to people on the
internet and ask for it so I just went
up to research and hey I need a TM over
for research purposes she's like are you
sure this is for research purposes I
mean yeah and she just sent me a bunch
of those I was really happy but yeah you
can also do it with google hacking and
obviously because sis admins are people
some people just upload a TM ever to
virustotal so yeah
interesting thing about yukine is that
it's written in C sharp or I mean dotnet
which is awesome because you can use DNS
pi if you haven't used the Nspire before
try it it's like one of the most amazing
free software I've ever used so you can
use this to disassemble it and modify it
it has some really really interesting
mechanisms built into it some which are
standard to male there some which is
unique to 80 another I'm gonna talk a
little bit about those as well and yeah
so the whole problem was this had to be
patched in order to be suitable for
demonstration purposes and I'm just
going to talk about the reasons why so
first of all the malware has an anti
sandbox check in check I mean it's like
one of the Maverick coding one of the
ones to avoid sandbox when the ATM when
the marver is started you put in a delay
asleep and you know the sandbox just
times out if it's not set up properly
obviously for demonstration purposes
this is not too convenient because no
student is going to wait 16 hours to see
a demo of
80ml there so I had to remove that that
was fairly trivial another interesting
thing the mavar was set up to only run
at specific intervals during the day and
during the week as well so all the cash
health operations apparently happened
between two at night and four at dawn on
Saturdays so yeah also not too
convenient for demonstration purposes I
mean I could have just set the clock on
the ATM obviously but you know your
thought it was more awesome to patch
this out as well there are a lot of
white papers on this malware online and
in Casper scales down one a bunch of
other companies is done one but is
usually obvious that they couldn't
actually try it on a real mother a real
atm sorry because the control mappings
were almost always incorrect so I had to
reverse engineer there as well and this
is messed up honestly so you have key
codes in hex
and well I spent like 1/2 hours on just
crazily pressing buttons is dead for
example the number of on key on the
keyboard is actually 0 x2 in hex it
doesn't make sense so yeah that's
confusing but it was really awesome that
the Melva routers actually could
intercept the keyboard messages from the
pin pad and use that for controlling the
ATM oh yeah
miscellaneous stuff so since this was
used by organized crime there was a
pretty neat authentication process so
how this how they operated from yeah my
point of view is kind of fascinating
because what they did is they had
apparently smart people in the gang and
muscle in the gang and they usually sent
out people to collect the money from the
ATMs but obviously the two groups didn't
trust each other so what the smart guys
did is they implemented a challenge
response protocol in the malware so when
someone went out to the ATM and
activated the malware it presented a
challenge code and wouldn't accept
anything until a proper response was
provided so the crook at the ATM had to
activate the marver phone the guys back
at HQ hey guys this is a challenge cause
I need the response code the guys would
give him the code and this way they
would know who was redrawing is how much
money at which ATM which is awesome
obviously you can deduce from this that
it had another software component for
generating the responses based on
challenge code and that just wasn't
looking included with the sample I spent
quite a lot of time we were sent during
this algorithm how this whole thing was
generated it's I mean it's messed up
seriously it's really messed up I'm not
gonna presented that now because I think
that would be a little bit our line but
I just ended up replacing the whole
thing with the static code so so it
would be easier to demo the whole thing
so oh yeah extra my first write it in
didn't work it just started spinning the
ATM and no money came out it was like
baffled I mean I spent like 20 hour
reverse engineering patching valuer
what's wrong and it turned out that the
mayor wanted to dispense a stack of 40
banknotes which is like pretty thick and
my ATM just couldn't do that so just
choked on the lot of money that was
trying to dispense and yeah I had to
patch it as well
so malware video let's see how does this
work to do there you go
okay so this is the default interface of
the ATM nothing fancier apparently this
one came from the UK yeah eight pounds a
year yeah
so first step you go up to the ATM and
you enter a cheat code and boom you have
a cheat menu
you can't just select the cassette from
each video cache and you have a
challenge code here and you see it says
enter session key to proceed so you're
gonna need the session key as I said I
just replaced the algorithm with the
static key because that was easier it's
really tedious to type because it's like
8 characters long boom it's really
awesome good oh sorry
rewind because it's really yep as you
can see it does a couple of other things
to protect itself as well I mean
disables the local network and only
after that does it allow the cache to
proceed this is obviously to disable
alarms and stuff like that okay and you
can see cached operation permitted they
go and yeah just pick which cassette you
wanna video from which is awesome so you
just select the cassette enter the code
and it starts working working working
again all the ATM super slow takes a lot
of time but if you just wait patiently
then we're gonna get a stack of
four pieces of copy paper yeah that was
what the ATM was filled with actually so
yeah it works so yeah this is problem
that was the conclusion of the the
malware part I was really happy with it
I honestly didn't believe it would work
but it did so yeah next step black box
as I said first I approach this again
from an engineering perspective so I
really really wanted to do it on a low
level and figure out how to you know how
this whole thing works the communication
protocol everything and I wanted to do
usb man-in-the-middle attack and just
hands up guys who has ever tried
debugging USB actually yeah
I mean I haven't before this so those
people will raise their hands gonna know
that this is nightmare
so the USB protocol is really complex
you have device classes different speed
settings whatever and the cherry on top
of the whole thing and obviously Windows
and Linux they treat the USB stack
differently so whatever we try it's not
gonna work even though I knew all this
I did try doing the USB
man-in-the-middle attack and I'm
mentioning this because I by doing this
whole thing I found a really amazing
tool and even though it didn't work in
the end I just want to talk a little bit
about this because it might be used for
some some of you if you try to ever do
this it's called the USB Q framework is
written by an engineer named Benoit
Cameron and I actually talked with him
because the documentation was yeah a
little bit lacking the point is this
software runs on a bigger bone black
board which is if you don't know what
that is it's kind of like a Raspberry Pi
the only difference is it has two USB
interfaces and one of them is a USB host
interface and the other ones are USB
client interface so what you can do is
if you have two devices I mean a USB
device in the USB host a PC in this case
and you want to listen on in the traffic
between the two endpoints you can just
plug this thing between the two things
and you can proxy the traffic much like
I don't know it works you just for USB
and I actually ended up writing a module
for it which can modify traffic on the
fly using regular expressions and so
this is how the whole setup looks
nothing fancy I tried a bunch of USB
hardware I tried intercepting USB
keyboard messages tried intercepting
various game controllers and yeah it
worked I mean I could do stuff like
flash I don't know not lucky and things
like that and at this point I thought
this would be enough because you know I
mean this shouldn't be so complex I mean
the protocol itself between the PC and
the dispenser
it just you know how much how many nodes
see one of these pens from which
cassette it shouldn't be something
sophisticated turns out it is I mean
when I connected my USB proxy to the ATM
there was just so much traffic on that
bus that proxy just crashed so there was
no way I'm gonna do this from the ground
up and I was kind of disappointed at
this point so I tried doing Plan B and
Plan B was to reverse engineer the
driver on the on the ATM which
communicates with the dispenser and by
reverse engineering the driver I you
know just did what every reverse
engineer does googled all the strings I
could find in the binary and I found the
legitimate testing to for that model of
ATM which could be used for testing the
dispenser now obviously this has
security controls so you can just make
the ATM spew out cash during the test
because that's you know outside
operational policy so it only works if
the safe is safe is open only then can
you test the dispenser which you know
doesn't really make it useful for that
attack purposes but it turned out that
someone has actually reppin eyes this
already
they patched it remove the security
controls from the tool and the attack is
actually called coffee maker you can
look it up online their only problem was
I could get my hands true I don't know
like rapidshare or some crazy side on
the original legit - so I had the real
tool but I didn't have the modified I
didn't know the patch and it's like I
mean that's not an enormous binary but
it's kinda big you can get lost in it
very easily because it can be used for
testing the dispenser the printer
whatever so it has a lot of stuff you
would need to analyze if you started
reverse engineering it and yeah but
there was a rainbow someone one of the
researchers to analyze this evil -
actually released euro rules for
detecting the modified tool yeah I can
see a couple of people grinning so what
happens you have a legit tool that works
you need to write a rule that detects
the evil tool that is patched and
obviously if the error will you wrote
detect the legitimate tool that's going
to be a false positive so you don't want
to do it what do you do you base your
error rule on the patch that has been
applied to the legitimate tool obviously
now if you do the simple math you have
the legit to apply a patch to it you get
the evil tool now you want to make the
error rule the right do you have the
evil to legitimate tool you get the
difference between the two and that's
your our rule because that's the only
way you can differentiate between the
legitimate and evil two problem euro
euro rule is going to be the patch so if
you reverse engineer the euro rule you
which is basically just a byte string
you get the patch and yeah the super
sophisticated modification the patch
it's blurry on reason on purpose but you
can see the arrows hands up who finds
the arrow that's missing or what
happened
yep yep exactly so it's like the classic
when you had correct means in the 90s to
disable serial protection or something
like that you replace a jump with an OP
and yeah that's the page basically so we
are based on this I could actually
modify the legitimate tool and yeah use
it as a black box um I was yeah so since
this thing is from 2006 everything runs
on Windows XP the driver only runs on
Windows XP the tool only runs on Windows
XP so I need the Windows XP machine and
on top of all this it won't run in a
virtual machine because it needed some
idle access to the USB stack funny story
just a week before I did all this thing
I went to my neighbor to fix this
computer and he was like I mean I fixed
it it was like super grateful and said
hey I have an old laptop do you need
that and I was like yeah sure whatever
I just tossed it in the drawer you know
I'm gonna do it something with it later
and yeah I ended up using this
monstrosity for for running the two so
yeah I got lucky
so this is the tool this is the patch
tool actually as you can see in the
background the safe of the ATM is closed
and I just you know I just have a cable
plugged in inside somewhere but the ATM
itself is closed and what you're gonna
see is basically you just press the
button wait a little bit and and there
you go
you acted and yeah that was the basic
idea behind this whole thing okay
as usual I was little but I think I told
you everything I wanted to I mean no
people are shy in the beginning but just
go ahead ask questions I mean usually
people have a lot of questions so I left
like 10 minutes for that so we have four
extra minutes just go add anyone
gentlemen there how do ya great question
so if you go back did it did it today
today no not this not this not this yeah
dad so depending on what you want to
deliver it to the ATM a black box or a
mail there you drill either on the
bottom or the top of the ATM because on
the bottom you have cabling which goes
to the dispenser and on the top you have
the PC on the slot and the PC has front
panel USB which is great so what people
do yeah exactly
so what people do is actually they use
like a a piece of wire or something
strapped USB cable on it use a USB hub
plug it in the USB hub has a flash drive
a mouse and a keyboard and just install
the mother on it so that's basically it
on some ATMs you don't even have to
drill because they have panels that pop
up for the purpose evil you know putting
in advertisements or stuff like that so
yeah it's it's nothing fancy nothing
sophisticated I'll bring the mic over to
you thank you
so about the mother part you mentioned
the smart guys and the muscle guys and
even in this picture it seems that the
ATM's has a camera did the mother do
something with that as well as I said it
disables network connection so the
camera is interesting I think in ATMs
because if you look at a catalogue for
ATMs that is listed as an extra so don't
so not all ATMs have cameras installed
actually and those that have cameras not
all of them are connected to the backend
some of them just log to the disk it
didn't try to delete any files from the
disk but the thing is so these old ATMs
have cameras that have resolutions of
VGA so 640 by 480 or something like that
so you can hardly make out anything on
them and some of the ATMs are only set
up not to record video just take
pictures at key moments so it's super
easy to evade it
it just takes pictures when you insert
the card you type something and you know
from a whole transaction you get like
three pictures which is it doesn't have
motion sensors or anything so it's
pretty bad anybody else have any hope
just just a funny one why didn't you use
banknotes from monopoly yeah I mean
these ATMs are fitted to do standard
sized cash I mean you know it varies
between countries but you have likely
the slides but that's actually a nice
idea but I don't think the slides ago as
little as monopoly money but that would
be cool true anybody else have a
question from ourselves
no it seems nothing myself thank you
very very much thank you very much
[Applause]