hello everyone I'm Tomas Tamera B's I'm
really glad to be here too my first time
in Hungarian activity so today we will
talk about little study of perform about
info sectors but first here's my geetam
maybe if you already seen one of my tool
just say hello but we'll see after so
here's the agenda I won't be too long
and I will show you a lot of stuff so to
be frank in the last decade I think you
managed to see it also there there's
been lots of new tools crafted and why
the first question is why because I
think from my point of view some horse
with dreams now come true just as you
can now scan the entire ipv4 space
within just before with an ID biani pot
you can scan all the around the world
and find a lots of multiple stuff you
can query all open source information
you want through a platform like scans
dot IO showed an and a lot of open
source massive databases you can know in
the cooperate Windows word you can pound
and a lot of cooperation first structure
even lunch one with to like blow down
and mimic ads and you can fighting is
the trend is the current trend so you
can first everything you want right now
you can you can stow a lot of password
and hashes try to crack them every time
the second reason I think is Hawaii with
you a lot of - right now because coding
became kind of Scioscia this is like it
was I think it's still the github dragon
social coding but to be frank I've seen
a lot of InfoSec people getting their
coding skills enhanced they want to
write some good and practical tool with
preference Lee with new version are
beaches and some exhibition already
devoted to the tool crafting art such as
the blackout Arsenal only devoted to
tools and to be frank as a conclusion
more and more people are writing more
and more good quality stuff and the
third one I think there's
Motul Halloween attack and defense why I
think we are gaining a lot of popularity
for the blue side we've moved we are
moving from the breaking era to the
securing and building in wrath through
bug bounties which honor some who knows
the blue side with the massive source of
information coming from the crowd and
then at a certain point I think we are
finally taking advantage of the
visualizations such as blue down
representing stuff in graph and it helps
you know defenders and attackers but in
the same time so a lot of tool have been
developed and good quality stuff but we
still rely on some horse cool tools such
as this one I think you can see it it's
dates from 1997 which is an map and it's
still the most pertinent for eminent to
tool to perform some port scanning THC
which produced a lot of fuel which like
Hydra you know you've seen the date it's
not coming from last year and the group
was formed in the middle of the 90s and
their truth is still quite use I think
even even folk from beginners to
professional in 2003 feel down the guy
behind a map perform like a benchmark or
a survey and in so almost twenty years
ago you can see what which was which
where they were told and the renowned
Toulon you can recognize that the most
most of the tool listed here are still
active and maintained nikto enmities can
iron only I won't say maintained but
still exist in IAM working cane in a
hovel OpenSSL which is the horse cool
stuff
THC Hydra actively maintained so in the
same time we developed a lot of neutral
but we are still using some good old
tools and to be frank I was asking I was
wondering when I facing this this
conclusion I was asking how are these
new tools really built and are they
really
than the previous one where they're
hosted if there are trends can we can we
say that every tool is posted some in
some places specific places how long are
the maintained you have seen some n
happens hold tools they are most of them
are still maintained and they're really
better design than the whole one
remember than the first version of
netcat was vulnerable to stack buffer
overflow so which is a shame for
security security practitioner using a
secret even Harbor stuff and all you
know how would it how did it evolve what
are the trends and how our community
have been doing with this kind of tool
so what I've been doing is analyzed the
metadata from full source of publication
for renown and major sources the first
one I think you know it it's packets Dom
which is a cool old-school platform the
second one to watch third one kid
Floyd's
and the last one know where this is the
source of my study from the to the the
first the two first sources I've been
crawling manually the results in the
achieve and you'll see just after for
the two last one I've been taking the
very nose that come feed which provides
structure data for free which is very
helpful and how did I did it with that I
take oh I don't know if you know it's a
French based startup doing an amazing
tool mostly I use it as a excel excel
better better than Excel tool mostly
excellent stories we can try it for free
there's a free fredison I will not Rama
stretching the two but I've been doing
all the study with this tool because of
the convenience and how many record have
been alized so four packets Tom you see
almost seven seven thousand tools watch
one thousand and a half deployed three
thousand and nowhere one thousand
just was as I was saying if you don't
know where that come just try just check
their website I don't know if some of
you know that come stuffy is here but I
want to say hello to these people
because they are providing for free
really good quality and they're
structuring data of instruct
unstructured feed blog
IOC exploit whatever so just check out
their website and I was using for my
study I was downloading the correction
the whole the whole dataset from from
what was it what are they calling our
chip so first the source of the data set
so I'm switching okay
wait for it so know what I've been doing
is I'm after collecting rubbing all the
data I was saying that packets Dom the
first post and the first tool post in
packets Tom started from 1994 which is
not relevant because all the other
sources are not where not existing at
the time so I was featuring so from the
last decade and you can see that the
most of the most of the sources have the
same order of magnitude you know it's
counts in thousands few thousands of
data so the first thing the first graph
I wanted to draw is this one so you can
see don't don't take a look at the end
of the graph you know it's it's it feels
like it goes down but it's just because
it's the four quarter of this year and
it's just started so it's normal that
the numbers are really lower than the
previous so you just have to just to
stop here and you can see that on the
whole if you draw a line it goes on and
it goes up from 2010 so the first
conclusion is more and more tools are
being published and if you see it by
saucers it will print so you can find
here the four major sources keep Lloyd
packets Tom tools watch and nowhere so
the first thing we see is Keith Floyd is
really buying everything and publishing
a lot of love a lot of Tours and is
trying to be the new references for
force for tool publication and here you
can see that by a packet Psalm it's
quite maintaining his rhythm which is
quite good
on the contrary then tourists watch the
talk which is I don't know I don't know
why I don't know the reason but
publication out decreasing a lot in to
be zero and nowhere the same there was
there was a peak few years ago but now I
don't know it starts to decrease a bit I
don't know the context I don't know the
reason but still so you can see kid
ployed is trying to build a new source
the other question I was asking sorry
you know there was a question I was
asking was where the tool really hosted
for Indian even if you get published on
one or one of the four major sources in
the end the tool is supposedly hosted on
Gita you can see the hegemony as we say
in France the magnificence of github
compared to all other sources
I was pretty to be frank I was pretty
surprised that to see that bitbucket is
ready go way down you know the good old
wood sauce for cut girl.com which is now
shut down but bitbucket is you can have
the impression that bitbucket is already
developed for security people but we
don't like apparently to host our tool
on bitbucket
which is not a good quite a good idea I
think we should build some residency
because tomorrow is github closes or has
a new policy what our stuff is gonna be
locked there then another interesting
RAF is so we can see from the previous
graph than get-ups was for google.com
and baquette kind of where
at least in our mind the four sources
for to law sting and you can see read
that before cute this is this one before
q2 or q3 of 2013 you know they're well
not like needed emo needs somewhere
because other competition was trying to
fight and try to share the market but at
some Tony turning points in 2013
ready github won everything you can see
the the graph now everything is indeed
up in our community that's a conclusion
of this graph apparently yeah so if
everything if I go back to my slides if
everything is on github let's focus on
github so what I did is taking the
analyzing to 2300 of github repositories
for info sectors and just having trying
to great to get some statistics for each
one and computing the average the median
and the standard deviation as just a
scientific study so stars here you can
see that on the average an info sexual
get one one thousand stars and the
median is 200 so remember the median
divide the words into the upper part and
the lower part so here's a lower part so
if you develop some tours and you gather
a number of stars above this number
almost as I'm sorry almost three on the
red so you're in the top part and if you
are below well you can gain some
popularity it will help then for Fox you
can see the number so there are more
stars on Fox people are more inclined to
to like it will then maybe trying to
contribute this is maybe the first
impression the Watchers is kind of the
same number of the stars why because one
star in this is one watch on github
release is a interesting number we don't
we don't release on much we don't
release motivation in at least in the
get up format you know
creating a real and a true release we
are publishing review on the average you
see few releases if you don't publish
anything yeah on the on the median line
if I think you cannot go down maybe if
you publish one release which is broken
maybe you're even worse than the median
maybe but at least
yeah we don't provision much the size on
the average our tool weigh 15 Meg's
on the median is one mix the commit
number of commits you can see it it
doesn't say anything I don't have any
expansion for this but the next one the
next indicator is really interesting and
what what was one of the the key points
I wanted to investigate on I was really
asking in our community we're publishing
a lot of stuff how long do we maintain
our tools ready because having a good
tools working on day one is group is
cool but same tool working ten years
after of five years affair is really
better so you can see that on the
average we maintain our tools during two
years and a half which is two to my
opinion pretty pretty good because we
publish a lot of scripts you know quick
and dirty stuff and this numbers show
that at least on the average well
mentioning train wanting to maintain
longer this kind of quick and dirty
stuff because maybe some people trying
to be trying to take this trip and try
to make them better and main officially
maintain them all the issues now you can
see this kind of numbers so a lot of
issues what really interesting that is
the ratio of whole issues rated to the
open one so I think you can see on
average we have this number in on open
we have this one so we are I think
pretty good on fixing stuff or at least
trying to closing tickets and issues
maybe not for a good reason but at least
we were trying to to get involved into
the maintenance maintenance
on the pull request is also I think a
good number with this kind of number are
continually evolving in increasing so
you have like 70 under average 70 pull
requests contribution total and we also
validate a lot of pull requests because
you can see that the number of open pull
requests is pretty low compared to the
pull request number so let's go back to
the graph so as I was saying so from the
first pile of stuff the study everything
that everything is kind of a steady on
github so let's focus on github and
right now I wanted to know what are the
the most stared info sector so you'd you
can see everything here but from the
study from the whole the 23,000
repositories in eyes you can see the
most popular one so here I don't really
know the what you stood is really
doing I I don't know it I don't use it
but I think it's for good see the number
is really the true one the true first
after we have a sec list from the onion
missile that shows something interesting
to me that we can have the best tool in
the world in the end we want with
preferably wants a good list a good war
list so this this repository hosts on
good words for every sing bass words
your user name whatever and that there's
something about the community building
to this quite ship maintaining and
having a good word list is the key is
the key to perform a good penetration
tester or to protect yourself
jacocks which is a reverse engineering
stuff you can see here Metasploit so
with this project is in the top one two
three four five top five most tears
almost appreciated through landeta
apparently Deidra which which did a good
breakthrough in this ranking because
it's
previously publicly a new tool and from
the beginning it just got accepted by
our community and the numbers are pretty
high pretty fast can reconsider SQL map
the NS pilot speaker this morning told
about this DNS pie so you can see it is
in the top 20 most preferred favorite
tools in our community the thing is from
this graph if I draw conclusion I think
mostly of France if stuff apart from the
apart from the from from few one which
can be used from attacking defense but
most of the tool you can see me to
sploit DNS PI for reverse engineering
cyclist for brute forcing stuff
deidre ml TM proxy this is more
offensive stuff which was I think I
don't know you cannot like you have you
have the right not to agree with me but
I think mostly offensive stuff then if
we move on to the most repository
you can see here the first one is
Metasploit so it's validates the
popularity in the attractiveness of
Metasploit for people trying to
contribute then you can see you can see
that off tool we've seen just before
jeddaks Deidre Emmett am proxy empowered
in the top twenty two repositories
mimikatz which again see I still see in
the most folk most mostly offensive
stores I don't know I don't know I don't
know why I cannot explain I think people
want to when this year good tour they
want to fork it making some slight
modification for their own usage and use
it for mostly offensive purposes and
maybe at the end trying to contribute
back and to pot back there a
modification to the to the official tour
then for the biggest number of you
cannot see but this is the biggest
number of open issues here I see mostly
maybe defensive stuff you can see miss
which arrived in the second position you
I think you who in this room knows raise
your hand about Miss
Oh phew your hands I would expect more
miss be the project from the Luxembourg
set and he helps certs and Bruce blue
teamers by being a summarization of fire
season and defensive stuff for everyday
purposes I please ashes from malware and
so you can see rather headers or so with
the biggest number of open issues so
people want to contribute Rio and to
trying to fix or to just to open some to
our sake I would I say just to yet to to
show some bugs in this world and want by
Indian maybe wanting to to infer to
improve it and you can see kuku some
dogs still Metasploit and map which is
real attack n different stuff
then let's move on with the next graph
which is the InfoSec tube with the
biggest number of open pull requests so
after opening your issue maybe at the
same time you want to open to contribute
by submitting a poor request
so here the I think we we see mostly
mostly defensive stuff with nmap I think
people want to increase their nmap just
to be allowed to be yeah not to be a lot
but to to be able sorry to be able to
detect no stuff you can see anger which
is not pretty a difference if stuff
maybe if mostly for reverse engineering
but yeah this is the I think this is an
interesting graph to see that the
project was the most contribution open
contribution and then when interest ring
graph also is the top 20 of the info
sexual with the longest maintenance
period so here you can see seven
thousand days it's in it's in days the
graph get up
so seven seven thousand days it's more
like it's close to twenty years ago 20
years ago get up wasn't invented so I to
be frank I was expecting six is roughly
the number already cheap you know my my
whole my whole study is up
nothing is really good here and I've
been to several repositories and no I
discovered that on github you can have
back back dates so some cricketer which
is the first one with the being the most
the most maintain yeah you can you can
see here the first I don't know if it's
big enough for you but it dates from
1999 for the first commits on this
implicit O'Toole after being published
on github dates ready like 20 years ago
you can see in also in the changelog it
really starts from from from this period
so good news in my study is not that
factored so this graph here you can see
you can you can find after sampling
quatre TCP replay which is also a good
good old tool ettercap in packet which
is which start to be a whole project
actively maintained but still a good
good framework for Windows Windows
communication and map you can see your
Widow land map here a crack or so
Trinity I don't think it's them I don't
know if it is hunter in Norway with
Justin before so yeah it was interesting
to see because to be frank
apart from an map attack happen and in
packet I wouldn't know a lot of tool
here so in apple-pie net Spock PSEG I
don't know this tool maybe you do but I
don't know and to be frank they have
been actively maintained in our
community then what I wanted to see are
interesting the languages so
we've seen so far that everything is
hosted on github there's more and more
tools we have I think maybe good numbers
of maintenance and contribution in our
community so the next thing I wanted to
see is the language the most preferred
language we use and so from the github
repositories in scanning the languages
there's an API to determine for project
the proportion of Python or whatever
language code you have in this project
so teram the first language our most
preferred languages python I don't know
if it's surprising to you I don't it's
not a surprise to me because first I
like peat Python and I see a lot of
total written in Python because in
Python you have can do everything
there's a lot of library you can really
perform everything and reuse instead of
develop then you can see shell HTML so
in the top five we have C and JavaScript
and what's interesting because I have
been doing this study I've been praying
the study twice this year and I've seen
a nice trend in the in the figure so in
the early early year version of this
study C shop was behind Objective C so
you can see that C shop is drained is
gaining popularity
then go was behind Perl so we can see
that go is trying to again advance in
our community and the last one which is
interesting
get up classifies it as a language
docker file so and the cough I was
behind CSS so by with this movement we
can see that docker c-sharp and go is
gaining popularity and being more and
more used but still Python in shell is
are the most predominant languages that
we use so whatever so if a lot of to
laughs are mostly developed in Python
let's focus on Python and then
on the next part of the study I've been
taking all the Python tools published on
github and trying to see some trends are
trained trying to see the
characteristics of this of this movement
so here I don't know this is a dump
I don't know why I've been doing this
but I wanted to see the top 20 of the
info sectors in Python having the
biggest number the biggest number of
dependencies so maybe the most complex
stuff we have so far so you can
recognize some leaking cut which is if I
don't mistake an Andre the Andre the
framework or general purpose stuff to
act on Android application so plazo you
can recognize plays over here silent
Trinity which is quite a tiny project so
far but still with a lot of dependencies
you can see almost 50 so when it was the
first graph I wanted to to show and then
most interesting ref the top 20 of the
most used Python third-party modules
that we use and here you recognize that
the most popular library we use in our
Python program requests so to perform
HTTP requests beautifulsoup and Alex ml
to to to pass HTML XML and so on
6 just to this is des turns out also 6
is the utility to to convert your Python
to script into Python 3 so we are seeing
that a lot of people are you are trying
to port the script from 2 to 3 then we
have Kohana because I curse wonder fancy
shell with some colorful stuff DNS
Pathan flask
Charlotte Charlotte is a good news to
see Charlotte in the top maybe to a 10
or 20 15 most popular sorry most popular
library because Charlotte is made for
shattered detection and trying to Train
to n giving your script the ability to
to be used worldwide
in every languages so you use please use
charted for your program then you have
term column which is like the Nemesis of
Kalama so Kalani is way more popular
than term color for your for coloring
your shadow and what's very interesting
in the in the in this list is you can
see that so far is really general
proposed library to perform some HTTP
request it's not it's not I think
specific to our community in foster
community but the first specific library
to use the people using their project is
Scapa this is the first
security-oriented library that we
apparently use because it's the first
one in the top 20 not being general
general for general purpose then digging
deep digging deep into the into the
study I wanted to see that which crypto
module in Python that we like to use and
I wasn't surprised by the result but
Freddy I think you if you're developing
your Python trip and wanted to perform
some crypto stuff you Rea need to be
careful because a lot of people are
using PI crypto apparently PI crypto is
not maintained anymore since to 2013 and
there's some some very nervous that
affect this library so please stop using
PI crypto prefer if you want to poach
your script you have rather to you PI
crap totem which is which are maintained
and the fixed route knowledge is that PI
crypto had and the general-purpose
library for crypto operation in Python
is cryptography so from the early
version the first version of this year
study by crypto was had a biggest a big
sorry I had a big share and the share is
trying to be reduced which is a good
news but still it's represent like
thirty person of crypto usage in our
Python tour so so please stop stop you
that
but Viraj that's sorry that's library
and the last part of this study so I'm
showing you I'm giving you all the
references here the last part of this
study is to focus again in Titan
libraries because I wanted to see if
what was the the ijen of our Python tool
out there vulnerable to a lot of stuff
are we using dependencies that has some
CVE do we maintain do we increase and do
we maintain actively our requirements
dot txt and to be frank item some
surprise here because I've seen a lot of
project so for this part of the study I
have used the PI up dot IO rule now
ready databases it's focused for python
libraries and I crossed and I joined
this data set with my data sets to see
how many project had their dependencies
vulnerable to some cv and the the first
library the most preferred library that
we use n which is vulnerable and not
maintained is jungle for building a web
server then we have request which is
using as you seen as you have seen the
favorite library to perform some HTTP
request and then we have we have a lot
of different libraries that we don't
maintain anymore and we don't upgrade
their number in requirement at 60 and
here you can see in this figure that
this is the representation of the Vanara
which is per python dependency so here
you can find you can see that request
this cv is related to request and is
really present in a lot of deeper in a
lot of repositories so again please fix
and maintain your requirement at sixty
and stop this kind of declaration you
know it is not good because it fixed it
yet it this is a strict requirements and
it cannot if you use this tool it
doesn't allow you to upgrade the jungle
version and because it it gives you a
static reference to a version so please
use at least superior than this version
I know you can have some compatibility
issues but still don't use equal equal
because it it it fixes some some stuff
in requirement at sixteen so you may ask
yeah cool this industry huh it may be
useful maybe not I don't know but anyway
everything including this presentation
is already available on my github so
I've made it to be to be repeatable so
today you can take the project and
replay it by your home hopefully it
won't break this is the power of that I
could just you just have to play to to
press
build and it will build a whole the
whole study updating the figures
updating the data sets of the English
shots so here you can find so the
project slide the project that that a
good project and some significant data
sets that you've seen today to be
exported and if you can if there's any
usage of this as that I said for your
study for your own study I would be more
than happy but J I released everything
so everything is available with the
tutorial so how to install that iku and
to import the project and so so I'm open
to to your contribution and to and for
your your remark about this project and
then for the last part of my
presentation which is which should
should be to be frank should have is
owned his own presentation is the golden
rules from my point of view for modern
tours if you want yours to be modern
easy to use easy to install easy to
contribute to so please follow this kind
of rule I think you're all experienced
like Mira you wanted to use a tool and
in your environment it doesn't work it
doesn't compile you cannot install it
you cannot contribute it breaks stuff it
doesn't support proxy whatever so I try
to list all the problem everyone as a
community we've been facing before I
think so first please pass pass some
argument with some standard library in
Python each it's called hoc pass the
previous one but which was called opt
pass so please use our pass and make
your script accepting arguments with the
standard library you'll see it's very
easy to do then as an input a lot of
scrip I are accepting only a single
entry just please if you want your tool
to scale accept an input file with
around 1 on 3 per line and it would be
better build it with modularity to twist
public contributions from my point of
view I think I don't know if you know
the tool reckonin g4 reckonin sense icon
- Angie I think it's pretty well
developed and it's based really on
modularity and each plug-in for each
each thing each side to be grabbed and
to be collected is built ready with a
good framework and to me it's a good
example of how you want to develop your
own tool if you want to is public
contribution
please also provide some easy to pass
output in sales with JSON please know
Excel where this is not modern at all
from my point of view CSV or G's
ancestry for human reason is for
programs but really please allow
standard output
make it please not everyone I - I think
you you you will better understand my
point of view here then maybe in the
u.s. we have accents in our shaft sets
please use utf-8 with this is coming
from a French guy so really make it make
it usable worldwide and not only in the
US
use for performance in synchronous
execution
thus simple rules for this if it's if
your program is IO bonded you have to
use a multi thread if it is CPU bonded
you have to use a multi processing in
Python this is in Python 3 and even
tuned right now because it has been back
ported there's a stander and cool
library which is called concurrent
concurrent that features and it allows
easily
you've seen my project I've used it I've
using it a lot to perform some multiple
process I've been using a lot Compu on
that futures and it has two subclasses
for merge is read in which it processing
it's really easy to use trust me provide
multiple verbosity level like from info
to warning to debug for for users to be
able to to understand what's going on
for failures please in our copper word
cooperates world lots of thing is based
on Windows please in your tool if it
does some internal scanning internal
stuff please support ntlm authentication
at least please if you are even better
please support Kerberos opacification
please also support HTTP proxy traversal
to be able to to go outside of your
cooperate environments if it's even
better if you support socks proxy
fication
its reeyou SFIL for everyone as we've
seen it's just before just don't use and
maintain please your dependencies being
for branching people the possibility to
upgrade their code and to maintain it in
the long run sorry package your tool
please package the tool in make it's
easily installable there's a lot of
tutorials to build a pip Python pip
package is pretty easy
publish your tool and your package on
piped organ could be easier for everyone
in the same way please provide
pre-built binaries if you
if you compile if you develop some some
compiler barcode or containers there's
the office as we've seen just before the
car is having better and better
represented representation in our
community a lot of people are publishing
the other Co file ready to be installed
and it's it helps attackers and
defenders so I've seen some people
saying that providing free build stuff
helps attackers only and no this is not
true you have to help defenders also
because different just has to attack
their home platform to be able to
understand what would be going on so
they don't have time to spend to build
your your your your program in your
audio tube chain so please provide
pre-built stuff please and in the end
encrypt traffic so to be you you build
some secure some security tools you have
they have to be secure this tool has to
be secure and it has to encrypt traffic
because extracting ashes fishing people
fishing password logins is cool but
making so touchy attackers not being
able to see what's going on is better so
please encrypt your traffic so as a
conclusion and I will be ready for any
question after as a quick conclusion to
my to me if you can make this video good
tool some good tool will work if just if
your stool scale it's better and in the
end great tool ass
thank you
you