man you drop them off I have assorted so
you can come up kind of money anymore
and yeah secretary reception us-based
profit center at Davidson center you
have military and had an opportunity
wall under a siding by as a trusted site
and it sort of the Grigori talk Charlene
acer is only on Ibaka decal- community
college where she responsible for
teaching here forensics sanitarium and
Ethel Ethel chanukah courses Cheryl PhD
in education PhD in management all the
Masters business master sergeants
hearing and is sigma black belt she
spotted me side of myths had been in one
of the overnight for reading be sized to
hustle so we bought not dominated the
stage and she stresses mobile presence
and social have now we're gonna make it
sure that you will end early because we
want to argue machine hey West a old all
the way through when I marry the wrong
address so that's why i got a new dress
part number but anyway besides the way i
am so grateful and very able to be here
is such an opportunity community concert
in song cheering I really appreciated
this was small yeah that's the rain
riders welcome
here and I'm starting from the whole lot
at this my teachers use of a poem union
you must be certified magnet examiner's
olo you just say certification in just
five about that at all I need a lot of
hot and jelly so I cannot all this video
online so well
so that tells us something isn't it
that's not in the future that's right
now that's what's happening right now
for us going so if you think that
everything is safe with your video wanna
the RFID all that information your NFC
that's what's going on right now in our
system especially Todd well and you just
have the bridge and he was human
everybody in there good for you when you
get in phn yeah they have a bitch so
looks like something I know a lot of us
know about our house our Android is
actually over passing everything used to
be equal with Mac and now pretty much
android is moving so fast we set up a
million population ashley is almost like
number one last time
the Ox is 1 million and also we have a
lot of games as well as some of it are
actually infected with viruses and drugs
and that's actually 1.5 all of our game
so there's we have a thing about how can
we actually put up our identity or our
even all our phone numbers that's very
important because this one right here is
stalking us and everything we do I'm
going to show a last video as well the
chocolates and everything that we do but
right now the total and we have is
rookie 48 and according to its
aggressive that there is actually in
facebook Israel is the country is the
third world loves company it is because
Facebook ovulation is actually three
hundred million which is close to
American our organizations are all 320
million Chinese one point one point
three genes and then he is 149 so
Facebook to turn the third one you might
have to try to pull have multi strand
and we are they coming from mainly
mainly they come from our phones or any
devices that you use that's why I always
encourage students or every time I go
speak that you always make sure to have
two computers I know we're not rich but
at least one more personal and one for
financial browsing that's just the demo
of Trance right now because if you do
have one computer and you use it for all
the arousing for financial and for your
personal browsing you can actually
increase the dress of your computer and
you reach the darkness and respawn MERS
virus and all them there's a lot more
there's the inspirer there's the fishing
screens the background processes there's
a run somewhere then are you right now
there's the violin
are comfortable so 174 million ha ha ha
she is a t-shirt and Irish person
actually is being a harsh word I detail
losses per person I also mean my average
down at least close to 300 million
that's what it is and the total is
actually born in rebellion amazing OMG
that they can actually get our
information I'm strong would be trampled
upon billions restaurant then so we need
to take care of something the best thing
is that all those free we're just feel
very good old girls we didn't create
information for you so I always look for
the Commission's and one of the
conditions don't believe you even less a
fine start it doesn't need that they're
good because we give doesn't really show
you 10 / and install permission will not
show you what is really your your
community to give our friend Roger
Gilligan sdn going to the farm right now
Oh me which is not very restless for the
gods probably so the relationship any
moment because most of the time it will
always try to ask to the network that it
will all say full network access you
don't see after the dust hidden you have
to all the young you when you go for a
pretty badly whereas final to get again
do you feel we're from your run you
don't react for today to get on out here
for Ashley I'm voting in a house they
wanna have everything full hello actions
will have more passion filled in this
planet you on camera whaddaya mean
Camilla they can have it information
most of these apps are coming on China's
well and we wanna make sure all the
overall
united states now c'est la vie in China
because there was actually a pre strike
two months ago we're something off that
came from China they already met at
bonded bars do it see mama said you're
gonna see if any animals around will
ever know come on said you never know
and um just last night I google hangout
and you know who who's always the usual
to use and I google my friend why I
don't really use facebook account to
descry trying to hack my friend with her
mom so she's in while she's in Hannah
national oh by the way again good
morning so I did all that I want to
actually have to her information aki and
using in the pool I just go a little in
her future and that's not believe on her
picture I go on these floors and
estimates cult leader used to work
whether this one and so tonight these
whores i press control app and then just
trying to find the word like um the LP
or confirmation so sorry Hannah I
actually went to the Facebook Graph API
and this is your this is your website
right here groth about facebook on a
night when I asked me to ill niño the
user ID Roger it pulls out the
information are there so it gives me all
the information no I'm gonna use a tool
what I'm using right now I use the
internet evidence provide I mean
presence I actually asked permission to
all my tools that are used today
is where I'm gonna be one from sorry
cutie run so i was able to actually for
chase a lot of things today helping Rory
squad my starter as well so I let all
the equipment and I'll be we roll up on
four I think it's almost not sure five
million but it's an explosion were
buying one of the universities and if
you were any more software princeton and
skater as well so you know Paul's doing
to this game so this is what I again I
actually use the internet evidence
present coupon see if all the
information that I got it from facebook
if they are malicious because do they do
IM will actually tells me right here one
army to deter fishing is iffy sign is
the wrong first time this is the longest
time I Alston will only show Ron if i'm
dishing the world all be part of it
Peggy budd l time they ok nasty royalty
i'm actually using the apartment to
lumen I used 99 bomber from Maui to
Luton and it works pretty good that's
good job you also me haga my chakra so
it pulls out all the details and
information runners gonna tell me
everything so I can actually use my
mobile home wrecker and you can download
this one as well for free for 30 days
okay for all the engines make sure the
vegetable gardens or swim all red one
here opieop on the theater on there
primo or jmo this one right here is
pardon I used to be my sister for some
information about one hour party as a
block all the informations in the gas
station so from all these passwords and
all this history example Don and I phone
so you can see they're all you on
official shows many pools on but I think
all the software that even though our
school is actually ignite it releases
its still go of all the informations and
there is brother there's the full name
so we're all if you leave your
suspicions with your boyfriend it's not
an anomaly in the Mayan it does allow
some very good information from and I
want them we're actually shining from
our old phones and we were in skills new
thing so I did one thing this one sly
$77 to identify our second investigation
to win and you'll see seem to have our
divorce anyway so it doesn't matter so
your song is israeli ark in i think this
was in it has to be either you pay or
something and I collects information
even though computer decreases i was
able to move all the information so that
i can talk is to my ears the solid you
can go to know the source but you can go
babe akari got company there's they're
very good day doctor familiar that so
there are very few tools but they're not
realistically safe to use for level you
can't use them it has to be something
definite by say for example
case for spk fills our physics on the OC
and uses it for legal purposes this lots
more for your personal needs personal on
time but a still wrestle if you're
looking for something is still working
on dug in so everybody else bought em
CNN is the enemy man o Canada is the
enemy of things that's going to be the
next two years from now everything's
going to be all about your RIT have you
heard about the doctor who got virus
from the embedded chips and they put in
his own so he I'm gonna show you now
delphos a wireless hotel room king Radio
Free wat wild about the wireless
frontier it's a privacy nightmare Walt
August dinner which is the guy who
warned us that new wireless credit cards
like the ones with this logo are easily
hacked and there's your master her he
rigged up a portable scanner and when he
got near people's wallets Walt could
read their credit card numbers that's
actually uremic so probably be next blue
now Walt says he's found an even bigger
breach he says these don't need a
scanner anymore and they don't even need
to be anywhere near you to steal the
credit card number from a wireless car
how's that cell phones there's an
antenna behind your search for new bones
contain something called NFC Near Field
Communication the app that makes your
bog your watch it's the innovation
behind services like Google Wallet with
Google Wallet you can pay with your
phone it stores account numbers then
transmits them to cash registers on
demand you lock move along with a pin so
it's more secure than a physical laws
look Walden twisted the technology press
it over
and that's how you pack he's figured out
that when there's a phone with NFD near
a wireless credit card the phone can
secretly pull account numbers what makes
the other completely danger yes your
phone could be stealing your credit card
number my hacker can pull off the heist
cyber mon lazy but lucrative pickpocket
it will actually scam a credit card
secretly sent off the David Cook email
address anywhere in the world an
infected phone could really go to work
in a crowd the screen could be black but
in the background the virus is scan or
credit card numbers know you're going to
have a person on the other end of
your email box fill up with red
/ without ever having to get near you in
a world away even more alarming is how
easily hackers could infiltrate our
bonus wall worries we could unknowingly
grant them access in a nap say a
tempting new game is free so your snacks
but what you really install is a credit
card dealers viral oh so the minute they
downloaded it whether they played it or
not it's sitting there looking for these
credit cards for all the convenience and
wonder a wireless technology wall says
this is the downside having to keep up
with crows so he recommends exchanging
wireless credit cards / old-fashioned
one and for cellular users download it
what he has virus protection virus
infections in it from our phone you can
buy it for 1999 34 I'm not trying to
sell that's not my student told me in my
valuation she seems like she's selling
everything for us no but anyway it's a
really good protection if you guys have
the virus protection from your phone on
semantics is good one and um kazursky
all seven nineteen ninety-nine a month
but not also protect all your data or
you can also buy like on like fraud
insurance as well there is a protein
surance for our phones our house just
interviewed by ingles ADC
they asked me you know how are ones that
are PII data information for the
hospital and best thing to do is always
matches and always buying insurance
frauds technical terms as we just
returned product toss toss toss toss
toss is beyond because information is
the last evening together love
information I mean solar to ensure an
artist of mobile phones one for evening
without reading English line so the next
really big one which we talked about for
our class it's actually the embedded
wearable RFID okay look at this one this
is actually right ear they see a lot of
five minutes and the operation is done
and one of the doctor in UK did it for
research and he actually had wires after
a week of using it so iris as well is
that it can cause cancer that's not
really grow from it yet but that's what
they said that it must be implanted
something in years bien it can a
constant cancer and the Facebook is
going to be letting you or tummy RIE
because the desk you are working to the
RFID expert dr. all branches that is
going to be everyone will be tagged in
one way Marcos's already re only used up
for the whole Nazi beauty will be word
one you know a question to them so true
citizenship very good yes sir for all
yes
that is that's correct what else how's
that work but maybe what they want to
protect us is Ashley to protect
criminals ok so to me there's some
insecurity writer is it because moms are
everywhere we have the bar oh we have
the poor going on right now in other
countries what else we have you have all
the other ones and animals those those
people are also trying to get an
information from school data isn't it
but the major cost why they want us to
use our bodies actually around alarm for
all the citizens to make you easier to
go what is it like you go to airport so
we have to do is plug it in your hand
that's one thing that they want to do it
will replace all the gargoyles in the
next five years that's what's going to
be definitely didn't ask me things going
to replace if they call our idea in the
middle of things they want to place this
for everyone so they can inventory they
had a trauma what I was going to put de
los they are all day Amy total for all
day long we're entering pretty much the
only thing we cannot prevent is that to
make us to get our safety that we have
the array of one how can keep them from
all these days yes that is really just a
you stop loss
that's how we learn cause when you can
be my name is Donna begin home with an
inoperable and I'll volume for our body
choose gone wrong Google cool huh really
water amazon awesome an awesome is going
to be the next evening I'm dying in
Auckland is Ashley planning an s clear
to bring all our packaging wrong but
they all have a limit long hospital
hundred and we supply but that's why
your mind so I'm getting in washing
Austin rising that was the very story is
it in yeah bezels is trying to how this
very big vision of getting all these
product in seconds and you guys are on T
seconds you just have to read I'm just
your home is already losing the CMOS
don't give the walmart gold are
targeting but anyway they're really big
being wise is that the dubious buyers in
china china's largest um the artist
convey your orders are to buy asian
chest to the place in vienna swans and
also for informational dirty young women
personal information as well as they
want to talk all the people for not
communist but it seems like that's going
to be the nasty thing they were I
thought all our information to them then
I get it all of that are right in there
ok so a lot stronger that's gonna be
wanted to be the biggest one that we're
gonna face this year right now so we
will have a lot of acreage information
you can get them out of the palm drop
bombs what else do we use Moodle
what are their on cloud infrastructure
is all paying all these simulation
google hour ago and it is real of cars
and insurance on this is the cameras
going to eat about class for cars
they're gonna play in one class per ours
for all he models of cars and i also
believe only have their and then I'm
gonna leave a la kasbah you're our
friend what is the world about us
through your arms maybe it's supposed to
be for insurance purposes but I can
actually use some more other things
audit information or something like that
metal me drive anywhere we're not even
into play we're being drunk and where we
go nobody's paying us to trauma so I saw
our songs on YouTube that area is not be
no easy to guard garçons those are for
tonight right so do you think you want
I'll you know do my new part of lockbox
on it may be more like is I don't want
to do that the file will give my son 16
yet over the car right now because i
rolling this ammonia six of the rocket
the caterer combos and you get one of
all rock all the way through maybe you
won't get DUI at the black box drives
you home okay not gonna be the next one
and so here comes the wrong who do you
think is going to be didn't a small
water with leading over the line do you
think it will be sprung AT&T Verizon
Wireless and what do you think is the
biggest provider of mobile industry is
nationally t-mobile
Verizon 4G version Britain coming I'm to
see what you say is that the cream
frozen yeah it is gonna be tmobile and
Al Rosen those are tvs because they are
international any hard times they
actually your hand because I call all my
friends before I talk here I do mind you
they intended give me all this what what
how they can get you by gone with a
contra mi informe de tomorrow in every
year for the last year one to year
mantra but a young man they can get
65-inch TV a novel or read what are we
have it here in anaconda data bit like
different types of gifts are gonna be
whores you know you guys Myra Tony how
does it begin no such thing as I've
lived in Canada well my country in
Logans we're going to be passing copying
the whole world this Pete ass we can
have a core two by phone on her so we
don't get it anything we get its crime
from the US there but up your man
sitting before they do have to over a
lot of day and I'm visiting the whole
driver in the menu and go fishing for me
so the last they came is actually google
chrome and move on how many of you use
that because you don't even use has
launched our wife I'm who needs a long
you can use your old contract phone and
you can use the patient's don't mind the
mom just doesn't use google talk and
then install the blue
voice a slight talked on true body or
box art rock on you can use those die
download it and then put it from your
old phone and give it to your kids to
say honey as long as we have a hard line
and the military school didn't realize
then that in a row seat is good because
my school on Monday to the very smart
they brought the other thing up the dog
more dominant across the room just want
to say anything another the nominee
hansa yellow stars Ron Barber socially
media sizable and the Romans nothing in
here actually totally spoon home
schooled on and also lo lo que celle
look at all your own self our equation
or words involving your long lost or
something like that he wanted no more
talk on phone we use material you can
use our first time some Canadian hockey
games this one of my student and we go
to work to go to 12 hours to really go
him to get someone a connection yeah spy
on people spying on people he's going to
talk about I'm entering in and kebab his
invention he got some inventions going
on so I'd like to you to meet one of my
student james coleman you can put me on
google voice crib that's my nigga why
someone always includes program arms
topography video I'm afraid and just a
little yesterday I was verified at the
CH i'm currently going to call the
cryptographers assurance and I'm mad to
share of my stuff so I'm sure some of
the wrong side up starting off i created
a clock because i was you know a knowing
that you have all over my head
100 is molar so I decided you're already
underwater so I don't happen to think
about negatives mystica tutors are rated
in Robin and they basically displayed in
a number with i'm guessing it is some
sort of thing it's like what we have and
likely this is what I can ride a
complete a bit you got the different
whores average in its essence and these
are all the components just far out on
the right we head up in our minimum
there are animals basically the growing
operation I have to do that alone all
kinds of things to that then I have
broken o'clock we want to block revised
different on there which is able to read
in this book cut above all that we have
set of coasters and elongate the city
foresters basically allows you to have
many other pilots from the art number
which is great hints so the owner a bit
so it's eight times three because
there's great of them and a lot of gates
what they do is getting along with the
higher globe or instant doesn't do them
it chooses which number to put it around
whenever is put the ground the literacy
is able to vote and you get a number
Bridget 11 straight so this caused the
riverdogs make its getting into a lot of
honors is it expensive and I want you to
meet this oh I'm of course as I said
ever and exits are awesome and then
everything I need after urban all these
watches they're going on like you know
the anyone watches that Apple's is also
been announced
one down never maybe we don't know
sobbing my own this is my launch it is
basically a round of your mind with a
pietà teach screamin opposite all that
in what's going on I used HTML java to
design the internets that displays the
current on and i towed it is to run very
cool print on the dead end of us with
this i think you all have a record I you
can go to the head once listed is Eric
you didn't hook it up to a TV with RCA
or you can use hdmi with that you can
watch TV shows like your look at them on
their watch TV shows music whatever you
want so there's later and minerals won't
you seen your father can I act it out
micro point and what we're planning to
do in the future maybe in the next five
years it might be added in your hand as
well so you can watch your TV rfid found
like that so that's that's gonna be the
future that's what we're planning to do
that's why I'm trying to mentor him can
you meet your wife is a comb oh you can
in my mind they don't have a forum on
there so this is me every minute is a
relative a pilot monster Franz on arm
and day so watch by your hand on my line
I have a little USB stick you can flow
in there get a go so yeah yeah no I fine
and you know the mouse and keyboard with
a huge ego state and throw it all men
just sort of it I don't remember going
to be reported so it's so small but
you're gonna motivate TV with HD mine
ever mine you got internet and there's
hdmi okay so that's my watch made and
the first project i started
was I wanted a bum that ball ground war
and happy people stare at me so I went
aground does he have one of the little
bones you know the spoiler eons and it's
together one so I don't worry about
having included hmm so you can dial it
just want to go every mom put it here in
it toilet and you're acting darling I
like these two days funds which you're
actually pushing hear about the power
switch and the Charlie Moore or they can
recharge the batteries and last but most
i have recharged it since i made a
tactical january and it's still a word
they're part of these things yeah and
then whoever the consulate you got a
programming book so you can return it
wanted to buy a some aversion to make it
into a jewel box braids on over and play
the song it runs off the adrenal and
then three reporters also on v load and
i have an entire test Peter finished
I'll get her mouth on and that's figure
is used for the green dome or play music
but our heroes at the top right that is
very exciting probably most of these
prodigies have made I made them open
source the exception is that clock
because I had time to finish it but I'm
gonna happen late everything into that
available source you can buy all my
travels of the going roommate these
electrons go into my blog you can go to
get it out and get it sorted for all the
things that are meeting and that's it is
you got your end up seats you yeah I
have an interesting room she wanted me
to show that so you can access
everything out but anyway I'd like to
end up that you guys to protect your on
your data your
as well as your cards make sure to buy
one of this RFID shields you can
actually use a regular foil to do it but
thank you so much I really appreciate it
you guys have a very wonderful night and
thank you so much thank you
get out the rebels upstage shithead
morrow you guys remember I said check
out a way out and also a new here actor
philip into a hat back again just wanted
to go to the party names that are dirty
it's a vital hotel filet o is it dried
out here over to do listen alas they had
a bus going from hotel shoot us good put
in a little game miss if i give the
monitor but not out Ryan you know we're
all still vocal can't leave this rig
here