dad once you're actually let me talk to
my shows how reflector well what we
roughed up with her please go ahead it
up join out but not for not our
guy what why im a boss like all that
secret appear sharing okay um what's
ministers yes so as you know minus 40
but also i'm sitting here on the
different kinds of us he believed me
wrong and useful not very far away from
here i'm sitting at the tax office just
what you're gonna speaking today while
talking i'll read it I've anybody ever
do this if you're interested anymore and
recession Ida recordings that are on the
town online website so they can tell
there and some locations yes minister
mentions why the presentation one is why
we're discussing that there are /
tráfico y that such yeah so it's
reasonable right I want to show you
after would you kind of my passion about
Emma and also a security or according to
very severe cramping up he neither so
I'm probably not and last year and this
is the tiny hole ego that my husband is
coming from
how much I'm not oh my gosh or extreme
games or I wanted that so last year I
made 248 points I wouldn't on your only
sold us a lot alike come on destinations
another day or birthday this year I back
around I have another around 170 so
Elizabeth I am living experience and
whenever I'm flying over the phone
careers when it's pretty interesting for
me it's holistically I sneaks and people
behaviors that are not really you know
assuring the security is there yes so
I'm like wondering what is just get
really up in the air because you know
the case of the Malaysian flight yes we
have the store there was a story that
there was a militia bite and was blown
from Scott because transponders work so
what is the transponder that's the whole
transition workers concave up right and
the other thing is that the protocol
Laguna thought about it is implemented
we are so many countries within us venom
vs Europe definitely it's also their
their stuffs kind of near the countries
that are getting completed within the
protocol least you know remember now and
the pretty big problem is that it's
supposed to be in 2020 we all get the
community any movie that is it is
incredible and it is the protocol as
used in between the plane in the ground
so the very could say word applying
technically a snap d with my daughter
brightwater to anymore they can watch at
the landing awkwardly
after you so the problem is that erst
tiny security 10 out there a theater it
was a debacle that up you're using it is
based upon nineties and imagine like the
person that were grown in 90s how many
screws on these right now the college is
a little more technology remind mr.
communication all right up when weird is
having that peeking lives into extreme
interest alone PTI will implement in two
thousand so local before are funny and
kind of messages 18 points is there any
more information along well the ladies
that I'm not really and it's not a
secret that we are a version of much an
organization that I'm sure another item
which called FBI and everyone i said
that this is potentially well the next
terrorist attack is going to happen it's
scary so what's the thing first of all
whatever i wanted to show me you don't
do this at home because it's not quite
legal but he has been really lucky
because you able to come to visit us for
five years nice oh this is where it
means i'm going long yellow butter
getting home is so if I'm about to make
it my mom just kidding I don't go into
the internet but it is the one that you
want your hips just good at all you have
to go it's just terrible okay so oh is
that a prettier transpiration you know
this will hear so what kind of soft
without putting in the operator
automatic dependent survey is broke this
household and this is the problem that
starting all 1099 Hertz frequency and it
could completely
schedule technical to come in between
the policemen around that's how we are
able to see and salt and put on the map
in public where the plane yes so the
question is if and this is a pretty sad
thing power we learned that not only
that but also on that the question is
were clear for example having a few
texts prodigal we go skinjack ready
suddenly one thousand please 45 minutes
poppy described and it'll be punished
him this couldn't be small s name
someone's gonna crush me to get on out
there are still people working in power
they got their own eyes and a very
fiddly your experience and they don't
see that something was going on but a
beach queens blue they wanted I'm
talking to a little burrito okay level
of your fault what about 999 other ones
are no real or fake so I've heard but i
think is the more auditioning I hope
it's rumored but I am still in this game
before I understand came that excuse me
at least transponder trust me
technically the messages that affluent
or coffee in a moment and you can
actually fly the real win the game
aircraft visible but my life people but
I can't open skylight phone so you can
land your flake like also hard work and
everybody else for you will see them
excuse me it's a powerful miss also
useful at our to mark where these are we
would have a great deal with classical
methods of communication need a doctor
one of the staff is here okay so how
does Charlie looks like because it'll be
nice to have some practical experience
around it so he didn't we must offer and
then i'm going to show you first over
the role in a speedy communication and
then i would like to show you that and
go
Khoda Khan so um NM he goes to market to
market us in that me lunch the software
that i got for this tiny man i'm going
on back then Rosita kind of you see it
oh this is erroneous because it's like
so we're gonna show me a lot in London
now the VMS and indisputable main theme
of a bizarre we're going into a solid I
just over her face so under the money
could buy some pita and it's going to
regular as bdrm Hannah and you can buy
for water we're coming you over there
somewhere yes and I gonna radio haha
good and that's tiny radio i gusti
indirect Americo and looks like this it
is exactly that my slack that's the only
difference in a car so you can combine
money even and this is what we made its
acidity to employ a little bit with a
whole communication so let me start of
course that also how the role aug looks
like here we go you so this is set so
this is going to communicate in a number
here so why are able to the variable not
for the plane up in sky if we see
something like that well that's why we
were to be called it and all right
you've got a lot of software that is
actually I want of you is from the
numbers it is so whatever flies over yes
if you wanna turn by the way what is it
arranged all this is about 100 miles all
right okay so disappointing off topic
but no it's trying to see how we're able
to do it again and the thing is
it is me traffic in my balcony and also
my house massages we've got a big
antenna that is listening the whole
communication and if you guys for money
man we are able to our neighbors so how
many working on so this hasn't asked
really pretty okay like 150-200 spirit
for wonderful want the german guys that
its patent guy on an awesome it really
is often but and let me show you a horse
and i'm going to run again notice how
the hell did abs be used and if you
wanted to say subudhi that is super fun
because so we're going to see everything
you're gonna have to engineer pani as
well to the mid-80s be ma vie EST SED in
error OTL and the cord is thirty
thousand and three and maybe we can use
to a planet or row as well and then see
and the discrimination it was what it is
so this isn't nicole with it on the
dependent think about that i'll stop at
rivermont ended here as you see i have
we got 35 times of measures because it's
three four five seven four and small
this is all the time all the time saying
but this is basically that identifier of
the aircraft if you are a longer where
we are able to find get a kind of
information but Bernie's eagles flying
of austria 4888 0380 we were able to
find it or leave it at front runner at
english so let me show you here forgot
that this time off go to the time
yeah and here you are able to put it
over here 48 8800 search for answers and
is that so as long as you will see it 48
in any sub a here we go forgot the
aircraft exactly full my information
about that lot because originally it sir
from my hand at all that I require
anything through talent and this certain
aircraft it's kind of summer here Matt
yes so we mentioned mainly landed maybe
do not so here are losing we'll see it
yet but we here see literature and these
are the current pictures they are today
the real pictures what is this well it's
not something with the logo is this
grain and here we see of course who
schedules certain era and everything you
can also search history and it's kind of
scary when you are flying some awkward
airlines to see how old is the aircraft
as we are always talking for that like
whenever you get the aircraft and you
don't trust me unlike hmm let's see Oh
25 years old long before I have their
hair ways oh I mean you're a person
without it what ru mine from me there
yes I do not so
this is this whole scenario ok this one
less really does seriously into the de
feels hot rodder and kind of message in
the first time of right now I can enter
it one time it allows you to move more
earnestly the traffic and why it doesn't
work I'm worried and you see that on
travelers Delta so I will be I will
advise and through that why do we see
that the cost of the ats-v de streaming
the Talmud Russian Jew is a perfect day
needs within protocol not do it outside
at all everyone can send a car give
information out to the Earth's legal
everyone can do it and cause a little
bit more plain very overcome and threw
in the morn patina excuse us why does
like this cuz I do they do have a GD
weekend you have a fever enter their own
models as their share in the field who
my brother the devil cleared it with my
friends are doing we are very beautiful
flight 405 butter anyone here life sa
tourism some have a recognized antenna
over the balcony at all it's for example
covering bahria town and this it's five
people were you able to get a feed at
all why you Hannibal why do there were
no fire because it is like a new test it
with everybody know neither so again
what about safety so let's take out an
empty vector presentation whenever we
are thinking about the whole
communication offers it has to have no
conclusions as usual it is not limited
it is not a good time there are no
confirmations need to be employees
locusts but what kind of the register
is an obsession gold or exchange session
over the session bobbing on that so
another thing is that it is available
under air sensor regarding 1090 and
everyone can i connect with and impaired
one condition this is alternate struggle
to the internet to decision 80's beats
for free every walk into that who can
ascend it whatever pose assistant
transformer that's why this degree
anyone have fun how to provide rather
meet how to share her people that I
driver and you don't worry about these
charges call to share and how come on
you three different device and why do I
he's so cool you know this is joe she
knew rain right it's kind of hard over
there and there's a time when sort of to
be hard so also motivating with my
husband the airspace I you know what I'm
going to do in the run ok so I'm sorry
it's about dangerous and as we know if
history has some issues with our
neighbors as well so they're like my
house let's see what gonna do we are
monitoring their error and what we saw
was amazing I never seen over Poland not
only through and every three but over
Poland so let me explain you know the
vid exploring playing with a mushroom
over the top yes so we have to yes yes
yeah you know
okay so yes I never saw that and they're
not only sweetie sure or closure for new
Papa as german air force so many are
worst life going on a multiple a very
never going to you mean like are they
getting hard to say or too hard so that
we have to be yeah it's kind of notice
no I wonder if I'm kidding it's must
have an away game 1 i'm listening him
over i'm going to be quick meeting or
partying with your kisses and find us
who does okay sometimes is funny to see
it is like that because of the situation
that we were stored in that region all
everybody flies cooking destructive life
channel it's amazing because how else
even upon as you're able to solve oh and
one more thing you're going to be
masters New York about you come it is
the first animal minutes upon is any
fashion of the tank we've got a
registration place we're going to fly
number here asshole named after the day
this time in session but we were
spooning presentable message number
three message number four altitudes not
too strong ages so we know ready to play
when it's like this so we can put it on
up how fast is going he's these
core slowing down because it means that
it's probably and it up here still able
to measure how high is that so that I
asked to go over the plan what's going
down it's then so sticking to the core
and you can order community and basic a
massage this is that transformer
motorcraft so is the very identical can
transport a little bit whose name is
sadly this information but that tracks
are reasonable because points and
definitely you had of the ocean we in
the moment so we are the equal variable
fine I'm transponder on the eway to call
some purple airport um happy we get here
yes we are
and the part is quite legal not a very
long time ago on ebay there was for
20,000 euros to involve a professional
our transponder from Castile yes what if
you want to be the earth it's quite
cheap ok and not that's not acceptable
I'm so serious I was except every bit of
that sergeant so any kind of situation
while walking this every year could be
really happy for evil someone is just
having fun five minutes is enough maybe
you're going to cause the crash movie
night with a for sure gonna call the
computer and people gonna get scared so
this is close to the pond ok the next
thing that I wanted to show you it is
basically some included in a cooperation
we wanted at zero p.m. flood
organizations and this is zero unless
you notice in overtime on that is the
hotel for error control over certain
country and all I want to show you a
quick movie and this is basically a
beautiful bit about they are playing
within that and with a topic what we did
we cost lot of flames on the sky for
real and we want or if this is seen you
dead can love it is seen anonymity a
little if they're normal and a ver
playing Dave product in this class so I
don't know first of all the movies kind
of slow so i'm going to describe
everything so this is all for that i'm
using very well it's called playing
poker and playing poker and Lady Bears
to listen what is going on on the sky
and right now always wise what our
transformers wiki that means that we are
transmitting their messages than I do
have after the air
I was going to eat it and that's just me
and just kind of like walls an ipod pour
homme hair up oh and these airbus are
approaching the abruzzi airport and one
honey think the dash dimension we're
gonna start rock I mean it was offers a
thing that women in a controlled
environment but an evening with a
certain attack this number is quite
important cinema 600 so this is called
scope scope is the message is
transmitted by transponder in certain
situations and there are being popular
and sorry for the stupid I'm enormous 30
very close at bigger one is the 75 the
department announces with a transponder
be that means men with night sat on a
fire bundle 976 radio clicks we are tons
of any right now instead of the six said
I'm 600 that means that X FX bar here
sorry no not really because my brain is
broken but I'm approaching the airport
where all that that's really like you
know canopy enema for the face before
the airport in tower oh yes facebook yes
and 77 is our set we just go to heaven
he said face in class problems and these
will not probably a tapestry and there
were there were seven cents in history
because we have mando crashes and apply
to are aware that the Arab sorry to say
about I so this part is a taste of me
that this
holding on to receive and you know that
there is something very wrong and the
magic dimension is quite scary videos
what was happening is that there's this
um approaching the airport we walked
anybody to so the only thing we have to
do is to spend money to assess the jets
and as which are out wherever our FCC
star able to prepare oh it is closed I
will not I can't see them but I
determine up or not yes and then they
spend their country spends money once
and their toys can get over how much
money it is a kind of silent interesting
as well so thank you dad says sorry out
of the field um I need to connect on us
and i would like to show you something
that I'm really laughing us and
everybody talking about everyone else's
part in Eastern Europe very often this
is what is happening lots of one time in
the right but after figuring out what is
how many more than a tsb I'm not doing
to the cross that kind of situation and
baseless okay all right everyone in
rockmart interruption Bravo for medical
record at Bravo point I our skipper 4
530 1140 one run
so pretty on the car because they know
so this is a star oh yeah thanks good
upon a thing good job success Sasha and
unpredictable you're so nasty Jean yes
so this is a nothing to play with and
you only have communication it's move it
over that bendini differently us gps for
us is one of the protocol to the muties
fluid in aviation and this is something
that is also running eluding her desk
and you're able to snare it and we're
able to school and school in the 30s or
early raphy versus believe that these
particular are you gonna meet Harry to
play with engine idle rockets going to
the destination for the municipal is
going to the stages and basically GPS
spoofing bit of all the GPS community
soon is that I reckon to Spartacus yes
so far superior throws it to be speaking
but the question is were elsewhere
reasoning cheapest instead of your
communication instead of the navigation
where are you also for time sitting and
I so how will our rooms that are safe
actually at the time we leave the
organization usually condition yes GD 8
o'clocks and your those tablets
providing time variability yes but a
funny thing is that the GPS can be very
English school and jammed don't even
easier in the school school in do this
expressive now there are bunch of you so
sure
the whole be spooky in this chart and
we're going to meet the varied equipment
you're able to do that and with the
first pretty hard it's about Jean Jean
yes that's what sometimes poor miss
Goodin because we are right now it's not
that I have a couple of years ago their
cars being stolen was Marie let's say
the situation yes so will the divorce
get is so what you think I can protect
my car Senate owner and include proves
it up some low jack or any kind of gps
tracking gears and when the teeth takes
in a car each Carson ha ido so why isn't
it oh well brucey because that kind of
device it is not for scratching her life
really it is 40 gb is junk yes and my
husband's it's really lovely it was
supposed to me Wi-Fi repeater already he
wanted me to do with wife every theater
as you can imagine and there is a month
away that he's using an opportunity of
my luggage I'd always trouble with a
hand luggage and I don't want to focus
on the airport so when i'm thinking the
gps jammer to the airport really goes to
school haul ass just imagine so that you
want you know who's mean further than
the moment but then it is always asking
like why did you meet this girl
obviously I any more time here you want
to totally new hotel work so weeks going
through and I ok
the there was through security Harry
gonna be looking at leg walk it was
quite nice it was where did an activity
and it was going when you're sitting or
the security scanning and now you asking
me to take it out because of Thomas so
it was going out and I see like all
around at work very good food yeah and e
mu sees us he's eyes on my walk but i
can see lead is commercially going on
but it's not asking you out to this one
life thank you so much nobody that's
that yeah if you consider maps furball
do to jump gps near the point come on so
what is the range is around 12 in this
room yeah it will cover me on the back
rows but here it will cover that yes she
is top it easy okay one thing I'm trying
to figure out that if a student advice
is kind of hard when this leader over
here so i always show you this on the
milk illustration earlier so right now I
had must not like and we'll do over
those to my gps we hear all the ball or
somebody like this yes and basically
what do you see this nice to know ultra
German after a little right now she lets
go it's just a little whore sucking the
my dear mama going to prime slow I was
turned off
when I heard of kind if I said oh here
is some thoughts again and there for a
year earlier I would enjoy a more visual
presentation for asking if I record a
video does he is one equals three i
think that the single can't even show
you this is basically my talent so I'm
sitting the GPS and this is the same
nice sandy nice as it is to show family
women ever you're going to eat you're
going to change your job you're going to
eat carbs teeth then let me go I'll tell
it was kind of us that it costs around
three hundred dollars and you can buy a
lot and I don't care you know and now it
goes to zero satellites zero fix called
test to see on here and when I'm turning
it off so now scroll and I'll turn it
off then but we need any have two days
and to be able to offer our tentative is
a list of aircraft miles long and after
turning off it goes really Hilary
co-parenting size for album on for our
minds so this is the thing next thing
that we got it is relatively related
with GES moving so is this legal or not
definitely not because trouble fitting
and comet burger on the vibrancy that if
it's not yours that it is not illegal to
those tried at home and really serious
you have to loose women in Oklahoma I
asked managing rotation as you see a
developer this is a Depot or antenna
made from that is ponch good gosh this
is relatively soddy-daisy silver the
demonic inspired style uses the military
equipment to do this opening for
limors here's the new president around
thirty thousand dollars it was up with
Audrey so um total us just check out and
how goes the way the wrong I'm gonna
give you that I tu another video maker
so you'll see that give away as well
fish box what is the various kind of
hoping so I mean a lot of connected to
the starting eyes and this is our
eternity yes that I showed you and we
are related be moving hours of the masks
all the devices to know them in England
and right now we are coming with a
problem that I realized to to school the
GPS and to enforce everybody I want to
cash the information to the very model
and that was having a very quickly water
garden problem a GPS and then basically
all of our annual is made in UK systems
not stupid so in e sometime but one has
to go tomorrow yes and become both how
they're so let's move and we started to
generate signals and other supplies
already could not cautious taste it too
quick change so we're talking about is
if I were your eyes for murder into a
problem but then you're on you see how
signal is the signal in the bottom two
ritual it is coming from the CMOS and
the next thing because of the darkness
out we're going to move to each in China
this was our population here Moscow
dumplings and we ran out as being the
signal and in the moment we're going to
move all the Masters to try and
communicate could look at it he was
tedious to me some time in his civil
service
and so but I put a bitter taste and
around five minutes for the crashing
University depositor some of you girls
could just sort o composed it have asked
um it was coming to very slowly and the
US for example tablet form none of the
professional gps receivers this was
cutting it pretty fast so they got spur
you merely need to pass to the base it
was a luminous one and I'm over here
instead of the valuable cash because of
their life sauce on that right side and
in with this poster pain burning clicks
and at Otto's possible to China if you
have these are Chinese and this is a
signal the permanence plus the signals
and super strong these helpers are fake
gay love you and an hour moving into
2016 time so we are at the meeting
changing that then we'll work a little
bit of signal so anyone that was only
complete a rush to like checking the
delegation and it shows in China and is
authorized are giving us here 16 because
wound in time 2016 and matter playing
with this ensemble shatter this lingo
time for the kerberos it could be any
kind of any cool yes and organizations
are sometimes oh sometimes sinking time
on Naruto we wouldn't hold
constructivism Eugene yes fine and
basically this is a whole sword so you
need to see so I hope it wasn't too
scary I hope you are wrong if you have
some impact on the ats-v implementation
it will be right this is moving about it
it explained it is cool that is creo
text not eat ice on
to be spooked super easy and then look
this hammer gonna cost over summer
because the Equal Opportunity sheet yes
it's really of the first movies but last
point this vector don't care think of a
good reason that will be someday no
cargo so different so you have any kind
of evil thing is being development good
of a seat please after five estimate
because um def 11 how their property and
for now not me going on and sss 2020
everybody going to provide a EAP that is
an egg model different names so this is
another how the should go back and
care about safety why do we have a dog
because sleeping on the ground but out
there it's not that set if you have some
questions let me know thank you so much
for listening I hope you
you