hi I'm sandy Murphy from Sparta there's
West Griffin from Sparta sitting right
over here and he swore to me that he
would answer any questions you asked
about DNS SEC because that's not my
particular focus I'm here to request
feedback about some work that's going on
for DNS and routing security DNS SEC is
actually being deployed out there Sweden
has signed its top level zone and ripe
is signing its reverse zone and some
select forward zones as well as doing
some secure delegations dan massey and
licia zhang also told me that some of
their graduate students are going out
looking for secure zones and they've run
across some fifty or so they promised to
send me a link but I don't have it quite
yet there's an open working group called
the DNS deployment initiative that we're
involved in and a bunch of other people
are involved in it has a active mailing
list it has regularly scheduled telecoms
this is a bunch of DNS experts that are
trying to get together and do what's
necessary to see DNS SEC deployed it
also has organized some DNS SEC kind of
training workshops for hands-on work at
various different venues apricot and
eight I can and places like that there's
a website listed there for giving news
and announcements of new workshops this
is a screenshot there's a technology
part of it that lists a pretty detailed
road map the working group part here is
where you can sign up for the mailing
list and there's operator gaiden
guidelines links to nist and ripe and
our own particular operator guidelines
documents and then the vents and actions
are about these workshops so that's all
across the top on that screen
there's another project the intersect
tools which is our just pretty much us
creating tools and patches and plug-ins
for web browsers and such all the focus
is to try to make it easier for people
to begin to use DNS SEC and that's the
website we had a just recently had a
release of a new tool set we also have a
rpm for firefox on the client side that
will actually check and validate the DNS
SEC records that it gets back so to
point out some interesting parts of this
website here's the that's the main
website but there's the announcement of
the tools being released and one of the
most interesting tools probably and this
just failed no I did this is the zone
signer tool which is how you sign and
maintain a sign zone there are some we
hope very detailed documents about how
you step-by-step guides for signing and
maintaining a sign zone interactions
between the parent zone and the child's
own and on there they're also the usual
sourceforge mailing lists provided and
this is on sourceforge the DNS SEC tools
download and the of the Firefox rpm down
here okay
and moving on to securing the routing
infrastructure I'm trying to go through
this pretty fast the routing
infrastructure I've been kind of nagging
about this for 10 years or so it's an
important problem everybody knows it's
an important problem there have been a
multitude of different suggested
solutions none of them have particularly
gotten any any traction so there have
been three workshops held in the last
year inviting the interested parties the
intent is to find an acceptable and
deployable solution get the people who
would actually have to be doing that
working on it get something going to
move forward to get security at least
started we had service providers access
providers content providers vendors the
security research community the routing
research community DNA DHS was the host
and the facilitator they are not
themselves making any suggestions as to
what the solution would be and that's
the website where you can go look at the
presentations and minutes from all that
from those meetings now in those
meetings I think I've said in a couple
other places that the strongest called
the thing through all meetings was it
sure would be helpful to have an
authenticated list of authorized prefix
originator 'he's which a SS are
authorized to announce your prefix and
the intent dist use it in in however
many ways you want to be using such a
thing in responding to customers
requests to router prefix in
troubleshooting routing problems exactly
who is supposed to be announcing that
prefix in constructing your filters if
you want to be constructing filters but
this is also the first step in any of
the suggested solutions for protecting
bgp it's the first step that has to be
done so out of the last workshop arose a
suggestion that aaron's should begin
to collect in all the number templates
allocation and sub allocation and
assignment ins and such should begin to
have a new field that we collect a list
of the a SS allowed to announce that
prefix the intended benefit is this is a
procedure that the operators are used to
there they used to filling out the
templates they know they have to fill
out the templates for Erin in order to
do new allocations IRR entries are in
the back of everybody's mind perhaps but
they aren't always done hopefully with a
field in the template as you're filling
it out for another purpose you'll there
will be more motivation to go ahead and
put it in there but it also inherits the
scrutiny that Erin does on initial
allocations and on any authentication
that they have with their with the
members to ensure that the prefect the
requests are coming from the correct
people furthermore Erin is the authority
for who is allocated what prefixes so
they are the ones that have what you
would have to refer to in creating any
route object anyway so speaking of
authentication I are ours that are run
by our IRS and the person who chose
those two acronyms really has a lot to
written to answer for any of us who have
left right coordination problems can't
get those type properly but if and irr
is being run by an r ir then they have
internal access to whatever
authentication is is set up for their
members non r ir run IRRs would have to
consult the rirs to find out how do i
authenticate with this person who tells
me that they are authorized to to run
prefix to enter a route object for a
particular prefix that's one minute two
minutes left easy less line so not even
the RIR run IRRs would have this problem
if they were registering route objects
for resources that weren't in their
particular domain for non-member
resources there's also this problem with
currency which we've heard referred to
in the recent panics problem why don't
round objects have a TTL I don't know
perhaps it certainly would be good if
they did but in particular for the RIR
run IRRs if a member ceases to keep up
on their prefixes if a prefix is
reclaimed or if they prefixes returned
all of the route objects in the IRR
should go away that's ok for the RIR run
I are ours but not so much ok for the
others all of this is intended to
solicit request beg for plead entreat
feedback the DNS SEC tools pull them out
try them if you're interested in signing
his own look at the step-by-step guides
see if it's thorough enough for you if
it explains things clearly look at the
tools try the client system that
actually does the DNS SEC validation if
you're interested in the routing
security part participate on the air and
ppm L list give feedback to to me or to
anybody else who's in the air in group
and that's the end thank you
we're in section despair