I good morning everybody today I'm going
to give a little talk about DNS cache
poisoners the motivation for this began
almost a year ago when the sans internet
storm center reported that there was an
ongoing DNS cache poisoning attack and
was a couple URLs there for your
reference if you want to look up the
background on those the basics of the
attack were that some name servers had
been poisoned and they were giving out
bogus NS records for the coms own and
the folks at sands is C had theories
that one of the reasons for this may
have been as a way to propagate spyware
and other things like that and that at
that time they noted that most of the
name server software from windows
including nte 2000 2003 and this
semantic firewall products were affected
by this vulnerability in this attack
you
oh right these are these are now
available on the web okay so here's
here's a one slide it just sort of
describes the DNS cache poisoning attack
an authoritative name server that is one
where queries would normally go for for
certain names is intentionally or
unintentionally configured to return
bogus and out of bailiwick NS Authority
records and the four following slides
have an example of how this looks a
caching name server sends a query to
that authoritative name server and gets
a response and trusts the the bogus
referral and it stores it in the cache
future queries for names in the poison
zone then go to the bogus name server
and that bogus name server returns
incorrect answers to queries that it
should never even be receiving so here's
a here's an example with dig you can
probably run this command yourself and
and you might see the same thing I ran
dig with the trace option for long
island auction com and the first
response that it shows is the set of
name servers that are authoritative for
the DNS root then it sends a query to
one of those in this case we got a
response from M root and M root says
gTLD servers are authoritative for the
comms own k dot gtld servers says off
one off to off three NS Sargasso dead
net are authoritative for long island
auction com and then finally we got a
response from off one NS Sargasso net
and we have an an a record in the answer
but we also have three NS records that
show they list themselves they list the
Sargasso net
nameservers as authoritative for the
coms own so if this response was
received by a vulnerable DNS cache it
would then send future requests for
unknown names in comm to one of those
nameservers and you can simulate that
yourself by again using dig you can send
a query say 4w wal com to one of those
nameservers and you get an answer like
this you get an a record back with 127
127 127 which is not particularly useful
and again you get the authority
Authority section says you know i am
still authoritative 4.com so a little
bit about the implementations that are
known to be vulnerable windows NT is
vulnerable to this attack by default if
you have service pack for you can make
it become not infernal neural with a
little registry editing pain if one is
2000 the early versions were vulnerable
by default and later versions were not
windows 2003 is not vulnerable by
default but it's remarkably easy to make
it vulnerable you just have to go to the
properties section of the DNS server and
uncheck the box that says protect me
from DNS cache poisoning Symantec
Gateway firewall products were
vulnerable and there's a couple of
keywords there you can google for if
you're interested in following up on
that so one of the things that that I
personally wanted to do was I wanted to
find out how big is this problem and how
many DNS poisoners are out there so
here's the the technique that that I
used first and one of the hardest things
is to just get a huge list of DNS names
and go through them one by one and for
each name discover the set of
authoritative servers for the zone and
to do that my little script
sends its own query starting at the root
and follows the referrals on down once I
get the the set of all the authoritative
name servers send a query to each one of
those and in those replies I compare the
NS RR set to the previously learned
referrals from the parent zones and if
they don't match then that's the case of
DNS cache poisoning this technique only
finds cases where where a parent zone is
cached and at this point we're sort of
only interested in cases where a TLD
becomes poisoned because those are sort
of the big targets so there's a survey I
have a survey that I started earlier
this month and it's actually still
running the input list is a little more
than 6 million names captured from
various name servers that that we have
access to and in those so far we've
found 284 sources of poison these are
the ones that return incorrect referrals
to top-level domain or to the root zone
this little table shows which zones are
being poisoned or attempting to be
poisoned most common one is the root
zone itself with 217 and then you know
not surprisingly c-calm net org and so
on there's actually one case where
someone is returning a bad referral to a
TLD called default which for most people
does not exist although it's sort of an
interesting way to perhaps capture
traffic for a TLD that that people may
be using but that's not officially
sanctioned if you added these numbers up
you'd get more than 284 because some
name servers poison more than one zone
here's a list of a few of the poisoners
that we found and when you read through
those lists something becomes sort of
immediately apparent that a lot of these
names make you think that they're sort
of in the business of the DNS we have
internet after
directnic domains are free my name
server expired domain services dns made
easy and so on some of them it's not so
clear that they're in the in the dns
business but by far most of them are and
by the way at the end of this talk I'll
give you a URL where you can go to our
database and you can sort of browse the
list of poisoners yourself and explore
it and find more interesting things so
as I already mentioned a lot of these
poisoning name servers appeared to be
companies that are an idiot dns business
registrar's and resellers and perhaps
speculators and typo profiteers others
appear to be companies that are
unrelated to the DNS business certainly
those that that are the business of
handling domain age they should know
better than this and you would hope that
that they would be able to configure
their own name servers correctly and
properly so that this kind of thing
doesn't happen another thing that
becomes obvious is a lot of the names
that lead to the poisoning authoritative
name servers are names that have been
expired or have been parked recently
registered but not yet placed exactly in
service and by the way I forgot to put
this number on the slide but for the 284
poisoning name servers that we found
there's about 20,000 DNS names which for
which those nameservers are
authoritative so all this kind of begs
the question is is the sky falling is
this a big disaster with you know so
many poisoners out there why don't we
hear more about this well one really
good thing is that even the vulnerable
implementations do not allow the root
zone to be poisoned so that sort of cuts
out a big percentage of the poisoners
that we see out there
but for the others it's it's clear that
the name server can be named server
cache can become poisoned and that they
are so then it makes me wonder if your
name server was poisoned how would you
know in the most obvious way I can think
of that you might know is that if you're
browsing the web and you go to some site
and you get back bad information what
does your what does it look like in your
web browser so we simulated that for
every bad referral that we found we put
the bogus name servers address in
resolv.conf we open up a web browser and
request google com and microsoft com and
then we took a screenshot so here's some
examples of some of the screenshots that
we got note that in the location bar the
URL there says WWE google com and on the
HTML page itself it says WWE google com
this page is parked free courtesy of
godaddy.com so one thing that this makes
me think is that this name server which
is listed at the top there probably has
a wild card and answers any query that
you sent to it and then you know the CGI
script or whatever is configured to
insert the name that was quite for in
the HTML there here's a sort of a
similar example again it says Google in
the in the location bar we recently
registered our domain name at name scale
com what's also interesting about this
one is that they're displaying some
google adwords here and it also appears
that the contents of those google
adwords are related to google itself so
they they've asked google for Edwards
about Google and they got all these
links about search ins and some search
engine engine submission and so on
here's another example very similar not
really too remarkable except for the
fact that and this one the location URL
has changed so there's probably been an
HTTP redirect involved here here's a
case where the name server did not
provide an answer for our query to w
google com this is actually quite common
a lot of the screenshots look like this
it just says unknown host so in this
case you would definitely know well you
should you should be able to figure out
that something's wrong with with
somebody's DNS somewhere here's a case
where you can buy various types of pills
another example again this is google at
the top it has nothing to do with google
this this one I think is interesting for
a number of reasons first of all there's
this annoying shockwave download pop up
in the middle also note that the
location bar URL has changed a little it
says google com / start PHP notice also
that on the right side of the screen
there's some images there's supposed to
be some images those didn't come through
the server you know returned an error
for those requests but perhaps most
interestingly the the content of this
text down here talks about how Vint Cerf
is coming to speak at the domain
roundtable and the guy who runs the site
is very excited because he wants to meet
conserve and he's the executive director
executive event director of this domain
roundtable event so this is a guy that
you would definitely think should know
better than you know know how to
configure his name server here's one
where you can go and configure your your
power site system for google com
this one says smart people choose pair
neck and I sort of beg to differ I like
this one because you know if if you're
not the type of person that uses Google
every day you might look at this and you
might think that it actually is google
it looks sort of like what you'd expect
it's a find it bar with a search button
and some other things and the little tag
line there says we search so you don't
have to you know that could very well be
Google's model for all my mother knows
now this is the last one and I like this
one because it says I don't know if you
can read the text it says it has been
brought to our attention that the IP
address of this server is being used as
a local DNS resolver by a cable or
broadband provider somewhere this is a
mistake because the server reports the
same IP for all queries to an internal
application that has nothing to do with
you you need to contact your excess
provider whoever they are and get proper
DNS resolvers from them but what's
actually happening here is the the guys
running this site and this name server
are poisoning other people's DNS caches
and that poison is causing them to come
to this site so they're aware that
something is wrong here but they haven't
quite figured it out and I actually sent
email to these guys a few days ago but I
didn't get a response back okay so sort
of the last thing that I want to talk
about is you know why is this happening
or is this people being lazy being
stupid or are these people being truly
evil so I tried to define these these
categories for you here's an example of
what i would call laziness the name
server here is in this example is NS 1
dot and what it looks to me like is the
administrator is is too lazy to put each
of the zones that they've been delegated
into
separate zone files and give them their
own you know eat ideally each's own
should have its own file a known SOA
record and so on but instead they take a
shortcut and they create a zone called
calm and then they put each of their
delegated domains into their their comms
own and just lists one or 2a records and
I have an example on the next slide and
this kind of thing is probably the
source of most of the DNS poisoners that
we've found I'm just looking at this
example you may not come to this
conclusion but if you go to this
database that did you be able to see it
in a bit you would find that there's a
lot of this particular name server you
know is authoritative for a lot of names
and not only do they poison calm but
they also poisoned net for.net dames
that they are for which they're
authoritative so here's my guess at what
their zone file probably looks like they
have an SOA record for for calm they
list their own name servers after that
and then they list a records for their
comm delegations
how much time do I have
you think I'm doing a good right okay
here's an example of what you might call
stupidity this in this case it looks
like there's two things going on one is
the comms own technique is being used
again we're delegated names are put into
a incorrect calm zone but there's no dot
after the NS record name so this
response shows that for the comms own
the authority servers are ns1 calm and
s2 calm and s3 calm which have nothing
to do with in s1 dot Frank's net there's
an additional section here which shows
IP addresses for NS 1 comment as to calm
and n is 3 calm now if you if you go to
an employee's name server and query for
NS 1 2 and 3 you'll get different
addresses and you'll find that those
three name servers belong two entirely
different organizations they're
unrelated this this kind of example is
rare but there are actually a lot of
cases where you see the mistake that
there's no trailing thought after the
name on the NS record so for evilness I
actually had a hard time finding an
example where I could definitely say
this is this is somebody being evil my
definition of an evil poisoning name
server is one where it answers queries
that you know it shouldn't be receiving
it answers with the wrong IP address so
if you queried for Google Google you
don't get Google's address you get
something else and it also may be
proxies web traffic so that your you
still get what you expect in your
browser so to help find these kind of
things I came up with this very simple
ranking and for every poisoning name
server it gets a rating from one to five
one point each for
returning a bad referral that is just
being in our database poisoning a TLD
vs. poisoning the root zone answering an
a query for one of the quote
high-profile names that we queried
answering the query incorrectly gets it
another point and then finally if the
screenshot that we take looks like the
real thing then then it gets another
point so we found a few name servers
that are rated at four but so far none
that have been rated at five a few
miscellaneous notes here some of the
sources of poison that we found are
actually authoritative and vulnerable
name servers that is their authoritative
and they're running say Microsoft
Windows that have been already poisoned
by somebody else probably the in
addition to being authoritative for some
zone they're also used as caching
resolvers for clients at whatnot so
those clients have poisoned the zone and
when we hit them they return the bad
referrals in the poison I just like to
emphasize that having an authoritative
name server accept recursive queries is
an incredibly bad idea in this is a
perfect example of why some of the NS
records that we found during our survey
are the names are not fully qualified
the name NS is particularly popular so
that's sort of interesting because if a
caching name server becomes poisoned
with the referral to a name server
called NS it's not going to be able to
look up that name and the sort of the
poisoning would not succeed and it's a
very good thing I think that even the
vulnerable name server implementations
don't allow the root zone to be
I'm poisoned here's here's kind of the
bottom line at this point time there are
currently several several hundred
misconfigured name servers out there
returning bad referrals that can poison
Danish caches some of those perhaps with
malicious intent but I would say most do
not about 75% of those try to poison the
root zone which usually has no effect
I'm not aware of any implementations
that allow the the root zone to be
poison but that doesn't mean that
they're there are some obscure ones out
there probably ninety percent of the
caching name servers out there today are
running software that is not vulnerable
to this kind of thing and I would say
that most of the attempted poisoning or
most of the cases where it looks like
poisoning is going on can be attributed
to laziness and stupidity here's the URL
for this online database that we have
and feel free to you know ask me
questions after the talk or later on
during the meeting and if if you want
please send me some email and we can
talk about this some more thanks
friend or what River domain two
questions what do you do with these
poison name servers and do you put to
abuse department or do you actually
black hole them and be how often you run
these scripts to avoid false positives
well I don't right now I don't do
anything with the the information that I
find except for put it in this database
which is accessible on that URL I did
contact one technical contact for for
one of the cases that I found but I
didn't get response from them and you
know this has been talked about before I
think in the past contacting people is
pretty hit-and-miss a lot of times you
just don't get a response but it's
certainly something that you know should
be done but the second question what was
the second question how lofty run the
script other than false positive right
so we've I've run this survey a few
times in the past but not regularly my
plan is to say run it every month now
from now on it takes about 10 days to go
through the whole list of names that I
have at this point false positives is
not I wouldn't I don't know I wouldn't
consider false positives sort of in the
data I would say yeah things change over
time and they may be easily block in
yeah yeah and it's certainly possible
that someone you know fixes their thing
and it gets taken out of the next result
said well i'll ping you offline maybe I
can help okay okay yeah thank you
all right thank you okay