okay okay good morning everyone
okay sorry
so let's start so on
welcome to seek hem session so I think
you can get meeting information
including the meeting slides from the
link below and also you can get more
information about sick hem from the
tourist page so on
this the load wear and this the new
version of the and not where I think of
you and should be very family with this
kind of information because you know I
each working group needs to I introduced
a lot where before presentation so
actually you know this lot we are men is
about ITF policies especially IPR policy
and the definition of idea for a
contribution and participation so if
there are some newcomers please take a
look so it's usually have their you know
audio recording so please be in front of
the mic and state your name before
speaking and for the minutes so you know
our secretary Oscar he's not here he's
quite busy so on if anyone can capture
some minutes and captured the discussion
of this session we are appreciate thank
you chamber loom there are some people
are in the gem balloon I think we will
keep an eye home on the gem bloom if
there are some comments from the gem
loom I think we can read the comments in
front of the market
so this time we have two sessions for
second right now this wine test session
- so these two agenda so I think you
know this time we have more time we have
two and a half hours so we should have
more time for discussion so please just
take your time as to constitute any
comments on the agenda
okay none so an Amanda folder you know I
PR process you know usually we will do
the IPR polling before an individual job
- becomes a working group document or a
working document or group document
become goes to dub G last call and
usually we I and you know hope the
authors and the contributors to the
point the IP upholding as soon as
possible and then we can you know speed
up to conclude process another mind on
the manliest we always encouraging
people to use them many lists as much as
possible any technical issues technique
problems can be or should be discussed
on the list and also you know that
working group consensus it's determined
on the many lists and not about the you
know face-to-face fits committee even
though if we get some consensus here we
should print the tutor to the list for
discussion
so they're quite a lot of progresses
since since last meeting we have a new
RFC finally we put this this document on
all the for a while waiting for the
generalised extensions to be done to be
done in teaser the working thesis is
concluded and we could progress the SPF
availability extension in C camp which
now made it and it's now RFC 8380
we have one more document in the editor
cube this is another document that was
depending on the generalized the HESI
document and to two documents the
microwave framework and the DWDM
interface management framework both of
them have been submitted to the SD and
they are now in the expert review phase
working group drafts on agenda you will
see a new draft the transport mvi
applicability statement this is a merger
of the existing working group draft
produced by the transport MBI plus the
analysis of the use cases 1 & 3 please
each other than a correct me if I'm
wrong and the microwave younger working
group drafts which are not being
presenting presented today are the C
compiler module which has been which has
been adopted recently it receives
received a lot of comments on the
mailing list it's there's a lot of good
discussion on it and also we receive the
agent from ITT study group 15 on that
recently we adopt also the Flex agreed
the young model
to the other ones there is no update on
the ot anthropology and the DoD internal
model I don't know if any of the others
would like to say a few words about the
stages and the progress of the OT n
draft sir
however Holly and I'm taking care of the
OT in topology and Italian models and
this model is supposed to have the
augmentation from the generic team or
those of the increased working group and
the currently we notice there are some
changes on the fundamental model that we
hold on for this model update to make
sure that after the maturity of the team
models we can update accordingly we are
now working together with the team of
others to make everything consistent
thanks a lot another one that has been
recently adopted the dab is on Tannen
model there was a younger and right
yesterday we adopted also the w.zahn in
impairment impairment aware encoding
reasons we have as usual quite intense
communication relationship with the ITU
Study Group 15 we sent a liaison on the
younger module as as I said before and
the reply was an incoming reply is
available on the on the webpage for you
to read the in comment this is it for
the introduction we can start with the
first presentation
any comment on the agenda everything is
fine with it
thank you me Telugu see from away
represent Devine and update about the
transport MBI design team so quick
reminder about what is the objective of
the design team and its developers on
your skills and cap analysis to
understand how the ITF Yamada can be
applied to transport network and the
coordinator we see companies if any
changes needed to fit into the
applicability and what we do we have a
many list conference calls and we have a
Geetha where we track the changes the
editorials the worker and open issues
what we have Donna as already summarized
a quickly by Daniel we have a new draft
which is a transport MBI applicability
statements which is basically merging
the three documents that working through
document the two individual documents we
produce the pasta and this is basically
focused on analyzing the Yamada's can be
used to control a multi domain ot and
networks we provide Sanjay so-called
examples to see how the diff India in
this specific use case the different
fields are filled and basically we focus
on the MPI between MD SC and multiple
PNC's and we work about what is a
topology obstruction how to set up the
service and to end across a Muslim a
network how we can configure protection
restoration and we have recently added a
possibility to modify the service from
protected and protect in the modified
event rhythm we have a some open issues
which are we are working on the first up
initially is was resourceful on Monday
during the t's working group its
relationship between this work our work
and eighty tutorial we had a some
discussion yesterday with the autos and
we have understood that the objective
way to work are quite different so Tito
Paul tutorial is mainly focusing on
describing the principle the definitions
and modeling and modeling assumptions
for the T topology and tunnel models and
the use case developed in
documents are merely f2 to explain based
on demand people say how do you do this
case then they show how to do that and
they recover maybe also some of us a
topic like detail creativity metrics and
constrain part computation how do these
advances stuff our work is more focused
on the under and a specific use case
which is multi-domain no tiene we work
on that and we want to show how you can
in a multimedia network configure
services and to enter maybe some items
like like the tekken TV dramatics or
constraints but computation we don't go
into that details we go more on details
on how the different domains are
coordinated so there is of course there
are different objectives there is a some
overlapping and the idea is that the
authors of the two drafts work together
as already as already ran and trying to
avoid the inconsistency some duplication
it may be unavoidable especially on the
JSON code but we will make sure that
there is no inconsistency that's the
most important thing and people may be
interested in two different approaches
so it's good to have both so that's the
proposal from the auto shop that you
documents them the second open issue is
what to do about our worker so do we
need to coordinate or communicate with
other projects like of a config or odom
t IP and any affair I think again we
forgot one F as well but okay I see
there are other people and we want to
see whether we have to work together and
make sure that the use cases are covered
and I would say I would like to try to
answer your question in an ideal world
yes but I can understand it's it's
almost impossible to do to do everything
so ok try to focus on on our original
scope which was mostly main activities
yeah yeah yeah we are focused on
developing the use case but yeah the
question is do we want to look at say if
you have time appreciated okay I see I'm
not asking
okay that package clear okay thank you
good good input the other open issue is
we got some input about the multi-layer
city architecture it seems that when you
have any our key key but different here
key between underlying and lying
technologies and some information may
not be available to the top level MVS
see we are some discussion but we have
not finished analyzed that one doubt is
whether this isn't an issue that applies
only to packet an optical multi-layer or
is a general applicable for example to
Ooty and layer 0 layer 1 so we are
trying to understand because the main
your issue is the fact that the domain
boundaries between IP and optical do not
match so you may have a different
structure hierarchy and the ghast curve
to coordinated you may not have enough
information if you have struck too much
and that so we are still analyzing to
validate a concern if there is a
solution and to describe it and adapt is
whether it is generic applicable to our
says or not we still don't know we're
still working on that we have some
discussion on the client services so the
the big issue is that the eternal it
creates a tunnel between the end nodes
but we need to configure how they assess
a fee for example it ran says traffic is
classified and is map it into the T
tunnel and we are working as subjects to
use the motors that will be presented by
and later in the agenda but ok that's
something we have to analyze in the next
phase and that we have some minor detail
in technical discussion like how the I
to RS identifiers and identifiers match
together and somebody brought it the
idea to think about also what happens
when you have audio CN in the network so
we have to think about that yeah ok so
next steps is to progress to address in
the opera technical issue to integrate
edge as an example and provide more it
as an example we have a w we want to do
any formal or a liaison to ask people to
take a look to our document and give
feedback and then we plan to have a
face-to-face meeting basically this
afternoon at 3:20 we will meet by the
registration I gave registration desk
and we look for a for assault
okay so regarding the liaison
well the ATF as a formal reason
relationship with the some of the bodies
that that you've listed I don't see any
issue in preparing a liaison and sending
it sending it out mostly now that the
draft is a working group document so if
you want to try to propose attacks on
the mailing list that we can discuss it
and and send it we will then try to
understand who to send it okay
any comments we are still warming up
okay yes
I I'm Eunice all day I'm gonna present
the status of the young data model for
microwave radio link since the Singapore
meeting we have submitted two new
revisions the first one the 0 3 R
Edition contains updates in order to
align better to the eitf documentation
guidelines and we have looked at the
tour RFC in these subunits listed on on
on the slide here secondly we have the
simplified some of the names of the data
nodes where we have removed a
duplication of the group or container
name we'll see in the data node names
and finally we have added a couple of
examples at the end of the the draft to
explain how to instantiate two typical
configurations in the radio link domain
one configuration called want R 0 that
means that we have one radiating
terminal containing one carrier
termination interface and the second one
is a bonded configuration where two
carrier termination interfaces are
included in one radiating terminal the
second update since the signal Singapore
meeting is based on valuable comments
that we have received from Tom patch and
we have added missing references and
done some editorial Corrections based on
that feedback so looking at the
simplification of the names it's fairly
straightforward if you can see on the
left hand side that's the original model
and with the duplication of the
container name also in the data node
names so we have removed protection
xpeke and my mo words that we believe
are not necessary and then ending up
with the data model that you can see on
the right hand side and this is how we
have created the examples
this is the example of showing the 1+0
configuration so we use a picture or a
figure to illustrate the configuration
as such and this figure is showing both
ends of a radio link which is terminated
by the radio link termination or
terminal and then in this example it
contains one carrier termination and the
actual instantiation is done shown for
the NIR and one of the ends of of this
radio link so here we show one
instantiation of the interface of type
radio link terminal and the Associated
interface of type II carry termination
and way forward we believe that the
model definition is complete and it has
been stable for some time we have one
comment though that I would like to get
your important input on and that is a
suggestion from Tom to break out the
enumerations or the type definitions and
put that into a separate module and I
would like to have your input on that if
that's the way to do it or if we should
keep it within the same single module
module otherwise we would like to ask
for a work group by lost call again
thank you comments are mostly on the
last question Amy from Huawei so
regarding the last question and my
personal preference may be to break it
out I think that makes the models to be
clear and so it's either two after the
each individual module its own won't
affect another one so
Tom parent good morning yes it's just
based on experience particularly with
bibs and Teressa extent with yang that
what starts off as one piece then turns
into two separate pieces with two
different life cycles and so looking at
the long long list of cram in particular
I don't know I'm sure you know much
better than I whether that list is
likely to change or not and if there
were new ones coming along 6400 raise to
five sixes and so on
then it would make sense to break out
that list if you look back you'll see
that it's quite commonly been done with
mid modules and it's also been done with
things like interfaces interface types
where the interface types been separated
out because the expectation is over the
next few years the lifecycle of
interface types will be different to the
lifecycle of the interface yang module
and a number of examples of that already
systems cause it as well so it's a
rather belated thought means quite a bit
of work theaters and parade but if you
think over the next few years that list
of eg clam is going to change then I
would urge you to consider separating it
out into a separate yang module with a
different life cycle okay when you speak
about the different life cycles you are
you suggesting to split the two modules
into different drafts that's what they
do with the interfaces I mean and
there's an ultimate separation well in
the case the mid modules quite a lot of
the you numeration to put under the
control of IANA and put under expert
review and so you didn't even have to
cycle an RFC in order to add new
interface types to the list of
interfaces in this case we would be to
the list of modulation techniques and so
the ultimate would be given under an
yarn or control with expert review the
most tightly coupled is what we got at
the moment with a single module so if
either part of that information changes
we have to recycle the RFC or put in
something that the dog mends hit or
whatever so there's a spectrum of
possibilities and
to rehang modules within the one RFC is
the simplest separation but it as I say
it all depends on on what you think is
gonna happen to that list
my experience is people think lists
disabled and then five years later find
they weren't too wish they and built it
all into the same piece of concrete okay
Amy again I have another questions when
you mention about the sir case it was
the new in nations won't be changing a
few years I would like to ask how many
is the few years maybe in three or five
years or longer than that so we should
based on what kind of numbers we should
make this decision
don't batch again I'm saying that I
don't know what the likely lifecycle of
that list is and I think your expertise
in this room is far greater than mine so
if you think that list has been stable
for 10 years never going to change then
there's no point in doing anything but
if you think a new ones going to come
down the road and the usually come down
the road my experience much quicker than
I expect if you think anyone's going to
come down the road then it's worth at
least in my judgment separating it out
into two young modules within one RFC to
make them easier to update yeah it's
hard to predict what's going to happen
from a technology point of view but to
say that it's going to be stable for 10
years no I don't think we can say that
Amy again I agree with Yunus maybe 10
years that's no we won't we are not able
to see that but I could say maybe three
years you will keep on changes and I
still preferred this later but we will
keep the more user within one draft or
so it's easy not we could update and
keep them because they are so record
greater with each other so that's my
suggestion
so I'll tell you what we have not yet
discussed about this so it's just my
opinion not ours this is so we've been
working on young models for a while now
and I would like to have something
published and this is the only module
that has no dependencies on ongoing
drafts all the tunnel topology models
depend on publication of of other
documents this one is based on an RFC so
this is the one that we can we can
progress if you feel that there is a
number of parameter a portion of the
module that is stable and isn't not
going to change we can split the
document and progress just that one I
would say to go this way if that amount
of parameters is the something they can
you can be implemented it is something
that the standalone doesn't make much
sense is pointless to progress just a
subset of parameters that is useless in
the end if so if this split makes sense
we can do it and progress one document
if the splitter doesn't make sense then
we need to discuss our auto manage these
but I again just my personal inclination
is to try to progress this document
before the next meeting so now it's a
the microwave expert that need to
understand if there is a set of stable
parameters that we can progress and
leave the other part like work in
progress or keep everything together
and possibly move move everything
together if you if you believe that
things are not going to change a
significantly we can keep everything
together and move everything together
the way I don't believe that it's
possible to split it into two parts
where one part is stable and the other
one is more likely to change the
parameters or the inaugurations we
talked about or or a key to the model so
we cannot break out any of them and say
that we we take care of them later on
they are core for the modelers as it is
secondly we have defined them as
identities with the purpose to make it
easy to extend them with additional
modules or done the specific models if
if needed I don't know if that helps or
well it's it seems to be the good basis
to address a Tom's Tom's concern in the
sense that the modular is a quite of
future proof if a quarter to understand
what you're saying so this would make me
think that keeping things together
shouldn't be a problem if with a single
a short document you can augment it
easily and Amy again so I think even if
we split into two modules I don't think
that's a significant to change because
it's more like a a structural rearrange
the definition with real capes are then
the same the technique we don't change
any technical parts so but num an hour
will be fun with either way if there's
more suggestions to keep them together
and I personally like to progress that's
more important
Tom your last word
tone Pech most of my life I seemed to be
encountering people who come out to me
and say Tom we wish we didn't to you
five years ago done what you suggested I
have the art of seeing the right answer
being unable to persuade people it is
the right answer
so my I are would say spit out that list
of identities into a separate young one
you'll keep it in the RFC but spit it in
into a separate yang module that's
that's what I would do or do to do
hi this is Amy here from Hawaii and I'm
going to present about a new draft we
defined a young data model for microwave
technology so this microwave technology
to after is argument and t-top knowledge
models which is also argument is a
network technology model the use case of
the microwave technology were thinking
about the following two cans the first
one is for resource management and for
example you could exposures or radio
link frequency to the topology and then
enables you if you want to do our rate
planning and the frequency for example
to decrease in a various level of each
radio link so this could be one possible
use case another path important the use
cases for past computation as it's been
introduced or for several times that is
this radio link will have two feature to
change its span device so it is
important to understand what's the
current bandwidth of the radio link and
so we included this information into the
microwave topology model and also in our
case that we will use the availability
to describe the link characteristics so
we will also report through the topology
model and then this is the topology
young tree
it's quite simple in the first version
we introduced a new network type which
is microwave technology and then under
that we argument are teaming attributes
which includes a link frequency channel
separation or you could call it a
channel bandwidth we use channel
separation in our case and then also
have a nominal bandwidth and currently
penguins
and then the link availability so well I
would like to explain how this model is
related always the microwave the
interface model the one neurons have
just introduced I list this two models
under the architecture by using
architecture of France I see Jian
so in our step our understanding that
the topology model is expected to use it
as a networks terrorists young model so
it should be a user between the mtsc and
PNC our while the interface young model
S device defined for the physical layer
configuration so it's a kind of differ
device configuration module which is
supposed to be used between the PNC and
the network elements so at the level of
the PNC we are expecting that PSA should
convert the information from the top
knowledge model into the interface model
for example the link frequency from the
top knowledge model should map to the TX
frequency into the carrier termination
of the interface model so there's some
mapping between the two and it is also
explained that in our say 80 199 we have
different layers of the models and it is
possible to reduce the low layer young
models by the how high earlier modules
but we still need to explore more how
exactly as this map enum could be
achieved and then in the drop-down
appendix we add to JSON example because
we stored that the JSON coder will be
quite helpful to understand how to use
this young models the first example is
about the single of microwave link which
is the simple case and here we
demonstrated that way
the current signal will be isn't it so
it's kind of a isn't it over microwave
link and we'll use the modulator
technology the concept from the Tito
biology so advert in the t Ethernet
table which model you will say there's a
isn't it t links and then this T links
will have a underlay containers which is
supported either termination and the
Eternals
in the microwave topology and then in
the lower layers the Tito biology of
microwave you receives a microwave
kernels and the microwave links and
under the microwave links you can say
what's the young what's the dead anode
definition we just introduced in in for
most nights and the second the second
case will be a little bit complex than
the first one which is the crime signal
will still be the Ethernet service and
then the second we will use to microwave
think we could two plus zero to
transporter to Ethernet services so we
have a several discussion always some of
the tree topology waters regarding how
to model with this to microwave bundle
links here it is showed that or we use
the bounded boundary case in the Tito
biology so you can say that doesn't the
Ethernet technology will be same so I
didn't repeat friends of almost nice and
this Roger you could say at the
microwave technology we could have the
two component links but there's
different ideas whether this
two-component mixture be shown that ism
tea technology of you because there's
arguments to say or whether this
microwave links Phoenix
but my personal questions that if we
don't show that in the microwave
technology then well we can get this
Bing contributes for this each
individual component needs so this is a
little bit unclear to me right now and
then the next one last page is talking
about the next steps then the first try
plan is that we were updated draft again
will receive some offline comments to
complete the JSON example in the
appendix and then it is handed to in ECM
wtl to have a microwave SEO podcast and
this microwave technology model will be
verified in that practiced so we are
expecting more update according to the
discussion and and finally we would like
to propose to use this draft tools as a
starting point to defined as a microwave
technology young module so we would like
to ask for working group adoption and
finally in this video we will all have a
side discussion and if you're interested
you're working to join us thank you
comment
I mean hey look on journal from
telefónica a just to be sure that they
understood properly they proposal so
this topology model would be I mean
would allow to expose the information of
the topology for sure but also could be
used for configuring the device how
because you mentioned that in the
topology maybe you could specify the
frequency and this frequency be
configuring the device later on would be
the case not only it was post
information but also to allow
configuration from this the figure on
the left in front of top you we will use
the technology to config and then the
controller the PLC will convert that
into the enterprise model so which
allows you to come free grounds a
physical device okay so it would have I
mean we could have different someone
interfaces different models even
appropriate values and so on okay thank
you so anyone comment so could you move
to the next page next one so if you are
going to if you need to show the detail
information of the component links why
not just treat you know controlling one
single component at one key link one one
under the ring according to the
definition from the T to pathology and
actually you will say that the LTP one
and LTP to actually is a physical link
and this one is the component links
where is it no way there's a abandoning
switch is LTP straight so it's kind of a
virtual link that one is supporting the
microwave eternal so we discussed always
refer and also our search
Sturgill and the we have the discussion
whether this in such a case
it is whether this to microwave links
attaining so we have kind of a different
idea about this but I think it's kind of
a generic problem because I see in the
internet level the rules also isn't a
lack so but I talked to several people
and it is saying SMS it's not been
discussed in the MBR design team so we
this is the first proposal we propose
how to models or radio link in but if we
there's better ideas could update
according to that Thanks
okay come on good morning this is a
plantations an update today GMP is
routing and signaling funeral for flexi
it's okay
better okay yeah thank you yeah here's a
update to this wrapped
what happened since NASA my Ida meeting
so we update a new version version 5 and
add a new section to this version it's
many about open issues and and as a is a
lot said this section is not into intend
to be removed in a1 it published and
also it's just as a trigger to to check
more discussion about whether the issue
about our sweetie station folate layer
which one is better which one's better
and which wise should be adopted by this
work and also in this update we made
some mandatory changes and also there
are some work in remain to be done in
the future version and first one is
about to do some fighting final cleanup
for the requirement and so maybe some
parts of the text maybe need to separate
it to different separate different
documents so here's just a reminder of
what how GM peers control plane can be
used in the case of flexi so here we can
say that we can I think that GM's
control plan can be used to set up flexi
group and flexi client by using the
communication channel of the Flexi and
also we can use the routing protocol to
to advertise a flexi group and if I see
client into routing system I just like
advertiser normal link for example these
are easily being or other type of things
and also again once the flexi group and
flex kind established we can use some
signaling to set up example can use
amperes as missing role in to set up our
speed over those taxi instructors so
here's about this side is up is a
summary about the open issue now this
many about the flexi control plan
there's some question about the
relationship between module layer and
the and this has B TV stations whether
actually currently we at least four
options here maybe you can go yeah this
is the first one option one for this one
there's only one station established it
can handle all layers control for
example can just use one position to set
up Mexico flexi current or even to set
up our space over this track ceilings
and the second option is that is just
under country outlet direction just just
like for each layer we can use a
dedicate our decision for example the
flexicord can use a dedicated session
receipt client can use a dedicated room
and so this way you can each session can
just only behind each on necessary
information and and it's extremely
necessary information don't matter
don't think come back can you speak a
little bit louder please
okay
Thanks ah maybe slant direction yeah
this is a option two option straight
it's just just like come it's a mix of
the option one option two in this in
this option we can just use one our
decision just for only for the example
phoneme for the fact see the related
super layers for example excellent the
first probe just use one RGB decision
and for other layer control can use
another delicate art decision so option
for is about this is a similar like the
option one but here is the difference
that for each layer you have it will
have different dedicated control plane
and for and also has dedicate our
position yeah this this and and
regarding the next step we are helpful
there are more reveal from looking group
and also solicit more comments from the
body growth and we also think that maybe
it's right hand to ask talking about
option which is the option that you are
suggesting you don't have preference
from now and we just want to get the
back from Europe okay well identifying
the pros and cons could could be helpful
to to make a decision actually I would
be in favor of number three to do
everything that is flexi together and
everything that is known flexi in a
different search such the one you called
12 targets exactly but I will need it
well understand better pros and cons the
double or Nokia at the previous IETF
meeting when this draft was presented we
actually provided some comments also on
the mailing list after the meeting I
think in the replies to that email I
understood that
the concerns or comments that we made
have been confirmed and now looking at
the latest revision of distract I don't
see that these comments have been
incorporated into the document so what
are the next steps regarding these
comments yeah may be amiss that comments
maybe can just maybe we missed that
comments you can just you know to review
the comments a family-based my name is
and try to address it in a mixed
diversion but for this update didn't you
just add a new section to discuss or
open issues what I mean there were there
were some severe issues which we brought
up related to the Flexi implementation
agreement so we saw we believe that
there's functionality described in the
draft which is not covered by the
implementation agreement for flexi I I
don't remember the discussion honestly
but you said that you agreed on the
resolution of those major comments you
agreed on the resolution of the only
solution of solving those comments no it
was confirmed that the concerns we
erased are valid concerns but they were
not taken into account on the latest
revision of the document was produced so
as we said the update the latest update
that's presented here is just providing
a new section with open issues right so
could you please revive the discussion
yes I can thank you thank you so much so
this dafonte in the video I hope you
comment so why you need to introduce
these three types of the you know
multi-layer can show options do you mean
that the existing solutions or approach
for the multi layer cannot satisfy flexi
scenario or tweener something new but
just because there's some you know
discussion among ulcers and yeah there's
some maybe has some different so others
so we just want to give an open
discussion on this
the weather which one is more suitable
for this kind of use cases oh you mean
this kind of scene justified information
and the for example if you just pick one
of the three types options do you need
some different protocol extensions no no
I think no okay because it's traps it is
only about the framework and yeah so
that's not all about extensions to the
protocol so when calorific is in
question for tenure
that's a serie using that obvious Ansari
is the right one how you tackle in part
of this one okay so I think you're
talking about top one two out of three
you call twelve the option three but
thank you
okay hi everyone this is chili this
topic it is a party has come true of
beyond 100 Gig okay network it's about a
son for a mocha token okay a second
started to tell what happened during a
society of meeting and the during last
IDF media to face discussing happy
during happy hour month also than a
contributor of the traffic that's based
on the to tactical scenario dedicated in
appendix of 0 to 7 or none and the
discussion many on the challenges to
come true well beyond 100 Giga network
worth by the emergence about using and
audio saying as well as some potential
attention needed to Jenkins Singhania
and writing aquatic it doesn't talk
about this
so look take a look at a scenario force
the force of scenario and it starts the
the finger is copy the from they put
several none and rewrite but it's not
different
this is in this scenario it deploys out
using all audios in design between tool
and parts connecting to layer one
earlier only a 0tu course connects
within one optical transport network 102
using is actually carried by one okay
8000 tae
that is the optical path so after the
discussion we sink we also saying that
out you see a note you see ending can be
automatically established aft
altogether ways does that help out over
the optical path this is the FASTA
scenario and the second scenario is a
little complicated in the
scenario 1 and an audio saying and
actually supported a pass rate they find
out he'll say audio cues in desam
segments which I intend carried by the
optical party in this scenario
discussing with singer in a scenario the
audience will be established
automatically after together with set of
the optical paths while we sing has us
there some doubts about how do you
singing the instability in the Senate
especially what I'm talking about is a
transponder point how to set harbor and
to end the OTS a link of course a
transponder connected to out here and
course connects so this is the second
scenario that's based on these two
scenario and after that discussing we
can work from cholangitis and made some
uncertainty about asset Howell what
you're sending we think has a it's still
exists and this uncertainty may have a
relationship with the progress at UT so
it's much the another career I was
thinking and then also under some
contribute we just decided that the
scope of this draft currently may be
wish to the mainly focus on how to set
up audio ke audio for access P / audio
settings we also give some evaluation to
the current attention of GNP as a single
owner and the Jamieson
writing defining obviously something was
a Dallas fc7 729 after discussing was
saying that the signaling and the
writing mechanism the findings is - I've
seen recently can be it can be reused
- hi come favor the OT okay audio
for exampie with no changes once the
audio saying link I read easier it's
configured so so that's all they have
discussed during the last idea meeting
so the next page I just gave an example
it has how to use a label format the
funny of say 71 39 to describe how to
multiplex
oh dear fall unto audio Satan as in the
in this case one audio Satan has 255 key
gets lost and 20 of them are unlocking
that what you fall and about next steps
I think we should invite ball reviewing
a comment and then maybe I think I can
purple to request the father working
purple Dobson the reason that I want to
request for working for adult size
because to reading the fossilized I
think I talked to contributor oh no I
got a feedback a phone yeah but not all
of them addressing we have our children
we ran it all this I was still another
reason is I talk about the stuff in this
platter with a cute he expressed in
question 12 and a question 14 was from a
on a face-to-face and the feedback I got
from them asking it's about him they
some of them that's Italian
listen hit two cracks so they sound
there's a feedback form then I think
maybe it's time to request for what can
go about saying I think it would be a
good start upon okay thank you humming
Iftekhar
no infinera just quit I guess just
trying to summarize I guess are you
saying that because I missed the last
meeting so I guess the conclusion is
that based on the current scope of the
document there's no need for routing and
signaling extension is it a correct yes
and okay so and I think you just
mentioned you had a conversation with
the ITU experts and they verified your
may I did you send that actually in the
could you send that is it okay for you
to send that email exchanges to the list
or assign the email if I mean if last
week okay okay
what once the document is adopted we can
send a liaison
sheelane I wouldn't like to double check
so do you mean that there's nothing to
be extended further you know beyond 100
that's the base current is go wait
outside aside or second place the scope
of this traffic mainly focus on how to
set up audio key and all you flex as
over audio settings that the patient's
this wishing has needed to attend to the
current protocol based on a Cisco so you
mean that we can just use the distant
offices like FCR 71 39 right yeah and to
set up the connections for under beyond
100 yen yeah and then my questions what
the value of this document if there's
nothing needed nothing new needed hmm
I think it's because because of the
emerging shelves and beyond the 100
games such as OTO say OTO saying we need
to tell something about it because that
is still not document in current IETF
and doc know so I think maybe we needed
such a chocolate without containers yeah
I'm a little confused about looking at
agenda and and the you know draft itself
and and now this discussion is even more
confusing so in in the in the agenda
it lists essentially two titles and I
could figure that out because it looks
like there was a framework and a
solution and then in the draft itself
the major title is the first of those
two titles and then the title at the top
of each page is a BGP erm I'm sorry
extensions the G but whatever it is 100
extensions so it then looks at page by
page like it's a solution document and
I'm trying to read through it and I'm
not really seeing anything and it seems
to me that now we're saying that there's
no solution in it either so what is
really the point of the document I want
to give some explanation saying I think
a solution is needed but we don't need
to i dint sorry to do some acting job to
current the traffic week I just want to
give some very recent give some analysis
s the current current to the mechanism
defining is signaling traffic can be
reused it should it's because it's
because of the emergence of a some new
stuff so why don't you say and that
wouldn't be done here is that what we're
saying this is not publication for our
money
I would say that a sort of applicability
of existing GMP Alex gmpls extensions
defined for G 709 version 3 to this work
could be something useful obviously
isn't we need to change the name from a
framework and extensions to
applicability but yeah with with that
change it would make a lot more sense
thank you thank you Thanks
I am young I'd like to present young
models for flexgrid optical networks
this is basically a tunnel model in the
last IDF meeting the working group has
accepted topology model and actually at
the time I presented both models but
somehow this model has not been pulled
on the working group so I basically
represent the same same material without
much change but I'd like to give you
some background so this is based on RFC
76 98 the framework and requirement for
the Flex grid
DWM networks this basically arguments t
tunnel model so major changes from the
previous version is basically we
separated out from topology model from
tunnel model it is to be a one model and
a link channel is now reusing LSP from T
a tunnel model as opposed to private
extension and NN nmda compliant so this
is a basically a young model that we
argument from Thea tunnel model as you
see here and I believe order layer 1
layer 0 young models have been adopted
except for this one and this is probably
the last one to be adopted and move on
after based eternal model you know has
been stabilized so I think it may be
time to adopt this work
it was mostly question a matter of time
that because we have we have pulled I
don't remember four or five documents in
a row so it's not it's not just that
these one had something wrong it was
just a backlog of full of documents to
be adopted but let let's try two to see
if what the working group thinks so how
many people have read this document
quite a lot how many people think this
is a good starting point for a working
group document less than the people that
read it so I would like to ask people
who have concerns to come to the mic and
say why they didn't raise their hand
let's try again who is against adopting
this this this document as a working
group document so made a mistake account
in the end okay we will take this to the
list in any case no Tama you have a
concern
Tom Pech like in my comments on the
previous ID my comments are more sort of
administrative wrong technical that is I
see a lot of young models containing
very good technical staff having the
right sort of objects with the right
sort of characteristics and so on but
the rest of the information around it is
is lacking and my comments have made
which unisys very happily picked up or
mostly along that line and so what I'm
looking at it is a young model and
looking at the guidelines that have
recently been republished and seeing how
well does it conform with guidelines and
so the reason I didn't raise my hand to
your second question is the lack of
performance of guidelines
maybe the author's very happy to take
all that on board and fix it but I
haven't yet got to the stage of actually
posting a comment on the list and seeing
what was once I get to comments of that
nature about you know the copyright
being wrong with lack of references
there being references embedded in one
place the home after things in in the
guidelines reproducing a young model and
it's a conformist who's it's my concern
rather than the technical content which
I suspect will be of the interest to
more of the audience here you're Riskin
Chloe so I understand that your grant
based eternal right for the flux a great
model so the question is would it be
better to have like richer here are here
of the augmentations for example to
augment say layer zero do you turn off
right and then out of that lecture great
this direction we could it could be like
a more ways to explore and to
declaration of
previously provided marginality right so
you go when you say layer zero do you
mean w son yeah I mean just a simple
lambdas right the single channel lambdas
and then based on that obviously there
are a lot of things that could be
covered there which certainly could be a
reusable flexi very plug like optical
impairments for instance right was
discussed previously and then for
topology model you know not to mention
this tunnel model so I think working
group chairs suggested just stay with W
Sun and flats great separate photo
Palooza model so we just call out the
same pattern I attack you know when your
argument actually it doesn't make much
difference at the end yeah okay yeah so
it's more logistic issue and I think
working group has already made made a
decision to go this way so technically
it doesn't make much difference but you
know it's not beyond my you know
capability or beyond my so I think it's
a question to the working group Cheers
because you have made that decision for
topology model so we just follow it on
on more the same way so no I just say if
you separate tunnel proposal that makes
perfect sense right but if you for
example use to augment ation separate
augmentations from the base station or
model one for lambdas and another for
flexure grid then obviously would have
to repeat many cemented matrix right in
both like for example to do with optical
impairments so your concern is when we
do optical impairment augmentation the
world we start with a dis model or
Douglas non-motorized yeah I suggest to
start at where it starts right and with
single channel numbers yeah I think you
know it's something too
they don't remember this discussion that
oh you're the one who pulled and adopted
topology models so okay I think that
point is valid I think you go but we'll
discuss with working group challenge and
also also so this document of the Sun
and in terms of times comment
conformance I'm not sure what was the
real comment I'm sorry what do you mean
by conformance document is like in
conformance it said technically it's
okay but document needs to be more
conformance oh I don't understand what
conformance means so that I can pass
down to the others
maybe you should see to cause up to the
mic so I move to sit in front of
loudspeaker it was just tom patch again
yes what I'm saying is that you says
nmda compliant and that's excellent news
my question is how much does it comply
with the guidelines that have just been
be published for authors of young
modules laying down what should be there
in place of copyright RFC name
references how references should be
handled there's a whole raft of things
and every young model I look at apart
from those produced by the net conflict
mod working groups every hang model is
defective with respect to those
guidelines and so the starting point for
me is how receptive is the author to
changing it to be like those guidelines
and I'm saying
yonis earlier is a very receptive so
that's good news I have a lot of faith
in the rest of it model okay yeah
absolutely yeah so this is just yeah I
think I understood your point okay
thanks
[Music]
okay good morning everyone this is hamer
from Hebei i'm going to introduce the
updating from three different documents
including the client signal young model
client apology yamamoto and the client
on your model so we have this three
models application applied in different
scenarios and this is the second work
there are two version we are having so
we actually did receive some offline
comments after we upload the document is
this time and before my introduction to
the updated details I would like to
firstly answer two typical questions the
first question would be what is the
relationship between this work and the
layer 203 service model as we are
focusing currently the internet model I
think the the layer xsm it's mainly
referring to the layer 2 sm so we try to
explain this by using the figure ok use
a figure in r3 8080 309 and what we can
see is layer 2 sm is a kind of customer
service model which is referring to the
interface a in notation a between the
customer and the service Orchestrator so
and the models proposed in this draft
the client model which is mainly the
Ethernet model is a network
configuration model which can be
directly used between the controllers
for Ethernet configuration so that's a
different applicability for different
set of models question aramean why a
network configuration modern not a
service delivery model sorry why a
network configuration model and not a
service delivery model what you're doing
is is a service well actually well there
are something certain something
uncertain
the second years the model in this draft
can be confident be considered as a
network configuration model this is a
physician and second considering the
service delivery model we said I don't
think we still have a consensus on
whether it belongs to this and whether
the air to SME is also the service
delivery model we need to have I agree
with you that this is not a customer
service model right but please consider
analyzing it whether it applies to the
service yeah I think it will definitely
make sense if we can really figure out
how this model work together with the
layer two service model of course and
the second question okay is actually a
follow up path with the previous
question of how this model is applied
because of we have three graphs
including four different young files
then how it would be applied in the real
network configuration so here we propose
actually two separate different
application scenarios the first one is
Ethernet only we consider Ethernet as a
transport network and we do not consider
any blind in this scenario that means we
only have a flat layer of network that
is composed by Ethernet nodes so
consider it it has a single layer
technology then it would only be
necessary to to set have the ethernet
'knows using the instant nano models and
this should be based on the is new
topologies that connected from the
controller paese is an anthropology
model so this is respectfully in draft
number three and draft number two and
the second scenario would be a kind of
application of Ethernet as a client of
the transport so in this kind of
scenario there isn't a need to work
closely with out here now then there may
be a single box that integrates both is
an a-10 the ODN
notes so what we need to configure is is
a net access link in the in the to set
also in the two sides of the figure and
we need to configure this service by
using the client model in the draft
number one and after this is done we
also need to report the Ethernet access
link to the controller so we also need
to involve the topology model so
basically this would be updated for both
isn't a nose and the Ethernet access
link so after the clarification I would
like to introduce the changes from the
previous version and firstly we make it
an MD a compliance for all the three
draft and first draft
we had adjusted a few Ethernet modeling
in parameters we added some groupings
for Ethernet the stories performance
monitoring special then the statistics
we also added the leaves for a time lock
when when did you create when you update
any certain service and we also add more
types including p2p service and there
are M V service along we also provide
some more tags to describe the model
sorry to interrupt
please just we have this discussion
conscious about the service mapping
thing right so service mapping actually
occurs in the same way so we have a
service for example Ethernet service or
IP service like layer 3 VPN service
right and then this is what client sees
that and then you have basically the
network operator the provider which met
the service in this layer into
infrastructure in this very layer like
for example in case of layer 3 VPN you
may play a free VPN
on to IP t tunnels right and and you
also map information that is seen by the
client like availability protect stuff
like that you may up into the set of
attributes for the tunnels that could be
gathered from information about the
source this is one thing and then there
is a totally different thing of for
example a client service being in one
layer and infrastructure in a different
layer like for example say Ethernet
service and ot internals right this this
actually would G 805 calls adaptation
its internally a relationship and this
could be caught by the topology model
right because we have all the semantics
basically saying that particular tunnel
termination point can adopt certain
client links so so this need to be very
clearly separated okay
so sometimes we hear this confusion that
oh I I have clients phones that I could
just can wrap on odeon and why not
simply directly on lambdas somewhere
there okay so I'd like to see that this
clear separation and we also discussing
some kind of a generalized way to to
take care of T policies basically when
when you want to map services on to the
tunnels all of the same layer why you
saying that the team up being teased it
belongs to the same layer because there
we are mapping layer three or layer two
services against that the tunnels so
could be at any layer well for one
reason is that for example there could
be switching in this very layer I
thought like for example Ethernet
services could be mapped on on the
tunnel that could be switched but not me
like you know villain IDs or it could be
a switch by say s tax right this is one
thing but but the other thing is that
the adaptation it's a totally different
animal right okay so this may be a kind
of challenges that to generalize the
problem rather than separating the
different scenarios but we we can work
on trying to solve this problem to reach
a balance between the two like okay okay
okay we are here yeah and actually well
originally this drafter is named as ulti
inclined the signal young so Ethernet is
definitely one of the kind of signal
types of faulty an but according to the
ODN control plane draft may be 1762
there are also other GP there's two
different klein the signal types a
including those kind of flew SDH or
something like that so we we also try to
add another client signal models and the
basic shape would be shown in this
figure
and after we compare this model we
generated with Ethernet model in this
draft that we we concluded that the kind
of signal model is currently different
with isn't models and it is really
difficult to extract a common base as a
fundamental or generic models to augment
from both so we we separated the two set
of models currently in one graft and
maybe in the later version we are going
to split it into different drafts and
okay this slide shows the changes for
our update on the client the topology
young again we make it an MVA compliance
we adjust some parameters related in
anthropology the first one would be we
removed the note MAC address as early as
this is not interacted between different
controllers and we also add some add
some parameters to support the
configuration of the symmetric or
asymmetric bandwidth profiles on
internal links we also as a support to
reporting the wheel and classification
operations supported by access links and
we also change the types of kind kind
facing parameters from empty to bullying
as it would be clear to understand how
to use it and we also update some text
so for tunnel model there is no much
update according to the model itself we
basically make it an empty compliance
and update the text and finally this is
the current opening issues and the first
one is we want to grow the scope of the
Teton or server from OTN to transport
because we this is according to to the
previous comments from chairs to make it
too generalized so currently we hope we
can at least make the tunnel server
generalized and so not only focus on T
end but we also find it is difficulty to
to make the client signal general arise
because the ethernet a is too much
different with other kind of client
signals and we also received some
comments offline from some operators
saying that they only or let me say at
least they mainly focus on Ethernet
models so we would like to extract the
Ethernet part of this works and move
separately with the other kind of client
signals so we would like to ask for
working groups adoption and we also
notice there are some coordination work
left between these this work and the
other working group or even standard
organizations including I Triple E math
advanced and mode
on models so that's a plan for the work
dieter Bella Nokia I have a question for
clarification louder I have a question
for clarification you are saying that
there are quite some differences with
respect to the Ethernet model for client
signals with respect to the other client
signal types is that correct yes this is
and therefore you are proposing to
exclude have that Ethernet client signal
stuff in a separate document correct
yeah can you explain a little bit what
these differences are and what makes it
so difficult to handle
Ethan client services in the same way at
the S the other client services well if
you look at the trees from the two set
of models actually Ethernet current
model so it's a very technology specific
and we we include a lot of parameters
that need to be configured on the isn't
it for example now the important and
those kind of stuffs but this would not
be applicable to any other kind of
service of OTN and for those kind of
common-sense for example what is the
client and node kind link that may be
applicable to be found in this genus or
TP generic models so because this work
is also automating the TP models so so
we we think those kind of the common
area is already covered by heat for
health models and this we just make is
net model and other kind of models
augmenting to that he directly
[Music]
hi it's Glenn Parsons so I guess I don't
understand I'll start with maybe a
clarification of this is OTN yang OTN
being itu-t g 709 yang I presume and I'd
like to understand why we're working or
you're proposing network management data
models here in C camp as opposed to an i
to t study group 15 question 14 which is
working on network management
information models and data models and
such so maybe you could help me
understand that first and then I can
make detailed comments happy to delete
but referral
okay I don't know it says OTN and the
title here and it's a no TN service and
you're and you're having an Ethernet as
a client right and so now if you if you
want me to talk about details why on
earth are you creating a new Ethernet
yang model there's already one in I
Triple E 802 there's several there's one
an emmy f itu is working on one we have
liaisons between I Triple E and ITU to
work on one there's activities in IETF
on Ethernet yang models that we're
working with I don't understand why we
need an OT n Ethernet yang model perhaps
I just don't understand yeah maybe you
could help me understand I think we need
to separate your questions one by one so
consider okay this worker is specify the
mode or how to configure the ethernet
service given there is a transport
network that's carrying the Ethernet
service and basic idea is to configure
the Ethernet access link after you to
make sure that the Ethernet service
Ethernet technically is correctly
configured
and look according to your comments on
other progress all other standard
organizations I my understanding was
math defines some kind of Lisa net
service types and that would be a kind
of service service here you can specify
what is I yes MF is defining service for
for Ethernet there's three levels it's a
very complex life cycle service
orchestration model with multiple types
of service different abstractions from
business relationship service
relationship network element
relationship that's the M EF and then I
Triple E is working on the detailed
pieces there's liaisons with ITU and
question 14 on some of the the details
and then there's the L to SM work here
which is in a different group so I'm
just trying to piece all this together
because yeah you mean every group I go
to there's yet another ethernet yang
model I tend to agree that it would be
helpful if we put everything together
and see whether there is anything
inconsistent yeah I mean from from my
perspective there should be like a base
Ethernet yang model and then you augment
it because everyone there's like so many
VLAN objects and MAC address objects and
so on anyway so I'm just trying to
understand but we can discuss offline if
you'd rather do that ami
actually I would also add into Glenn's
comments and this lab aware of that Olaf
is also have an Ethernet of fine
management model so I agree that there
are several stills are defining this
looks like the same thing so we need to
push them in together and say what's a
difference and to me I think I also look
into the ME of Ethernet service model I
think that Y is clear because it's kind
of a very high level use at the
customer service delivery model so which
is different from the current one that
Whitney may need to expand more how it's
related with rest right Ruby and I hide
huger models Thank You Tallapoosa from
away I would like to help as well I
think if you look at this picture what I
mean is clearly shown that we have the
layer 2 SM which is applicable between
the customer and a service Orchestrator
and what we are doing is now is working
on the interface on top of the
controller on that interface what we are
using is the T topology and T timeless
models that are defined by T's and what
we need in that area is technology
specific commentation for OTN and for
creating eatin a service over ot and on
that level of abstraction where we have
a T topology we have the iterated TPS we
have to clarify and the T topology gives
us the interlayer LOC to let us know for
example from which us Ethernet access
link which ot internal TP we can use
that to create if you want to create an
Internet service ring it from one eatin
SS s port what other is transport we
need to know between which the OT on TTP
we need to set up the tunnel and that's
the internet a lot information that we
get from the topology so we need to
explore to expose at that interface the
internet topology SS link leads inter
layer lock the TTP of the OTN and all
these attributes and this not work is
not going to be done anywhere and my
understanding is our T poly model is
more able to 1q Bridge management so
it's more apart the device configuration
model so they are applicable on
different part of the overall contour
architecture thank you what is missing
in other in other models is the mapping
to a tunnel or topology so let's try to
focus all just on what what is missing
tried to avoid the duplications even
worse can I also would like to answer
you know various ultimen I didn't get
his name but the thing is that if
something is called Ethernet yon model
a huge number of different things could
be named by that okay and huge different
of aspects could be also considered like
for example say Mafeking defined I want
to have say appeal which is time
constraint it should not go beyond say
10 millisecond latency right but how you
can actually achieve this that's totally
different problem right so for example
it is quite possible to separate
responsibility and have say we have
defined Network wide service model
basically how the client percept this
service and then there could be a
infrastructure model which is a very
which has a lot to do with traffic
engineering and provide for example the
necessary disjointness or delay or
bandwidth and then there should be a
third type of model which basically it's
a device specific model which which can
tell each device on the edges of the
service how you map the services onto
the infrastructure right that's a third
type and all of these things are called
Ethernet right and some of them are the
world in idea some of them are the world
in different organizations and even in
ITF some of them have to do with
lecturers and like connectivity restrain
and say we want IDs to like see toxmap
in and stuff like that
but some like in C Company earth this
has a lot to do with the traffic
engineering particularly and also what
we contribute to the community as how
this infrastructure could be mapped on
the services which are seen Network wide
[Music]
oh yes yes
okay this is a second presentation from
me but our totally different topic this
is not young this is talking about the
interworking of the GNP ours control and
the centralized controller system so
this has been the second presentation
last time we did this in Singapore and
briefly introduced the motivation of
this work so things are now becoming
different after the appearance of the
controller system originally the control
plane is fully distributed with GMP ours
protocols that define the ITF C temper
working group the protocol includes the
RSVP OSPF RMP for different
functionalities but nowadays we are
introducing the controller system in the
whole area for a kind of centralized
control because we believe there are
some advantage your further centralized
kind of like past computation routing
and start and and so on to get a better
performance and their understanding so
the corresponding output from the
centralized controllers may have the ICT
and framework and the controller
hierarchies we also have restaurants
that consented always together with
young models and also the PC protocols
especially for past computations so the
changes are from previous version we
have two new clusters and we have also
updating the scenarios which we think
this is most important for this kind of
informational work that this kind of
scenarios are requesting the inter work
between the centralized controller
system with the previous distributed
control plane so the scenarios included
poverty collection and synchronization
multi domain layer service provisioning
and the controller reliabilities I will
expand in the future slides and we also
update to the reference so here is a
personal scenario we want to
analysis is a kind of interworking more
detailed because this is the most
fundamental scenario in the network
control so given the group of devices
composing some network and it is now
controlled by a single controller and
there may be a PC embedded for past
commutation and there's some other of
the control functions need to be
achieved by the interface between the
controllers and the network elements but
given this kind of network architecture
we are trying to categorize all the
interface in the networks into three
different levels the first level number
one it's between the neighbors we call
this temporarily called as the neighbour
level interface and the main function
and requirement for this kind of
interface is to discover the neighbor
neighbor and and we and the support some
of the exchange of information between
neighbors to understand each other and
the second would be are still between
the network elements but it's a kind of
domain level or we call this network
element level so even for those kind of
two network elements is not directly
connecting with each other the
informations can be flooded and received
by each network elements in domain so
typical typical protocol would be OSPF
or isis as seen in the on this level and
the third type of the interface is the
interface that connects the controller
with the network elements so this is URI
request an interaction between the
controller and the network elements and
the typical protocols include the p7
that comes with young models so around
will
when we really deploy a network the
topology is initially is initialized and
reported to among the network elements
and between the network and the element
and controller so while our mp4
interface type 100 SPF or is is for
interface type 2 and P Cybernet comes
for interface type 3 and when there is
an update for example we add one node to
the existing network then we need to
synchronize the information to all the
other network elements together with the
PCE together with a controller or PC
level so the the changes for this
procedure on interface number one type
number one is we need a new node to
create RSP so so create a RMP and two to
every neighborhood and we also need to
flood this information to other related
network elements finally we also need to
report or connect a new PC accession
from the new node p SE e or we need to
notify the controller that this there is
a one additional node and the only
database need to be updated so based on
the topology collected from the
controller system it would be then to
compute a path and deliveries a service
and we have decomposed the service
provisioning to different feel different
steps include the first one would be the
past computation and then it would be
the kind of past establishment
based on the past computed in the
previous step and finalized there would
be a kind of database update especially
for the one on the on the PC or
controller in the you know stateful
flavor to make sure that the zzs
status of the network is synchronized in
the controller
so the considering the perspective of
note actually the past commutation and
signaling can be either centralized or
distributed or a combination of the two
so in this table we try to show how the
different protocols is applied for the
different tasks so for a past
computation the distributed control plan
will need to use OSPF protocol to to
compute the pass well if there is a
centralized compute we use PCE no matter
whether it is a distributive signaling
or it is a centralized signaling the PCE
is used to compute the pass but things
are going to be different once we need
to separate the pass and usually for
distributed oh we can we can we can use
RTP and in centralized pass computer
plus distributed the signaling we can
also use our vp pass this is the story
for pc initiated and finally if we want
to come centralize the signaling we can
also use PCP or that comes to configure
the corresponding devices and after the
RSP is set up there is look a kind of
resource update we earlier this it can
be done by OSPF or pc peres question
please a question for clarification
regarding the resource update I think
that can also be done using the Netcom
protocol using an elegant notifications
right right right yeah yeah absolutely
we should list it also here and that may
change the default and the search
scenario we add can you please end in
moment okay okay this is a controller
reliability and this is something new
topic and we focus on solving the
problem once the controller is shut down
how will the full system acted to solve
this problem we nowadays we have to
branches off approaches the first one is
controller Federation by backup
controller and the second one is also
you can rely on the distributed control
play because we have the same
functionality set but maybe the
performance is not as good as a
synchronized control so a summary to
summary this work we have actually
received a good support the last time
and also received some offline comments
to update into this version and we
expected we the working group to reach a
consensus on the centralized and
distributed protocols is now
complementary with each other rather
than mutually exclusive so we we are
also open to the other variation of the
details for these scenarios and the way
we like to ask for working group
doctrine for this work thanks next piece
no matter how much time we ask for we
are always late deserve to your next one
short question a dealer
Nokia's what are we going to do with
this draft now what is the conclusion
from the chairs the previous one
conclusion about I it was asking for
working group adoption deferred okay
this is a zero one version update of the
layer one connectivity service model you
may recall the first presentation at
last the ATF are in Singapore so just a
quick recap about what is the purpose of
this draft we starting from the RFC 48
47 we want to provide that provides a
framework about layer 1 VPN services and
in particular these RFC describes in
the old use cases and all the dynamic
provisions the dynamic provisioning that
was take for also the scope of our draft
so our draft provide the young that a
model for layer one BPM connectivity
service model and also it is based the
bottom the work on that is made in this
deficit 48:47 but also is made in
agreement with MAF work on layer one
connectivity services now we can
describe volt are the most common
deployment scenario that are in scope
for a layer one with the end services so
the first that is the basic use cases
for the layer one VPN for external
customer so we have that we want to
model the interface between the customer
service Orchestrator and network has the
end controller so this is not so common
because she should be difficult to have
an external customer that ask for a
simple layer one connectivity but okay
we can consider this is cope because our
FEC 48:47 consider this case so it's
better to consider also this deployment
scenario the second one is about the
multi service backbone for internal
customer that in our opinion could be
the most common use case because it
include the interface between the Sdn
controller for different services so
layer 2 layer 3 and so on and the
network Sdn controller for layer 1 media
so we are talking about a multi service
backbone that is shared for different
department that can control different
services this can be common in a larger
enterprise when an organizational design
can can ask for in a typical year Arkin
controller like this explained in this
slide ok this is
just as light to describe the difference
between layers to assembly or 3sm that
are the other service model that ATF is
working on with the layer once he
connectivity service model so first of
all we have to Assam and the layer TSM
are service models so our focus on
customer service interface layer one GSM
can be the southbound interface of the
service Sdn controller towards the
network as the uncontrol so and this is
the typical archetype that I mention
before for the multi service backbone
for internal customer for example ok
this is the model it is very simple so
we have address in his light where
address also one out comment we received
in Singapore in particular we put the
Uni data client protocol and the value
that this variable can assume was one
over and the comment that we receive at
last meeting so of course gigabit at an
intangible internet fibre channel and so
on
ok in summary some operators are out of
service work so the operator expressed
the needs and for the IETF layer one
CSM there are also some lies on with the
MAF so we are working together to move
forward or so this work of course this
is in scope in our opinion of Sikkim
working group because this is the home
of layer 0 and layer 1 technology and so
asking for working up adoption if you
consider that document is stable and I'm
one of the co actually I think even now
in the last single moment in we've got
you know consensus that this chart is
really useful and helpful for the
industry so III think we would get to
opinion from the
Froy again so how many people read this
draft reasonable numbers so how many
people think that this job needs good
foundation for this work okay less than
the people rated this draft so maybe we
can take to the list for more discussion
yeah okay thank you
[Music]
you you have the 30 minutes for five
drafts decide how you prefer to split
the time post 1225 about you have also
taught us a lot
yeah yeah okay this is a Gabriela
convert this picky okay the first draft
is again sorry I pasa
I approach as for my voice is again on
the extension of the signaling for SSI
and in particular we want to address the
the case to signal the carriers inside
the media channel basically what we have
today is pretty good the draft like 76
98 that defines all the parameter that
must be signal to the network to define
to let's say to identify and distribute
media channel information and but we
don't have the possibility or we don't
have yet the way to signal what is
inside the media channel inside the
media channel dermis there can be either
a single carrier or there can be
multiple carriers and multiple carriers
are of course following the same path so
the same media channel should be the
same type because is very likely or is
or they are carrying the same payload so
they have to avril they have to they
must be routed in the same way to comply
with skew and all the stuff
then the position of the media the
carrier's needs to be identified to
signal or to be provision to the client
part where the transceivers are on top
of that we let me go okay
on top of that we we saw that also
inside the de Rodman so the pure rod not
the transceiver there may be the need to
know where exactly the carries our
position inside the media channel this
is to make the optical channel
monitoring operations easier and faster
so using this slide I would like to go
more in detail on what's going on here
so on the you see that the picture of
the network sorry I cannot use the
pointer and you see the en node having
multiple carriers connected to the
Rhoden that might be one part one part
of transceiver en connected to one part
road orderly there must be or there can
be multiple parts of en connected to a
single roadmap or it doesn't care is
just a way a different way to model the
interconnection in any case once the
client asked for a LSB so a media
channel in this case because we are in
the SSO an environment may require okay
give me these
this they give me a connection between
the egress node to the the ingress node
to the egress not with this bandwidth
net bandwidth for example foreign Rica
and I give you the de step let's say the
availability of possible for ports then
this is signal via uni to the gmpls and
then is the gmpls deciding number one
the routing number to the media channel
window and the media channel width is
actually depending on the modulation
format on the FEC
and on others other optical parameters
so what can happen is that the control
plane may decide for example to
implement the 400 gig LSP using for
example all four ports because the
circuit the LSP length is so high so
that has to use a modulation format like
QPSK which is pretty performant but low
bandwidth and then so make a media
channel pretty wide because as to
contain four carriers instead of in case
of LSP very short like I don't know 500
kilometer for example where a different
kind of modulation format like 16 QAM
may be used and so only two carrier and
only two ports are needed in this case
the media channel will be only
a bit narrow let's say almost 50% now
that the one that was carrying four
carries so to signal all the stuff
between either the client and the
network and inside the roadman networker
we we added some TLV that is that are
used to signal all this information
between crying the network and inside
the network inside the MPLS and those
parameters are and say mentioned here so
the first one is for the request the
number of carrier that the client can
provide so the number of ports basically
that the trying can provide or kami
available to the network to make any
recipe the total bandwidth this is that
the total bandwidth is the net bandwidth
is not actually the post factor and we
saw total value is 100 200 400 wonder
450 500 whatever and then other two
parameters that let's say tell the
network ok what I'm asking you
number of carrier for example I say for
total bandwidth 400 this our parameter
that are mandatory or this our parameter
that can be let's say best effort so if
you cannot give me 400 gig on for
carrier so give me whatever you can and
this is the s and be flexible
when when the police start seeing I'll
start calculating the optical
feasibility and the part of course is to
take care of the modulation format the
FEC and the betrayed the bit about the
the frequency of the symbols the symbol
rate let's say on top of that gmpls must
identify per carrier the carrier
identifier that is basically can be a
thing simple number simple integer one
two three whatever J which is the
granularity of the frequency for for the
carrier and K which is the distance of
each carrier from the center frequency
of the media channel we saw that also
the power the sub carrier power could be
useful in other word what we have done
is keeping whatever has been already
defined in terms of media channel
definition which is M and M and then
here is actually shown in in the picture
we identify the parameters that is K k1
and k2 in this in this case where K is
let's say the distance again between the
media channel Center frequency and the
real frequency of the carrier
so now we define the granularity of the
media channel or the carrier frequency
at point 1 gigahertz probably 0.1 is not
the good one could be point zero five
otherwise we are not matching 6.25 and
whatever but again this is what is Islam
so far again we have the association
between each carrier and each Rodman and
in the client part that is all we have
done of course is has been done as
experimental that is now actually up and
running because we have application
doing that we wanted to propose this
method as as an example or as to share
everybody what has been done because we
think we are addressing a real problem
in sense that if you want to make a
multi carrier little channel signaling
today okay that must be that might be
different solution different proposal I
am personally not aware of this is one
so if you have positive comments are
welcome if you have four negative
comments are welcome as well because we
can we can let's say share
different kind of experience and maybe
we find out even a better solution
I mean saying that okay at this point as
this document that didn't change since
the last ITF probably is worth two to
become working through document and then
we be open to any contribution and I
guess the negative comments are coming
dieter Butler Nokia I don't know whether
they are negative yet to some extent
probably are you aware of the latest
developments at itu-t study group
fifteen regarding inverse multiplexing
and OTS IG because they are moving in
that direction as well second point is
they're actually addressing services
with a larger data rate so it's beyond
100 Gig and looking at this looking at
the subcarriers it looks like the
granularity this currently defined in a
flex grid is sufficiently low so this is
a twelve point five gigahertz and I
think this granularity is probably
suitable also for these kind of
applications now that that's a good
point the sense that yes we are aware I
think this can be in some way extended
also - OH - OH - you see em and then
also to all - CN / garner radical well
you see n is on the only electrical side
and that's that's addressing declined
layer signals on the in photonic side
it's the OTS IG signal adds currently
and being defined or has been defined in
IQ t that probably what we miss here is
the link between the DWDM part because
here and actually the the client is the
ability decide where outer house or we
have a DW m interfacing the router so we
don't pass we don't have a a
clear mapping between the Internet
traffic and the yen but sure I agree
with you if you have a transponder I
think we will miss something and open
again regarding a lot regarding it Clark
the granularity I think you this trap is
actually moving beyond what standardized
for the for the G 709 date plane right
thanks good suggestion okay next step is
of course actually should be the first
step this one because first you have to
agree on the interfaces and then you can
start signaling but in any case it is
what it is the extension of the lmp2
support all the information related to
the interfaces and how the interfaces
are connected to to the network and what
kind of characteristic those interfaces
have basically the characteristics did
not change since the last draft since
the last ITF let me see okay this one so
basically what the client can tell to
the network is the kind of modulation
format the FEC the baud rate number of
carriers that are available bit per
symbol so basically the spectral
efficiency subcarrier bandwidth so the
minimum distance that should be taken
between the two subcarrier garb and in
case of a carrier is let's say at the
side of the media channel so basically
the filtering carbon
and then Jackson our X power
Oh SNR robustness and max polarization
power difference so they did the
difference between the carrier power
that is again to be honest not
implemented this one but is something
that would be beneficial it's not
implemented because today we shared this
information between the client and the
network using data controller the
centralized controller and basically
that is the reason but if you have a
full G MPLS network not having the
controller at this point the LMP and
sharing this parameter is mandatory
again common positive or negative okay
now is actually an extension of the the
the LNT document we have together so
Gavin thank you so I I have one comment
so on besides the OMP so on do you think
if it's also possible to use the login
protocol for example or SPF te to
advertise the link capability the
capability the capability of the the the
transceiver I mean yeah so for example
there's a link there is just two ends of
a link and this this and can advertise
the capability of this end and another
and can also advertise you know the
ability of itself and then the one or
the network can get there you know the
link information because they can
correlate this kind of capability
between these two ends yes yes yeah you
got a good point says that if the gym
implements source routing so as to know
number one the characteristic of the
port at ingress but as to know whether
and has to check whether the ingress
egress node has the same capabilities or
at least capabilities compliant with the
ingress not because a deado otherwise
the LSP is not feasible that's it yes
the answer is yes probably disease one
of the most mature drugs
yeah I'm pretty confident that is mature
because you know as I said we have an
implementation up and running we didn't
see any big issues of course as I said
can be improved as Peter said and really
appreciate the comment but I think is a
good starting point and if it becomes a
working group document then is open to
any any comment and any contribution as
well
I mean actually it is let's see how many
people have read the draft some how many
people think it's a good starting point
for a working group document is this the
the lmp1 LMP less than the people that
have read it just took we need to
further discuss this and try to okay
find more support can you squeeze the
last presentation to five minutes please
yes perfect you need to
we have to presentation okay
okay this is actually related to the LMP
for DWM interfaces so exchange of
parameters between in client and network
and then the same information are or
different kind of information or
standard information let me say our
model as a young let's start from the
Olympic consideration I think this is a
really document that is consolidated in
the past we discuss quite a lot what put
inside what to put inside the TLD and
then agreement has been reached and so
non modification was done since the last
ITF this one again is something that I
believe is is useful and then can can go
through in my opinion the modification
as the modification on the LMP document
has been just editorial just cosmetics
as co-ed for the Ahmadis okay there as
there are no changes so the document is
is there I think is covering quite all
parameters that are needed to make the
client and the letter interface working
and that's it then we can go to the
also these drafts probably are at a
point in which we should decide whether
to progress DRAM them or probably stop
working on on this kind of activity
well now that the DDI BDM interface
framework is an RFC it was a need ready
to a beehive sorry not yet
it's time to consider working on the
distinctions and not just the framework
sort of uncompleted so first a question
to you what to do you believe is more
urgent between the young model and the
LMPD extensions but to me the LMP
extension is more urgent because I'm
aware of some Interop tests happening in
an operator between different vendors by
the way
okay so leather and so we have been
let's say push to implement this stuff
so in my opinion the LMP is more real
check let's start with them with it now
so LMP draft how many people have read
it same two people reading every
document so we miss some people and this
ITF that's why yeah the support is yeah
this is just to have an idea of we are
not taking any decision with these new
callings okay okay try to quickly
address that we have two more
presentations and they're done
okay it will be very very short on the
last one
not this is still okay this is actually
reflecting what is already described in
the Giovanni draft that is becoming
working group document so can be
parallel document describing what
Giovanni has in in his document simply
in a different model so a more young
model that's it I don't want to enter in
details so if you want to have a look to
the parameters that are described again
I think can be changed and came follow
let's say like a shadow the new working
group Tom can document that we become
okay that's it thanks thanks a lot by
the way the draft that was read by two
people as eight authors I told you that
we got some people not come like and one
of the people that read it is not one of
the other like my decisions have taken
on the list and not two-faced two-faced
did repeal or Nokia I mean we had some
email discussion on the C camp mailing
list regarding regarding impairment of
the Dacian recently when during this
pall of the encoding graft I mean my
comments to also apply to this draft of
course okay okay
I am Nicholas ombo so this draft refers
to a specific use case for a young model
for finished state machine presented in
in Emmett mod so the the use case is is
the following what we want to do is to
instruct the optical transponder about
recovery actions to do in case of the
physical layer degradation or more in
general to instruct optical transponder
about reconfiguration in case of
physical layer changes so here you can
you can see the reference to the more
generic young model in that mode for
flexible transponders we mean
transponder supporting the possibility
of configuring several values of the
bitrate modulation format and code rate
so this set of transmission parameters
format in fact are are configured based
on some physical layer conditions and
they can be reconfigured in case the
physical layer condition condition
change
so what not normally what's happened so
assume to have an active service
connection we have degradation at the
physical layer so something that can be
seen as a bit error rate increase over
some threshold an alarm is generated
toward the on demand or in general
toward the management
system does some new computation of
transmission parameter is performed and
the SDN controller reconfigure it's the
the transponder so that the recovery can
take place so this operation can be
time-consuming especially if several
connections are interested by the
failure what we want to do with with
this with this model unfinished state
machine is to while while the the the
service is still active is to instruct
the the the optical transponder about
the the reconfiguration actions to do if
some event happens so that if when this
event happens the transponders already
know what to do and they can promptly
react so this is the the young model you
can see the current state which is
defined by a specific configuration of
the transmission parameters so betrayed
modulation format encode rate we have a
list of states to which state is is
associated a transition so here for a
for a transition we consider a bit error
rate change with respect to the generic
young more generic young model here we
we have augment the model with the first
two squared attributes so the threshold
parameter in this case we can set the
threshold on the bit error rate or on
the OS n R and we have also threshold
the operators operator if the bit error
rate is higher than or lower than
the transition is triggered then we have
some actions so in this case the the
reconfiguration of the modulation format
or or the order code rate and after the
execution of this reconfiguration some
new actions can be executed for example
a new action can be then the
notification to the SDN controller that
the reconfiguration has taken a taking
place then we go to the to a new state
so simply we can see these two state to
state machine we are for example in in
the first state which is which refers to
PM 16qam if we have an event of bit
error rate over the threshold we we can
we perform a transition with an action
of changing the modulation format to get
the more robust transmission but we can
also come back to that to to the to the
state of 60km a physical layer
performance improve for some reason so
yeah that's it if you can call way
so let's distinguish software us from
our trailers right so if it's a soft
failure there is no rush in do any
anything all right so basically
something this goes out of like a normal
behavior and it is possible for example
to update is the end controller and he
will actually explicitly reconfigure the
device right yeah yeah so if it if it's
actually heart failure then sometimes
there is no time for communication
between the device and the controller
and you want
need to know in advance but in this case
it would be better to have like some
hard configuration such as for example
parameters so that associated with the
Recovery Options a while the tunnel is
established versus to provide a script
kind of flexible logic which more
flexible however it will be slow as well
right so basically where do you see the
the real value of being able to program
the actions in this flexible way you
know like in your particular case so are
you asking how much is flexible yeah no
no I mean I mean this is all good when
you want to have a flexible way to say
that you know recover in this way we
configured this way in case of that kind
of failure right yeah yeah yeah we can
an SDN controller can well the operator
in general can can think about to
several situations and can program in in
the devices these several configurations
but in the relatives or in reality it
would be some some kind of script on the
device right right yeah it's on the
device but well yeah it's true
this use case specifically target script
to in to be installed in in the device
because the problematic that we have
seen with the with the operator it was
that we wanted to create more
scalability at the controller and and
also a faster reaction so for this
reason yeah it's it's true we installed
the script into the the device the agent
but this is a the young model finally is
so so generic is a finished state
machine we can we can install it
also at the SDN controller now I'm not
talking about
the uncontrol what I'm talking about is
that you actually assume that say a
device like Rotom have script an
environment like Python for example yeah
okay and or some tickler whatever and
then you are basically three on Moodle
and you provide a script that could be
translated into the side script and
invoked in case a or fara so what I'm
saying is that it will contribute to the
latency of the restoration right that
because because if you have like a like
a hard program and project it would be
faster to do this anyway
but if if I may jump in and I would say
that failures is just a minor subset of
the things that you can do with the
Finnish Finnish finite state machines
there are remaining here let's not focus
just on on failures because you can do a
lot of things yeah well then consider
another situations like like for example
sort failures or whatever any sim
prediction or whatever so then where is
the rush right so for example why Cannot
I just notify the the SDN controller
about certain event and then he will
explicitly reconfigure it will be easier
for the for the controller to do this
well it's it's not well it can it can
this reconfiguration could could be also
fast not only could be done in a in a
rush and finally these this approach it
is faster consider considered that we
test it in a field trial in Telecom
Italia and it is faster than sending an
alarm and and computer computer a
reconfiguration another element before
you continue this is just the technology
specific extensions of a generalized
work that is done in that mode these
comments needs to go to net father no no
I'm sorry I'm saying I'm saying that
basically I just want to see the actual
use cases for this particular
augmentation and I'm not talking that's
a different conversation with that
with LuAnn and Kim that's a different
situation okay it's also but but this is
basically it's kind of a policy that
you're imposed on the device okay in
it's a flexible policy defined by the
client and implemented by the server it
it assumes that there is a for example
if there is like environment scription
environment on the other Odom's and not
all of them have such thing right and
and basically in case of say protection
or restoration it is better to have a
heart-to-heart logic configured like
saying this is my restoration parameters
and this is what I want to do by
configuring and having the server to
implement this logic rather to provide
script and and making the same thing but
slower okay not I would think that turns
out I would kindly suggest let's discuss
on the list okay yeah thank you okay
thank you
yeah
and thanks a lot to blue brown and
orange for taking the notes
you