okay it's 1:30 so we should be starting
for those near to the dog these doors
yeah this is the cold working group I'm
a custom one this is I'm a few minutes
and yeah there was a mailing list and
there is a jabber room and this is a
Monday so just refresh their minds we
assume that everybody has met the drafts
and we are here to advance difficult
issues and all this is that you can
reach information so let's sum up the
agenda today today we will focus on
documents that already have passed and
today we will focus on drafts that
already have passed by noob last call
and I've various years of going through
the iesg and two sets of drafts that we
really want to work in glass call after
this meeting so this is things Jason
Oscar's animal resource directory and
said and tomorrow we will have cocoa
because there will be a transport area
of person coming in that's why this is
tomorrow we will there you and I have
managed to put this into other slides
yet and then we will go through
documents that are a little bit less
advanced and you can see there's a lot
of documents and so this will be little
bit of a gong show tomorrow we have any
changes additions to the agenda we need
to do okay so let me quickly talk about
the working group status we have one RFC
published since the last ITF which is
the coil over tcp TNS that was a pretty
long last fire we had with this draft
but we finally got it published on
February 15 and and one one of the
things that we actually had to do is
write another RFC that that was just
pitching a minor hole in the circuits
environment there's actually arm without
help so I could buy around a beer for
everyone each time this working group
gets an RFC done that's alright that's
alright if that motivates you okay so
this I'm not going through the
milestones right now because it's three
documents to iteration so we will talk
about the documents when we talk about
the recognition but I have a couple of
advertisements at the beginning first of
all there will be I think you think we
research group meeting on coexistence
this afternoon those of you who were
the hot FC talks have Laura talked about
the problem she's trying to address so
right now we are building cars under the
assumption there are no other cars on
the highway and that works for a while
but at some point we will have to put in
Direction indicators and all the other
things that allows cars to work in
traffic and so coexistence is mostly
seen as a fine layer thing but that's
probably not true we have to think about
coexistence how does our pet network
work in an apartment building together
with 200 other networks that's a problem
that we currently don't quite know how
to solve so its research but I think it
might be interesting to do this as well
second thing there is a draft that is
going to be workgroup last called
very very soon in the six dish working
group and that draft contains a co-op
option and that's I think the way it
should be quote is designed for
extensibility so other groups should be
able to define options it's an option
that we have talked about here the
stateless proxy option and I would
advise everyone who who cares about
things like this to look at the draft
and maybe send a message to call and or
six dish about any comments that you
have and maybe go to the meeting on
Wednesday and Viscount who so just to
give away what what I'm going to write I
think we had a discussion on whether
that option could be repeatable or not
right now it's defined as not repeatable
and we probably should think about
whether that's the right thing to do on
the the third thing is we are going to
talk about we saw through three today
and we are making resource directory to
DNS SD so we're going to briefly talk
about that
but actually there will be more
discussion about that in the DNS st mark
meeting on thursday morning so please go
there if you care about resource
directory and or DNS system okay and
that one message from our sponsors this
is really not directly related to to
call but it's interesting to everybody
who cares about constraint system so the
next right savage will be in September
and sediment you you might care about
that okay that finishes the first and
the next thing is links Jason so this
this drop we have been discussing this
draft for a wire actually it was started
in February 2012 so by the time when 66
ninety what is now 66 najuk became
stable we thought well it might be a
good idea to have a JC to avoid having
the need for another pass I in mid-2015
we added seaboard variant
so the whole point is about documents
that contained links and it is used for
self description of car notes it's in
flesh we're now instead called and for a
long time we have been working on this
document with the assumption that the
focus should be on round trip abilities
with RFC 66 ninety and that's actually
the that being the focus of the draft
that passed burden of last fall last
year and was submitted to the iesg
on April 2nd and then gates and we got
lots of feedback and there's also
related work for instance in BMC F spec
that we probably shouldn't ignore so
they are not using is they
same forward but it's kind of culturally
compatible and we should try to
understand what they were trying to do
so with all that feedback and all that
related work the it didn't seem
reasonable to continue with the
direction that work had taken so far
focus on round trip ability and so that
the proposal is to refocus this a little
bit and try not to inherit the
limitations that we put in RFC 66 19 for
it for it to be easy to implement so the
the idea is to have a full web linking
environment in the JSON or support
variants but of course still cover all
of RFC six is ignited because we at
least want to make sure that the forward
direction works even if the backward
direction may not always be possible
also communications there so that is the
the we focus if you look at the document
there's actually not much change I have
submitted event that does most of the
changes already so it's still pretty
much the same document there are some
details that are now refocused on this
and there is one background activity
that happened while we were last calling
the JSON document an update of RFC 59 88
which is the base level obviously 66 90
happened so the web linking people
realized their specification so RFC 66
90 is now based on what is an obsolete
version of the web link specification
record that's probably not a big problem
because they were careful of not trying
to break too many things but again what
happens is they have to refocus on it
little bit so for instance the the way a
B and F was used in 59 88 which creates
some of the little problems we are
having here that was fixed in 82 88
there is now a clearer approach to the
Unicode and language tags issue and most
importantly the document actually
acknowledges that there will be other
civilizations of web linking not just
the one in the HTTP link header which
this was originally about much for
instance obviously 66 90 links Jason and
other things that may be coming we
haven't seen a need to actually update
66 92 that Newbern we think a pretty
much works well as a cheese so right now
the yes yes to rebase links Jason on
8080 to make eh but at the same time
stay mostly compatible 266 90 which is
based on five names like it so there is
a few places where this comes up and I
just put in a one here to the slides
language tags our c59 8h defines some
some special target attributes that have
a star an asterisk in their name and
what's special about them is not
actually the attribute itself but the
way they are represented in an HTTP link
header because it should be linked at us
may need to be a ski if you will have a
link attribute that actually uses the
Unicode you have to do something and
what they decided to do was provide an
encoding of the unit water content and
also provide a language tag which is
typically useful to actually correctly
interpret the Unicode so you know
whether some some Chinese characters are
in reality Japanese practice
so 66 90 has some support in its a B and
F for a title star attribute but that
uses exactly the weird HTTP link kind of
syntax and originally we just copied
that over into links Jason and it just
doesn't make sense
you shut up cause decoder is this stuff
and put it in an extra Unicode and the
new thing is it became clear in the
discussion that we probably also need to
preserve the language I saw what but the
real a new piece of technical content
here is that a title star attribute in a
link head are in 66 90 what we
translated into a nominal title actually
root of the value of this attribute
would be a string qualified by a
language text so if you want to have a
title then the equal spring and put in
your language take it helps to okay so
this is the new stuff and we all have to
look at it and we this is the right way
to do it well that's that's a detailer
but on a high level is this right form
right way forward we they see the
document on other places where each wait
it has cleaned up things explain how
become links placed in touch so make
sure the nothing is fully defined in
that direction but otherwise 690 using
crystals that's one and another
direction that we as very know should be
deciding at some point is there and
intention of getting rid of in college
who actually want to replace when you're
caught by a Jason for more Zeebo form
that's a second thing which does not
have a bearing on what we do in the
customer but there's something that the
document is very clear this not
happening at this point so I think but
but we have to think about for instance
the simple representation is pretty
compact is that something much we have
know so is actually armed first three
bullet points I think this is completely
logical as a way forward so I don't have
any pushback there I not intimately
familiar with the ice-t comments around
those if this fulfills those
requirements so it sounds like Carson's
point of view it does the last one you
know I would comment that we have we
have media type variations with
different civilizations for a reason
I don't see any reason why these can't
coexist but this needs to be made clear
right like if I request a see bore
version of thought well known slash core
I should get that um rather than an
implementation just blowing up because
what you should get RC six to six ninety
why are you asking Rivers for Seaguar
alright so I think we need to be able to
be future proof also with how we deal
was slash download on slash course so
this fourth bullet point should we
mandate that it is just sixty six ninety
know we should mandate that you can
optionally support others but you
probably have to continue to support
this as the default yes so the question
was that's a lot of much about
forbidding it's in win of course will be
like that
but what is the mandatory to implement
ha I don't think we have I don't think
we there's a difference between
mandatory to implement recommended right
I mean you need something that everyone
has to support um right now you know the
wave flash sizes and and meta devices
are increasing at that rate C bar is not
an issue right we have more issues with
overhead on the wire energy etc so I
don't see C bore as a limitation in
these devices but we do have enough
stuff out there that's using 66 90 you
know it's in the wild it would be hard
for us to just say now the mandatory C
bore and does the device just what fail
if it doesn't understand C bar I don't
think that's reasonable yeah Michael
Koster smart things in Rd I think the
approach we took and I Christian can
correct me if it's that's been changed
was that we required RFC 66 90
compatibility and allowed additional
media types and if that's what's being
proposed here I think that makes sense
for well-known core also he did the
trick of causes if you don't care about
the old link forward is that you just
provide a very short link form a
document that points to a link SIBO
document that has the actual information
so then you are compliant to the little
okay so you can kind of gradually
migrate away without waiting okay I
think it that we want to continue this
play and so there is a dish out there
right now there are few final tweaks
that I probably want to make
[Music]
yeah this document is like nine months
after I see review so I probably should
return it to the working group it also
depends how many other changes you think
you want to do and for how long so there
should be a version of this by the end
of the month and that has all the
changes in the angles the working group
should look right I might be able to
short-circuit avoid another IT at last
call but this document will need another
IG review at minimum because several
area directors who balloted on it are
just going to step down from
IHG so you will lose some bows here it
might not have enough positions to
bosses which kind of linked to decisions
yes so let's take off line but the idea
is finish this quickly if there are the
next item is a score
[Music]
hello everyone I'm Yolanda from erikson
I'm going to present the next update on
our score so we are now in version 11 my
co-authors I'd like to go through the
issues from from the IC review um here
is the status number of implementations
we actually appeared one new
implementation at the end of the list
there which so it's really being used
several in crops up in time but topic of
today's presentation is about the ISD
your view we had also have some post
last call reviews and if you want to
follow the details we are handling the
review comments on the wiki and we're
having this new version 11 we think that
all but a few specific comments are
addressed so there are a few slides on
on on review comments I'm not going
through all but those that I think are
representative port for the type of
comments we've got and here is a comment
saying the document needs to security
analysis section and implications and
modifications of unconnected fields are
are not sufficiently covered so they
written was already a security
consideration but the IC wanted to have
more specifically an analysis of the
security that is being used in the
protocol and what guarantees are
provided so what we propose to do is add
and what we already have done is to add
an appendix describing security
properties of the protocol there are two
three sub sections one is looking at the
problem statement the assumptions from
even videos so that was not really clear
to everyone making the review so we
think that needs to be highlighted that
means the media are supposed to perform
certain actions using the available
headers but other other message fields
are not available to the intermediaries
so there are protective headers that are
unpredictable and then we will also
include two sub
as one which is going through the
security properties of the protected
headers and one which is going through
the unprotected fields and the
consequences of being operated and there
were questions around the nonce
construction why is Sandra include nonce
and the rationale a is that this the
security design is you it's intended to
support both the ordinary request
response notifications as well as an
interchange of client and server roles
and that required a special construction
so what we think is needed for for
understanding this better is that we
have a proof for how quino's uniqueness
is obtained and we put that as fourth
subsection in the new context but this
design actively works against any
involvement of intermediaries that also
attack or comment which basically shows
that we have not done a good job
explaining the problem statement what
the intermediates are supposed to do so
so we that's the first of the three sub
three subsections of the appendices
we're dealing with the intermediaries
and their role and we elaborate on that
so we can quicken on it but I think it
would be useful to start a document that
just explains different situations in
which Oscars being used so people
understand why that is actually not not
true I mean it should not go into this
document or to finish it but having a
short document that even might go away I
don't know that just says these are
different configurations in which we run
or score and these are the rationales
for why we want to support these
configurations I think that would be
used for Lynch good it could even be
done on top of 77 44 which has already
has use cases so you don't really have
to define these use cases in most cases
I mean part of this is actually in the
requirements stuff
co-op intent requirements there are also
examples showing showing how it's used
if along with the trust model for
prophecies so I don't extend something
that needs the abbot so should should we
maybe complete this requirements
documents please not with the name
requirements but as an informational
document that goes with Oscar or that
succeeds us because we want to finish
Oscar first but it would be useful to
turn this into an RFC I think what
happened with that happiness and so the
the is G is always pushing back a little
bit of information about humans but I
think in this case because of this kind
of question it might actually be useful
to do so we just need to find people who
want to work on this who would want to
work on this I mean there are authors of
the document but they are okay others
about come to where it's maybe anybody
else would be interested in finishing
there well you you will be reviewing
it's like yeah okay let's take that
offline and see if there's a way to yeah
okay then the what a set of high-level
comments related to I mean this case is
a statement about this that we this
draft is not it's neglecting to address
important the difficult part of the
problem like key exchange and we
disagree with this comment we are
addressing I mean the basic the host
comment was saying this is a partial
solution because there is no key
exchange protocol but there are other
ways to establish keys besides key
exchange and so you could either do it
with
with the the probe the Oh score profile
of the ACE framework or you saw my
deployments require PSK so because of
their constrained nature so it is a
complete solution but on the other hand
the key exchange protocol it is also
something that's needed for Osborne that
was discussed in the ACE working group
this morning so so that's so we we agree
with that you need for a key exchange
but it's not a necessary condition for
all school and then there were a bunch
of comments of HTTP and they were very
good because we hadn't focused so much
so first comment this protocol abuses
HTTP by tunneling over it and that it's
actually correct and that was exactly
what was intended we had a missing a be
an effort and that's fixed now yo and it
was a question about how how does the
coop HTTP gateway understand the
significance of the new header field so
that's the obvious security header field
and insert the medium pipe when
translating and that's exactly what we
wanted to intend so we don't want to
necessarily add at the content format
for knows a bit corny obviate security
protective message so but custom from
the floor I'm not sure we are actually
abusing HTTP yes we are tunneling
through it but we are using it as a
request response protocol it's not like
we are just using HTTP do to send
messages back and forth so I think there
are there are different levels of it
abused and I think we are not in the
murder range here we are just in the
manslaughter thanks for the
clarification
so another Winston question was do we
need a code point for coop for this new
media Titan and we had this question
before and we said as we said that time
previously we said no we actually don't
need it for this draft and then we
realized that maybe someone will
actually have a use for for this code
form so we decided to include that
anyway but not
not use it in the draftin and explain
when you're not going to use it so
that's a placeholder currently what if
the request is redirected by the server
that doesn't understand those core ok so
here are two these two questions are
actually still things which we would
like to have good feedback from the
working group
shall we support HTTP redirects and the
setting is two there are two settings
one setting this is one of the settings
HTTP redirects you have a coop through
an HTTP proxy coop HTTP proxy and you
get counter server and the server makes
the redirect back to the proxy that
would be the ACD no it's not okay let's
not recognize why is that a thing that
should be addressed in a score this is
the thing that effects it coop HTTP
proxies in general and I think in
general they don't but this is this is
this is generic good question I think
the reason why I mean this is one of the
questions we got from from the ISC
review so we assumed that this was
reasonable to address in the doc but the
answer could be that it's not something
that we are actually in this there is
also by the way when you define a new
HTTP header you need to answer a number
of questions how will will read is be
impacted by redirect so I think it from
that point of view we should have a good
answer to the question so and this
question was brought up again by Dave
Taylor you want to say something on the
first point I don't think that this is a
media type of coop it may be maybe a
title of a score but my assumption is
all of the is that coop out of that
strip so this is just it's just a
question of the content format of value
right there's no there's no co-operators
on us No
just I mean it's just the value for the
for so we have a media-type before for
for over for the object security for the
payload containing the compressed cozy
object we have a media-type for that and
the question is do we also need a
content format a value and we don't need
it for this draft but maybe someone
wants to use this compressed cozy object
and pass along a media type for it okay
I don't have a better I better answer
than that people have been requesting
this and we thought it better include it
now then you find a good use case later
and then how to do it yeah so maybe to
answer this question the there is no
need to include the content for adoption
because the object security option
already implies the value of the content
for adoption however if this media type
is used in some composite media type
that has content from it numbers on the
specific elements that go into the
composite media type then it is useful
to have a number for that that's all
that's the whole reason next ask him
sort of a while while thinking about
that so yeah so the question actually
was then brought got brought up again by
Dave Taylor so he said has the working
group made a conscious decision here
whether we going to support HTTP
redirects or not he was not he didn't
really care about the answer but he just
wanted the the working group to have
take the decision that either no we are
not supporting a stirry redirects or yes
we will support them and we will make
sure that the necessary whatever
specification is in place if there there
is anything
Aleksey I will try to provide nori not
very formed and not necessarily correct
opinion on this I was talking to Patrick
McManus one over HTTP base coach Ayers
about another document that decided to
prohibit redirects and he said basically
you shouldn't be doing this when you are
using HTTP the error direct is a
standard feature you should just support
it basically I'm not entirely sure
whether there are any exceptions to this
but that's the the gist of of the
comment I got from him besides I don't
think that actually I need to think a
bit more about this but I think you can
have HTTP proxies on the path that don't
have to understand or score as long as
they in implement HTTP correctly they
will work with what you know it's just
another payload for for for them so they
can redirect another source and it can
go to another server that is HTTP 2 core
proxy and and then everything should be
fine
so my gut feeling I don't think there is
anything inherently wrong with using
redirects Franchesca so the problem we
are thinking of is that if it doesn't
reach the right server the server won't
like the security material won't be
there if it's if it reaches a different
server it's not a proxy problem it's a
fluid who is this intended to and do
they have the right security material I
mean if it goes the wrong place that I
don't really see a huge problem because
they will basically just return in it
HTTP error and you're fine I mean it
maybe goes to somebody who understands
the format but doesn't have the right
key you're going to interpret much the
same situation
plus one okay so we will make sure that
this support HTTP redirects in some way
and you don't need to specify something
we'll find out what you what it appeared
the last point on this slide is the name
of the HTTP header field so originally
we call it object security and we got
some comments that we should probably be
more specific that it's not it's
actually dealing with constrain the
restful setting so the proposal was to
change to coop object security which is
the current text in the drafts and now
we got another proposal from Dave Taylor
he thinks we should call it core of it
security because it's if he actually
didn't want to narrow this down to coop
you think this is the in his view of the
end-to-end rest setting so so there are
there's a counterproposal get to change
the name to core object security any
news
well the whole reason you changed a name
to Oscar was because it wasn't a coop
specific anymore so putting co-op and
there doesn't make any sense at all
it was Dave who proposed to change from
Autosports consequential change
so what I'll just call it as cool so
that's a Google Google return which is
probably more useful than anything yeah
we had the discussion number of times I
think that most arguments against that
is gone I could you recall the arguments
that's quite alone so would that be
changing both the the option and the
header field or what would be you have
we have a co-op option and we have an
HTTP hazard
but the option name never occurs on the
wire so you don't get in a situation
where you need to google it but the the
HTTP header mean that occurs on the wire
and if you find a strange baguette where
that in it you might want to move it so
I think that the Google ability of the
header field name is a is an important
thing how we actually call the the
option we have very wide okay so any
other views naming it thinks we can
discuss forever as you know so really
important stuff so but so I put out the
mail on the mailing list and as this is
this is the proposal and I also I
respond to day's mail then we move on to
that was the last actually so this is
not a complete cover II of all other
your comments you could look at the wiki
and the commits that we have yeah I'm
gonna get off essentially but in summary
we have tried to clarify the points
which were brought up and fix all the
editorials and there is a new appendix
or reviewing which is going has these
four subsections as we discussed yeah
but essentially with version 11 are
always should essentially or issues are
addressed so are all issues addressed
there were some minor to do I would say
that let's say yes so will there be a
dish 12 I mean so okay so let me what is
the to do
or is doing the broth in the version 11
this was late night work I can't
reproduce so I would say that we should
be able to fix whatever is is in the to
do during today or tomorrow that type of
complete Francesca so if you take a look
at the wiki in the github we're really
tracking all the issues and what we have
done and we consider we just have to
answer and what we need to just review
in general I think we all the all the
elements are in the draft we might want
to rephrase some things but the content
is there in our opinion and yes so we
just need to answer the emails we got
the emails pointing through the new text
and asking if they are happy with
resolution okay so the assumption would
be there will be a distro in a couple of
days from now yeah okay there is a to do
so we need to have yeah but but we could
we could speak it at respond to the
emails sooner because yes basically okay
wait thank you sorry
[Music]
okay talking about quick state of
something on cinnamon I don't know you
did
now yeah works now no sounds like this
11.5 million meters from you okay it's
gonna be interesting
no no okay closer yes it's gonna be able
slightly awkward but anyway so update
for media tax force in ml okay stages um
first of all we're done from burning
crow point of view so sentimental is
currently I get last cold yeah that job
is scheduled one month from now so there
was a since last person Alex I did a
thorough review on it and some bunch of
editorial or clarifications etc that we
fixed there one that you could consider
a technical change was the media type
registration for exi was changed from
plus EXI to minus CX I although
yesterday we did discover this may be
worth clarifying one small point there
on the expert guidance or new values to
make it clear when new values are
registered in the name long name of the
value human readable party to take value
to make it clear this has the value
semantics are for the new field then for
early assignments so this um currently
the verse that is submitted has a bunch
of DVDs on the IDS course that's gonna
be assigned by iana but since there's
already a lot of use for cinema will be
useful to have those IDs assigned as
soon as possible so what we've been
discussing now with reviewers expert
reviewers for that registry is that okay
it is a good set of ID's have a one
consequent set of ID's for all that all
the numbers except for XML so the reason
for those XML IDs being in the two pide
range is that XLS anyway quite verbose
you're not saving much or have using the
one byte IDs so so length read with the
experts on this ante
we all seem to be having consensus on
this so we'll be going forward with
these assignments unless someone sees
any concerns
so procedurally this is in early
allocation so the the authors of this
document will ask the chairs and npad to
to earlier location and then and if you
approve it tomorrow we don't have to do
that right yeah I'm trying to remember
ah I might not have added it to the next
to each other it's probably going to be
a nice chair review in April okay so I
mean do you really need early allocation
on 5th April 5th you know two weeks
earlier than that you think we're gonna
have the assignments or well basically
you know fingers crossed if it's
approved on a tell a head and then it
goes into publication and Ayana does
allocation very shortly as soon as it's
submitted or easy editor I cannot
promise things outside of my control you
already got yes from me so that's fine
um okay so I guess we can see if there's
no discuss is flowing before the
telecheck then we probably don't need to
do it then it's only a couple of weeks
thinking if there's something we need to
do
Rod's updates having these ideas usable
for other SDOs would be highly useful
okay yeah okay let's see oh let's see
what happens during the Taylor chat week
and then remind me if if it's not done
you know the we'll discuss right then
now yeah the way to do it is I add
management item to the teller chart and
say you know can we prove this okay
thanks then there's another question on
early assignments how about extensions
to send a mail so since it's not an RFC
yet we don't have the registry actually
but there's already a request at a new
field from again
steal from a DM on the object links so
what is the general procedure here
can we already allocate but it's not
part of this spectacle
specification is external so what's that
is there a procedure for this kind of
assignments yeah I don't think there is
a procedure for early creation of a
registry in a document that wasn't yet
approved I mean the salmon can be done
very quickly as soon as the document is
approved you know even if it's not
published yet I think that will be okay
to actually basically say well
Ayana will create it right away in fact
they usually typically create you know
draft versions of the registries or at
least they suggest tell you what the
registry is going to contain during last
call so they will have information
available before they tell each are
typically yeah okay good so so much
about cinema oh so next up fits and
touch media types of course in ml so the
background for this one is that um
you've been seeing what a lot of lot of
synonyms earlier but this one part of
our use of cinema called the collection
use and that is what is used today if I
became protocol and also I'm so smart
objects so here's an example of an in to
smart object
it's a remote actuator it has actually a
cure for light it has that resource
filling if lights on and off what is the
demon cult deeming value how long it has
been on and human readable description
of it so use case here is that what
about if you want to retrieve or change
only two of these resources you could be
as of today doing two gets on a specific
resources and get the values and that
could be okay
how about but however
if you want to do this in order to save
battling only with a single request or
maybe you want to be changing the value
of a few of those but not touching
attitude
luckily we do have methods for that in
in koa we had the cooperation patch or
exactly for addressing a parts resource
updating or fetching them however the
KOA patch and fetch methods they do need
a payload format that is dependent on
the resource creepers intention format
and current there is no one force nml so
that's exactly what is proposed by this
craft the feds form loops last as an
example on the bottom of the slide it is
modeled after several JSON format axis
this is playing sin ml without the
values and the idea they recent you can
have simple parsing of these type a Log
form of course you already have support
of sentiment on the device it's using
this format a really simple format just
indicate the names and potentially times
if you're using x in their other values
of the records you want to fetch and you
will be getting the results for those so
this would be solving the problem of
getting two resources out of the center
go back at Susanna mode records in its
interval words under the packs format
exactly the same however you also give
the values you want to be changing there
so those of you are familiar with the
chase emerge as format assessing a
subset of that format applied or for
each record so that's the simple part of
the best cuts format but then there's
the optimization base now currently
called wildcards and essentially it's
about when you want to be selecting
multiple records using a single pitch or
Pat's record again it's if you have a
let's say a few hundred people records
and you don't want to be naming
explicitly hundred different records on
your pets or Pat's request you could be
using some kind of a way to select
multiple multiple records a use case
could be for example ghetto temperature
sensor values or be more like 10% so
currently the draft is proposing one
format
a new center field code specs filter it
can contain use you can use it like a
name instead ml your concatenate with
the base name and it can contain
wildcard characters that you are then
matching many characters up to a a
separator and you can see there in the
bottles like example that would be
matching all resources starting it by a
more common use would be for example
with wildcard for example in place of 0
on the best field and it will give you
all instances of an object so then the
considerations are recording this track
on the wild cards is the upper half on
screen okay
something simple it's needed for
addressing this use case and there was
quite a lot back up or what what is the
right way of doing that the current is
such that say early proposal are up for
discussion
we believe the basic format that were
you explicit name the resources it's
been a straightforward but this world or
is something bit more complex and maybe
need a spark more thinking and although
what we were discussing right before the
courses in here is that there is need
for the pitch packs format relatively
early be pretty much end of this year
however this wild card format is maybe
something we want to consider a bit
longer than triangle endpoint of this
year so it could be split out of this
document because it is quite a bit of
complexity and getting it right
maybe requires some some time but the
basic format seems to be pretty
straightforward and something what we
could be defining by the end of the year
[Music]
SEC shall be armed um telepathic
connection so soon as I stood up you
realize what I was gonna say right yeah
so I thought yeah we always have to be a
little suspicious about need um and it
sounds to me like this wild card things
nice to have now if you look at how some
of these resource
structures were designed like in OMA
objects right
in just referencing into like halfway
down the tree will get you the entire
object in there so having like a 5/8
star kind of okay you get part of the
object but why they're pretty granular
already 5/8 wasn't really a good example
accent I think much more usable would be
all instances of an object but you get
that if you just reference the root of
that object all the instances of an
object but the thing about specific
resource give good recommendation on
proper object design so that might be
something you you could do it say like
we do not have wildcards in this version
of this specification thus here's some
recommendations on how you can structure
your resources in such a way that this
is useful already not right that might
be a temporary
make sense and all in all this being
able to select multiple things maybe
it's what we need but a habit more
thinking think about the use is probably
and probably applies beyond 10 ml so
cinema is not where we hit it the first
time maybe something even think they are
cheese called want to think about in a
bigger picture and then do later on for
example and extends with this but having
the basic basic semantics or fetch and
patch defined seems pretty
straightforward so if we then forget
about the world card considerations for
a while and yet there's also question
about regular expresses maybe it maybe
later preferably not and under the patch
operations so currently the semantics is
that you can basically create new and
you can change existing ones but you
cannot for example and a similar so
there could be some need for operation
codes later but again maybe it's
something want to do as an extension and
really see if there's piece of news case
for it and also currently the draft
poses new responded permit IDs but as
Klaus pointed out there's no need for it
we can actually use the same existing
Golan format IDs and justifying the
semantics with the patch and pets that
are are slightly different from the
regular say never use
but then the key question since this now
zero zero crap Eastern interesting the
croup to work on it because there's
little interest external positive so OMA
DM has already requirements for
something like this and to me I got a
bunch of others here it seems very
sensible thing to do here a general
thing that is used by oma DM instead of
comity of specifying it work my personal
works for them but then that comes with
the kind of timeline stable by the end
of the year preferably RFC but if we
take the wildcard parts way it sounds
feasible it's a common the operations
are also taking out yes and all the
Mattias Kovich Siemens so for these wild
cards there could be a use case on
industrial systems you very often have
this right multiple read multiple and so
on so I would have interest to to work
on what is there that we need I'm not
specifically interested in the cinema
version but in this generic thing how we
could solve this multiple read right
sounds good let's get into it
hi Paulo from Nokia
my question is liquid all these new
additions do we have any impression on
the size growth of the code
for a constrained device I mean is that
something still yeah for supporting all
these new features and wildcards we
don't have a good idea yet
supporting the simple here's the name if
you already support getting senemo as
input the code change should be pretty
minimal but you already have all the
machinery who understand that and it
sends matter of speaking everything with
map it doesn't explicit match so I think
that should be pretty straightforward on
the wild card of filters and selectors
it really depends on the design and what
one question for it's on the wild card
was afraid how about more than one wild
card well that actually increased the
complexity quite a bit but you get the
vanity so again maybe that's something
we want to push later but it's not that
I don't think it's an urgent thing even
if ramadi yes this is des Browne
speaking about wild cards one of the
things that I was going to say is that
wild cards in the middle of the URI are
the or the evil part and you said oh
that's exactly what I want so but to
echo what Zach was saying so very often
with proper structuring of the data you
can avoid that if you think ahead to
what your use cases are you can avoid it
and possibly if your structure is
something that you're set with it's
built in stone but you really want to
query their different way there's
nothing wrong with having data appear in
different parts different trees
different views and so restructure the
data over there in a different view
which allows you to be properly
hierarchical that it at the very least
put your wild cards only at the end
because wild cards in the middle and we
know that's the search writing the code
for that is very difficult especially if
you have something that then you open up
multiple wild cards in yuku you know so
it different levels it gets very
complicated wild cards on the end are ok
and if you structure your data so that
that works that's ok yeah
and I think the wildcards in the center
can be okay if you must only upload up
to a delimiter so if you have clearly
delimited structure however there is
complexity different there I write that
right no so in case of for example like
with in managing Docs in to smart object
you would know okay this object ID can
be anything so there are some structure
where it works but I do what we in
general it is thinking right and that's
it I think coming back to you or rather
like do another view that's exact what
Cristian was suggesting earlier yes we
could be able to do that often gets you
away from having to do complex filtering
or complex queries where you just I have
I had the query for you already because
I know you want this and here's the view
that does what you want so yeah
something we could be exploring in the
wider scope of how we want to handle
this
Alexander path yes I'm going to echo
this this comment and just at a point
here that in karma we are using fetch
for this couple of operation so whenever
you want to do like like basically what
we get as an input is that tree
selection like a subtree if you want to
go and do some operations of trees
pretty pretty much everybody who is
asking for so maybe you know just if you
happen to want a couple of sub trees
then in a fetch operation you can get
them all of the things that you are
wanting I do see the use case where you
might want to say okay I don't know
exactly all the identifiers that are
here and you know I don't want to really
restructure if some SDO has fixed some
some particular you know structure of
your eyes then you know I don't want to
redo this but then I mean there I feel
that there must be some use case that
comes in a circle for this use case when
he just needed we need wildcard
operation and then to be narrowed down
to this use case and that could be
useful so would be interesting
interested in reviewing future versions
of this document 1 2 3 4 5
six so we do have some some interest in
this room and I think I'm only going to
ask for formal adoption when when
cinnamon is actually approved to reduce
the number of documents in the backlog
but I think we have some interest here
let's go ahead with us okay and we'll go
also ahead with that split of having
just the basics in here and then we do
that wider filtering hearing part on a
separate document sounds good excellent
thank you okay you have to speak about
1.5 millimeters from the like okay hello
my name is Christine I'm Susie I'm just
I will be presenting not only the main
resource document which is nearing
completion but also two documents that
are justly related to it um the SSD
document which Carolyn is primarily
working on and the personal draft that
moves some things that we've been
discussing in resource directory out of
the main out of the main document so as
I said the the resource directory as it
is is from the office point of view
pretty much ready
so nothing more will come of it if we
stay brooding over it so will we need
your input so this can go into a working
group last fall we've done quite a bit
of work in the last few years it is
mainly documented in the Isha tract and
pull request by the time we released the
- 13 draft we were down to one remaining
issue which I'll talk about
in just moment in the last days another
came up um that is mainly editorial do
we want to have this forward reference
deal in it or not and I'm hoping for
this number to go up a little bit and
while we are receiving reviews but I
expect that there will be mainly
editorial things that we need to clear
out um through that time um the issue
that I'm looking forward to solving is
that we'd like to show the
interoperability of the resource
directory as we have specified it now in
that sense that different people arrive
at compatible implementations from the
same document so far I have three people
that would like to work on this please
if you have an implementation of a
resource directory drop me a mail and
then if I know who else is participating
then we can set a date and we can set a
context and in which we will have this
in detail this will probably be a remote
interrupt because it's because we can so
what what changed recently this is
basically the the Delta since since I TF
100 there's been lots of smaller
cleanups so you if you want to do this
then this is exactly how it is done
because the mother document is not
completely queue about it if you want to
indicate your server version you can you
can do that without changing anything of
the mechanism we've we now allocating a
multicast address so the initial step of
this finding a resource directory can be
targeted towards a resource directory
without exactly knowing what it is the
there big change since - 12 is related
to what Caston talked about before the
fine points between RFC 66 90 resource
link format and link headers and for the
sake of not creating confusion and
having things just work we resorted to
in recent when when looking for
resources to just
turning absolute references because this
avoids a whole bunch of of ambiguities
as long as we're in at least as long as
we're dealing with a link format
representation so when the resource
directory mandates that link format is
supported by the server but all other
kinds of serialization of web links can
be used as well and if they don't suffer
from the same ambiguities then in those
cases relative references we don't
forbid relative references but um we're
there where we know there's problems we
just just hand out absolute references
and the last part of changes was related
to resource directories that are not
necessarily hosted on the same server so
for example if you have two resource
directories and want to do lookups
across them
we added some text in the resource
directory document document that says
that I do not expect this your I to be a
relative reference this can be just just
treated as a opaque your I the resource
directory will know what it is doing and
what exactly the resource directory
could do is outlined in in a new draft
that is called a resource directory
replication which just explores several
possibilities of what you could do if
you if if you have your research if you
have multiple components in your
resource directory because you want to
scale to large numbers of requests or
what's or not this doesn't propose a
specific way of doing it but shows that
it is possible with within what is
provided already by the resource
directory and this is also compatible
with them with an earlier draft of
Kaymer that deals with more distributed
resource directory so those two are kind
of a focal another
another document that is closely related
to the resource directory is the is the
export from resource directory to DNS SD
this document is still in active work it
has been updated to reflect also changes
in resource directory it now has an
intro a proper introduction so this this
is this is not nearing completion yet
but it is in a state where we can be
relatively sure that we only reference
to the resource directory and don't need
to forward reference from the resource
directory to our DNS st everything that
DNS st is supposed to do can happen as
an extension to the resource directory
as we have it now and this is this is
the way to go for what we think with
this and this is happening but not ready
for a working group last call
as of today speaking of working group
last call what is missing for the
resource directory reviews because the
last once we've received from Jim and
another review we're on - 11 so in order
to go from working group last call I'll
ask for for some people to have another
look at it
so any any volunteers I see at least
three um maybe some of the other NGOs
OCA or may could also volunteer since
they use resource directory and their
members in the room of those obviously
but I wasn't talking about you yeah I
was mentioning possibly yes okay so for
the the minutes Marty right yes any
value had the hands up first and then
Michael and yeah I think that's good for
this round we we will have a blast
having a few reviews before that would
be great and as I said if you have an
implementation and
this again also goes especially to to
stos please contact me so that I can
arrange for whatever we need to to to
run this against each other and see
whether we all arrive at the same
practical implementation from no
specification so the plan is to have a
blood test run mid-april depending on
the availability of people of course so
we have a month to get our
implementations up to speed and then the
practice itself will not have physical
the physical meeting but will be done
over the internet questions commands
yeah
so we have to draft here that there are
working of documents and one draft there
is completely new and the question is
who cares about this ah de replication
scenario Christian brought up so do we
do we have the energy do we have the
interest in this group to look at this
is this something we should push to the
research group well I am interested
because I also work on that some years
ago but I wouldn't mind revisiting it is
it something where we think there will
be a standard track document or is it
something that just is good to explore
some more in the latter case I would
push it into the research group because
let's maybe do these things
research research group sounds good to
me because I this this idea I don't plan
on this to be the way how those things
work but I like this to document that it
that it could work and to explore what
we are running into when we are when we
are when we're doing this so probably I
should just ask t2 TRG if if there's
interest in picking this up there yeah
so maybe you have to find the chair
Stewart Cheshire from Apple I think if
we move to a world with many many things
in the home automated work and to not
want a single point of failure so this
may not be urgent but I think it is
important at some point we'll want
things like this um so since you're
there do you have an opinion on how to
distribute it is it dhts or are we
thinking something else it's too soon I
don't have any strong opinions for or
against any solution I do feel like we
will want some kind of solution we're
not there yet
most homes have a single Wi-Fi access
point and if it fails it fails so
clearly we don't have a fault-tolerant
system but I think we will want
something like that in the near future
Thank You Otto Kira and without any hats
I think it's a very interesting topic I
would like to explore it with the
thinking Archie co-chair hat on sounds
very much kind of the explorative thing
that we should be supposed to be doing
in the Archie so we very much in favor
of taking this here ok ok so I think
we're done with this point here
Michael since we are ahead of schedule
we might be pulling the group
communication to today so just prepare
for that but the next item on the agenda
is come on and I have to dig out the
slides for a little so start talking and
I will try to find the slides and yes
and you can have a laser pointer but ok
I I love the background here I'm not
sure if it's going to represent
connected devices 20 years from now all
them talking co-op anyways yeah so ok
hello everyone my name is alexander
panov and i'm going to present the
advancements of the things that we've
done with kamae in the in the in the
past months
so there have been several quite
exciting things out there and and now
the basic message that is the takeaway
from you is that we really need your
input now and he'll be asking for all of
reviews so the looking at all the people
that are here each of you can get a
documentary review so that could be good
but I really am going to be to be asking
for you for this so what we done the
last time and what we had so we that
there are new releases new versions of
all the documents so there are three
main documents for three main documents
for Africa my so we have the yang to see
bore the carmine document in the state
document so these are all working group
items and the yang to see bore is from
the point of view the altars it is ready
so we would like to make a working group
last call on this one and yes so please
do review this one and I can talk on
this also okay now I can know what I'm
going to talk about okay so this is what
I was saying about so we have these
three documents that are working with
items and they have new versions so we
did some minor changes there to the yang
to see Boer and it is ready for a
working group last call so basically the
things that we did there is you have
this thing that is called young template
and we just needed to make sure it is in
rest conf and we just needed to make
sure that it works out of the box which
with the
encoding with a young to savour encoding
and as of today it works so basically I
don't see anything that we could add to
this document
so please do review it then we have the
comments so the C bar is the encoding
thus it provides you how you encode
identifiers and the comma is the
protocol itself so here for the set
document that provides identifiers the
only thing that reminds that that that
remains is for us we need to to see if
all the things that we added actually
that we made sure for the yang to see
bor are actually also true for the sit a
document and go again through a jana
about this and i would like for us to
make a working group last call after
this and on the comma i draft
well here we need to go over a couple of
things to make sure that it works out of
the box
the first thing is the young template
then there is this new thing or at least
for me it was relatively new the yang
attached we need to make sure that it
works with nmda and for yang push so we
talked to during the weekend with wood
Hank
so we found out that there is basically
it should work out of the box so it's
pretty much okay so this is here
actually it's pretty strong what we are
seeing right so we at core we develop
this protocol come by and we say okay we
take the yang world and bring it here
into the IOT world and so the people in
the yang world they continued building
new stuff that is quite powerful and we
are just making sure that how it
actually works without changing the
thing that we did we did here so I think
that's a pretty powerful thing that we
are seeing here and and yes so these are
the three drafts here and there is this
new draft that it's not an inn of the
receipt it's in version two so it's
stable since IGF 98 and it is the coming
introspection model so basically how do
you learn for models that are already
there
and so here this is a question do we
want to do this in in core so I'm going
to ask all these questions once again
and the end of presentation I just
wanted to give you a couple of pointers
how you can start using come by today so
there are a couple of implementations
from that's from from the last from the
last time they were they were existing
in go in see and there are some people
that tell told us that they had their
own implementations we had a virtual
interrupt at the last hackathon so we
tested it with fetch and so we just the
fetch operator without that system and
it actually proved to be quite
challenging to have such a big a module
for for interrupt from the start so that
was a lesson learned and on this
hackathon what we what we did we scale
down a little bit on what we wanted to
do we wanted to start an open-source
implementation of kamae so we were
postponed in this for the next time but
what we did do is we joined the semantic
interoperability we she hackathon where
it you had the things coming from coming
from the t2 TRG coming from the w3c
though so you have this thing
description and what we showed was that
you can do the mapping from yang to the
thing description and you you have the
bindings from comma to expressed in this
thing description a lesson learned from
there we need at least to have to save
the get method but mostly we need to say
to keep the methods that we have get
post put delete so that we are able to
keep this compatibility with the thing
description so if you remember the last
tight if you are saying okay we would
like to simplify the document and remove
everything except fetch and patch right
now this thing actually seems to point
out that it is it's going to only I mean
the whole day the ecosystem as a whole
would take a little bit of time to be
able to express everything in only fetch
and patch so it would seem a little bit
too fast to go and say well we don't
need get input
it's already there on the document it
there is just an implication that we
will not be able to simplify the
document by just removing things I'm
Matthias Kovac speaking for WC vapor
things so in the TD we try to to allow
for adaptation so if you have an
implementation that uses let's say weird
methods that we can allow for that
however they have there was quite some
pushback there that like the sensible
default should be in place that there is
something that people can converge to
and something having a get for something
that this link to is is kind of one of
those if you want to simplify and say
hey this is a very constrained
environment we really have to cut it
down to the minimum you would have to
deal with something that you cannot have
properties that are something that their
state is directly exposed but you have
to use actions all the time basically an
action to read something an action to
write something but that's what you're
doing if you only have fetch yes so so
that's actually a very good first lesson
that that we that we have out of this
and it was you know at some point we
were super excited that's okay when all
we can do really super simplify the
thing have only fetch in patch but it
from all this interoperability point of
view and from the from semantic
interoperability it wouldn't be
reasonable so this actually says that ok
we did our work right it's everything's
there we cannot really simplify it more
than it is so so yes and then the last
time we didn't interrupt that was some
kind of a private interrupt you know we
like you over the internet and people
are just setting up things so it showed
up that there are actually quite a lot
of difficulties doing this one of the
difficulties that you know we were using
ipv6 and UDP so you tend to have some
filtering from time to time with these
things and we had these issues so from
the last IDF we saw some great people
here that work at eff inter up and so
their logo is cropped here but they will
forgive us about this so I've interrupt
for those of you who have not heard this
is a platform so it's an open platform
the
you can go and you can do your
interoperability tests on that platform
so you have like an environment that is
set up for you it is open like it's a
European project like so it's you know
it's really used for this and you have
the way to coordinate the things to just
nip the traffic that is so--but when you
do your inter up you have a sniffer that
is going to write down the all the
packets that are exchanged and and you
can have even in some cases a verdict
that will tell you okay that the
interrupt passed or failed so what we
did is we actually published our
implementation on on this on this side
so it is called like a reference
implementation which is reference for
the eff interrupt so this means that you
can go there and you can set up your own
interrupt session and you can run it and
it will run and you can have come I
server setup and akamai client so
depending if if you wish to test if you
have a comment you can go there and test
with Akamai server if you have it from
my server you can use the come by client
that's over there
and for the moment the methods that are
implemented our get fetch put patch I
patch and delete so we have not yet
implemented the post
so just to working to show you a couple
of photos that it really works so you go
to this Internet address you sign up and
then you'll get good to go and then when
you when you sign up the only thing that
you need to you know you say okay I want
to new tests you need to click here on
interoperability and then you see the
because you here you have a list of
tests and you need just to click OK I
want to do come my test shoot and then
you know you click Next Next and and so
forth and you have like you have all
think out because there is a VPN you can
connect over VPN and then you have five
to v6 and you know that no filtering and
so forth so it's really user friendly
and like it's not us that we're running
it so you have a whole organization
dealing with this so really great you
can start using Carmi today the test
file that were published so we wanted to
do something simplified and we mean I
Jeff system is you know if you want to
make sense of things it's it could take
a little bit of time
so there is a very simple tile that it
basically has three so it's a simple
model with three leaves so we have a
container interface and three leaves IP
address name and throughput like it's
almost invented and then we have the
seed file that is generated out of this
so you have so this is the the
identifier that number you have comma
int or blah blah blah and this is the
SID
so for the moment we are using seeds
that are from the experimental range and
basically if you want to run today your
first command request you go to F
Interop you create your inter up stuff
and then you do a coop get to slash c /r
f y and this does get a get on this set
file so you're going to get the IP
address of that thing so it's as simple
as that so that was the first point
there is implement so there is the
implementation you can start running it
today
the second point is about the registry
so now the the registry is so this is
the first draft of the registry if you
wish it is not yet approved by a Jana
but we have started already allocating
ID so that we can learn how to use them
so you can come here so the name the URI
Cisco my dot space come I dot space so
you go there
fortunately here it is cut but you have
a couple of URLs your eyes so he can go
and you can say well what are the more
models available and so you can see all
of them so there are some of the
system's ones are over here so you can
see the models and you can click on the
yank file and the seed file you know
this is only about the sits right
Yankees just for consulting that thing
and you have tools you can generate the
seed file from here you can you can
generate the egg file so you can do all
the other young file but you can
generate the city file and all that
stuff so it's all there just go there
and with this I'm going to say ok well
we want we need reviews of young to see
Boer and I think the best well this is
just starter working group last call
we have core and the the sit and the
comma drafts and here we really need
neat reviews so we will check these
things and you know by the end of March
that's sir by the end of March us for
sure maybe I'm not sure by the end of
the week we'll bind of by the end of
March and and yeah then we need we
really do need reviews I mean we as
authors have done have done so I'm
reflecting what Christian said we have
done to what everything that we could do
here and we can spend lots of thoughts
of time just you know trying to say okay
improve readability but if we don't have
any input it's difficult for us to say
well you know it's so who is willing to
review the yang to see Boer Hank yeah hi
this is
listening half-year I can make a
exploration endeavor Internet conf
and maybe select a specific individual
there that helps me in concert to a
review on that but that is the only way
I would commit to that if I do not find
a partner there then I will not but this
I will try to okay okay
thank you that works pretty well for me
yeah the whole situation is pretty
complicated because we are doing
something here that that goes into a
different ecosystem and so the the
reason we haven't last called Yangtze
bow yet which which is essentially done
and has been saving for a while is that
there is a certain risk the more we
learn about using it in practice the
fewer mistakes there will be in there
but one one view would be we can do this
now we have played with it for long
enough even though we don't have
specific event where we could say oh we
just went through an interrupt and and
it was great but it has been around for
a while people have played with it and
when we do the working last call on this
this certainly will be in concert with
net mod which is doing the yang work the
the other draft are slightly more risky
because yang is right now going through
their second system syndrome and has
actually it's not yang it's the natural
environment that wasn't precise yang is
not a problem that's why we can just
call the first one they have this nimda
thing I forget what dimdim means but it
essentially means let's redesign
everything and so all the the documents
that into H with the Netcom freeing
space need
huge weeks to make sure that they
actually work in the nominal space as
well and right now I personally am I'm
not feeling very sure about the fact
that we have done this but I also don't
have any indications that we don't have
done this so that's something where we
again need input from the network
management people and the same thing is
true for the yang library I think it's
not yet entirely here that we have to do
this at all but it's it may be a good
idea to have our own way of getting this
catalog information so it would be
really useful to have input from people
who want to use comai whether we should
be pursuing this or not yeah so I think
as a worker we are in a somewhat
difficult situation here but on the
other hand this stuff has been stable
for a while apart from the nimda issue
and we should be finishing it
so yeah you asked for reviewers for the
yangtze bar who would be reviewing the
CID and comma documents from this
working group nobody nobody in this room
do we have a conflict with some net not
thing or net conferring so everybody who
who would do this is not in the room
that that sometimes happens that's a
question is there a way to have last
working replace going to working group
and consulting and another working so
yeah so that there is no formal last
call and everyone rules but by just
informing
then so how about we we say okay there
is the last call and wake up and we say
to net Mott also and this should make
people react because then we can stop
the last okay let's try this out with
young people the reason why young people
really would benefit from from an early
last call is that there are people who
want to use yang as a data modeling
language way outside of net Conniff just
used yang as a data modeling language
and and used the CBO representation so
the this draft it contains everything
that is needed for that so we can can go
ahead with those applications
okay so commute seems we should be
starting the the last call on now should
a little bit for for named our
verification of the komali things
there's probably not that much that that
will happen with CID based on him but
I'm not an indirect spurt and then go
for last call next month okay thanks and
do the interim it's really cool
interface yep one comment not related
with this one but with the DNS there we
saw rectory DNS SD caroling is pointing
out in the jabber that the DNS is the
working group in on Thursday will that
drop will be presented on that group on
Thursday for those interested yeah I
said at the beginning Jerry was a
reminded because it's not in the
miniature yes thank you okay so I think
we are done with this item here and that
means we have about half an hour change
or 25 minutes gained and we can start
doing atoms from tomorrow and I think we
should start with the grew from stuff
because that also was discussing is too
a quickly find the slides for that and
it's usually just allowed to start
talking while I'm digging out this ledge
okay they're really allowed to start
okay
hello mark hello karai six this document
got adopted right after Singapore
it was resubmitted with minor polishing
well this version zero one is an actual
major update after that yes
most of the updates are actually out of
two major reviews we got from ESCO and
Peter after Singapore thank you very
much for that
indeed so based on that on those reviews
we essentially euro structure the
document organization quite a lot and
clarified as many things are possible
and here just summarize the the main
ones we took care of already started
from the terminology we notice that
there could be potential for confusion a
third work group so we we provided the
exact definition we intend to have for
that we refer to a security group as a
set of n points sharing the same
security context and essentially key
material and policies and so on so this
doesn't have to be confused with other
possible meanings like network group
when it comes to possible IP addresses
identifying a multicast group for
instance or even application group
meaning a set of nodes running the same
application in the context of a security
or network group so here we mean only
security group and you you can map that
quite flexibly in other kinds of groups
as well in the security context
especially other comments from Peter I
guess we try to clarify as best as
possible how the different types of
contexts so commands and the recipients
are established and arrived later
derivations especially occurring around
time and obvious requests as well we
added a new table highlighting the exact
deltas from the contexts we already have
in the menos core document and and do
the content we're adding here in this
one in section 3 about the the cozy
object that was an explicit request from
s call so we had the examples on request
and response messages before and after
compression and we switched to
countersignature
0 because we believe it's quite
effective anyway rather than
countersignature
and we updated the externally ad in
order to mention explicit with the
signature algorithm used in the group
for counter signature and we removed
after the the group ID for external a
because it was really necessary to have
section 6 is a new one to have
definitely because considerations on
what the group manager is supposed to do
in the difference days of the protocol
were actually scattered all over the
document so we essentially collected all
of them now they are list all together
in a single section where the last two
or three are actually optional features
that the group manager can help so now
they are all collected in a single spot
we had some work also in the appendices
actually that they were a little bit
restructure rephrase the move appendix a
used to be a section with assumptions
and security objectives and it was quite
distracting where it was and it made
also cooler the alignment with the menos
core document so we thought just to move
that as an appendix we got some feedback
in those reviews about the use cases so
we just improved their description
appendix B well in Appendix C where we
already gave an example of how a group
identifier that partially changed
dynamically can be encoded now it comes
also with an actual examples considering
again the constructor we already had as
prefix and above then in appendix D this
is also
related to what we presented this
morning in India's meeting we consider
also the alignment with new draft a ski
group calm because the panic still
provides an high level description of
the joint process that pointing at the
ACE approaches the recommended way and
now we have announced that pointing at
the new draft those are the main points
addressed in the revision now there are
a few points open to discussion for
which further reviews and feedback are
or an welcome there's a point about the
Independence of the security group from
IP addresses altogether so far we have
mostly thought in terms of a request
message especially sent over multicast
coops over a multicast IP address but
there are some cases were requests
especially selectively retransmitted can
or should be same even unicast both
online the group identifier should be
just enough to retrieve the correct
security context one needs to process a
request right now is the the draft says
the context is retrieved considering the
pair group ID and IP address of the
group so perhaps is just better to force
this the coupling altogether and use the
group ID alone and the sate another
thing we have kind of solved that with a
few may exchange with with a school
today - we are currently stating that
it's important that the G ID is partial
at least in a part of it random and
large enough especially to to avoid
global collisions with group identifiers
of other groups under other group
managers we can potentially and neglect
at least be less strict when considering
randomness and large size of that part
of the group ID please beat that I
pitiful most okay very obvious question
how do you see there how do you want to
get a relation between multicast
address and gid then handle you think
about the resource directory or do you
want to do autonomous maintenance main
vehicle management okay do you wanna
mismanagement of the multicast address
with respect to the group ID can be
through a source directory or group
managers then in case you need to
coordinate with one another or both
online one can try possible different
security contests that can be both
retrieved and try them until the right
one is found out as a tiebreaker okay do
you want to remove it completely from
this document and even or any reference
to the multicast at the as I said this
is a different problem or that I'm not
quite sure here it is essentially a
separate problem the point is being able
to send the request of a multicast API
that is still possible anyway okay I
don't believe that this is necessarily
restricted to multicast it could be
unicast reso thanks a lot
oh yes this is about the terminology so
right now we have force and stress quite
a lot the multicast were so that's why
the terminology multicast there meaning
an endpoint sending requests over
multicast IP and that's it but back to
the comment before perhaps we could just
consider to simply the the same
terminology we have in our score and
that's it and and that would in turn
simplify also de the enrollment of new
nodes in the group cause it just reduces
the amount of roles they can have and by
the way they are just the same again so
you'd have positive side effects too
it should be totally doable and finally
more on the joint process actually as I
mentioned also before the appendix
covering the
process is still a high-level example
but is structure at very high level
guideline more discussion on about how
to provisioning and handling public keys
and I'm pointing at the Essbase approach
we we have an SS the recommended way
should we keep this line of reasoning
and keeping the the way open for a
possible alternative approaches that
then the one in a soar we should just go
for the ice one as the one the ACE one
is aligned with the general guideline in
the first part of course but just in
case other approaches can come up later
on so far we are allowing that in
principle because I would like it if the
interface that you are assuming here is
very documented that's good if you want
to put another joint process in there
but it's also good for verifying the
east joint process so it's clearly do
you find what security of the property
is you you expect from that joint
process so I think it is a good thing to
to keep a clear boundary okay yes sum up
they own the implementation we already
have last year in Prague a proof of
concept in contiki of course along with
it now old version of the drug not with
the very last one but I recently came to
know about an implementation from other
innovation developing see for the anklet
a smart board and that's also centrally
aligned with the very same version of
the document considered by the kontiki
implementation so we were wondering that
this is possible possibly good for
taking first steps to an early interrupt
perhaps already marell can promise that
but you can try
yeah we've already talked about that but
it's essentially a related activity nice
describing how the joint process is
performed key provisioning including
using the ice framework and whatever
profile of AAC you need to use to secure
communication between the joining
endpoint as the client and the group
manager as the resource server but you
find more details in the ACE draft about
that that's all I have thank you so who
is read the most recent version of this
document how long has it been out okay
so generally who is interested in
reviewing this document so we have had a
few people who reviewed it okay so there
are about five hands up now okay thank
you so we still if I left and we could
just continue with the agenda which
would make re the next guy who is yes
but it's less juggling if we just use
them the next item on the agenda so we
have a few surprises in store today okay
um so too many requests response code
for code how to check what is actually
on the agenda so the background on this
is this common cold case that a client
can be bombarding a server so hard that
the X becomes overloaded and the
question is like how can server tell hey
you are doing this too fast please back
off I nee to DP
there is already find an error code four
to nine called tool a requests so it
seems quite sensible to also register it
is for coop with a four point two nine
and the acog specific edition here would
be I would use the max-age option to
indicate for the client when is it okay
to try again so that's rough
the gist of it and this is originally
part of the co-op's a broker so it was
decided in the last IDF meaning that it
changed this kind of an error code seems
have used much more wider scope than
just a broker it makes sense to do it as
a separate RFC and there's also a recent
ocf interest for the same kind of
functionality there's all one question
that came up during the drafting of the
details of this specification is that
should there be a way for the server to
say well don't do that but here's a set
of things that I might be considering
okay for you to do so what the current
text says the client shouldn't sent the
same request before the max of max age
option has passed so however something
may be useful here but maybe again this
is something wire and just for this
response code could be actually
applicable for other response code so
maybe this is something we want to
consider but keep actually outside of
scope of this draft some generic method
for some hypermedia controls in the veil
or perhaps or some header extends until
I hey here yes okay okay actions but
that's the key part of it our previous
slide so constant again from the floor
this sounds like a really good place to
remind people that they can actually
send response bodies with error
responses and you could explicitly point
out that that the array response that
comes back might give additional
guidance and then people can just
register media tribes that they provide
that their guidance and we have a nice
decoupling from respond fault code
itself exactly however maybe that's not
something you want to specify in this
draft that has a generic mechanism so I
would recommend keeping that I'll scope
for this however would be very useful to
progress this draft relatively fast
because of its gonna be now a normative
dependency for the
Bob's a broker and as it's also interest
in outside of the IEP f-for using this
so keeping it simple and being able to
progress seems like a sensible way
forward however there has been a
discussion that well there's also
another and some other response codes
that we may want to be defining and
shoot this draft then be bundled with
some of the other other response code if
they are something that we can progress
fast and in a non-controversial matter
probably it makes sense
if it would be delaying publication of
this draft I would be bit worried of
that but the key question yeah okay
working group item since it's a normally
dependency and was agreed on the last
IETF that it's already it was already
part of a group document but we just
played it apart having work group
working on this seems to be a reasonable
way forward yeah so it seems to me that
we should just do the reproduction call
on the mailing list now and then
essentially when that time is over do
the working class code sounds like a
plan to me Peter farmer stock I also had
an controversial response code which has
been presented already twice I think and
I very much would like it to go forward
it the same smooth way as is proposed
for this response code and I would say
that bundling the two response code to
have the same smooth treatment would be
very welcome indeed you know I have a
slide for you you have a slide for me
yes no but let's do this this thing
first so anything else we need to
discuss about that so you you have a
little bit of feedback you can do a dash
to zero ITF - the view of the document
after the Wagner adoption and then we do
with the working class code and if Peter
is fast enough to get his stuff in there
before the way you bla scroll
immunes oh the cheese okay thank you we
have fun okay we still have six minutes
left enough for Peters
I don't do you want since you've already
started we have to pick it up again
tomorrow but this comment goes between
these two presentations that there is a
second response code that we defined in
observe that is similar to this which
one is it
it's basically analogous to the HTTP no
content response 204 and HTTP we want to
define a similar response code for co-op
okay and please to oblige what is the
motivation for this draft that the robot
of secure transport uses the HTTP
response 202 and which means it's not
immediately available but say come back
in ten minutes three hours and then you
can get the response and this response
code can be returned both for and get or
on post so just doing an observer on a
ket it's not sufficient because you want
also on the post to have this response
caused um though we have no such
response code for co-op and nevertheless
we need we need this the HTTP 202 and it
commands the HTTP 202 has been done for
memory here I'm not going to read it
aloud I mean it tells you look here it
can be a request it can be delayed and
eventually in the response that can be
said where you can monitor it your
request
well we have three use cases for this
kind of response codes first of all
there is this is D co-op s then there is
the cutoff score perp SERP which has a
bit different treatment it doesn't say
you have to wait for the raise
for the result but actually it says
there is no result yep
so you go away and don't bother me and
then there's of course the too many
requirements which we have from we have
just about which is also a new response
code so the proposal is one RFC which we
discusses these three response codes and
we go forward smoothly and hope that it
will be here a proof by the working
group I want to stop here so I could use
the the last three minutes to present my
slide on this so basically co-op is is a
lot like HTTP except where is and we
have tried to keep the the color state
machine simple so for instance we have
decided not to do redirects even though
redirects are but by mini HTTP people
consider to be a basic part of HTTP that
everybody should always do koib
doesn't use them and there are two
reasons for this one is redirects are
really badly defined in HTTP so that
that's would be hard to do this right
but also we just want to keep the state
machine Center and the difference
between error response codes and success
response codes is that error response
codes all create the same imprint in the
state machine there was an error so the
request as done no caching and so on
while a success response code actually
requires every single client to have
code to handle this success case now one
one way to handle it of course is to say
I don't understand this so I give up but
okay I think that's that's really
counterproductive so adding a success
response code is an expensive operation
because kind of
it's the whole ecosystem and now that
the question is if there are
application-specific state machines that
that happened to have something in HTTP
that kind of seems to have handled that
I mean that the way ESD has appropriated
tort words is I'm not going to comment
about that but is that a reason for us
to emulate that or should we just say
there is a rest approach to do these
state machines if an application needs a
state machine and you transfer
representations with the important
information to run the state machine so
my feeling is just as with redirect
where we told ocf oh you can define a
media-type that has all the information
that that would be an redirect we could
do this here and say oh we can defined a
media-type that has the content is not
yet available now those applications
that that need to cope with this of
course now have to implement that media
type so we have reduced the complexity
to zero but other clients that they
don't care about applications like this
don't have to take an impact on on their
state machine and I think this is since
we have about 40 seconds left this is
one thing that that you might want to
take home for for the afternoon and we
can continue discussing tomorrow morning
but I really like to hear what what the
view of the working group on this is do
we want to open the floodgates here or
do we want to be as frugal as we have
been in the past with that thank you for
coming today tomorrow 9:30 in another
room I hope everybody will find other