a lot of things for good night good
morning it's 9:30
so we're gonna get started welcome to
dead net thank you for staying until
Friday we have I'm Lu Berger patellar
and the Archos is joining us as a new
chair I will talk about chairs in a
moment our secretary is remote see if
this works there we go no that's so
we're actually going to start out by
calling Deborah surprise surprise so
we've seen this a couple of times but
this is Det Annette
this is Pat's working group so we really
want to state a special tribute and
thanks to Pat as we've heard that who's
retiring so they're retiring okay so as
we know Pat's retiring and well we're
very sad to say goodbye to her we do
wish her all the best and happiness
going forward so we have something for
her and then because she only brings a
carry-on with her
and purposely got her something really
heavy so
but it's small hey hey thank thank her
for this she really kicked off the debt
net and really made sure we stayed with
I Triple E and I have on this slide I
mean she she she's much more beyond the
debt net she has been the go-to person
for ietf for anything on entrepot a most
poor she helped kicked off the
coordination group in 2012 which has
made a huge difference in the
relationship we just had the meeting
this morning we meet once a week even
here at ITF and it really makes the
things go smoothly and and it's really
of course the people involved and Pat's
one of those people anyway we think 50
was her first IETF probably it could
have been earlier and in 802 they had a
big thank thank you to her because she
is known to have been the one to have
she's chaired and held leadership
positions the most of anybody at most
varieties so we were really thankful to
have her here as our debt net chair for
these first couple of years and going
forward of course we have a very good
video knows to continue on but we will
miss her so thank you all make me proud
let's get this thing finished up so I
hope we'll make some good progress on
this today thank you thank you so much
so here is our note well it's the end of
the week everyone should be familiar
with it even though it's a new form if
you're not please take a look at the
link on the bottom and read about it so
we are doing
audio and video streaming we're also
doing our joint minute taking through
etherpad
I just sent the link to the list so if
you want something easy to click on just
click there it's also it's also in the
jabber room which I will do my best to
watch if someone else can enjoy it and
jump on jabber that would be good
because sometimes I am busy focusing on
the discussion rather than jabber the
the etherpad link I want emphasize is
very helpful to make sure that we
capture the discussions that go on the
presentations the what we have slides we
don't need to worry about that but the
discussions are pretty important to
capture particularly in this one we're
expecting a lot of discussion in the
second half if you make a comment at the
mic just jump on etherpad and make sure
that the comment was appropriately
captured so that it's reflected in the
minutes route that would be very helpful
thank you and of course signed the blue
sheet so we get appropriate room size
our initial RF session our first session
is a bit packed it's this is definitely
an eye chart the point of this is we
have a lot to go through and we'll try
to stick to our agenda int by the way we
will have to remote presentations our
second session is a little different we
are going to have a real working meeting
and we're going to try to confirm some
of the discussions that have happened in
interims in that since the last meeting
we have had three of them and also
highlight issues that are still open and
we would really like to try to close on
what we think the the direction is that
the working group and as always we don't
do final confirmation of decisions in
here we do it on the list so the
discussion follows on to three in terms
that took place it will we will have
hopefully a good discussion make some
progress hear the results of that
progress will be captured in a document
and then that document will have an
opportunity for everyone to
review and comment on list so that'll be
the focus of the second session the
we're going to adjust the timing a
little bit partially to allow for a for
Stuart Bryant to talk a little bit about
his enhanced VPN framework which we
expect to show up at ease but is
actually answers one of the questions we
have on our slides is how do we that we
need it we need some text covering our
the the VPN behavior we've always talked
about about carrying TSN no for debt net
and that's going to provide a
higher-level framework of it so we want
to make sure to give some time we'll put
that at the end as well as if we have
time this is this other presentation on
control plane which is definitely out of
scope of the the working group but it's
good to be thinking about where we're
headed particularly as we're trying to
develop our information model and yank
parameters for describing service and
describing middle behaviors and Link
behaviors as always we really like
discussion on the mail list and we have
an IPR disclosure process where
basically before adoption and before
working group last call that we we asked
all authors and contributors named in a
document to explicitly state whether
they know of IPR
this is also the time if you're working
in the working group and you know of IPR
that and you can look at the definition
and then oh well what that means know
about they are if you know of it that's
the time to disclose it if you haven't
done so before so where are we in our
documents we have three documents that
we keep saying we're good at last call
and this time we're not kidding we
really want to last call these three
documents we thought we were going to be
into last call on two of these the
architecture in the use cases but each
time we went to do just to really start
the last call the author said that we
have one more thing to do and in the
case of the the architecture document we
we're there now in fact it's not on the
on the agenda for that reason we think
it's done I did talk to Pascal who's not
in the room but is a co-author and he
says he thinks everything's incorporated
if it's not you'll send it to the list
so hopefully we won't have anything but
even if he does we can capture that as a
last call comment use cases will here
shortly
the problem statement has an asterisk
next to it because we talked a few times
that it it's a document we spend time on
and be nice to produce it
it's an informational document we spent
time on it so it's good to capture it
but if the text is a little too dated
now and it causes us a lot of problems
we may bring it back to the working
group and say do we really want to spend
focus our energies there perhaps it's
better to focus somewhere else so we'll
see how that one goes
on the agenda we have three of our
working group documents that are not yet
ready for last call the security
document Ethan will give an update on
that hopefully he's online it's seven
hours earlier there and the data plane
solution is the focus of our second
session but we will have an update in
the first session on what's changed
since since the last meeting and the
flow information model is on the agenda
in terms of our deliverables uh welcome
Ethan that's good bodies there so in
terms of our deliverables and milestone
we're actually moving along slower than
we had initially hoped but we're still
we're moving along on three of the four
in terms of what we have is adopted
working group documents we don't have
any yang documents or yang models as
working group documents yet but we do
have an individual draft on it that's on
the agenda that we'll be talking about
today and with that I think I've gone
through the list oh yeah I forgot to
mention something
we are in a lucky situation that the ITF
and I to Plato to face-to-face meetings
are back to back in the same hotel in
Bangkok and we discuss it in this
morning as well that it's an opportunity
for a joint session I mean for the
coordination team between ITF and I to
play to two and we are thinking of as
well potentially having a Saturday
afternoon joint session between at night
and 802 dot on TSN this would be the
first opportunity to two groups could be
in the same room and I think it would be
good for proposed loops for a
collaboration and and many many items
are our interest for four groups this is
an idea so far we will have further
discussions on the wrist and so on so
just purification are so Saturday before
ITF meeting on Saturday Saturday after
because ITF is first then we have the
weekend and then the article limiting
norm fin right now I checked the
published schedules and ITF is first
it's the third starts on the 3rd of
November and then I Triple E 802 starts
the next Monday on the ninth so I I
think or Sunday on the night I think it
might be that at one time they were the
other way around or something because a
couple of people have thought they were
in the other order but but I checked
online this morning and it's definitely
ITF first and I Triple E 802 the second
week go ahead right now the I Triple E
802 that one has a joint effort going on
with ie CSC 65 which is on industrial
a profile for time-sensitive networking
for industrial uses if we can get them
to come that would be a third group that
would be I think it'd be really valuable
for them to see what's going on in debt
met because I think that will be
relevant to them as they get into larger
networks also I'll be pushing to that
right well we did discuss that this
morning we would certainly invite them
Glenn seem to think that they might not
be available for some reason for that
but but we should certainly invite them
and and whether they show up or not is
up to them
welcome Ethan we can see you and
hopefully we can hear you when you're
ready for me to switch sighs just say
slides say next okay yeah you sound
great okay so I'm you think grouse go be
laboratories and this is the update on
the debt net use cases draft and next
slide please
the current status is that we did put
together a use cases draft 14 but it has
only very minor changes from the last
one the main one being that we moved all
of the authors which all used to be on
the front page to a contributor section
because as you know can't have them all
on the front so that's what we decided
to do fixed a few typos basically the
same as it was we consider the draft to
be basically stable ready for working
group last call there was a couple of
things that we decided we would defer
till the last call process instead of
trying to get him into draft 14 one is
that there are some texts related to
network slicing that we've been working
on we'd like to get that in there but
it's it's just a more clarification it's
good stuff
and I sort of wanted to bring up the
topic of whether we should say something
in the youth cases draft about ipv4
because we've got a lot of conversation
about it generally speaking in the UK
draft we don't attempt to suggest any
kind of technology or solution but on
the other hand there was this sort of
moment when we realized that for a lot
of the use cases it it was important to
have at least a solution for ipv4 even
if it wasn't the complete more complete
solution you could get with with ipv6
for example I don't know that I want to
actually have that discussion now
because this is a very short update but
I just wanted to put it out there that
that's another thing that we maybe
should consider on the list or if
somebody already knows the answer then
it can just be done with that
so I put on it so that's the end of the
update we're ready for last call and and
that's it so I did put in a couple more
slides if anybody is interested in
reviewing stuff about the use case just
briefly one of the things was the notion
of the use case common cleans in the
only reason I mention it because we've
gone over it enough times is because it
does get referred back to in the
security draft update which I'm going to
go over next so Lou maybe just let's
just page through the slides and all
spend fifteen seconds on each of them
and then we'll just move right along the
next slides are part of this
presentation on security this draft or
on security it's there in this one okay
okay so just I mean the goals we provide
the industry context for debt net a
yardstick for functionality of any
proposed design and we highlight the
commonalities between the use cases so
that's that's kind of what I'm getting
at about these common themes and so next
slide please
okay so we're gonna go so future plans
even though we're gonna have last call
we're still going to use the use cases
draft as a yardstick to consider the
value of the proposed solutions next
slide please
before we go there Ethan I that's Lou I
have a question you mentioned earlier
that
your plan was to go to last call and
then to add text that's not typically we
don't do that typically if you have text
that you think needs to be added we
would add it now before a last call oh I
miss have must have misunderstood then
because I thought we had had the
conversation and that there was going to
be when we do last call there was going
to be one more oh sorry I must have just
misunderstood if you have the text ready
to go I think it would be much more
efficient for the working group if you
do an update and then we issued last
call and everyone has an opportunity to
review that new text does that is that
work for you how long do you think you
need for to get the next Rev out with
that text that you have in mind on the
order of a week the text is basically
prepared it just needs a little bit of
editing honestly yeah I think it would
be much better to hold off last call
until that's ready and then because if
as soon as we do last call we're asking
a lot of people to look at the document
and if you then add new text that it
means they have to look at it again and
it's less likely to get as good review
then okay that's my fault I just
misunderstood no problem I thought
somehow I got a different a week is easy
so that's fine so we'll look for the
next version and then and then last call
it okay it sure brought is the
community's name please Stuart Bryant I
said oh I didn't hear orrible is the
confusion that actually quite often
another Rev is spam as a result of the
last call comments so there will be
probably be several more revisions
afterwards it's just that we should
start with the cleanest ten yeah I think
I heard what Stuart's saying it's a good
point it's not that the last call
comment the last call version is the
final one we may have updates based on
last call comments but if the author's
know that there's texts that have to go
in we shouldn't start last call to that
text is there either does that make
sense yeah I guess I was thinking more
along the lines that it was a minor
enough provision I thought we had
discussed it but I just must have
misunderstood
it's alright it's not an issue I can get
the text in there in a week or so
great ocean thank you do you have an
opinion on the ipv4 thing is that just a
non-starter can we just say we're not
going to mention to you aren't ipv4 is I
think ipv4 is in our Charter so you know
the fact that we have to deliver an ipv4
solution isn't surprising but if you
think there's a place to mention it that
that's not unreasonable it's in our
Charter so mentioning is fine okay okay
I'll just put some kind of brief
mentioning yeah certainly the it's a
good issue to highlight to those in the
room so that when they're reading the
document they keep in mind ipv4 and ipv6
and make sure that the text is adequate
to cover the those cases as well as your
own use case all right we can proceed
okay so I was just going to there are
two of these slides on that show the
common themes and I was just gonna show
him again because when I talk about the
security draft I refer back to these so
I just thought instead of having to go
back from there we go forward from here
so the point is that these are like the
least common denominators of all of the
different use cases because the use
cases are many and they're complicated
we decided that it was good to identify
the common elements of them so we refer
to these as the use case common themes
and they have things like it has to be
scalable in size it has to have high
availability it has to be secure the
flows have to be deterministic I use
this deterministic flow is isolated from
each other that one I'm going to mention
that specific common theme I'm going to
mention in the security update so that's
the only reason I'm pointing it out okay
that's it for that we can move on to
security
okay this is the update on the security
considerations draft next slide please
so the current status is that it's still
at draft one which is unchanged since
the last IETF the draft is considered
currently to adequately cover the
general topic of security for debt net
that is to say it doesn't yet include
the security considerations that are
specific to whatever data playing
protocols we choose to use so that
comprises what we have to do next is to
add the security considerations that are
specific to the data playing protocols
once those decisions are made
note that the scope of the debt net
security draft is limited to security
considerations that are specific to debt
net ie time sensitive things that we
we're not trying to cover anything
that's covered anywhere else we're just
trying to focus on these specific things
so that's the update I thought since
again since it was a short enough update
I did prepare two very brief slides just
talking a little bit about the draft and
what's the structure of it and part of
it that maybe is new and and I might be
worth a word so let me just spend a
minute going over those next slide
please so the overview of the draft
abundant one minute I cover security
threats
for example delay spoofing and so on the
impact of those threats you know is that
a financial impact health and safety
impact mitigations in other words what
do you do about those threats and the
association of attacks to use case
common themes so in that this way we're
trying to narrow down the problems of
securing a debt net based on knowledge
or the specific application or use case
it's hard because there's so many use
cases so instead of by use case we
organize it by use case common theme as
I was just discussing
so if that particular theme is important
to use your use case and you're involved
in security for dead men you should pay
attention to that section if you do the
last slide this is an example of that
for example the deterministic flows one
that we just discussed this for example
the third paragraph here says a flow
modification or spoofing or header
modification or control packet
modification act attack could cause
packets from one flow to be directed to
another flow
thus breaching isolation between the
flows so this is this is bringing
together the properties of a debt net
with what the effect of a successful
attack could could could do to that
particular property interesting way of
sorting that stuff okay I'm done that's
it Thank You Ethan
and thank you for being up at what 3
o'clock in the morning or staying up
until game time yeah wish I could be
there well thank you very much for
participating nonetheless I like the
background with the mics there are eight
I think the last night
hello my name is Balaji Olga this will
be a short update on the ethnic flown
information model this draft became as a
very I will do it in that way okay thank
you
so this draft was adopted by the very
group recently at the last after the
last meeting and what we have discussed
there is that this draft will contain
not only the flow information model but
also service information other specific
aspects and practically this is that we
have updated in the draft so this is
about a VSO very shortly in the slides
regarding the service information model
we have identified only the basics many
things will depend on law also on the
result of the data plan discussion so
but we have put in the draft in a
conversion is ingress related
information element egress related
information element that not domain and
service day to a specific information
element and we have was a distinguished
two type of service over the dotnet
domain one is a layer 2 or TSM
connectivity service but flow contain
Ethernet frames and this is what we are
transporting over the data domain the
other service type is IP service type
where the floor contains IP packets and
these IP packets are transported over to
service the basics of
service attributes were also listed it
is the bandwidth parameters delay
parameters loss parameters I think
nothing surprising the connectivity type
which is selected what type of service
connectivity is provided a layer 2 or a
layer 3 connectivity in order delivery
and the service rank we have added also
based on the architecture draft some
reference points this is there in the
text in order to have some better
further discussion so they might be
removed if we don't need these reference
points for the service definition but I
think some of them will be definitely
needed so what we have added is just
what we have in their architecture draft
the application flow endpoint the Uni
interface and the neural interface
regarding the service scenarios we have
not added yet the interim results the
two service scenarios the internal
service and the darkness service this is
what is referred in the current version
of the document and practically that's
it the plan for the future is to
incorporate the conclusion from the data
plan discussion because that will impart
the attributes and of course
contributions are welcome thank you
I told us Eckhart is there no support
for the model where the end device
itself also performs dead net so for
example I'm aware of a lot of the video
application devices that are you know
performing something like what we call
press meaning receiving both streams
aren't able to merge these and so I
think that the use cases are maybe not
explicitly mentioning these details but
obviously these video services and so
I'm wondering how that would be captured
in that architecture I really that is
important scenario but let's wait for
the discussion and that not data playing
stuff but the general question of
whether or not host is described in the
information flow models it is it there
they are
yes so so to take a look at the hosts
description I use the mic please we
definitely have people who remote the
Uni looked is is exactly not saying that
the the user interface is dead net that
the user that the host is dead not
capable right so it's kind of just
consuming the edge representation of the
dead net service which is not the same
as as the full data just specifically I
think a breath yeah I think that'd be
definitely an important piece to cover
and if you have some specific
suggestions on changes the document
remember it's a working group document
please ask for change and even better
suggest test that excuse me
text for the document and maybe I think
you need also new reference points for
for that discussion so let's discuss it
for them in the the model should be
independent of a necessarily first step
that we take so later on we're going to
talk about some first steps where we
make some compromises but the the model
should support even without those
compromises
the target is in order to have it's
practically service provider independent
and and co very generally yeah that is
the target thank you
[Music]
but stay in the pink box okay I'm sure
so and I will introduce our work about
done that configuration remodel this is
the first time of this part work
presentation so we will go to kind of
detail and some and first I want to
introduce the dinette models and their
relationship we can see from the picture
the user will send the flow data model
and service data model to the controller
and at the same time the network will
collect the topology data model and send
it to the controller and the controller
based on the these data models will do
path computation and comes out to the
configuration in her model send it to
network and the network is configured
and then M flows are being transmitted
through the network and the network
awoke collects the status data model and
send it to the controller and a
controller will send it to the user and
the user depend on the current network
status maybe change the flow and the
service data model we can say this
picture shows the circle often that
control and manage
and the blue box shows the flow and
service data model is covered by a
current draft which is just introduced
but then I'll flow information model and
our work then and a configuration model
covers the red box including three parts
topology data model configuration data
model and the state has data model the
first I will introduce the then that
topology data model the net topology
data model is used for than that
features and resources discovery in the
network and we do some analysis about
the current working a ATF and the know
we have network topology data model and
now we have te data model and in the t's
working group we have te topology data
model and then that data mode does not
polish it in the model is the
augmentation to the current te topology
data model and including two parts know
the attribute augmentation and the link
annotation and let's do some a detailed
introduction these are the attributes
are included in our work and which is
necessary for DES net but not in the
current D each of Holliday data model
versus in no time in the architecture
drafted there are three no types
internet as node relay node and the
transient node and that way well
specifies the elimination and the
replication capability of the node and
we also include the queueing management
algorithm the type and their
corresponding basic parameters actually
as we all know there are some queuing
algorithm defining in actual ETS or
tasking group such as time of are
shaping credit based shaping and secured
a lot of the of them it's not in the
scope of the current than that
but perhaps it is an interesting issue
to consider that whether them that
should have their dedicated queueing
management algorithm or we should do
some should have some new queue
management of rhythm and question later
okay so I will continue and different
queue management algorithm has
corresponding basic parameters and we
also have a resource reservation base
which is also has been defined in the
maximum thing imports maximum packet
size and maximum data there's not a
classes let me a little explain about
what is standard class especially we
should have a tetanus traffic class to
distinguish 10m flows from mountain air
flows and the question is whether we
should have more than one traffic class
for ten that to distinguish different
data flows
that means the 10m flows have different
priority and the different process in
the device and we also define the
bandwidth and the delay metric for test
not in the delay metric we just do the
delay classification in the into three
parts link delay processing delay and
output queuing delay link delay has
already been covered by the counter work
and packet processing delay describe
delay from the packet from the packet
goes into the device and arrives the
output queue and the queuing delay is
the from the output queue and outside
device so we think this this
classification is not the only solution
and there may be other opinion it's open
to discussion but we think it's a
general classification for this period
yes I blog mirskiy is et yes my question
is on a link delay and
usefulness of this metric because I
remember correctly this RFC's
specifically exclude queuing delays and
actually that's what we are interested
because queuing delays introduced jitter
to the packet the rest is just physics
so because of that link delay is not
characteristic if we can calculate link
delay based on a distance so what we
need is residence time and the residence
time is not interphase residence time is
measured by ingress egress of interfaces
how we traverse the node so it's an
ordered pair and order it characteristic
because it's directional so ingress to
egress that's more useful and helpful
information and we have this already
included in SFC document and preparing
some document and more general use of
residence time in calculating T Greg
there's mothers may be multiple ways to
to measure you're actually making a
comment on the information flow document
not on the egg model you know it's a
Yank more though as well because they
salute Lee but it's derivative of the
information model so the the base
concept you're saying that here is
represented wrong please please go
please go look at please go look at the
the previous document that was presented
and see if you think it's right there
and if it's not suggests a correction
okay list yes I just want to clarify I'm
not saying it's wrong I'm questioning
whether it's usable well we if there's
something more useful again
it belongs first in that other document
then it'll flow down to this one and
sorry I think it's very important to
mention that I think the magic of tenets
is it's not the delays not from
measurement it's from the calculation by
the particular queueing management
algorithm it used so it's not matter so
it can
we calculated so the delay is
deterministic that's the point and that
is different from other other mechanisms
other working group work norm fin we've
got a new draft and I encourage it to
participate perhaps in the new draft on
founded latency where where we'll get
into the network calculus and what how
do you compute and there did there are
different ways to do it and we'll pick
one that works I would just like to
comment on the more more than one that
net class of service a great many
applications will not need that but if a
for example I may have a factory floor
that may have different kinds of flows
that have different need to make
different trade-offs so it's easy to
imagine leap Li's don't exclude having
more than one net net class okay sure to
your question on the left hand side like
a lot of work is going on in 802 the 20s
sense providing the yank for for all
these queuing mechanisms so it and and
as well the the delays like in hope and
so on it's good to have aligned the tool
and and leverage as much as possible
response to comments actually we are
open to discussion there is already some
work in actually and this is a
cooperation between two organizations so
it's very necessary to sit in the same
room the the topic okay thank you tell
us what what is the benefit of you know
having I mean not happen so Tim to me
what would be a lot more logical like we
do in many other working groups to have
something like the yang model be
normative for the information model if
it's whether you want to one translation
seems like rather wise just getting
ourselves into the additional problem of
you know creating yet another round of
box mapping information model to the
young model right so just curious
I didn't hear the question I think you
were directing that at the chairs but
I'm not a hundred percent sure can you
Greg can you repeat the question because
I know I'll rephrase and then you can
kill me too so the question is that
there interpret so there is a mechanical
way of derive yank model from
information model
so what's guarantees that this yank
model will be identical to one that
could be derived directly from
informational model actually we should
go back to the first picture it's not
the same data model covered in by these
two traps we can see the flow data model
and a service data model from the user
to the controller that is covered by the
information model and what we cares the
tenets configuring a model covers
different parts just like the salt bond
and the what guarantee is there what
guarantees that there is no overlap
between yank model derived from
information model and these models I
think it's a good suggestion perhaps we
should consider the interface between
these two models it is a good suggestion
thank you I'm just I'm just talking
about getting the you know human
translation from the information model
into the data model out of the picture
to reduce the places where we can create
bugs so what is your proposal well I'm
not sure if it would work very correctly
right in terms of if there are so many
abstract things in the information model
that we haven't captured in yang then we
have a problem right but if everything
that we have in the information model is
meant to be captured in yang why the
heck is that not the equivalent then
rights right well and that's the
normative part and we only have one
place we can make bugs
I'm not so I have coming to here so
actually the commodity model is not part
it's not a fan car
in a mission model it's it's just too
you know dependence model to collect to
discover information about yeah
capability of didn't work it's not about
keeping him northern I didn't mean to
say that there needs to be an
information model for for every data
model that we have but if we have
obviously data model for every
information model then I question you
know what's the added value of the
information model other than in creating
buzz so again I hope that I'm not
contradicting tutorials because
organizations usually do one thing
either information model or data model
because from information model its
mechanical operation to derive data
model making two parts of the same issue
problem because basically we are talking
about part that covers lifecycle
orchestration okay with their service
model using two different ways of
looking different players because one
layer is information model another layer
a little bit it's like a server to it
it's a data model the problem is how we
guarantee consistency of these two views
well do we need to guarantee consistency
is another question think so yeah so the
intent has been or the discussion has
been that we have the information model
that helps us understand what needs to
go in to the yang model and the yang
model is the thing that actually drives
the implementations so the information
model is more about our the process that
goes in here well the data model is more
about what happens with implementation
and I see that's a controversial
statement I'm really good at holding yes
something up that at least that's how I
viewed how we were lining up but
organizations use information model to
produce data models well that's our III
amusing
that's true and when they when they
formally define the information model
using tools such as UML we're not doing
that we're in in we're documenting it in
text form which means that the only way
to translate from the narrative to the
actual data model is a human process and
that's the way we've been doing it
whether that's right or wrong we can
certainly debate no no that is I think
that there is I believe there is no
right and wrong
I just might suggest that maybe we'll
need to rename it from information model
to information flow or something else
because information model exactly
associated at least in my mind and I
think that in mind of others couple
others here with UML and being able to
produce data model as derivative right
so it's certainly in the ITT context
information models are done in UML there
have been other information models done
in the ITF which are narrative and form
and this one is aligned with what we've
done in the ITF before it's not aligned
with what has been done with information
models in ITT but you're absolutely
right there's different approaches when
we give some chance to some others to
talk this is an extremely just one thing
to add to this and there's an RFC 34:44
which which explains exactly basically
the difference of the relationship
between the information model and the
data model I think basically the trunk
of this we could clear up this really
clear clear up some of the confusion but
I think we're having here just one more
addition barrage rather the information
model is about the flow and the yang
model is for configuration for all the
details so from the fall flow you will
select but to configure in the normals
and it is not at all mentioned in the
flow information model or the
configuration related details this is
why we have separated the to document
microphone
yeah we should be we should be careful
about what flow means because we can
look at it as just a the specific series
of packets or we can look at it in the
broader context of of how our charter
reads it where it talks about
information needed for flow
establishment and control and that's a
little broader than just looking at a
particular flow because it's all the
information needed for flow
establishment I control right again it
might be just a certain perception that
when we somebody mentions we are
developing information model I
automatically think that that could be a
derivative that could be a source to
produce a and model and it's not only
ITT that uses this approach worth
creating information models some other
SDOs produce information model and then
out of there
mechanically derive game data models yes
sorry for bringing this up and just you
know the original goal was really trying
to ask is there something we can do to
simplify our life right so not to have
more discussions that are not ending
right so just if there are pieces you
know that we know are going to be met
one to one right is there any way to
avoid that we have to always continue to
check consistency because that's where
it came from right you said oh don't
talk about these parameters in the yang
model go back to the information model
then update that draft and then
basically you can come back to the yang
model and get that draft updated right
so I mean that that was basically is
their way for simplifying our life
saying you know this is basically the
yang expression of parts of the
information model or something to avoid
the duplication that's all yeah you
always have to have a narrative form and
then the the actual model or module
description and one is more about syntax
one is more about concepts we've split
it in the past that the most the
concepts are coming in in the
information model
and the syntax is in the yang model yeah
but so we have also enough examples
where we're really just you know having
the yang model where kind of the logic
is kind of the informational part in the
beginning and then all the details of
parameters also aren't duplicated right
they're just in the yang model part of
the document so often often you'll see
it a reference in that case in the yang
model where you have a normative
reference to where that parameter is
described and the problem is is that
being new we don't have somewhere else
to reference so either it has to be in
the same document or it has to be in a
new document and we then take the
approach we've been taking is to have
them separate we could certainly combine
the documents if that makes sense but
then that becomes a new massive document
again as I said right I mean if it's not
you know really saving us work at this
point in time right forget about it I
was just thinking that you know looking
at these consistency issues trying to
you know be as efficient in what we're
defining you know with the least amount
of work yeah I mean I I guess sure thank
you actually we have in that document if
we use the the same information from the
information model we will do the
reference so keep keep them try to keep
them yeah but it's I think it's actually
a good point because right now we have
information split over two places having
it split in two places is it good and I
think even hopefully everyone will agree
that we really want to capture the
narratives in one place and then have
the syntax definition and in one place
as well right now it's a little bit
spread which is definitely not a good
situation so I will go to the next night
and after the introduction of the tenant
apology attribute and to the debate of
the models we will go to some
introduction to the 10m flow
configuration data model and there are
some different No
types which has already been mentioned
in the telnet architecture dropped and
the different node types play different
role internet network including ingress
node replication no transcendence
elimination node and egress node these
different roles also can be mapped to
the people below and all these different
different roles can be characterized to
threaten net architecture layers
the first one is service their service
layer prophecy which is consisted of
each node and its main function is
encapsulation and decapsulation and the
second layer is service layer which is
consisted of rellenos and its main
function is packet replication and
elimination for service protection and
the third layer is the transport layer
which is consisted of transient notes
and it will do congestion protection and
the configuration we defined will depend
on the different rows and its function
so here we are there is the low lowest
layer of the architecture transient node
configuration and we will include some
parameters including flow priority flow
identification key management algorithm
configuration and explicit wrote which
is needed to be considered and it is
also mentioned by doing in the Middle
East is there is a very interesting
draft in another working group it is
about the queues young model and we have
do some analysis the cucm model is
consistent for Bayesian models
classifier policy action and the target
and it also defines IETF tips or young
model based on these four base Llamados
and this part work may be can also be
used in our transcended configuration
young model because we can do
augmentation to this llamado and and and
that that's not features into it this
may be the next step work of this
document and we also here are some
attributes about the relay node
configuration the relay node has main
two functions replication and
elimination first we will do flow
identification and the specifies whether
the flow will do a replication or
elimination if it does replication which
specifies the copy numbers all the
redundant numbers and after do the
replication and elimination we should we
should end the information of flow and
notification to guide the packet to the
next relay or edge node here is an
example any question yes so you use term
no yes
have you considered that this
elimination function could be a part of
their edge node yes actually we can see
more clear in this picture we can see
there is some overlap off different
which means the edge node can also do
replication
right so yeah might be better not refer
to as a node uh-huh what function yes
perhaps the name should be considered
yeah I think it's supposed suggestion
thank you sorry to do this again you're
making a comment on the architecture
document she's just she's just
presenting what is in the architecture
document so the architecture document is
about to be lost called
if you don't like anything something
it's in there they'll be please don't
wait for the last call you know read it
and send comments the list not thank you
and we will continue here is an example
in the umpires data plan solution we
will use the as label as the
identification so in this really note
the flaw added
acacia is the incoming Ashley and the
way well specifies whether the packet
will be replicated or eliminated or both
and we also have to specifies the
outgoing as label which guides the
package to the next relay on each node
and we also have to specify the output
pot which guide the package to different
explained wrote and if we have already
done this kind of configuration what
will happens in the data plan we can see
in this picture the first package
encapsulation the lowest is the payload
and we have the tenant control world and
the 100y is the as label and the t label
is for transmit and the ingress the
encapsulation is like this and in the
relay note that we can see that the s
label is switched it has been switched
to 201 and which and do the packet
replication and the kinda packet to the
next the relay node and the label is
switched again to 301 and the packet is
a will cost go to the egress and then we
will do some configuration in the edge
node in the ingress node configuration
it should include flow identification
praxic sequencing technique capsulation
travis specification and perhaps also
flow aggregation because the flow
aggregation solution has not been
clearly defined in the data plan so it
is open to discussion and in the eQuest
node configuration will include flow
identification pack hillary ordering and
the packet decapsulation what is the
next actually because there the data
plan solution is being discussed and
perhaps there will be some conclusion
today in the afternoon and so and also
we are we should consider the
cooperation with the I Triple E data
model definition so this will remain
just the beginning of the work
we will have more considerations about
queuing algorithm configurations and
will improve the replication and the
elimination part and also end the 10's
status data model and also ask for more
contributions and the comments okay
that's all thank you thank you very much
any other comments so as we know we do
have a chartered item to work on any
models it sounds like we have a little
bit of a some follow up that needs to be
done to make sure that the document is
appropriately aligned with with the
other documents one one suggestion I
have there is is that if you find that
you're just repeating text that's in
another document don't repeat it just
point to the other document yes and if
you find that that you need to repeat it
because you think the other document is
missing something perhaps proposed to
some text to go into that other document
and so we don't end up having to look in
three places versus just two and then we
can as a working group decide whether we
want those two places to be in one
document or in two documents and
personally this is my as a personal
perspective as working group chair is I
hope you do it quickly because I'd like
to see us have something that we could
pull the working group on before the
next meeting I'd like to not wait to the
next meeting to do an adoption if we can
get there actually we plan to update the
this draft very soon yeah yeah I think
the the the narrative parts are going to
be a part that is going to be a is a bit
of a sticking point right now okay okay
thank you the descriptive parts of just
so we have an idea of the room how many
people have read the document it's an
okay number we could definitely use some
more how many think that after the
update that's been discussed
that it would be ready to pull for
working group adoption and keep in mind
an adoption isn't the final place it's
the starting point so about the same
number so it sounds like it's a good
plan and we look forward to seeing the
update and and others please feel free
to to review it and send comments to the
authors okay thank you thank you very
much
yoni here you're up next if you could
join the queue welcome your name we see
you yeah you're a little low and you
know yeah and we maybe can adjust the in
room speaker a little bit we have
someone who's doing AV for us so let's
let's continue thank you
and just say next when you want to go to
the next slide quick update on the
working cook draft on on the day to play
encapsulations and the next slide so we
had a bunch of interims
and after those interims I made a couple
of our updates actually to the last one
was uploaded yesterday and the I took in
the what we discussed during the
interims
and what the accurate are in the rims
and also the input from some couple of
other volunteers who contributed take so
basically from a front from the two to
zero so this is after the interim three
ballast put a bunch of text about the
domain specific consideration and the
draw lines picture about how in
in scoring a different deployment cases
for the routing service and preaching
service and so on and auntie em so this
was really useful it probably should
clear things up for quite a few people
and then I also added the preliminary
text for the a simplified IP service
that was the solution that we came up
with and I create a after the interim
tree so next on then from three to four
so this was a minor update at test
because we also create that that the
native ipv6 based solution that that was
drafted into the draft it's a no-go just
because it's an ipv6 only solution and
so on and there was a push for four also
covering ipv4 so I took this text and
references to ipv6 souls in a way and
put some more text preliminary text
reducing fat IPV pypy solution also I
added a note that that in a document
that I pointed out about the previous
work that we had in the very first
version of the of the working group
document on beta plane where we had this
is pseudo wire in a pseudo wire Congress
tree at the mpls piece and we also had
the IPP SM and and there we had the kind
of if you want to transport something
over IP you should look these another so
it had the solutions that we had in mind
based on the RFC 40:23 and ends 7510
so after the so bit of history so just
that the we kind of been there already a
long ago where we are heading again so
there's a couple of presentation
bringing this up IP solution it was
basically in the first cut of the
working group draft does remove based on
the occupant ation what he had at that
time and after this long rule VB came up
with in the interim tree we came up with
the simplified IP solution so I hope
that that today we can make kind of
final decisions where to hit and I kind
of think that the encapsulation become
stable okay next slide
the only it's Lou what the point that
the only made I just want to highlight
because that's going to be one of them
the important topics that we talked
about this afternoon so keep it in mind
and come to the second session I know
that's attractive to do other things
Friday afternoon but please come join
and participate in that discussion okay
so this slide just highlight the the TX
on contribution from pelage to kind of
spell out what is assumed to be visible
in a text already but what was kind of
hidden and and and these things show up
the routing service and also the for the
written service for Ted net so and and
the one that I have rounded with the red
circle on the right left right bottom
corner is the simplified IP solution so
it assumes that the the end system IP
whatever it
she stays unmodified and all the didn''t
functions that we have so the queueing
and the bounded latency explicit routes
and so when they are provided by the M
transmitted layer below it has certain
limitations that we come later on and
for the other solution saw the tunneling
and the IPPS N and M PS PS and there's a
good chance that if we are a go continue
on this route at the same between the
the Etna layer and the end system
payload the same actually can be unified
with a small effort in my opinion ok
next slide so I'm just reminding the
constants from the interim so we to
simplify the IP data plane service the
identification because we don't have
anything that we could insert into the
application initiate it originated IP
packets so we basically settle down with
a sixth up or so that the typical file
support plus DHCP for the flow
identification and and the addition of
DHCP allows you actually a kind of
distinguishing between different TechNet
flaws and also kind of also builds the
kind of basis for the aggregation of
definite flows and as I said earlier the
underlying sub-link sub network is
responsible for different functions and
the Saudi SEM IP packets mess on to each
hop and then map to appropriate the
dentate bullying and sub network for the
next hop and so on so browse for the
solutions it's simple and doesn't
require me from the application IP the
concepts is that we already discussed in
the last time and what is this figure
tries to explain that we
that we kind of lose the intent
properties of one of our dear child or
discussion points of the elimination and
packet replication so that cannot be
done in to end without doing that at the
upper layers so therefore application
layer but that's out of scope out of us
so what actually happens that you still
have this this service protection but
that is on each network segment so
that's a separate so you don't have the
end-to-end Service protection at the
data layer which simplify the IP you can
build that on on your higher layers if
you want yeah yes okay
this there's a more neat and more more
details about this in a later
presentation especially the one at the
next session ok next slide and what next
so I think we're in a part that we can
split the document the simply got IP is
going to be as well encapsulation pretty
simple the MPLS based so we can do the
clear-cut in my opinion what I was
hoping for but didn't really happen
is that getting input for the wishes
that people want to see in the document
so I'm still calling for the
contributors to kind of provide text
it's there in the github every cut every
anyone can go and mock it if they want
so there is still kind of missing things
especially on the kind of detailed
behavior of certain knowns and the kind
of advanced parts of the behavior they
are boring so that's why they haven't
been progressed and then something that
that be properly and I hope that we
discussed today and make a decision
whether the impedance based solution
also allow IP PSN or just MPLS PA
in Seoul I think we need to have a sort
of agreement on this part also yep next
light that's it questions again we're
not going to get into the heavy
technical discussion but if you have a
question on where we are in the process
or in the document now's a good time
with that thank you very much Yanni okay
and we'll move on I believe it's Stuart
so what I was doing with this document
was to talk very close and see if it
works
thank you
so what I was at was attempting to do
with this document was to take the
latest version of the data plane
document as it existed and write it as
an MPLS specialist might wish to to see
it what the the idea was to make it more
easily and readily reviewed by MPLS and
and PW experts so there's some there's
some language difference between the
description used in the solution
document and the language that one would
naturally use in an IP MPLS context and
indeed the language that the operators
of such a network would expect he to say
so I wanted to get it aligned this is a
possible starting point for an MPLS data
plane spec what we do is with it is
really up to the working group so I
think it's unlikely that in the MPLS
case we will have anything other than
the overlay model
I know of no example where MPLS has got
to the to the end system and so I wrote
it really as a multi segment
Suda wire design would look and the the
the picture I show there is exactly it
is exactly based on on that what I kept
finding trouble was was I wanted to call
everything a PA and we don't call it
that so we did will have to have a just
a further discussion I think about whose
dictionary we use so we have lots of
discussions over the over the months
have been involved in this about where
replication happens and where
elimination happens I think the thing
that we have to be clear is that
replication and elimination essentially
happens in the edge nodes and the relay
nodes one of the things that's quite
interesting is if this is a pure in that
net system then there there are no there
are there are service labels visible at
every node and the transport labels are
all are always missing I don't know
whether that will lead to a scaling
issue because it certainly led to
scaling issues when people tried to map
pseudo wires directly to LSPs and so the
scope of the S flavour is always the
receiving decnet node I think that's
where I thought we got to with the with
the yang model but I in turn the earlier
descriptions that wasn't obvious to me
label is always swapped to the debt that
node because it's always the receiving
nodes view of the label that you need to
use
so one of the issues that I came up with
was how do we handle suit serve sequence
numbers so is it a fixed 28 bit value
can we live in an overlay model with
only 28 or 0 and if it's going to be
anything other than 28 is this a
parameter of the wire at setup time or
is it a parameter that's carried within
the within the the packet in the
philosophy of MPLS it would be a
parameter of what I've been calling the
wire it will be a parameter of the set
up thing so you do everything in
signaling I have an extremely
lightweight data plane is the MPLS
philosophy the OEM can we assume that
we're only going to use VCC V type 1 or
something very similar that is to say
can we assume that we always use the ACH
model or do we need to support the gal
model in the dead net layer there's a
decision that we're gonna have to have
to take flow aggregation so I put two
models of flow aggregation in there
because again it's not clear to me
whether we want to aggregate so that a
new S label and control light well so a
new control label so a new control word
is available each time we do an
aggregation if we don't do make the
control word available ie we split the
stack and have two s bits we don't do
that then we can't do press on a an
aggregated segment and I think that's
something that we need to think
particularly carefully about when we go
to wide area versions of this as opposed
to low period versions p-waves right so
in pwe 3 we just powers we just used to
who wrap everything and send it across
in dead net we're going to have to have
some sort of ACL thing and we're gonna
have to support as I understand it three
types of packet ethernet/ip
for an ipv6 and it may not be commonly
the common knowledge here that MPLS
never uses the IP version to figure out
what is what type follows so we have to
have three types and are we going to set
up a different flow group as it were for
each of the types Greg yes Greg Mirsky I
would probably restate this that MPLS
never used it
MPLS relied on the first label that is
correct it never did never figures out
what well right it does sort of figure
it out because it does how am
recognition on the first nibble right
because basically because in MPLS LSP IP
was that one of native payloads then it
was assumed that after we have a label
element with as bit set the first limo
will tell us what the payload type is
but that's not the way MPLS works
MPLS may do it an OEM discrimination
based on that we'll use the pseudo why I
think one does but no piece of no no LSP
relies just on the nibble it rely you
get the packet on a different ether type
for example well if you have there was
either that so if you have Ethernet MPLS
over Ethernet so you have MPLS
encapsulation yes yes if you have pseudo
wire you use control world right if you
have gal label than you know that you
have om but if the player itself other
than OEM we have one different LSP for
each payload type so I think you
actually this is Lu year I think you're
actually you're actually both correct to
some degree you rely on a combination of
the control plane and typically you rely
on the control plane in there is a case
where the control plane says this is IP
in which you go look at the first nibble
get to figure out the versions I think
I think you're both actually and they're
the reason why for example in control
world the first nibble is zero and in
MPLS encapsulation of beer
the first nibble is 5 the first thing so
you're doing st so you can differentiate
it's from IP so version 5 is a protocol
that was defined by the idea if I happen
to chair that writing but yes I know I
know it's a trivia question no no that's
that's correct because it needs to be
different from 0 1 4 & 6 are the labels
that already been used 5 had been used
to what yeah all right so that's
something to take up with Ayana that's
interesting any all just learned of IETF
trivia there but I think the point is
that we need to align with the way that
MPLS does this an MPLS sets of a
separate vector before as he does for v6
I don't think it says I don't that
that's the way it's commonly implemented
I don't think it is actually stated that
that's a requirement
ok I'd have to go looking and I don't
remember LDP well enough anyway so the
question we go ok I'm sorry
from the standpoint of FAQ yes it will
be different fact ipv4 ipv6 will be
different facts doesn't mean it's a
different label right but the label
could be the same yes we can you need
discussion so there's
a question of what how we set up the the
path can we use the the PW signaling
protocols that we've already got in
place for exchanging the labels between
DECT their peers and one of the things
that wasn't clear to me is how we set up
the graph because it's a graph we need
to set up and not a tree or a unicast
path and not we don't normally set up
grass in in the routing world so I think
there's some more work thought needed
there comment on that actually there is
an ISAs extension yes RFC seven eight
thirteen right we need to see how that
applies to to this yes yes sorry but I
told me that earlier in the week and I
thought about it um so I think there's a
few things we need to do here right we
need to verify that detonate that we as
a working group consider this is an
accurate reflection of the design I
don't think it's quite an accurate
reflection yet but we need to make sure
that it's an accurate reflection and
then we need to go and get the pseudo
wire and MPLS experts to review it
because I don't think there's been
enough review from those knowledge
groups on this piece of work and whether
we merge this back into the salt
solution draft or whether we make it a
separate draft or whether we merge this
with a draft split from the DP Sol graph
of what we do that's up to the working
group but what I wanted to do was to try
and make sure that we looked at this
from an MPLS in pseudo wire point of
view to understand that what we were
doing matched well with the learnings
we've had over the last 20 years thank
you all right thank you
as we talked about earlier we're gonna
be having a good discussion on data
plane in the second session we'll look
to in their wrap-up to figure out next
steps
certainly as yani already said in his
slides he sees there's good
text there I personally see there's good
text there we'll figure out how to bring
them all together into a working group
yeah give you guidance from the chairs
as to how we move this blue code that we
discuss it in the wrap-up section right
this afternoon just a question for
clarification balázs Varga on your
aggregation slides well you have a bingo
back where you have added additional
control aggregation right yes this slide
yeah and here you are stated that
preface possible I think that there are
limitation on perhaps in that situation
because for that aggregate you have just
that single control work so it might not
be an end-to-end graph in that case
anything you need to do I think that's a
good discussion for the plane discussion
hopefully we'll get there
we actually are already ten minutes over
and we have quite a bit of time work
this afternoon hopefully we'll get to
this one at this point one one key week
we should take it till later and Andy
you'll see a clock in the corner
anything you can do to I will try my
best yeah and I'll do my best to try to
get the slides I'm just making sure I
stay in the pink box okay I'm Andy
malice my co-authors are Stewart and
mock and pelage so this right here is a
derivative work from DP Saul it's also a
a a derivative work from Stewart's draft
that we just heard from so we use the
same terminology in the same
abbreviations and so on
it's basically meant to augment or
replace the text that's currently in
sections 5 dot 2.27 and 8.7 of D piece
all in its talks about the encapsulation
for debt net packets
when carried over an ip-based debt net
infrastructure and it's not just an
encapsulation for IP over debt Annette
all of that certainly one of the
multiple use cases so I just wanted to
make that clear it's the capsulation for
debt net when carried over IP whether
published is a standalone document or
reemerged and in 2d piece all is up to
the working group to decide exactly the
same as it Stuart's draft before the
authors are fine either way I'm gonna
actually interrupt for a moment because
just as for context for the working
group this is documenting something that
was presented I think in Prague and and
as this in the solution document so you
can go back there and at the time the
feedback from the working group is we
didn't want to go this direction and at
the interims we were struggling with
this and this was a discarded option and
so it's good for understanding that this
was basically ruled out in Prague
Stewart made the point that this this
approach was never implemented and we
shouldn't head this way and then we also
had discussions we also had discussions
wait one sec you're free to correct me
in a second more importantly we had
discussions that this did not align well
with hosts and that we wouldn't be able
to deliver an end-to-end debt net
service with this approach and that is
what led us towards the simplified
approach and in the interims
so I think one of the things would be
really good in this presentation is to
say why do you think we should bring it
back so it's not that we shouldn't
consider bringing it back it's just you
should articulate why they should have
to technical discussion okay if I
mischaracterized Stewart I apologize
that's how I read it and I think that's
how others read it and if we
mischaracterized I apologize and just
have the technical discussion and see
whether this is the best of yes and and
also just to to
to talk about what you just said this is
this is actually the result of the third
interim and I'll be going to that a bit
more in the next slide it's basically a
dis got a result of the discussion in
the interims especially the third
interim where we decided on the
simplified model also there were
comments in the third internment perhaps
of previous interims that debt net is
basically for at least some of the use
cases a non-starter if you can't use it
over ipv4 over an ipv4 subnets
met to basically allow debt net to be
used in the use cases that require an
ipv4 subnet don't forget the host just
bring in yes please address host in this
to yes I do that on the slide right here
perfect thank you okay very good so
basically this is based on the
simplified model as discussed during the
interim the third interim on on the 14th
of February basically in this case and
systems are not debt net aware so that's
the host there's no debt net header in
the host they typically sent IP packets
or non IP application frames over
Ethernet over an Ethernet DSN link or
even a TSN network to an edge node which
is shown as the next node over next to
the end system there which then adds the
debt net encapsulation so the debt net
capsulation is not being done in the
host and this is based this is by the
way the exact same figure that Stuart
had in his document and in his slides I
just changed a couple of the labels
because it's not it's not using an MPLS
subnet it's using an IP subnet other
than that this is the exact same figure
that Stuart had in his document and it's
based on the figure that you showed low
in the third interim okay so so in this
diagram edge nodes and relay nodes are
the
ones that are getting it aware so you
can see that we show detonate in system
edge no transit node which is not
detonate aware a really note in each
node which are an event end system which
is not aware and the edge notes is very
similar as Stuart said to PE routers for
pseudo wires or MPLS VPNs okay any
questions on this slide okay so what we
want to do is we want to take advantage
of work that's already been done in DP
saw and so basically the transport
getting it over IP you require a couple
of things you require a method to
identify the TechNet flows and a method
to carry the dead net sequence number
well both of those are already available
in DP saw in the MPLS encapsulation so
this is just copied directly from DP saw
as a reminder for people this is the net
MPLS encapsulation that's currently in
deep in DP saw the control word has the
sequence number and the S label
identifies the flow so the Iping
capsulation is very simple for transport
over IP the transport labels from the
previous slide and replaced by UDP and
IP as specified in RFC 7510 for a carry
MPLS over UDP
the encapsulation is added and removed
in the edge notes ok some notes on this
encapsulation first of all it works
equally well if ipv4 and ipv6 just to
show you right there that IP header down
the bottom that could be either v4 or v6
everything works just fine either way it
works with MPLS based segment routing as
Pesa fied in ITF spring segment routing
MPLS in that case there the t label that
you see in that picture right there
is retained in the each segment endpoint
the top to you label is popped and
mapped to a corresponding UDP IP tunnel
so the next steps are to either as the
working coupe and the chairs
prefer either merchants back into DPS
all or to continue as a separate draft
and that's it
any questions I don't have a question I
do a terrifying point which is the
assertion that this encapsulation string
can't be used in a host from a host
point of view the UDP piece down would
look like a socket call and the piece
above it is just some magic numbers in
the in the host payload so I don't
honestly see why we can't use exactly
the same thing from a host as well as
from an edge so the discussion was is
that we're inserting between the
transport protocol that the IP transport
protocol let's say UDP or even TCP even
SCTV @rl but between UDP and TCP and IP
and that's not an easy thing to do in
most host acts well because you think
the coast has already put UDP on it
before we get it hmm no the applicants
of the application that makes a socket
like a POSIX socket cost yes and then we
have to insert our header in the middle
of the stack well indeed but I wonder we
could persuade the application to insert
just some magic bytes in front of its
its output and then we'd be done I I
think the the feeling was that you know
we operate on consensus a little loose
was that that wasn't a reasonable ask
and we certain if we did that we
certainly would have to coordinate with
the transport area because we're now
mucking with basically the transport
interface right and and that was viewed
as too complex now the approach taken
here to me sounds like it's just running
taking the MPLS solution and running it
over an IP PSN which you know that
that's just I you know MPLS over IP we
know how to write how we just need to
make sure that we do it consistent with
how the whole industry does it now yeah
you know sure that's that sounds
reasonable but taking it to the host was
where there was a lot of pushback and in
particular we wanted to make sure that
we didn't forget about v4 hosts and and
some of those hosts are and this is I
think something that came out of
Giles presentation was this or maybe
some side conversations is there's a lot
of devices out there that are embedded
devices where it's really hard to go
change the stack and we want to support
those two and just to be clear taking it
to the host is not a part of this trend
Oh indeed yeah so Greg where's kitty
so I understand the idea is similar or
might be derivative of unified segment
routing yes it's it's so much that okay
so if when we discuss the host we need
to understand and then we'll need to
extend a GP segment routing support to
the host to participate in this if we
ever take it to the host yeah so
basically whatever we don't know right
whatever edge of that net domain is it
has to use a GP segment routing
protocols extensions and again this is
if you want to segment routing at the
house because you don't have to I'm
gonna actually yoni was in queue okay
and he actually was in queue after
Stuart I apologize I missed him so
Stuart I think this is in response to
you the Oni says it is doable one can
view it as tunneling stripping the
additional IP header away was the hard
part
for the host that was his view of the
host okay I mean I'm just talking to
Jakov just here and he thinks there's
another way visit so yeah I think we
need to have two discussion this is not
the probably the time to have the
discussion but we do need to get into
these discussions as part of the design
process
okay honest yes I heard something here
about inserting the setter in the middle
and to the best of my knowledge if the
host
you know generates IP packets then I
don't see a way today allowed by the ITF
to not have basically two IP headers
writes your IP error from the dead net
and then you know the payload packet
would have to have its own IP header
right you look at role and others that
have tried to insert things in the
and they fail on the constraints of the
ipv6 architecture before you're not
allowed to do before and you're not
allowed to change ipv6 so this is going
to be you know two headers unless really
we have you know a model where that net
goes all the way to the host and then of
course you know the whole state can do
whatever it wants and then you would get
away with just one IP header I wish it
was different and maybe you know we you
know we can try to fight the windmill
I'd love to but I'm sure who from
Alibaba I just noticed you are talking
about how to use MPs SRO or IP in
completion for dotnet if so I suggest
you to order please I
I believe this format is almost no
difference from the MPs are a YP
capsulation
right yes that difference is on the neck
controllers a layer but this is the
original than that MPs encapsulation yep
like so I suggest to and a reference to
the MPS or IP dropped in this in your
document yes that of course there no
need to read describe those details
which had been describing another
drought yes exactly which is why I
referred to section 3 of RFC 75 10 which
is the description of how to do MPLS
over IP
okay so we have failed that running get
speeding up the discussion we will
resume data plane discussion this
afternoon thank you okay thank you and
we really need to ask you to squeeze
time
[Music]
got switched off okay so I don't think
we have talked much about multicast
forwarding planes and you know it could
as well talk about yeah the the existing
multicast forwarding planes but you know
given how that net is a future
architecture that we want to build we
wanted to kind of show what we think is
the you know the best forward going
multicast forwarding plan giving traffic
engineering and everything else and were
just also in the process bringing into
that work the elements that we think are
missing for that net so in beer with
traffic engineering what you effectively
have is that every adjacency every link
in the topology it has an address which
is a bit that you ultimately insert into
the header so that you can engineer the
path by simply you know having every
node in the network looking at the bits
that are its own adjacencies and our
forwarding and replicating towards them
so if you see here there is this red
path with the bits two three four and
five meant to deliver traffic from P 11
to the receivers P 2 and P 3 and that
would effectively result in a beer te
header with exactly these bits set being
sent from the source which we call the
ingress VFR ear router and being
forwarded along that path to work and
replicated to what these receivers so
that's a really a very simple thing and
these bits are per packets or at that
level we don't have any notion of flows
so you know the sender is free to choose
that on every packet now
when we look into what we think is
missing for a debt net in the in the
forwarding that's primarily the aspect
of pref or however we call it now and so
in this example what we're showing is
that we do have two alternative paths
right one going through p1 on going
through the other part of p3 and p4 all
these bits being said and the
elimination function itself is something
that as we said in the architecture also
can happen in the middle of the path so
you know these bits being set the
elimination function of course for its
operation needs to have a context which
I you know call the sequence number
space here and then the sequence number
associated with the packet how we
construct the sequence number space is
something for us to work out we
currently have two fields in the your
packet header that are filled with the
source and you know a random part which
I call this electorate so that would be
a good part to define that a sequence
numbers based then the sequence number
itself obviously so and with the ability
of the elimination function to happen
midpoint in the network as you know
provision for the dead net service and
not only on the egress you can also and
this is the next slide by the way see
that you can sustain arbitrary level of
failures depending on how much you know
path your provision so this is basically
the example where you have two
consecutive failures on different paths
right but you would still support it
because the elimination function helps
you to basically overcome this amount of
failure yes a great mercy city I just
wanted to ask you so you do realize that
the proposed format for beer te debt net
is incompatible with the beer
encapsulation so this is this is exactly
the new proposal of the of the beer
header which adds the the control word
sequence number right so that's exactly
what we need so up through right but I
think that then you cannot really refer
that as a beer because it's not with
80 629 RFC they defined a beer we look
forward to hearing the results of that
discussion in the beer from the beer
working because then then you have a
problem of how you encapsulate it either
in that because you cannot use either
type that reserved for beer no I think
that's exactly you know whether we want
to reuse the existing ether type or
quality v2 of that or assign a different
ether type so I think that's good work
to figure out but I think it seems to be
clear that the control work that we need
for prep is a similar element in the
headers as we have for other services
right they're not needed for the actual
beer forwarding but for the overlay
service that we're running here and that
would be the dead net service so that's
basically the resilience the pressure
part I think you know given how dead net
you know targeted for layer 3
environments would get into topologies
that one ready one minute are not that
common in the TSN case so I'll skip the
OEM stuff this is basically an example
that you can read on your own time given
how I'm shot down to basically show the
efficiency that we get with the EF in
you know typical layer 3 topologies like
rings and that's basically exactly the
considerations what we said elimination
function is on ingress and then of
course the whole you know traffic
engineering architecture PCC managing
the vent with and providing calculation
of the past so that discussion has
started in that he's working group yep
also we're looking into allowing to do
the prep in beer itself there's
basically the path engineering
resilience discussion because we'll have
to rely on a GPS as opposed to on a PC
ECC and yep those are the references
thank you and just to make you feel
better
Norman gets half his time and his is
actually within charter scope while
yours is the hot so give you more time
actually I made a incorrect statement if
someone wants to work on beer debt net
over beer we could consider that as
charter scope it's just it's not what
we're going to do initially so I'm it's
not that it's ABS coca sees me just just
a reminder I find it handy when people
are in the room we're what we care about
is upper bound on latency not low
average latency if we have bounded
latency we can compute how many buffers
we need to get zero congestion loss any
scheme that regards that uses feedback
to slow down the source is not an option
we have fixed band where we have minimum
bandwidth required for each flow and
mathematically sound assurances can be
given on latency and congestion loss
we're not interested in probability so
given that most of the debt network
we've been done has been talking about
packet replication and elimination
because that's more a fun topic
everybody has an opinion there's lots of
ways to do it but it's not a trivial
problem so that makes it really
interesting and it's very similar to
existing uses and MPLS is a familiar
technology so everyone has an opinion
okay well this isn't the only thing in
debt net founded latency is the most
important feature to most of the
application if you look at the use cases
document what they really care about is
bounded latency and we've talked almost
not at all about this because random
unexpected congestion is exactly what
prevents mixing critical traffic and
other traffic and one network and that's
one of our important goals is to do that
in some this in IETF a long time ago a
very long time ago in-service was done
but in serve quote doesn't scale and
queuing calculations are pretty
complicated
well the unserved technology
technologies do work hardware is a lot
cheaper now than it was in 1995 there
are also a number of new queuing and
transmission selection techniques
besides those that were explored in it
serve that offer different trade-offs
and there are awful lot of trade-offs in
this space and I'm anxious to get us
talking about them between low latency
latency variation implementation
collection complexity and the complexity
of what you have to do to make a
reservation ok there are all different
places in those Speight in that four
dimensional space for sweet spots for
solutions and now if you remember in
Singapore we got a presentation from
jean-yves Lagoo Dec which was very
exciting because he's one of the people
who have pretty much invented Network
calculus as we as we know it and we
believe that we can do the net necessary
network calculus in a way that doesn't
require a PhD to do a thesis for each
flow that you set up so we've got a new
draft in here bounded latency the mate I
drafted a bunch of it jean-yves has put
in a lot of work to it it has an
introduction it has a section on network
calculus which will be greatly expanded
in the next two or three weeks I believe
we have a section on what it takes to
compute the necessary buffers we have a
section that may be too large on queuing
models at some point we need to a map we
need to make a salon to make a selection
of queuing models or at least going
forward anyone who has a queueing model
that they want to use for that net needs
to be able to map their queueing model
to the requirements to the parameters
that we're going to have in this bounded
latency document the most important
section I believe is section 8 which is
how to character
Rhys queuing models so that you can
compute the latency for a flow so this
is very much a work in progress we're
certainly not ready to adopt it by any
means yet it's a start those who have an
interest in this are encouraged to
participate so I encourage people to
join me and jean-yves if you feel you
need to write something totally
different
I certainly can't stop you it would be
more fun if we work together I think
thank you
so when you compute these qyx there will
be the outcome of bounded latency or you
will determine the queuing models and
then compute the latency on top of it
which way will it go it is a somewhat
complex problem the expectation is that
a given application a given flow has a
requirement for end-to-end latency okay
and that you have to reserve resources
in the network for that latency and that
maybe we have a meant to control plane
issues at the very least using the yang
models that we're developing right now
we will be able to have a central
controller make inquiries of the network
and be able to construct a yes or no can
we meet that latency
it will be the central controller will
be able to compute the latency that can
be achieved for this flow okay whether
we go whether we have a protocol that
goes in to end along the path to
actually reserve the resources or
whether that's done with a controller
that's to be determined
does that answer your question okay
try again Queen queuing models are
bonuses for each name you get closer to
the mic yes thank you for each note you
will determine the queueing models
because queuing is specific to a note
it's not Network level the expectation
is that we have a timing model that
includes queuing delay okay so we should
we should let the next presenter talk
okay if we have and if we have time this
is I don't think we have time this
afternoon to get into it but it's an
important discussion that would be great
to take to the list it is an important
enough discussion that if we want we can
even schedule an interim just on this
one topic what once we're settled out on
the caps elations norm would that work
for you to just give a thumbs up all
right normal istening is no idea what I
said and he gave a thumbs up so that's
awesome thank you he was listening
multitrack brain okay please go hello
the unknown from Hawaii we are talking
about to the net over there and
apologies to backgrounds our mark cast
series and we can see in the use case of
the net that are some use cases around
mark cast and it said the mark has
capability I should have be integrated
into the to the net
another thing is a marketer and
broadcast is a a key enabler for the 5 T
and we can see quite a few use cases
relied on the market share capability
for minutes we not to spend too much on
better shop as we can see most of the
accessing the network and aggregation
Network her I filled in the de plata by
surgeons since Adagio networker scenario
ie for a city that traditionally we can
use the PDMP a surveys in the MPS to
provide at Peter Pan Pia service here in
Turin
if not a failure in the genes and the
services are wrapped up and into the
North Direction some other tests to see
which can get around failure that will
bring a delay of the series which may
override the COS change of the delay
well sister Bachmann propose another
solution so we can use another
technology here as you can see how when
the services are going to sell from the
routiers and it's a replicated into two
directions one in that clockwise and
another in the context otherwise and
then i each node around the union we
were processed advisor it was a pea
under ten to the Walia
now it's area called The Saboteur LP
also theater flu label and center to
know the
and happy with the livewell to
elimination and the applications there
so that is a ways has only one copy to
the leaves this is another scenario for
the interconnection of greens whether
good service is located in the not a
upon the ingress and then it's a
replicated and eliminated in the index
nation knows and then replicated over
post darshan of the Union in another in
second a linen so as we can see the mark
asked her in the terrain it's a very
efficient at most only two copies of
package is center of the in this
solution it's also a very comparable
with Kitty to know that Annette as you
can see it's almost great us for the net
and the unicast and I mean mark
asked can use the same Magnussen such as
the replication and the elimination it's
only so maybe yeah since then has a inch
in siga estimate take a zombie take a
pass so this may play a constant on the
marksman factories of the surveys
especially when they're 16 number it's
not a very long for the number 616 piece
so as this is a preliminary job so we
would like to your question more
feedback sound workgroup thank you thank
you very much we are now at the end of
the first session I see people in line
and this is great let's get the comments
sent to the mail list I just want to
point out that it's hardly can be called
admission because you are not using
physically disjoint network and you're
cutting your bandwidth
I look forward to the discussion or we
look forward to the discussion on the
mail list and with that it's break time
we're gonna come back at 11:50 and then
go for about two and a half hours so
take take your break and then come on
back
I think they usually do little
sandwiches at this time so go find them
and enjoy the break and we'll see you
we'll see you in 20 minutes
well we can we can talk line
yeah please continue the discussion on
the list let's go