Picon hello can you hear me oh they're
like this or mike is black sorry about
that
it's 11:50 it's time to start our second
session I think we lost people to the
break and hopefully they'll trickle back
in I apologize for advertising
sandwiches that weren't present they've
been doing that last few years and I
missed the memo saying that wasn't
happening
Pat found them I'm jealous oh well next
time next time we'll get them in
Montreal and I should say that speaking
as an individual not as an IOC member so
thank you for coming back to Friday
second session we are dead mat for those
of you who are joining us remote and
we're not here in the first session this
session is going to focus on data play
discussions one of the most important
things we did in the first session was
to acknowledge that the the services
community that Taylor has done in the
last I don't know how many years but she
is retiring and will no longer be
serving as chair after this meeting we
we really want to show our appreciation
or we showed our appreciation and we
want to thank her again for contributing
to this group and getting it's helping
to get started and of course the IETF
and it's your work here as well as Court
with I triple-a thank you again so we
have a new note well Friday second
session we've been over this too many
times so we'll just skip right there
we have the same audio streaming and
video here and please join either pad
the link is in Jabra at the start of the
Jabra session for today as well as on
list we really appreciate you helping
take notes I'm on jabber and I'll look
at it as frequently as I can although
sometimes I miss things so it'd be
helpful if other people join as well
blue sheets are going around please sign
them I was trying I was madly trying to
update slides because we have an agenda
change I did manage to get the update on
the data tracker
in the slide deck but not here the
change is that excuse me is that we're
going to aim to do wrap up actually a
little earlier and try to really have be
wrapped up on the data plane discussion
by two to have then Stewart talked about
the advanced VPN or enhanced sorry not
advanced enhanced VPN which we actually
have talked about in this group many
times as the TSN over debt net service
and he has put together a framework that
covers both that case as well as other
use cases our expectation is is that you
will be talked about in the t's working
group but we think it's really important
for us to be aware of it and it actually
fills one of the gaps we had identified
in the slip slide that you'll see in a
moment so that will come that will come
before that IGP presentation
if we hit the if he still we still have
time after that we will talk about the
ICD presentation as I mentioned right
now control plane is out of scope but
it's if it helps inform what we're doing
in our information modeling and our yang
modeling having that perspective is
useful still so what are we doing here
in this session we really want to focus
on making sure that we have number one
decided on what encapsulations what are
the data playing formats look like that
we are going to use for supporting debt
net services that's the number one piece
data plane of course is larger than that
but that's the piece we wanted to really
ensure that we are we are on rock-solid
ground by the end of this meeting now
there's other parts of the data plane
that we are still left to be done like
the queuing discussion that we had this
morning or even the aggregation
discussion that was touched on where
we're a little bit of where we were we
had alternatives completed in September
of 16 we basically had a design team
look at a whole slew of different data
plan alternatives and try to come up
with a recommendation we had some
discussion of those came up with a
recommendation that was captured in the
design team individual document and an
adoption of the working of the the
design team document in March as a
working group document sorry that was
October we said that this is sort of the
direction of the working group and we've
had some discussions along the way then
we've gone back and forth on some things
and now is the time that we thought we
we say these are the
national data plane encapsulations used
in debt net one of the important things
to note is that this is the doesn't say
that there can't be future enhancements
to these data planes or future
alternatives for instance the beer and
doing debt net over beer teehee is
something we could consider but only
once we finish this the baseline work
and of course when there's support from
the working group and of course we have
to make sure that beer the beer working
group who owns the data playing is okay
with what we're doing so keep in mind
that net is more than just pref although
preface certainly folk taken or consumed
a vast majority of the data plane
discussions it's just one of the debt
net services and it is only one way of
doing service protection for example the
architecture allows for should allow a
useful life or hopefully still does
allows for alternate service protection
mechanisms and I believe network coding
is mentioned as a future possibility so
pref is just one piece
certainly we like to focus on it but we
have to keep in mind it is just one way
of delivering one of the core services
of debt net we also have congestion
protection and latency control my
personal favorite there is zero
congestion loss but that's it's personal
the favorite we have explicit routes or
route pinning and the talked about with
already service protection the core
usage scenarios we've been focusing on
is TSN over debt net and ipv4 v6 and end
service we certainly had a time where we
said that we're going to do v6 first
then worry about before later and I
think we've received enough discussion
in the working group that we really have
to look at both cases equally we can't
treat before as a second-class citizen
so what are the key questions can we
reach agreement do we have agreement on
debt net over MPLS it what the
encapsulation and that's both for the
press and non preface I think we have a
good idea of what what it looks like and
it's just let's confirm and document it
and then ensure that we're that that is
what we're doing
so the the next thing is is do we have
agreement on what the simplified IP
approaches and we expect that to be for
both v4 and v6 if we have time it would
be good to agree on approaches for IP
over MPLS there's a couple of different
ways of doing it we can either do in to
carry IP sort of the natively over MPLS
like you would do in a core instance or
we can do an l3 VPN approach we have to
talk about that with whether we want to
allow for well certainly we don't want
to preclude anything but do we want to
define both or do we don't want to focus
on one we have the queueing discussion
and that norm touched on aggregates that
Stuart touched on actually you also hit
o a.m. and transport protocol impact
which was touched on in the last meeting
by Pascal and we really don't expect to
get to that last one if we get to any of
these other topics for me and for the
chairs that's gravy as long as we hit
number one and two will accomplish the
purpose of the meeting is that my con
so and I'm not quite sure if if I should
read the the current documents with the
maybe multicast we don't know or yes
multicast or no multicast it would be
nice to have a clear yes or no for this
first round I would assume that the the
data plane covers multicast I haven't
heard any discussion about unicast all
like well okay but that basically means
yes multicast for the data plane but I
don't have to revisit all the
implications of you know the multicast
group as a destination address and you
know whether you know that also means
point to multi-point in the MPLS side so
I would expect the answer is yes I mean
those we've always said that we'd be
going past the multicast but you're
right we haven't talked at that level
and I'm saying assume I'm not saying
that we have consensus yeah I think it
would be good for this to to make an
explicit ask you know for people to have
feel confident of explicitly revisiting
this in the case of multicast I'll try
to do it for myself but if you don't
have sufficiently many people coming
back say that they feel sufficient you
know having reviewed it sufficiently to
support multicast then you may want to
not want to claim it right right so I'm
not sure I've assumed multicast press
because I don't know really how to do
that I think I think it's doable yeah I
think me I think at making sure that we
when we get to the end of the discussion
of each of these one and two we should
say does this work for multicast are we
all on board for multicast then to be
clear for MPLS I'm saying point to
multi-point for IP I'm saying multicast
addressing again I think the high level
stuff would really be when we go to the
review and have people feel confident
right maybe ask the question if you also
feel confident about right there
supporting multicast and then you make a
judgement call of whether it's
considered to be included because I can
think of thousand examples like you know
differential delay for norm fins
you know bounded latency document is
another factor that you know doesn't
exist in unicast and yada
Stuart I think if we get the
pre-function right we can probably get
multicast for almost free because it's
kind of PR without the EF having
previously had some prefs yeah and this
goes to a side conversation Stuart and I
had and and we've has been mentioned in
group before is while we look thinking
normally of the 1+1 case it actually is
a 1 plus n case and you may have n plus
1 1 plus n you may not be receiving two
packets that you have to eliminate from
but you may have n and that we certainly
have mentioned that but it doesn't get
mentioned a lot and I I suspect so what
is right that will multicast will fall
out if we get it right oops yeah ok Mike
we've spent a lot of time on on that
issue of multicast and so on and in NATO
2.1 and yes you're right it just falls
out that's great
this is really the key points for the
kickoff I had a couple of slides that
just reminded people of what IP over TSN
is and what we mean by end-to-end IP I
think the other documents other
discussions have hit on this a little
bit and and we'll get on this get more
on this and so I'm gonna skip over that
and a we previously did say that we are
not gonna aim to do end-to-end IP with
trying to modify the IP staff I think
tour list really captured the key point
earlier in the first session where he
said other groups have tried to modify
the stack and put something between the
transport protocol and IP and have all
failed and that the only option there is
IP and IP and we didn't want to go that
direction and so this this this one has
been discarded
at this point we have some ramp up
slides but we're not ready to wrap up so
with that we'll jump into the largest
presentations and I'm not sure how
you're breaking things up between with
yoni and norm whether it makes sense to
bring him in yes okay as I expected
hopes that's I forgot that they were out
of order for a little bit so that means
I'm out of order
okay this is just a slight get in order
to to have some background photo
discussions and we have added here in
this slide kit some background material
and some drawings which we think can
help can be helpful during the
discussion so this is how we have
constructed with the slides with Norman
Union so what we know is that we have
two service types one is when we are
doing clear two or TSM transport or
whether data domain or we are doing IP
transport over that mental main and we
are considering two type of
encapsulation MPLS and I think
observation this is a drawing from the
architecture draft and this is just in
order to highlight what that net
functions we have and how we have
grouped them so the first is congestion
protection it is particularly the
queuing related stuff and this is value
annuity flow identification for this
function to work properly explicit rules
which means practically traffic
engineering parts and again for it this
you need flow identification and there
were third rule which where we have
spent a lot of time and this is a real
service protection this is where we have
application elimination and in order to
livery function and this is the
functionality which required a sequence
number to be included in the transported
packets and we have three type of turf
that nodes defined H nodes relay node
and transit nodes so that was super only
background so we have proposed lies for
these topics so let's start with the
MPLS definite encapsulation we have
separated slash for MPLS
with breath and without prayer so this
is a slide to discuss what if prayer is
intended to be implemented in the data
domain and that means that you need that
that control the earth in order to being
able to serve the replication and
lamination functions so we have
practically two fields update the data
control work which provides secuence
number for packet replication and
duplicate elimination purposes and that
net service label that identifies the
rapid flow within the death net agent
relay notes and what you can see on the
right side this is just something that
we have put in the data plane solution
as a simplified representation of desync
observation formats so that would the
first slide where you might have
discussion or everybody seems to be
happy with that
for the for the control work for the
sequence number right I'm assuming the
the context is the s label not that you
label yes alright so I think that's
that's a scalability question we'll have
to ask ourselves right I'm not I haven't
try to figure out if they're maybe need
to have the context be defined for
through the T level because that's not
mistaken the aggregation and would
result in fewer interrogation will be a
separate topic so discussion um you've
got this for pref I don't see that the
key capsulation looks any different with
and without prep except that the exact
of the sequence number in the control
word everything else should be identical
that's the next slide no that's not
isn't really important that we must
always have a control word there because
it's a whole lot of work we're doing in
PW III to retrofit the fact that we
shipped a load of Ethernet without the
control word and it causes those
problems so keep in mind that this is
the generic MPLS encapsulation so this
applies both to Ethernet and IP I'm not
saying it doesn't counter your point
about if we always want control word or
not we still may always want controller
but this is equally applicable you look
for the L for an L to VPN as it is for
IP over MPLS in any any of its usage
context you you hurry to net I think
it's absolutely given we have to have
the control word there even if it's just
a bunch of zeros right you actually can
we can we finish on the previous slide
before we jump into this slide so maybe
just to finishing my point right I'm not
not the expert on the MPLS side enough
right but I think it would be good to
figure out what's the you know best
flexibilities we have to define or
assume context for the control work
right so if it's just the the fix the s
label that's probably the most simple
definition but I'm just you know worried
about the scalability of the number of
kind of control workflows we can support
because yeah I mean well it's it's it's
fairly heavy state right in terms of
trying to keep memory for the sequence
numbers you've received in the last
reasonable window of packet so they're
they're I think a lot more expensive
then let's say the per flow Q s thing we
may want to have for the bounded latency
so we want to be careful of if we have
anything that could make it you know for
aggregates like for I mean we've been
thinking of the 28 bits as something
that is fairly large enough for
aggregates right for all the traffic
from let's say one ingress no to one
egress node and so yeah if the context
of these could be defined more flexibly
so that we can support them on
aggregates that would help us a lot with
yeah optimizing hardware resources and
emails just in response to to Alice's
point about scalability the scalability
is exactly the same as both for pseudo
wires and for layer 3 VPN s and I would
like to you know just point out that we
have extensive experience in the field
that that the the routers work fine with
the in terms of scalability with the
current definition of of that label so
I'm not aware of implementations in l3
VPN equipment where the sequence number
is actually used to do per packet
deduplication and that's basically what
brings in the state requirements so any
evidence of that to work at the same
scale is the well-known large number of
l3 VPNs
that could be supported that would be
great input because right now I don't
think it exists no so you'll note that
there's multiple T levels so we
certainly could there's nothing that
precludes an implementation from adding
more labels if it needs more context and
based on the control plane we want to
just or or the management plane you'd
want to ensure that it doesn't preclude
that yeah it translates to control plane
or management plane
trying to bring it up from the
perspective that you know Stewart or
other NPLs expert would jump up and
saying yeah that what might be you know
what changed the control plane to imply
that type of semantics that it would be
you know that the context would be the
the T word or no you can't do it even
not in the forwarding plane that
semantics the existing control planes I
think are pretty flexible in terms of
that so so yeah I mean I think this is
the right way to go on if we end up with
and I think we could here to skating
them it much earlier than we do in
pseudo wires if we do well at a context
label who re spin the design but there's
nothing fundamental involvement but do
you think that even with this forwarding
plane the interpretation later on could
be that the context or the sequence
number is that he labeled no I think
think think I'm be look at we're jumping
ahead cuz I'm sure you're gonna talk
about aggregation I think we'll do
aggregation first sure and an
aggregation will will save this because
you can you basically get a new new
seven years of labor's so the one
related topic that I expected to come up
and I even have a spreadsheet that I
sent around to a few people ready to go
was is the number of bits in the control
word sufficient for the data rates were
expecting and so losing my voice
apparently when we did the analysis
offline we identified that there's a
spectrum where there's absolutely no
issues and it's only when we started
talking about flows at about 400 gig so
this is a flow of 400 gig at 64 byte
packets that we started running into
issues with the number of bits we have
available and again that's not a link
that's a flow and when we get there I
guess we'll just have a different
slightly different modification on the
design but it'll be awhile when it right
I think what we'll end up with is an
extended control word that you know it
becomes a 64-bit control word
then northen are we saying we're good
with 16 bits can i show that it's an art
equation of this line okay let me let me
know that I have it here no let me say
I've got no problem with doing more bits
I think people need to understand what
we're using this for okay
the implication is that we're using this
to eliminate duplicates okay if we're
worried so the implication is that I can
remember which if we're for the
implication of 16 bits is that I can
remember among the last 32 K packets
that have gone by which of them I've
seen in which of them I haven't seen so
that I can pass the ones that I haven't
seen okay so that implies that I've got
at least 32 kilobits of memory at 400
gigabits per second and I can remember
so I can tell which ones I want to pass
in which ones I don't pass okay so it's
not just sequencing it's not just the
things we've used this before and yes
it's true that it's some that very high
data rates per flow I could overflow
that number but keep in mind that
anything more than 16 bits assumes that
I can remember which of the last 32 K
packets I've seen if you want to go to
28 bits that implies that I can remember
exactly which of the last two to the
27th packets I have seen and I haven't
seen okay my opinion is that that's
absurd okay that I'm not going to do
that in any foreseeable future okay now
I don't have I in spite of that I'm not
going to object if people say they want
to have more bits than that but it's
absolutely essential that we have an OP
for 16 bits only because I want to
interoperate with existing equipment
that has only 16 bits so I have to know
when I see when I go from 2 to the 60 2
to the 16th minus 1 to 0 I have to know
whether to reap treat that as a new
packet or as something I've already seen
ok
so every device has to be able to run in
16-bit mode whatever we do that would be
also good for the TSM in Turkey so I
think this this goes back to a more
precise specification of you know the
behavior of the duplicate elimination
right because in my mind I was assuming
something like I would definitely never
have more than 16 bits in the bit mask
of the you know packet numbers I've
received but it might be sliding window
within the 28 bit so you know everybody
may have their own assumptions right so
I haven't tried to figure out if all the
things that people typically do when
they have larger sequence number but
obviously only a smaller part which is
active how much better that is over
saying model everything is fine with a
16 bit and we may get very close to you
know overrun there right so I think
that's that's an important design
parameter but yeah I mean I'm not sure
how fast we can work out all these
details but yeah definitely if we can at
least start agreeing that there will be
never more than 16 bit you know for a an
elimination function and whether or not
we then still need a larger sequence
numbers making that relative or
shrinking it to 16 bit all good
questions I have to say I was assuming
we did add the sliding window approach
and I was assuming the sliding window
approach where the number where the
number 16 is an implementation choice
and norm is saying right so I think
we're we're aligned on that but no
matter what we decide it's got to be
documented so let's do it
absolutely agree with all of it I think
what we're headed for here is that the
size of the window and the size of the
sequence number are parameters that we
set up when we establish what I would
call it a pseudo wire but whatever we
going to call this
being a name what this thing is is it
you know debt was it sad ECW alright do
you see that when we set up a DCW at
each node along the path that's treating
it as a DCW most real a note we need to
establish the parameters of that
specific instance of DCW and in the
terms of the control word and stuff we
just need to make sure that there's
enough space in there for the largest we
think we're gonna need right and we
think that the space available now is
sufficient for everything I think it's
in the yellow band yes and will disrupt
will define a new DCW if we have to okay
Yanni's in queue okay alright girl
yeah it's 23 Monty yeah so I agree what
what said about the what norm said and
what's worse said about the sequence
number so so even even the current draft
the working group traffic sir says that
the the amount actually used pcs is
something that needs to be accurate by
the control plane and the the current
hardware that I'm aware that that
actually do packet replication
elimination so T dot one CP and and
which are fixed to a 16-bit a sequence
number they actually are able to
remember on a couple of thousand of
packets so they have this D sliding
window and they have a history buffer
off of only a few thousand packets
that's how it works
should've done simply just to your
comment all as there is a specification
for the detail behavior it is described
in dot on CV so either to that one CB
has a definite different definition
microphone we are people you per month
so the comment from the floor is that
just because you know to you has done
something doesn't mean that's what we're
doing and that's absolutely correct and
that's why we have to have agreement
make sure our document captures it and I
think yoni you're saying that our
document already captures this point so
do i extent okay okay let me jump to the
north yes okay you should have control
yeah yep so norm is approaching the mic
norm then in just on what you just said
Lou it would be nice if we interoperate
well with that one CD so unless we have
a good reason to do something else I'd
like to see us do the same thing the
thing we need to keep in mind though is
that we're probably gonna have to
operate this over very large wide area
networks for some of the applications
and that's where we need to be careful
about
yeah and interworking functions are
really important but we should figure
out what's right for dead net first and
then it that goes to the complexity of
the networking function so norm saying
right let's try to do have good mic
discipline we definitely have people
remote yoni could you hear either normal
or Stewart's comments no but I know what
they were saying
well I think what we said was no
gratuitous differences but differences
if they are needed right I think we have
agreement on that thank you
great all right
okay no prep so that is the nice
discussion topic so if we do not have
ratification and elimination function
for in order delivery then we don't need
to stay friends laughter so the
discussion point here is whether to
include always about that I just want to
to echo what Stuart said earlier when we
first came to the slide we just finished
some work in the pals working group
which was the result of routers doing
the wrong thing as a result so they're
not being the control word for Sue the
wires so we absolutely must contain the
control word even if it's just 32 bits
of zeros you know through two bits is
cheap and we got a lot of functionality
out of it and we absolutely need it so
you're also needed for your OEM if we're
going to have a standard OEM method but
yeah we've been through a whole load of
pain as soon as you launch any of these
packets to a non detonate part of the
world if you're ever going to go across
it those packets could go anywhere and
be completely miss ordered if you don't
have that control work there so please
keep the control word a career so that
covers the case of Ethernet a layer 2
VPN where we control word is currently
used pretty much everywhere there's one
case in evpn where it's not and it's I
think agreement from field experience
that's a bad idea and that's what that's
what I think you're referring to a
palace of cleaning up
so that's l2
VPN so that's pretty clear so that's one
case of MPLS without graph we also have
l3 VPN and one more case after that but
it looks like Stewart you want to say
something yeah III I think that if ever
you want to be in complete control of
what happens to your packets you
probably need a sequence not a a control
word to do isolation so but maybe I'm
jumping too far ahead well you know
there are plenty of l3 VPNs that don't
run with control word and have good
isolation and they and they have they're
subjected to be CMP so the thing you
need to be really careful is do you wish
to control whether the underlay
does he CMP on you or not right and yes
these you have to recognize there's a
lot of bad Hardware out there yes there
there there is a lot of bad Hardware out
there which makes terrible assumptions
about what it can do regarding a CMP the
only way for us to be in control of that
situation is by including the control
word even for IP and that only gives you
partial control because some of them say
if I see some zeros here then I'm going
to assume it's an ethernet and you see
every way way way deep into the packet
it's a pretty bad world out there right
yeah I think the and this is as a
contributor or not as a chair I think we
have to be really careful if we start
changing how IP over MPLS works in the
data playing that we have to be really
conscious of what we're doing and make
sure we have really wide buy-in so if we
do decide to go that way we really have
to be talking to the MPLS working group
on this well I I just want to point out
that it's really not a change for how
you do ice because this is going to be
IP in MPLS over IP right why right okay
just so IP IP IP over MPLS today there
are two different ways one is I seen the
for instance which is directly mapped
onto a
in fact it's directly about to a label
that's one way the other way is with l3
VPNs and there's also no control word
there but there is an assumption about
no one cares about the order of delivery
ish and people expect the package to be
CMP so we may be in a different we'll
probably are in a different world from
the established IP VPN and IP of MPLS
world and this is part of the reason why
enhanced VPN is a good topic forties by
the way is is that that's a good good
hider discussion and takes your charter
[Laughter]
fix your charter no I mean if I remember
correctly the the control word and the
zero bits were also done as you know way
for worker rounding on something was
broken in you know the way MPLS was used
right so I think we've prior evidence
that if we do understand problems and
you know they create more ugliness and
what we want to do then let's bring it
on the table I'm not sure if any of the
things that Stewart mentioned would have
you know reasonable additional
workarounds or else we're saying we
don't care about you know broken
equipment that's just documented a
proper coordinate right it is true that
my memory is a reson IP pseudo wire
defined also but at Stewart and Auntie
may know better I don't I'm not sure
anyone ever used it
however implemented it so so I think the
main point here is is if we really think
we need to do something different than
what is typically done in the data plane
here we should be careful to coordinate
with the folks that own the data plane
which in this case is the MPLS working
group so I think what we heard here is
without pref for layer 2 VPN this is a
no-brainer
to always include the debt net control
word is that correct does anyone object
to that great with IP I heard that there
is a preference to use the control word
from some
people I'm not sure we have it's clear
to get that we have agreement in the
room because we didn't get here from all
people so I think it would be good to
ask the folks that are here to questions
of do we want to use the control word
for l3 VPNs and do IP yeah but sorry l3
VPN implies IP so question one do we
want to use control word and l3 VPNs in
question two is that we want to use
control words when we're not doing l3
VPN but I as I'm saying this I realize
the first question is is that we want to
support IP over MPLS only via l3 VPNs or
or both ways that are supported today so
let's have a discussion on what way we
think we would prefer to do IP over MPLS
okay so very generic and maybe this is
not a permitted opinion but you know
whether we do Paula for ian's are
permitted I would always like to have a
control word even if somebody doesn't
need the resilience of pref because I
very much like the OEM aspect of it and
so I think that would help a lot there
are just to clarify there are ways to do
oh I am on MPLS I understand that there
are all these type of other wonderful
subnet layer specific om technologies
and I'm saying that if I want to figure
out what can I do with detonate itself
you know across all the different
possible and capsulation forms the most
simple one can I use your name yes sorry
right so I guess but they all come with
a variety of issues right and I think
the control world is really a very
strong you know operational feature as
well for for didn't itself and not only
for press
well I'll make one observation there is
we're talking about that net over MPLS
not dead not over pseudo wires so we
have a control word that's part of it
but so does MPLS so if there's a
mechanism that we're going to use it's
okay to use MPLS mechanisms and
fact particularly when we get to the tea
level we're gonna have to use those
mechanisms right so we shouldn't you
shouldn't say that that is only you know
understood I saw it's a good refinement
right if the underlying you know
mechanism we're using does provide a
control word that is equal or better
than what we could have in a dead net
specific header I'm very happy to use
that okay skew it so I guess the right
way to think about this is we we almost
certainly need to have a VPN type
approach in the system because HPE H
nodes may well be handling two different
clients on two different term services
we also need to consider that we will
probably have to run prep on some of
these so the right way to approach it is
probably to define VPN over with the
control word in there and if there are
specific cases where we want to simplify
that by taking bites out of the of the
header then they should be they should
sort of stand on their own merits but we
can do everything if we have a VPN label
and a control word in there you know
we're kind of golden as far as I can see
we may put ship a bunch of zeros but we
can solve all the cases and E and one
other thing I just want to point out is
that it makes implementations simpler if
we make the header the same in all cases
right can I say something please
yeah so alright you don't if you don't
leave the queue I don't know we don't
know that you're backing here okay so uh
in my previous life so the experience
will start the the last option is best
better so echoing what Andy was saying
that that is do a unified heater
constructive Tiff's as possible so it
just makes life easier even if you are
not using at some point so that we can
work around with some some mechanism
control plane or reserving bits or
something
again and of course since you have to
configure this you have to set it up and
expect this is going to go through there
the hardware can just skip all these
zeros it doesn't have to sort of past
them and figure out that they're there
it but it just gives us a sort of simple
okay so I think I heard that there's a
strong preference to always use the same
format meaning always keep the DCW
present I'm gonna go out of order in
terms of questions just because it seems
to match the flow of the conversation
but if it just Peters out maybe we'll go
there oh go back to it in terms of
support for IP over MPLS do we want to
support an l3 VPN approach or an
enhanced l3 VPN approached first Stewart
I think that's what I was trying to
propose before just because if ever we
need prep with I with with IP we will
need the sequence number which means we
will need the control word which means
that and we probably want some context
for it so what I've been saying is let's
always go assume VPN which provides
context control where which provides
context and then the IP and we're not to
optimize away those two those bits
okay so separate your control word for a
moment yes not talking about control
word right we always want to say we're
doing in order to support the IP over
MPLS do we always want to use an l-3 VPN
technique that is what I've been
suggesting because it might think it
makes our life a lot simpler and it
makes everything a lot more flexible
okay and I'm actually saying do we want
to do it first and that's gonna ask only
but that's fine how you want only that's
good yeah certainly first if someone can
build a case is Stewart still if someone
gonna build okay
/ optimizing away those 64 by about 64
bits then great but I think we should
start by building the general solution
which will cover most of our
applications okay Andy I would also like
to point out that without the VPN
approach meaning the s label the flow
identification becomes much more
difficult are there any objections with
having the initial approach to
supporting IP over MPLS be within the
context of an l3 VPN any objections I
see no hands in the room that's good or
that's fine is there anyone who would
like to see that our initial definition
includes native IP over native MPLS like
you would do in a core instance today so
if you're running in a router today and
you're an Ellie are and you're not
running VPNs
you would just map IP and temp Els does
anyone want to see that as part of the
initial definition of IP a debt net IP a
over MPLS I see no hands
hopefully it means that people are
paying attention and they're just not
interested in that so one thing is we're
not precluding that in the future and it
does seem like a reasonable initial use
case all right so I think we have
unfinished hmm I think I think we have
MPLS finished I'm not sure I got all the
good some rice make sure the minutes
have a summary of that okay so the next
discussion point is about ith
observation here we have the
scales during the winter in the
simplified IP approach and that would be
that they are using the application
native encapsulation format so the
dotnet encapsulation is the unmodified
IP stack and here we can use a sixth
uproar in order to identify flows of
course we can make white card on it and
that means that there will be no
segments number included so the impact
of that that there is no sequence number
included that as you can see here in the
slide this upper break and two and prep
scenario this is what is not the case
for the simplified IP approach what we
have is the case below where in each
segment ring or subnet the appropriate
Mohamed's will ensure pref inside that
link or subnet so how the encapsulation
looks like so this is how a simplified
IP packet looks like so we have a
payload and it is in a IP transport
rather like UDP they have the IP header
data link and physical and we can use
the six that were in order to match the
flows and we have this flow
identification per hope and the standard
route I think had a processing at each
hop so we are just touching the TTL and
the checksum infant and to implement
that functions with the simplified IP
then for the congestion protection we
need the flow identification and we can
do that with the six double match we can
have the explicit rules based on the
sextuple mesh with some policy-based
routing and we are not supporting the
service protection like replication
elimination and in order delivery
because we have no sequence so that
would be the scenario
maybe it's good to show the next slide
just before just to see history so this
is something that is not updated in the
current data playing solution version so
it is boot of day from that perspective
so this is there something to be added
to that I'm pretty sure actually only
updated it last night in reception
it was just removed yeah just released
but not I did the simplified IP so so he
hit the red X but X is that okay okay as
I pointed out in in my talk earlier if
we want to do press we really do need a
sequence number and my draft provided an
encapsulation which allows us to do
press for IP which still conforms to the
simplified model so I would much prefer
that to this so maybe we should take it
as from the perspective of host first
and then other cases other places where
we would use IP because because you
mentioned that host was out of he
weren't proposing it for the host that's
correct okay I'm cool with that
is that does that work yes Stuart so
[Music]
Stuart
so what we're proposing here is
basically a Ciel's throughout the
network directing us to queues and
nothing else is that is that where we
are do we have the network diagram you
have the network layer I think we need
that for the discussion so but this
means that where the red circles are
this is very very to simplify the IB
encapsulation between the segments which
is just a highlighting did that blue
Tannas
inside that you can have additional
encapsulations you can add sequence
number but your prayer function will be
limited between that blue stuff so here
in this figure for example you have
three prayer domain and they are
operating independently you cannot do
that you are replicating in the first
domain and then eliminating in the
second one so that what we just wanna
measure on we're all actually in sync
here so this is the case where basically
we're not doing anything different from
what we do today we're doing a an ACL to
use to map the packet into a queue at
each hot where we care and the packets
go as regular IP in order so this is
just unmodified IP with a bit of ACL
mapping to cubes except now we're
mapping into debt net and I'm not sure
if you want to call it ACL or PBR but
either way it's a rule in there in the
router
yoni is in here before you norm yeah so
I want to point out so we did discuss
this interim tree quite extensively the
same same situation so assume for
example a deployment there you have TSN
Ethernet TSN in segment one and segment
three and then you have the dead net
MPLS encapsulation in segment two so
within each segment and and between two
segments you have a router so you are
doing a routing between segments but
party within each network segment as
Paula said you can do all the service
protection of things until to a point
when you reach the TT routing hop for
example that is between the segment and
and and that place is somewhat what
non-trivial in the sense that that
because because each of the segments are
independent more or less so so if if
basically it's usually in the simple
deployment it ends up to a case that you
have a single point that that you go
from between segments if this will like
replication taken place in segment one
and segment two a real estate those
replication eliminations are separate
eight they don't share any state in
between each other so it's a bit more
than just ACLs so Andy I would like to
ask that we separate the discussion of
what's in the red circles at the end
points and what's in the red circles the
network because I'd like to argue that
those are not necessarily the same all
right and and in fact that's exactly
what the proposal is is that the end
point would be limited to the sub
Network alone yes which is which we're
saying is for it right for example TSN
in the other places you might have a
technology like IP over MPLS yeah it's
like we just described or IP over MPLS
over IP that's also yes so yeah I would
have been happier if those circles have
been different colors because just
because all four circles are red someone
could get the impression that they're
all the exact same encapsulation okay
right and the same treatment hmm and you
know someone could get the impression
just by looking at that diagram as it is
now that that all four circles get the
insane capsulation and the exact same
treatment
yeah that's not necessarily so at one
level at the at one level they do get
the same treatment at another level they
don't that's right so it's a it at the
IP layer they're getting the same
treatment and I subnet layer they're
getting different treatment absolutely
yes so I just want to make sure that
we're all on the same page with respect
to this diagram yeah thanks
told us yeah so I'm still trying to
understand the sixth up what we already
were chatting about that in before and
I've got this phantom pain enough you
know 10-year old technologies but trying
to use dscp for something that they
weren't anyway you know I'm having
trouble hearing you okay yeah now I got
you know the phantom pain phone from old
technologies we're trying to use the
ACPs to indicate you know different
paths through the network and other
things there weren't meant to be used
for so I'm a little bit trying to
understand what it would be an example
of having you know the same five to call
only different in the DHCP field to do
different things in that net to map that
they don't okay well I mean if it's if
it's also keep in mind that maybe it's
not necessarily one value mapping you
know you could have a few vscp values
mapping to a single flow no no if that
is fine but that basically would be in
my case a five type of mesh and then you
basically have the intra flow Q s
behavior which is how we define it in in
you know our Q s architecture write PHP
s can you know as an AF can have
multiplicative server architecture do
you mean the diff server architecture
well yeah I mean if you look at AF right
where packets are having a of 41 42 43
and so on right it's one flow right but
it's basically you know that the PHP is
defined through different DHCP classes
that's fine right but that is not a
sixth Apple classification to me the
flow is classified by five couples and
menya sure you can use multiple DSPs but
so what is your idea of a six type of
classification as I said right is there
any example we have the same five purple
two different DSC PS and they're matched
to I don't know different flows is it a
observe does it today no no for example
you can you can use different classes
there's no you can use EF and yeah EF
and AF on the same flow just focus yes
of course but that but and they're gonna
receive very different reason and then a
but that's one flow that's one flow
that's five type of classification is
that's right so we're not talking about
of what a DIF server flow is we're
talking about a dead flow right and a
dead net flow can have multiple DSC
piece but the flow is identified by five
couples do you want different treatment
based on the DHCP
course that's intra flow that's not
interflow right so I think we're arguing
semantics from a debt net level those
would be different flow different yet
net flows yes and then I think the debt
net flow is identified by a five couple
and of course inside the debt net flow
there is dscp and the SCP is treated as
we've always done it or we define new
dscp treatments in the absence okay let
me put this angel I don't know what to
do with a debt net flow that with
different priority levels in a single
flow because I don't know how to
guarantee in the in latency now there's
nothing wrong with having different code
points now in 802 we do have that
situation where you have a layer two
priority which is different on different
packets and the rule that we use there
is that it has to have the flow ID and
it has to have the right priority or in
this case the SCP in order to get the
debt net bounded latency zero congestion
loss service if you have a packet in a
flow that has the wrong dscp I would
expect it to not get the same treatment
the same queueing the same QoS that the
other stuff has and so that's not a
problem I don't think maybe just one
more comment is that in the flow
information model you have a flow rank
flow rank and this is exactly what you
can encode in DHCP for example I give me
any example so let's say we're saying
what what I think is correct is we're
classifying flows by up by the five top
line each of these fields and the five
couple can of course be you know
wildcard what do you think we can't do
right inside the flow we can use all the
DHCP s as we want to define sure if we
want to put it right is a right if we
don't include dscp
in the
NetFlow definition they will all receive
the same debt service independent of
dscp so if you want to have different if
you want to have different service from
debt net but that's not the flow
classification that's a different that's
a debt net flow classification we're not
trying to use the don't use the the dscp
flow and sub flow definition where we
have this is the debt net flow
definition so if you want you can think
of it as am how do you map dscp the SCP
aware flows to debt net flows or to get
to the debt net service
so we're saying well here's maybe this
is a better way to phrase it for you is
that these map to different debt net
services does that help you think you I
think so Stewart I think the right way
to address this is just is to start with
what the application is I mean normally
what you do is you classify a flow
according to the by couple and then map
it to a service level using dscp
really it may be legitimate to have
different dscp values within a blow as
absolutely great I think we need to
start by understanding why you'd want to
do it then I think the whole thing will
just fold out and we'll all understand
what we're doing so start from the
application point Pascal did he want I
think here in Cube yes we shall stick
pointing out that maybe the application
flow is the five topple but the debt
that flow the thing that that net cares
about inside that flow yes is the sixth
of off so it might be that I'm selling
video with some ads on it maybe the ads
flies with normal internet but the video
flies in my dream world the point is you
I'm surprised that you're surprised
because because it's normal the death
net filters out what goes through the
deadly fight and may be worth multiple
that the pipes that net doesn't care
about the overall application flow just
about the piece that it needs to treat
which can be a subset of the overall
application flow and it really strike
that based on the GCP and put it on the
right pipe and that's it don't see why
you okay so I it's
you know I'm defining my debt net stuff
I have one at the same five couple I'm
saying okay this dscp your map to this
debt net flow goes across one part of
the network the other deep dscp in the
same five title goes another path
alright that's what I'm worried about
I think it's a bad idea but you know I
think just get TSV review get get TSV
review on this right they're not only
responsible for congestion control but
also for the QoS architecture yeah so it
may be that it's not that it uses a
different path it's that it has a
different reliability on it so you might
have one for example you use pref and
the other one not yes but the whole
point is right now the model that you
have allows everything to be applied to
it that would be possible to apply to
different flows for the other five
tuples right so for sure and we're
building a toolbox and if someone wants
you or cool bucks you know right if I
have I have some strong opinion because
of you know qsr routing in the past
right I think that's a bad idea but
don't worry about me just let's have you
know what he has via review on this and
then I think they'll tell you what the
constraints are used to follow maybe
just one addition is that an application
always have some regular traffic and the
definite traffic they might have regular
traffic the applications are usually
same kind of like where they're going to
use the same five to do it so I agree
with Taurus about we need to go and talk
to our transport area colleagues that's
the first thing and the second thing is
I think we absolutely have to have that
discussion with them in the context of a
real example that crystallized it so
that we know this is not a sort of
theoretical thing that we might do it is
very unusual to have different classes
within the same five couple in existing
applications and please count on my help
to bring up the most horrible examples
of what we could do with the current
definition it looks and I'm sure that
I'm sure that that you're thinking also
of good examples right which I think
would all work with the five couple
definition I'm saying that I'm worried
about the really bad things you can do
with the six type of definition so the
if we
make it five tuple to me that means we
ignore dscp
so the dscp has no influence on on
selection of a debt net service is that
what you're saying oh no so what I think
Lera fide well I think we've always had
the model where you have you know insert
flows but then for example as an AF you
had basically within the flow different
code points right that's your pair hope
behavior if you look for example in the
8th class so if I have a debt net flow
which is defined by a five tuple hmm do
I provide any different debt service
based on dscp yeah of course I mean you
have to have some some some
understanding how you define for the
service the expected you know pro-hop
behavior right and that's basically the
perab behavior is defined by the debt
net service so we have yeah but you need
to express it typically through the dscp
right I know we're just pressing it here
based on the fight on the flow ID
wherever our flow ID is tells us what
service we're gonna get right but it
seems like you also want to be able
within a flow to have you don't want to
have any relative behavior between
different packets all right that's what
AF gives you for example that means you
need to have a per packet marking within
a flow right now if you're basically
saying that all packets in a flow are
always treated equally then of course
you don't need to code points in the
flow but the the pure fact that you're
trying to do this with you know without
relying on the existing architecture for
the code point marking would be another
good question to TSV actually that's
exactly the question we're debating is
whether it should or not I I still I'm
not sure I understood toilets where you
point you're making but it's it seems
much simpler to me that we seem to be
getting wrapped around the axle we're
not trying to change how dscp
and how the meanings of the five couple
are the meanings of dscp we don't route
based I mean we're out based on the five
couple when it comes to assigning a
given packet and deciding what how I'm
going to treat it in terms of class of
service not where I route it but how I'm
going to treat it in terms of classes
serve
the VA we have today the option of
people look at the five couple and
assign it change the dscp people look at
the five couple and treat it as
something else other than dscp says now
we don't need to change that included in
the definition of what it means to if
we're doing per-flow class of service
and we don't always need to know the
flow when we're doing the class of
service stuff when we're doing the
cueing we don't always have to
distinguish one flow from another
sometimes dscp is all we need to know
and we just defend at the edges of the
network making sure we don't get bogus
traffic in a dscp that's that'll get
polluted if we have excess traffic in it
just keep redoing things we don't if we
don't have dscp in something as we
consider as part of a debt net service
we can't use dscp to trigger groups
which is rare things we have to in we
have to allow dscp to be used in
identifying the flow but many people
won't need to do that I think that's
absolutely correct but I don't think
that's what what you said I agree with a
hundred percent I don't think that's
what oralists was saying no but I mean
norm was also saying something that I
don't see in evidence here which is for
example that you're routing on the five
couple there's nothing that basically
what limit no I mean if we base so we
select paths that net selects paths
based on a debt net service and the
different services like the six top will
right right any of which that can be
wild carded anything in there can be
wild carded in the past selection part
of dead net how many mean how does it
decide which traffic to map to a path
based on the debt net flow ID so so so
quickly do you think you want to have
support within a single debt net flow of
packets having different DCPS
but I think this says is that we can
identify a debt net service so
independently provide different service
levels at different QoS different delays
different production levels we can do
that based on any of these fields I
understand that but that wasn't my
question
what's that that was not my question I
think I answered your answer your
question oh you're saying I can I can
map a flow to you know any individual
service I understand that I'm saying do
you think we need within a single debt
net service support for multiple dscp si
no norm doesn't I I'm saying we allow it
or less from a toolbox perspective I
think this says it's allowed from a
toolbox perspective whether or not I'm
gonna actually use it or not that's a
different story for example I can
imagine limiting the rate of the full
frames on a video and the full frames on
the video take a debt net path through
the network to make absolutely sure that
they get there and the other frames take
some other path through the network
which is not guaranteed debt net service
sure yeah I would afraid I would phrase
it as I think different dscp si might
give different probability of delivery
yes
for example right for us that's a real
case okay
comments through the simplified idea so
I've been trying to build a mental model
of why you would want to do this so
let's see if I'm sort of if I test this
weather is my molds correct if we have
an application and as far as the
application is concerned the five top
will just really finds a tunnel to get
it from one part of the application to
the other and within that application
you have packets of different priorities
oh and different characteristics needed
then you distinguish between them using
the disso code point rather than the
standard method which would be to set up
a different UDP port or something or
other and run two parallel sessions so
is that is that model the right model
because I kind of need a mental model to
understand why we're why we're doing
this because it's not standard behavior
and I'm finally here the standard
behavior in different AF classes sorry
we have different AF code points right
you've had different co-pays you don't
normally have them for the same five
couple normally you take the five couple
and then map them to it to add if served
class rather than try and distinguish
within the five couple and I'm just
trying to understand why we would want
to do that what would cause us to set a
different code point and I the only
thing I can think of is that this is a
really legacy application but that wants
to run on foo and we're actually
substituting UDP IP instead of foo and
the application has different service
characteristics and we're using the dish
so code pointer map between the two
rather than traditional thing which
would be to put the two of them on a
different port and hence have a
different five couple maybe this is
maybe I'm wrong maybe there's something
else but I just want a model MIT let's
turn it around in tour let's do you
think there's being being more in the
TSV area I'm looking to you help us out
is there ever a case where you think
that it would be normal for an
application to use the same flow five
tuple but to mark some traffic with one
dscp and mark other traffic with another
dscp
and if so why just so I get my models
right so I had
followed the laid stuff right I had a
draft five or six years earlier up where
we're doing exactly describing the
benefits of that but you know the
details of the qsr weren't really
matching up that's simply exactly the
differentiated drop priorities which AF
has but then you look at the details of
how it works so yeah I mean you have the
iframes you want to have them through
all the time and you can do it very nice
I mean it's all non-deterministic right
which is why as I said you know if norm
tells me here and don't need this with
deterministic behavior
I couldn't refute that right but yeah I
mean the different priorities right IPV
so yeah so that's sort of exactly the
case that this I think is aimed at yeah
no no and and I'm mostly worried about
the definition part right I was there
always expecting that we can have
multiple DSC pieces in the flow but I
didn't consider the exactly because of
this reason I didn't consider the dscp
to be part of the flow definition right
I was always considering that if an
application has a five couple all the
DSC piece are always part of that five
couple that's kind of the application
level flow of course when you're saying
oh we don't care about application level
flows we just met you know whatever we
want to detonate level flows that's a
fine toolbox stuff I agree with you on
that I'm just not sure what tool box is
you know the ITF would like us to do
layout right I mean there are two boxes
that make it very easy to shoot you in
the feet and that's typically what the
owners of those areas or so may want to
put constraints on but I exit I don't
know the current policy which is I said
let's take it offline talk with the TSV
chairs I sent the email and put you on
so that we can have that quickly
resolved so right now we are delivering
service on that net flow basis so if we
wanted to do things like give different
drop probability to different packets
within the same five tuple we would have
to call it a different flow and I
suspect if we called it a sub flow that
would work better for you well oh but I
okay can you go back to the slide that
had no no but yeah that is well but no
no I wasn't even sure that it meant this
is a one-to-one mapping right I was
expecting that you could map all these
different DSC PS or all the dscp with a
star to one that NetFlow you could do
that also
right and then base
turn without saying right and then that
that of course is fine right I mean
we're saying that it would equally be
fine to say you must always have all DSC
PS of a five tuple within one that net
flow and that seem to not be acceptable
here I'm not sure why but I thought you
said it wasn't accept all right no no I
was just saying I only need to
distinguish the dead net flow by a five
tuple and then it's basically you know a
service class definition of the dead net
flow let's say I'm ignoring the dscp
because the applications sent me
and I'm going to you know do one service
or I'm treating as exactly as the DSC PS
are to be treated according to RFC
standards right if it's AF in there
right and obviously oh you must do the
right DHCP to get deterministic I mean
that that sounds like logical to me
right it's a different order it's not at
its all right of the service one reason
we have to consider this now is what we
do now what we're doing right now we
want to make it so it's not incompatible
with things that come down the pike so
if we said we're going to only use the
five tuple and ignore dscp it would
preclude a debt net service that was the
SCP aware I don't think so it would
because hardware would be built that
ignores it why because that's what will
happen because if we say you're going to
only do flow classification on these
five it won't look at those bits so we
could say those bits have to be zero and
that in the future we may allow a debt
that's a dscp aware debt net service
that does something different and we'll
figure out what that is down the road so
either we ignore the bits we say the
bits have to be set to a specific
pattern to allow for the future or we
allow arbitrary bits in our in the
mapping that's really what it comes down
to and I think it would be good to get a
sense of the room which are those we
want to go down I I think the reaction
you were getting in terms of just doing
five is that that breaks diffserv the
ability to use this sort of code points
ever in the future no I'm so and as we
don't think that's I think no no I but I
think you know when you want to emulate
something let's say
cadet net service with the AF class
right whether or not they would be good
deterministic example right and you have
a 41 and a 42 right and obviously these
have different drop priorities right
there in one queue and they have
different drop priority right that's
what you want to model so now let's say
that how would you express this in the
current model are these two flows is
this one flow for debt net it would be
two flows and then we would expect in
the control plane to somehow associate
it to that they share share bandwidth
just like we do bandwidth sharing in
other cases okay I mean so far we
thought this is fully you know just a
forwarding plane thing and now you're
outsourcing that we're supposed to be
coming up with control plane
requirements no no but I think saying
architectural II we had this all working
in the forwarding plane and now you're
saying I can just only reconstruct this
when I'm having a control plane
stitching together I'm not saying it's
wrong I can't do any of this without a
management plan or control plane that's
where we're doing a model no no but I
think if if you would so if we want to
do bad that's one solution I'm showing I
have no no no I'm trying to get to the
point that so I could basically say that
I can ignore in the forwarding plane the
DSC PS if I you know as a separate
lookup if I think as you're saying I'm
doing 2/6 Apple lookups and then I'm
basically having in the in the
forwarding model the thing okay so these
this one flow needs to be treated like
AF 41 the other like AF 42 right even
though you're not doing the dscp lookup
separately right so I think that's
that's the difference in the model right
I was thinking of doing a five type of
lookup and then basically you know once
you have the flow you know the the
details of the dscp called Point Lookout
are the same unchanged as their today
and you're saying I think that we're
just doing the lookup of the full six
topple in this example and so at this
point in time we don't need to know
about the the packet dscp anymore but we
expect in the same PHP based on so yeah
I guess that's that's kind of the
modeling question and I guess that that
would get back to again I'm not the
expert I'm just the I was a victim right
yes I say six tuple we think we can
support basically any mode that TSV
wants me okay
swine it was a nation of the good things
you think you can do with it and I
completely agree that we want to do
these good things right I'm worried
about the fact that you can also do the
bad things like you know oh yeah so the
question I think it's a good question
for the working group is do we say we
want to do this now the six tuple
includes six tuple it's the definition
or do we say we're only going to do five
tuple and we have to have we ignore the
value in the dscp
or that it has to have a specific value
so that we allow for use in the future
no I don't think we can take the
decision to a day we need to write this
down well we can we can get the sense of
the room so the plan is is we're gonna
get the sense of the room on these
topics Association and then and then
write something down and then do the
normal review that you would do I think
you have someone else a couple of other
people who haven't spoken so let's give
them like there's there's early TSV
review right we don't have to wait no no
we're talking about review of the draft
like the next version not when the work
know that but that's what I meant right
if you have TSV questions you don't feel
comfortable about waiting for the isg
review they offer your TSD review at any
point in time to clear these questions I
wouldn't do it way before last call
Stuart you know behind you that have not
opened what's let's hear from them hi
sorry on Schneider NEC just a quick
comment I didn't I don't want to derail
the conversation here but I think I saw
some implementations where actually a
forwarding element is only looking at
the DHCP value maybe at the beginning of
flow and then for caching and
performance purposes looks up only the
five tuple and then for what q so
mandating a DHCP lookup for every packet
might be very hard for general adoption
on every forwarding element so you might
want to consider that useful feedback
thank you I just want to say if we do
five double match then how will we
classify a dead net service when the
packet is coming in and request by
movement a dead net service how do we
this flow belongs to a late-night
service we would do it on the five tuple
and independent of the dscp does that
answer the question
no I'm Finn there are different ways to
provide the debt net service different
queueing technologies on many of the
queueing technologies you don't have to
identify the individual flow the dscp is
fine you defend the edges of the network
to make sure that the only people the
only packets with the it with the
correct dscp with a diff sir excuse me
with the debt net dscp are packets that
are coming from people who know what
they're doing and then in the network
all you have to do is look at dscp and
assign that to the right class of
service that is certainly a possibility
you don't always have to know which flow
it is in order to do to give it the
founded latency zero congestion laws
there are other cases where you do have
to look at it because you have to do per
flow shaping depends on which technology
you're using to achieve debt net this is
sure I don't think we're gonna share
knowledge to take a meaningful decision
to be quite honest I think we need to
write down a focus document on this
problem with some mapping to some
applications and then take the decision
in the light of that the reason this is
so complicated is that the idea of a
debt net flow does not is not the same
at every hop through a network it is
entirely possible that this device looks
at a number of things that had separate
reservations made for them but it lumps
them all together in a you looks at any
of these things count as this one debt
net flow as far as I'm concerned okay so
no it's not necessarily true that every
device has the same idea of what's a
what
whether two packets are in the same flow
or a different flow yeah it's really
important to capture that in the
aggregation section of the of IP you
understand how to do aggregation very
well in an MPLS land I think we
understand it less well in IP space and
what you're saying is exactly right for
that so it's really important to capture
that so I have a question maybe maybe
minute device Tola so back to this
iframe example of a video stream if you
want to have prep for the iframes only
but not for the rest how do you do that
with five mm only that's probably
exactly a very good example to do it in
to judge this model and basically say
that's why we may want to have two
different services there right I'm not
quite sure what happens with the
relative queuing order once you do that
but I mean those those are all the good
cases I wasn't even saying that I don't
necessarily like this right I'm saying
there is just what I'm worried about is
what TSV does and you know what can we
do to prevent what I would consider to
be abused which is kind of dscp based
routing right so the per node behavior
the per hop behavior right which is kind
of to me EF the the elimination function
right that's a pro hop behavior I think
that's perfectly fine to do that but
what an important point - one of the
commenter's that maybe it's not every
hope we don't have to do it every hope
the it's only the relay well whether we
need to do it every hop or at the end
I'm not quite sure what what you folks
want I was just in the beer technology
saying it's possible right but it gives
higher resilience no no but I mean I
think it's a per hop feature did the new
elimination function and so that's being
you we can also argue what we want to do
for it so that that's a really good
example and that wasn't worried about
the the good ones just you know how can
we constrain okay the framework so that
we can avoid the bad ones Lincoln from
Hawaii I believe with the best ways
remove the DHCP because to distinguish
it for different service part Apple is
enough for example if you can use a
different port number for different
service and also as a
gentleman said the jsep is kind of
independent the PHP behavior that's a
Miss may mix with the five couples is
better but but how would you do then
this example I wrote up for example you
can set up so the iframes
you need proof but the rest not overseas
that's a different story
what I mean the the service level means
one flower once always you can
distinguish by phone number I missed the
last two words just the last photo
number I can use a different phone
number to distinguish the service you
don't need to use a DSC so you would
want let's say the iframe iframes on a
different port yeah whatever
but that's a different because that's
more complicated one of the issues there
is that I think they the point that were
let's just made a moment ago it's
because of a yes gentleman said and very
likely check the early before the fog
Papa means that or yes if you said yes
if you very well go to thank you they
don't care about others Stewart sir can
I suggest a way forward there's been not
moving very fast here norm says he's
gonna write his lot of material on this
in a document he's going to publish why
don't we wait till that documents out
and then call a quick cut a virtual
interim call when we've got a bit more
information a bit more shared model and
then make a decision then okay
can I ask the chair to concisely state
what we're arguing about
okay we have three options on the table
for flow identification of IP flows
option one is that we use I'll start
with one on the slide where we classify
flows based on standard five tuple and
the value of dscp so based on those
values which could be set as a wild card
being ignore or bit mass so say look at
just these values that that maps to a
single debt net flow which is translates
to a debt service that's option one
option two is we completely ignore dscp
so any value that's there is ignored
so you and you only look at the 5-tuple
flow so if you have a five tuple flow
with multiple vscp guys doesn't matter
they all map to a single dead net
service thank you
the third option is we specify a
specific value that must be present in
any debt net flow so we use five tuple
plus let's say zero and if and behavior
is undefined if it's not zero where we
say the different it's not part of the
debt net service at that point that it's
regular diffserv service saying those
are those are the three options that I
think we we've talked about tolis wants
to jump in and say that I'm wrong so
well I'm gonna I'll deal with that when
he gets to the mic so so I think that of
those three that you mentioned we're
talking about equality of service
feature here this is all about providing
a certain quality of service to ignored
ifs to to require that we ignored dscp
is silly okay I reject that one out of
hand of the other two I don't have a dog
in the fight I would be happy with
either one I think that there are use
cases I would look at what people are
doing now with use cases I my belief is
that today people do things with iframes
and such such that you use different DSC
PS on the same exact stream you use one
stream to make sure they all take the
same path and hopefully stay more or
less than order and you use dscp to mark
the important ones and the unimportant
ones I see no reason why we need to
interfere with that convention okay so I
think whether you I think it shows to me
the obvious one is make a dscp one of
the wild carnival fields okay
so the the model that I was thinking
number four is that you have the five
couple and in the service definition of
your flow you basically have the per hop
behavior definition of what dscp within
that flow means right which is what
we're doing today which basically means
that yeah
so the dscp cannot be used to define you
know the path behavior like the routing
stuff but it of course can be defined it
can be used to define the perab behavior
which is basically that you are
obviously when they're multiple DCPS in
the dead net flow that these are going
to be treated differently and
preferentially in the way that you know
these DSPs are defined in RFC s today if
we want to change and add you know dscp
behavior that's fine that's a typical
you know discussion in in TS vwg then so
to be clear what you're saying is is
you'd like option one with a restriction
that they must follow the same path yep
so you want what's on this on the slide
but with the restriction that they have
to be routed carotid that's what I
ultimately want but I'm not sure if
there are other implications about the
dead net service definition right that
aren't appropriate for dscp right DSC
peas are for poor hop behavior right so
obviously it's not the path behavior but
I'm not sure what else is in the overall
dead net flow definition that would also
be inappropriate for the SATs actual
actually if you use the SCP to
distinguish whether we need breath or
not that that has bet implication in the
sense that you use two bets or if I can
I think we're confusing two things here
which is quality of service and routing
while it's true that there are people
who who just do mask and match on the
front of the packet and do anything they
want with the packet and the fields mean
absolutely nothing okay to me that's the
Sdn model okay that can be good or bad
and I'm not going to argue with that
okay but within deck net I don't think
our intention is
to define a new way of doing routing
okay I think we want to be it's a tool
box we want to be compatible with stuff
so there are different reasons to look
and identify the flow one reason you
look at the flow is to route it one
reason you look at the flow is to sign
it to the right cue okay let's
distinguish those two purposes tirta
seems to be really worried that we're
going to route based on vscp
okay we just lost our III I don't want
to I don't want to rule that out right
now
so okay because in order to get you that
service I may have to pass you down
through a nail down path okay I may have
to pass through a nail down path and
that's complicate things so can I make a
proposal to make make the next step from
here to for now for the documentation
next next revision of the documentation
to keep it as is on the slide sixth up
with the SCP and on the way as we go on
if we figure out how to scroll down off
we need to scope down and so on we
figure out on the way yeah and I I think
the what we document should capture the
intent of 5-tuple is on path selection
and dscp is more about per hop behavior
which really translates to queuing yeah
traffic treatment it translates the
local traffic alright so toyless said
off mic is that he would like to he
thinks it's great to see prep as an
example of why you might want to do this
yeah okay so I'd like to I think did we
finished in provider you have more
points this is what I wanted thrust yeah
I think I think we just finished
simplified so I'd like to note that I
think we've accomplished our main goals
for this meeting and
weigh-in time we did it like on schedule
because we said we wanted to do that by
1:30 mark privately we didn't say that
everyone but that was very internal goal
so I think that's a great accomplishment
even with the fact that we have two
major open issues here one major open
issue is on MPLS hopefully someone's
capturing notes here ok great
one major issue we have to check is with
the MPLS working group we have a major
change there I think actually more major
than in TSV that we want to use control
word on l3 VPNs
that's not anything that's done today
and we're proposing that we will always
do that so that we can support both the
pref and non preface seamlessly can I
have a show of hands of folks who think
I got that wrong wrong because I was
going to ask you to go to the mic so I'd
note that that's no one now I'll say how
many people think I have that
characterization right it's it's a few
people I was hoping for like at least
half the room it wasn't half the room
but it was a few people and those know
so norm you could put your hand out for
so low Anderson I just wanted to explain
why I didn't raise my hand without the
ampulla share hat I would have raised
the hand hand but he says you say you're
going to talk to us I want to be or take
that decision decision without four
prior commitments of doing in that
discussion okay I actually appreciate
that because I did happen to notice
whether what you did there and frankly
is part of the reason why I asked for
objections first so that was that was
item one for item two I think our main
discussion has been on what's going on
in the host not in the middle of the
network and that we are saying that the
I think it's you want do you have six
super loose yeah you do that we're going
to go down a path of six tuple but with
the qualification that five tuple is
used for path selection and dscp is only
used to differentiate local cueing
behavior and reliability delivery how
many people object or disagree with that
statement again I see none that itself
is an accomplishment thank you
how many agree with the statement
interestingly it's slightly more than
who agreed with the mpls statement which
I thought was really non-contentious
although I do note that it is a bigger
chain it actually is a bigger change in
terms of what's done on the wire what we
read to there while we all agree in this
room that suit that a patrol word is a
good thing to have consistently it is a
big change to l3 VPN and we should note
that so miscanti huh
the reason why I did not raise my hem
this time is I'm still concerned with
noms point about the mail down path
basically I'm actually not hearing you
here it's on it's just you have to speak
up low okay so the reason why I did not
raise my hand this time is I'm still
concerned with noms point about the nail
down path it seems that the way you
worded it if we nail down a path for us
that NetFlow all the rest of the flow
has to follow this same path and I'm not
sure we can say that we may have done
all we have circles and we may inject
that data in that circuit it's a power
hub behavior just put that in this
circuit but we may have to do that and
this rocket may be following a path
which is
design controlled by a controller
somewhere where has the normal flow will
follow the IP routing it's going to be a
different thing so it's not really a
routing decision it's not capsulation
decision if you like but I want to make
this this this distinction because
otherwise we seem to imply that
everything has to go about the same part
of the tunnel okay I they will be really
good to make sure that the nodes yeah I
I don't think the easier pad reflects
that well and I'm not sure how to
summarize it so if you could if you're
on ether pad if you could just make sure
it's put in there or or I guess if you
don't want to do that send it to the
list so after the meeting I will fix
that but if you capture I mean it's
right after the meeting then no I can't
because if I have my laptop I read it
during the meeting so I took this rule
as maybe just restate it again or
restate it differently exactly okay so I
try to say that it might be that the
dirt net service is a certain path which
is nailed down by a controller which has
and it's kind of a circuit and it has
nothing to do with the path from A to B
that a packet following IP routing would
follow and in that sense when we take a
packet we look at the deserve flow in
there and and we figure out that it's a
dead net flow we put it in that circuit
which is someone capsulation and it goes
over a certain path and if it's not
determined I said that that's pakiya
then we leave I P do the routing for it
it's gonna go over a different path
which is not another control of the
controller and the result is those two
packets for the same flow will not
follow the same path and I think it's
very important that we can do that so we
can call it a pair how behavior and I'm
happy with it because it's just that is
the decision of encapsulating or not
encapsulating in this node after that
the routing will do its thing but on the
encapsulation
but still the packets will throw
different paths right so to make sure I
heard your point right or everyone else
agrees you're saying that there are
cases where you think that it's okay for
different DSC p-values for within the
same flow to follow different paths yes
because one of them gets on capsulated
and the past is determined by the
encapsulation not by the encapsulated
pocket that's so the the document will
start out talking about that five tuple
is used to select path I think it'll be
really important to bring in this case
you're thinking of and make sure it's
adequately covered my expectation is is
your should object to the first version
of the document so the I mean so far I
haven't heard you know an example that
would really make me say oh I like this
or like your example for the EF which is
kind of new prop behavior there was a
good example of what we're doing you
know usefully better right so the
example I heard from Haskell was more
like okay so it still can't guarantee
that you know the same or different DSC
piece of the same dead net flow will
flow across the same path if it's kind
of not in our control but an underlying
service right I think that is true but I
mean we whatever we can't control we
can't control right so I mean that's
that's not an argument to say it's a
good thing so it would be good to have
an example of a good thing we're saying
okay the same five couple two different
code points you know here's a good
definite reason why they should be
routable across different paths right
because i mean if if once we have a TS v
argument and i think that could really
example that would persuade them might
even say okay fine then maybe we haven't
done it in the past right and we have
felt there was a bad thing to do in the
past but you know that's Carrigan I
don't like the terminology of saying
they are rotting or rochet of a
different path because once the packet
is on the dead net ingress the packet is
encapsulated the inner packet is not
rated anymore it's just following the
encapsulation so so there is no
approaching decision along that path is
just the initial encapsulation on the
definite ingress which happens or does
not happen if the ingress are
capsulation happens then whatever you
put as the outer either will determine
what happens on this packet and it won't
be erotic because of the SCB it will be
rotted because of the are capsulation
it's just the decision of encapsulating
or not at the ingress of the death net
Network which decides whether you are
caps or not and then rotting is rotting
let's go this is bad no no way there's
something that actually part of your
discussion made me think how does this
work with ecmp
because what you're saying is I am not
understanding how we're going to make
this work if you have a cmp so can I
suggest you're really having that's why
when you mix all this together it
becomes much more complex can I suggest
to continue this discussion on the list
because I'm afraid we cannot make any
step further like we will see text in
the document it will make easier and we
can wish to definitely continue all
these aspects being discussed on the
list just to be able to progress with
the wraparound and the rest do you want
to talk about this time because oh I'm
sorry one more conclusion from the group
is that we can provide debt net service
over IP in the middle of the network as
a case of MPLS over IP using the define
building on the standard techniques for
running MPLS over IP that are already
exist as our FCS and I think that cut
that should cover what Andy was saying
so this is not really native IP support
what it is is our MPLS mechanisms over
sorry yar MPLS mechanisms including
graph over IP and IP PSM ok does anyone
object
- that no-good no one it does do who
agrees with that statement basically
handy no we got a few more people okay
so that that's the smallest of the polls
but still a reasonable number so with
that there was one other important part
in your deck Sagan I would like to know
about that to you for this one yeah so
there's a bunch of other topics sorry
there are a bunch of other topics that I
don't think it makes sense to or we
didn't think we'd get to today and it
looks like we haven't we don't have a
lot of time to dive deep in these that
is if we want to still do the other
material that we've talked about and it
would be very good if we could get some
texts contributed on this Stewart has
done a really nice job on the with some
starting tax law saying its finest the
finish but it's it's still a nice start
on aggregates for MPLS for example it'd
be great if we also got I forgot who
described what happens in IP networks
norm described in what happens in IP
networks and we really good to get a bat
tax captured and sent to the authors or
sent to the list and get that into the
document as well we have lots of other
areas where we're gonna have to go
through work through the details of
these and you want to switch the wrap up
yes I think we're gonna have some
regular interims to sort of virtually in
terms to make sure that we keep up with
some velocity on this so that's exactly
where I wanted to go on the wrap-up
slide and why I wanted to switch to it
let's give me one second sorry I thought
we had a queued up on a different laptop
run so certainly we need to go so where
do we go from here
certainly we need to capture the results
of this this discussion and some of
which is already there but what we
certainly need to get the full piece and
the question is is who should do those
those pieces we have good text that's
there that it needs to be split we've
talked about a document split multiple
times we've delayed it my my view and
I'd like confirmation from the working
group my view is we should do the next
version should be split where one part
is MPLS one part is IP if we want to do
more splits down the road we can do more
splits but initially we should take the
existing document split it into two
publish that did not have a what it's a
zero five version of the data plane
solution does anyone object to that it
Louie Anderson I think I agree but then
you're not cleared so sorry I think we
should split in the two pieces you
talked about but at least on the MPLS
side I think we have good text from
Stewart that you actually can put into
so you could Martian I'll get there okay
III wanna me I will get to what we do
with other text okay um I would like to
work on the split version in whatever
method you decide to make it split on
the MPLS partner split version I was
gonna say I heard from both authors say
that they both sets of authors that they
want to work together so yes will you
work together yes awesome so and more
than that even if you don't work with
them your document is published and they
have every right to take whatever they
want from it
included in their split document I think
the same as will will be if we found a
way of working together right so I I
think it would be wonderful if during
that split that the authors of the
current working group document and the
authors of the other two documents work
with the author team on that split and
participate in it yes I didn't have time
to do it before but I I think absolutely
the people who read the original text
should be part of the team that
construct the new derivative text yep
I'll also be glad to help in any way I
can
great and this should be worked at the
author's level without any chair
interaction is is our hope so the only
thing I'm not clear about now is are we
going to post one draft that is just a
split or can we actually put the new
text into that if as part of the the
work on splitting and
so the split should the next version
published should be a split and be
capture as much as possible of the
results of this of today yes and I think
for cleanliness we should call it a cuz
something completely different
not the old name not the new name with
the people who have worked on the text
call it's something else for the time we
next meet we will have a brand new
document that so let's have a DP soul
there sham pls and a DP soul - IP yes
it's let's go it you're probably being I
I'm not telling you what how to title it
I'm telling you what the file name is
the file name is DPS old-fashioned pls
and DP soul - IP okay and we are
assuming that those will start out as
working group documents not as
individual documents and that is based
on the assumption that people can work
together good
all right though those I think are the
most important pieces the last thing
that say on the document is if you are
present here and haven't written
anything on any documents you too can
contribute so it would be if you feel
like writing take the initiative write
up what you want to write send it to the
authors send it to the list do both
that's great it's a great way to be
involved in the process and make sure
that if you have a particular issue that
you care about that it is captured in a
way that you think is accurate
okay the last topic is we want to be
able to move to continue working at a
higher pace and we think that is really
important to try to get through that
list of issues and was the reason why we
wanted to make sure that list of issues
was shown before jumping to this slide
how do we want to do that as a working
group some of those may be appropriate
to have to call an interim on some of
them may be just working through the
issue we don't have to have a a an
interim in order to make progress on the
document other working groups have made
great strides and great progress on very
complex work by holding regular meetings
that are advertised to the working group
and anyone can attend and that there's
notes that are sent to the list those
are not formal and for interims they're
informal working meetings very focused
on specific technical issues that
everyone is can participate in anyone
and everyone can see what the results
are in the minutes
I'm not we're not saying that we have to
do one or the other but we want to
suggest that if the people involved who
are want to work on this at a faster
pace they can self organize and do those
things and we do have resources
available that we can give access to the
debt net WebEx if no one if there's not
a WebEx available
there's pluses and minuses with the ietf
WebEx right including a limited dial in
numbers so sometimes that's not the best
thing but we'd like to consider we'd
like to consider this one comment we'll
make is the frequency and open frequency
can be self-determined weekly bi-weekly
openness you definitely need should if
you're going to do this it's important
or we're gonna do this it's important
that that if he the invite be open to
all and that the reporting is to all one
thing is is keep it keep conscious of
what time you meet because by selecting
a particular time that's always it's
fixed you might maybe making placing an
undue hardship on someone who's in a
very different time zone so if you do
this perhaps think about shifting time
zones since this since the WebEx
detailed up the art in the public list
remember the precaution that we were
given the other day about making sure
you shut it down afterwards because
people have been hijacking them yeah for
if you didn't weren't aware of it
there's if you see random attendees who
don't have turned on their voice that
means they're trying to hijack you and I
have definitely seen that we also wanted
to raise the prospect of a physical
interim we tried to have a physical
interim with a toe to code it's in our
Coast collocated thank you with 802 and
it failed because we couldn't get
critical mass do we want to start
thinking about a physical interim just
for completeness the three of us have a
runner and exercise on checking and a
possibility of co-locating again with a
total in May but it's too many holidays
around us holiday and so on and it seems
it's it's not feasible in May we make oh
god it's not feasible in May because I
couldn't be me either but I do think
that the amount of progress we've made
today so to suggest that getting
together is a very valuable thing to do
but
should be an addition to virtuals told
us I mean did you make try to make roll
calls how people felt about the virtuals
I thought they were similarly effective
I mean this is a lot nicer but yeah with
you know all these continents and
airplanes it came at a cost yeah yeah we
do recognize that budgets are a major
issue with and want to be sensitive to
that and that's part of the reason for
asking for input here Jonnie yeah just
was my opinion so I would avoid a
physical in terms just because they are
just hard to justify to cause out there
for a day or two and but the brokers
today are in my opinion is mainly
because it was well prepared people put
a lot of effort to prepare things in
advance and we can achieve the same in
any interview people - same effort of
the preparation I think they may be the
next step then is rather than trying to
schedule a physical which would be nice
but I don't think we got overwhelming
support for here is that we schedule a
an interim as soon as we have the
document published and I should have
said one of the documents published it's
perfectly fine if the split that well
let's say we get the mpls document first
or the I and it's probably the mpls
support first because the text is a
little more mature there we can start
the interim there and then once we have
the interim on that document we can
shift more to a working mode of working
through those more detailed issues yeah
please
check for blue sheets so I kind of
understand who's on the mpls right
thing who's on the IP writing team we
are the default is all the current
authors yes and they we have two
documents one that's focused on IP and
one that's focused on ILS phenomen I
think that complete set figures it out
okay fine and then in addition to that
is if we start getting contribution from
other people absolutely they get to
participate to did like you told and I
appreciate the but the author's that
have been working this for a long time
notably Yoda had to corral to herd the
cats so I have one other bookkeeping
issue when we start doing the informal
meetings among a group of co-authors
well no it's interested parties its
whoever wants to show and we start doing
meeting with the interested parties we
actually need to make sure that the
working group mailing list gets some
type of report on that I have had a
couple of problems on the mpls side with
people go off and have a couple of
meeting and then they come back with two
line report summarizing like three or
four meetings that doesn't work we need
to get Lee make sure that we report each
and every meeting each and everything we
want to change to the main list a
hundred percent agree and I apologize
for not saying it I thought you didn't
say anything else I'm just kind of
creating a mindset that we actually do
it absolutely I mean to me that's part
of openness and include and and
consensus building yeah you said briefly
that it has to be reported underneath
but it's good to put put emphasize on it
all right with that we'd like to know if
there's any other comments that anyone
would like to make related to data
playing solution because we're about to
move off data plane solution into the
other two talks just a very old question
I don't know if then that one talked
about a control plan one more time
even more plan so right now control
plane knows a charter doesn't know it
right now our deliverables do not
include control plane yes we are and
from my perspective and if you look at
the milestones were behind on our on our
deliverables so we really can't talk
about expanding deliverables at this
point once we have some very good a
little bit more progress to the point
where we're close to publishing or we're
at starting to wrap up Network it would
be fine to be talking about what how we
deal with the control plane so if we're
lucky maybe we can have start having
more serious discussions on control
plane in 103 but that's assuming things
really come together between now and 102
so we'll have to see the other thing is
certainly control plane requirements is
something that's appropriate for us to
be talking about we wouldn't want to be
getting deep into extensions in other
working groups protocols those really
should go over to those working groups
so we have to be careful about when we
start talking about control plane to
make sure to keep in mind that the we're
not the owners of those protocols so
it's fine to talk about it here the
requirements are important to talk about
here but the actual extensions and go
into the working group that owns those
six them those protocols is that piece
of question other other comments all
right well that's great that we
accomplished our our number one and
number two okay thank you so we can move
on to more presentations for the next
you can have the control so puts into
some silent background in front is still
need to island background in front row
because everyone asks the question the
the reason we're doing this inspired by
the need to have an underpin for net net
slicing we didn't want to get involved
in all the politics and all the
strangeness is and the huge issue of
there slicing what we wanted to do was
to find the underpin it would allow
someone to build it noting that that
same technology is useful for other
things as well for example you could
integrate this and we show to show you
that you need to do that with
deterministic networking just did its
own right without really for some
completely different application so well
I kind of ignore this one because it
just sort of says that we've been
writing this for a while we've been
working on this for a while we've been
working on it in the RT gwg area and i
think we've had some discussions with
lou and this will continue now in the
t's area and to be clear that was in
conversation also with the ad who owns
the writing group it wasn't like I just
said it no no no no I'm absolutely fine
to have a willing home for this so this
is what we're doing we there were a
number of enhanced data planes that
people are designing
mainly as I say influenced
I the big influences 5g net slicing but
there are other reasons for wanting to
do it so we have an enhanced day to play
it might be a flexi data plane it might
be a TSN data plane it might be a death
net data plane or it might just be
simple queue
complex queue management stuff well what
we want to do is to create a VPN for use
by a particular tenant and in order to
give them the enhance service they want
we need to map their VPN onto some
dedicated resources in the underlay so
the big thing that we're doing
differently here is the integration of
underlay and overlay there are a number
of ways we may do this one of those ways
is with segment routing but that is not
the only way that we might do it on top
of that we have a control and management
system which we note has to be have some
scalability properties but that's not
where the focus of our work is so this
is what we sort of see the thing what
that differentiates this is the need to
provide isolation between the different
tenants that is to say the tenant
shouldn't realize that other users are
anywhere on their network if we look at
what happens in ours at the moment
normally we have statistical
multiplexing ordinary VPNs people who
want absolutely isolation we could build
that for them but essentially what will
be building is an isolated independent
network and that's expensive so what
we're trying to do is to have a safe
flight what we're trying to do is to
have a pragmatic solution kind of the
same philosophy that we had in pseudo
wires if you want a rule run by a real
run but we can probably do you a cheaper
deal if you should if you share on the
next same network as everyone else and
it should be good enough so we're
looking for this sort of pragmatic
approach in the middle our performance
so
at the moment VPNs are largely
best-effort we can do a short bandwidth
but we are concerned about whether they
scale to the number of tenants that are
needed and what we don't have is
guaranteed latency and enhanced delivery
which is what you're working on here
and so we see the work that's going on
in decnet is a really important underpin
for this VPN Plus work so in order to do
that you have to have a mapping of
resource to to the V to the to the VPN
to the particular packet that's going
through those things might be diverted
with links and I'll be dedicated queues
etc we have a draft that was being
discussed right now in spring or has
just been disgusted spring that
describes some of that and we'll
probably have a draft in LSR next time
we were worried about scaling scaling is
a problem because at the fundamentally
if every flow or every service has to
have its own dedicated resources at
every half then you kind of need to have
one label per service per hop
we suspect that actually some services
will require dedicated resource at each
hop have some we'll be able to share and
some will need a mix depending on the
service capability as the let the
underpin and that's why the aggregation
stuff we'll be talking about it's
important that we can ignore this it's
going to go into T's is the is the
agreement that we've got and that's the
end of it there was a be a bit more
discussed in r2 gwg I probably gaveled
this a bit if you go listen to the
recording you don't have a more measured
approach okay so thank you feedback
contributions particularly welcome
thank you
Thank You Stuart
moving out along pretty quickly that was
quick yeah yes yesyes I think I think
probably some of us saw it earlier this
week as well so yeah yeah yeah I think
it's so great
send it listen to the other recording
send email whatever I can do to help you
understand it you don't have the links
to the drafts here but I guess people
can find it or or do you want they want
to send an email to the death net list
we do it yes I'll send you a link to the
technics I can't even remember the name
of the drop yes sir why the study mail
is whether I'll send you some pointers
to the list when I get back home so any
any comments questions okay then let's
go to the second presentation
this forest lot yeah so this is the mark
for you yes I will introduce okay does
it work now okay I will introduce our
work about the IGBT extensions for then
that information this part of work is
just I think help to understand the work
of the young model and you can use
please stay in the just for the video
okay just to understand the work of the
topology llamado and as we all know in
the current IETF work we always used AGP
to collect topology information so we
want to do this part of work - - just -
to complete it and this page we have
already showed in the 10 that
configuration young model that means all
the other attributes we defined in the
ITP extensions goes along with the data
medium model and the part of the
attribute has already been defined in
the trapped and a part of the attributes
is is waiting to be ended now we do the
OSPF extension for them that including
for a sub t always to link to your V
they are congestion control matters up
to LV maximum 10 that reservable
bandwidth sub t lv available then has
been with sub T of e minimum and maximum
queuing delays up to LV and I think all
all these she always has already been
its corresponding attribute has already
been discussed in the last session so
it's just some
encapsulation and considerations and
next steps we have already declare that
it's goes along with the topology data
model and we asked for more comments
from the working group and we will
improve the document based on the
feedback and actually in this work is
not in the current chatter because has a
new has already said as the control
plane protocol is not in the current
Charter but it is a good supplement
invention man man attention to the
general configuration young model so
perhaps how to process this document is
another question
- dissolved okay great mirskiy could you
please roll back one slide okay and one
more well you have very good slide that
captures list of all parameters that you
extend all the metrics yeah now before
that this one and one more before yes
yes
this one so again I I'm very interested
in what norm presented and again I want
to bring this residence time so again
there some limitation of the metrics
that currently being advertised and T
extensions that exclude queuing delays
and when we propose new metrics we need
to think at the same time how this can
be measured because if metrics cannot be
measured reliably I don't see it very
useful actually I have already said that
I think this part of attribute is not
for measurement it is for a calculation
computation because as her
norm has already showed about the
pounding found in latency mechanisms the
Pandya latency is guaranteed by the
queueing management algorithm and
depends all on all of these algorithms
we can do the calculation about the
community lake and there is no need for
measurement now in the doesnot scope
again we can discuss it because I think
that that net application services will
have different requirements towards
guarantee so thus there might be some
services that give you well that can use
multiplex of a subscription and then
your parameters will be different so
again there will be necessary and I
don't see that only installing without
feedback based on performance
measurement is a practical solution
because are only configuring something
in not being able to verify through our
active or hybrid measurement method I
think it possibly creates a black box so
when we think that we can configure
something we need to think about how can
we verify that in the network whether
it's an activation testing or life
service I hear my name being used this
is norm fin III I think you're both
right in creating flows and so on does
not depend on measuring what how the
network is used being used now and
responding to that but certainly a user
of the system may want to verify that it
is actually giving him the the service
that he wants and when
not if but when something gets screwed
up and you're not delivering the service
that you want you want to find out why
so you know you're both right it's not
necessarily a part of making the
reservation but there's got to be some
way to verify that it works yeah yeah I
agree and as I understand these
parameters the ones that noted vertices
of itself you know in an IGP of course
it should by not for us so it should be
really value and we need to be able to
verify I want to mention again this RFC
seven eight thirteen which provides ISS
extension similar thinking similar
similar aspects like available bandwidth
making bandwidth reservation simple ones
on a on a graph I'm not saying it it
covers everything needed here I'm just
pointing on it that has been a similar
approach a couple of years back already
and that that is used in in bridge
networks today so if you want to be
aligned it it is good to take a look a
question do we need so you this has
maximum debt not reservable bandwidth
and available death not bandwidth like
wine we specified that Nitai you really
want to dedicate by configuration to
some bandwidth to that net because in in
certain it can be a simple simpler
approach to say that oh this is the
total available bandwidth and I can this
is what we can we can use so you
distinguish that nut and on that night
bandwidth as I understand I'd say this
doing OSPF extensions for that net is
reasonable if we when we have the model
reasonably solid or our yang models and
so on a reasonably solid we know what
the parameters are I think that we
may not know all the parameters right
now for if you're going to do one
particular flow if you're going to use
OSPF to create is your plan to use OSPF
to create a reservation for a flow okay
this is just to distribute information
about the network yes okay well then
I'll just say that it thing something
like the max Det net reservable
bandwidth I assume that would be per
link or maybe it's a percentage yes yeah
and you know that's essential yeah sure
available net net bandwidth actually
maximum a tener reservable bandwidth is
the whole bandwidth can be used by the
net and available then the bandwidth is
the unused part and it can still be used
by new Denis flows so these parameters
so that would be dynamic then the second
is dynamic yeah dynamic it will change
when you then have flows choice yeah
okay and what's min max queuing delay oh
yeah the queuing delay I think is what
is that the min max queuing delay you
mean oh wait what does it mean your last
bullet min max queuing delay what is
that I think it is the based on the
queuing algorithm and we can compute the
queuing delay the maximum and the
minimum for a link for output queue for
a hop for one I think it's for output
port per port
yep so that's the time it takes to get
through that node yeah I think just the
packet cost goes through the device and
in the egress and the area is the output
and the cueing will deploy that then
that queuing algorithms okay there and
so the queuing delay can be calculated
that's the point then I would suggest
and I apologize that it's taken so long
to get the bounded latency draft started
but I think that will that that
parameter would change I think as a
result of the bounded latency do you
think all rhythms will will influence
the value of this this parameter I think
part of the aquarium's my point is that
is jean-yves labou deck gave his talk at
in singapore and and looking at his book
and talking to him further saying if I
understand what that is obtaining the
worst case into n delay by adding the
worst case delay at each hop is not the
right way to do the calculation yeah I
get your point that is the budget of the
network calculus right yeah yeah but I
think it's a little different in
determinist networking because it is
guaranteed by the queuing algorithm not
the the calculus right well no because
the the worst case delay at one hop
depends on what's been going on in the
previous hop okay so you simply cannot
sum up the delay at each no you can but
then you get an answer which is much
worse than the actual worst case delay
so you'll get an answer that says the
worst cases is 18 microseconds and my my
my flow needs 16 microseconds but the
real maximum is 15 yeah I got sewing so
you know I would be okay so yeah so I'm
just saying I think that this may be a
great idea but I think you maybe need to
wait until we settle on what the
parameters are yeah I totally agree
about the fantasy trap - well influence
this part of definition and it is always
often too
discussion but a little comment about
your response is that I think that is
the way of calculating the end-to-end
latency right we perhaps we cannot just
1 + / 1 / hub Flat Earth how to say it
just one perhaps agency plus another
probability for have plus another for
halogens and it is not the answer of the
end-to-end the latency perhaps right
okay again III support norms if I may
use his name again
no call him to the mic I would it's
discussion it's a very good and healthy
discussion and useful great that we have
this discussion here and face to face
what I want to say is take a look at
some documents and actually I can take
on looking and sending to the list more
specific references to documents in IPP
and working group because it's not
necessarily the min and Max are useful
metrics
maybe not minimum maximum but main
parameters might be more useful not here
no not here
here at least might be percentile but at
least what I want to say is keep it open
yes so so as known points out in this
room we are after the bound we are after
the worst case not Kabbalistic is this
meant to enable you know rsvp-te see SPF
like calculation of path and a
calculation of resources perhaps we just
extended a collection part and that's
the calculation part if I gather your
own question right right but I mean it
is the so then the answer is it's purely
for OAM it's not for for path
calculation yes I think so it's not full
path calculation I think that perhaps
have other considerations for path
calculation and we just do the extension
to do the collect the topology and the
capability of the network yeah and then
right okay no no right if you if you'd
said path calculation would be totally
different but so are there any perhaps
different perhaps not but it's not all
you said no so I'm not going to make
that argument what I expected so let's
say this for the OEM part I have no good
background of prior art where you know
you would flood this OAM only
information into the IGP because I
always thought that they are not so
happy to have a lot of you know be
abused for flooding for anything that's
not involved in path calculation so is
there prior evidence that we have that
your point is correct that's my
understanding as well so I mean I love
to abuse AG pieces we just saw but
actually actually these type of
parameters available bandwidth and so on
for path calculations in classic IgE is
exactly yes but that's why I was asking
because if we go back to the the use
case of the path calculation and the
resource reservation then I think that
will all be subject even more - you know
these classifications of different
mechanisms from north cue estra because
you know i mean there may be
calculations that depend on knowing
exactly every individual other flow that
was allocated which is a lot different
from what you've needed in the much more
lightweight in serve service model yes
that RSVP does right yes I think it
perhaps related to this page about the
queueing management algorithm I think
just as you have comment the different
queuing algorithms and the queues
mechanisms will influence attribute
exactly so and you know I mean I just
think it's it's somewhat premature right
now to try to already get into all these
you know and attributes rather than I
think looking at the framework right
what is it that the and maybe even you
know this should go to T's and I'm still
trying to figure that out myself what to
do where best and unfortunately I think
we just lost the taste share to an
airplane or something yes and the future
is not here yeah so
right in terms of you know what are we
trying to do with the IGP right and what
what what type of information would we
need what amount of communications
needed right I think the parameters in
the end you're at everything
once everything is settled that's the
least amount of problems right but just
high level trying to classifications of
what would be done what type of
information is needed I think that would
be I think highly useful as a starting
point when we get into the control plane
so that we understand what dynamics we
will have yes and I think it's a ghost
station for just not only this atrophy
extension but also the llamado
configuration configuration llamado
should cooperate with the ponty latest
draft and try to define the parameters
needed yes definitely
so this okay I think the tourist makes
excellent point because if all the model
for the dead net
it's a centralized controller not
distributed by them then we don't need a
GP extensions you never know I mean no
you can you can have you can have an
approach when the center has come to a
collects all the data from a GP so there
are HIPAA hybrid approaches it's it's
they're out out on the field because if
somebody wants it then of course that's
a valid otherwise we need only OS
extension and did you pay extensions so
I mean they're they're all type of ways
to cut the cake right so for it for the
for the beauty framework entities which
you may want to take a look at which
isn't really trying to get into these
qsr things right because I wouldn't have
figured out but I was trying to come up
with with the data model right that we
can use through yang or that could be
flooded in the IGP so that in the end
you can build yourself the network
solution you want everything only from
the PC CPCC C and or just you know I
mean maybe there's something about that
I haven't really thought about all these
qsr things for for debt net in in the
context of such a framework but I'm
saying maybe starting with the framework
might be an easier
step as opposed to random details on the
bottom yes you let's get you there I
respectfully disagree with Gregg I mean
we we have written clearly in the
architecture that there is a need for
having a network which can support both
deterministic and non-deterministic
flows at the same time I think it's a
key design point and thinking about the
IP on caps if you are using IP I expect
there is an IP network doing what you're
watching is is in place there and that
there is a controller some place which
will establish some circuits or whatever
we call them using IP over IP and then
the sequence counter in the desktop and
everything will be fine and that's
that's kind of an exception rule for
those definite flow that where's Ally
advised of the sixth up or whatever but
for the mainstream packets it's still
gonna be IEP nigp so I disagree with you
I I don't see that some people may do it
but the general case I don't expect it
to be a death net only Network I think
it's a shared infrastructure and that
net being some of those flows controlled
by the controller but the whole
background traffic would be still no
more IP at least that's how I see it
just maybe even of this okay yes there
are many ways to do it I think you have
got quite enough food for thought like
on on what steps or what investigations
make as next step but ultimately we need
to do the basic work first as many
people point out before going into
control plane details so thank you for
the presentation and we have five
minutes left left to wrap up any any
other topic to discuss before we close I
think
okay then take
very much for staying this long and
thank you very much for this this
efficient session it was very good thank
you and and pay attention to the email
list there will be further virtual
meetings coming up working meetings and
maybe in time thank you
you