do you want a Java scrap since you're
sitting right here yeah cool and I'm
happy to take notes I don't think we'll
have that many decisions to note so good
morning everybody probably particularly
good morning to Ken who's up at 5:30
a.m. over in the US
welcome to the extra extra work now it's
not the extra we've only got one extra
working group this is it on the Thursday
morning we have here the note well
updated I did actually check there are
two copies of BCP 25 in there for
different reasons and they're both
actually I mentioned in basically 25 so
I think that's actually real you
obviously can't read that slide but you
can easily search this seam on the
Internet
all right are you doing well I've made
it very very small this is the rough
agenda I've put together absolutely
happy to rearrange move things around
whatever people need does anyone have
anything they want to add to the agenda
at this point I've already noted that
Barry's proposed new draft is in there
do you think five minutes will do for
that excellent shall we begin
I have there are only six open issues in
github I closed the two regarding unique
ID because I have now written a draft
for unique IDs I promised and there's
been a bit of backwards and forwards on
that so we have issues on saved a
special use something I created to put
an informational document about how
thesaurus replication protocol works
because it's designed to replicate the
IMAP data model and it might be a useful
thing to have and there are a couple of
issues about 64 bit or 63 bit extension
I believe all of these should be covered
in apart from the size replication thing
there's space for each of them under
their draft so we probably should speak
about them then sorry I guess we do we
have a separate item for the 64 bit yes
okay I'll wait till then all right so
these are the existing drafts that we
have sitting in our queue in various
state there are six of them so far and
we have three more proposed coming down
the way I don't have enough experience
to know if that is an insanely large
number to have in a working group at
once or not but some of these have don't
have much work left on them yeah I'll
have to wear multiple hats here so with
my ID hat on I think it would be nice to
get one or two of you queue
yeah because I suspect that list my
right instead stateís eyes are done
maybe see especially use as well yep
this is Barry and I think the one I'm
proposing is basically done on contact
Isis I think we should leave the imap
Rev for after we get a few of these off
the queue before we start on them and
then concentrate on that anyway
definitely have a conflict of interest
because I think you can probably
speaking as a participant you probably
can work in parallel but you don't need
to be done with it
all right wait all right so I now have
slurred speech this
so since Ken's on line are you awake
enough to start talking about your ones
Ken here we go all right so there's the
first slide and here's Ken waiting for
the slide to come up can you guys hear
me okay yes hey beautiful
both of my eye my eyes aren't turns are
concave ago okay so I'm atlas right this
is very very similar to an existing RFC
which does the status extended the list
so all this is
is a new return option for extended list
which will return a my rates response
for each of the existing list of all
mailboxes that come back in the list
response itself the benefit of this it
reduces a round trip for each of the
mailboxes that a client would want to
get the rights law next slide please
and there is a very simple example of
what it would look like as the only
interesting bit here is is the last
mailbox bar which is not existent you
obviously do not get a my rates response
for non-existent mailbox that's pretty
much it shell questions and this is
Barry it strikes me that retrieving your
rights could be an expensive operation
relatively speaking is there any
discussion of that in the draft I don't
recall
I don't recall off the top of my head
either Barry I would say I don't have to
take a look so I believe there is a
mention of it I do not recall to what
level okay because I just worry that if
someone had access to ten thousand
mailboxes and you did this command right
it could be very expensive and it might
be worth calling that out so I was
thinking about how I'm going to
implement it in our server and I suspect
I will probably do least return my
rights and specially use at the same
time because that's a note that you know
and this is list is very small so that's
probably the mailboxes I care about and
everything else I will do as as the user
selects them but no I'm not suggesting
that this document needs to mention
special use but I think it's probably
worth discussing
don't other comment I have is you have
the M right showing an example which i
think is annotation extension or
something yeah yes so I think because
it's not part of standard time app ICL
it's an extension to it
I think you should point out and in a
comment saying that well in case people
will try to actually analyze your
example where this is coming from
obvious remove it'll actually it's
probably simpler that way yeah yeah that
makes sense obviously this this has been
implemented in the cyrus server because
this is where it came from
it's used certainly the reason I asked
for in the first place
for fast mail is that it's used to
display whether a mail box is writable
or not through to the UI and that's very
useful to get for all the mailboxes at
once so we we run my writes is very
cheap in our server and we just run a
select or mailboxes with my right so we
can keep the display up in sync
yeah I think in our implementation we in
a web mail server part of our
implementation we open drafts and sand
folder as soon as the user logs in
internally so you want the writes on
these you know that's sort of again so
to know whether well do you have this
folder and you know what kind of writes
all right so I guess next steps here
African to take those two suggestions
probably produce one more draft and then
probably take it to working group last
call after that I would think I can't
say anything else that's likely to be an
issue here but back to Barry's comment
there is a one or two sentence paragraph
that does say that if the server is
unable to look up the set of Rights that
the server may drop the my rights reply
I don't know if that's sufficient or if
you to expand on that no I was looking
at advice to clients to be careful about
how they use it okay fair enough
did you want to well we have have a room
poll for people interested in
implementing it just to verify the spec
house sure that seems reasonable does
Chris Newman by the way I'm taking notes
sure he seemed interested in
implementing this so few people in the
room I don't know that only the room is
going to be too valuable but who's gonna
put it in a client that's the I'm
usually less worried about servers
because you know we got a bunch of them
and they all seem to want to implement
everything so all right anything else on
this so should we move on to the next
one cool all right thank you Steve extra
FS they say well we've got a TA Ken okay
this this draft essentially is a way to
copy a store a copy of any outgoing
messages that get generated by sip
actions obviously the name SEC came from
a non-standard header that some some
email clients use right now that the
draft stipulates that it's only
compatible with vacation and notify it
is specifically not compatible with
reject any reject that was basically
because it violates the SMT principle of
either message is delivered or bounced
this would break that obviously by
storing a copy next I please
is the next slide coming up yeah go yeah
so that there's a very simple example
basically the tagged argument takes a
mailbox name so in this case it's added
to the vacation extension next slide I
did make this work with the existing
file two options that make sense so
those additional options would get
placed in between the FCC tag and the
mailbox name so in this case you could
use special use create and add Flags I
don't know if that is too complex for
this draft but it is a flooded in
Cyrus so it's certainly doable that was
Barry : looks good if it didn't come
through on the microphone okay thank you
alexey III do have possible concerns in
a sense of I'm I need to double check
whether save back allows basically
you're sort of trying to say that you
have the grammar structure that you have
options to existing tagged parameters
and then you are using other tag
parameters names with the same syntax
here and a question number one can can
they be repeated with and without FCC in
the same statement I don't know the
answer to this maybe it's a stupid
question
and if they can whether this is actually
allowed according to the serve spec so
it's not a showstopper but I have a
concern and I think I have a work item
to double check whether this is okay or
not and I would like to hear other
people what they think about this this
is very I'm not sure what you're getting
at in this case I mean these are
parameters to the FCC action so I don't
see that you're not using special use as
an action you're using it as a parameter
it's well there's no nesting of
parameters done here it's there is
there's the special use parameters to
create parameters the flags prep yeah
FCC is a parameter to vacation and then
it has something yeah there's definitely
a level of nesting yeah yeah I think
it's okay Alexia's gonna check so I'll
shut up hmm
apart from that are there any other
issues we should be so again I think
this is probably resolve this issue and
then take it to working group last call
another question I'm sorry I haven't
read the mailing list there was a
discussion about reject whether it's
actually okay and I think mad commented
on this I don't know what the other line
was happy with the resolution that we
say it can't be used for reject and
nobody else wants it enough to argue
against that if there's a demand for it
again in the future then we could do yet
another extension to allow it for reject
but you know intermediate message in the
thread saying that actually maybe we
should be allowed because this is
internal to the server anyway so I
didn't read the conclusion this yeah
nobody really needs it for that the
thing that that we definitely wanted for
a fast mail is if we send out a vacation
response we want to have a copy of that
if we send out a notification response
we want to have a copy of it so that we
have that
history of everything that's been done
on the user's behalf reject we do at the
boundary anyway so and I think a lot of
sites will be similar this is very I
agree that we should not allow it and
that anybody who wants to have it will
implement it anyway and ignore that so I
don't care I'm actually I remembered
another issue the way how notify
framework was written was very carefully
we were separating method for
notifications from the general framework
so notification methods is keyed of the
UI that you are using so you can use
notifications to you to generate XMPP
some messaging notifications or you can
use mail to to generate emails and the
way the document says is it doesn't talk
about this it just assumes that you can
always archive now it might be a wording
issue or clarifying that it only applies
to when you use mail to notifications if
you want to talk about sympathy
notifications then you have to say much
more and say what exactly does it mean
yeah so Lexi you're uncomfortable with
the hand waving I did saying that it's
up to the server to determine how to
save a copy or depending on the notified
action yes you effectively you there was
a deliberate decision discussing in
notify framework that there are
different sort of plug-ins for different
types of notifications of different
protocols and they will describe
requirements for how messages are
generated how they look like and stuff
and you're deliberately your blessing
over it or whether you are omitting
details or you are violating this
separation so I think you probably need
more text either way okay if you've got
something in mind
please open an issue for available
either option one you just say this only
applies to email notification framework
and you had a reference to secondary
which describe the email notifications
if you
to use it for other type of
notifications you say you can use it for
the tab notifications but then you need
to add details about how what does it
mean okay so I could see text that said
something like if the server supports
file into F say say for this type of
notification then it accepts a civil
script otherwise it rejects it is
incompatible with FCC and if it if the
server does have a way to take a copy of
it then presumably that's what the user
was asking for yes again using XMPP as
an example if you want to allow for this
even if you don't specify the exact
message generated because it's going to
be effective XMPP in message converted
to email at least say so you know this
is still better than just you know there
is nothing there okay so it needs some
more words for that so maybe this one we
should finish that and then come back
for one more check that everyone's happy
before we cool all right moving on the
next one is 64-bit alexey welcome back
thanks Ken so this started as a very
simple draft that oh why don't we make
you know message size is 64
well 63 bits and just update the grammar
everywhere and then Chris and his email
with lots of operational issues which I
think about it is I intellibid
I just haven't thought about this so
I'll invite Chris to talk more about his
issues
okay this is Chris Nilan yeah I so one
of the issues was this is an implicit
format change the mailbox for
implementations that assume 32-bit sizes
and that's a you know that's a lot of
code changes often you know in in Syrus
based servers that's a new mailbox
you know index format which has which
can have migration issues you know I
mean it's supposed to auto migrate but
you know there you go does mean it's
perfect
so I'm curious what's driving the beo
before yo I'm probably not interested in
implementing it but I'm curious what's
driving this is there you know is there
actual interest in implementing this for
some particular class of application or
something
yeah they the question I saw in your
stuff and I think is even more important
than this because the server can
implement it or not is if the server
supports it and a client that uses
32-bit storage for fields that are now
64 bits the client can't really opt out
because the server has data in there
which it can't represent over 32 bit
anymore
so the client the client will fetch
something that has a number that's too
large for the space Astoria there's an
enable so what happens to what happens
to a message that's too big right well
well that's the question so the coin has
to obtain into syntactic extension so
the server will never send 64 bit sizes
to all clients the question happen is if
a message is more than 4 gigabytes
what should the old client get in this
case and it ain't
yeah tombstone or maybe responding now
to the fetch command no we'll break a
lot of clients it'll just break they'll
just up everything so well it can
be I'm tagging now but you know even in
tag no I think is it really good oh I
think you need to either eliminate the
message which I don't like or send a
tombstone that indicates it's an empty
message or something at least the user
will still scratch its head but there'll
be an indication that there's something
funny there is there really a use case
for this or are we just saying why not
that's a question for Lexie who needs it
who wants it I don't actually have a
good answer to this well I was I didn't
think of this I thought it was a good
source to the community to document this
but I personally don't have a use case
so then this is Barry I recommend that
we park it and you know it can it can
just be an expired draft until somebody
says oh look we do need this because
it's just too complicated to put out for
nobody who wants it so I I see you know
the question is we should probably ask
does good guys and saris fast mail camp
well you can talk for yourself I don't
know if you have use case but we should
probably a staff court because they
commented i again i just you know i can
ask privately or publicly saying you
know is it just you think it's online
from dovecot yeah and well he's packed
manning across if he wants to pack man
across we have no urgent need for a fast
mouth we we would
possibly implemented but we wouldn't be
in a hurry to and we wouldn't need it
Stefan did you want to comment your next
anyway so it's a good time to hop in the
line now yeah dovecot supports sixty
four-bit internally Sean Leonard says I
don't think 64-bit should be parked
reason is because if the implementation
tail is long at least by having the
option out there all week so he's
finished well maybe it was a dot dog it
gives developers time to prepare okay so
this is very i I don't think developers
are going to be because this is
sufficiently complex to put in
I don't think developers are gonna stick
it in just in case just because we've
published it so I don't really think
that's going to give us a benefit
Jenkins can use clarify in dovecot what
they support a 64-bit is that 64-bit
message sizes 64 bit you IDs or
everything or what sorry okay watching
for their comments to come through on
jabber as long as we're talking about
that I would be more willing to support
64-bit you IDs unfortunately that's that
requires the same mode switch that that
this does so yeah
the Stephan says I don't know Jeff might
list don't you dance in the room I think
that's fine yeah yeah person am okay
with parking it if there is no immediate
use that's fine all right next up is
status sighs yeah jeff says in dovecot
your dates are 32-bit but message sizes
are 64-bit yeah I guess Stefan appears
not to have audio or speaking times all
right you're honest yes so what should I
say does anyone have any questions about
this draft
I think the second bullet is appropriate
so status size is I think everyone
agrees is ready to go to working group
last call the one clarifying question
that came up was what the size should be
and I believe everyone's agreed it
should be the sum of the RFC r2 to dot
size of all the messages that exists in
the folder which matches the example in
the draft
I think the drafts also says this
explicitly so yeah I read the draft I
think it's ready
cool Chris Newman are just just vetoing
I I wanted to ask how would this
interact with the email address
internationalization extension so what's
why I ask that is once you implement
email address internationalization
you've got two different classes of
messages in your mail store you've got
the e aí ones and the traditional ones
and if you downgrade the
ái ones they have a different size so
what did you serve a return when you
asked at fire CI to two dot size so
message so right the way it kind of has
to work is if the server does
downgrading it has to depend on whether
or not enable enable the the utf-8
command has been issued by the client so
the server will actually have to store
two sets of sizes for the new messages
so I'm wondering if it would be helpful
to just have a little implementation
note about that so when people are doing
this they can think oh wait you know
maybe I should have two slots rather
than one in my data format I agree on
this I agree on the note the other thing
that occurred to me sort of related to
this is we do have metadata that we
store with mailboxes if this value is
used to calculate quota or inform users
about quota we can possibly say that the
server may return value which is bigger
than the some message sizes that
includes the other information in this
case if you support utf-8 then you might
just count both of them as you know it's
metadata about happy to discuss yes this
is very that's what I was going to go
somewhere related to that at the white
why why do we need this and so do we do
we need it to be exact and if if it can
be if it can be a little larger maybe so
it's an estimate
it cannot be smaller but if we can say
that it must be at least as big right
now I was just looking at the text right
now it says rapid scrolled funny this
must be equal to the sum of the values
of the RFC 822 dot size fetch Maps
data item of all the messages in the
mailbox and I suggest we say this must
be equal to or greater than and then
explain why it might be different and
then it would be happier Stefan I must
say I'm not too well-versed in the in
the internationalization part of I'm up
at the moment
you still haven't implemented that but I
see what you're getting at I think the
original reason this exists is webmail
clients so those have more trouble if
they want to establish how big the
mailbox is so if that sum is a little
larger than the actual value I think
it's no problem
okay one other issue which I don't think
yeah I don't think we need to worry
about I just want to make sure people
are aware that this issue is out there
is that you know sometimes people yo-yo
when there's a quota on usage that quota
isn't restricted to just mail it covers
other sorts of objects which may not be
stored on the mail store and so there's
actually an integration problem with our
current specs where there isn't a clear
way to have sort of an uber quota that's
that's that's integratable with with
other services I'd be tempted to set
that telescope III for the spec what
we're interested in is a way to avoid
having to count the sizes of all the
messages to know which folders are big
right I did yeah just I I agree with
that but just wanted to point out the
issue yeah thank you this reminded me
though the quarter spec is really old
spec I think it doesn't even use the
latest hey B&F syntax it's old yes so so
as a question maybe this working group
wants to revise this it's rate the rise
quota
and I'm sort of half volunteering Dave
Cridland and I had a proposal like six
eight years ago which expired which was
trying to talk more about different
Quatro routes and quote usages and other
things so there is something to build on
if you want to do this interesting I I'd
say probably let's clear a little bit of
the decks first before you add another
thing in but yes I must be part of rf2
right sorry about that
it could also be part of it I'm at four
F - right let's talk about this later
we have a couple of additional quota
types in the Tsarist server we have a
quota number of folders so because
that's one resource that doesn't count
towards your quota see can't create an
infinite number of folders you can set a
maximum and you can fetch X number
olders extension we have a quota for
annotation usage separately to mail
usage so that the number of per message
annotations and per mailbox annotations
gets counted as well again so that you
can't store infinite data and something
that's not being counted you need limits
for everything that a user can do or
there's an abuse vector so
for this document I suggest there is you
know one or two sentences as per comment
from Chris and the discussion that
followed but I'm I'm almost tempted for
you to start working group last call now
and we just take it as a one working
group Lascaux comment okay do this so
that we can get this one quickly I think
it's really you know in a good state
excellent everybody is happy creases
happy with this we've got a working
group last call with with a comment
saying greater than so hint-hint chairs
can send the working group last call
message today yes hopefully today it's a
very busy day all right next up for
we've got here Stefan save date yes well
this one open issue there lets me
discussed on the main this and it's what
to do if we have a mailbox a text duck
she doesn't actually support the save
data metadata
yeah to actually store it so and if you
have search queries that involve that
particular save date what to do and also
if you have the multi mailbox search
extension you can spend multiple
mailboxes with your search and if one of
those of a few of those don't support
save date what do we do with the query
right Alexi here I don't think client
will cope very well if you fail such
exam with an extension and there is no
there is no signal coming on mailbox
open that you don't support this so the
client cannot actually know without
trying so I suggest either make the
fairly silent or the way for the select
to come back with the you know I don't
know no safe date or something factories
that the response code or something like
that and then here with naughty mailbox
search you know if you just do it silent
or
there is a way of returning response
code saying well some mailboxes didn't
support this but I carried on anyway so
I'm not speaking for myself I'm not too
worried about the multi mailbox search
case I think that's unlikely to be the
kind of place where you would need this
yes Chris Neil and I we actually
implement multi-valve our search and and
so my preference would be if Dell we
don't have any mailboxes that don't
support safety we've got a proprietary a
private extension for save date so it's
good it's being standardized so I'm all
all good with this but if the way I
would want to handle it is if a mailbox
didn't support save date I treat that
query term as equivalent to internal
date yes so that is yeah that is that's
and whether or not you get signaling of
whether about a mailbox supporting save
date I don't really care I don't I don't
see anything useful a client can do with
that signaling so I don't care if you
signal or not okay I can I'd like to
tell you the use case where I'm worried
about this which is that you do an auto
purge after one month on a mailbox si
save dat query and if you do that
against a mailbox that doesn't support
save date and messages that were moved
in there but we're old will disappear
immediately which is not the intended
behavior I actually heard from the main
programmer of Java that in some cases we
actually use the current dates at the
moment where it becomes relevant and
then it's safe to cash so there's a
separate store and yeah that's you how
applicable that is to other systems so
the client figures that out when it
first sees the message ash was that that
moments the defect the second storage
doesn't support it but the cache will
and then it will be in the index so
this is very my view of the end-user
using something like this would be
exactly with a multi mailbox search
where show me the messages that got
stuffed somewhere yesterday so multi
mailbox would be an issue but I agree
with Chris on how to deal with that
which means that you'll you'll break
that case you know but you won't find
all the messages but that's the way it
is yeah I I think the client needs to
know whether it was broken for any of
mailboxes I think that's what we're
arguing because the client might
potentially do something else or decide
you know if this is Verge messages from
the last months maybe I'm not going to
do this the Younger is fine because
sorry Stefan did you want to finish well
we had an initial proposal to return an
additional response in The Selecter
reply right so yeah I would indicate
it's not supported or it is supported
not sure which one is better but I'm
really happy with the amended Libre
Office is crashing on me right yeah why
I suppose just for completeness you
could have a search term saved eight
supported which would allow you to
construct searches for any case that
that is better than the two things I
came up with yeah the part I mean I'm
suggesting this I'm not convinced it's a
good idea because if the problem I have
with it is is clients tend to not do
this sort of thing right in yo III I
think I mean I don't consider it really
a hack it's it's a it allows you to
construct searches that that do what you
want based on the presence of the
extension ok can you elaborate
it sorts of boolean flag so you know if
you want to do if you want to construct
a search where it's you know uses save
date or internal date then you you you
mix this flag in with boolean logic and
have the search covering both or if you
want to do a search that's for purging
then you mix this flag in and with
current date okay I'll send that to the
mailing list so we can consider it okay
yeah I mean I maybe I kind of like
Chris's idea this is very because it
solves the problem of the purge thing
you can eliminate the mailboxes that
don't support it from your purge it
doesn't solve the problem of the use
case that I had where I want to see what
I added to my mail store in the last two
days and I'm just not gonna I'm still
not going to be able to know about that
from them if there are some mailboxes
that don't support this feature but
that's okay all right so I think the
conclusion here is let's take us to the
mailing list this there's a favorite of
discussion still to have yeah I'm just
thinking about the use key so from again
I'm making some some assumptions here
but I suspect that you're probably going
to support it for your personal
mailboxes or none of them or for example
all shared mailboxes or none of them I
think so you're unlikely to not support
it for trash where it's probably the
most useful right so but probably we
should have a text about this saying
that if you choose to implement this
consider this carefully I yeah I kind of
wonder we're speculating on this dude is
there really we really expect servers to
be to support it for some mailboxes and
not others in the general case and
okay right different namespaces but
that's different from different
mailboxes in the same namespace and I my
view is that I don't think any server is
really gonna support it for some
mailboxes in what in a given namespace
and not others so I think really what
we're thrashing about on something
that's not going to be a problem in
practice yeah so the main issue is how
it behaves in the case where it's not
supported and we do need to have both a
well-defined answer to that and and a
way to detect it yeah cool
so this will go to the mailing list and
for further discussion next up is
special use it's the registry actually
tickets for this draft yes no tickets
one of them is a we need to create a
registry of special use with IANA I
don't know if someone has already taken
that or what the plan was for that
that's all right that's in my draft so I
think we should just leave it there yeah
and again we'll get to that in a minute
okay so just just define me mmm come on
excellent so that does this mean we wait
behind Barry's draft for Cola can wait
synonym swear together we can send them
through together we can send this
through ahead of time just have a an RFC
editor note if necessary to say that it
has to wait for the registry creation
but I don't think it's going to be an
issue because I can't see that my
document is going to take any
significant time to finish and I will
need some time through the fixed dose
came up
come on the examples cool all right so
we wait for another draft and then I
believe it's ready to go to work and go
to law school
once that wordings put in there yeah
excellent and that's all that counts
office thank you
next we have the proposed additional
work and we're pretty much on time
according to the agenda so let's start
with special it's important okay and the
first bullet is me and the second bullet
is what it does the the background is
that as I said in Singapore the guy from
Google and I wrote this up a long time
ago and it just sort of it got discussed
a little bit and and sat and so I
brought it back up for this working
group I've made one row of changes so
there's a zero one out there now and
that covers all the comments that have
been made except for the elimination of
spurious words a spurious word in there
that is queued up for the zero-zero
working group version should this
working group adopted so I asked the
chairs to call for objections to taking
this on and then as soon as I post the
0-0 working group version I will ask the
chairs to working group last call it
because I think we're ready with it yep
absolutely
are there any objections to Neil Jenkins
just be registry that we're creating
we're going to want to reuse with came
up here and might be useful for the
registry actually to note when if
there's something that if the if
registrations apply to both I don't need
to just check in your FSM I mean we
won't need to say in the registry that's
specific about Jim Apple I'm up I'm
clean your things like in J map you just
say you're using this registry so it's
not problem I mean unless I don't think
there is any special information that
you need in the register do you so well
for example in terms of differences
in j-mac there's an inbox special use
because there's not it's not a fixed
name you can have a localized name
unlike I'm IMAP so there's no current so
if you added that at special use
registry would that also apply to IMAP
or would that be Jamie phone me I will I
will add a column to the registry for
use restrictions or something like that
thanks Kristen you and the other option
is to put that in the Jay Maps back in
the I on a consideration of the Jay Maps
back where you say where you add the you
modified the registry to allow use
restrictions so that's a little icky
because you've in the j-man spec you
register the IV inbox special the inbox
special use and there's nothing an IMAP
that says that doesn't apply here so I
would rather have something in the
registry that says that this applies to
all uses of the all users of the
registry unless specified here and then
in the Jay map case you can say Jay map
only yes I'm okay with that
um I was about to add to the bike shed
by saying would put it out in a separate
document but it's probably not necessary
sir excellent so everyone's happy right
we have had no objections Barry's going
to upload a new draft which is going to
go straight to work improve last call
and we'll have a registry by next week
good work team all right next is me the
unique card a draft which I wrote a few
days ago just a procedural thing for
just to make sure everybody understands
what the registry but the registry
actually gets created when the ie when
the iesg approves the document not when
its publishes in RFC so you actually get
the registry on the soon side of things
excellent unique ID I wrote the first
draft using names that were derived from
the xgm google names
everyone said funny idea why don't you
make them match jamup names
so I did that I've published a draft
zero one which has the matches of I map
names instead of Eminem's instead there
was debate over whether the syntax for
the status response should put brackets
around the value since it is not an
integer it's not a simple value
Aleksey it's your draft that we're
messing with here for somebody who
didn't get a chance to of show radio
draft can give you do you have an
example yes I do because I I think I
need to double check status might have
it item as a possible value so if you
have sixty four-bit thing there it's
it's still an item but so I would prefer
you you reuse the syntax yes cool all
right so this is draft so I wanted to
ask Alexia direct question about forty
four sixty six so there is a restriction
in forty four 60s I raised this issue
there is a restriction in 44 sixty six
that says the arguments to status items
are either a number or a parenthesized
list in the syntax and I wanted to know
why you did that was done and why you
didn't just allow a string as well
I don't remember yeah so I think we
probably didn't have example of a string
at the time okay I think I probably have
an action item I think in this case yeah
I'm quite happy to make it parenthesis
list with an a string you know that's
absolutely fine it's the real question I
think for me is whether there exist
client implementations which would be
confused by having a bear a string
rather than an a string in a list
because I know certainly with our fell
client libraries does wound up with an
extra level of indirection to either
item that was sort of the reason why
there was a restriction on a regular
syntax so that client well coins are
more likely to generate these things but
if the different components is trying to
parse it then it should be able to skip
the stuff that doesn't understand that's
why you want to put it in it garance but
let me come back to you on this oh and
there are on where they think it's okay
syntactically so that that's one
question about the idea the other
question about the IDS which we do not
have sorry
crushed can't bring the slides back up
here there we go again I haven't put it
up on the slide for this but the other
big question is the format of IDs do we
allow one to 255 characters of seriously
crushed again of random crap or do we
limit it to a subset of characters Neil
and I are discussing this over breakfast
this morning said that URL safe base64
care
per set seems like a sane set of
characters that's a disease in capital
and lowercase 0 - 9 - - and underscore
that's that gives you 64 code points
that you can encode your ID in allowing
more efficient representation than pure
hex but it's still safe for all the
contexts JSON or URLs in which you're
likely to see one of these things so if
your client doesn't understand about
escaping things properly it will still
not break anything this is based on
feedback from aren't from the list we're
planning to do exactly the same thing
with IDs and in J map as well like this
seems very sane excellent I will update
the text to limit it to that so work
items from here for Alexi to look into
the syntax for the status response for
me to look into the document in the IDs
so there are three things that this
gives you it gives you a mailbox ID as a
status response which is supposed to but
not absolutely required to remain the
same when you rename a mailbox so in
every case there isn't a potential
implementation which you can do without
requiring any additional data storage
you wind up with a less efficient
behavior but a rename doesn't guarantee
you the same mailbox ID at the far end
of every name if the server has no way
of storing an ID no Dinkins just keys
why cuz wouldn't in that case you just
not implement this extension if you
can't actually provide any useful data
again it's where you have different
things supported by your server some
mailboxes support all this some don't or
is where you could do unique IDs on the
messages but not the mailboxes yeah for
example or any of those cases you can
still generate a thing but it's not well
so it's nice
I think this particular extension client
waters are actually probably not pretty
quickly or like a lot cuz it's really
useful and knowing what they can rely on
is kind of I don't know I guess I guess
and also getting something useful but it
pointless if you say you implement it
and then don't actually give any useful
information from it yeah I used to give
them an idea that they can use as a
cache key again sorry
so I come throughout the draft yet but
maybe you want to split the capabilities
into mailbox ideas and message edges I
don't know the downside of that is that
if you're likely to implement one
another that might be around it'll be
fairly rare it will it will either be
all or nothing
yeah one thing in particular that I was
careful not to mandate was threading
because that's charge learning
strategies is much more complex than
just storing any code if everything
thank you there has been some debate
over whether it should be nil or whether
it should be a string value derived
somehow from the mail message email ad I
am in favor of nil because it gives
information the argument in favor of
having me having it be the same as the
message ID and then you know it's the
same thing
Gmail responded they used the same ID
for both we used to use an ID that was
obviously derived it was the first n
characters of the message ID and we
changed it in our server deliberately so
that they didn't look the same so that
someone some client author looking at a
message ID and a thread ID didn't say I
can derive one of these from the other
with some string string manipulation and
we didn't want that so we now XOR it
against a number that I picked out of
somewhere other and hard-coded in the
sauce the
it doesn't matter but it just means it
doesn't look the same all right so
there's there's some worker there and
probably a little bit more discussion of
what to do it's ready on the list
because we clearly didn't have consensus
amongst the people have been discussing
that so far so I will take that back to
the list as well but you can ask whether
people are happy to take it as a working
group document yes because I think we're
so blessed passionately discussing and
because we're public here yeah all right
any objections to taking it sa working
group document jabba anyone give him a
moment Alex he just as a participant
haven't been talking about this for
years so I think that's a good yes this
election from Jeff and they the
discussion on the mailing lists in the
last few days has has been people came
for it so there hasn't been anyone
saying no y-you don't miss excellent hey
Lexie I have your slides I will pull
them up now after I kill off the
multiple copies of crashed libreoffice
that are still running here so yes just
as a side note it's very useful to to do
slides when you already present it in
this few years back i think it was like
three or four years ago when actually
presented and this one was in Absaroka
group back then
I always fullscreen full-screen mode and
it's come back over here thanks
alright maybe I'll just do it in mostly
fool that's right there you go sorry
Linux how does it even work math
over here and okay yeah I don't I'm not
going to go through the history of this
I think I've been working on the
document for years now and three or four
years and it has been 15 years since I'm
at full of one next slide please
alright there's a question from Java
from Stefan saying a red eye map for Rev
too long ago wonder what if anything has
changed so just depends which version
you've read but I think I'm trying to
summarize all changes so far in this
slides so for the most part this is
presentation of how I view this
obviously if we take it into the working
group different people have different
opinions so we can tweak things but this
is where I'm coming from with this
document so three main goals one is we
have lots of useful extensions that have
been deployed since I'm up for f1 and
that they make clients joke much easier
they're relatively widespread so let's
add them to the document at the same
time this is not a major rewrite of I'm
up for f1 most of us already implement
these extensions these are just minor
tweaks and there should be a section
just saying you know what you need to do
update on the server to be compliant and
the other thing is you should be able to
implement both imap4 for everyone under
F 2 on the same port because you use
enable for Emma for f2 that serves as a
switch for the server
this mm-hmm excuse me this is Barry
should we put ID I haven't read this
recently
should we roll the list extensions and
quota into here
hey let's defer this in too late in the
slide I have a slide on this here all
right so next slide there are three set
of changes that I was planning for this
document roughly speaking additions as
in adding common extensions just to the
base clarifications and fixes you know
updating references and then at the end
the probably the most difficult bit is
taking a few things away that we think
is really obsolete so the first set of
changes is I've folded all the errata
I had dated CLS recommendations Chris
published one document on
recommendations for MEA and you know
that effect this document I had a
separate RFC about Els or identity
verification so both of these are now
referenced then I added response codes
and pieces of I'm a PI BNF which I think
was more relevant into the to this next
slide now this slide is talking about
various extensions that I already added
I can talk
each point where people can just treat
volume or parties making protocol more
symmetrical like adding an unselect
edging your ID plus because we're you
know in the I'm up for f1 we have some
commands which are only using message
numbers some use both your IDs or
message numbers and you know the way
your G+ extensions that made it more
complete Toby's in discussion here like
whether we should be doing literal -
rather than literal + fine given that
that was ours today okay gives you a
nice balanced usage fine then also add
very common things like special use
which is very popular namespace bits of
list extended it's not fully integrated
I think there is some work to do basic
syntax and basic extensibility is there
because we have so many extensions that
throw and us use enable because you want
to coexist with them a fateful one you
search instead of search really but the
syntax more compact
blah-blah-blah-blah-blah few other
things also our literal + I'm happy to
discuss literal - idle look at appendix
B it should list no I'm sorry sort of
has to list one list is the changes
already done and that the list is
changes planned with some extensions
marked is being done but I'll make it
clear in the next revision next slide so
future directions I would like to take
this clarify a few things like booty
structure and how its generated for
different my messages I think them are
for f1 had an extended example to which
I have to refer to every time I have a
problem with a client or the server on
this but I think we can have more
examples to actually show special cases
in particular folded message with
message RFC 802 because it's really
special case
every time then there are a few key
boards that I think are in common use
that I would like to add and maybe
fishing is another one and junk but we
can discuss order no drinking's is a
reason they need to be there when they
were in the registry now and we just say
refer to the registry yes the reason is
that well at least as far as I know
there are servers that don't implement
extensibility they don't implement
arbitrary keywords or there are servers
that have limits the one that have
limits are less problematic but the one
that don't implement for example
Microsoft Exchange for them I think
listing the one that we really care
about is important so if they can
upgrade easily then they can it yeah
this is Barry I think in general listing
the ones we think are important is
useful anyway I mean saying really these
are no longer extensions these are
things we consider part of the base I
for those of you who came in like by the
way we're officially five minutes over
in time but we have a half hour break
before the next session so we decided
we're quite happy to keep running on I
see no no problem with that right and
then I think the one thing which is I
haven't done is we do a lot of
extensions to status and also status
with lists so I think probably adding
this to the spec would be also good idea
next slide
right I know it's potentially at home or
something that we might talk a lot about
this is things that I think we should
take out if chairs want to discuss them
now or not though these things are you
know you tf7 encoding for mailbox I
think the world has moved to utf-8 to a
large extent I think we should accept
utf-8 that I'm up for that
one implies that you can use them but
doesn't provide enough details
I suggest we change the same
tax service can still encode them to you
gf7 internally if they want to support
IMAP for f1 so on the UTF seven mailbox
names I the way I'd lean is allow
clients to express mailbox names in
utf-8 in the protocol but the server
must downgrade the media to UT f7 for
for backwards compatibility we're trying
to run both ports now if if a client
does enable utf-8 they go away they go
away if it but you know I know that's
clunky but you're not going to break any
software if you do that well because
this already requires enable IMAP for f2
I think that's sort of similar to enable
utf-8 and you just have utf-8 clean
mailbox names and the server can store
them a in modify view to f7 on the
alright there's still some issues with
encoding of separator if you have a
mailbox name it has the separator
encoded in it as modified UT f7 you
still can't express that as utf-8
cleanly a good point some you know add
this to the note I'll I'll have a look
here I would all up for mailbox names to
be a list of individuals names rather
than a this is separator but this is
ship um and then I'm not trying to get
him to this you at all but there is only
one through satellite oh really
that every server should implement I
remind that I agree then the other thing
is take out the recent flag which I
think most of the people find it to be
useless and it's just such a pain to
implement it requires extra local
mailbox if there are multiple clients
accessing the same mailbox
free disclosure I will you know the
server I'm working on just never we just
ignore this through this requirement in
I'm up for that one I think nobody
complain and the other thing is there is
unseen response code and mailbox open
first and seniors and authorities out I
think most clients don't care and
clients that care can issue such a
command for this so yes and if you have
a search you can ask for the first match
exactly you get the same girl yeah you
do men he said yeah okay no no that's
too much from jabbar
backwards-compatibility deserves nods
not fully aware of all the
implementation headaches udders declare
a winner definitely think that binary
body encoding should be included in
Homer forever to want to take the
opportunity to have a BNF checked and if
necessary corrected has a be enough in
this draft been given much formal
analysis yet that Sean Leonard I'm not
entirely sure what formal analysis is in
this case most of the things I've done
is existing a BMF last pieces of I'm a
baby NFRC 44 66 it's entirely possible
I've made a mistake but this will go
through three jewels so we'll have to
make sure let's try to before it and I
didn't understand that I mean you rat
you appeared to run a couple of things
together I didn't understand a bit about
compatibility what he's looking for
they're definitely think binary body
encoding should be included in the
before that there was stuff about
countability
okay I grated making it clean backwards
compatibility also deserves a nod not
fully aware of all the implementation
headaches to declare a winner though
that's that's okay so it's a question to
Sean
is Alexei his original comment that you
can just you can run this in parallel
with imap4 red one is that sufficient to
deal with the compatibility for the
moment hi okay sorry those were actually
separate comments to separate separate
parts my point about compatible or my
point about making it clean in backwards
compatibility specifically was
addressing the UTS 7 vs utf-8 discussion
because other people in the jabber list
were chiming in about making it clean so
I just wanted to clarify that's a
separate thing from my other comments
okay yes I recognized that it was that's
why I was trying to figure out where the
dividing line was cuz the whole thing is
once yeah I hadn't I hadn't been aware
of the earlier one at night I'm saying
okay thanks okay okay no problem yeah
the binary body encoding and the stuff I
said after about 18f are totally
separate yep I agree with the binary so
binary is actually one of the following
slides so yeah it's bad come back
well so we're getting backward
compatibility there is actually a short
sentence with a short section which just
stop sentence they're saying it's okay
but I think we probably need a bit more
tax Anna and the purpose of it we need
to help out implementers to maybe have a
list of all the things they need to che
change if they want to start from Lima
for f1 to bring it up to day to this so
right next slide so okay I think binary
I would personally like to add it to the
protocol and we can ask on the mailing
list and I would also like to get three
devel sub because we have list extended
which absorbed the whole thing it makes
it's a bit easier but
not talking about Elsa okay the I would
have two things the eai utf-8 stuff
should be part of the base and quota as
an optional feature I think it's better
to have it in the base rather than as an
extension but but specify it as not
required to be supported it needs to be
with editor hat on my preference is to
have a section on other recommended
extensions and don't pull quote Ian
because this is going to be at home I
know where as in right okay and and this
can a the reference to holder FC where
you published or whatever gets it gets
to replace it right yeah I'm good if you
say these these are also recommended
that that's good okay a couple issues I
want to raise the first one is I'll note
our server implements list status and
will implement list rights and will not
implement list extended the reason we
won't implement list extended is because
it allows multiple multiple mailbox
wildcards if you if you restrict this to
single mailbox will do list extended I
was young and ambitious at the time I
think I can't I I can live with this I
think it's yeah I tell you a secret with
in our so we didn't implement it either
so making that work you can sue
dualistic standard I'm at sort of to it
[Music]
okay well I I think these days you can
just pipeline multiple requests if you
really want you know listing box unless
also three of these and everything in
this namespace so it's actually not yeah
I already have to ship so yeah I
I think that should be ready reason you
know reason both change yeah
okay the second thing I want to consider
is either mailbox names or NFC
normalized or the server can change a
mailbox name when you create it this is
Barry I think for former what would you
what change it how I would change it to
if it's not if it's not NFC I change it
to NFC on creation I can't do that in
the I'm at bass back because of the
modified UTF seven ward right no I
absolutely that the server needs to
enforce the NFC absolutely Sean hi I
don't have a lot of experience with
changing mailbox names for normalization
purposes but I would say that one way to
analyze it is to look at how file
systems do it and the advantages and
pitfalls the consequences of what when
they do that because some file systems
don't change at all and they survive
others like I think apples HFS
normalized to NF D and that has
different consequences so I just wanted
to make that up so really I'll tell you
the reason I'm asking for this is apples
file system leaks this crap all over the
place including into you know and
mailbox names and everything and add it
and then when you take that and try to
feed it into like a an index search
system
you got to normalize it and it just
creates this disaster so that we have
unique odd days on mailboxes now and if
we defined a return of the unique ID at
the time you created the mailbox you
could use that to discover if anything
weird it happened to it that way that
would be adequate for
the problem may be but the problem is if
you're using systems where you might
type in a mailbox name then you're and
you have issues with the normalization
so and the reason showing from NFC
rather than an FD is simply that we've
been using NFC pretty consistently in
other protocols yeah to be clear I think
if you have to standardize on a
normalization form using the NFC would
be more appropriate because of the IETF
way I'm fairly certain once you have
something in one normalization form such
as NFD it should go or transmute to NFC
okay it just means it gets recomposed
although there's a lot of Unicode
stop that you have to deal with I mean I
hope nobody's using NF KC for anything
but yeah okay that's I'll stop now
however you have created an action item
for Unicode a draft to have both append
and create potentially return the ID it
straight away interesting yeah yeah
that's that is really interesting okay
okay so Alex e as a participant I don't
object to the normalization of some text
about this but I need to we need to
think about the text how you returned
the new name to the server I would also
like to possibly fold unique ID into
this back I would like to fall
to the document which is already
specified so hopefully it will be RFC
you know before we actually do this so
I'll be pushing that one pretty hard
yeah basic that the point is try to
avoid too much experimentation with
stuff yeah you know we don't want to put
something there which doesn't work I
want to do minimal changes yeah to there
if there's a safe way to returnest as
part of the create response then that
shouldn't be too difficult especially
now that there's no encoding issues
okay I'm support about adding binary the
proposal to fold in all of the utf-8
stuff from AI I'm not sure the mailbox
name stuff from the e aí spec absolutely
[Music]
actually the new EA I expect dropped all
the username stuff so so you have to use
plain if you're using a non ASCII
username you have to use authenticate
plain yes so yeah yeah you could
deprecated login no we can't actually no
I could but but it's nice to think about
you can't can you enable before login I
guess if you can enable this before
login then you could deprecated things
if you're not enabling things before our
syndication
I can say from our proxy architecture
that would be a freaking nightmare
because you don't even know which
back-end you're on before he was
indicated you might wind up unable de
ghin once you logged in I think there
might be one or two more slides just
scroll down right okay I want to get to
this point and the rest we can take to
the mailing list about a specific puzzle
were to add on so for Chris go back to
the previous thing what
I want the imap base if we're gonna Rev
the I'm at base I want the I'm at base
to support the ei I stuff if you have an
AI message you know the EI I downgrading
and all that crap that it does I yeah I
think we need to think about I am
supportive of trying to figure out how
to make it at least ready for it but on
bullet 2 on this slide I'll be I'll help
you and clearly that means that I agree
with the first one although as I said
earlier I think we should not we can we
can adopt it I don't think we should
crank it up until we get some more of
the documents off the queue well that
means you and I can still work on it in
the meantime right my preference is to
adopt it and we just take our time and
then I mean but but not deliberately
trying to be too slow but just you know
there is no pressure and then we'll
figure out it as we go all right I'm
happy to call for objections to adoption
at this point anybody fantastic or I
will adopt the work and the agenda at
this point said any other business
there's nothing else so I'm not going to
bother changing back to the slides so I
had published a draft a while ago that
is expired which was the unauthenticated
extension and at the time I brought it
up there was no working group and and
not enough interest expressed in
implementing it to get it adopted by yo
ad I would like this draft done because
it's an it's an interim
I've implemented a private extension but
it's an interoperability thing so the
purpose of this is when you have a you
have some sort of appliance or
application that's talking to an IMAP
back-end on behalf of multiple users it
allows that appliance to have a
connection pool and leave the
connections open and switch users within
the session so that you don't have to
renegotiate SSL or anything like that so
that's the motivation specific use cases
of it are like a voicemail a ploy Smail
front end for IMAP that would feed
voicemails in or j-mac proxy to an IMAP
server would also you know might also be
interested in a connection pool it
sounds like it fits in one of these
earlier slides we'd make a protocol more
symmetrical that yeah now it you never I
do not want it I don't think it belongs
in I met for up to I think this is just
a separate extension you implement if
you had if you you put and I am the
draft actually advises you leave it off
by default yeah I I haven't I haven't
read the draft I assume it it clears old
enable flags and everything else that's
been done as part of the honest indicate
yes yes yes this is Barry with that
edition I'm happy with it the server I
wrote has severe isolation stuff in
there and I would not implement it but
great I have actually implemented it so
although it was experimental branch so I
was never turned it on I know I haven't
that sounds to me like a call for
adoption are there any objections to us
adopting this piece of work excellent
we'll adopt your expired draft and start
working on coming I this is Sean Renard
I'm in favor of adoption of this draft
that being said yeah isn't there like a
procedure supposed
the list and give it three weeks or
something like that or not oh absolutely
I wish it wasn't an Epicure you need to
double-check yes I
he's our ad at the moment but might my
view on on this sort of thing is that
the the working group is agreeing to
take a starting point it's not a big
thing and if the if the working group
later says now we've thought about this
event we've talked about it it's full of
get rid of it we can get rid of
that I really don't think we need to go
through a formality of making it wait
two weeks but we will defer to our ad I
think my point is you need to ask the
questions are there any objections on
the mailing lists yep I'm already happy
to two four chairs to optimize it
adopted and there is if there is a storm
of objections on the mailing list then
it can be honored I think that's okay
cool I will I will run a call for
adoption later today and and if there
are no objections we start next week
yay for all of the the four things that
we've decided to adopt today making a
stack now ten documents we're working on
at this point unless there's anything
really urgent I'd like to give up this
chair and allow the the next session to
set up because we have run nearly half
an hour over our allocated time thank
you everybody
Thanks cool thank you for this