i'ma show how to get clear to the other
settings so we we started a young
working group meeting by the way i i
think i recommend you to move maybe come
to the first rose i think it would be
more easy to have a conversation if then
if you sit in the back but feel free I
mean it's just and folks can you make
sure you sign in and the blue sheets
that are circulating because we have to
submit that to the Secretariat later
thank you and thank you very much for
coming to Gaia you all deserve an award
for finding the room in and of itself
this is the global access to the
Internet for all and I was talking to
John crow Croft who's in the back from
Cambridge University he's the one that
came up with a name
so thanks John for naming us and Arjuna
who used to be the co-chair of Gaia and
who deserves an enormous amount of
credit for getting the the group off the
ground and for rallying people around
the world to talk about critical access
issues and one of those people that he's
been rallying is Leandro Navarro and
I'll let Leandro introduce himself
hi I'm Leandro I'm associate professor
at the University at political Catalunya
which is a university in Barcelona and
I'm also involved in
relativities with her sock with european
commission and also our executive board
member for the association for
progressive communications so it is a
pleasure to be in this group i've post
member since that model at the beginning
and I hope we can contribute to make it
like even more successful
excellent um what we'll do is the the
agenda is online and I'm going to pull
that up now and what we've been doing
over the last two to three meetings is
bringing people in who are practitioners
in the field researchers obviously
because we're under the IRS yet who are
doing work on whether its network flows
trace routes to take a look at where
traffic is going or isn't everybody from
the African projects to a mo Gareth this
year who's working on that the Internet
Society is doing some traceroute work on
traffic flows in Africa as well but as
Leandra said one of our big focuses has
been on community networks and that's
something that internet society APC
different university researchers and
people in the field are very interested
in and it was part of the plenary
yesterday where we're seeing places
where connectivity isn't and because of
the confluence of cheaper technology
people connecting to each other are
seeing each other at meetings there's
this wealth of knowledge that's
transiting across borders through
meetings like this meetings that I saw a
PC may pull together some of us Steve
song and I were up in Geneva at the
beginning of this week for something
called the World Summit on the
information society forum some people
think it's a talk shop but actually what
we're trying to do is bring more
technologists to these places where
people talk so that we can start to Mary
emerge the talking and the policy and
the regulation with the reality right
sometimes you can't get a project going
because there's a licensing issue small
start-up networks in regions with not a
lot of capital but a lot of human effort
they can't afford a year to get a
license right or an authorization so
we've been trying to work with people to
encourage the idea of giving these small
networks a break helping them out by
giving them social purpose or
experimental licenses to get off the
ground with spectrum or changing
Universal service there are millions of
dollars sitting in banks around the
world that are supposed to help rural
remote and underserved projects you
can't get them started so governments
are beginning to realize that there's an
opportunity to work with technologists
researchers universities people like all
of us to try and promote connectivity
because some of the bigger companies
right now do not see a return on
investment and going in some of those
smaller places that's their model but
we've we've seen models that work at the
local level and some people here here to
tell you about that so don't the photo a
project in Greece very interesting
project I see Lisa is here to talk about
that so I will stop talking anything
else from your saying yeah maybe maybe
one comment is that depending on the
time we have left at the end we should
probably try to discuss about how we
move forward and especially as Jen said
I mean one of the objectives is to
highlight good experiences and maybe if
we discuss about how to make them more
visible how to give them an opportunity
to be known through the means of the RTF
documents that would be very useful in
if you're first-time attendee we've got
to show you the note well it's part of
the drill of the checklist of things I'm
supposed to say
so one make sure you fill out the blue
sheets if you haven't signed up sign up
this note well I'm going to go through
just a reminder of IETF policies in
effect various topics patents code of
conduct it's meant to point you in the
right direction exceptions may apply
there's a patent policy definition and
you can see that each of the the website
if you want to take a look so as a
reminder by participating in the IETF
you agree to follow
have processes and policies if you're
aware that any IETF contribution is
covered by patents or patent
applications that are owned or
controlled by you or your sponsor
you must disclose that fact or not
participate in a discussion as a
participant in or attendee to any IETF
activity to acknowledge that written
audio video and photographic records of
meetings may be made public
given the European rules on GDP are also
if you're in this room does anyone have
a red lanyard on you do okay so I'm
gonna have to ask you do you mind that
this is being recorded because by being
in this room okay thank you
wonderful there's some other people too
so I'm not saying I'm not signaling
anyone out but I want to be very
cognizant that we're aware that if you
see somebody with a lanyard that's
orange or red please don't photograph
them without asking them for their
permission also just this is being
live-streamed so just know that and if
you're comfortable great I know your
face is a can be considered PII right so
as a participant of sorry personal
information you provide to the ITF will
be handled in accordance with the IETF
privacy statement as a participant or
attending you agree to work respectfully
with other participants and please
contact the unn
on buds team that's weird word if you
have questions or concerns about this
anyway there's more information at this
site if you have questions so back to
the agenda we have dirt traulsen who's
up first
and Dirk you'll be speaking from this
microphone and we're going to pull up
your presentation and thank you to
everybody that expressed interest in
coming and we're so happy that you're
here and we'll if you have presentations
for the folks in the live stream and you
weren't able to meet the cue them for
presentations here we're happy to load
your presentations to the website so
that others can see them so over to you
Dirk good Thanks so this is a small
introduction into the field while in the
rifle project that we are conducting at
the moment still the presentation
disjoint
renowned Krishna who stunned a lot of
the legwork in our company and watcher
who can't be unfortunately from goofy
dog net who provided some of the sights
at the end let me give you you see the
URL of the project here so I didn't have
a partner slide at the moment but if you
go to the web site you can see the
partners involved campus university take
the University in Munich Alto but I
might miss a couple of Tallis don't list
them all just look at the web site
it's a neat project that started in
January 2015 it was meant and by the end
of last year but we extended it in order
so by the end of January we extended by
two months in order to conduct the field
trial which you will see in the in the
following slides who is going to last
until the end of next week that's when
the broker usually over and I come to
the next steps at the very end of the
presentation so the talk a bit about the
objective just one slide about we know
what the project intended to do at least
with the field while I'm there a number
of research activities in that project
but I've focused particularly on the
ones that we were looking in the field
trial bit about the architecture
background where this comes from what
we've done what we actually deployed in
the field this is no courtesy to to
Roger who provide a lot of these slides
of what's actually the boxes and bits
and pieces that are employed north of
where they deployed and then a few words
on the next steps so rife a lot of these
easy approach in case you're not
familiar with have a short work and a
long title rife is they should work and
it stands for architecture for everybody
now if they whether or not we've done
but it remains to be seen but definitely
we wanted to utilize a new network
architecture to provide better
connectivity or Internet connectivity
for communities for community networks
with better paying a number of things
that the ones I focused on here which we
try to address in the trial is easy to
deploy meaning a software-based solution
relatively simple to manage performance
benefits for certain IP based services
as well as enabling services there are
otherwise hard to do particular if you
have remote connectivity and you might
have a constraint backhauling
that you might need to overcome
as an architecture backer and this shows
the system architecture that we've
developed as part of this project and a
companying project that we ran the so
called point project which ran in
parallel to ripe and there's a lot of
overlap with respect to the actual
architecture and the technical work so
these two protists collaborated and what
you see here is an edge IP architecture
where we use standard IP devices
obviously like your your home Rooter as
well as your home devices that use all
of them still IP based and we replace
the inside of the infrastructure in the
cloud you see three main components are
forwarding nodes which in our case is
the one that we deployed in the field
file is an SDN switch soft switch and a
an open V switch TM and arvy are terms
that come out of the information setting
networking research and sense for
topology mentioned rendezvous because we
use a nice en information sending
networking abstraction to realize the IP
connectivity on top might sounds a
little bit strange but it allows us to
do things but they're very difficult to
do in a normal IP network at the at the
at the side of them that's why I decide
you see the border gateway so abnormal
activity to peering networks and in the
case of our futile deployment that's
provided through goofy dotnet we use
edge caching solutions to front-load
content which then could be used which
then it's consumed purely in the front
whole network that's our aspect that
mics at these antenna cheaper for some
content services but just front loading
the content and make it available
locally and then we just appear to other
networks these other networks could be
other community networks or they are
just they what you commonly know it's
the normal internet the from the from an
IP perspective they obviously the
biggest requirement was that it must
support the current internet so anything
you're really used to and we used to run
the demo I think I actually pulled up
slides of a guy a presentation I gave
about two and a half years ago so and we
actually ran the demo there where we
just you know open up a Wi-Fi access
point people could connect to it and you
were actually running over it you don't
see any any difference because you just
we noticed that most of what the people
were doing is accessing
funny enough when they went to the wife
access point and probably that would be
slightly different today I don't know so
it must support the Korean Internet
we hope obviously was better performance
and it addresses the affordability and
key aspects in the sense of but that we
can provide advantages over normal IP
and I come to this one in a bit the
foundations are for other proposition
that we've built throughout the projects
and one of these is the so-called
surrogate I have a separate slides on
those these are alternative service
endpoints that are deployed within the
network in order to either reduce
latency or cost or a cost of the
deployment and this is all achieved
through what we call the IP or HTTP over
ICN solution if we filled in these two
projects and arrival points we also were
looking at new services either by using
native ICN in selected areas are we
haven't done an awful lot of this but
you have as you know this is actually a
different picture I would be blessed in
this picture but you also have obviously
access to the actual eyes here and under
light that we are using and therefore
you can deploy in native ICM services
the project just hasn't done that much
on this because they're totally separate
ICN work that's currently ongoing in the
community but you could utilize this
also DTN based services as one
particular form of an ICN we have
working on delay-tolerant networking and
in the trial that is currently based on
this architecture we replace temporarily
the for the last week which should be
next week we're replacing actually the
the trial with attn based file even
though I think the last information I
have is meant to run in parallel to this
file usually have some spare capacity
the deployment flexibility we want is
this is kinda like a terminology we
developed in the project together with
Roger age to allow us to go from really
well-planned
networks these are not the networks
we're really talking about well-planned
means I have a relatively good
flexibility and ability to actually
place infrastructure that's not always
the case right we are more after well
connected less well planned and this
means when the community secures the
place that's probably where you put it
that might not be optimal you might want
to use the church tower but you can't
get to the church tower so it you just
make do with whatever you get
so it's more this connectivity well
connect connected is is the local
connectivity we are using with directed
by face rather if you well connected the
connectivity itself is quite good but
again it might be saw optimal from a
planning perspective we also were
interested where the DTN the DTN
deployments come in unless well
connected and very little planning
almost down to random encounters and
this is obviously where you know your
your fixed infrastructure is literally
out of the window and you're trying to
make do with whatever connectivity
that's currently available at any point
in time this is why we had the DTN angle
in our trials as well the the surrogate
placement knows that is we experiment in
the very beginning very much with the
edge caches which are which are normal
HTTP proxy caches but they are pre
placed they offer pre place content and
we replaced this with it with an idea of
surrogate servers endpoints the
difference they are is it keeps the it
exposes the service under the fully
qualified domain name of the original
service so it isn't working in a proxy
mode or in a portal mode
Tallis our cellular operators has a
solution that is portal based and
therefore it is obviously exposed to the
end-user because you have to access
condom wire portal in this case we are
really replicating the server's endpoint
in the frontal network and the entire
service is exposed under the original
fully qualified domain name that
obviously requires that you have name
authority to do that which were selected
service that you have this is the
architecture we build I won't go into
too much detail but the main message
here is but the move was to really move
from content retriever from pure caching
to entire service routing over ICN so
you really front all the entire service
endpoint into the frontal frontal
network under this name authority and
therefore both content as well as
computation is front loaded and out of
it uses traffic obviously even more so
you say computation content the latency
is there for one target so really want
to make sure that don't only your video
asset is there but anything that's
around it in terms of computation is in
the front a whole network as well not
that relevant for the community of
course you haven't done it but we pushed
it in other deployments at the moment
further where we have
advanced infrastructure is for instance
network function virtualization based so
the new platform that we have built from
in the digital side deploys entirely
through an earthly we demonstrated this
this year where you can boot a pristine
infrastructure at municipal scale within
about ten minutes and you have your
entire routing infrastructure deployed
and you can run your service that's off
it but again all of the infrastructure
is essentially the same we deployed in
the community that book is a slightly
more powerful their normal x86 white
boxes it's just in the municipal and
that's the deployment we have in Crystal
those are you racks so they're actually
really powerful Dell service while the
community networks be deployed are
slightly more resource constrained but
the computer architectures design
alright so therefore we see this still
as relatively interesting once you have
advances in the in the in the
convenience of structure you can easily
run those in community networks maybe in
a furious time good what have you
actually deployed so the actual feed
part takes place in Tarragona that's not
the city that's the community which is
in Catalonia it's a production network
so it's actually they're real people are
part of the trial which is also it
explains a little bit our delay if you
fiddle with people's real internet you
want to make sure you're not screwing
this up so that's a bit of the issue
it's a production network and people are
actually really accessing at the same
time the links are technology link
technology is Wi-Fi so there is directed
wire between the actors so called super
nodes there are six super nodes in the
infrastructure and the access points are
15 access points was more than 40
households that are being served julia
scrubber truck what's the scale of the
map actually these these these are a few
a few kilometers between you know
sometimes several hundred meters or it
provides a mean word environment some of
the things I said that complicated
things was because it is a trial and I
come to this you see this and to set up
and I'll show one of the boxes in a
second it's because they have parallel
connectivity we do because this is a
field trial is the experimental software
we have normal IP routing software in
how running to the IP over ICN one and
that
learn some of the complexity in the
setup way I mean we can switch
immediately between our experimental
trial and normal off shelf IPS and that
increases the complexity of the
configuration that's one of the reasons
why we had to delay in our trial there's
also power also the way the statute was
you should be actually the other way
around is because we staged everything
in the lab so we started at first and
then we go into trial where we take a
very simple sweet super note
model test everything we have on test
Suites and if it's working it's being
deployed in the actual in the actual
village so we've also meant to make sure
that we are not messing too much with
people so they should say the the router
boards we are using in in the trial
point-to-point links to other super
nodes so these these are the the the
distant are point-to-point links and
then the actual point-to-point links to
the access points and we have two models
of deployment one is the where the
access points are IP devices or where
the access points are IP over ICN
devices it's a different form of
deployment which has different benefits
which is why we try both of them the the
the reason why you see always the
everything in pair in in threes is
because we have a management VLAN setup
if you have an IP only a VLAN setup as
well as an IP over IC and that's the
parallel setup we just have to provide
to in order to not mess with people we
switch in a few seconds from a 40 IP or
I see and if our trial fails we're
switching over in a couple of seconds on
to the normal IP network so they the
households don't really quite notice
something and then we'll repair the
issue and we're switching them back all
right you can get rid of all of that if
you and I come to this in the next steps
if your software stable enough you just
remove all of this nonsense
all right this is really trial stuff and
that's the reason why you know this took
some time to do yeah the compute devices
so these are as a normal commercial
super router boards and the actual
compute infrastructure are embedded ad
devices with full course as if normal
x86 infrastructure on which we're
running the software directly
yeah I won't go into these ones so it's
a dualistic backbone IP or ICN depending
on our boat the ICN backbone is purely
l2 so you run everything straight on l2
and I can give you more on this takes
about 20 minutes longer to explain that
the households are attachable either the
AP level and that means that you know
every household is spawning of an actual
IP or each household has an IP actually
built in these are the two different
boats I mentioned before the core
components are always reach of a yit IP
management connectivity just in order to
login and maintain the software so what
are the next steps that we are really
looking into now this has all turned out
to be much more complicated and the
reason for that is if you actually again
if you deploy this in real life of
actionability communities it does take
significantly longer
so the triose has actually have been cut
short quite significantly and we are
currently in discussions with the
community that goes to comment again
right before to actually continue and
help them to get off the ground with
leaks to a an extension of the trial
this would run after the project of the
project finishes next week and we made a
commitment to the community to continue
to try it for another year to gain
insights and also to switch the software
that goes back to the comment I made
before we really need the softest
individual has a new software solution
and we would like to replace the
original software with a new software
return Allah also allows us to simplify
all of the setup because we have
significantly higher trust in our new
software than we had in the original
software and that kind of like makes the
whole VLAN setup significantly better as
it has higher stability better security
there are some security issues with the
current setup because it's experimental
um so if you would really switch this to
production you would get rid of some of
the security things very significantly
we also want to plan to perform planned
experiments some of the benefits that I
was talking about before they do require
some planning with a community for
instance some of the benefits that we
have is in the the community here likes
watching football events and not telling
your PC which clop it is but you can
imagine which club they like watching me
live
and that's a very very particularly
expensive service because if a it goes
white appearing Li which is expensive
and it's usually watched wire HLS
technology is speeding on HTTP level
it's unicast and therefore puts even
more strain on the peering link because
40 households for these claims right we
can cut this down we demonstrated this
in separate trials that we're done in
the second in the sister project and
this is an experiment we are trying to
run with a community next year to have
these type of community and kind of
viewing experience is significantly
cheaper than they are today
okay thank you very much Wow so each
speaker is 10 minutes and we've got
about 2 4 QA but obviously they'll be
around but does anyone have a question
for Dirk
yep please go to the microphone there
are people remotely participating and so
you've got to speak into the mic stand
raised from University of Cambridge you
mentioned that you're switching from ICN
to IP so what are the specific cases in
which are doing that and what are the
implications of that switching the cases
are purely failure so we have watchdogs
in all of the software components and we
switch over in failure cases I said it
takes a couple of seconds to do that and
that's mainly well if one of our
software components as you know some of
them have a couple of issues and we
switch over we can't the soft is not set
up that we can experiment that we can
experiment in parallel we had to run a
trial in another project last year we
actually had powerless setups that
that's even more expensive to do and in
this case we actually bound some people
on an IP netbook some people on an IP or
ICN and we ran experiments in peril or
some and they had no idea it was
randomly done I'm it tossed a coin and
then we looked at the database of it but
they were and we asked them questions
that's quite interesting but it's
actually that's a very complex to set up
and at this scale we didn't want to do
that so this is really faint over only
excellent and we have a question a
remote remember person in Mexico it's
Luis Martinez who runs a network there
I'm gonna try and bring you in Luis give
me one sec go no I can ask your question
hmm so that's not working but Luis had
sent me a note saying you wanted to know
what this how the simulation compares to
reality
well this is reality we have actually
done a number of simulator scale
significant so the communities actually
is a decent size so even here we would
expect to be there still one of the
project deliverables this do that
actually performs the socio-economic
analysis on some of the friends of the
multicast benefits that we are talking
about and the scale is similar to the
child community if your scale is even
more up we've done this in the sister
project where we perform simulations of
significantly higher scale Austin Lewis
you might want to put that out on the
guy a list to ask the question to endure
could respond on the list as well so we
have about 30 seconds John brewer and
SRC and this sounded a lot like what
Fraunhofer are doing with their fit
their Y back project which they've
contributed to Facebook's telecom in for
project how similar and are you working
on the same problems from different
angles
they say similar from the so the caching
work is very similar when actually
Avanti was part of work as well I want
the it was fun the partners I forgot to
mention before so one day say it comes
from the satellite site and the edge
caching I was talking about before is
very similar so they approach their
original education solution be improved
on the education solution but then also
went further by actually looking into
entire service placement so not just
content but the entire service is pre
placed so it takes it on we also have
more frontal work because this project
it was mainly focusing on caching part
and it was using the standard frontal
network we also look specifically with
these IP over ICN solutions at the
improvement of the front hole delivery
in the in the community network
excellent thank you very much this was
fabulous and I appreciate you
participating in Dirk's on the list so
if people have more questions and he's
also here for today yeah excellent
next up is connecting the edges the
UMobile project so TVs are you here
excellent
so each speaker has ten minutes with two
for Q&A and over to you hello this is my
first time in the guy a meeting and this
is a vivid community now I'm sure there
is Emma Douglas coming from Shanthi hi
I'm with a a scenario search sander and
Innovation Center and I'm going to
present you actually research directions
in the in the human world project which
started three years ago and is going to
be concluded in two months from now
one month from now actually the main
objectives of the project were to
develop a consolidated information
centric opportunistic and delay-tolerant
communication platform at the basic idea
was to integrate information with
networking and delay-tolerant working
but finally this led to multiple
research directions that I'm going to
present and other the objective was to
provide an architectural support for the
network heads drive laden a towards a
communication platform for universal
coverage focusing on remote areas or
disconnected areas and drive along the
way new application models and services
from a high level perspective that the
mobile domain starts where they either
in domain the end and they our focus was
actually the other one was to create a
networking platform that will facilitate
communications within
community without the need to
[Music]
communicate with a with some centralized
services and there are some mechanisms
that I'm going to present later the
other idea was to create the
infrastructure again to move services
closer to the to the users when this is
necessary so the what we've done is was
to try to exploit all communication
opportunities try to incorporate DTN in
order to support disruptive
communications actually supporting
devices that may be disconnected in
space and in dive facilitate user and
service mobility create and mechanism in
order to support application data and
computation sharing and create routing
routing mechanism for the for
opportunistic neural networks which
which is based on social based routing
actually social based matrix the apart
architecture is depicted here the blue
boxes are native and the end name data
name definite working mechanisms such as
the end and probably the faces which
other interfaces at the end the end
users know that you talk to other
protocols the the red boxes are what we
have done in the project some of these
here in terms of forwarding we have
created a DTN interface for the end the
end platform to provide its reach
ability and reliability when necessary
we have
done this protocol which is called
opportunistic of past Condon Discovery
weeds can be used in AI in a remote
decentralized network where a new table
this is in the end terminology this used
in order to find data which is of path
let's say not exactly under the root of
on the central nodes of the of the
network and name based replication
priorities where there is some
prioritization mainly focused mainly
used for disaster scenarios were some
data some interests and some content is
via as being forwarded based on the name
and priorities time to live in the
geographic area of dissemination in
terms of routing we have worked on this
opportunistic part of the NBN platform
these are some modifications on the
basic Indian plateau a platform in order
to facilitate communications in
opportunistic scenarios where
connectivity may not be so good we are
working on the dagger protocol which has
a draft in the RTF community with our
partners in and code labs Portugal also
we are with regards to the context
contextualization who we are employing
social metrics in order to improve data
dissemination this is work from work
from our partners again portal in
addition what's route inoko clubs and
censorship
then this contextualization manager is
the one that can pass information not
only to the routing mechanism but also
to any other information other
application that would need this from it
now this sounds like Ambridge
analytically now regarding the we
provide two applications we have the
keyboard based mobile application
sharing this is the mechanism an API
that will allow applicative allows
applications to to share the data so
that if you're in this connected
environment and you don't have you have
access only to an access point or don't
have even access to an access point but
only access to other nodes you can use
an application which can be which is
must be compatible with other
applications to exchange application and
computation data okay regarding the add
service deployment we have created with
a baton we will present some results and
the following presentation we have
created a quality of service mechanism
that can migrate a service from the
central part of the network towards a
remote area and maybe it can be affected
area or anything in case this kind of
services needed in this area we're gonna
see some results later on and migration
this would be the new mobile platform as
a whole meaning that we have an area
which could be a mobile area with hot
spots
along with a hot spots or in this area
we could have also a mobile user service
which is based on a smart phone which is
actually located in this mouthful what
this can be
in this allows communication between end
users and also between the end user
Center divided area and we also are
close to the base base network through
the immobile service manager which can
move services we said towards the
unaffected area that was my presentation
brilliant ok because you were spot-on we
have three minutes and so who has
questions for Sotiris the microphones
here up at the front and if you can make
them as succinct as possible so we can
get in as many as possible
i'm julia scrubber track i have two
questions the first one is does twerk
never told us about the results the
second question is what you are speaking
about note to note communication without
an access points what are the link
layers that work we mentioned wife you
are speaking about node to node
communication without going through an
access points yeah and you mentioned
Wi-Fi direct that's the only link layer
that you yes so we need to make sure
we're speaking into microphones can you
can you yeah go ahead
just because there's a remote
participation and we want them to hear
it and it's being recorded
it's like overlay so you have microphone
come into a mere physical layer a layer
to lie for example in our department we
also pluck the over the type to the
Wi-Fi access voice as well so it can run
over the Wi-Fi or can run over Ethernet
or Wi-Fi the liquid solder or so ever
okay but in the absence of the
infrastructure its Wi-Fi direct that you
use yes yeah okay next question um hi
yeah you've also talked a bit about
receiving data that someone had already
received from the wider internet but had
a cache copy of how do you plan to
validate that that data is actually the
same as the data that the
I mean how you gonna validate signatures
and all that sort of thing on these we
are relying actually only on the
functionality that the endian platform
provides meaning that you can have this
some hostage that can be used yeah but
if you don't have access the internet
you can't validate the signatures that
you would see there sorry again I mean
if you don't have access to the network
itself then validating the signatures
might be more eco well this is another
thing that we're working currently we're
trying to design and decentralized
mechanism for providing the public
infrastructure that that could work
towards this direction we haven't talked
with these problems actually that this
is interesting okay and one other thing
do you have any data that to suggest how
much of that how often a request that
you make actually is something that's
similar enough in your social group that
you would find the data work on no I
don't think I have something
we're having a field study which is more
related with scenario where we need some
kind of services urgently it's a
distraction scenario in three weeks from
now four weeks from now but it's the
most Asian area not actually we're not
using any kind of finally for the record
I should say I'm a mature thank you
right so please announce who you are
when you come up to the microphone and
please keep it really short because we
have about a minute left
hey this is my salad I from University
of Essex you talked about moving
services to affected areas or so I'm
wondering how do you discover affected
areas or disconnected areas and how fast
you can move services well I guess that
the discovery part would be somehow yeah
what we're going to do in at the most
ratios and are is that you can inform a
user that I identified something good
inform using that this again some parts
of what we have is disconnected or
affected it can
and infrastructures network meaning
device-to-device communications creates
a Wi-Fi hotspot and time to pair the
data from the user maybe a photograph or
something and move it towards a
generalized Mississippian service
Protection Authority and then this
Authority would be responsible for
moving the service to the area all right
so basically relaying approach ok are
you looking at the security issues that
comes with that
sorry yeah we're running out of time but
we haven't so much into that but this is
ok we'll talk offline so 6-week
Cambridge okay so we're gonna shut the
line down now for that the next speaker
thank you so TV's yes is mesh networking
so this is the Picasso our mesh
networking we're just mesh networking
this is men okay so I'm just going to
talk shortly in the next five minutes
about our experience with a mesh
networking so this is EMP mesh network
which is a subset of community network
located in the city of Barcelona as as
many of you know if he's the one of the
world is the largest Community Network
were part so basically can be it's a
urban community network of people given
at located in the Barcelona it has
around 80 nose distributed in the center
of location in the stands district of
Barcelona and there are like to speak
place let up connecting these users to
the internet right we have a monitoring
service which is running in the network
at the monitor of the service for the
last five months and we try to find
patterns regarding different metrics
right it's a production network more
than 200 people are using this network
so here you can see some of the what we
say outdoor routers which users are
using basically to build point-to-point
links between them you can see some nano
station and five and three devices so
was to analyze the network from the
local services perspective so is it
possible to run local services in this
network so we looked in three dimension
but one dimension was to analyze the way
the topology of the network than to see
what is the node availability and and
then with distributions right so
basically we wanted to know does the
topology follow some pepper how does it
grow right so it started from this
situation when we have like 30 nodes to
a situation we have 80 nodes so with
time it became a full dimension effort
so one so we we wanted to predict the
growth but we saw that the growth is
unplanned totally unpredictable in this
manner right so yeah it is a fully mesh
network it's becoming fully mesh network
the next thing that we wanted to see was
the node availability basically how our
nodes available or not so basically when
I say availability is the which ability
of nodes in our monitoring system we saw
the 25% of the nodes are less than 90%
of the videos in less than 90% of a low
so this was one metric to include you
know heuristics right and the most
important thing was the bandwidth we
wanted to see what is the performance
like is it possible so we characterize
the bandwidth of the of the ladies from
this five months area and we saw that
there is a high risk
skewed them in distribute wrap 50% of
the links in the network they have less
than 10 megabit per second and the other
50 from 200 megabit per second so what
was the reason so we got like I mean the
it's rather be even better than the
orange connectivity Falana so then we
want to see the reason why and so
challenging
which is the nodes which are the nodes
where the services are deployed right so
some and this is the this is the MP 18
based on the mystic we went home by home
to these community users and we deployed
raspberry paths in their homes and now
Amazon is going to talk how we deploy
our framework in this raspberry pass
thank you
hi good afternoon everyone my name is
Alison that's in South Korea so I'm also
from Cambridge but not committed I think
so yeah Oh to the mo if she can speak a
little slower yep so today I will talk
about Picasso which is like the HGH
computing platform that we develop in
canvas which is also part of the mobile
cortex as well absolutely it's already
mentioned ah so so am I keep talking
then why waiting so actually uh this is
a I work with Maynard's as well so
basically what we try to do like to
understanding the characteristic of the
container working cofee and we try to
define what is some kind of requirement
that we should design the edge computing
platform okay
my is coming okay so uh as we see from
the minim slide like local services is
going in continued worldwide so it's
some kind of the need that we need to
provide a service close to the user as
possible so however you look into the
platform that we have right now we have
the edge computing which is mostly
related to the data center environment
where you have they're using my high a
server current machine and they use like
a heavy weight which will machine that
and moving them across the so it can
winged moving them across a server but
still inside the data center and also
the fancy that is quite coos as well
like they have a really reliable clinic
city and also a high-speed Internet
always in connection however look back
to the what we have in the complete
network we have a mini a limitation and
concern like we have the limited
bandwidth to exit internet and then
that's why it's gonna be very difficult
to provide a good service is inside the
community itself that's why we come up
with some idea that why not which is why
to move the service closer to you that
possible and the time to the other it
advancement of language so nice session
that I think you might know about that
like we have unique canals or we have
Dockers that allow us to maker so is is
really small and we can move them across
with a little cost and also finish
we can try to overcome internet in the
intermittent connectivity as a network s
as well and this is some kind of
overview of implementation so we can't
pick a so and the so as I mentioned is
based on the content the doctor
container base and also we have the
words is important in Africa so so we
have we implement the the Sri controller
we can have the automatic decision how
to make to decide at where and when you
want to place a services regarding many
conditions like a network service
network condition hybrid resources
quality of service and so in the
agreement however to support
decision-making we need to build
reliable marine systems as well like how
to collect the data in terms of the Nord
user our level CPU memory and so on on
equal condition and also one particular
thing and 14 for the offical so it's
different form another issue completed
form is about is not forwarding so in
here with the with the context of the
mobile we integrate the name data work
in the end name return working and also
delayed for a network as well to
overcome the challenge of the interim
intermittent connectivity is konley
network and also in the emergency
situations as well so this is the
architecture of you Picasso I might not
go to detail for that because this would
be contact but we also submit the papers
to the confident but are they the paper
should and if you want to see we can
download the paper after that so
basically as I mentioned we have so we
controller which uses in central entity
we have the building the mooring system
to collect the data statistics and also
the hardware sources as well and also we
build it's an engine which is a modular
design where they can upload or update
they are taught him how to select how to
deploy the services building that and we
have the local so Italy for Sicily where
so we provider can upload their so is in
May before you submitted to the H
Network and also in terms of deployment
we never using Casa di and the so it's
gateway where you can plug does not
apply to your home router and yeah and
it's finding your element run the
services locally
and accommodated the Commission between
the no one here is based on Indian over
IP so I think I might not have enough to
go for that one minute left so but this
is like a solve architecture that we
feel I might skip this one and here you
see slide last November we went to goofy
it's the help eternally indoors as well
so we try we try to deploy and test our
system voice is how it's working
so I've met men enough mentioned that we
have run summer garden called baths
try to select what could be there are
typical note that we should deploy to
overall area of urban Eliot of Barcelona
and this is a location at the end we're
now able to the point tending of the SEC
to across the and then we run some
experiment so the first thing that we
try to looking to the how can we improve
the quality of service so and here it is
some some of this or that we have like a
we can improve the latency that the user
can exit or so is faster and also and
this is like the cost and also looking
to the the network services as though
that how fast that you can deliver the
services to the edge so we compare our
polish because so the classic IP unicast
and elephants ela become so actually
they've used a lot of latency because we
can benefit from the caching and then
there's nothing ok at the end and
important thing we are so measuring the
traffic on some chances well when we
decide services how efficiently the
Picasso can give you the traffic and we
can compare to the IP unipass and
somebody saw I might skip its financial
for a while they sound so ok at the end
so I would like to thank also lion-o and
the goofy people as well from new PC
because carrot a lot in terms of
deployment right now departments in
running because is running and then
people the community will look taking
out that you know ask to monitoring yeah
the Tiffin oh I'm mayor yes for the
previous presentation
and I let you know how you measure the
the capacities you say some nose has 20
megabytes another 100 and I have a
second question
it's not a nose we were just measuring
with simple Linux commands the bandwidth
of the links right so we'll just
collecting all this in a centralized you
are seeing each each interface and count
the bytes and so on
okay I mean you do that in the
transmission to like hey I hear helpful
to burn okay thank you
so again one question each so go ahead
hey this is Mason I died from University
of Essex and are you planning to make
these traces available or go so I'm
asking okay so we'll talk later about
yeah thank you for those on the live
stream that was a question about the
trace routes yeah yeah I lesson is
sourced from NASA and the piranhas look
what kind of services did you would
blame and how did you decide that you
wanted these services or not some other
service we take all 34 thousand knows
they databases and select the type of
services that people use the first
service was distributed Scott must use
service in the network right so this was
and we tried to find open source version
of this to select our labs and these
kind of things second months ministry
because users in the mesh network they'd
like you to stream like El Clasico games
for example we were trying to find
thank you
excellent any other questions for Alice
horn mmm no thank you both this is uh go
for it you have a minute in November so
peace we also have agonizing the
carbonator since why make good idea so
he's considered to submit a paper or
participate
normally the the data for submission is
in August so this is half time but they
don't make a new agenda thank you
excellent that's cool
and for those of you that may know dr.
Kanchana who knows runners which within
the past she has an interesting project
the dumbo Network yeah is that still
running yeah so if you go to the
Thailand meeting there's a great project
where she's using mesh with elephants
and others in the upper regions
seriously ok so next up is Vasily scree
sauce from Siddhanta Porto Greece we're
pulling you up sorry I'm not as
organized as you there we go
hey Ella there you go so tell them who
you are well and now for something
completely different
actually we're going to see the same
things but from a zoom out perspective
perspective let's see about the social
aspects of all this technology that you
people here are building so I'm going to
talk about our network it's a community
network called seventh apologia which is
based increase and i'm vasilis resource
just a few words about me so that you
know who who's speaking
I'm an engineer a mechanical engineer
actually I am an entrepreneur I'm an
open data evangelist and I'm a member
and administrator of the seventh opera
gotcha our community network so
7w is a village in the same in central
Greece it's next to Olympus mountain and
you can see it over there when we
started our network in 2010 there were
no telecommunication companies there so
people did not have an opportunity to
access Internet so we are talking about
the rural isolated mountainous area and
a group of people stemming from silent
opera village decided that they wanted
to change this and they built the first
mesh network in the village it's a
volunteers driven endeavor and soon
after that villages from all around
surround apparel from the area wanted
the same thing to happen for them as
well so they addressed this team and
said okay could you come and build this
network for us too soon from we had 15
villages in the area having their own
mesh network offering open and free
internet access connectivity we have a
nonprofit organization it was founded in
2013 our vision is actually to create
opportunities for people to stay in
their birthplace because Greek villages
are some villages from all over the
world are being abandoned our young
people flee fleeing to urban centers
because they don't have opportunities so
we would like to do something to change
that our mission towards that region is
to eradicate the digital divide and
provide local communities with equal
opportunities to access digital economy
and citizenship so we are doing this by
deploying and modern telecommunications
infrastructure as a commons and also
training local people on the on how to
use this technology how to build it
themselves how to expand it but also
working on building a community around
this infrastructure and around this
project so this
so on top of all that networking numbers
we have a backbone network which
consists of 24 backbone nodes connecting
today 11 villages 3 farms and one camp
and 40 point-to-point connections and we
have 95 access points these are access
locations in the villages and more than
almost 50 active local community members
these are actual people living in the
villages who are building and
maintaining their own community network
these are people we work with in order
to be able to run the network I didn't
say that an our base is in Athens which
is 500 kilometers away from these
villages so we definitely need people
avail to work with this is what we do
this is the antennas that we do just a
quick question on the previous line yes
chroma-trak what's the scale what's the
scale let's say that from from here
which is Suren barbara to here which is
Marisa in 60 kilometers this is no white
link this is yes this is a webfiling 60
kilometers yeah this is the work we do
the mountain you can see a new boost
mountain here and this is my keys who is
looking at mesh mesh access an access
point excuse me yep no it's monkeys
monkeys is his name so this is a local
so should we have in a very much this is
how we work actually this is how we
provide the support to the locals we
have a map we draw the position of the
equipment and we say here it is a link
that can be improved you can see with
orange color and then people will go and
set it up and
it will work fine we provide training
our main challenge is the distance and
communication with local people because
as I said it's a five kilometer distance
from 500 kilometer distance from Athens
so we try to build communication
channels we have achieved that by using
popular application so yeah I don't want
to negate that machine that was here
true anyway so our goal is to empower
local people to build maintain and
expand their own network so we don't
want to do it for themselves we want to
we want them to be able to pollute
themselves and we have been very very
thankful to be funded by the internet
program of AIESEC in order to achieve
this for 2018 and 2019 and not started
they actually we have this workshop in
village called Flamborough we taught
them how to make an Ethernet cable how
to change the IP settings in their
computer we are talking about people who
are farmers although people you will see
them in the photo that comes next so not
very super techie stuff but enough so
that they can work with and troubleshoot
their own network so this is how a
workshop looks like in those villages
you can see the people participating
here this is so this is a euros
explaining how a point-to-point link
works and this is hilarious and the meat
is here who are building the equipment
so that they can also look at that how
it looks and how they can make it
afterwards as you can see here most of
the people are over 50 years old and
they are farmers so one would wonder
what's going on is it possible that
these people will go and you know build
the community network like make links
and work with IPS and work with cables
and why would they want to do that in
first place since many of them do not
even use internet yeah well there's one
very basic reason for that in order to
have the grandchildren visit them in the
village they have to have internet if
you don't have the grandchildren won't
come so that's a very good motivation
for them to be there and to learn how to
do that and to and to do it well we also
have women participating here these
ladies building the cable and actually
in this workshop they were the first to
successfully complete working network
cable and they said that yeah it was
easy it was like knitting so for them
it's almost natural to do it this is how
we show them about the network
architecture literally using satellite
photos and having these tokens with the
strings connected so they can visualize
the actual network architecture and then
after we would do that we will go out on
the field and start looking in the
various play locations where we can
actually put the equipment so that it
works very well some best practice that
we have learned and throughout the years
that we work they need to have a belly
support and this is something that they
cannot find with the Inca bands they
shoot a question in our group in the
next few minutes they get an answer they
have a need to have a personal contact
because we are talking that we are
building a local community we're not
just building putting technology in
place so it's all about building a group
building a team being part of the same
team and we're also social events to
facilitate interaction between the
villages because these villagers it's
not forgive for it's not given that they
will know each other or they will
interact with each other just because
they have in the same region many of
these people did not use to know each
other before and now they are a group
that is developing this network this is
how it looks the support that we are
providing so they will ask what's
happening here okay then you can check
this area or you can check here and here
and this happens in real time
this is a regular day of communication
with the community we are trying to
celebrate our success everything is
green everything is working fine we are
trying to provide support we are trying
to provide update of the progress that
we make so that everybody shares the
community spirit
so Wi-Fi and internet connectivity are
really really important for these people
it has to have relevance with their
everyday lives so this is why I asked
for the services before because we
cannot just go there and just deploy
some services we have to know what it is
that these people can use and what it is
that these people need this my time ok
so for example this is a agricultural
community they need tools for their
everyday everyday job this is what we
are trying to build with them and
something that very important learning
about computer networking helps build
awareness and privacy and personal data
in this workshop that I told you last
Saturday when we were explaining about
how the controller the access layer
controller works then one of the
participant turns to another and said oh
they are watching everything we
said yes this is how internet works this
is this is the reality so yeah we also
see that people when they are supported
and informed they don't get frustrated
and this is really important in the
community networks and they really feel
proud to contribute and built they feel
it that their own infrastructure grow
what happens after that well this is the
magic there was a local riding club who
asked to the incubate I want to have
internet connectivity
and they said okay you are off the grid
you have to pay six thousand used to
bring you Internet and then they came to
us and said can you help us with that
and with a few hundred euro we expanded
the network and now they are part of our
network they have a very very good
connectivity our older members older
community members helped the newer the
newcomers and now they're even
organizing their own workshops without
us in the winning at all so it's taking
a live one of its own this community
they participated yeah the women you
show them before we are developing a
farmers log application through Europe
European funded program which is called
net Commons which is really really
important for what they do it can be a
really important tool for these people
yeah telegram application has helped us
very much to keep in contact we have the
really important debate with these
people about the data that they produce
and they somehow they have built
awareness on the value of this data and
of who's managing and who's owning this
data which is a really really big issue
we didn't expect that they will be so
advanced in thinking about this stuff
but it came up and we were very glad
that it happened so yeah and the latest
news is that we have had in the village
we have had a crowdfunding from from
people of the village to buy a an access
point for one of their fellow villagers
who is disabled they wanted to support
here support him that way and they
bought it and put it in place there well
this is enabling exciting stuff to
happen in energy in an area just imagine
that the visiting doctors in the
villages could not prescribe medicine
because it couldn't have access to the
online system and now they can use out
networks they do so that meant that
people who would have to travel 30
kilometers to the nearest city to get
their medicine prescribed right and
we're enhancing social cohesion the way
I told you before so the grandparents
have their grandchildren's visiting them
and we're strengthening the citizenship
by providing access to the dual public
services
we're are organizing new workshops
throughout the year we are planning to
share our know-how with some other
community in some other place because we
believe that this is how it works
the Internet and the second one is how
you manage the maintenance of the
network this looks like a large area so
how do you manage to keep the older
network running is community based on
the maintenance thank you
thank you
questions concerning our funding it has
it
we have various revenue streams so one
is through programs like funding
programs of European Union's another is
through organizations such as acts such
as I soaked that is a happiness with
some funds but also local people the the
node owners as they are called they are
contributing a fixed amount of money
which is like 60 euro per year to cover
for the maintenance costs and yeah the
the other pillar is that we do a lot of
volunteering work so everybody is
volunteering here we don't have any
professionals working on that still and
the second part is that we have let's
say hybrid model our the core team as we
call it which is our organization as an
overview of the operation of the whole
network so it's very centralized
overview of if it works correctly like
access to the controller and then when
we see that something is not working
right then we will contact the local
team the local group in the village and
ask them to go in and intervene so that
we can fix that the other way is that
they are complaining so they're writing
in the telegram saying yeah my access
point is only 10 megabyte per second 10
megabit per second so something's wrong
and then we will work with them and
bring it up to to speed and very yes we
have a unique let's say help here we are
connected to the local University of the
nearest city so they are providing us
with the back hole and they are giving
it as a social responsibility towards
local villages towards the local
community towards people who cannot
access internet otherwise ok and in the
queue at us fern yeah I should leave my
question is related to the first
question of Louise but I might are a bit
more further like in terms of
sustainability you say that Nadia
subsidized internet connection right to
the village so and also the the related
also sharing some cost as well right so
my question is what
about the long-term for example like if
some relator decided to quit for the
member and you might lose some of your
the user who pay right so what is your
idea about how to yeah this is something
that we are currently working on we
haven't solved the business let's say
the social business model question yet
but it's an ongoing process we believe
that the more you engage the local
community the more they will support it
so now we are receiving support from
many people everyone who has an access
note in his house will contribute with
steady amount of money each year and we
also do with fests local fests and we
cover some contributions from there as
well we try to diversify our revenue
stream as much as possible so that we
minimize the risk but we cannot say that
we have solved the sustainability
problem yet thank you I rich thank you
from jangula just question about your
workshop and how you're teaching people
about the basics of network building and
basic concepts so two questions both
linked to each other one is what are the
areas that people had greatest
difficulty with say IP addressing or
whatever and secondly how close are you
to I mean how has your model been
replicated by nearby communities and
other similar communities and and
getting these skills to spread is is the
important question to make something
kind of that can grow quickly so how is
you to that mm-hmm
okay concern me the first question
thinks that they cannot see like the
they cannot visualize they cannot
comprehend because these are people who
are not experts on technology so we find
it quite difficult to understand for
example the network architecture the
the backbone there the access layer
these are things that confuse them so
that's why we try to visualize it with a
map and the tokens and yeah if if you go
deeper into more advanced networking
concepts then we lose them there it's
really really difficult to work with
that and this takes time to build but
let's say 90% of the problems that our
network has can be solved with basic
knowledge on how to make a cable or how
to align the links or how to put it in
the right position and the right way the
second question was how to replicate
what we do it's really really important
for us to let's say package our
knowledge and experience and let's say
export it or transfer it to other areas
it hasn't happened yet and it's really
important for us that this summer it
will be the first time that we will go
to another village along with people
from our villages and stay there for
three days do the workshops build the
first mode with them and try to teach
them how to do it themselves but it's
really important that you create
connections so that after you after you
you're gone after you leave they don't
feel that they are on their own they
have to feel that we are there to
support them and this is how the wind
continue growing make let's say thank
you that's a great question thank you
Richard okay we have about a minute for
a question and a minute for an answer we
got two more speakers yeah I'll be
superfast cuz I my question overlaps a
bit with that one I was curious about
the engagement you get from that large
bunch of people
the time do you find that maybe after a
couple of years or less you become very
highly dependent on one or two very
engage participants and in that case
there's kind of a single points of
failure move away from being the
infrastructure and towards the
individuals and if that happens to be
someone who leaves or commonly dies does
everything fall to pieces
we have we have we are here we are today
after many years of intervention in in
the region so we have worked with many
people people actually have come and
have gone we renew the human the human
resources that we have and we see that
in each village in each village there is
always one or at most two champions the
people who are most militant and they
will go and put everything and move
inspire other people to do so these are
not let's say unique people I mean if
somebody leaves then somebody else will
eventually take his place not very not
very soon but there will be somebody and
it takes a lot of effort from our side
to be there and to continue building the
community and yeah this is not something
that you can you know let's say securing
for 100% because what we do is like 90
percent social and perhaps ten percent
technical so you have always human
relations to work with Thanks thank you
very much this sounds like IXPs in the
making as well yeah 80% we're in 20
percent technical sometimes Thank You
rusty Lisa it was great
next up is Muhammad with the community
cellnet so please welcome muhammad qasim
from edinburgh yeah hi i'm muhammad it's
quite a voice is fine or I need to are
hello yeah so how much calcium from
university of padova
working a pitch decent worker well that
was my hitch Mirena
so today I'm talking about our recent
studies about using T white space as a
black hole for a cellular network over
some deployment and highland in Scotland
so as we already know that almost fifty
two percent of the population worldwide
are still doesn't have internet
connection which is more than 50 percent
more than half of that population
worldwide but this is I wouldn't be very
very very wield if we know that forty
percent of population worldwide are
still living in rural area and the most
contribution are coming from from Africa
and from from south edge of South Asia
so small least these figures are more
related to each other meaning that this
50 percent that offline people are most
of them are likely living at the ruler
area
so why provide the connectivity for all
people in rural area are are challenging
it's mainly for to for two main reason
so the first reason is the
infrastructure cost so from the operator
perspective it's not very economical
there is no any gain from providing
deploying a very high cost
infrastructure when we came very minimum
revenue or
or or something that covered the coast
so this this del Matt between how much I
pay and then how much I get back
meaning that preventing that the actual
operator from doing this this deployment
so but why while there is no much
revenue in this area it's mainly for for
two reasons first reason that either the
people in this area are very sparse are
not really maybe you find find one or
two houses distance between them like
one kilometers or something Oh either
they are low-income people living there
solo this lead us to that the second
problem which is affordability so if the
people living in rural area has a low
low income then asking them to propane
have a high monthly subscription for the
Internet connectivity is not very
helpful so we thought that these are the
two main reasons that prevent actual
commercial operator from going through
the ruler to deploy a co network there
so but this problem is not only a
problem of developing countries still
it's a problem of all also that the
developed country here's a figure from
from Ofcom the office of communication
in UK it's showing that only two percent
only two percent of premises in UK they
have only they can have we can have only
a 10 megabit period less than 10 megabit
per second broadband speed so the
problem is not just a problem of
developing countries is still a major
barriers in rule at measure a rule
Araiza areas worldwide facing this
problem of low speed or non connectivity
so house that is related to 5g so
recently 5g have has a some some
objective for for what we called a 5g
air which is 2020 so one of these
objective objective is to write
something called universal axis or to
write to connect on the remaining
unconnected people the 50 person
so there's a lot of effort for from both
industry and and income and research and
different solutions have to have been
proposed including including for example
diverging that lower frequency like a TV
bands frequencies or using drones like a
mobile base station that can be moving
from and in the rural area connectivity
and and and more more of that some some
recent work from from Facebook and
eurocom team that the this open Siller
software-defined platform or open air
interface from mera kaam it's very it's
very familiar as really recently become
very known in the community of research
industry that they provide like an
access side but from software-defined
that you can easily deploy over the
platform like us herpes and this type of
software-defined platforms so but what
work is made most of what is missing now
so in this work we propose re designed
for this for this ruler cellular
connectivity we thought that this design
preferences print prints principles are
not yet recovered and the community in
both community
so first things simplicity so because
it's because it's a community based
infrastructure so we need simplicity we
need something but in play that the
community themselves that can they can
go and plug the device I mean the access
device which is could be either either
Ruto or could be a base station small
base station and then and that's it and
then everything it's work fine second
thing a scalability so how we can scale
scale this up so if we start by 10 years
on how we can does this is scalable can
we go for forty four hundred and but not
just less qadian is capability in terms
of the number of user but also in terms
of the services I can provide so if I if
I can starting for it start for example
by 10 megabit per second speed
can I go 400 just this is the stability
we mean from in this
the third thing makes the applicability
for a new services so I will talk about
this remote it is and in the coming
slides falses is a cost-efficient should
for sure glad to need neither because
the whole the whole objective of less
that we cannot have a commercial
operator operating operating in this
rural and this area so we need something
cost-efficient something can be deployed
with a minimum amount of cost so in the
last a last thing it is a double ability
so I mean by that is the ability of this
community networking or network
infrastructure to communicate with
existing either existing other community
network or a existing commercial network
like maybe a if Canon can I call from
boom if I'm for example if I'm using my
commercial network in an area like 100
kilo meters 10 100 meters if I go away
from this area then I still use my my
community network so this is how we see
would talk about mobility so because we
have too much time on but that's all we
talk about the Third Point which is
providing high broadband speed and the
next couple of slide so but generally as
a high-level architecture architecture
about this deployment model we we didn't
in Highland we have the three three main
component first component is as access
point from our or or the access network
site which is which is closer to tie to
the users which is a normal could either
be an LTE base station which is a
commercially available or one of these
open software-defined platform which is
open air interface or open solar the
second part is TV ad space backhauling
link from that from the location but to
provide which is carried at traffic of
the access point or all the access
network to the put on to the internet
the third part which is the cool because
it's the cellular networks who need a
cool part cool part meaning Mme and a PC
which is we implemented by couple by
cooperation with Microsoft
cool cool cool in the cloud but also
because if there's no not a lot of time
but this word it is is are in our paper
so I will focus only on the TV at space
by calling link so before before we we
went to the field we do some analysis
using a splat software which is a
software that used for for a train for a
for connectivity for availability
analysis and it consider the train and
the shape and and weather and these
these type of things so we select an
area in Highland in Scotland which is an
area at like 60 kilometres some 60
kilometers and we do our analysis in
this area so we mainly focus on into
question cook two questions the first
one is how much how many user will
channel out there by here here by by
talking about usable channels it's
different than available channel I will
define the difference between usability
and the availability and then in next
slide and then the second question is
how the spectrum is distributed as a
contiguous area as it can available
continuously or or fragmented into
different fragments so starting by the
first question which is give us
usability so a recent study over the
last ten years the world the whole term
commonly used in the literature is key
word space availability evaluating
meaning how many channels are there and
there is a lot of models either it's by
using sensing techniques or by using
geolocation database that ask that the
TV works based device to query the
database and then the data by where it
sends its location and then the data
being supplied by list of available
channel but least this is the tpod space
availability but this this list of
available channel it's actually over
holistic it's unrealistic because in
some in some situation you could have
like the whole available channel 40
channel are available the base said that
but when I'm trying to use them deploy
actual middle mile or backhauling link
between to two point I'm facing a
problem of severe interference
receiver side while this has happened
because the receiver side which is a TV
ad space receiver it's it's suffering
from different interference coming from
different primary TV transmitter and
which just means that the Dyson are
level at this receiver is very low which
make that the connection was that prime
was up at Eva's restaurants hotels is
not possible so the main difference
between diverts miss usability and
divots miss availability is how much how
much it's about the qu quality rather
than the quantity so that channel as
channel is X has a snr above some
threshold which if it is true then this
channel is usable if it is not then the
Shannon is is non usable so this is the
main difference between TV OTT space
availability until he was first
usability availability is using a coin
the quantity side how many are there but
usability are using that the quality how
many can be used actually for this link
communication so for this we have here
some result from from our analysis so so
the graph shows the difference between
what is reported from that TV ad space 0
location database we use the Commission
data is called first spectrum from fair
spectrum and then we did some analysis
about either this or I will are actually
usable or not by usable I mean or
measure this and our level on these
channels and and by the front you
threshold so 5 DB and 10 DB and 20 DB we
see that you can see that the for a
median for a 50% of the location the
difference between the two terms
usability and availability is around 200
megahertz so for example the database is
reporting that there are 30% I mean 30
channel are available but the actual
usable Channel are just five this is
this is a 4/4 50% of the location for a
second
a set of experiment I said of analysis
we did it shows it's suspected
fragmentation so we now know that the
spectrum is available but because
because it's the TV channel is just
eight megahertz and to achieve high
capacity link between two point like you
need something you need to aggregate
some spectrum right so so I mean the
eighth the eighth McGirt is not
sufficient you need to have like 10 mega
then I mean like 20 and 20 megahertz 40
megahertz
60 megahertz so you need to know is that
the frequency is available contiguously
or fragmented so we did this this study
to figure out that what is the nature of
the spectrum there and we found that the
spectrum was still fragmented yeah we
could have 30 20 10 hours are available
but they are not available available in
one chunk they are separate they
separated by some non free channels and
we found that for a 50 percent or the
median of these of this spectrum there
is the fragment the fragment around 8
fragments hit by 8 frankerz I mean if I
have 200 megahertz I have 10 then plus
10 plus 10 plus 10 and they are not
contiguously
they are fragmented so so last last
thing we did there very since the
initial deployment using this using a by
this model we have a client abyss based
keyboard space and our client was using
that then the adapt room divide space
devices for well 1 kilo
it's 1 kilo meters yeah just very still
very Jewish crab attack that was my
question
[Laughter]
yes
so the idea of this deployment is not
about the distance that is important
what the ideas to achieve the
high-capacity link that we can go from
eight megahertz channel until up to 80
megahertz channel so we started this is
a very simple payment to start by eight
McGuirk channel here that here are the
based in world space we have and we have
the Internet cabinet which is has a
fiber connectivity and then we have here
with a client TV white space which is in
this area there's no any connectivity
and this is the backbone link also you
also here we have LTE base station small
base station that provides so a
connectivity for a for a 4G mobile
network and in this in the surrounding
area so this is our present and it's
just an initial deployment our new our
objective is to to make this link over
like like I said 80 megahertz channel
not just eight and then to scale up the
number of future that we can serve by
the LD base station in this area and
this conclude my coax coax thank you you
refer as excellent any questions from
Mohammed yes hello very nice
presentation really good results I think
so I get a couple questions so the first
one is in databases models most of the
time overestimating the occupation of
the channels in the areas in which the
primary users are deployed how would you
explain that you are finding this
counterintuitive result okay so for that
yeah I get another question but patience
yeah so basically the table the database
is focus of from that transmitter
perspective so the transmitters and its
location to the database and then the
today is supplied by a list of available
channel but in our analysis we focus on
the receiver side which is not part of
this communication of the database so
saying that if I - I'll fight for
example if I choose sunshine helix and
unlit loud primary device with
transmitter to transmit by by this
channel at the receiver side it might be
that the case that this channel will be
very interfered why because because
maybe this this receiver location isn't
an interaction and an intersection
location was different primary
transmitter di transmitter which make
the interference are very high on this
channel that's that's how we find that
we have a set of finances that we found
that in different location that there's
a huge gap between the availability
using divert space and usability have
you experimented with transport
protocols TCP actually the equipment
you're using I assume is using 802 22
standard yeah it's the very very
Commission is have you perform some TCP
measurement mainly on physical layer and
all right I strongly recommend you to do
that you might find surprises yeah yeah
class of service thank you Thank You
iris ring okay hi I have a question
about the Phi G because you mentioned in
your titles without 5g right so how it
lit it to the T y space are you gonna be
like a Phi T for developing Layton or
something using okay so so far big 5g
contest here is just been so fab G has a
promise of having a very high gigabit
per second speed and low latency yeah
and that's how this related to what we
are doing now we are in this lunar area
are using 4G still a commercial devices
and then we have this capacity this link
which is 8 megahertz so to provide a
high a high bandwidth for these people
in this area so you need to aggregate
multiple the bottleneck is end up in the
back rolling link so we need to
aggregate multiple TV channel so from
from here there's a link between what 5g
proposal will having a high-speed
broadband and what we are trying to
achieve quite right we are trying to
solve the bottleneck at the back rolling
at
honing link to aggregate month to
restrict or that we can achieve the
throughput that 5g promised was okay so
uh one question are you working with the
liquidators or something like that
I like letters like Ofcom or something
that what is their wheels about UI space
or 5g obvious in each hand to provide
you some Dyson tool under fight cheesy
as far as I know no of coming there
trying to to sell the 700 megahertz yeah
but I'm not very aware about what's the
view of this as I heard so far off comm
they want to use 700 for something air
live but you still have 600 megahertz
for running the device well my question
about be the best time I using is from
IP access excellent we one minute just
supposed to go as quickly as we can a
minute in a minute
so really interesting presentation quick
questions um they're high bandwidths
that you need are you talking about
point-to-point bandwidths yes oh so if
5g seems almost a bit redundant here
since you know you have point-to-point
technologies that can do I mean for
example even 5 gigahertz at the moment
60 Hertz 24 Giga Hertz and many parts of
the world it's you know you have low
cost commodity equipment based on you
know available in unlicensed exempt and
licensed bands that can achieve the kind
of speeds that you need I mean I think
in 5 gig you can get up to a gigabit per
second and 60 gigahertz and 24 gig you
can get even higher yeah that's refusing
divert space here is just because it can
also prog it for a longer distance right
you can achieve the same amount of that
of broadband or throughput that the
actual commercial device that you
mentioned that yeah it's achieve now but
over a longer distance yeah this is that
so I'm failing to see the relevance of
5g here so like say reaching that having
that kind of propagation with 5g need
similar kinds of spectrum so you know
you would need you know 20 40 60
megahertz chunk of sub 1 gigahertz
spectrum yeah now that is a you know
precious valuable stuff that it's being
snapped up by mobile operator
kind of world right so so and but if
that was available then you could use
any technology in there to achieve that
kind of throughput 5g does not
necessarily let you break Shannon's law
or me doing miracles really yeah but
it's mainly because we provide here and
it's not like it's mainly solar
connectivity that's why we mentioned 5g
and designed it so it is not just a data
it also the next one our next focus will
be on notes of the voice just also
providing a voice for this for this
community not just the data
thank you for questions and thank you
for the presentation excellent job and
next up is John guru from NSERC and if
someone has the blue sheets please
circulate them we'd like for you to sign
in if you're here for Gaia who has the
blue sheets wave them around
got'em no yes somebody awesome
can you just recirculate them yep thank
you okay so 30 30 or 45 seconds of
background here I founded and built a
national wholesale wireless access
provider in New Zealand starting in 2003
and sold that company in early 2011
400 point-to-point links about 10
gigabits per second of licensed capacity
another 10 of unlicensed capacity so
I've done a lot of this stuff from the
commercial perspective we did use a lot
of open source technologies Linux
routers bgp OSPF a lot of that stuff so
I love what's happening in the community
network space in fact I was inspired by
mi t--'s roof net to start my business
way back then last seven years though
I've been a consultant to network
operators to governments to commercial
organizations and I do a bit of training
for network startup Resource Center who
send me places to teach network
engineering Wireless engineering and IOT
these slides were developed for an IOT
workshop that I give 4n SRC and I'm just
going to take you through a couple of
protocols because I know people
want to start adding IOT to their
community networks so first off i OT
protocols exist because we have device
constraints we've got low power we've
got low CPU we've got tiny devices and
we have network constraints because IOT
devices do not have big antennas put on
them you don't put a dish antenna on an
IOT device you don't put it on the roof
so you get clear line-of-sight you got
radio power utilization because a lot of
times you want these things to operate
on a battery or a small solar panel you
have interference from yourself you have
interference from other devices and you
have these ideas that you might want to
have itinerant connectivity or mobility
of this device you might want to take
your sensor and move it from one place
to another these are not things you do
with an antenna that you stick on a
rooftop so unfortunately fortunately
Wi-Fi is the most popular iot protocol
out there the Internet of Things really
is built on Wi-Fi today what's crazy
about this is you can get a Wi-Fi module
and a microprocessor on a system board
with an operating system and have a
usable device for seven bucks and that's
buying one at a time once you start
buying a thousand of them you get it
down to 3 bucks if you buy 10,000 it's
probably 2 bucks so on and so forth so
Wi-Fi is like the default protocol for
connected devices and it works well
where there's power and Wi-Fi coverage
but doing secure mobility with Wi-Fi is
quite hard a lot of people when they
talk about moving Wi-Fi sensors around
say oh I'll just latch onto an
unlicensed network Richard lamb formerly
if I can had a little device that he
would find open Wi-Fi networks and and
infiltrate them that was cute Richard
anyway Wi-Fi does not solve all the IOT
problems most of all because it's not
designed for battery consumption but the
great thing about Wi-Fi is that anybody
can run a Wi-Fi network and you'll find
with IOT this is not the case so we have
got the I Triple E 802 15 4 and whatever
series of protocol
which includes igby Bluetooth low-energy
6lowpan I've gone to two different
research groups and working groups this
week about 6lowpan frequencies 868
megahertz 915 2.4 you know you're just
talking about TV white space a few
minutes ago and we're talking about TV
white space because the frequencies are
lower than 2.4 gigs they propagate
better through trees through difficult
environments so getting your devices on
UHF frequencies low frequencies like 8 6
8 9 15 means they're gonna have a lot
better performance than 2.4 gig uh
you may have anywhere from 20 kilobits
per second to a megabit per second of
traffic coming out of your IOT devices
IOT devices I work with or like kilobits
per second at the most and that's like a
couple of times an hour anyway you get
start apologizing that go to the working
groups low-power consumption you can
have battery-operated 6lowpan devices
that may last a couple of years if
you're careful with the power management
they can be low-cost if they're in the
2.4 gig band 802 15 devices in 8 6 8 9
15 are definitely not low-cost because
there's no economics of scale there
people just don't make enough of them
for them to be cheap but 2.4 gig
everything's cheap so there is
encryption 128 bit keys it is a personal
or local area solution without any real
options for mobility
if you build a 6lowpan network or you
build a ZigBee network or a bluetooth
whatever it's going to be for a small
area and it's not going to be a network
you're going to build across a number of
communities and share resources you've
just got a bunch of little islands but a
great thing about this is anybody can
run an 802 15 network anybody ok we have
some really bad stuff like if you buy if
you go to the toy store and you buy an
IOT device or you buy it off Aliexpress
or Amazon or whatever you've got a
weather station
I hate weather stations cheap weather
stations do things like run unencrypted
cereal across 433 or 868 megahertz or 9
fifteen some people take advantage of
this by having fun and capturing the
information making it useful some people
take advantage of it by making a garage
door opener that they stick on the roof
of their car and they drive down the
street and they open everybody is garage
as they drive by a colleague of mine
gave a talk at a hacker conference that
how he did this in New Zealand that's
because things like lo-fi and moti know
based on the RFM 69 w chip which is like
pennies for the chip very very insecure
in most cases but it is very inexpensive
if you want to buy one of these and play
with a module with a CPU and the
wireless three bucks fifty for like one
yeah pennies if you're buying ten
thousand or a hundred thousand of them
this doesn't scale beyond local
applications yeah I guess anybody can do
this please don't don't don't just home
sick fox there's is there anybody from
sick fox here in this room because there
have been sick fox people in in the
research and working groups that i've
attended this week sick fox is crazy
because there are an IOT company that
owns the like the whole stack they own
and operate the receiver network they
own the protocol they own everything
about it they've been very successful in
infiltrating local governments and
utilities in selling their sorry
accessing working with i didn't mean it
infiltrated relationships they have a
cool device that has very low power
consumption it was designed for a
battery operation its limitations are
you only get 140 messages a day and
they're 12 bytes so you don't have a lot
of data capacity it works out to 10 to a
thousand bits per second look that's
great if you're a water meter or a power
meter or an anemometer or something that
has you really only need to talk 140
times a day or five times a day that's
great you can do payload encryption it
is possible to have mobility so like you
can roam a cig Fox device within Europe
because it's all eight six eight
megahertz you can roam a 915 megahertz
device between American country
countries in the
North America possibly other countries
that have 9/15 like Australia and the
thing about sick fox is the only sick
fox can run a sick Fox Network if you
are a sick Fox Network you become a
partner they lease you the base station
you put it up on your Tower communities
do this small wireless operators do this
but it's not yours we got another one
here called weightless and weightless is
funny because it was designed as an IOT
protocol for TV white space and I got
involved with weightless in 2012 and
they just had this beautiful protocol to
do very low-power a battery operated
they just built a gorgeous protocol and
then they were really constrained
because only one company was making the
chips this company called Newell and in
2014 Newell sold themselves to hallway
and then hallway took the intellectual
property and sort of shoehorn that into
n B IOT which is now a 3gpp standard and
a lot of people call it 5g I think
technically it will come out in a
release before 5g but people are calling
it 5g it's it's a really nice protocol
battery-powered nodes they can sleep for
days and the base station will keep
track of the fact that these nodes are
going to wake up in like three days and
want to talk at a particular time you
can go from bits per second of traffic
to megabits per second so you've got
this whole adaptive modulation regime
for what you need public key encryption
mobility scaling to international
networks mobile network operators will
be running if they're not already will
be running n be IOT on their existing
base stations and existing antennas just
by adding a software load to their base
stations because NB IOT will run in
channels the same size as GSM or GPRS
channels that they've just retired so
you may have a cellular operator running
a 900 megahertz 3G network and in the
padding at the side of the carrier's
they'll be running some env IOT carriers
the problem with MB IOT is that only
mobile network operators can run it now
waitlist does have a narrowband
option that technically you could run as
a network if you could find somebody to
make and sell you hardware and I keep
looking for hardware and I haven't found
it yet so that's kind of a not yet type
thing we've got another cellular thing
that's also referred to as 5g yeah 5g is
everything everything everything is 5g
LTE machine-type communications Kat m1
or Kat 1m however you want to say it
uses existing LTE base stations and
there's six 230 kilohertz channels so
this is narrowband but not like super
narrow band so you get six channels per
one point four megahertz carrier which
allows cellular operators to say take
their 20 megahertz of LTE spectrum and
maybe portion off 1.4 Meg on each side
and run some LTE services on the side of
their big fat broadband lte-a errors the
endpoints like the terminal units they
decide how often they want to talk of
course its cellular so the mobility
scales to international networks is like
sim card based stuff and since it's that
way only a mobile network operator can
run cat and one two minutes I can do
this I'm almost in the last slide I am
on the second to last slide
Laura Webb low power wide area network
nothing to do with Laura one was
invented here at IETF or at I Triple E
or anything like that but Laura Wynn was
designed for battery-powered Y wireless
devices supports bi-directional
communications mobility localization it
is a star topology it does not mesh mesh
is another big supporter of mesh because
when you mesh you've got to have nodes
that are on and listening all the time
and listening is quite a hard thing for
IOT devices to do on battery power
because you've got to run your CPU
you've got to demodulate signals you've
got to say hey is this for me do I need
to do something with it whereas star
topology your
device on the battery says hey I want to
talk I'm gonna talk and I'm gonna go
back to sleep until I want to talk again
so 0.32 50 kilobits per second via
adaptive data rates we set everything to
0.3 kilobits per second in Katmandu
three weeks ago when we ran a workshop
and did a loyal and deployment because
we just wanted it to work there are
multiple levels of encryption it's
really cool I'm actually the operator of
a Laurel mind network in New Zealand and
Cook Islands and now some base stations
in Indonesia as the network operator I
can never see application payloads
because the application data has a
second encryption key so I can see the
metadata about the packets going over
the networks that I operate I never have
any idea what's inside the packets
Laurel and can scale to international
networks anyone can run a low online
network and that's where we get to the
community part because we have this
wonderful thing Oh No I've got two more
slides sorry okay if you have a
community network and you want ìit you
can use 6lowpan but it's a personal area
network lower line is probably the best
for large areas and we have this group
called the things network based out of
the netherlands i think thank you who
have done this amazing thing because
they have provided a Laurel and
controller the way Laura went works
you've got ends devices you've got base
stations and the base stations talk to a
controller and the controller is like a
mobile network core it kind of
orchestrates the movements of of packets
to and from TTN is a free cloud
controller for community IOT networks at
the moment there are 3317 as of whenever
I took this screenshot yesterday or the
day before gateways online and if you
make an application on TTN like I make
it here anyone can join that application
on any TTN enabled network and it will
just work so if you want to do Community
Network
my recommendation is Laurel run in CTN
but you could do Wi-Fi you could do
whatever sorry for going over time Jane
I get excited about these
we do - we love it okay are you done I'm
done
Wow right on time we've got about two
minutes for question answer and can tick
tick tocks coming in this is
informational I posted on kya mail list
but there's a cool measurement of IOT
homes in UK there's a paper on archive
you can see it I think I said which is
pretty alarming in terms of the amount
of data most practical systems people
are buying in developed regions generate
which is very scary second thing is if
you turn if you if you run alone at
where we have one for air quality and
transport monitoring Cambridge where
they we then brought some those to
London you discover you're not to learn
this stuff works really really well like
you said it's a really nice thing for a
low bitrate long range but then you just
cover everyone else's discovered it
because you can get USB dongles and
build a Raspberry Pi based thing in a
tomorrow or today or last week so I
think you found 12 in London last year
and there's an issue with coexistence
for multiple radios so this came up and
one of the folks visiting I think thing
and there was a site meeting about what
do we do about all the different types
of radio variety that a low bandwidth
for living in the is M band and the band
is getting card it by different
protocols that don't know how to coexist
nicely and it's not just being underlay
and overlay because there's n of them
not two of them so it's a really hard
for most sort of generalization N
squared worse than white spaces and I
think somebody needs to do IETF scale
thinking about how we do the coexistence
I don't think it's an issue for the
capacity of it's just a coordination
issue sure thing it my only counter is
that I believe that chirp spread
spectrum is indestructible and if you
have a sensitive enough receiver you can
listen to multiple interfering
transmissions and pick out the right one
but that's just my professional
experience in a much smaller place than
London okay I have not seen the type of
interference that you have in London yet
and so it could well be an issue that we
need to think about so really fast
questions fast answers we've got about
two more minutes the tick-tock folks are
here they probably want to get in the
room so Dimitri's in Nessa
I hate to ask about because some
the types of IOT are not really open I
will adjust you mark which are open
which are not okay
so Laura LAN is an open network stack
however the lower radio protocol is not
opened because there's only one
manufacturer of the chip which is SEM
Tech Kat m1 I guess it's open and that
it's 3gpp but there's a lot of
intellectual property encumbrance and
you do have to get license fees for that
again NV IOT wait list probably
technically no maybe is mostly open but
I think there's IP and licensing to do
with that sig Fox of course is
completely proprietary lope these things
are pretty much open but they're rubbish
eita 215 protocols I mean yes they're
open you're going to be paying licensing
fees bundled into the chips because some
people have IP around them deep down
inside there are some things that are
not open but they're pretty open pretty
okay okay and John's here for the rest
of the day to go for it I'm not assuming
to humble just about the coexistence and
remark though is a draft and that
teacher TRG group about exactly that so
in case you're interested in discussing
that father maybe you'll want to go
there thank you very much and we had a
question from far afield in Mexico which
is going to be typed into the chat which
it's regarding security can you comment
how you secure your house secure your
proposal is rather the infrastructure we
want to take this to the guy list yes
but my own infrastructure of the base
stations or IP backhaul but they don't
have a default route they talk on a
private network they only know about a
proxy server that gets their traffic to
the Gateway to the the network
controller so I'm pretty happy with the
security and of course all of the
over-the-air stuff is incredibly secure
other protocols yeah not so much
in some cases in gracias from Mexico
answer the question thank you thank you
very much we're gonna take this to the
guileless
[Applause]
huge thanks to everyone that kept a time
it was amazing and we're gonna scoot so
the tick-tock folks can come in but
thank you thank you and stay tuned
because lot Leandro and I are going to
probably do what we're gonna work on an
info doc so in any event for those of
you leaving excellent for those of you
who play on the list we'll see you later
thank you so I know
you