okay
it is the appointed minute
yes I can be heard so we should start
because we have a very full agenda I was
fortunate we have Mallory doing jabber
scribe and we have Korean doing note
taking the notepad is there for other
people to add and of course others can
add to the jabber but thank you very
much so moving forward this is the IRT F
research group on human right protocol
considerations HR PC and yeah the
administrative we have a mailing list
there's github there's meet echo there's
minutes there's a website the agenda and
the agenda are bash we start with the
beginning describe and note takers
agenda review assorted document status
update from the hackathon luca
discussing networked self-determination
update on guidelines update on anonymity
update on association update on
political update on implementation of
451 a discussion of the Human Rights
review team discussion of any drafts
that that are either under 80 to 80
consideration review or should be if
there's time open discussion and if
there's time any other business notice
that the times are short so hopefully we
can keep two subjects of content and not
just go through things that are in the
document that others can read but try to
both have people do the reports and be
able to talk so any comments on the
agenda any changes any bashing anything
wrong with it
hearing nothing will go on with it so
now to then we'll go to the assorted
there's the note well read the note well
I was actually in a meeting today where
somebody read it out loud
I will not is this a new one or the old
one no it's the new one sorry sorry that
it's a new one so you really ought to
read it if you haven't read it since you
read the old one
okay document review document quality
relies on reviews we need lots of people
to review them and we've been getting
some but not a lot and you know so it
read not only the ones you're working on
but other ones this is this is brought
and if you like documents you care about
reviewed put the effort in to review
other documents you must be reviewing a
lot of documents considering how many
documents you're getting us to review
and you do that's good okay so please
but also we need people to review our
documents more the status of the group
basically where we are now is March 2018
I will not read through all that what
has changed is we had no research group
documents accepted as of ITF 100 we had
finished 80 to 80 did a call on the
group on the group list to see which
ones should be be made research group
documents two of them there was general
consensus that they should be there's a
couple others where there's still open
discussion and I think they're on their
way there but but the group itself
didn't quite have comfortable we can
check after the discussed here to see
whether people feel they're ready to
become research group documents but if
not we'll keep working to that there's
no great win in having it be a research
group document than your private
document but perhaps it looks better
yeah he likes it better and I understand
it but the the thing that I bring up is
it's your document before it becomes a
research group talk
once it becomes a rich research group
document it kind of comes community
property and community property can
always be an interesting challenge
okay context an objective of the
research group to expose the relation
between protocols and human rights with
a focus on the rights to freedom of
expression and freedom of assembly and
Association now we are not limited to
just looking at those it's just that
those are the initial focal point but
since rights cannot be divided from each
other it's understood that that we will
discuss other rights as we go along to
propose guidelines to protect the
Internet as a human rights enabling
environment in future protocol
development in a manner similar to the
work done for privacy considerations at
RFC 69 73 and just an aside on that one
if you now notice the pervasiveness to
which people are actually talking about
privacy the number of working groups
where there's at least one draft there's
at least one discussion of going into
privacy elements I see more and more at
each of the IAF's if we can reach that
status with the work we're doing so that
that work our work becomes as solid as
that work is we'll have done really
quite well to increase the awareness in
both the human rights community and the
technical community on the importance of
the technical workings of the Internet
in its impact on human beings oh no
first we had the the hackathon correct
in the in any agenda we can go first
with this but I thought we had the
hackathon first but since this is the
slide that came up Luka would you like
to go and then we'll do the hackathon
after or yeah we had them in the
opposite order on the agenda but if
nobody objects then
of course you can you have to stand in
the box
thank you and tell a little you know
present yourself as a world when you
start a newcomer to our crowd thank you
so good morning to everyone Thank You
mill salary for the kind invitation I'm
Luca belli I'm senior researcher at the
Center for technology and society of fgv
degrees from the surgical Vargas is one
of the main academic institution in
Brazil it's currently ranked as the
seventh most influential think-tank
worldwide and it has been ranked as the
most influential think-tank in Latin
America over the past eight years the
work I would like to speak about with
you today is this work on Network
seventh rumination is part of my work at
fgv I am I had the Internet Governance
project which deals primarily with
connectivity in data governance and this
work actually has a little bit of both
so first of all all the information I'm
going to share with you today are taken
from an article I published in this book
the name of the article is network
determinations and the positive
externalities of community networks and
this book that has been officially
released at the IGF in December is the
official outcome of the dynamic
coalition community connectivity is a
group a multi-stakeholder open group of
the IGF that analyzes community networks
and the community network mode and you
can freely share it and download it and
do whatever you want with the book so
network server termination what am i
speaking about it's a right to develop
your own network infrastructure and it
is what I think could be conceived as an
instrumental condition for people to
enjoy and truly exercise their
fundamental rights this is the
definition quite long that I provide is
the right to free
assemblé associate sorry and to define
in a democratic fashion the design the
development the management of the
network infrastructure as a common good
and this is to freely seek impart and
receive information and innovation those
who are familiar with human rights law I
think have already spotted some elements
that we will analyze in second part of
the presentation and first why this is
relevant here well I think it resonates
with the work the HR PC has been doing
particularly with RFC 82 80 and the fact
that you explicitly say that the design
and development of the network
infrastructure has a growing impact on
society and the Internet should I mean
can be considered as an enabling
environment for Human Rights so the fact
that by building the Internet you enjoy
your human rights is actually that
should quite resonate with your work so
coming back to networks of determination
finally it's a concept that is both
based on human rights law and on
empirical evidences so let's start with
the facts with the observable phenomena
that allow me to state quite confidently
that Network self-determination actually
already exists de facto so as of Monday
the world population was about seven
point six billion individuals and the
internet population was 3.87 so more or
less fifty percent according to this
more optimistic visualization is the
global average is 53 percent and then
you have these average of the various
region which is well it's nice to see as
a visualization but it's not really
useful because the problem with this
kind of visualization is that you always
find only the average this kind of
visualization on the other hand is much
more in
and interesting because it allows us to
understand where are those 3.6 billion
individuals connected to the Internet
and it is immediate to see that you have
people in the most developed country
with the highest standard of living and
particularly in or in urban areas that
are connected and then you have it is
not desert all the rest there are people
living there but it's in especially in
rural areas connectivity is much the
level convey or connectivity are much
lower and this is particularly evident
if we narrow down to Brazil this Brazil
you see that in the cost where the major
cities are you can spot all the red and
yellow which are the connected people
and all the rest the rural areas are
much less connected but this is not only
a problem of developing countries or non
developed countries of course it is much
more relevant in developing or non
developed country but in highly
developed countries such as the you
remembers the problem is not that
different
well of course is less intense but you
still have rural areas that have half of
the average of the total European Union
and if you see this graph with all the
Member States in rural areas there are
countries well more than half are have
less than 50% of rural areas are
connected and some countries like Italy
with 60 65 million inhabitants rural
areas only have 15 percent of the
territory that is connected so it's
actually quite quite telling of how the
lack of connectivity may also impact
developed country in so the conclusion
that I start to draw from this is that
mainstream networks are not so
mainstream and when I speak about
mainstream networks I refer to what the
request for comment 79 62 calls
mainstream network so the authority
network deployment RFC provides the
economy of an in identified mainstream
networks as usually I mean the
traditional networks large network they
span large areas controlled by
traditional operators in a top-down
fashion they require substantial
investment to be deployed and there is
no user participation in the
government's deployment the operation of
the and so here we can start to think
why are people not connected to this
mainstream network there are several
explanations several factors and if they
depend in different countries in
different countries you can have a
completely different importance of these
factors but they are primarily this for
first of all connectivity is not
available
these simple economics if there is a
rural area with a few inhabitants or a
periphery with very low standard of
living an operator will not have a
return investment to expand natural fear
or when some operator venture into this
area then they may be the only player so
the lack of competition may keep the
price is very high and there are some
studies for instance by Carlos ray
Moreno in South Africa that explain that
people have to sacrifice food to buy
connectivity and then there is the lack
of interest which if you think about it
we see the entry interest of the
internet but if you're in a rural
community you may need local government
services local e-commerce platform to
trade local goods and local services
news in local languages if you don't
have them you don't really see an
interest in connecting to internet and
again the low level of literacy and
numeracy is in specially in developed
continuing countries one of the main
causes because if you don't really
understand how the internet works and
you really not have basic skills it's
quite hard to understand what are the
benefits that you may have by connecting
to internet so what Michael might make
us read is what if you could build the
internet yourself what if people could
mitigate at least some of the these
these elements that I was mentioning by
building their own internet well they
actually people are already doing so
since almost twenty years with by
building community networks through
crowd crowd-sourced networks they are
built by a group of individuals and
managed by them in a bottom-up fashion
as a common good so they are managed by
the local community as Commons and this
gives rise to a distributed architecture
actually bringing us brings us back to
the original philosophy of the Internet
a network of networks where people can
add new networks and those network will
interoperate through open standards
started out here the ITF and actually
this is quintessentially decentralized
and this architecture is usually put in
place using wireless technology low-cost
Wi-Fi equipment and the use of
unlicensed spectrum to Randers equipment
or maybe TV white space it with dynamic
spectrum and allocation and but it can
also be built on fibre and there there
are some pretty impressive results here
are some of the most outstanding and
renown examples of community networks
and the one that you see there and on
the corner on the on the right barn
broadband for the rural north which is
the British champion built in Lanka
Shire by local farmers and the
hairdresser that we're kind of tired of
being disconnected I decided to create
their own network which now connects
angles of people and provides speeds of
up to one gigabyte per second which is
as they proudly say more than what NASA
has so besides this benefit of the
access to information having
connectivity obviously that we all know
there are also collateral effects
external effect it's a virtual circle of
knowledge and innovation that is
triggered by
this because when the communities
involved there are new services that are
developed by the locals for the locals
so the time the families government
services or local language content that
I was speaking about before they are
developed by the come by the locals that
are into the community networks for the
locals so it in almost all community
networks you see this phenomenon the
element of maps voice-over-ip
local fora health applications in the
Nepal network wireless project they have
developed a application for pregnant
women to receive information about
pregnancy it also has stimulates use of
smartphone by people living in Malaya
zones so it's quite impressive result so
all the positive externalities of the
do-it-yourself connectivity of course
freedom of expression we know to impart
receive seek information ideas but also
the education that comes with it and
capacity-building because people that
are actually in developing networks
usually also provide training for for
the locals and everybody the training
for the locals the locals actually start
developed new services as I was
mentioning before this is permissionless
india innovation meaning that people
develop the services the apps that they
need and they freely share it and if
really access them and that is precisely
what create a more interesting internet
because if you don't see the interest of
the Internet when you have the exactly
the service that your neighbor needs the
interest becomes much more interesting
and it fostered the centralization
because as I was saying before those are
new networks that are added at the edges
so quintessentially decentralize
architecture and also last but not least
obviously employment opportunities
definite which is one of the most renown
committee Network and it's the biggest
currently in word employs more than 100
people only for maintenance those are
direct jobs created by the network and
I'm not counting all the developers
and up providers that may be created
they may be promoted by the local
command connectivity used as a comment
so I think so far I've provided a little
bit of empirical basis on which we can
start to think that Network
self-determination already exists
de-facto now let's see very quickly how
it can be constructed that you were
using international human rights law if
we come back to the definition I provide
at the very beginning we can decompose
it in three elements and the right to
freely associate the definition of the
network governance as a Commons and the
freedom to seek important receive
information innovation the first and the
third are quite self-explanatory
meaning that the first is simply the
right to freely associate it's already
protected by very explicitly by Human
Rights binding instrument the third is a
simple rephrasing of freedom of
expression is traditionally it is
defined as the right to freely seek
important receive information and ideas
here I'm just substituting ideas with
innovation because an idea in the
digital ecosystem can easily translate
into a new application of new technology
and people should be our actually are
according to fundamental human rights
law free to fear receive and access
those ideas in the second part is a
little bit more tricky why because there
is no agreed definition of what is
democracy in human rights law so the the
the the rights to define the in a
democratic fashion the network
governance well one has to understand
what is what does democratic means and
here we usually international UN right
so you will refer to the right to
self-determination and the internal
dimension of domination there are two
dimensions one is external dimension of
self-determination the right to have any
depend territorially independent states
sovereign states it is not this what
interests interests us and I don't want
to start a discussion about territorial
independence in the UK which is not the
most advisable thing to do to mean
recently I want to focus on something
else which is what really interests as
internal self-determination so the right
to define a governance system according
to the will of the people it's really
technology they must characters the
government of the people and this right
to self-determination is so important
which is the that is the first right not
only of the Universal Declaration of
Human Rights but of both international
covenants of fundamental right the same
wording the same phrasing in article one
of the three document all people must be
free to determine their political status
this is external dimension and to pursue
their economic social and cultural
development and if you are fundamentally
free to pursue your economic social and
cultural development you are free to
develop your own Network develop your
service and to share them and to have
them accessed by whatever you want to do
and then we finish with the last cherry
on top of self-determination which is
information or self-determination a
concept developed in the late or in
early 80s by the German Supreme Court
which defines it as the capability of an
individual to determine who can access
and use his or personal data basically
is the base is the the founding basis of
the right to data protection which is
enshrined explicitly in article 8 of the
European charter of human rights and is
at the basis of all the 125 national
data protection frameworks around the
world which is the right to know who is
collecting that about you and how those
data are being used and for what purpose
so why this is important this becomes
very important if you consider your
personal data our money your personal
data are the digital currency that is
used to pay services
and it's not only money it's really the
most important resource you have in the
world and if you think in internet terms
the main business model you have so far
is zero price model right you don't pay
with money you pay with data well the
same logic the zero price logic has been
transported over the past four or five
years to zero rating offerings which are
another strategy that has been advocated
for by some several operators to provide
subsidized services applications to
unconnected individuals so this is
basically price discrimination you don't
do not count the consumption of specific
services against the monthly data
allowance of the user but what are the
purpose is why or is this way are these
strategies being implemented it's not
only because of second operators have
magically become philanthropist is it
because there is a commercial logic
behind first of all you attract new
users if you give them a gift I will
give you a free service but if you think
about it that gift is only useful if you
have no access or a very reduced data
cap every month if you have the
possibility to create your own network
and your own services you don't need a
freeze for one application as a gift
because you're already having all the
applications that you can do which you
can connect through your network plus
the one that you really need you are
developing them through your community
network the orientation of user choice
and user attention towards specific
applications is also another another
reason of these strategies and user
attention in the eyeball economy equals
to data data are the most valuable
resource so I will give you the example
of Brazil where despite being this
practice illegal operators are providing
integrated services
so that they can bypass the prohibition
to harvest data on their users through
applications that are providing that
harvest data of the users and then all
last but not least this selling the
preferential access to your own
customers to the application providers
that are willing and able financially
able to pay for this preferential access
so this obviously this kind of strategy
presents some advantage for the consumer
because you have a free app but the
problem is that it is it is an advantage
for that app consumer not from the
internet user and it transforms actually
all the potential Internet users and
presume us into app consumers because
that is what is free and it is that is
particularly evident in developing
country where people do not have the
money to buy access and have free access
subsidized to specific services and they
turn out to be only users of those
applications again Brazil is very
telling only three weeks ago the
Brazilian Institute for geography and
statistics which is a public entity
releasing statistics on Brazilians every
three months started for the first time
to release data on what are the main
reasons for which Brazilians access
danger in 94 percent 94 percent of
Brazilians access the internet to use
messaging applications now it might be
that Brazilians really love messaging
applications or it might also be that
whatsapp is the only application it is
subsidized by all operators and these I
mean if you are any behavioral designer
will explain you that a good application
is the one that hook the user into the
application and therefore maybe by
subsidizing only a couple of
applications you are hooking people into
those applications so maybe yes the
consumer the previous consumer of this
application will have a benefit but
those that may have focused their
attention in building connectivity new
networks and new services have data
retention and data drain into
to subsidize and all what they subsidize
obviously is chosen by the operators and
sponsors and this I think risks to
transform the internet into a
centralized rather than decentralized
environment and fragmented into users
into clusters of users of integrated
services of the operators or dominant
services if you want to know more about
what services are zero rate in the world
with the IGF dynamic coalition on any
Friday we have built this nice tool that
allows you to see in 87 countries so far
what are the services that are generated
and what are the does your rating
policies in naturally poetry and no
surprise the Facebook application
Facebook group applications meaning
what's a primarily Facebook and
sometimes instagrams are those that are
zero netted in all countries basically
and with some rare exceptions and well
this leads us to what I rather
provocatively define miniaturization of
the internet which is transformation of
the internet from an open a
general-purpose network into a
centralized and predefined purpose
network and but that is not the only
option
this is the probably the most advertised
option but I as I was explaining the
first part people can develop they on
their own network so why shouldn't they
be allowed to do so thank you very much
for your attention and all information
are here and I hope I've been enough
provocateur II to trigger questions
thank you yes we have about five minutes
that we can go to questions so if we do
have any or were there any in jabber so
please go to line thank there's no
French in the room please Nick Terry UC
Berkeley thinks your talk is very
interesting um
I was curious about the early set of
slides about access in rural areas so I
guess I had sort of one clarification
and one sort of open question so I I'm
curious when we were describing these
percentages whether the percentages yeah
this show that chart yeah whether these
percentages if I put the percentage of
people in rural areas who have access or
is it the percentage of areas that's
broadband coverage in rural areas
according to European Commission's
report yes freely available in the BCO
web site a broad balanced capacity
office website and is like coverage by
people or coverage by like area by area
I mean by network deployment in rural
areas I might respond me to your
question or not is that like the number
of people who live in rural the fraction
of people who live in rural areas who
have access or the fraction of the
territory of territory yes because like
we we might want to know what fraction
of people who live in our earlier
because because it might be that
actually 99 percent of people who live
in rural areas have access but lots of
rural areas which have no people don't
have access well the conclusion of the
study is that 39 percent of the rural
areas is not covered so maybe in the in
that 39 percent all people are living
there it is a possibility but I think it
is unlikely as a scenario it although it
is possible yeah okay and and then the
sort of more general question was yeah
you were pointing out that we should be
thinking about self-determination and
that the creation of our now like that
the sort of DIY creation of networks
might might speak specifically to
self-determination I'm curious if we
have any idea about how many people are
not connected to the internet because
they don't want to be versus how many
are not connected because they don't
have the capability or financial success
so I have a double reply the first one
is it I mean when you have the even your
freedom of expression you
a fundamental right freedom of
communication is a elemental right but
it's not an obligation you don't have
you don't have to be connected and if
your choice is not to be connected it's
a perfectly respectable choice yeah but
if you are not connected because no one
is investing in your area or because the
price is too high or simply because you
would want to do it but you don't have
accessible information well this may
solve some of the problems is obviously
it is not a silver bullet it's it's not
going to the committee networks are not
going to bring high quality connectivity
everywhere in the world but it is part
of a solution I think and there is no
they do not limit the right of everyone
of anyone sorry by being constructed so
if your your right Network
self-determination does not limit anyone
else right so why shouldn't you enjoy it
sorry you're saying the fact that I I
would join into the network doesn't
prevent someone else or I mean the fact
that the local community develop
networks yeah is not hindering someone
else right it's only bringing more
rights to some community that are
disconnected okay Thanks
thank you I want to cut the line after
Mallory but please go ahead hi my name
is Andrew Sullivan so I really like this
thank you very much one thing you were
talking a little bit about about subsidy
subsidization of in zero rating and so
on and and the way that that promotes
certain kinds of applications but I
wonder to what extent you think the
logic of applications makes for
winner-take-all anyway because an
application layer in a in a web
environment there's there's basically no
bit no no advantage standardization
right everybody can just use the
application as it is and and so what
this means is because of the way network
effects work it's it's better to be on
the application that everybody else is
using than not now this also promotes
the mini tail ization that you were
talking about that is it it turns the
Internet into like a sort of boring
substrate for on these monopoly
applications but it it also means that
there's literally no like there's no
subsidy so there isn't really a lot of
there's no a lot of public policy tool
that you could use to try to try to
discourage that just because the
advantage accrues to the users well the
thing is that you are seeing this from
the perspective of someone that is
already a user of the application if a
consumer application and that has a
benefit I'm not saying I'm not rebuttal
in that point I'm I'm taking that the
other point of view which is the point
of view actually of the 3.6 billion that
are not connected and maybe don't even
know what are those monopolistic apps so
if you don't even know what they are if
someone is giving you for free as you
are saying that it creates some sort of
I mean I know if you're not we're not
saying it explicitly but it creates a
sort of dependency so you start using
that it's like I mean I know I know I
know that I've been enough provocative
today to have another proof occasion so
it's like I know if you remember in the
90s those candles about tobacco company
giving to kids in Africa
free cigarettes right it creates a sort
of dependency again I was mentioning
behavior design because a good
application is the one that creates
addiction if you don't create an
addiction you have failed with an
application so if you're giving that for
free to people that don't even have
basic literacy skills well a very good
chance of creating a good addiction so
if I mean if you're in an individual and
unconnected maybe literate individual
you're excused you don't know this but
if you're a government that also see all
the world's most valuable resource of
his citizens being drained away you not
be excused for this got it thanks
Neilsen uber for the wreck
thanks so much really interesting and
I'd like to pick up exactly where you
just left with the final answer
what and would you like comment on why
you think that the right to network
self-determination is more useful than a
governmental obligation to network
provision so why do you put the
obligation for the gathering of the
social financial and cultural capital
with the individual whereas whereas they
would already be disenfranchised I mean
again I'm not putting any obligation I'm
putting the right to do it doesn't mean
that again it's same think of
communication you have a right not an
obligation meaning that what I'm just
pointing out is that if you and your
community members want to develop
infrastructure you should be free to do
it so paulien governmental policy should
allow you to do so without restrictions
but no one will oblige you to do so I
mean again it's not a silver bullet it's
part of a bigger solution that has
multiple different strategies there is
I'm not arguing that there must be an
obligation on the individual to build
its own network on the government an
example again from Brazil is incredible
source of thoughtful examples so over
the past 10 years
universal access funds collected 20
billion reais 20 billions realize that
with the current not very favorable
change exchange rate means roughly 5
billions dollars right 5 billions
dollars it's good money there is a an
inquiry going on from the High Court of
Auditors because only 1% of the that
money from the universal access fund has
been used for connectivity and 76
percent is unknown it is not known the
no one can tell you how it has been used
it's at 76 percent of 5 billion it's
really a lot of money and that money I'm
telling you I mean obviously if the
we're really interested and efficient in
doing so we were not being speaking
about this here but if there are three
point six billion people still
unconnected it means that the
traditional solution we have been using
mainstream network be them there by
traditional operators or by the
government have not been affected
effective sorry and from what I've heard
it isn't just Brazil that have those
procedures that's general nature I was
gonna say the same thing as in Africa
all that all that money
sort of I'm not accounted for I mean
mine is very similar and that I
challenged the idea that we should be so
for rural people that are already
experiencing a lot of inequality that we
should be putting onus on them to take
care of this and I understand that
that's not the intention of getting
Network self-determination and
legislation or other things that it's
really about making sure and this also
happens making sure that community
networks are not then targeted by
corporations and like you know sort of
regulated out of the picture which
definitely happens in my context in the
u.s. I'm from a rural place where like
community networks have struggled for
legitimacy but I do think that if we I
think one of the issues is we put
connectivity in its own context when
we're trying to when governments are
trying to incentivize building of
connectivity into infrastructure and
they're incentivizing companies to do
and companies don't feel like there's
profit to be made so they don't even
take the incentives that are offered to
them sometimes I think it's because
we're not thinking about the underlying
issue with that because if it's just in
connectivity equals Facebook then I can
really understand why people that have
not already been connected maybe don't
have an interest in connecting that was
something you said early on the slides
it's like an interest to connect but if
they have to get their drivers license
using the internet or they have to seek
medical care using the internet then
like it's almost a critical service and
that if it were if connectivity were
provided maybe through the provision of
those other critical services instead of
a standalone you know backbone of just
telecommunications then then perhaps
that could change because I think what
what we risk with not putting the onus
on government
and companies is that yeah you're you're
basically disenfranchising people twice
because one they're not connected to the
internet but then two they're also not
able to get the services that they were
previously able to get in an analog
situation because everything is moving
online so now they're doubly sort of
stranded right I just wanted to
reiterate it I mean I'm not saying that
the government should be disenfranchised
to its obligations I'm just saying that
the government should not impede people
from doing something that does no harm
for anyone and only improves the
standards of living of the local
populations thank you thank you and
thank you and and hopefully you'll join
the list and we can continue the
discussions there if you haven't joined
already sure I've already joined okay
fantastic we could work on networks of
determination as a new point of draft is
always welcome okay thank you
next we'll go to the to the hackathon
slides as soon as Neil's gets them in we
have three relevant hackathon projects
do you still have it take advantage of
this to say that they have actually five
copies of the book I was saying with me
so if anyone wants them there for free
so we had free cookies we have free
books
there we go so three projects at the
hackathon one on web RTC HTTP status
code for 5-1 and we've been working on
the qualitative analysis of IETF mailing
list with Nick Doty and a couple of
others we've been collecting although
the IETF mainly archive we've done some
Bayesian statistics from words analysis
and some network analysis for the use of
Jupiter notebooks and Python we found a
lot of issues namely with a lot of
encoding and the thing
happen when people run their own mill
servers you can find the code in on
github so please contribute we did it
with a bunch of people and we think it
might be really interesting to analyze
the participation in ITF and see how
that impacts the kind of decisions that
are made and how it influences the
process so we've been looking at almost
2 million emails from 190,000 email
addresses from over 955 analyzed mailing
lists and of which one mail address and
eight more over 80,000 of the messages
but most contributors and one or two
messages so that might be spent if you
look at the whole community it is
actually quite modular and integrated at
the same time which integrates with only
a few outliers and some people might
expect that early participant of state a
long time might dominated in discussions
and this is actually not the case we got
from the statistics and also it's not
just a few people that send most
messages there's quite a long tail also
recent threat threats on i.t the longest
threats on i-80 effort IETF the org are
actually long threats are actually quite
recent and are also about issues that
are relevant to to discussions that
we're having here in HR PC so that's
actually quite interesting but it also
shows that these topics are very alive
within within the community the
centrality shows you how many people are
applying to who the the most central
note the the redder the note the more
they reply to messages and the people
the whites and the whites are the note
is the more the less they reply to
people so if you're at a big note in the
middle and your whites that means that
you're a rock star that never talks back
to people that really likes you we've
been looking at word trends and everyone
can do the word trends for all the lists
so we've been looking we see you we just
took three random concepts here where
you see that there is an
increase in discussion of a security a
slow increase in the discussion on
privacy but actually when you look at
excess there was a it was building up to
a peak of the around 2007 but it's it's
falling off right now so if we want to
understand more how these discussions
are held in our community
and also how they travel between mailing
lists have a look at the code and police
contributes a hero will you
okay thank you my name is hirotaka I'm
talking about HTTP status code for y1
which is our C 7725 so during the hug
yeah so during hakonsen we we made a we
improve the click web crawler to
collects which website actually returns
HTTP service for 4-5-1 because we
already have the receipt but not we
don't see not not lot of lots of the
deployment on about HTTP for 5-1 say
let's call 4 by 1 so from last ITF like
no that's ok yeah we can we can we can
take a look visitor
yeah so from the last couple ITF and we
create we collected it's the web crawler
to create clothes which websites returns
a 4 by 1 and this time we made block
collector so which collects the
statistical information that which
website actually turns 4 5 and took from
the clutter and also we have the web
browser extension like Google Chrome
extension so which that we made during
the hexam so this is a screenshot of the
4.1 reporters so if if that any 4 5 but
if the browser or if the cola founds any
4 5 1 0 s code that we can see the which
website returns of 0.1 yep so now we
have the data corrector so we can so if
you're interested in you can check you
can pick you can get so source code from
github and which we talk show right now
that crowing reddit.com that which
potential returns
for advanced 4-5-1 status code from the
Germany but but unfortunately I couldn't
find any for five and status code I
actually finished calling yesterday and
there's no for abandoned status code at
this moment but if you think there's any
potential for five once it's called web
the website which returns for five sets
code please use that data corrector and
also a color and also collector and so I
think next step is we can we can use
that data if we found some so we can we
can put some input to this working group
and also that improves aged 4.1 status
called draft thank you
just want to mention that all the slides
are on the the you know in in the data
tracker so so please go through the I'll
stop and take if anybody would like to
ask a question on any of because this
was the end of the the hackathon oh
there's one more ok please sorry and
then after that we can take questions on
all of the the hackathon before moving
on
hey everyone yeah so my name is Shalon
so for the hackathon Christine ALP and I
we worked on examining how different
browsers implement WebRTC or in
particular how they how they get the
local IP address so about TC is a
technology which is basically used to do
real-time communication in browsers and
especially peer-to-peer and for this
they need the local IP address so but
the thing is that we found that Firefox
and Chrome they don't ask the user for
any kind of permission when they get the
local IP address but Safari does and
would not work if the user hasn't given
like a camera permission or an audio
permission so we have b2 in the
hackathon we made like a demo website
just to showcase that we got our first
demo so this is the website it's netlog
github that IO slash WebRTC privacy and
this is Safari so if I don't allow so
then you know we did not get user
permission nobody support it and it
doesn't reveal any local IP addresses
but if I do give it permission then it
does see all of my my IP address my
local IP address but if I go to Firefox
and I click don't allow it doesn't care
yeah so that's it so basically like the
idea is showcase how different browsers
have like a different implementation of
web Odyssey but so this is not ideal
either because like Safari the
permission it's asking is microphone but
so it's not clear that this is you know
related to your like the fact that it's
revealing your local IP address but at
least it's some kind of user consent but
so it says I think it's just a place
where more research should be done and
more work should be done and yeah that's
it please use the microphone you've got
one there the VPN like that's we didn't
look into that too much like for for the
purposes of this hackathon you're mainly
focusing on another case where you have
like you know a whistleblower in an
organization who does not wish to be
identified so the local IP address is
more important but yeah I mean I think I
really try out so I can't really say too
much but I would imagine that it's the
same issue with respect to that as well
Thanks and it would probably come in to
consent issues because even on Safari
where you're giving consent to your
microphone you don't know that you're
giving consent to your IP so the fact
that Safari asks for permission for your
microphone really is not the same as
asking for permission for your IP okay
so go to questions now yeah yeah please
hey so I think that Roberti stuff I
think it's a user agent issue so I think
it's it's it's great ear to talk to the
web CC see people in WCC they might be
have some privacy privacy consideration
on their standards so properly it's the
very good information to input them up
to to have a discussion about a privacy
issue
yeah I mean so Mozilla and Google I
think have been pretty clear that they
don't want to do this at least in the
privacy discussion that have been
happening up to this fight and you know
the web RTC the ITA button group doesn't
exist anymore
but yeah I think it's maybe we can talk
to the VC PI we see a group like I said
thank you thanks so any questions on any
of the the hackathon discussions that
went by before we move on ones coming oh
yes from w3c to say thank you for
putting together that this demo and I
very much hope that you'll share that
with the WebRTC yeah working group
because that kind of input is very
helpful to us and making sure that we
have the right privacy considerations
which is our aim and all the work that
we do thank you thank you it that's
great
okay thank you so seeing no more
questions I guess we'll go on now to
draft IRT f HR PC guidelines is that you
nails yeah so as aviary mentioned there
is RG adoption of the draft so oh yay
there is one small change and that is a
change in relation mentioned by mark
Perkins
in a in a reference we refer to
intellectual property but intellectual
property was not thus described in in
the Universal Declaration as we refer to
it so we we changed it into the original
text after that I got a email I'm not
sure if it was on a list or directly to
me yeah from Teresa that it's a bit
unhappy that there is that there is only
a masculine tense here so we changed it
between square blocks into place he is -
they are I made it clear that what did
not come from from the UDHR that's its I
think we will work with this more and
we'll see more changes in relation to
the review team but we have that later
on the agenda so if there are no
questions yeah I wanted to ask a
question so is the review team or maybe
you can cover this later using this one
and is there sort of a feedback loop or
we need to make sure that there's a
feedback loop I see a head nodding so
there will be a feedback loop on this
this is one of the things where I am
personally very concerned that we get a
certain amount of rigor in in these
guidelines so that as time goes by we'll
have things that people can really count
on so go to the line your that were
first in the line
nikto UC Berkeley um I I'll certainly
follow up on the list with with some
comments but I thought one useful thing
to discuss in person would be how we're
coming up with the list like there's 19
things and the in the in the table of
contents and I'm curious how we're
coming out with that list because for
example there's a lot of things like
confidentiality integrity authenticity
anonymity pseudonymity that that are
also covered in the privacy and security
considerations recommendations and and
so I was just quite confused reading it
and I don't know how we're gonna do
reviews if we're if we're hitting the
same topics multiple times in different
documents yes so the reason why they got
there is that they are important from
importers from RFC 80 to 80 whereas also
the methodology why why why they got
there so leaving them out would in will
be problematic but what we try to do is
cross-reference as much as possible to
RFC 69 73 and 49 49 or what is the
security considerations one so I think
we could largely import the work that is
being done or respect the work that's
being done by the security and privacy
work and work around that where but it
might be that people when people are
looking at it from a human rights angle
at privacy issues it might be a slightly
different but I think that's also a
question that hopefully will come up and
we will work out when we're doing the
actual reviews does that annoy you
leaves you skeptical certainly yeah
well maybe that's another way to put the
question like is this document for the
reviewers or is this like four or is
that for people who are reading a 280
and trying to understand human rights
like I think this one was attended
mostly for reviewers and as the 80 to 80
is there is the whole document this one
and then everybody said it's way too
long it's way too you know it's got good
stuff in it but it's way too long to be
useful therefore right so so I guess
maybe I'm just thinking like if we're
gonna say it's for reviewers then we we
don't have to have every like wait we
can we can consolidate for the sake of
the so perhaps something like and and
and and pardon me is to it just to add
something that sort of says if you're
doing a privacy review and this is
already covered there then you could
skip this one but for the purpose of
testing the guidelines and as what we're
looking at in the review team is for
people to test the guidelines they may
not be doing the privacy review or or it
may be done separately so so having them
there may be useful but making it
conditional on if you're not doing a
privacy review could also come out
different and but you jumped up to say
something in response so I should give
you a chance it's not only for the
reviewers it's also before everything
for the internet draft authors so they
can check their own protocol in the
spirit of fc-69 73 and privacy on the
one on security consideration I don't
remember the number but this to MFC are
actually used by a lot of internet draft
hours up because if they don't if they
don't use them they will be cut later on
by the Esley so the idea is in the
future that maybe that will use these
guidelines as well but since it's still
just a research document it can't make
assumptions about how it's being used
okay any other questions thank you but
let's so maybe we can though just sort
of out of line if you're actually doing
this for a review and doing a privacy
review cut-and-paste or ignore okay so
yeah that one's you too right oh no that
one's okay
about the anonymity draft so the draft
is adopted whatever it means by the
resort group up to now there have been
very few reviews as we mentioned this at
the beginning that the walk of wizard
group or walking group is to wit draft
to review to comment because otherwise
we don't know if it means that the draft
is great and there is nothing to change
or if it means it's so broken that
people cannot comment on it so please we
don't review and I also noticed that if
you care about the document and what
reviews you have to do with you for all
the documents that's why we a few open
questions if you read it you will see
that there are several places where
there is a to do G audio is things that
should be improved really should for
instance there are some examples of why
it's good to have anonymity but not a
lot maybe it's not in this draft because
there are a lot of documents other form
academics or for activists about why
anonymity is important so maybe we
should just reference them or include
them but anyway we need something there
is also a second about why some people
disagree with anonymity or says that
anonymity should should be must be
limited this section could also be
improved with more examples on the
whether it's a good idea or not this
sort of thing for instance on Monday the
iesg
adopted the draft on the effects of
pervasive encryption on operators which
explains that the operators because of
encryption there is a lot of things that
they cannot
do anymore such as modifying the HTTP
requests in transit to other personal
information in it because of encryption
it's not possible so the draft explained
as a point of view of the operator this
is a sort of thing that that should be
read in the context of the discussion
and anonymity so I think up to now all
that have been little interest as a
scene is in reviews in commands in etc
so in my opinion if the draft for for
the draft to go somewhere we need much
more involvement from the wizard group
and so I just asked to read it to
command to review on it's maintained on
github so you can also send the pull
request you're welcome thanks first I
wanted to apologize I read it and never
got around to writing down the questions
that I wanted to ask but a couple of
things that occurred to me while I was
reading it is is um the anonymity and
the right issue and and so in other
words how is it a right describing its
relationship to rights
is it derivative in some sense is it an
enabler of right so some discussion on
that and you know anonymity seems a good
thing but that discussion doesn't seem
highly developed I was wondering whether
there were levels of nanana MIDI and I
was thinking about that and I was
looking at things like you know one of
the things that worries me DOS now is
we're identifying ourselves we're all
going out actually I don't but we're all
going down and identifying ourselves
with our biometrics so that we can use
our things easily how does that relate
to anonymity does that blow it out of
the water completely or or you know or
is there a warning to be put in there so
I'm wondering whether it's useful to
have a discussion in there of of
biometrics in that yeah I had some other
small questions but I'll ask those later
but those were really the the the ones
that that really had struck me while I
was reading it
and for the first point about the
relationship to human rights I agree
with you something that's something to
be done
Wendy Seltzer thank you I do think that
this is an important area and I will
offer a review and some comments one
thought I had on the framing is that
anonymity is valuable as a compositional
issue that you can build identity on top
of protocols that start from anonymity
it's much more difficult to build
anonymity on top of protocols that start
with strong identity so as long as we
see some value in anonymity and I think
we do as connected to human rights and
self expression and Association then
it's valuable to assure that we start
from there and protocol design and
that's why it's a problem for the IETF
when we design protocols we have to take
care of this because as you said if
there is if the protocol itself we will
sever a thing it's will be very
difficult to delete it afterwards
hi Brian wouldn't I want to echo the
thanks for this important work on
anonymity defining the protocol
considerations um one of the things that
strikes me though is most of the places
we go on the web if we show up is
completely anonymous we stick out like a
sore thumb and it to be believably
anonymous we need some sort of a persona
that might be crafted it might not even
be true and so a lot of people when
they're trying to be anonymous they have
a phone number for one persona an email
address for one persona and then in
their other personas they have other
phone numbers other email addresses and
other characteristics and they keep
these identities separate and it's just
that aspect of anonymity or pseudonymity
I just didn't seem well developed in the
draft and I I wanted to throw that up
for discussion to see if there was sort
of alignment in principle and if so I'm
happy to help flush out that text one of
the reason why it's not well developed
is that we the draft is mostly focused
on infrastructure the
at all every user has to use you are not
forced to use a Facebook or to buy on
Amazon but if you use the internet you
will reveal a lot of things so it seems
to me that there have been a lot of
discussion outside of IETF about things
like the rights of the user to some
anonymity of pseudonymity when using
services like Amazon Facebook etc but
little discussion about consequence for
identity of the infrastructure of the
internet for instance IP itself on this
is clearly some things that could be
done in the IETF III RTF while other
issues such as anonymity in database for
instance we are not the best experts on
it's already Endel by other people I
think so I would say coming from the
security group there is a lot of work
there in authentication of various kinds
PKI based as well as Kerberos based and
so it's not just a cookies in CSR auth
tokens but these things all have
relationships with each other and then
they get tied to IP addresses and then
they get used to linked IP addresses
together so I would recommend that we
broaden the scope a little bit in that
regard why not but there is also a
simple practical problem as I said we
had very little activity on the draft so
I would suggest instead that maybe it's
better to focus on the few things we
really know about because the entire
issue of anonymity I don't eat the
authentication is extremely wide on we
clearly have limited limited workforce
in the group test one what clarifying
questions then if I bring expertise in
those areas which would you want me to
help flood actually if you bring text ok
thank you I will bring text it's it's a
research group talk now so you know you
got something saying it's not in their
contribute text wanted make sure the
text was welcome thank you ok and I'll
cut the line after where it is Malory no
no one idea is you have pseudonymity
which is quite good but you might us we
could also talk about randomization it's
kind of related like sometimes if you
don't
certain values you're not allowed to
connect to the protocol won't work but
you can randomize certain things so
there's some ideas there and my second
comment was about the section I think
that's new about objections against
anonymity I would recommend just killing
that section and using it to basically
enhance your introduction or your your
arguments that you make further up in
the document rather than presenting the
opposition you just sort of you know
what the opposition is and you write
your introduction and your supporting
arguments with those in mind that's just
where you at the plenary yesterday
because I've been a discussion about
this about the draft on this left and
what an effect on encryption with the
supporters of this draft that we have to
lay down to write down the reason people
don't want or don't like encryption so
we can once it's documented we can do
something about it on other people like
me said that while writing it in I've
seen no official RFC will probably have
exactly the opposite effect giving them
some credence so it's probably more or
less the same problem okay Nick Nick
Terry UC Berkeley
first of all I'll commit to sending
review comments I hadn't gone to that
yet and I have a lot of comments that
can't work right now so some of those
look of an email um I I was sort of a
plus one on the idea about perhaps
broadening this to pseudonymity or or I
guess maybe more to the point I I think
maybe we can't I don't think we can do a
very good job describing the protocol
considerations if we're just talking
about anonymity that I think actually
there's been a trend to not use the term
anonymity because it is so misleading
the the idea that that you could be
completely anonymous in a set as opposed
to having some control over pseudonyms
or or their breath so I that that that
was that was my concern and I'm curious
about how we want to do it for this
document that if
if we're just talking about anonymity
which which can have very specific or or
otherwise very misleading definitions um
it might be more useful for us to look
at the breadth of pseudonyms or identity
is more generally as a draft as
definition for anonymity and
pseudonymity because one of the problem
is outside of the IETF people use
anonymity for everything even inside I'm
not sure that all the ETF participants
are very clear about that but the draft
as definition relying on previous RFC if
these definitions are incorrect all if
the draft afterwards use them wrongly
please comment scream do something
because indeed one of the point of the
draft is to be very clear about what it
is to be anonymous to be suddenly mousse
was the sort of thing so if it's not
clear then the draft is use this so
please if there is a specific problem
with this speaker okay Paula fuga book
from pepper you can hold it comfortably
to this way
first I like the draft and I really like
the definitions and I want to add
something we are actually implementing
anonymity features in our apps and we
have another thing which I'm a little
missing I can combine it all of the
other half definitions I think but
likely using them like a toolbox which
is what definitions are for we are
differing between a person talking to
another person and no attacker can even
know who is talking to whom even not
know that people are actually talking
that is I think coming close to what you
call anonymity but actually there's
another thing which is two people are
talking to each other and they even
don't know who the other person is and
there's two very different things to
implement I can name the applications
the applications for the second one is
obviously for example for Lee
King things we call it internally the
WikiLeaks feature you want to and I
think because that's very different from
implementing and a ITF draft has usually
the intention to help implementers
getting things done I think that could
be something you could add unfortunately
I don't have a good name for it so
beside WikiLeaks feature we call it full
anonymity against anonymity but perhaps
have a better name Thanks and can you
give your name and where the we are
working is yes I'm toka book from pretty
easy privacy Thanks any comment and and
and again the offer of text we're
something to be explained isn't in there
yet is a wonderful thing thank you okay
anyone else final word okay then we'll
move on to the next one thank you okay
and the next one is Association is that
you know I think it's a she's Ella she's
Ella can you uh there you go hi everyone
how's it going so we'll you startled you
take it away yeah okay so we are making
a lot of progress and taking a lot of
containing into consideration a lot of
the wonderful comments and very rich
discussion that has been going on at the
HR PC mailing list Neil's loves this
quote and I'm starting to love it as
well we changed a little bit the
arrangement of everything and just
trying to think how the architecture
itself impacts and enables her in our or
inhibits their right to association but
also vice versa
if we could apply the right to
association legal standards to the
internet itself as an infrastructure and
what would it mean so a quick overview
of the changes we ditched the right to
protest as an angle of analysis because
that's where the your
idea came from but we later realized
that just association and assembly by
itself were way more interesting and
protest was just making a lot of noise
so we ditched that we removed the filter
bubble section in the literature review
because there was the opposite of
consensus on that we were discussing a
lot about the approach towards that so
we just removed it as well so we can
unban some building this consensus we
have new vocabulary we were taking
vocabulary from the past
RFC that I don't know the RFC numbers by
heart but maybe Niels and all the rest
of you do we have different research
questions as well that I'll show in a
second changes the structure and we
added to discussions in the end
protocols versus platforms and the
internet assess an association so the
first research question you'll see it's
pretty much the same that's basically
what the guidelines have been building
upon and the second one we change it
just like this if the Internet is indeed
used to exercise freedom of assembly an
association what are the legal and
technical implications of this at the
infrastructure level so that's the new
vocabulary I don't think it makes sense
to go through all of it so I'll just
throw it back to Neil so he can talk
about the discussion we had around
defining internet ISO
what happens in in several of these
discussions has happened during RFC 80
to 80 so it's starting to become a
familiar thing that we need to have
technical legal and some what
sociologists explanations for or
concepts from Science and Technology
studies to come to the same thing so an
example here is where we look at
internet so there we have the standard
technical one of the network of network
that consists of a asses that are
connected through IP but then we also
have other beautiful ones with it that
it's a persistent socio technical system
over which services are delivered but
also a techno social assemblage of
devices user sensors network routers
governance administrators operators and
protocols and then as last because and
rule of the emergent process so much we
have an emergency press driven thing
that is born from the collection of the
ASA's that happen to be together at a
given time the fact that they tend to
interact at any given time means it is
an emergent property that happens
because they use the protocols defined
at the IETF so I think this this this
this definition is somehow a bit the
it's yeah it's a bit what we do here is
I I really like the beauty we've added
the new structure so we added a part on
IRC which we did not have we Giselle and
I first talked about XMPP but XMPP was
already extensively discussed in RFC 82
80 so we looked at IRC found some
interesting things in the grouping
together
we ditched the process but looked a bit
better at a SS and had a lot of
discussion about that and on suggestion
of Steven Ferrell he said we had after a
thorough review we said we said
initially said we do not look what
happens
on top of the network but we do but now
we added something on protocols versus
platforms and we had a discussion of the
Internet itself as an association as
assembly or we'll get to go get on that
she said are you taking over am i
continuing I can take over just to
explain the difference between this and
then be great if you could continue so
in the beginning was that the internet
constituted an assembly but Sandra Brown
and gave us great comments at last ITF
session regarding the lack of accuracy
in our definitions but because
assemblies are a temporary nature we
change to the Internet as an association
and we argue that that is exactly the
point
so yeah you take Cornell's so then we
come to the conclusion that the internet
is made up of interconnected guesses
which jointly form an association and
that Association should be protected but
what does that mean because it might not
be the only Association because if every
network isn't an association within the
Association that the Internet is does it
hat does the a s have an absolute
freedom to implement its own rules or
should it rather have commitment to the
larger Association so does the
importance of a functioning larger
Association the Internet prevail over a
preference of a smaller Association and
how does it then what does that happen
if there is an assembly of two people
that associate over to a SS that's then
over to one Association that's the
Internet so what is the relation between
these assemblies and associations and
how is that prioritized and what does
that actually mean so one could arguably
say that that the largest Association
enables the most assemblies so that one
should be most protected but in the
human rights practice one normally
argues from starting from the end user
from the rights holder sorry in which in
this case would be the end you
that are assembling so that would mean
it from the other way around so that is
something that we would really like to
discuss with you because that really
changes the the conclusions and then
also there was a there was a thing that
we all Tercel like when do it when
doesn't a s become part of the
Association of the Internet's is it when
it receives an autonomous system number
is it what in ounces it routes or when
it starts shipping shipping packets and
if it's only routes with with another
IAS over the Internet is it still part
of that association and what are the
implications of stating that the
Internet should be protected as
Association so just one quick comment
since the beginning we started
discussing about like private networks
having public impact there for aligning
towards the larger public ensemble and
we kind of left it over in the middle of
very many other super interesting
discussions and recently in the mailing
list we went back to it and it is also
reflected on the draft itself so I would
also echoing on what Nilsa saying would
love to comment forward more on that and
what we have discussed lately is where
to go how to conclude this how to start
closing up all the discussion and ideas
that have been flying around so in terms
of the legal I'm gonna start with with
illegal I'm trying to take all of the
consequences of the right to Association
apply them to the internet as an
association because that is our thesis
and in terms of technicalities could it
be that technical consequence of this is
the obligation to pass some packets so
that's more or less where we are right
now and if you want to add anything else
no I'm very curious actually what people
might say and and think on where we
should take this and where it is weight
forward sounds reasonable
and whether there are major critiques or
disagreements first I'd like to ask how
many people have actually read the the
reworked version that's a good number
that's good um so we don't have anybody
at the line yet is that just because
there are no comments okay at the end of
this I'm also going to ask after we've
gotten the line whether this has
progressed and changed enough since I
assume you still want this to become a
research group document so at the end of
the discussion I'll ask if we're there
yet and then go on from there but please
hi this is Karen hey Sheila future now
bug so I had a question in terms of
where you want this to go in a sense
that I think the discussion has been
really interesting on the list but
especially for people who aren't very
well versed and like the kind of stuff
that HR PC does it might be a little
hard to understand why we're having this
conversation and like what the problem
is it is trying to solve by trying to
figure out whether this is an
association or an assembly you want to
take that she said ah or shall I I can
take the association and assembly part
legally they have different implications
because one has a more formal and
established nature and the other one is
rather temporary the assembly is
temporary and the Association is a forma
thanks for your question crane by the
way so the it has different legal
implications that could replicate as
well in the technical and infrastructure
level and regarding the research group
sorry the HR PC bigger perspective I
think meals can be better suited to
answer that yeah so I think your
question is about why are you sparing my
mailbox with this theoretical discussion
and relevance etc well I think the
answer can be found in the Charter is
that we're trying to understand the
impact of writes on protocols and
protocols on writes and that's exactly
what we're trying to do so even though
that sometimes needs a significant layer
of extraction but but if we have
discussed
the freedom of association and assembly
I would really like to have the feeling
that we discussed it from the rights to
the tech part and back again and perhaps
that sometimes ad nauseam but that's
what research is Malory noodle I'm just
a suggestion and how you tackle some of
these questions like round is and
witness and a s become associated rather
than maybe asking the determination
like that question a friend just
exploring and the nature of that
activity is that Association June and
I'm saying like so instead of asking
does this make a s is an assembly but
just talking about the things that a s
is do within the context of how that
maybe shakes out as an assembly or an
association if that makes sense
and then that takes the pressure off of
you having to determine upfront what you
want to say yes hi I'm Andrew Sullivan
I've got to admit that I continue to
struggle with this draft and and I just
you know I sent some things to the list
already but I I think there's a deep
confusion in this because I think you're
not you you're not distinguishing
between a s is just being a tool of
individuals all the time versus you know
the individuals themselves and it seems
to me that the individuals have rights
but I don't really see how you get from
from those individuals to the a SS or
the internet or any of these underlying
things being an association or an
assembly or any of that stuff it's just
it might be a forum for this thing
although I feel uncomfortable with X
it's not really a space so there's a
whole really I think what's happening is
you're you're you're working very hard
with a bunch of concepts that that work
well for meet people walking around in
the world and you're trying to try and
pull that in and or and overworking the
the the metaphor of cyberspace
and that is is causing that that's
causing it for me anyway
the the difficulty that are having with
the terms here and and so I'm just
afraid that there isn't a way to make
this work because the because the
concepts don't really fit the the
underlying mechanism it's it's like you
know sometimes when I'm reading this I I
feel like you know you're saying you
know well if I put a whole bunch of cars
together is it an assembly or an
association well neither it's just a
pile of cars it's traffic or it's a
parking lot or something like that and
and I this is a similar sort of it's
just a technology and and it's the
humans that you're trying to talk about
so I don't know if that's very helpful
but I I still don't think this is ready
to adopt oh and I'm I think the I'm
trying to think of it it may be you're
right
right but III haven't come to the same
conclusion as you yet but I think a
newspaper or a media house or a radio
station is itself also a technology
that's enabling freedom of expression
and it's actually the people that are
doing it but still the the whole
licensing scheme and the way people work
in the labor laws and etc the they are a
specific ordering that enable or disable
a kind of enabling of Rights so the same
is true for the Internet infrastructure
and people do associate over the
Internet so I think it's important that
we try to understand what the structure
and potential consequences are of that
and the reason for doing that and to go
through it as nauseum is because else
someone else might do it for us so I'd
rather have this this this this may be
sometimes confusing or irritating
discussion here then that other someone
comes up with with it elsewhere because
we keep on saying that if non-technical
people make decisions about this then
it's shitty so that's why I rather have
this discussion with
well I can buy that but but I mean you
just actually walked right across the
the distinction that is the point I was
trying to make so so a radio station for
instance is a corporation it's got a
it's it's a radio station is always or
not always but mostly controlled by some
somebody some some collection of people
I can identify who those are the point
of the bit that you quoted from an email
that you know ended up in the in the
document is precisely that it's it's
fuzzy at the edges there's no boundary I
can't say what the internet is today
because at any given moment it's this
sort of fuzzy collection and it fades
out at the edges is you know is a node
on the on the quote on the internet
behind the the Great Firewall is it on
the internet or not well kind of yeah
kind of no and that's and that's not a
thing you can say about like is this an
employee of the radio station yes or no
well you've got an answer to that it's a
legal answer and I think that those I
think that the III I believe that that
fuzziness in one case and the lot and
the non fuzziness in the other case is
part of the problem here now I agree
with you that you know maybe the answer
here is well it's neither an association
nor an assembly it's a different kind of
thing and if you try to use this other
kind of framework and beat the internet
with it you're gonna have a
dissatisfaction clusion because because
it's the wrong tool anyway I don't take
up all the time something yeah ah okay
you're getting up so you'll be the end
of the line because and yet please Brian
wooden again so I would agree that the
document is not yet ready for adoption
I would also echo the importance of the
area France when I think of the social
credit system that's emerging in China
and I think for the potential for that
system to actually hurt people just
based on who they associate with having
a lower social credit score than them
and the many different ways that that
can hurt them you know I think work like
this is very important at the same time
I in my mind I struggle to separate
Association from anonymity because one
aspect of our identity and one aspect of
our anonymity is you know with whom
with what metadata we're associated and
so those friendships those relationships
are part of our identity as part of our
anonymity and so I'm wondering if this
work could be folded in with the
anonymity draft as that as that takes a
more more maturity but again echo the
importance of the area and +1 on the not
yet ready for adoption although I
applaud the other work thank you I would
not want to lug our piece of problem on
to it might even get more problems by
sometimes when problems are interrelated
you can only solve them together
Teaneck I just wanted to join the
confused individuals that voiced their
confusion before me especially in in
those situations where I don't know why
I tried to go into much detail when you
try when you describe technology or
technical terms like the DNS and the the
autonomous systems there's almost an
obsession to get some connotation
attached to the a s which doesn't really
match the technical terms and by
shifting this from one sphere like the
technical sphere into the sociology or
social sciences fear that the
connotation breaks and then the of
course the analogy breaks so to that
extent maybe less would be more as in
not trying to do this right now and do
it afterwards so we so we can get a bit
easier to their to the core of the
message because so do people would
people feel happier if the last cuz
actually so the part people are hating
is the last part I guess right a
discussion on the Internet as an
association I'm not commenting on
because we could consider cutting that I
would like to understand if people are
if that's the source of confusion and
problems then perhaps we should consider
that and try to move the rest
the drafts along and keep that for a
research part for another bit maybe if
we look at I was especially confused by
section section six six point three and
yeah so I I'm curious Andrew if we if we
cut six three would that would that take
away significant parts of your confusion
as well probably I I you know I read it
pretty quickly I mean it just came out
so I I think probably the bits that that
talk about you know what the internet is
in this are the ones that are most
problematic for me I think that's
probably fair okay then maybe we have I
have a way for it in a clearer way yeah
and also like on a really quick note I
think the effort here is also trying to
stop separating its side Michael from
the social and the political looks more
and more they come intertwined so I mean
we could argue it towards there but yeah
maybe we can from this we can take a way
forward I'd be happy with that are you
okay with me to wait about asking again
okay thank you I got I got a head nod
that doesn't translate too well on yes
right but thank you okay then we should
move on so next one's or did you want to
say and you're all ready to move on
are you political let's see how
political diskettes so the HRP see
political we're doing this work cuz in
RFC eighty two eighty we've been trying
to research the protocol impacts on
human rights and with this draft were
also understanding the dynamics impact
impacting protocols and architecture
development so we're trying to describe
the political aspects of protocols also
because these came up time and again as
discussion in his research group
and it is because the internet is a part
of the basic infrastructure of
information societies and protocols that
are being developed here in the ITF
influence these and a part of this
process is political which and political
here includes economics but this is not
described in RFC s
so we need to take this into account if
we want to understand our own decision
making process and making this explicit
it helps us helps us to understand and
take it into account also it's it's so
if it sometimes makes us uncomfortable
and I was very happy to see that we were
not the only one struggling with this
because a part of this was also
discussed by the internet architecture
board in their blog post on
consolidation and there was also an
interesting discussion on ITF at IETF
lists about this as well as architecture
discuss so the latest changes a lot of
typos thank to mark Perkins for going so
so thoroughly through three drafts that
was really appreciated lots of work a
lot of people several people contacted
me about this off list and this resulted
actually really good discussion editor
position that all protocols are
political sometimes and is largely based
on the law of unintended consequences
improved examples in the field of
competition also by separating standards
general and IETF specific parts added
more dynamics about standard development
general and ITF in specific so where do
we go with this is there anything
missing nmi are we also causing a
ridiculous amount of confusion with this
draft or do we feel like well this is
about it any comments nobody at the line
nothing's missing somebody's coming to
the line so for Brian wooden again so
for political I thought um one seminal
work that could add value if just
mentioned cited and maybe even pull a
little bit from is a seminal paper by a
rogue away on the
moral character of cryptographic work
because it really speaks to the heart of
how what we do with protocols really
really matters ethically morally
politically in people's lives etc could
you share that one on the list and I'll
make sure that I sure well as soon as I
get permission post to list thank you
thank you so any other yeah this is an
awkward room to maneuver so someone is
coming to the line now please come to
the microphone and introduce yourself
into that very health and inner area so
I think it's this is a very important
topic and I think that the the the the
question which I have to I guess the
chairs and stuff is what is the criteria
for Rjay adoption so obviously we need
to understand the politics of standards
for offering a standards body there will
be political ramifications the standards
we create having doctrine which explains
this background very very well is very
useful do we imagine this being
operationalized somehow in a future
process not necessarily I mean this is a
research group so I think you know the
criteria has been that there's a
consensus in the group that yes we want
this to be our document as opposed to
just his that they are ready to give up
their control of it and make it our
document but operational not necessary I
mean some of the things with
considerations in them like like 80 to
80 yes that was meant to be
operationalized once it's once it's you
know verified etc this not necessarily
it doesn't need that to be comfortable
yes please the other chair as as author
I think I really want to understand to
map the problem space before and then
maybe consequences of that or or
specific problems arising for that might
come into a new draft but I think if we
first have this if we first can agree on
this I'm already really happy with
having that in a document section in
which case I would strongly support RG
adoption okay thanks
and I just want to take this moment to
salute a little bit
business when you touched your hat to
say as author I thought that was good
Teresa had I read the draft and to be
honest I was a little confused by
everything basic by the structure from
section four onwards like section three
I can understand its different positions
that some people have and then four
until the end I'm like what are these
headings
what are these sections supposed to tell
me I just went back to the abstract and
it says here we are mapping different
positions and I'm like okay that's
section three but the rest like what is
the focus but I've only read it once and
then got really confused yeah that that
yeah so section three was different
positions that people had and section
four is a different ways in which it
plays out but I agree we should I should
we should clean it up and make that make
it more structured yeah we could work on
that thanks for that suggestion uh Nick
Terry I think I had similar confusion um
and and in particular I think if we want
to have more reviews or or possibly go
for the research group I think that I
think the abstract and introduction
needs to match the rest of the document
or our common understanding but good
because I I struggled to read the
document understand what was going on
and I and I think a particularly R to me
for making the document or from this
discussion whether the purpose is to map
different views of politics on standards
or to make a proactive argument that we
need to change IETF process or we need
to consider politics in a certain way
and and I think if we don't have that
clarified like I don't even know how to
send comments on the list until we have
some context of it so I think I've
gotten clue without asking a general
question that it's not quite ready and
I'm getting a head nod okay great thank
you
and so you'll keep working on it and
we'll keep coming on okay so we're now
up to update on implementation of 451 or
did we already do that no we did the we
didn't do the
we did part of it right right oh that's
where you would stuck that one I see
yeah so for the draft new protocol
elements basically what I'm trying to do
is propose new elements protocol
elements to HTTP 451 to make it more
useful and reflect what how it's
actually being used so yeah it is an
individual draft and the recommendations
I was making were mmm based on feedback
and the research done was that we should
have a geographical scope to the
response that we get to so that if
because blocks are often nationally
scoped so if you are getting an HTTP 451
response then you probably want to know
where it was blocked so that's one so
the other thing was to disambiguate so
make a difference between like blocking
authority and the implementer of the
block so for example like the like the
entity mandating the block would be a
court or a government and the actual
implementer of the block would be an ISP
and it's important to distinguish
between these two things so the work
done was to combine this draft with the
draft many folks they charge see RFC
seven seven to five so basically what
this draft now also has is the
guidelines from RFC eighty to eighty as
applied to 451 and yeah so I guess the
next steps would be I spoken to mark
nodding him if there's interest in the
HTTP working group to adopt it so not
sure entirely right now Priya so I guess
I'll be working with him I figure what
the next step should be
thank you how many people have read this
one okay a much smaller number okay
anybody wish to comment
yeah thanks sis Corinne I just wanted to
say I think this is really useful I
think it does a lot of the stuff that
we've been aiming to do which is like
take the discussion that we have here
and bring it to other working groups
that are actually in the IETF so I just
hope you continue doing this okay yeah
and in some ways it's almost serving as
a first template on a way to work with
with something so I think it's really
great thank you okay then the next thing
you want to go back I think the next
thing is the discussion on the Human
Rights review team which I really want
to hear about yes there it is again
so we now have Human Rights review team
what does it mean a review team is a
team that we've used basically that
we've used internet draft we've been
reading them understanding them and then
making commands remarks instable a lot
of people when especially when they are
new to the IETF believes that a review
team is something very organized very
formal requiring approbation by the IAB
iesg etc but in reality most of the
review team that you can see during
discussion in the IETF are quite
informal even sometimes unofficial I
mean two people can gather together on
declare we are a review team it's a
freedom of association it's good of
course the comments won't have any
specific weight unless Java they are
good the point is that review team are
typically not official part of the
process I mean they comment if the
command are good they can be taken into
account otherwise nope so we view team
as to prove that it's comments our worth
it on it has to establish a reputation
all the review team that we know today
like Jen art for instance started as a
small group of very informal people and
then we'll the repetition
so the human so it does not have to be
sanctioned by a higher authority because
it does not have any specific power so
current state the review team exists
which means that we have a mailing list
at this time it's all some review team
of more formal group where software to
work together it should request things
like that we don't at this time at all
Artie its public because of well like
everything I mean there is no formal
membership of the review team anyone can
join the list but it's not supposed to
be a general discussion list we already
have one for this it's supposed to be a
list focused on reviews so publishing
reviews discussing meta discussion about
the reviews a thing like that
it's very recent no review was done yet
so at this time it's only vapo well but
we will try to turn it it into something
more concrete
so the reviews will be based on what the
the idea is to focus on draft which are
in IETF why the last call I Center some
examples to the mailing list because
there was a draft where iesg is asking
for comment from anyone at the IETF but
of course as I said the review team is
quite informal so if people want to do
reviews on other draft they can on the
under method
the idea is to is to use the
framework of draft guidelines which is
now draft
I have tff Campisi guidelines it was
published which is itself derivation of
ofc 80 to 80 section 6 section CC of the
FFC 80 to 80 is supposed to be the list
of things at the OFC authors should a
check to be sure that their draft the
protocols
don't have an intended on bad human wife
consequence because I have see 80 to 80
is bigger the idea was to move this part
the concrete part to a separate shaft on
the review team will both use as a draft
on guidelines to guide its walk on also
will produce input about this draft does
it walk is it realistic is it a good
thing or not maybe we should change the
draft on guidelines at whatever so
volunteers are welcome but not too many
I mean it's the review team is supposed
to do reviews so we don't really need
people who just come here for sending
one questions and that's all we mostly
need people who will commit to do
reviews and to discuss reviews with
other people and with the IETF commands
and all I've got one and then hopefully
people will come to a line okay so when
I was looking at it I was sort of saying
okay it's an independent activity that's
kind of hanging out in the HR PC but
because of the that it would be
following the guidelines and and we
spoke before about not only following
the guidelines but giving feedback as
part of that that it's also kind of an
activity of the HR PC so is it is it
okay with you kind of and with you kind
of to look at it in that sort of doorway
it's sort of independent it's sort of
hanging out here but it's also an
activity because it will feedback to the
group in my view yes it's an activity of
the NPC we saw a group it has a separate
mailing list because it seemed a good
idea to focus on the actual work a
concrete work on the review team but it
could have been also done on the it's
not a matter of principle
just efficiency I just won't understand
that because we hadn't talked a prayer
of course so please when you're talking
if that's not okay with you say
something please
Mallory knodel um it's okay with me I
think that's a good idea
um
my comment was about what I think we
could work on so I'm already on the
review team we haven't really started
yet but besides doing last call drafts I
think it would actually be useful to go
back and look at RFC's that are already
out even far like long ago and I'd like
to volunteer to do a sort of simple
mapping or even just creation of a
matrix in which we can evaluate whether
or not a draft is worth assessing
because I think there's just so much
that we probably risk being flooded and
if we had a quick way of determining
whether or not either a past present or
future in the case of IDs are worth
looking at maybe they're the right size
maybe they cover the right topic maybe
they are related to the work we've
referenced them in our other drafts like
that could be that hopefully would be
useful as a starting point for some
people to know where they want to dig in
I already went through all the draft in
the ietf white last call to get an idea
how many were relevant for the review
team many of them are on very specific
and very detailed technical topics that
I understand nothing about so it's very
difficult to find the human rights
issues in it maybe they'll but it's very
difficult to dig them out so that could
be a first criterium on then for your ID
why not but so if your team is made of
volunteers there is no hierarchy so if
people want to do a review of this draft
even if it does not fit the meta
guidelines there is nothing to prevent
them so it could be a good idea to have
this sort of rules to filter the draft
but people won't be forced to follow
them of course in a cost Inuk
more review is always good to that
extent any initiative that organizes
this can only improve the documents and
that that's a good thing when I missed a
bit on your slides is what are you
trying to achieve
usually the the review teams are in
support of one or more 80s so what you
might want to have is the ear of an ID
to to channel findings through you can
always post them to the ITF list of
course but the other many of the other
review teams again serve serve a
particular ID eighty but you didn't say
what the what the outcome should be a
year we could go back to two older RFC's
to generate maybe more work for the
research group or is it to flag issues
in in proposed protocols or in protocols
in last call my ID was more flagging of
future i've ever seen with doing this
analysis for existing FFC could be
interesting to inform the discussion on
the guidelines left on it could be
interesting also if some people want to
develop this version of the RFC
addressing the problem that we found but
at this time on remember that we did
nothing yet it just took his trip with
at this time the idea is motor focus on
a last call draft because we could flag
problem related to human rights and I
don't agree with you there are many
review teams not all of them related to
nad somehow related to a specific
technique young for instance young
people with also draft where there is a
young the EEOC IDs to focus of course on
Human Rights so to distill human rights
issues in the draft on to mention that
there is a potentially a problem of
things that could be improved or at
least document excuse me for
interrupting we have only three minutes
left I want to be very careful we're a
research group so it's fine for us to do
this and it's fine for us to scream in
the wilderness that
hey we found human rights stuff in this
review but I don't think we can
operationalize it in such as attaching
it to anything IETF ish I think we have
to be very careful in that boundary
we're a research group so we can shout
hey we found human rights stuff in this
last call document and they can send it
in as a last call document as a last
call comment but we cannot cross that
border I was trying to sorry I was
trying to manage the disappointment here
like naturally by addressing last calls
you are you either the last-minute
obstacle and assuming that human rights
issues might not necessarily be in the
detailed and at the core of protocol
they might not care yeah exactly right
it would be an another comment sent in
on the last call that somebody didn't
care about oh well it's like hate HRP
see confused and disappointed which is
just a quick non non-binding suggestion
i reviewing last calls is great everyone
I've support more review you know the
message layers security group just had
their charter Vogel what's up everyone's
going to see me go forward
lots of obvious human rights connections
the Indian encryption and group
messaging and and they're basically
making a charter what security
properties and privacy properties so
another model or something which you can
do in addition if people have lots of
time would be the liaison with working
groups which are in charter stage and
talk them about their threat models and
their charter and that could be informal
or could be done over their mailing list
I think that could be a way to influence
new high profile work that hasn't quite
got to the last call stage yeah as long
as we can totally stay on our side of
the border in that one too and I and I'm
very i I think what we're doing is
important in this group in the long run
but I want to really careful not to
transgress that IETF IRT F different I
would say differently we have to be
modest we are we did nothing yet so we
should start
slowly and build a reputation at a time
kawaii high current I was wondering if I
could provide a little bit of pushback
to to what you said ivory because I
understand that you want everybody to
stay in their lane for this work to be
effective but at the same time you see
people who are in this group going to
IETF working groups training they're
standing there saying this and I work
for the ACLU the cdtv article 19 coming
with a very specific perspective and
that isn't frowned upon as such I also
think we need to be bold to bring what
we do here to other places bold but
careful a very short suggests and how
this really a team could be useful for
other groups and I think especially
advertising it as a service and saying
oh if you're designing something if you
have something you're not sure about or
you think that might have human rights
considerations come to us we'll review
it and we look at that and either we
make you feel comfortable that you did
the job right or we point out things
weird might be problematic
I think the framing it this way would
disappoint nobody and help to getting
this stuff forward okay thank you
again we're one minute over now because
we don't we cannot yet pose as the Human
Rights review experts because we didn't
do anything at this time not really so
better to start to build things to send
reviews and then we will be able to
outreach to the rest of the IETF and to
tell them a we provide a great service
but it's too early yeah thank you I
think it's a great idea thank you for
the discussion we got to all the agenda
items except for open discussion and any
other business but we can have lots of
open discussion on the list and I really
appreciate the amount of good discussion
we had in the meeting see on the list
thank you and anybody that did do the
blue signing thing please come up and do
the blue signing thing
done thank you
[Applause]