hi welcome to ATF 101 welcome to i2 RS
you might have noticed that I'm not
actually so unfortunately she's sick and
Russ is still on the way from the
airport so you get my shining
countenance don't look so puzzle Chris
hi
she's yeah she's yeah she's uh she is
noticeably sex so let's go through so
the first thing is of course the agenda
bashing in RFC's I'm going to talk to
you about the current status
I also want to make sure that everyone
knows who Martin is because he is going
to be the responsible ad for i2 RS after
Wednesday don't forget to smile and talk
about what's going on with the drafts
that are in working group last call and
the transfer of work to RG gwg and then
party time did you all bring hats all
right well if you didn't bring hats
that's okay we'll get on with it
so let's see we've gotten a number of
documents published from the IRS working
group most recently in anthropology and
else reads apology model we had the
architecture down a while ago the
traceability framework publications
subscription and work which we all know
have turned into a good amount of work
over in net cogs there was a serious
drive for that you only see the impact
of that happening in telemetry security
requirements ephemeral state again where
net mod is done the nmda which is also
now in RFC so that we are able to have a
ephemeral state and use gang models for
basically the api's that were envisioned
fra - RS we still have three documents
that are in working group last call
there's the rib data model the rib
information model and the yang DC fabric
network the rib data model and
information model are familiar to you
all because we've had them in the
working group for a very long time and
they're really important documents
coming from the working group I'm
extremely excited to see them go forward
I did an ad review they're all good and
they're in IE TF last call they're in a
bit of a prolonged IETF last calls we
had a large number of documents in IETF
last call and so some of them had to
stretch out what that does mean is
Martin is going to be being the
responsible ad for i2 RS and plan is to
get these through documents through
and then the working group is going to
be closed because you know we've gotten
the work done which is awesome
the there is one document which is the
elta to network topology draft where I'd
like to see some discussion on that
document if possible there's a working
group last call conformation happening
on the mailing list right now and it's
you know the documents been dormant for
a while but that was basically because
it was done and waiting on the topology
and l3 topology ones I haven't done a
review of it Martin it's gonna be up to
Martin to do their ad review of it and
decide whether it's going to be ready to
go from this working group or whether it
needs to move over to Archie gwg so does
I want to talk about the l2 topology one
oh yeah go for Chris awesome thank you
Hey
so I'm the yang doctor reviewer of this
document it was requested to be done by
ITF I did not get it done by Kristian
hops by the way there are some issues
that the TLDR version of my review is it
defines features like I can't think of
any off the top of my head that it
doesn't use PBB right and I don't know
if it should be defining features that
it literally doesn't reference the other
thing is the end caps it defines end
caps like ATM that it doesn't add any
attributes for and I'm I don't know
exactly what the right thing to do here
is but I suspect it's to leave that end
cap to be defined by somebody who
actually is understanding the technology
and wants to put the attributes in so a
few things like that I think it's gonna
have to wrap though that was my main
comment was I don't think it's ready to
go completely final so I guess it would
follow with Martin or move to a
different working group right so I had
intended to close I tore us this meeting
but because of the documents that are
not through that's not happening and as
I said Martin's gonna wait and close the
working group when the documents are
done which should be well before a next
idea I
yeah for the l2 topology model I want to
have to see how if the responses are
quick to your comments or if it needs to
move to RT to WG for discussion hey Alex
so does anyone else have any comments on
the l2 network topology okay so let's
see there one other document that was
being started but hadn't progressed
fully is the ephemeral data store model
and the ephemeral data store model is
going to go to our teacher WG to get
finished we've made a lot of progress on
that in the last couple IETF cycles
which is really great but it's just not
quite done yet so we're gonna have that
happen in our twg and the IQR s security
environment requirements draft has been
sitting for a while it did go through
working group last call but it's one of
those documents that was really useful
to sort of pull things together and be
clear but we don't see it as having
longevity in meeting archival you know
keeping so it's not gonna be published
so any right before we go to celebration
time let's lease over for a few minutes
does anyone have any comments or
questions so I I don't know if there's
if it's appropriate I don't know how
about how far and wide spread the
topology models are yet at DT I think we
have a use for them specifically we've
been talking a lot about lately about
the you know being identify all three
links when we have like a fiber failure
right so having the the way that it's
organized is really well the models
could do with some I mean I don't
understand why like types are containers
I unfortunately I think the ship sailed
right because it's an RFC they are we do
bise's yeah and and like the
notifications in l2 are really generic
like why aren't they just generic
notifications that when they identify an
l2 network
you know it's an LT notification but I
don't know if there's any room for any
cleanup or rewrapping probably not since
you're gonna close this group down so
the there's a lot of work as you
strangely enough well now in Archie gwg
onyang models and so my expectation is
that there is absolutely room for rework
if it's needed particularly since you
know deployment and you know
implementation experience is really
excellent so I think that it could
happen in art gwg if it makes sense I'd
encourage you of course to talk to the
authors of the RFC's and the authors for
the elta to apology
since the LTH apology model is not as
far along I think there is the
opportunity there for some rework based
on your experience yeah I mean that's
kind of what I was thinking right since
we haven't pushed out to through yet
it's maybe we've moved the notifications
to abyss of the generic but I don't know
because all three also got published so
now it has specific notifications okay
yeah I think it's it's they're perfectly
fine for what we need to use them for
but yeah as I try to use them more
directly maybe we'll find a few things
sure that sounds great
okay any other comments or thoughts
considerations so I mean thank you all
thank you all for your hard work thank
you all for coming thank you all for
getting the stuff done I know the
working group has been has gone through
some challenging times to get the work
done and I think that we've made the
impact that was anticipated in terms of
the technologies that were necessary to
support I tore us and and also just in
terms of changing how people think about
yegg models what we can do with them and
having them not just be for a
configuration obviously the ability to
go forward and use the same kind of
models with different protocols as more
of an API or interface is now there that
we've got the functionality
the femoral data stores being fit
working is going to go off to our twg
but the understanding of how that works
in net mod and with yang is there the
notifications are there we've made a lot
of progress over the last few years and
so I just really want to say thank you
and now you'll be shocked to hear it's
time to celebrate so I hope you all had
breakfast oh please do fill out the
wishes so I'd ask you all to you know
continue to help with as Martin has and
just with comments particularly the
author's for the documents that are in
last call this is Martin he's going to
be the routing ad of course as of
Thursday and not me anymore then you
know please do work with him to get
those documents done because they really
matter the one which is in let's call
the layer two topology one really if you
could take a look at it
send your comments if you don't have
technique
commence at least support or comment on
the progression of this document because
it's really important especially at the
stage of the working group to have a
real situation on how to progress it on
up yep
and really that's it so you can all
start milling around and talking to each
other all right fine if you give an
author of one of the documents one of
the RFC is could you stand up and if you
could share yeah I know and you know
what I think that's a good thing if
you've worked on yeah and if you've
reviewed a document and provided good
feedback and thank you all very much
it's really awesome and that's a wrap
not very long
you