[Music]
if if folks could take their seats we're
gonna get started
welcome everyone I'm Alisa Cooper I'm
the chair of the IETF and in case you're
not sure where you are in this hotel
you're in the plenary so welcome to the
plenary here in lovely London I will say
that on one of the first days that I was
here for this meeting end of last week I
was trying to figure out where my next
meeting was in the in the hotel and
walked over to the elevators and was
kind of shuffling with my phone looking
at the at the floorplan and I figured
out okay I need to be in the West Wing
which is where we are now and then
realized I actually don't know which
wing I am in at the moment and so I sort
of looked up for my phone to see you
know maybe the wall is gonna tell me
with a sign which wing I'm in but of
course it didn't but what I did see on
the wall was was this sign and and and
then it became very meta because I was
like wait a minute I'm in a sort of maze
or labyrinth if you will and and that
guy is also in a labyrinth and I sort of
thought what is that sign doing here
like why am I looking at this guy who's
in a labyrinth and I'm in a labyrinth it
only took a second but then I realized
of course that this is part of our our
dear Secretariat's scavenger hunt to
help people familiarize themselves with
this venue and I just wanted to take a
moment to thank AMS and all of the
Secretariat folks for all the support
that they provide to the IETF and in the
very unique way in which they understand
our needs and tailor to them so thank
you very much
and you know that extends to things like
showing up with a leprechaun suit
in honor of st. Patrick's Day which
happened on the weekend in case for
those of you who weren't here Alexa was
wandering around as a leprechaun as was
I think Stephanie and she as you can see
was not wearing a red lanyard and gave
me consent to use her photo in the
plenary so kudos to AMS thank you so
much for all that you do for the IETF
today we will have our sort of typical
agenda so welcome to the plenary we will
hear from our one of our hosts at this
meeting and then we'll have brief
updates on hot topics so as people have
seen in the plenaries the last couple of
years we have sent out many reports in
advance of the plenary that contain a
lot of detail about all the things that
are going on in the IETF and we are
attempting to make the plenary
presentations short and to the point and
highlighting just the most current
issues for the community so well I will
get one of those we'll have
administrative update an update from the
IRT F chair Alison Menken here from the
past and incoming NomCom chairs and we
will hear from I sock about the Jonathan
B pastel award then we'll get a bit of a
preview of IETF 102 coming up this
summer we will recognize some folks in
the community who are transitioning in
their status and then we'll have the
technical plenary which I'm very excited
about about the future of Internet
access we have a bunch of great speakers
for you and that's a program that the
IAB has put together and then we'll
close out the day with the typical open
mic sessions so first I want to say a
huge thank you to our co-hosts for this
meeting Google and I can thank you so
much for your support of the ITF
we really we we really could not have
the meetings without the hosts although
we occasionally do there just not nearly
as good the host plays a really
important role not just through their
financial support but other logistical
and administrative support of the
meeting and so we really appreciate that
and now I'd like to ask urine to come up
to the stage and we're gonna hear from
one of our co-hosts I can
[Music]
don't you feel alone sitting up here by
yourself anyway thank you I never have
in I never received so many instructions
going to any meeting since I started for
joy for I can I just want to share with
you some of them
my first mission here is to make make
sure that I don't embarrass my team
where is my team I think yeah they also
told me they'd be nice and be yourself
that's contradiction in terms isn't it
and I didn't I don't I don't have to I
shouldn't wear a suit and a tie which
most people never seen me have anyway so
I don't know what that I was actually
thinking of wearing a suit in entire yes
for that
thank you I don't know how much you know
about ICANN itself or myself by I
actually I am called the most nerdiest
CEO like that ever I have a background
in switching routing mobile telecom but
for the last year I'm now a recovering
telecom regulator so I've seen them you
know most things from both sites but I
never been to an ITF meeting before so
I'm really happy to be here for me
in a sort of personal way when people
ask me what is ICAP and I always start
with one sentence I can is not the
Internet what we may be is the sort of
user interface to the Internet for the
domain name system but more importantly
we're a member of an ecosystem and aleko
system is you who'd understand the
relation work is aisaka does the policy
or the or ers or the numbers community
and from the outside and I'm not
supposed to say this according to my
share we're in this together I
didn't say that did I thank you for
listening
and that's important to me a couple of
years ago when I was appointed to CEO I
had the pleasure of going to you as
Congress to meet a guy called Ted Cruz
and one of the things I talked about all
the time is in the voluntarily of the
system we do this because it's set up to
be voluntarily we work together because
we have to in a voluntary way everybody
can sort of walk away and do something
different I don't do this to sell domain
names I do this because I think it sends
an important that the internet stays
open and interconnected I think you have
done a great job all of you
despite all you even have more acronyms
than we have yes you do
do all the winners but now for the first
time I also see that the things we do
together collectively in DeCecco systems
is fretted I can give you one examples
there are many legislative proposals and
discussions around the world right now
here in Europe in the US and other parts
of the world that maybe for the first
time ever will have an effect on our
abilities to makes policies and there
are any discussions and I don't judge
from them or being good or bad I don't
say that that is the stupid idea but I
know that some of them can actually have
hurt the interconnectivity of internet
that itself and I think that we need to
continue to work together what I heard
from this lot this week has been very
interesting and my team has been
stopping me for going in or having
opinions about technical stuff which I
don't know about that is otherwise what
I love to do but to continue this work
together and hopefully me being here and
you coming to us and we can work on
issue base together we can make sure
that what I'm here for and what I know
that many of you are there for is to
make sure that internet stays open and
interconnected we do our part I would
love to continue to work with you thank
you very much
[Applause]
you're a now you can take back to your
community and I can the virtues that
you've actually experienced of having a
plenary in the evening rather than in
the morning firsthand experience so
moving on to highlight a few issues of
interest to the ITF community at large
today I'm going to cover some statistics
about participation at this meeting a
new event that we had on Sunday hot RFC
a little bit about the side meetings and
code lounge experiments that we have
continued to run here at ITF 101 an
update on the ITF administrative support
activity to dotto is a todo and just a
note about respectful behavior in the
community so first a participant
statistics at this meeting we have one
thousand one hundred and eighty nine
people on site and we have two hundred
and eighteen attendees for whom it's
their first meeting so thank you to all
of you for coming for the first time to
experience an IETF in person and thank
you to all of those who've been coming
for a long time who've helped those
newcomers find their way if we compare
two meetings our most recent Spring
Meeting which is last spring we have
more people showed up here than did in
Chicago at IETF 98 if we compare to our
most recent European meeting which was
last summer we had more people show up
in Prague than than we did here you can
see the country breakdown on the slide
we had the the largest fraction from the
US followed by the UK not China Germany
Japan and and you can see the rest a
fairly typical split for us folks from
59 countries have showed up at this
meeting again that's kind of somewhere
in between the statistics for IETF 98
and IETF 99 last year just a word about
the hackathon
participation in the ITF hackathon
continues to grow
meeting over meeting so this was our
largest one yet we had about 220 people
participating on-site and 20 remote we
had 35 projects which is substantially
more projects than we've had at any
prior hackathon and new for this meeting
as well on Monday night for those of
those of you who caught it we had a hack
demo
happy hour so that all the teams could
have a little bit more time to present
the results of their work to the
community and to engage in discussions
with with people who are interested in
their projects to understand what they
got done over the weekend and how it
fits into the rest of the work of the
IETF and we're gonna continue to
experiment with that sort of thing so if
you have feedback about that event or
about the hackathon itself you can
always email it to the hackathon list
you can email me you can email charles
eckle who's who's been the main driver
behind the the hackathon and for
planning purposes we are certainly
planning to do the hackathon again at
IETF 102 July 14 and 15 in the Saturday
and Sunday
at the start of the meeting week at this
meeting we also tried a new event on
Sunday night organized by Aaron Falk
with support on the IHG from Ilya Atlas
and Spencer Dawkins odd request for
conversation otherwise known as hot RFC
so this was an opportunity for people
who wanted to give brief lightning talks
to encourage brainstorming to find
collaborators to advertise their their
bar buffs or to just generally raise
awareness about some new idea that they
have or that they that they've been
working on and by all accounts it seems
the feedback that we've gotten so far is
quite positive we had 17 lightning talks
that were given and we had about
somewhere between 80 and a hundred
people in the room it ran concurrently
with the second hour of the Welcome
Reception and you can find the
proceedings online all the slides are up
there the is she is very interested in
hearing from the community about what
they thought about this of whether we
should do it again what we should change
or do differently so please send that
feedback to iesg at IETF org or happy to
talk about it at the open mic session
here as well and big thanks to Aaron for
all his work in
helping to organize that we've also
continued our experiment at this meeting
with side meetings and and the coat
lounge so what we've done for side
meetings is we've allocated one large
room in one small room that people can
book in advance for their side meetings
so no more going through your area
director to book those slots as long as
they are not conflicting with with the
mealtimes both of the rooms have
projectors and then if you do want to
book a meal timeslot signups for those
open up on-site and just a reminder for
people who are thinking about using that
again in the future that we do have the
IETF meeting rooms policy which
specifies which kinds of meeting
meetings can be held as side meetings
and which ones are considered corporate
meetings that require payment and so
it's important to remember the line
between those things the code lounge is
a portion of ITF meeting room space
which has been set aside for people to
get together and hack together to
continue their activities from the
hackathon or just generally do some
development work on the side of the ITF
meeting and both of these are still kind
of in the experimental stage so we're
continuing to collect feedback about
whether people find them useful and and
refinements that we can make we've
changed up the side meeting sign up a
little bit so that anybody could sign up
this time definitely interested in your
feedback about these experiments now to
the IETF administrative support activity
or I asset Udo so is is the name that we
use to describe the way that we
structure the administration of the IETF
that means the meeting planning the
financial planning the fundraising and
so on I asked a toe toe is an activity
that started in November of 2016
with a sort of project plan that yarko
the previous IETF chair mailed out to
the ITF list over the last year we've
had a kind of extensive discussion on
the is a to-do list and at the ITF
meetings about restructuring or
refactoring the way that we conduct our
administrative activities there's a
bunch of different factors that have led
to the current structure being not the
best
as it was in the beginning and so we've
had this conversation about
transitioning to a different structure
or whether there's things that we can do
to improve upon the current situation
over the last two meeting cycles the
group has been considering multiple
different legal options for what a new
structure could look like everything
from staying exactly as we are which is
as an activity of I sock where the ITF
does not have its own legal entity all
the way to becoming an independent
organization from I sock to how's the
administration of the ITF and yesterday
we had a Boff session where we talked in
even greater detail about several of
these different options that have been
considered and that about which we had
sought legal advice and what happened in
the bathroom is a couple of things first
by the end of the session we had rough
consensus in the room in favor of
creating a limited liability corporation
that would be treated as a division of I
sock for tax purposes in order to house
just the administrative piece of the ITF
so this doesn't really have anything to
do with the standards process and
everything that the IHG and the IEP do
and that happens in the working groups
and among document authors but just for
the administration of the IETF and this
particular legal structure has a number
of values and properties to recommend it
as several of the others that we
considered but that was kind of where
the the room landed and if you want more
details on any of this it's all
available on the is a to doto mailing
list we also in that session got lots of
good feedback about many of the
organizational details that we would
need to hammer out if we went down this
path of changing the administrative
structure so the plan going forward is
first of all to confirm the hums on the
list from from that session which is the
mail has already gone out about that and
then to basically take the choice of
legal structure assuming it gets
confirmed and embed that choice in a
working group Charter which has also
been circulated on the list and via that
mechanism confirm the the sense of the
ITF community that this is the direction
in which we want to take our legal
structure for our administration going
forward the Charter for the working
group would be to update our existing
RFC's that this
drive all of all of these administrative
structures and then outside the working
group we would begin working on the
actual legal documentation which we
would not write in the working group
since that's not an appropriate venue to
do that kind of thing and these
processes would work in parallel so if
you're interested in any of this please
join the mailing list I asked a to toe
I know that many people are not
interested in this but for some people
it's an it's the choice of an
administrative structure embodies a lot
about the IETF and and how we operate as
a community and so I really wanted to
just take a few minutes of your time to
raise awareness about this in case it's
something that people haven't been
following I also wanted to just take a
moment to touch on respectful behavior
in our community so on the slide you can
see we have us of our existing policies
that govern behavior in the IETF we have
guidelines for conduct which is encoded
in a PCP we have an anti-harassment
policy put forth by the IHG a couple of
years ago we also have anti harassment
procedures which created our Ombuds team
who's here on site and the newest policy
of these is the IETF meeting photography
policy that we that the IHG put forth
just before the meeting after
consultation with the community and
which has been supported by as you can
see some folks wearing red lanyards at
this meeting with their choice to not be
photographed as an individual when not
operating in a leadership capacity and
white lanyards for for the rest of the
crowd so you can take a minute and you
can kind of peruse the policies
familiarize yourself with them if you
haven't before but perhaps more
important than reading the policies I
think it's important for everybody to
think just for a minute about what
happens in this community and how much
it is derived from the individual
choices that we all make so this
community is really made up of it is
what we make it and if you want to be
treated respectfully then you need to
treat other people respectfully and I
think sometimes like it's a little bit
lost like it's really easy to get really
amped up about whatever technical topic
you're discussing or if you're having to
be discussing say one of these policies
on a mailing list it's easy to get lost
in the details
and get overheated about those things
and I think it's important for all of us
to kind of take a check sometimes and
and think about are we conducting
ourselves in the in the best manner
possible to achieve the goals of the IHF
so I wanted to take a moment to do that
today and hopefully that's been helpful
we have a whole bunch of other topics
that are covered online in the report
that we sent to the community at the end
of last week so other experiments that
were running information about appeals
which we haven't had any of in the last
cycle status update about how we're
trying to handle some Demark issues with
IETF mailing lists and lots of other
reports from other parts of the IETF
that you can find online in addition to
the blog where we're regularly providing
narrative content about what's going on
in the IETF
and with that I will turn it over to
administrative hot topics so beyond say
if you're come and come up to the to the
mic and Porsche wind family
[Laughter]
so just to explain why the name fiance
is on the slide so the the IASE which is
the administrative oversight committee
of the IETF doesn't elect its share in
the ITF week until Tuesday morning so
yesterday morning was when we elected
the new chair of the ia OSI and yet the
slides for this presentation need to be
built
you know eons in advance in order to
make sure that they're all correct and
that the full IOC has the opportunity to
review them and and get every detail
right and so in the in the initial
versions of the slides that you're about
to see the IOC chair was listed as
Beyonce because we didn't know who it
could be and and the thought of it
actually being Beyonce was pretty
exciting for some of us so we thought
you know why not put that in there and
then after we did the election and our
new chair andrew sullivan
was was elected i dared him to leave it
in on his part of the slides and he said
yes and so I left it in on my part of
the slides as well so
alyssa is going to learn not to dare me
to do things thanks Alysa wanted to make
sure that everyone knew that i was not
trying to be Beyonce
sorry I thought it was one deck
okay so I'm here to thank our hosts
again and Google + icon our co-host we
really thank you for everything that
you've done to help put on 101 there's
no way that we could have done all of
this work without you and we appreciate
everything that you've done for us this
week the slot has all of our sponsors it
of course we really appreciate your work
BT British Telecom is our connectivity
sponsor Facebook I is Facebook and
Oracle our silver sponsors for us and
Google icon and the Hilton Metropole are
the sources for our Welcome Reception
so thank you and of course in the
background there's so many people who
are working to who come into the into
the venue so early to make sure that
everything is going as it should and
also just working behind the scenes
we've got our codes front and I each
have data tracker enhancement our
volunteers for that and for some reason
that the slides are going faster than I
am and next for the hackathon thank you
so much to Cisco and Deb net we
appreciate everything that you've done
for us we've had the biggest hackathon
that we've had to date so thank you
and of course there's the knock the
knock the great knock so volunteers
there we've got line speed and thank you
for from elfin for you and your team and
me deco who brings and remote
participants for the meeting
a reminder that thursday is tomorrow
we've got Dave Conrad for Thursday Tech
Talk and hopefully everyone will have a
chance where most of you will have a
chance to stop by and for that and last
but not least certainly we would like to
announce ours go global host for
Montreal OneNote ITF 105 July 20th thru
26 2019 and thank you very much Tom Cass
NBC Universal
[Music]
so the problem is that I can't dance and
I only sing old standards before I
before I that's right before I begin
before I begin talking about the IOC
more generally I first want to start
with some infinite thanks to to two
people who are leaving the IOC Leslie
and to be us are both previous chairs of
of the IOC you may not know this but not
everybody in this room is always
entirely nice to the IOC and and and
these are the people who who took many
of those slings and arrows arrows over
time and and I understand something
about how you can you know sometimes you
misjudge things sometimes the community
is not perfectly clear about all of the
things that it wants and I think that
both Leslie and Tobias did some
wonderful work they helped us over time
so I really want to thank them very much
I know we're gonna thank people later
but I want to do that mostly because
sometimes I was the sling holder so
Glenn and I are joining the the IOC
again I for my sins I'm coming back and
so my colleagues picked me as the fool
who put his head in the sling so here I
am on we have some other welcome to make
we have a new legal counsel and this has
been split up a little bit so a brad is
actually here and will be coming up a
little bit later so you can see him in
the flesh but there is a picture David
Wilson is the last not here but he is
also part of our new counsel team so
that's great news we also have a new
sponsorship fundraiser ken is also here
and you know keep your eyes peeled for
him and get your wallets ready now we
put up the detailed report already so
I'm not going to go into all kinds of
details here but it's there on the on
the slides and of course you can find it
on the web but I do want to remind
people of a couple of things first of
all we have this new venue selection
committee
so the meetings committee was is is
coming to an end and the new venue
selection committee has been announced
the IOC appointed Glenn Dean who is a
member of the IOC to to chair the new
venue selection committee we're still
looking for community volunteers for all
of the committee's but I want to take
this moment to thank Olli and averey for
their leadership of the meetings
committee in the past now why am i
standing up here well because of budgets
that's the reason we have the IOC we're
the you know people who are nominally
responsible to you in order you know
having to do with anything to do with
the money here and the the news is not
as good as we would like so we put up
the expenses and the annual the the
budget and also the budget narrative
that was announced a little while ago
and it's on the list
I urge you to read it this is how we how
we are accountable to you you know we do
the counting so this is this is
something that I really urge you to have
a look at because after all you paid to
be here or most of you did anyway and so
the the the budget is not going down
it's the same but but what's really
happening is our expenses are static and
our revenue is not it's falling in
particular we got a problem with
meetings so so we're having a hard time
predicting what the attendance is going
to be and we don't know why it would be
great if we knew why then we would have
a model and it'd be fine but actually
our models broken our sponsorship
however appears to be stable other
challenges there as there always have
been that's the reason of course that
ken has joined us but you know that part
seems to be pretty good but I'm quite
worried about the attendance so we're
gonna have to do some things about this
now well it's been how many in the past
is every time we run into a shortfall I
socks says well don't worry about it
we're gonna look after that but that
can't go on forever right so we're the
this this year what we're gonna do is
we're gonna take last year's actual
contribution and we just increase the
budget by that much
the budgeted I saw contribution which
means that we better come in inside our
our targets right so that's one thing
we're planning to keep the meeting
registration fees the same in 2018
there's no current plan to raise them
this year but I want to draw your
attention to that third bullet the
current forecast is that we're gonna
raise the meeting fees next year and the
guidance that's currently in the system
is that we're gonna do it a little more
than 10% and then 3% you know in in the
following years now we have not voted on
this so we have not in fact decided this
but it's early in the year and we want
to warn you now that this is coming so
that you can start budgeting in your own
budgets for it so that when it happens
next year it's not a giant surprise so
be aware of this is potentially coming
up we will be debating this we'll be
discussing it in the IOC we have a
retreat in April and there will be you
know blood on the ground and everything
by the time we leave because of the
discussions over raising rates nobody
likes to raise rates but it's it's a
fact of life at the same time we know
that I asked a 2-0 is coming along we
don't know how that's going to affect
ietf finances there's lots of things
that could happen there and nobody knows
what's going to happen that could affect
registration fees as well so you need to
be prepared for that there is the Budget
and Finance page I urge you once again
to have a look at that budget because
that's how we're held accountable to you
so a quick snapshot of the numbers so
far we've got paid attendance of about
1200 which is just 40 fewer than
projected so this meeting is looking
better than the last couple we have 418
remote participants registered however
and that that is changing you know
fairly rapidly which has some
implications for our budget as well
because we have to support all of that
there were two hundred and thirteen
letters issued visa letters so we've got
some registration revenues and
sponsorship revenues there I don't think
any of this is final usually this
there's some you know final adjustment
that happens but these are pretty close
so you know these are the numbers right
now so thanks very much for this there
are some additional materials at the end
of this slide deck
that you can download online if you want
but I'll stop talking so that we can get
on to the interesting things in this
meeting thanks very much so next we have
the IEEE RTF update so Allison if you
could come on
hello I think people know who I am and I
want people to know more about what the
I RTF is as well but I'm Allison Lincoln
this is you've seen this mission
statement before in others of these
plenaries but we have a parallel
organization of research groups that do
work that's forward out ahead of what is
reasonable to standardize and the goal
is to strongly have a close tie between
them to make this a great a great place
for new and innovative thinkers to bring
work that can then become applied we
I've added the no standardization
sentence here because we continue to
have confusion about whether if we're
producing RFC's they'll also be standard
so the the documents from IRT F even if
they if they are FCS and they aren't
always going to be will be experimental
or informational and will be and are
clearly labeled as such and we're
working on that within the context of
the of the stream owners in the in the
with with Heather on that this is a list
of all the research groups that I just
want to mention that they are continuing
to meet avidly here and so I think
there's a lot of it there seems to be a
lot of bringing together of people who
are researchers with people who have
been more traditionally not researchers
and we have a method of something called
proposed research groups where you can
meet quite freely if you have a good
idea for three meetings and then we'll
decide if it's actually progressing it
is going to be useful so we have two of
those at the moment path aware
networking and the decentralized
internet infrastructure group that are
are moving along in that process and in
fact path aware I had its third meeting
yesterday and the room was strongly in
support of it moving forward and I think
that will happen another bit of news
tonight the technical plenary is partly
brought to you by the IRT F because it's
it's co-organized by the the
B's committee and by the Gaia global
access to the Internet for all research
group we encourage the group's to meet
not only at ITF but also to meet where
the researchers are and to import people
from from the protocol community to the
more abstract or theoretical groups and
NMR G has been doing this for years so
they're the only one that's actually not
meeting here because they'll be meeting
at a conference in tae Baek
and then we've started initial
discussion because of some wonderful
advocates for it for a quantum internet
research group and the room there we
didn't actually take a hum I I don't
know what a quantum hum would be like
but we did actually ask about we got
some comments about the fact that this
might actually be timely now there's a
lot of likelihood that protocols will be
developed to manage this really cool low
layer that can do quantum entanglement
and those protocols could be developed
by not us if we don't take action so
keep your eye on that join this mailing
list which is currently called quark Qi
RG and C that's very interesting and
also eventually we have set make this
joke so anyhow probably people have
already heard it from me somewhere but
you'll eventually have to call
yourselves the classic IETF and we'll
also have the quantum IETF classical
IETF I've also one mentioned that we
have a yearly workshop which intends to
slightly formalize how we do research
being brought together with with
protocols and the submission date is is
April 20th so it's it's still in time
for you to do your submission you can
either submit a paper that was published
in the last year or a short new paper
that would be sort of like a lightning
talk and it will take place in Montreal
at the next meeting what we will do and
this is another experiment is have the
meeting during the ITF week so it'll be
on the Monday rather than co-located but
not during the time this is intended to
help people to attend the workshop we're
still I need to have a conversation with
Beyonce about the way that an team about
the way that
going to handle the registration fees
but but the goal is again to bring the
people together and we'd like for people
to stay and go to our g's and working
groups now that there so people have
never come we have quite a few people
who are new attendees who are here
because of the IRT F and then learned
something about many of the speakers
were or new attendees I should probably
start tracking that and the other thing
we'll do is we'll have topical blocks so
that sono research groups will meet that
day but also will make it so that it'll
be easier for the ietf areas to say most
of the routing things are there so I'll
try not to schedule routing things where
and I'll have to hope that this doesn't
blow the minds of our very wonderful
Secretariat as we try to work on this
but but I've been active in the
scheduling anyway so there's another
another note on the relationships we
have and there should be a good song for
this but anyway we have we have many
times when I I say oh I wish that people
from such-and-such research group had
been here because look at this great
stuff that is being presented which is
from the measurement world or something
like that so I want to advertise that
yesterday for example the map RG had
great new data and analysis about about
current research working group topics
ipv6 the HDTV to push quick DNS SEC you
get the idea so corner me or send me
mail send mail to the IR s G about what
you think might be useful in way of ways
that we can help with the interworking
here we have another feature which is a
every year we pick two best papers at
the applied networking research prize a
NRP
for each ITF and announced them just
before the ITF we had presentations
today during the IRT F open group and
I'll mention them these are sponsored by
Comcast NBC Universal and Internet
Society and I'm very we're very grateful
for that the sponsorship has been
increased this year and we're looking
forward to adding some ability to give
more people chances to come back
after they've done one of these press
patience and continue their engagement
we had the biggest set of submissions
ever this year and as a result we could
have actually had 10 or 12 of these
awards but we don't really have enough
time to have presentations and and
finally IOT F dot org is where you can
find all of our info but if you also go
to our Twitter feed in your Tahoe you
can see the victorious picture of the to
a and our P folks that I just posted
today and find out more and I'm very
happy to talk with people or answer
questions during the open mikes okay
next we're gonna hear from the past and
current NomCom chairs so Peter Yi and
scott mansfield if you guys could come
on up
already--as this is the NomCom report so
for the NomCom 2017 2018 I'd like to
draw your attention once again to our
voting members list and for the list of
non-voting members as well those are the
liaisons advisors and chair positions
and this is the output of why there is a
NomCom we made selections for the IAB
IOC and iesg as you can see there yeah I
didn't get the memo but Beyonce as part
of the noms de nom comms work we also
bring up some areas of weaknesses these
are things that we notice well we're
doing going through the NomCom process
and this is not new we brought up these
issues last year as well it still
remains these still remain areas of
concern so some areas have very small
leadership pools and perhaps even
smaller pipelines of future leaders the
internet area the transport area we just
find it difficult to get nominees there
and we would very much encourage anyone
who's got the slightest interest in a
leadership position to consider running
there's also the obvious concern about
employer support and so we are giving
some consideration Scott may address
that about an earlier call for nominees
to give people more time to line up
employer support because it takes a
while we understand that and sometimes
if you don't get into the process early
enough it's hard to get feedback as well
and really be engaged in the the NomCom
so our requests of the community check
your eligibility to volunteer for the
NomCom I think last year we had about
125 people you can check online and you
can actually volunteer for the NomCom
just by putting a checking the the s box
on the registration form
and I think it looks back a year so I
know that we surprised some people last
year when we announced the selections
for the NomCom and some folks couldn't
remember having actually volunteered so
we will work on that also if you're
interested in providing feedback on the
nominees you need a data tracker profile
so make sure you have one of those and
then if you have any specific inputs
that you'd like to make that are not
necessarily about the actual nominees
but about the area and issues and things
like that
do let us know thank you
Scott you're up thank you very much so I
just introduced myself real quick I
don't want to take a lot of time I'm
Scott Mansfield I of course an
individual of representing the ietf
community but my employers Erikson and
so I just wanted to give you a chance to
see who I was and if you have questions
about NomCom please come and ask me I
would really like to start the process a
little bit earlier this year so that we
can get some more feedback and try to
get a much bigger pool I would also like
to see more people volunteer to be
selected to work on the NomCom because
it really is a great rollercoaster ride
you'll have a great time and we actually
even feed you a little bit at at the
meeting so that's about does Spencer
have a question Spencer Dawkins third
term area director for Transport and I
was I was just going to suggest to the
community that we also remember that you
know thank you all for serving and thank
you for now comes for serving serving up
a pretty impressive group of leadership
over a bunch of years which I've had the
opportunity to serve under and serve
with it seems to me that at least a
little bit of what we're talking about
here is kind of like the Kobayashi Maru
thing where it's like basically this is
a fascinating problem to solve about how
we how we recruit leadership for a
couple of the areas and that there may
not be anything that other than doing
the james t kirk thing of saying we're
going to reprogram the simulator b and
that's not your problem to solve
okay and that's not the iesg problem to
solve or the IBS problem to solve
particular that's really a community
thing so i would ask the people in the
community be thinking about what what we
as community can do to reprogram the
simulator so that we're not sitting here
in 2028 having the same conversation
about in the area in the transport area
because i'm almost sure there will still
be an IP protocol and perhaps even
quicker tcp yeah thank you very much for
that i think that that is excellent
input and what the NomCom can do is
continue to bring that that message back
to to the leadership and help foster the
discussion because like we always say
with these nam cons it's it's basically
you get a big box you put it in the
middle of the room you let the cat jump
in it and then you close the lid so the
last thing i'll say is I'd like to thank
Kathy Brown for selecting me and then
Peter and Lucy I'm going to rely on them
heavily to hopefully that this this
NomCom for 2018-2019 will run as
smoothly as the last two thank you very
much so just a real quick thanks I
wanted to thank everybody who did
volunteer for the NomCom 2017-2018 look
for scott's email shortly asking for
volunteers so if you haven't volunteered
previously on a registration form you
can do that by email as well I'd like to
thank all of those who were nominated
and accepted their nominations obviously
as we've said we need more of you a
special thank you to the Secretariat who
makes it so easy for us to have NomCom
meetings NomCom sessions here at the
meetings it really makes a difference
and then finally to the tools team for
some quick hacks to the data tracker we
use the data tracker all the time all of
the data goes in there and they made
lives a lot easier so thank you everyone
I just want a second that appreciation
for the NomCom for for Peter and
everyone else who was on the NomCom last
year it's it's an arduous task
particularly in the in the November
meeting and the fall and winter
timeframe and those who volunteer I
think deserve special recognition from
us for their willingness to commit the
time and energy that it takes to help us
find the next generation of leaders for
the ITF so big thanks to all of you and
to Scott for being willing to Shepherd
it this year so next we're gonna hear
about the Postell award
I'm Kathy Brown in it is that time of
year again that is my great pleasure to
introduce and that the pastel award to
those who don't know John pastel was in
the center of the the Internet you can
see by the relationships almost
everything
some of us all of us are doing he was
there at the beginning he is his memory
is kept alive in this award it's kept
alive and all of you as well but the
year after his untimely death the
Internet Society established the
Jonathan B pastel award to honor
individuals or organizations that like
John pastel have made outstanding
contributions in service to the data
communications community the list of
awardees is quite impressive at this
point there are some things of fabulous
recognition here on this list of people
I know in the last four years that I've
had the privilege to be involved this
community has nominated and then
selected some incredible contributors
and I have noted that the delight the
delay of those who win is quite
authentic real and they feel quite
privileged to have received it so I'm
asking you to think about the
nominations for this year here are the
criteria for the award for those who
might ask the leadership award committee
is actually the past recipients they
appreciate a good list
and that list mostly comes from you all
there is a obviously a a crystal trophy
and and a dollar award but it is really
the honor of receiving it the
nominations opened today they will close
may the second and you can do your
nominations at this website
so next we're going to hear a preview of
ietf 102 I could invite Chris Bowers to
come on up
but we don't really so on behalf of
Juniper Networks I'm happy to be able to
invite you to IETF 102 in Montreal
Canada coming up this July and we're
looking forward to another very
productive meeting Thanks
big props for brevity okay so next we
are going to recognize a few members of
our community and so I'd like to ask
Debra brown guard to come on up oh
you're already here
great
okay well these two people are currently
in the routing area and as chairs their
influences extended way past the
Browning area and I'm sure you all are
very familiar with them the first one is
George swallow we want to thank him for
all his contributions and best wishes
for his retirement he has been chair of
them pillows working group for more than
20 years I think it's going on with 21
plus now your third more than 40 RFC's
he authored the first RFC on RSVP
traffic engineering and also many have
pointed to me that his OSP pain has also
been one of the most famous of his
accomplishments and yes as they say yes
we still got it up and he's mentored
many IET efforts throughout his time
with us including myself so George would
you like to stand up would give you a
hand
okay and the next person is a very
familiar face to you all also its Pat
Thayer
she has been IM TF i triple e go-to
person for everything and she's been i
triple e 802 participant since 1985 she
has I've heard held the most leadership
positions in I Triple E of any person so
last week or the week before they really
honored her there and we are honoring
her here her first idea for tenon we
estimated ITF 50 and she most
instrumentally helped us form our IETF I
Triple E 802 committee coordination
group which has really helped or
relationships and currently she's the
debt networking group chair of Pat
Bennett
thank you so thank you to both of you
thank you so next we're gonna recognize
our outgoing iesg
members we have three people rotating
off this year first Illya Atlas from the
routing area Illya has been a persistent
voice on the iesg at least in my
experience keeping us honest as far as
the way that we operate the way that we
try to shepherd work and steer the
community in order to make sure that our
process is open to as wide a variety of
voices and interests and individuals as
possible and I think that has made a
lasting impact on the IHG and the work
that we do in the ITF she's also really
focused a lot on the leadership aspect
particularly in the routing area
thinking about you know training new
leaders and how we can help people be
successful in the ITF and I think in
addition to all of her many technical
contributions we we owe her a debt of
gratitude for for those efforts which
you know for the rest of the community
maybe not what weren't visible outside
of the routing area or the ihd but I
think we're quite important we have some
gifts that we got for our ASG members
here actually there's three of them and
we had to kind of decide we want to get
all of them ponies weird want to get all
of them unicorns we ended up getting two
ponies in a unicorn so alia we have a we
have a pony for you up here
it's actually a pony in a beer mug one
of one of the groups that alia has
shepherded at length
so next we have been wah plays he's been
that one of the ops and management a DS
so on Sunday I think it was the Sunday
IHG meeting this week Benoit put his
hand up to speak on some topic I don't
even I don't remember the exact agenda
item that we had in the is Xi's own
Sunday morning meeting and on jabra one
of the other area directors immediately
wrote to me and said what do you want to
bet he mentions Yang and the crazy thing
is he didn't it was crazy it was like 30
seconds of speaking and he did not
mention yang in addition to his many
efforts to to push yang throughout the
industry and in the ITF Benoit has been
relentless in holding us accountable to
being relevant to the industry to
adopting operator feedback and input
into the IETF and to trying to make the
ITF a a place where that sort of input
is welcomed and incorporated and that
the on-the-ground experience that
operators have is reflected in the
standards that we create and I think
again that will have a lasting impact
not just in the in the ops area but but
throughout the ITF and certainly in the
is G so Benoit your pony comes in a yang
mug so if you could come on up I'll give
that to you
actually it says forever yang so and
finally we have Kathleen Moriarty who's
who will be rotating off as well from
the security area Kathleen has been a
stalwart colleague of mine personally I
would say we joined around the same time
has really brought a view from the
operational security community into the
IETF itself and onto the isg that I
think didn't really exist
in its in its current form before and
that has I think enlightened all of us
into many of the aspects that were not
often considered in protocol development
in the IETF as recently as four or five
years ago and so I think she I hope she
will continue to provide that
perspective in her future endeavors and
as an individual participant and that we
will continue to carry that work forward
as we transition to the new iesg now
Kathleen we'd up since we you know had
to go with either ponies and unicorns we
got you a unicorn because you know
security area but it's actually a pretty
special unicorn because it's musical
when you squeeze it so yeah Alexa just
showed this to me so let's see
if if you can find a way to use this as
an as an individual participant going
forward like bring it up to the
microphone with you I mean there's all
kinds of things that could be done with
a musical unicorn let's be honest so
come on up
additionally we couldn't figure out what
what to put in your mugs so we didn't
get you a mug but we did get you the
required security hoodie
[Applause]
[Laughter]
so it falls to me to notify the
community when two members of the IAB
have escaped and it is this particular
year the escapees are Lee Howard and Joe
Hildebrand if I think these guys like
each other so if they would come up
together I'll embarrass them at the same
time first I want to call out Lee's
service to the IAB because he did
something that's really important is he
was a champion for a particular
evolution of the internet becoming the
default so we have seen Lee in almost
any context to challenge us to make sure
that whatever we were thinking about
whatever we were building not only
worked on ipv6 that it was ipv6 native
in every possible way and so as a
champion of ipv6 he's really helped the
the whole ieb
not just focus their attention on that
particular issue but make sure that that
context is the base part of how we think
about the network going forward and I
really want to thank him for that
service
and for each of them we've developed an
architecture tester so that they can go
out into the world and continue to serve
the Internet this particular one which
is a dev device triple zero to make sure
that the network gets connected to his
ipv6 capable has no Nats on it and
traverses with absolutely no
interference so please take it with you
and make sure that you use it well Jo's
service to the IAB started at the same
time as mine and I'm desperately sorry
to lose him as a colleague because he
helped me birth so many bad ideas and I
even helped him birth one or two the the
one thing I really want us to to focus
on from from Jo's service in addition to
his tremendous knowledge of both modern
development practices and how
middleboxes work and how the web works
is his insistence that we think about
explicitness in the network when we when
we think about how people derive signal
from the network we think a great deal
about how people watch the network as it
passes and although Brian and many
others of the of the community think
about measurement very deeply Joe was
really insistent that we think very hard
about what it would take to make
explicit signaling a core part of the
network architecture that work is still
going on but we think Joe can take it
forward in Mozilla and his other roles
and we've built for you this network
tester which looks very explicitly to
see if there's adequate TLS whether the
domain name system is working as it
ought to and whether the the rest of the
things that go into making the web
substrate work exactly as they're meant
to if you would like to play along at
home this is of course an open source
project it's
we'd like to thank the RER Co for
leading in its it is github repo so
github.com /er ER co / arch tester it's
fully open source you can add your own
tests and change it any way you like
thank you to both of you for your
service to the IEP thanks to both of you
[Applause]
it's great that the the ISO plaques are
themselves an open-source project
because we'll be adjusting this in the
back as we go
our next appreciation is for neville
Brownlee Neville would you come come up
please I don't see Neville sir
so let me let me tell you a brief story
before we appreciate him in his absence
and that is Neville actually served a
year longer than he asked to serve he
actually tried to retire last year and
Robert sparks and the rest of the IAB
basically through our collective arms
around his knees and said we're not
ready yet please
wait and he was kind enough to give us
an extra year of his time and attention
and this year he spent a great deal of
time with our incoming ISE Adrian
Ferrell to bring him up to speed and to
make sure that the RFC editor function
had no no blip because of any lack of
information being transmitted and so
although he has probably escaped for a
very well earned pint somewhere I'd like
you to join me in expressing your
we'll catch him sometime later in the
week for the obligatory picture with the
plaque Thanks so that brings us to the
technical plenary so Brian I'll leave it
to you and I'm gonna go sit down
hi good evening um I'm about to say
something that's gonna surprise some
people in the room the Internet is a
network of networks not as good as the
Beyonce joke I know I'm sorry so the
variety and diversity of networks that
people use to connect to the Internet is
increasing so part of this is due to
innovation access technologies part of
its due to the fact that there's just
they're just more Internet users in the
world and the diversity of sort of the
ways that they can connect the Internet
the physical infrastructure is is
expanding and we thought it would be
interesting to have a discussion about
the future of access networks given this
diversity so I'm going to escape very
quickly I'd like to call Jane coffin the
co-chair of the Gaia research group and
director development for the Internet
Society director Phil and strategy for
the intern Society to come up and
introduce our plenary speakers if you'd
also come up
good evening and thank you very much for
staying we have three fabulous speakers
I'm not gonna speak very long but what I
am gonna do is let you know who is up
here with me
we have Leandro Navarro who's a
professor at UPC in Barcelona but he
also works with we feed net which is a
community network in Spain we have Steve
song who if you haven't seen as many
possibilities dot in that website
take a look don't crash it right now but
he has great mapping and it was one of a
fabulous a host of humans that I work
with on community networks John brewer
knows a lot about community networks and
a lot about what's up in this guy with
satellites so if you give us one sec
we'll get started I just lost my phone
and got it back so I'm very excited so
how do these people all weave together
in this network of networks so one on
community networks I have the privilege
to work with people every day who are
building networks from the bottom up
ground up community up we call it for
the community with the community by the
community its partnering at the local
level to provide connectivity where
there isn't connectivity as many of you
know there's obviously this digital
divide around the world and we see the
gaps where people aren't going to
provide that connectivity whether it's
wireless wireline Wi-Fi or other these
networks
Leandra will tell you more about them
but they're sparking innovation at the
local level and we're stealthily using
major meetings like the IGF I know that
can be a point of contention for some
but we support the idea for many reasons
but we're using it to bring community
networks together so they can meet each
other know each other and do more work
at the technical level on the mapping of
infrastructure side and resources the
spectrum cocktail Steve will talk about
that and you'll see some of the stories
with respect to infrastructure gaps from
his Maps then wants move over to John to
talk about the future in the sky many of
you also know that with respect to
spectrum and satellites you need orbital
slots something very important we don't
do that here the ITU helps out with that
that's part of hanging the birds in the
sky so that's a network architecture
that meets spectrum clues with technical
innovation and the question is is that
really going to be the future of
connectivity so I think satellites are
almost as cool as submarine cables but
that would be up for you to decide each
of our speakers has 12 minutes then
we'll take Q&A so Leandro you're up
first
we couldn't have done any of this
without Cindy so thank you
I okay so I'm gonna start talking about
the local part of of connectivity so so
this is about community networks or in
other words this is about about everyone
but not everyone in the room but
everyone in the world and that is not
initially technical it's about rights
human rights so if you look at article
19 well before the internet appeared it
says that we have the right to seek
receive and and exchange information and
ideas through any media and now we are
talking about the Internet so you don't
know not everyone has access to the
Internet but even worse
not even everyone can provide it so this
is quite diverse if we look at this map
about the world's population you see
it's quite diverse in density if we
focus on the that the part we are like
London and and that column we see that
Europe is is well populated as it is
most part of Africa but when we move to
let's say the IPS base
Europe is there is a hot area even the
northern part which is not that
populated it's also well connected but
you don't see Africa there why well we
we you know and it has to do also with
any other type of infrastructure so when
you look at electricity or lighting you
see that Europe is right as well as
Africa is is not so we know there are
many obstacles but we are aiming or I
think many of us are aiming to what we
call it when people call it the
universal service so it is the right of
having functional internet connection
that is affordable for those means
different things for different locations
and Indiana's is to participate in
society
we know how to do it in urban areas in
rich areas it's very easy because people
is closer to each other so
infrastructure is easier to deploy and
how about rural areas
I mean places where people is spread out
and maybe they have less money to spend
so the solution to have sustainable
infrastructure sustainable surfaces it
is a combination of business models
diversity in business models and
technology diversity in technology so
just looking quickly about what is the
distribution of offline population that
there is a kind of market a big market
in in Africa by more than about billion
people if you look at the Asian Pacific
2000 so I think it deserves a lot of
attention also when you look at at the
gaps there is in addition to the
geography there is a gap of gender there
is a cup of income there is a cup of
non-being in urban areas there is a gap
of age there is a gap of education so
there are many gaps and and well I mean
it's a challenge really to deliver in
such a diverse environment again we know
how to do it for the world economy for
the rich countries it kind of works in
in some local markets definitely is very
difficult in in what they call it
subsistence economy where there's little
money little formal structures and
basically survival
so how do we offer how do we provide
affordability well there is one model we
know is we bring the connectivity to do
them and then while they pay if they can
or the other way is like we try to to
help develop those infrastructures
locally and
and bootstrap an economy in a way
so within farms fields and less
profitable places they found out
sometimes oh my go that that is possible
to do to do that
not at market prices but maybe at the
local provision and people learn and
many examples people learn how to do it
and they created their own
infrastructures so that's what we call
community networks
I mean networks which are with we call
it cloud source which are built by
citizens and by contribution and
interconnection sounds like the Internet
and then so we end up having a shared
networking infrastructure and that
infrastructure is built on anything
anything that works there is cheap
enough that it's interoperable enough
with the different other components so
you will see community networks are not
by far our genius anything is
interconnected and then governance is
quite open it's like you will see some
examples later or one example it's open
to anyone
it's cooperative sometimes because it is
no other way than doing it at cost
there's no margin for for-profit
initially at least who invests anyone
anyone small investments together make
produce results and and of course it's
happened to anyone
so openness in many senses is critical
for the development of these local
infrastructures this is how for instance
looks like one of these networks in a
semi rural area where where you see a
lot of connections a lot of homes
connected through Wi-Fi links this is
part of giving it which in a way is a
small Internet in in in this region of
the world many local networks many
groups they connect with each other and
then they share some internet connection
all these islands are not in many cases
are not interconnected among themselves
just belong to our to a community that
have common governance principles
so they they are not like like a
restaurant model I we call it like I
it's not that you have to go to a
licensed place to get connectivity of
course there is a operator model but
it's more like a homemade home-cooked
connectivity produced by by volunteers
that becomes sometimes operators small
operators by based mostly on five on
Wi-Fi nowadays also including fiber and
they learn how to organize and grow
themselves and they have created like an
optical backbone they share a number of
internet connections there are based
access Faline in traffic and inter
connection with the local exchange so
and this is only like in about 1213
years the governance of many of these
community networks are hundreds around
the world they are typically based on on
the idea of a common some of an
infrastructure Commons similar to
fisheries for community forests I mean
it's an old model formalized by Ellen
rostrum on oil price of economy and and
of course the objective of these
initiatives
it's about sustainability mainly which
is they call it avoiding the tragedy of
the Commons
and ensure that everyone has an
opportunity to expand the network and
use the network and everyone means not
only citizens but also professionals
small companies private public
organizations that benefit from that
infrastructure in that place so so you
know if we want to address a problem of
the deciphers needs of the unconnected
there must be multiple business models
probably adapted to different local
conditions we know the large operators
we know the wisps we know for instance
community networks and then they defer
in in in many aspects which is good so
you can we can find a optimal solution
and also we have to be careful because
technologies usually come already with
some business models think about GSM or
5g they
the operator model behind but also there
are more decentralized technologies like
Wi-Fi mesh Bitcoin all that stuff which
allow these kind of initiatives and and
of course all these all these models are
supported by the idea of infrastructure
sharing which makes things more
complicated but less costly and open
access networks are useful internet
exchanges are useful even some community
leaders become become that in along the
growth so related to our IETF community
committee Legos are places for
experimentation basically so you find
anything I mean giving it has a lot of
autonomous systems that use BGP the user
SPF any kind of routing protocol you can
imagine someone try it they they it's an
epi Network so anything anything works
there are a lot of like expansions
towards like creating a regional
internet exchange about experimenting
with network virtualization anything and
also in the economic model because it's
based not on our centralized Authority
but on on a compensation system we call
it that we compensate consumption and
contribution incentives and now they are
exploring for years the idea of Luxur in
crypto coins as a way to decentralize
that so my final point is that yeah
there is a need for an open Internet
without an open Internet this network
will not be possible without the idea of
cell provision it wouldn't be possible
we have to make sure that this is legal
allowed fec accessible to everyone
cooperation is the basis to construct
these infrastructures then a single one
can build a lot of lessons learned from
community networks not just in bringing
connectivity but also bring in
development bringing business models
bringing income bringing jobs bringing
local resilience to the digital
infrastructure of many communities we
need standards we need interoperability
we need commodity components we need
ways to incrementally upgrade the
networks we need to decentralize all the
aspects and my point is that I think
that connectivity for the next 50
percent of the global population will
come bottom-up and and that's a hot
topic of the Gaia working group so you
are welcome to come tomorrow to discuss
the details okay thank you
[Applause]
good evening my name is Steve song I
work with the network startup Resource
Center on on increasing access to
wireless spectrum I'm also a senior
fellow with the Mozilla Foundation
working on digital access and inclusion
I'd like to apologize in advance where
the title of my slide opening I don't
really know how to connect everyone but
I do have some ideas about how how we
could improve things um the guy you see
on the right hand side in that slide his
name's Peter Blume
he runs a nonprofit organization in
Oaxaca in Mexico and they build a
low-cost GSM base stations in remote
areas where the larger operators don't
go and and Peter was at the Mobile World
Congress a couple of weeks ago and the
Mobile World Congress suit in case you
don't know it's the kind of global
shindig for mobile network operators and
he came back from it and he said to me
he said Steve you know I get the feeling
that people care more about connecting
refrigerators to the internet than they
do about connecting the poor and I and I
think this is actually true I mean if
you look for a conference on the
Internet of Things I mean you probably
go around the corner I mean you go to
one every week for the for the rest of
the year or not run out
whereas trying to find people to talk
about connecting that those who can't
afford the internet or or where the
internet doesn't exist that's a lot
thinner on the ground and and that
matters and and the reason it matters is
because of this I mean they I mean the
Internet is a mutant superpower I mean a
is there anyone who doesn't feel like
the Internet is a mutant superpower I
mean it hasn't been like just profoundly
changed by the way the internet sort of
enables you to to learn to manifest
things in the world to connect with
people it's incredible and as we were
discussing at lunch today it's not
always a good mutant
power but it is indeed a superpower you
would not want to be without and the
problem then is that for those without
access they're moving backwards only by
standing still as the Internet becomes a
more and more valuable resource and so
by not focusing on connecting the
unconnected we're creating an
increasingly large digital divide and
this this is not okay at least it's not
okay for me and so most of my work is in
sub-saharan Africa so I want to talk a
little bit about about the sort of
technological development of access and
I'm I'll start here this was 2005 and
the economists had worked out that
mobile phones were actually going to be
the big thing in terms of access and
indeed you know even in 2005 we had no
idea just how important mobile phones
were going to be in terms of connecting
the those without access and that was
before before you could actually get the
the internet on mobile phones and there
was a general perception and I think it
persists now they basically the problem
solved right mobile phones are just
going to sort of eventually connect
everyone but the reality isn't actually
like that subscriber penetration is now
tapering off and the business models for
the large operators simply don't make it
into sparsely populated rural areas we
we actually need something different and
before I talk about that I want to talk
about one other technology that doesn't
get talked about as much as as as mobile
networks or mobile telephones but I
think it's a technology that is having
as big an impact in sub-saharan Africa
as mobile phones themselves and that's
fiber-optic networks so ten years ago
there was effectively no fiber-optic
undersea cables reaching sub-saharan
Africa well technically there was one
but it was controlled by a cartel and it
was more expensive than satellite so
we'll just say no but and and fast
forward to to 2018 and there were over a
dozen high capacity under seek
Abel's reaching sub-saharan african
countries with six more planned in the
next couple of years and for me this is
staggering I would never projected this
level of investment and of course that
investment sparked a tsunami of
investment into terrestrial fiber
infrastructure now to the extent that
primary and secondary cities across the
continent have access to fiber optic
infrastructure which is amazing because
once you're on fiber you are on a
milliseconds from the living beating
heart of the internet but the challenge
then becomes how do we actually get from
those fiber points of presence out to
reach everyone and that that answer lies
in wireless spectrum and of course we've
all seen headlines like this you know
the spectrum crunch cometh the access to
spectrum has become a real issue it's
part it partly a real issue simply
because of the pace of technological
change the regulations simply isn't
keeping up with technological change and
I'll give an example of this this was a
decision taken in 2006 among African
countries to make a transition from
analogue terrestrial broadcasting to
digital terrestrial broadcasting and it
was projected it would take about 10 or
11 years which is pretty speedy by
regulatory standards for the reef arming
of spectrum and mostly it hasn't quite
kept up with that it's it's it's not
done yet but what is interesting is what
2006 did not know about the future it
didn't know about the smartphone which
was going to be introduced in the next
year actually it did know about Netflix
but the prime means of delivery of
Netflix in 2006 was the US Postal
Service and it didn't know about tablets
and the confluence of those things
streaming media on tablets so while this
decision was chugging along
technologists just blew right past it in
terms of the the delivery of media and
this is going to happen more and more we
need regulations that can cope with the
pace of technological change and we need
access to spectrum and so as demand has
exceeded the administrative available
available 'ti of spectrum
we needed a model for making spectrum
available and the dominant model is now
the spectrum auction which the
economists tell us is the fairest way of
making spectrum available because those
who value it are willing to pay the most
for it but it becomes problematic
especially in poor countries now these
are some spectrum auctions in the last
four or five years across a number of
African countries and what you can see
there is the price pay paid for it for
spectrum is you know between twenty-five
and a hundred million dollars but that's
the successful bidders for that spectrum
we're a maximum of one and that's
typically the largest mobile network
operator or the incumbent who got access
to that spectrum or in fact sometimes
it's none because the actual price floor
in the spectrum is so high and what
happens when the price floor is that
high you don't get the competition that
you wanted from from the auction in
terms of multiple winners but also
recent research suggests that very high
fees paid at auction for spectrum leads
to lower quality networks to reduce
build-out and worst of all to higher
prices for consumers but this is the
future we are promised this is a right
now in the UK there's an auction going
on for for 5g spectrum and that mobile
networks will will will solve all these
problems by rolling out everywhere but
in fact this is not going to lead to
increased rollout into poor sparsely
populated rural areas because this model
doesn't incentivize anyone to do that
and then there's another piece of
spectrum a tiny unloved corner of the
spectrum band the is M bands and Wi-Fi
which I mean I think we all know and
love but the meteoric rise of Wi-Fi
technology in terms of its pervasiveness
and embeddedness and everything is
absolutely phenomenal and doesn't get
sufficient record recognition by
regulators in terms of its impact and
it's not just Wi-Fi in you know Heathrow
Airport in this hotel across the
African continent there has been in the
last two to three years
a spectacular rollout of Wi-Fi enabled
networks and those models are some are
community led models some are government
led models some are commercial models
but it happens because the technology is
cheap and powerful and because you don't
require a license the barrier to
actually rolling out rolling it out is
very very low so you have you know and
and the way I the way I sort of think
about it is you know if you've seen the
movie Aladdin you know in there and the
genie describing himself you know
phenomenal powers maybe living space you
know and that's sort of that's that tiny
amount of spectrum that is available for
for a Wi-Fi it is quite small compared
to the rest of the available spectrum
one of the things we could do is simply
expand that those is M bands a little
especially in five gigahertz just by
expanding those iesson bands we can
increase the amount of innovation that
goes on by community networks like kief
e net but it doesn't stop there because
there's a host of new companies out
there building incredibly inexpensive
power technology inexpensive low-power
and low cost technologies and those
might be in dynamic spectrum like TV
white space technologies they might be
in a new generation of LTE base stations
but you know what's the point of having
a $3,000 LT base station if you pay
twenty five million dollars for your
spectrum right it's ROS the entire sort
of you know affordable access visit a
business model off so we need new models
I mean our current regulatory frameworks
for for respect around a bit like a 19th
century hotel you know where barons
Sternberg has his room reserved whether
he's traveling or not you know and many
of the rooms are empty and it's just not
an efficient way of making things happen
and one thing we know about software is
is very good at resource management so a
more Airbnb style approach to the
allocation of spectra
might serve us better and not just for
spectrum that's that's been unassigned
but even spectrum that's been been
assigned to operators where they aren't
using it perhaps they can get a rebate
on their Universal service obligations
by allowing other people to use that
spectrum so the way I think of it and
I'm trying out a new metaphor so bear
with me it's like a jar filled with
these large rocks you know and and
that's their current regulatory regime
is just we have a job we have we have
large rocks and we have the jar but it
doesn't that jar looks fill full but
it's not it's it's actually less than
50% of the volume of the jar and what we
need are smaller we need regulation for
smaller operators whether they're a
community nonprofit for-profit or
municipal to be able to fill in those
gaps whether their regional geographic
gaps or niche sectoral gaps we we need a
new framework that has you know as this
jar has smaller rocks and but the last
point I want to make here is that as we
do that it turns out that not only to be
needs regulation for smaller operators
we really need more diversity in the
access networks themselves because when
you get identical business models and
identical investment frameworks as we
see across you know mobile network
operators it's very hard for there to be
real competition what you ultimately get
is a kind of race to the bottom in
technology or in terms of service but
when we have a diversity of access
technologies whether it's unlicensed
spectrum dynamic spectrum light
licensing and licensed approach and
other technologies like fiber optic and
then it's very difficult for the
competition to become like for like and
you get more innovation and service
provision and that leads me actually to
our next speaker talking about a really
exciting area of access diversity the
emerging changes in the satellite market
so with that I thank you very much for
your time
[Applause]
all right thanks Steve John brewer as
you can hear from my accent I'm from New
Zealand my my talk is premise that the
future is up in the sky we're going to
be talking about satellite and to talk
about the future we need to understand a
bit of language so first we're going to
start to talk about why we need
satellite then I'm going to introduce
you to the three main orbits and there
Layton sees of the satellite networks
we're going to talk a lot about radio
spectrum we're going to talk briefly
about satellite architectures and I'm
going to take you through three new
commercial ventures so first off why we
need satellite this is pretty easy it's
a chart of the cost and relative cost
and complexity of various technologies
servicing broadband access with
population density along the x-axis once
you get to ten or fewer people per
square kilometer satellite is less
costly and less complex than any other
access method I've adapted this chart
from a communications research Canada
chart they submitted the 802 22 working
group about 15 years ago it's an amazing
chart though and it holds true today so
we're gonna get into the orbits and
latency here I've got a scale drawing
here of the earth with the three main
orbits will talk about low Earth orbit
léo medium Earth orbit neo and geo
geosynchronous orbit we've got Leo down
there at about a thousand kilometers
above the earth give or take a few
hundred
we've got mio at ten thousand k's give
or take a few thousand and we've got geo
sitting at about thirty six thousand
kilometers above our heads
I've got Layton sees down there and
these latencies are actually for one-way
trips put together because when you're
sitting at a computer on a satellite
terminal sending a request up to the
satellite it's going down to an earth
station it's going out to the internet
fetching your data coming back to the
earth station going up to the satellite
down to your terminal so these are the
latencies before you hit the internet
best case in leo is going to be about 12
milliseconds that's imperceptible mio
120 milliseconds still pretty much
imperceptible
and geo at 480 milliseconds yeah that's
gonna be perceptible and so I've got
this little curved this funny bunch of
dots there in the middle and that's
actually a about 40 million samples from
of human reaction time where people have
sat in front of a computer and they've
looked at an image flash up and they've
clicked on it basically this shows that
about half of all people are going to
perceive something as being slow if it's
slower than 270 milliseconds so very
very very few people are gonna notice a
latency of 120 milliseconds everybody is
gonna notice a latency of 480
milliseconds that's before you get your
webpage so the perception of satellite
to date has been oh god it's slow and
yeah that's gonna keep going for a bit
with some technologies now introduce you
to the spectrum here three terms I want
you to know in spectrum our seam and K
you bend and ka-band I've got a little
note down at the bottom about L band and
V band which are also satellite
technologies but they're not really used
for broadband access Steve was talking
about the small amount of Wi-Fi spectrum
yeah I've got that in blue down there at
the bottom and then I've also got the 2g
3G 4G bands in orange still a very tiny
amount of radio spectrum C band is is
the smallest of the broadband satellite
bands and it's got a couple of holes in
it because of Wi-Fi but there's still a
bit of spectrum there see van kayuu band
starts at about 12 gigahertz goes up to
about 18 gigahertz and there's a bit of
interference from microwave linking and
other technologies there but at least in
New Zealand we're starting to shift
shift some some microwave services out
of that band and freeing it up for
satellite that ka man starts at about 26
gigahertz and goes up to 40 and there's
not a lot going on there a little bit of
microwave linking a little bit of lmds
which never went anywhere so it's pretty
clean pretty empty huge amounts of
spectrum and ka quite a bit NKU
not very much in Seeman a quick primer
on satellite spectrum we've got four
things that we think about for spectrum
we think about availability reuse
antenna sizes and rain fade and see man
very little spectrum ka-band quite a lot
reuse which we'll talk about in the next
slide we've got very low Reeves in seam
and very high recent ka band antenna
size pretty obvious huge antennas for
seam and tiny antennas for ka band and
then rain fade very little rain fade and
see quite a bit in ka band I'll quantify
that in a few slides first off we've got
reusability so reusability is a function
of the frequency the size of the waves
little waves spread less and also the
distance away from earth so your
low-earth orbit satellites are gonna
have better reusability of spectrum than
your geo satellites just because the
spot beam has less time to spread with
seidman spectrum imagining we're at a
geostationary satellite orbit now 36,000
Kay's up you may get a C band channel
covering about half of Australia I made
this slide for the AHS nog meeting so
it's Australia Kay you Bend you're gonna
get about four spots of the same of the
same channel you're gonna get to reuse
the same channel about four times in the
same area as you would a single seam and
channel and km n is 16 to 20 times so
you get an amazing amount of reuse from
K you bet from ka band now about those
antenna things well an antenna basically
focuses energy focuses radio energy it
doesn't make more energy but to focus
right a 1 watt of radio energy in C band
you'd need a 1.2 meter dish in K you
bench to focus the same amount of energy
you'd only need six hundred mil dish and
in ka vent 300 mil dish we're talking a4
sheet of paper compared to 1.2 meter
giant thing that acts as a sail in the
wind
so really ka been huge amounts of
spectrum very small antennas huge
amounts of reusability it's like a
panacea until you get to the rain
and I could really just leave this slide
up here and you just believed me but I
made a chart that you can download and
look at offline because it's a bit dense
but here in the right hand side y-axis
we've got drizzle light rain medium rain
heavy rain tropical downpours and on the
left hand y-axis we've got attenuation
in decibels per kilometer when you're
going from a satellite terminal on the
ground to a satellite and you're going
straight up you're going through a
couple of K's of rain if you're going in
an angle you may be going through a
couple of more K's of rain having
attenuation of a few decibels per
kilometer you quickly lose your link
budget and you run it a signal in a
medium rainstorm see men doesn't notice
K you man doesn't notice ka Ben starts
to go away in a heavy rain see Ben
doesn't notice K you men starts to
flicker you might get a bit packet loss
ka man just goes away it really just
goes away and in tropical downpours
which you know happen every afternoon
for a couple of minutes in most tropical
places your cave and services just gone
even with a several meter dish so I've
got a straw man here for temperate
climate saying say I've got a 1.2 meter
addition on my roof I like 1.2 meter
dishes they're nice and big
so we might out of a KA service get 512
megabits per second off of one of these
new satellite services but only
ninety-nine point seven percent
reliability there's a satellite company
in the Pacific actually selling
ninety-nine point seven percent
reliability and talking it up is a big
deal and really the people buying it
don't have any idea that that means
they're gonna drop out like every single
day and they're just gonna hate it
because they're gonna lose a few seconds
here and there all the time
kayuu man same size dish 64 Meg's 99.9
percent reliability your seed man
service you may get four and a half or
even five nines but you only get 16
megabits per second because you've got
less spectrum to work with anyway a
couple of architectures to think about
because this is sort of a place where
people think about
architecture and this is going to matter
we've got our basic old-school v set up
and down and some people take two V sets
that's a very good idea especially if
they're pointed in different directions
you go through different weather and
different directions you may start to
have multimodal configurations where
you've got a geostationary primary
service and a low earth or medium earth
backup service or the other way around
you may have a multimodal service which
does exist where you have a primary
fiber connection and a backup satellite
or the other way around a couple of
providers in American Samoa actually use
a satellite as their primary and fiber
as their backup because the fiber
capacity from American Samoa ye has been
full for years a couple of advanced
architectures here we're starting to get
networks where the you're doing
satellite cross links so your signal
goes up to one satellite goes over to
another goes down to an earth station
that's well beyond the horizon and cloud
avoidance for your ka service where you
may have very high rain fade there are
places like Rarotonga where they've
installed two terminals on opposite
sides of the island connected by fiber
measuring the signal levels from the
satellite at all times handing off
automatically between the dishes to pick
up the one that has the better signal to
avoid the rain because rain storms do
just move in small cells across the
cities when I operated a microwave
network in Auckland I could watch my 23
gig links fade and I could tell you
exactly where the storm was going across
the city because Nagios would pop up
alert alert alert alert and they go back
and yeah that's how that's how rain fade
works so considering the architecture
you're gonna have companies starting to
offer blended satellite services where
they're gonna give you connectivity over
multiple modes of satellite you're gonna
have different capacities on these
connections you're gonna have different
levels of availability you're gonna have
different Layton sees you may actually
have rapid latency changes with some of
your services how do you make this work
heck there were a couple of research
groups I sat in on yesterday where
they're thinking about these problems
and and may come up with the solution so
lots to think about here now three
representative commercial ventures here
number one we've got NBN Co that's
Australia's national broadband network
company and the one thing that they've
done right is they bought a couple of
satellites a few years ago everything
else that done wrong but a couple of
years ago the Australian is in the crowd
know what I'm talking about a couple of
years ago they they launched two Space
Systems Loral satellites sixty seven and
a half gigabits per second look at the
engineers in this picture and look at
the size of those dishes up there this
is unfolded and the dishes are beaming
down anyway each of these satellites
sixty seven and a half gigabits per
second twenty-five Meg down five Meg up
to end-users balanced across ten earth
stations it is ka-band so the people
that live in the far tropical North
Queensland
Darwin they hate it because it rain
fades it's just awful for them but
everywhere else in the the dry bits of
Australia they love it because it's it's
really fast its kind of laggy they know
it's satellite but it's much better than
what it was expected lifespan until 2030
and NBN Co does expect to increase the
speed to end-users to 50 Meg's down in
the pretty near future now you've got
another one look at this satellite here
and look at the people next to it for a
compare those drawings yeah okay this
one is a mio satellite and it's operated
by o3 be the first real mio broadband
network ever launched in 2014
they're a carrier I want to say
wholesale only but they sell the oil
rigs and cruise ships too but they only
sell one product which is big fast fat
access pipes and you basically need to
be buying a minimum of 600 megabit per
second for them to care about you they
will take one of those satellites and
they'll beam it down to you these
satellites was around the earth if you
take an O 3 B service you actually need
to have two antennas one of the antennas
is in service and tracking a satellite
as it whizzes across the sky while the
other is hunting for the next one to
come over the horizon they do the
and over with bgp which is just bizarre
because it's a bit slow but it does seem
to work anyway they've got 144 gigabits
per second at capacity online they've
been so popular they've ordered another
96 gigs of capacity there is KA mint and
there is rain fade even with people with
4 meter dishes hence the whole multiple
terminals and fibre between them and
cloud avoidance don't try and run this
on a tropical area with two point four
meter satellites you can ask Solomon
Telecom about that if you want okay last
one one web this doesn't exist yet and
really we don't have any low Earth orbit
Network broadband networks yet but gosh
we were about to have three of them and
there are a few other people who've put
into the FCC for permission to launch
these networks one web has gained a
bunch of investment from companies like
Virgin companies like soft Bank soft
might put a billion dollars in last year
met somebody from Softbank last week and
they said yeah it was a small investment
so anyway they're looking at putting up
these little satellites into low-earth
orbit
700 plus of them and each one is gonna
have about six gigabits per second of
capacity so they're building a 4.2
terabit per second network to service
rural and remote people nice Intelsat
plans to offer blended offerings
combining this low earth and their
existing geostationary assets
imperceptible latency yeah consumer
focused and it's K u-men so it is not
going to have the fade problems of
ka-band in fact you should expect to run
this off of an antenna that is maybe six
hundred mils a company called Chi Mehta
has made an antenna especially for one
web that is built into the roof of a car
so neat stuff going on that is it I only
had 12 minutes this is a 45-minute talk
there's a couple of versions online
there's one I did at a panic in Taichung
last year one I did in New Zealand last
year fortunately the oz nog talk was not
recorded because I swore a lot in it
anyway there's a Q&A at the end of this
and of course you can come up and pepper
us all with questions thanks thanks for
your time guys okay so now we are going
to take questions question and answer
for about 15 to 20 minutes
QA anybody yes oh no okay go easy on us
yeah Bogdanovich three very interesting
presentations I'm really was interested
to hear about the satellite and the
speeds up because I started my career
Mongols in the satellite communication
and having a 1.5 megabit connection was
a big deal back in the early 90s and
that was a three meter antenna in order
to get that and the per minute was
insane but the cost per minute was
insane but what I'm really interested
was the spectrum sharing spectrum is one
of the most expensive and most
underutilized resources that are out
there and many of them are lying dormant
and I was really when you were
mentioning your mentioned many about the
software-defined radio but they didn't
mention much about spectrum sharing and
were you have some mechanisms in order
that you can get the dynamically
allocated spectrum and what is
developing there you mentioned a little
bit t vision but they are just you know
TV white space sorry TV white space yes
but I would be really curious to hear
more because I know FCC was looking into
that in order to make it the more
popular but they haven't followed up
lately okay thank you so Steve shared
spectrum yeah I actually when when I
mentioned software I didn't mean
software-defined radio although that is
also very exciting I mean software
managed
and of of spectrum so the the two
interesting areas one is TV white space
spectrum which has particular
application in sub-saharan Africa
because all of that spectrum is
virtually unoccupied so there's hundreds
of megahertz of spectrum that could be
used and the other interesting space is
the CB RS band in in the US that is
being promoted by Google and both are
basically the same idea is using a
geolocation database to dynamically
assign spectrum based on an availability
map that's calculated on on the terrain
and unavailable frequencies there's
absolutely no reason why we shouldn't be
using these technologies I mean the you
know auctions are incredibly risky
strategies for for regulators as as I
pointed out in in my talk they're not
turning out well especially in markets
where where there are limited resources
but they're too attractive in terms of a
kind of financial windfall to get away
from but if you were if you were
thinking about spectrum regulation from
our risk management point of view that'd
be a really dumb investment you'd like
put all your eggs in one basket and
dynamic spectrum regulation is actually
fantastic because it's it's a secondary
use of the spectrum so you're not
committing yourself to to the spectrum
use you're just allowing it to win if it
if it wins so the rest of the regulator
is very very low and and and it's a bit
like Wi-Fi you know is it that that the
opportunity to to succeed is there the
problem is that it gets a lot of
pushback because it is a potential
game-changer if if it takes off and so
the mobile network operators actively
discourage its use the ITU for reasons
which I can only imagine is industry
influenced actively discourage its use
so this this technology which has been
available for four years now is lies
unused
and their manufacturers waiting for a
regulatory signal to you to ramp up I
think the u.s. FCC was really trying to
push it through and I don't know with
like in 2014-15 they were trying to push
but was it because this is also a
political issue thank you for those who
and actually I think we need to skip
over to the next speaker over here and
thank you Steve for that so to my left
or to my right your left thank you very
much my name is Abdul Karim I'm from
Nigeria
and I'm glad that we are having this
type of discussion in this room because
when I look around I look at people that
look like me I don't find a lot of us
like nice and a lot of the issues that
we discussed this evening actually
effects people from where I come from
Africa so I'm glad that we are having
this type of discussion and I when I'm
glad expecially with Steve with what he
has done and what what you guys are
doing and looking at the examples of
satellite communication my problem is
satellites generally is expensive so I'm
thinking is satellite really one of the
solution we can look at my question is
have you looked at something like IOT 2
platforms as an alternative to satellite
thank you John
I think you said IOT correct ha I ought
to do platforms which is high out of
HAP's sorry high-altitude platforms go
for it in the longer version of my talk
I discuss a few high-altitude platforms
but so far there has not been a lot of
success I have watched the Loon project
which started in New Zealand a few years
back quite closely and they really
haven't achieved the speeds to end-users
or the economics required to make it a
viable platform Facebook's Aquila was
was great for a while until it landed
and Google had another high-altitude
venture that they purchased and it also
looks great and they shut it
last January and moved the engineers
somewhere else so I haven't seen a lot
of success with high altitude platforms
I really think the satellite is probably
more realistic at this point and I think
for many in the room would know this but
98 to 2002 there was already another
there was a space race then ya Teledesic
others who were during the house
Teledesic wasn't doing haps about other
platforms like that so it's just the
second generation of us of a race in the
middle hi my name is Aaron Falk I
currently work for Akamai I was part of
that first space race I worked on space
way Astro link tea set which was a Air
Force program
I followed Teledesic closely and most of
those systems were never put into
service
and the decision was ultimately around a
business model and that the problem was
for these kayvyun systems especially
with onboard processing that they're
very expensive and they're very
expensive to launch and and when you
have enough users in one place that you
can make money off of a satellite link
somebody will dig a trench and drag a
fiber over to it or now they'll put in a
base station right but that was the
problem then
so clearly launch costs are dropping but
I'm wondering you know art do you
believe that the economics of satellite
communications have changed
substantially enough to support 700
satellite léo system I think they have
changed significantly because not only
the competition in launch with SpaceX
and Blue Origin coming up and virgin
attempting to replicate what orbital ATK
have done with the airborne launch
coming down the pipeline but the cost of
manufacturing satellites has just gone
way down and the speed at which you can
manufacture a satellite has gone way
down to the point where one Weber
building two satellites a day you think
about how long it took
Space Systems Loral to build the geo
satellites for NBN Co like years and
here we are with Leo platform's building
to add a there was a bit of a scandal a
few weeks ago somebody launched some
micro set some Seattle startup launched
some micro sets out of India and I mean
these things are working much to the
dismay of the FCC and everybody else in
the world they built something in there
a workshop they launched it into space
illegally and they're actually
transmitting radio signals from it so
yes the costs have gone down of
everything so I think we're we're not
going to have quite the collision I
don't believe that all five of the LIA
ventures are gonna make it but I'd say
three of the five easy like and I think
I'm getting signals from the floor are
yep over here hi I'm Mark Nottingham
John you mentioned very briefly a
satellite to sell about communication
and building a mesh up in space was
wondering if you talk about the
technology used for that and and tell us
a little bit more and also giving us a
sense of you know where are we gonna be
at do you think in three five years how
many satellites you know how pervasive
is excess by satellite one to be with
these newly Oh networks okay so really
what mark wants me to do is start
talking about space lasers yes we said
we weren't gonna do that but because at
all honestly we are gonna see some
optical cross-linking of these
satellites and there's actually a mio
platform that's well into being funded
that is going to do optical earth to
space links to there's gonna be a lot of
laser cross-linking but funny enough
since my talk at oz nog last year
there's been a huge race in the band
cross-linking and a couple of new V band
constellations planned basically just to
do cross-linking because V band is
useless for going earth to space unless
you're in a desert but out there in the
sky there's nothing to attenuate your
your V van which is basically millimeter
wave microwaves so they're going to
build these V band overlays in terms of
number of satellites we've got
fifteen or sixteen hundred operational
communication satellites now and I'd say
within five years we'll be up an order
of magnitude it really will go that fast
like people have booked their SpaceX
launches iridium just put iridium next
up I think they've launched sixty
satellites in the past year so that's
kind of the volume we're looking at like
ten to twenty satellites per launch and
a huge increase in launch and it's all
comm satellites so we're gonna have a
lot a lot a lot in space lasers from
lasers to across the room and my name is
signature Eliza Molina young tech fellow
from the IDF I would like to ask about
the community networks because perhaps
was very very short at the time that
that give to you
but what about the certain certain
proposal like Barcelona Libre one Oh
seriously it was a group of like hackers
of wifey that try to to provide this
kind of access but but what about the
names on this kind of I mean if you know
how many are or more data about data so
one thing I would say is that there is a
forum called battle mesh where they do a
lot of hacking of mesh standards and if
you want more data I can give it to you
later about that people do get together
to hack some of the technology but I
would ask Leandro there's a initiative
among some of the community networks
right now with something called libre
mesh libre router could you tell the
group about that yeah if you know the
difference or the defining factor about
community networks is not that they just
not focus on and getting the
connectivity but in finding
other ways to do it and in develop
software and spray options so so yeah
there are many initiatives particularly
there is one that is developing a new
meta distribution for for community
networks
it's called libera mesh and that builds
on a lot of contributions from many
communities all over the world but I
mean yeah yeah so many groups so many
forums and as I said the good thing is
that the on the way they are
experimenting with the technology they
are creating new technology new ways and
sharing information in many forums and
and that's like very promising because I
mean many of the for instance many of
the mesh routing protocols there are
nowadays came up with from
experimentation and and yeah the bottom
edge is one of them but there are there
are many other groups around so if you
are interested we can give you some
pointers thank you
there's also a group called the
Association for progressive
communication Steve works closely with
them and we just held two community
workshops in Geneva two days ago we were
there for another meeting but we are
potentially in the gaia group gonna try
and put together either an informational
and Greg would always keeps me straight
on this it's either an informational or
an RFC that we can put together a doc
it's not an RFC but an informational
document about community networks which
could include some of the data that APC
is putting together they're doing an
analysis of about 60 different community
networks around the world so stay tuned
pardon so we're gonna cut the lines
brought we did cut the lines Brian's
helping me here so forgive me if I I
don't have it all down I'm gonna go to
the set oh hey Paul Wilson pull from
pull from ap Nick yep okay another
question for John on the satellite
tracked but hopefully it's women also
relevant to Steve I'm kind of fascinated
by these flat panel antennas on the
ground side and wondering if you know by
avoiding all the hardware and the track
and all that stuff whether there's a
with there a game-changer in terms of
the cost of delivering receiving and
having a satellite station on the ground
on account of the different the
different hardware just wondering if
that's a game-changer that might sort of
have some impact on the issues that
Steve has Rosen Thanks I have a feeling
the flat panel antennas are going to be
quite expensive to start a lot more
expensive than just a stamped aluminium
dish I will take this opportunity to
thank Paul and ap Nick because it was a
panic and the issah program who got me
researching networks in the Pacific
which is what introduced me to all the
carriers using these new k-band
technologies like oh three B and really
gave me a great perspective on their
problems with weather and their problems
with capacity and how these things are
going to be solved Thanks thanks Paul
all right well thank you very much we
know there are more questions that guys
are here for the rest of the weekend if
you want to tune into Gaia tomorrow it's
at 13:30
can check it on the app on the schedule
but just let's give them a round of
applause for the excellent
thank you
we're at first
so we're gonna invite the IAB up onto
the stage oh I'm sorry go ahead
the IV tears the new night the IV I'd
like to remind you that you you you
outgoing members of the IV have not
escaped yet we'd like all of the IB
incoming ongoing and outgoing up on up
on stage at the moment
one member of the IB who unfortunately
is not able to join us tonight is Robert
sparks he's recovering from a series of
surgeries and we wish him the best and a
speedy recovery but unfortunately is not
able to be with us either in the room or
online tonight so as you can tell the IV
is very concerned about queuing theory
and not so good it's been spread
spectrum technologies eventually Gabriel
would you start by introducing yourself
go dear Montenegro a be well into Shore
IAB hello Joe Hildebrand out coin my
abhi Susanne wolf cheerful and outgoing
well actually staying i abhi Yadier kab
Heather Flanagan not IV at all but RC
series editor Eric Nord mark Iovine Lee
Howard outgoing I IV Ted Hardy Elissa
Cooper Brian Trammell IB no just until I
be Christian Emma because you need more
guys with a funny accent on IAB
will surely mark Nottingham Miami Mon
Thompson white guy elephant merican IRT
F chair so the mic lines are open for
your questions to the IAB either in
person or from our online guests it it's
Pete Resnick um and one that I am hoping
what you say is oh that's the IAS jeez
problem ask them later be prepared so a
few months back I sent the IAS G a
message asking about the state of the
RFC series who gets to be an author who
gets to be a contributor who gets to be
on the front page who gets to be where
when how and they said yeah we'll think
about that someday um since the RFC
editor is under your purview is this a
question for you guys or because it's
their stream it's a question for them
guys so the rules for that are made up
on a per stream basis so if you are
thinking about a standards track RFC it
is indeed a question for them guys
however I'm also going to turn to
Heather because she has guidance in the
RFC style handbook style guide excuse me
on this point which many stream managers
take quite seriously many of them do
some of them really wish they didn't
have to and would love it for to be my
problem but this is a a stream by stream
decision our guidance continues to be
we'd rather see no more than five
authors or in this case we're using the
term authors fairly broadly that can
also be editors there's a lot of
logistical reasons for that I'm not
going to get into right now unless you
really want me to we will start to
question once you hit seven and we've
mostly beaten the isg into submission
such that we'd often they'll often tell
us in advance yes we know we're sorry
but
let me um short-circuit a little bit
because the question is can contributors
who are not on the author 48 who are not
necessarily on the front page appear in
the RFC editors index so that they can
get credit in ways that this community
sometimes asks for credit for their
publication because right now people in
contributors do not and they are
required to both be on the front page
and be an author forty-eight if they
want that and if the IAS G insists that
for their stream they want credit for
people in the contributors even if they
don't appear in all 48 and even if they
don't appear on the front page will you
fulfill that the last time that came up
with the IAC this is something I talked
to them about annually because we have
no memory they were unable to reach
consensus on that that didn't quite
answer the question I thought that it
means your question really does belong
with the iesg if you wish to Ted can I
add one little thing so some of the
tooling that that we have that that
leasts authors dust they contributors
into account and and some don't so so
there's always that
so everybody is clustering at one mic so
clearly the interested people in the IAB
were leftists for at least from the
point of view of the IE maybe from other
perspectives as well just a comment here
not a not a question really since since
Martin kind of teed it up so plus one
good plenary topic I think it was
interesting relevance to this crowd
but maybe - one on diversity I mean this
the topic we were talking about today is
an important one but hearing it from
three white guys is maybe not the best
way to address it as our Nigerian
colleague pointed out as our Nigerian
colleague pointed out there's some
different considerations when seen from
different perspectives around the globe
and so it would have been nice to have
seen some more diverse perspectives on a
panel on this topic
thank you very much we have a plenary
planning program committee and all of
the not-quite all of the members are up
here but I believe they're all in the
room and we'll take that advice quite
seriously thank you thanks my name is
Andrew Sullivan at the diva saw meeting
on Monday there was a an interesting
talk by somebody about ways that maybe
that protocol had gotten away from us
and you know it occurred to me listening
to it that that this is another one of
those protocols we're always talking
about ossification and at the same time
it seems to be growing mostly bone spurs
and I I wonder I wonder whether there is
a thing that the IAB wants to say about
that or whether there are things that
you think you know need to be done about
any of these protocols that are at what
in the same time critical kind of in the
middle of the the hourglass and at the
same time growing hairs and bone spurs
and other kinds of things that might
turn into bone eventually or stone or
something else because I'm just I'm just
nervous about about this this being this
pattern being repeated and and then
working groups you know still having to
work on on the on the protocols and
develop them in ways that are you know
responsive to the to the pressures of
the internet as one of the perpetrators
of the DNA sought meeting in question I
can say that the the challenge there and
I think that was the outcome of the
discussion which would be worth
reviewing but I think what came out of
that discussion in the room was not
that this is a a novel thought and I
think the challenge there I would love
to be able to come up with something new
to say about this about the
architectural implications of Aging
protocols with many teeth and many bone
spurs and trying to but trying to come
up with something to say about it
besides yep it's self-evidently true and
we don't know what to do about it I I
would welcome that and and now that
you've pointed this out I can go home
and think about it some more but so can
I so can anybody else including I'm the
IAB because I think you're right I think
that we have got to come up with some
we've been having that conversation
about DNS and there are probably other
protocols we could have it about and
we're getting to the point where the
infrastructure and the architecture is
aging enough that we should be able to
say something about that and you're
right we don't I just wanted to point
out that Collin Jennings gave a similar
kind of talk in art in the dispatch
meeting on Monday morning so you know
convergent timelines nope
Phil Han Baker I'd like the IAB to
further consider what expectations we
have from users of the Internet and how
they're using it and how they expect it
to affect their privacy now the reason
for that is obviously you may have
noticed we're currently approaching a
constitutional crisis in this country as
a result of people using the internet
and we're approaching weapons of mass
litigation and I think that and one of
the things that troubles me most when
I'm reading comments on that debate is
when people are saying well the users
should have expected this because here
on page 57 of the terms
of service they signed away their lot
their right to their privacy and all
their friends privacy and so it was
settled and I think that we need to look
at what our expectations of users
understanding of the technology is and
make some sort of statement because we
are facing something that is going to be
unprecedented and you don't do what the
Internet has just done to two countries
without consequences
Christian do you wanna stir yeah I mean
there is a real problem that as the
Internet has grown into a big
infrastructure for the society it has
changed I mean it used to be 20 years 40
years ago these wild conquests that we
are making of connecting everybody in
and we were very happy about that
now we have to go to the next level
clearly I mean understand that we have
this infrastructure we have to make it
matter we have to make it more reliable
not to Phil's point they are clearly I
mean our initial ideal it was let's
connect everybody and what we've been
pretty good at that now that everybody
is connected we might have to think
about what to do to have every connected
in a useful way if you have ideas or
specific action that would suggest I'd
be happy to organize that
yeah I I just wanted to add all the
comfort not all the conversations but
pretty much all the rooms have been in
this week I think people have been
thinking about this and it's definitely
on people's minds the question is always
how can we help and how can we affect
this with what we do here it's it's and
this goes to a lot of conversations
we've had about human rights and other
aspects where we're trying to respect
the users and trying to further the
goals of the internet that we share I
hope without taking a paternalistic tone
or or trying to do something where we
don't have the expertise or the
authority and and that's the balance
that I think we're still searching for
is finding where we can make a positive
contribution without taking
responsibility for more than we can chew
so just as a closing comment on this
topic I want to point out that I sock
actually hosts policy fellows at many
IITs including this one and one of the
conversations that those policy fellows
have is actually trying to understand
the interplay between the the social
systems of their countries and the
Internet as a set of platforms and I
think it's very important that we
continue that engagement outside of just
the technical circles as we look at
these problems because it's quite clear
that some of our own understanding which
might be based simply on how the packets
flow or the pieces of information
traverse the network that that's not
actually capturing the whole problem as
it's seen by other parts of the
ecosystem and so I really encourage
everybody to remain engaged not just
with AIESEC and its policy program but
with the policy and civil society folks
wherever it is you will go home to after
you leave London job
it's keeping in mind that I know we're
already over time I want to try to be
brief but apropos of the bone spurs the
message I heard during that excellent
talk was that stuff has gotten beyond
the point where the actual where the
operator is who actually need to use
this stuff can understand it and we're
sort of we have a problem here that
we're sort of self selected to be
exactly the wrong people to evaluate
that problem and because no no no
because there are operators here but
they tend to be the most sophisticated
the Lark you know it's like okay what
the ANS operators very well you know
Google is here and CloudFlare is here
and you know and the super the super
sophisticated people are here you know
sort of the random you know the random
business that's trying to run a DNS
cache on there you know on their windows
box probably is not now although I could
say oh then we just need to get more
operators here you're like that ain't
gonna happen
but I'm wondering is there some way that
we can figure out that we could like you
know and perhaps with Isaac's help
figure out somebody we can go pull the
operator figure out some way to go and
talk to the people who we on whom we
will be inflicting our stuff and try to
understand better whether they'll be
able to use it you know and to privacy a
slow to slow down our wild enthusiasm
for innovation and direct it more in
places where it's gonna get get better
uptake is this a follow-up question or a
follow-up comment on that if okay please
yeah Darren Pettis speaking as a network
operator you know as many people know we
brought a proposed internet draft
forward on Monday and it's I don't want
to go on and on it's just it there's a
dichotomy here between the need for
privacy on the Internet which we
completely understand and a requirement
by many operators to manage their
networks internal to the data center and
not being you know an expert on on these
solutions we tried to follow the process
a little bit and come up with some
proposed solutions and I want to thank
everybody that's been helpful to throw
out different ideas of what can be done
I've learned a lot in the process
we would have liked to have had maybe an
IB architectural board review or a board
meeting for a couple of days to discuss
it a little more maybe understand the
situation a little bit better there's a
lot of confusion out there on that but
that being said the situation remains I
know we didn't come up with a solution
that was agreeable at the time which is
understandable so I have to figure out
how we go forward but but as I say the
situation remains that we have to manage
our networks and we also want things to
be secure on the internet so where we go
from here I don't know but just wanted
to share a little bit with that and if
anybody has any ideas of better ways to
accomplish that and get through that
Academy we're happy to listen so before
we turn this over to Lee who's going to
be the first to speak for the idea I
just want to distinguish between two
different problems because I believe you
you've elucidated two different ones one
is a problem with management in the face
of ossification a set of systems which
have gotten so difficult to configure
because they're old enough and have
assumptions built into them from 30
years of different sorts of use that
they're not usable in new situations or
not extensible in in particular ways and
then there's a different problem of
innovation where we have changed the
working of the network in a way that may
have an impact on those who use it who
operated and I think those are
distinguishable enough that possibly we
ought to treat them as two different
items of inquiry so when you answer
please be clear as to which one of those
problems you're tackling I actually
think that I'm being responsive to both
because I'm talking more about our
processes and the IAB activities that we
have been trying to do more more
outreach as the IAB or and with the IES
G we spoke at a recent nanog for DNS in
particular I don't know if there's
representation at des Eaux arc but
that's not necessarily the kind of
operator you're talking about if I get a
local - yeah they're super sophisticated
right exactly yes that's a sophisticated
crowd - so I and I don't know how to
reach out to
you know small network operators I know
how to find Darren I can I know where
he's right there
but I don't know how to reach I don't
know how to reach people who manage a
small network and don't go to
conferences and may not read the same
trade journals that I do and so there
that's I think that the the ia
I'm gonna speak for the IAB since I'm
leaving and they they can't fire me I
think there's a just on the IAB and we
could make you stay
I think there's interest in continuing
to find ways to do that kind of work to
make sure that we incorporate more
stakeholders perspectives as we're
developing systems here at the IETF and
I don't think that's limited to the IAB
I think it's also represented on the
iesg
that's but there's a I think we also
need more suggestions on how to do that
outreach and do so in ways that scale
because there's you know there are a
limited number of us and ours okay so
I'm gonna cut the line and Spencer since
we are as you said over time Spencer
what what's your last question one last
thing one idea was that it could be
something similar to ipv6 where there's
split into an operational side and a
maintenance side because it's very tough
for non-programmers to come into a
cryptographer session and try to come up
to speed on what's going on so if there
was an operational side where they could
look at the need and then for maybe
partner with some people on the
maintenance side that might bridge that
gap a little bit thank you thank you
Spencer Dawkins I just wanted to follow
on the please comment a little bit and
to say you know I've gone to our
conference that you know gatherings also
but but this this last time I know I was
a little bit different we we had like
six or seven people we had an hour slot
to talk about IETF stuff we had at least
a hundred people in the room listening
to us there was no plenary slot but yeah
that was there was a lot I'm I'm
thinking that I'm thinking that I
I'm sensitive to the part where those
are not the right operators I suspect
that if we had the right question the
conversations with them we might
understand some things better and they
might have a better ability to flow SEF
downstream to smaller operators than we
do
so just up level and say the IB and iesg
both have members that are more
intentional about contact with the deaf
community than I've seen in the last
four years and I would encourage the
community to make sure that we're
talking to them about the right things
it seems like this is a right thing they
could be on our list and I'm pretty sure
that there are other right things as
well okay thank you thanks everybody
the next group to come up for open mic
will be the IOC so if the is you could
come to stage and the IB could
oh no I haven't flipped it yet the way
are so while the IOC comes up here I
including the yes they're all here so I
want to apologize to to Leslie and
Tobias because I didn't invite them up
here I messed up the the run of show so
I apologize to both of you
but Leslie is over here GBS is over here
we'll do the photographs with the
plaques later just because we're running
over time but again I want to thank them
very much for their for their service so
thank you and with that we'll start over
here and if people can introduce
themselves please
Leslie naval escaping IOC Ted Hardy
ex-officio IOC I'm still Beyonce Cooper
to be asked on ROM surviving IOC
blueburger Nam comment appointed John
Levine I sought board part of the IOC
clenteen coffin transfer Porsche when
Stanley IAD Kathy Brown I shocked in IO
C I should note also of course that we
are also the members of the IETF trust
and cavae
is the the chair so this is also the
time for questions for the trust if you
have them and with that we'll start here
my name is Jang Ha Noi I concern about
the I have the registration fee increase
um when I first thought or idea what the
registration fees or around of $500 so
now will you nicely here maybe or on
earth in one southern US dollars maybe
our time on after another 10 years maybe
2000 US dollar I is it so I kept
register fees the most like Spencer fee
I have him all the money I
in her net he'll relate her medians so I
saw because I my company sponsor me to
join the meeting so mm Oh 1000 no fire
if $500 is no problem for me but her it
if we have more than what one southern
US dollar maybe is plot we plug some
open source project manager or small
companies to join the because what once
on the US dollar is much to them every
year maybe it's three thousand US
dollars so I my suggestion is we may be
a future two sons away and so what is a
maximum register fee that I am community
can in do accept her so I also also
suggest IP fo use another financial
source local for maybe have a idea for
discussion how to increase the financial
revenue for IT I hope I'll not only full
song so registry fee if we register fee
like a text more test so maybe the the
command here it may be another happy
says it's a my suggestion thank you so
others to go first if they want no no
you see this is what happens if you
allow yourself okay so oh people are now
struggling I I have a weird yeah I'll go
I mean we when this question comes up I
mean first mean the the proposal where
our current you know straw man proposal
is to raise the price from $700 at 770
and the one of the topics that always
comes up is that by the is that nearly
everybody track nearly everybody travels
from far away
so there is hotel costs and there's
airplane costs and which for most people
I think are probably more than $700 so
one thing I was actually planning to
spring on us at dinner tonight was the
possibility of of tiered costs for local
local attendees which I think might oh
yeah which well I'm what I should
meeting I might as well finish putting
my foot in it
we're well no no no please go on okay no
we're meeting no we're meeting in
Thailand this fall and this is the first
time since we met in China that we are
meeting in what would be considered to
be a middle income as rather as opposed
to a high-income country you know and I
could easily imagine there are people
who live in Bangkok you know and can get
it could get to the venue on the bus for
whom a $700 fee might be a deterrent and
and we've had you know and we in fact
it's not well it's not super well
publicized but in fact you can ask you
can ask for fee waivers but I am you
know but as we become more international
the fact that different people can pay
different amounts will be an issue and I
think that particularly as you know
we're talking about satellites and
community networks and stuff like that I
mean to me I think it's important that
we encourage people to participate from
countries outside of the kind of the
traditional g8 g8 countries so I think
so the yet so the actual answer to your
question is you know we are aware that
raising the price is a problem and the
more we raise the price the more we're
the more we're gonna scare people away
you know and we don't have all the
answers into the exact you know the
extent that people can give us advice on
how to do it better I think we would
like to hear it please okay so why we
are handing out the rope to hang
ourselves let me do that as well and as
an outgoing IOC member maybe I can be a
little bit more relaxed about hanging
myself so you can hit me one my way out
so definitely in all the discussions we
had at the IOC we are always very
cautious about increasing the meeting
fee so I hear you yes
also faced with the challenge that
Beyonce raised before between the gap of
what we have is income and the gap we
have towards the cost there's a number
of things that we can debate or discuss
in the community so one is for example
can we get more sponsorship money or
other sponsorship revenues should we
expect Isaac to pay more I mean Isaac is
already paying a lot more compared to
some years ago but maybe I don't know is
there something to discuss about remote
attendees should they also care some of
that these are all discussions I think
for the community to have at some point
the only thing I would say in addition
to that is that we need to look at the
financial picture as a whole
so meeting registration revenues is one
one source of revenue but we also have
sponsorships and we're looking at some
innovative ways to formulate those for
ietf 103 in particular that that Jon
raised to try and work with sponsors to
help make it possible for more locals to
attend but there's lots of other ways
that you could think about managing the
the proportion of the budget that is
divided between sponsorships and meeting
registration fees and the proportion
that comes from my sock so I agree with
with the notion of you know sending us
your ideas in that regard but I think
it's important to not look at it just in
a vacuum and I'm going to cut the mic
line it's just in case anybody else has
some bright ideas up here only the
people who are standing are going to get
get hits at that but the last thing that
I will say about this is that as I said
in the in the earlier part of the of the
program we are not promising you this
increase this is this is a warning now
so that you can budget for it just in
case it comes but that doesn't mean
we're going to do it and as you can
already tell we're going to have lots to
talk about at our retreat at April and
will definitely be reporting back to you
as soon as that is done about you know
what what we're thinking about also if
you have bright ideas about what we
ought to be doing please do send them to
us right we we want those ideas so you
know we're not foolish enough not to
listen all right I'm gonna go over here
first and then come back belly button
excuse me part of my voice didn't wake
up with me this morning I have a comment
on the respectful behavior topic that
Alisa brought up earlier thank you for
bringing it up there's a point about it
that I think deserves highlighting we
are often abrupt to each other we're
often rude nasty whatever on mailing
lists or in person and what I hear often
in response to being called on that is
they can take it they their long term or
their long time participants you know we
know each other
or sometimes even I really don't care if
that person is a jerk I really don't
care if I Drive him away but we don't
consider that there are ten other people
watching this exchange saying I don't
want to put myself in a position where
I'm treated that way and this is not
just theoretical I've had more than one
person I've had more than a few people
tell me that they either left or didn't
participate because they saw how other
people were treated so even if you think
the people who are having this
discussion or thick skin it is affecting
other people and we need to not behave
that way thank you
[Applause]
so Barry I think your point is
well-taken but was there an action for
the IE OC there I could have chosen
either the IOC or the IAS G to make this
comment - I chose you
it's a comment and it's something I
think we all need to think about so okay
Kyle Rose I want to call the AFC's
attention to a grave injustice and that
was the the lack the shortage of cookies
or as the English call them biscuits I'm
just wondering what you guys are gonna
manage to do next time to make sure that
there's enough sugar to keep us all you
know awake and working you have to talk
a lot you have to talk a lot faster if
you're gonna complain about cookies
so I want to point out actually that the
next time the the ietf meets together
we're going to be meeting in Montreal
which is in Quebec and Quebec is the
maple syrup capital of Canada and
they're actually there actually is a
snow Arctic there's actually a strategic
maple syrup reserve in the province of
Quebec so so I think that's what we're
gonna do yeah I just want to make sure
that you understand the gravity of the
situation right I mean I was reduced to
buying cookies with cash like some kind
of peasant we are sorry about the lack
of cookies
i-i-i-i I understand that that there
have been on occasion various views
about the this venue and the way that we
interact with it and I think that we
will look seriously at at this venue
there were the last time and I will say
I was on the IOC the last time when when
the decision to come back here arose and
cookies were on the list of complaints
the last time - and we thought we had
ironed out many of those difficulties my
impression is that this venue has been
better for us this time than last time
you may decide for yourselves whether
that is an acceptable answer but I you
know I recognize that some people have
faced some challenges here I will note
that there have been some improvements
in the in the food handling it appears
to me that there has been some effort to
to label things a little better and I
think that that is mostly down to Mary
Barnes but I recognize that I recognize
that there have been some cookie
shortages yes quick plug so the
Secretariat sends out a meeting survey
after every meeting and well you know
threads on the attendees list are useful
for collecting ad-hoc feedback about the
venue and any other aspects of the
meeting the structured feedback that we
receive in the survey is a really
valuable source of information for us
it's really hard to make decisions in a
vacuum about what we should do in the
future so if you have opinions about how
you thought the meeting went or the
venue itself they tailor the questions
specifically each time about a
particular thing
please fill out the meeting survey so I
will note that I cut them up mic line so
it better be really urgent right and so
so you'll be you'll be forth
please up my name is muqam salmon from
afrinic um first of all let me begin by
acknowledging that the financial
sustainability of the ITF she'd always
come always take a priority over
everything else
however the same time we do realize that
technology very quickly takes up the
character of the people that have
created which is why I think the the
goal to have a lot more representation
geographical racial you know also AM
agenda is was important and when we talk
about the total cost of attending a
meeting for a room like this there's a
cost that most of you don't ever
understand the cost of getting a visa it
could easily be as high as 500 US
dollars to a thousand that's for someone
coming from you know very far off so I
want you to have those things in mind so
once you raise choose to raise the fees
please do consider what does that mean
for your strategy to also have what a
lot more accessibility because just the
fees automatically is going to shut down
a lot of people a good rule of thumb is
to just look at that say what is the
average salary of the kind of person
from the Africa or Asia that you would
like to be here because if this doesn't
get to the point where some engineer say
in Lagos were in Cameron decides okay
actually which could go to this event
and pay for my pocket then it's always
going to be no lock up for lot of people
and final immunity for some of the
solutions the answers are not going to
be found in this room of self selected
people maybe the idea I don't know
whether you guys the right people should
think about sending missions where you
go to like was the African in Assam it
to the asia-pacific and happy working
sessions what can we do in other to make
the ITF make make make it possible for
you to be more engaged in the idea I
think the solutions are not always going
to be found here thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you
so just a couple of points in response
first of all we have we are I think many
of us very cognizant of the visa cost
issue and it's something that we talk
about quite frequently one reason why we
rotate the meetings around to different
parts of the world is to try and
distribute some of that difficulty for
people so that while we acknowledge that
not everybody can make it to every
meeting if the visa cost issue is
prohibitive in some places that it might
not be in others and fully acknowledging
that that does not solve the problem for
everyone from you know with every
passport but it's one means that we've
adopted and that we're actually trying
to adopt as a consensus item of the IETF
to try and spread some of this cost
across the meetings over the years so
that if you can't attend one time you
can attend another time and just in
response to the your second point so the
IETF itself is all volunteers we can't
send people anywhere because we don't
really have the means to even cause
people to come to the to our own
meetings I sock does have programs that
are involved in trying and trying to get
people to participate in the IETF and to
do outreach in various parts of the
world and it's something that we could
look at that we do look at collaborating
around but for the IETF itself you know
since everybody's a volunteer we can
just ask people to do things we can't
make them do them and that's definitely
something that that I at least
experienced every day of the job trying
to get volunteers to do things is pretty
challenging
Lee Howard Andrew doing your earlier
presentation you'd mentioned that when
we have a shortfall in the past I sock
has covered that shortfall on an ad-hoc
basis and that can't continue and I
wanted to ask why I don't understand
well I I think what I said
it's possible that I did say it can't
continue I think what I meant in any
case is I'm not sure it should continue
and IIIi don't control I socks budget of
course so I can't actually speak for
what I sock should do but I control the
the part of you know I don't control
anything to be perfectly honest with you
I barely control my mouth but but but
you know I I'm part of this body and we
have responsibility for our budget and
we're trying to stay within our means
that you know there is this danger that
if we continue to rise that we we have
the opposite problem of what we've just
been talking about that is we you know
our expenses start to get away from us
so we have to be careful about that the
final thing that I would say is I am
concerned about about having this this
this way of operating where we come up
with all the stuff that we want to do we
talk that up we figure out how much
money we got and then we go to you know
our our parents and say you know can I
have the car I think that there's a
certain responsibility to live within
within our means and to understand why
our budget works this way some of this
is structural that is we've moved some
things on to the budget that were things
that we were getting for free and not
accounting before and so there have been
changes there and this is part of the
reason why I think the IOC has to spend
a good long hard look at this and try to
figure out exactly what's going on but I
would like to have a model for what our
meetings are doing and the fact that we
can't really explain
we've got theories we've got all kinds
of explanations people can come up with
them they're plausible ones but I don't
think we have a really good eye
as to why the meeting that revenue has
has been changing so much and I think
that if we don't have that it it's
unreasonable for us to ask the you know
the wider I sought community to just pay
whatever it is that we managed to come
up with people are gonna start to ask us
well what are you doing with you know
with these unpredictable expenses and I
think that that's part of the part of
the reason I don't know if Kathy wants
to say anything more about the budget
itself I think if someone said it
earlier about taking a look at the the
whole of the not just a business model
as to who's supporting what although
we've gone through this a number of
times because there's basically three
streams of revenue right registration
fees sponsorships and then the I sock
piece and I think that's okay I mean the
point is when you see this kind of
strain on the way things are it's worth
looking at it across the board I don't
think there's any yes/no or even maybe
here there's a desire by all of us to
get hold of what the actual costs are
why and I think while some of the cost
got moved I think it's really about the
attendance and I think that that issue
is one that deserves some attention
because that's I think you put it up on
the slide right that's where you're
seeing this gap and so I think the
collective thought was well it should be
examined as to what's going on here
so just to follow up on that a little
bit I think that the concern here is
only about money flows it's about
whether or not it's signal that what
we're producing isn't a value to the the
folks who were producing it for and if
the reason that we're having lowered
attendance is because the online
mechanisms have gotten better and remote
participation is successful for
people who might have previously come
for one or two that's not a statement of
the value of the hf and it means that we
may need to change the funding model to
not be based on attendance over time but
it it doesn't say anything as signal to
the leadership or to the to the rest of
the ATF about whether or not what we're
producing is the the right thing for the
value needed by the ecosystem and I
think that the point andrew was making
before about this can't continue is
really about it can't continue that we
don't have a workable model of how what
we produce and the value we provide maps
to how people interact with the ITF and
developing that model isn't the work of
just EEOC it's the work of a lot of
people including everybody in this room
that wants to be part of it but I think
it's important for us to realize that
it's very easy to make a kind of post
facto narratives if I well this one
turned out to be too far away and that
one turned out to be yes in Europe but
during the Cold season where the
predictions were for Europe and the warm
season and you can come up with very
easy explanatory narratives but they're
not a model and I think we need to
understand how to make predictive models
of this that actually succeed and if it
turns out the predictive model for that
says hey you're going to continue to
produce useful valuable things but it's
going to go to all online by the end of
some particular time then you know we've
got to develop completely new funding
streams that deal with that that's ok
but we can't tell whether that's what's
going on or applicability isn't where it
was when we're in the midst of the RAI
boom or the SDN boom or some other
previous boom and that's really really
important for us not to hide by taking
it to AIESEC and saying make us whole
and you could I add one more thing so
was Lee's first toast ah yes
Thanks so I actually don't want to speak
to the why can't I sock just pay all of
it because I think if you want to have
that discussion you need to go to the is
a 2.0 meetings um but I do want to speak
a little bit more about this model
question and some work that Lou has been
spearheading in the Finance Committee to
actually have a look at well what is
what is the actual model of as Pete
Resnick calls it no it's Elliot Lera
calls them cos InDesign goes out as
write what what are our inbound flows of
money and what are our outbound ones and
one salient thing that I would pull up
here is that a decade ago or more
meeting fees covered more than the cost
of the meeting and now they don't and
that difference is largely a function of
it's not just our costs that are going
up at the costs of you know hotels and
whatnot and food etc so it is a it is a
bit of a tricky business it is it is
challenging to get a picture of you know
how how does our financial model work
and how would we like it to so I I think
I presume that the IOC when it comes
back with a statement about whether or
not it's raising meeting fees in the
future will also come back with a
statement of this is how our financial
picture looks and this is why we have to
raise meeting fees as opposed to getting
more money from my sock as opposed to
expecting to get more money in
sponsorship and last thought just to
show you just how squirrely this this
attendance thing is and how it does tie
with what is the work being done when we
were looking at the early numbers of
paid registrations for this meeting this
one right here
like three weeks ago it was the lowest
curve ever and it was you know we have
all of the graph with all of the lines
going up like this and in this what this
meeting was doing this and it was like
it was gonna be a sub 1000 person
meeting and as you saw in earlier slides
here we are 1200 people missed that
missed the prediction by 40 people so
some of this is just tricky hard and
subject to new new good work being
introduced
to the agenda so just one less thing as
you're contemplating all this I heard at
least two of our colleagues from Africa
talk today about the needs of people in
those nations and we here at I saw a lot
of actual interest in people in the
other part of the world where there is
not an internet yet that would be 40% of
the world that we're hearing from those
folks that hey we'd like to create - we
want to be part of this part of what I
wonder is whether there are new demands
that we're not looking at that would be
served in different ways that perhaps
result in some different costs
structures and so my raise my hand
saying I sure hope as you take this
issue up that that is part of the
discussion and that the testing what
those new markets are for the IETF I
think would be really smart I know that
that my last trip to India all of
everybody wanted to say how do we how do
we get there how do we do this we can't
get there from here
financially but why don't you come here
well are there other ways to actually
attract more attendees and so I would
hope you would put that in the in your
model now or a new model and I hope that
would get in the conversation I want to
thank you all for all those comments and
endpoints and I do think that looking at
the value that the IETF offers to the
not just participants but potential
participants does need to be part of
that model and I hope that you will look
at that probably with the iesg when
you're talking about how do we make sure
we're actually providing value and and
absolutely as Cathy's you just said and
we've and we've heard please make sure
we can include we can be inclusive and
that includes you know financial
inclusivity Thanks all right so there
are two things first of all I have now
run to
stakes today so I got one more and then
I'm fired but I run two mistakes today
that the second one was I did not in
fact invite Brad and can here on to the
this stage so that you could see who
they were so if you would come up here
now with the remaining people who are
willing to do that I'm going to ask you
to come up here while you ask your
thirty second question that's you Erin
yes excellent
dear Beyonce so an email went out
recently asking for input on a number of
potential destinations for future ITF
meetings and I'm just back from a week
in Bangalore and while most of the days
were very enjoyable I have to say that
it's very different as a business
traveler it's a very different
experience and so I guess what I'm
looking for is a little bit of
confirmation that this is not going to
be asked for input collect input make a
decision but there might be a little bit
of chance for some dialog since I think
that it is it is different enough from
the standard work environment for ITF
that it might be good to have a chance
to talk about it if you're seriously
considering locations for meetings that
are so different from our current
expectations so thank you for that but I
hope that you are sending such such
remarks to to the relevant list to the
to the inbox that accepts them and I
also want to remind you that we have
this this new committee that is is
tasked with with dealing with that with
that input and also finally that you
know we do have an open mailing list
right the ITF mailing list is is is open
and we can discuss those things there
but I think that it's very important
that people raise issues about you know
what what the differences are to that
committee we are not going to be able to
solve the problem for everybody all the
time and I think that you know raising
the issues is important but but it
doesn't mean that that's going to be
definitive and I'm not sure that we can
decide meeting venues with 1,200 of our
closest friends on a
list it's a fair point yes please
so to the other tone of your question
one are one of the ideas of the meeting
menu above and of asking reaching out to
the community is that we want to reach
out early in the process this doesn't
this is not the last step this is one of
the first steps where we start
contemplating about something so we can
receive your feedback early so see it in
that spirit so I've now been the the
medium review chair for I think about 28
hours so how's it going so how's it
going so far so I will say please send
the feedback in through the channel
we've established it can be good
feedback can be positive feedback where
you say good things but why we should go
to that particular place has been
requested input on as well as reasons
why we should be concerned about it we
should maybe reconsider going to this
location so it doesn't always have to
just be bad stuff so if first can and
then bread if you can introduce
yourselves very quickly and then we'll
have a stage over to the iesg
hi good evening hey I'm Ken Boyle and
new to service to this wonderful
organization and I'm grateful to be here
and if I can help anybody as as you
heard my responsibility is sponsorship
so I'm happy to interact with anybody
before I depart on Friday and even after
thank you hello I'm Brad Biddle and the
new legal counsel I'm really I'm excited
also about being engaged I have huge
respect for ICF and everything that's
accomplished and it's kind of daunting
we roll to step into ITF had incredible
legal support or you know the past
number of years with Jorge Contreras so
I feel like I'm standing on the
shoulders of giants and in one sense
because there's really been amazing work
done I really you know appreciate the
warm welcome I've had
and really love the culture and the
people of the ITF and and thanks for the
opportunity to to be here thank you with
that know we cut the mic long some time
ago I'm sorry we're gonna invite the isg
to come up next please thank you
[Laughter]
sit down
are they good okay time for the
ceremonial passing of doubts go ahead
pass your dots a few if you so choose so
let's start down on this end Spencer
Spencer can you introduce yourself I'm
Spencer Dawkins I'm the outgoing
transport area director next year
then campbell continuing an art area
director i letter that I wrote kaplan
Moriarty outgoing security area Benkei
duck incoming security area McNally Cola
incoming routing oh yeah Atlas outgoing
routing Warren Kumari continuing ups
Alexei Melnikov continuing applications
in the real time
ELISA Cooper Suresh Krishna under
Dunning internet said Hardy accept as
you as IV chair Terry Anderson internet
Mia Kulemin returning transport
depo-provera brownie nearing goodness
book dullness incoming operations and
management burn Walker is happy outgoing
Eddie ups Adam Roach returning
applications in real time
Eric risk Willis security okay my
clients are open I think I can speak on
behalf of the IHG that we encourage all
questions about space lasers and we
discourage all other questions keep that
in mind as you go to the mics I refer my
right honourable friends to the question
I asked some moments ago right so so we
sent you a response Pete which indicated
that we thought that the right time to
come back to this discussion would be
when the new format tools were a little
bit further along because we might be
able to leverage them to address some of
the issues that you raised so we had a
we had a lively discussion about it and
there were kind of differences of
opinion and on the topic itself but it
seems like that's that would be the
right time to take it up again
of what is this month's months yes
months yep we were just talking about
how to how to phase the rollout on the
weekend with the RFC editor so yeah good
so I stood up here last is G if you
remember and calling the
IETF arrogant and how we needed to get
the user community together and I said I
would take the responsibility to try to
get the group together and the group
that we chose was owned OGG because they
were interested in talking to ITF people
so we had a common there was a
conference call i forward mail to the
iesg asking people to participate I
wasn't able to attend so I have no idea
if anyone was on that call can you
comment I said you know I know I wasn't
able to be on that particular call but
we have been having some conversations
about seeing if we could ask some folks
at OU not to come either to talk and at
the routing area meeting or RT gwg and
do a better overview of what's going on
at we are getting some work coming into
the routing area meeting sorry working
group that is very related to what Onaga
is doing so I think we really need to
continue and build that relationship so
the plan was to get oh not to come here
in London that didn't happen the Onaga
is going to be held in May so let's us
put our foot forward to get somebody
there so if anybody wants to work on it
contact me you know I'm planning to it
and the nog meeting in San Francisco in
May exactly for this purpose Thank You
Tobias yeah Tobias so this is related to
the NomCom comment that the pool of
potential future leaders is relatively
small and the first question is it's
like one question someone's up question
first question is what do you think
you're gonna do about it because we hear
this like every year that oh we are
facing a relatively small pool of
potential new ATS and so on and the sub
question is might it be one option for
example to be more risk-taking in terms
of choosing younger working group chairs
with less experience in the to give them
that opportunity to
grow and learn and develop in our
community so that's one idea and I'm
sure the new ADEs will take that into
consideration the security area has done
pretty well for the last few years and
so we've been trying to share with the
other areas what we've been doing in
case that helps others maybe it's easier
for security or maybe it's the
mentorship but we have paid attention to
who asks who's interested to eventually
be an area director and have tried to
work with them on different
opportunities whether they're very young
in their career so we may only have
openings for a secretary position for a
working group and then help mentor them
in two roles for working group chairs
and you know I could name several
instances but we have a pretty good pool
of more than five people that are
interested to do it probably closer to
ten that are interested do it either
soon or at some point in time so it does
require outreach from the area directors
it requires mentorship and you know
showing interest in in building people
so I do hope that continues and I know
Ben and Ecker are interested to continue
that right and we discussed who was
interested so far and hope that the list
grows and we encourage through the
sector as well oh yeah so yes we can do
a lot in our areas and obviously Alvaro
and Debra and I have done some of that
encouraging our chairs and appointing
new people but to pretend that this is
isolated from the other industry effects
and the consolidation that's happening
in portions of the industry would be
absurd and I have to note that even when
you look up at the iesg we've gone into
four years that I was on the is G from
having essentially it completely
full-time is G - one where that is
distinctly not the case and so I feel
that the concerns that about finding and
mentoring good leaders and encouraging
the industry is even more critical than
it appears and
it's not just those areas Spencer
Spencer had his hand up before you been
my hand up so just just to follow on
coming I was making from the microphone
I think at this point we're
reprogramming the Kobayashi Maru level
of needing to think about things
continuing to but you know get up and
say boy it would be great if they were
more and more transport nominees for
downtown every year for how many in a
row I mean you know it's like we can do
better than this you I having said that
this is not the is G's thing to fix is I
think it is the is G's things to make
sure that we don't keep the community
from fixing and it's not the num Tom's
the thing to fix I mean you know they
can ask for nominees earlier and that
would be awesome but I think that we're
you know I think we're reprogramming or
simulator at this point and I'm I'm
interested in talking to people in the
community who have ideas about that I do
I'll just say this for a couple of
examples we we met with the working
group chairs today to talk about changes
to the way we schedule working group
meetings and resolve conflicts between
working groups and stuff like that so
the Secretariat got up and talked about
stuff that we talked about with the
secretary at the IHG the meeting this
morning and there were probably nine
working group chairs that made really
good suggestions that we had thought of
I'd say to be generous three of them I
think there's a lot of clue out there
that isn't up here and I think that I
think that might be very helpful for
that part of the community that has that
clue to be involved in this conversation
you will notice that everybody on this
stage managed to figure out how to get
funded to at least start their terms
that's not true for the rest of the
community so we were the wrong people to
solve this problem
then so uh sever I agree with pretty
much everything that's been said so far
I won't go on to say that the art area
directors and some of the chairs I've
had a similar discussion this week about
how we can better grow our pipeline
because the pipeline has been pretty
thin sometime that's not just at the
area director level that's at the chair
level and all the way down where it's
hard to find people that are both
willing and capable feel filling the
roles so that's something that we're
actively looking at Thank You mr. Van
stefan-boltzmann yeah I have a concern
about the approval of on Monday of the
draft Effects of pervasive encryption on
the operators as a draft describes a lot
of all food behavior that some operators
are practicing on then states that
encryption prevent them and instead of
seeing this as a good thing as a draft
frames the problem as as if encryption
was a problem because it prevented all
the sort of things that operators would
like to do a typical example is section
2 3 4 which describes either HTTP either
insertion in an HTTP flow when the
operator adds personal information such
as a phone number as an HTTP header so
the website at the other end I have more
information this sort on also the draft
says of this action the specific
technique is sometimes seen as
questionable it's not sometimes seen as
questionable it's all fool it's bad on
if encryption prevents it it's precisely
what was invented for so I think that
this draft sends a very bad message it
will clearly be read once published as
RFC it will be seen on described as
going back after RFC 7258 on will be
clearly will be discussed on presented
as if IETF went back on encryption
Warren do you want to address so I mean
as I'm sure everybody knows this
document has had a long and varied past
it's gone through multiple IETF lost
calls and yes there's a lot in it that
doesn't make everybody happy
but what it was trying to do and perhaps
doesn't do perfectly in fact we'll say
it doesn't do perfectly is be judgment
free throughout no we tried the author's
tried multiple times to remove any sort
of judgment and Chris try to be these
are things that people do by the way you
should know about them if you're going
to be running a network I don't really
know what more I can say on that but I'm
sure there are many other who can
can you spirit that consensus product
where we landed on the consensus text
that might be a useful I could finally
find the draft but I mean we published
we took the approval thing on Monday
what the consensus Bitzer - no that's
right can you or can you explain the
yeah and it's one of the very very few
documents where that we've ever
published that has the consensus but set
to know what shows up differently and
the boilerplate so if you have a look in
the data tracker maybe that wasn't here
if you have a look in the data tracker
it's got consensus knows so it has the
different boilerplate on the front of it
once it's published it will have the
different way plate on the front of it
so I don't think I explained that very
well hopefully that helps at least um
deviate your concerns and oh sure
Kathleen has more sure and I'll keep it
short so this was a follow on from RFC
7258 and Stephen one of the authors of
that was the original sponsoring area
director for this and he also agreed it
was a follow on because if you read the
words of that document it is also asking
to find a balance and figure out what
that balance is between network
management and privacy and and and to
consider those controls this was a very
difficult document to work on because
people needed to feel acknowledged and
when what they were being said
what they're contributing and and feel
heard that these were real problems in
their spaces and there may be alternate
ways to do these things so I do hope
that for areas where you are objecting
to practices that you help coach and
provide guidance as to what should be
done in ways that will be received well
additionally we addressed every single
comment that came in so if you didn't
send comments in and the many times that
this has been out for review we weren't
able to address them the other problem
we ran into his authors is that
everybody is bias everybody every piece
of text that came in just about had some
bias in some direction so it was very
difficult Spencer so I'm the responsible
area director for quick so I've spent an
entire IETF meeting talking to people
about the spin bit in the halls so I
want to I want to do real quickly two
things one is to say there's there's two
things going on here one is the way we
ballot on informational documents I had
a fairly short but intense conversation
with the isg about that this morning and
that's continuing informational I'm
sorry informal our chats and and retreat
topic I'm sure but for us to be able to
for us to be able to get the stuff out
that needs to be out the way it needs to
be out and I think we made some I think
eight we actually make some progress
with that with publishing the draft that
we've been talking about but I want to
uplevel to another thing and basically
say that you know we're talking about a
problem that is difficult it is a tussle
it is we have managed to not make it go
away for a year and I have no reason to
believe that it's going to go away so I
think that this is the point where we
need to be engaging with the community
and I think this is the point where we
need to be steering because we need to
be able to do the right thing whatever
the heck that is when we're talking
about G we have privacy concerns
G we have operational concerns that's
been really difficult the IAB has had
has had a workshop that tried to you
know try to engage the wireless
operators and basically you know it's
this this is hard you know and that you
know that conversation hasn't stopped
either so I think you know again this is
a thing where it's like you know we need
help from the community and we need to
be steering oh yeah this the work to as
I went deeper and deeper into it it's
really also a control issue between apps
and management and security kind of
stuck in the middle and right so I know
why she got the unicorn but more
seriously this isn't something that the
isg needs to solve this is something
that we all need to solve as a community
this is a tussle this is impacting the
internet this is impacting people out
there and it's a balance between as
Kathleen said the endpoint and the
network and we've all had their
arguments about some network and smart
network since we were in well not
preschool I guess but you know at least
college and at the same time it matters
and we also had that lovely plenary talk
with David Clarke talking about how one
of the things we can do is wait and
figure out how to make the stage of the
tussle something that considers ethics
and the challenges that are ahead so the
question I have for you back is how do
you frame it how do we pull consensus
together out of the IETF how do we get
the work moving along that's needed
because no matter how fervently we care
about the ethics and privacy of the
internet and Internet users at the end
of the day folks are reading to manage
and run their networks and
frankly make money so we need to figure
out how to balance the tussle and how to
do the right technology to solve this
and that I'm afraid is not something
that you're going to find up here
because you know there's so many more
brilliant people out there thank you
speaking about the government's free
character of the draft I don't think
that it's a target in itself to be good
runs free but it sees things like as a
fool as inserting HTTP headers with
personal information or many other
examples in the draft we should not be
judgment free we should clearly say that
it's a bad thing on
if encryption stupid it's good for the
same reason I'm unhappy with the use of
terms like balance I mean the priority
is protecting the privacy of the users
the rest comes after we don't try to
balance everything there are some things
that are more important than others so I
as an author I'm one of the security
area directors and there's countless
drafts in the IETF that have been
published during my term where I pushed
for encryption to be required on those
drafts I I have firm belief that it is
helpful to have encryption we are not
going to reach and end encrypted
networks unless we address these
problems and help people understand
better ways to tackle these issues so
publishing a draft like this in my mind
and and it says it within the draft
itself is meant to be helpful to
overcome these obstacles people have to
deploying encryption if you ignore them
they will not deploy your encryption
right so this was hit it head-on
let's start talking about this and
figure out how we can go forward so that
we could have end-to-end encryption so
yeah I guess sort of a follow on from
that simply continuing to say that
something is bad doesn't make it go away
and we spent a long time saying that not
has horrendous you should never deploy
not didn't so much work out well for us
this document isn't saying that you
should spy on your users it's not saying
that in any
the tone I believe is these things are
things that we need to realize exist you
need to understand that you know there
are these middle boxes that do these
sorts of things if you want to have an
encrypted network or you know a network
we encryption is ubiquitous you need to
understand that these things exist and
that if you don't provide some other way
for people to be able to do the stuff
that they need to protect their network
they will just not allow you to deploy
this and oh dear wait wait please please
there's other people in the mic line
ahead of you
Illya didn't were you coming up again
okay so I just just an observation which
is that as Illya said this the
responsibility for trying to figure out
exactly what the precise thing to do
here on a case-by-case basis does not
lie with us utilize with the community I
think if you review the extensive record
of commentary about this document you
will find both your own view reflected
and some of the views that the 80s to my
right over here have been reflecting
this is clearly a point of contention
for the community the same if you review
the extensive mailing list traffic on
opps AWG related to the ballots right so
I think it's it's not a question that
we're going to resolve here today and
it's not even necessarily a question for
the IHG as a body to resolve we had we
made a group decision about what did the
disposition of the document based on you
know many many many many many many
rounds of edits but this is really not
the end of the story it's probably you
know somewhere towards the beginning I
think we should move on that's that's
okay
I'm I'm gonna move to this gentleman
who's been standing along extremely
patiently for a very long time and then
I think I would like to cut the mic line
given the time so Bret Jordan I just
want to publicly stand and thank
Kathleen Moriarty for her years of
service and her willingness to seek out
and understand all sides of an issue
thank you I fell on Baker yes just
echoing that I was very surprised when
Stefan said that the first and only
priority is encryption for me as a
security person my biggest priority is
usually integrity and authentication and
for many users access to their data
if you've encrypted all their pictures
of the kids when they're 5 and they
can't get access to them that's a much
more serious loss to them than the fact
that somebody might else might have seen
them so whenever you are designing a
security protocol if you're not thinking
about the balance of the users concerns
you're failing the user and one of the
three things that has frustrated me so
much is that I got into the internet
because of PGP 30 years later we're
still not using end-to-end encryption
and that isn't the fault of the end
users the fault is in ourselves because
we haven't yet given them the end-to-end
tools that meet their needs and we must
understand their needs and address their
needs before they will use our stuff
Thank You Harold how this film seems I
get the last word I don't know I didn't
mean to make me have you sit down if you
wanted to be in the queue so if it
wasn't clear-cut after you miss the last
word sorry
couple a couple of points on which
internet we've built both universal
access and this particular debate
illustrate that we want an internet for
everybody which includes that we connect
all the good guys and all the bad guys
and some of the bad guys run networks so
we got to admit that and we got to say
that that's a good thing because the
internet is for everybody
however I hope that the IHG will
encourage in the future positions to be
stated not only on what exists but on
what is good and what is bad
[Music]
so that destroying the integrity of
other people's data whether it's HTTP
headers or other things is condemned as
bad even though we have to make it a
separate document in order to do a
separate Constance's call all ends so I
commend you for having gotten this far
in describing what goes on in an
Internet that is for everybody
thank you Thanks you know so looking at
this problem purely from technical and
not policy or moral or anything I think
it's a simple problem to solve every
single packet on the Internet should be
encrypted I'm looking at this tech as a
technical problem as a trade-off between
privacy and network management every
single packet and then Internet should
be encrypted IP headers go in the clear
so network management at least has
something in outer headers they don't
they can't look at port numbers but
something has to give
they don't have zero management they
have IP headers but every single packet
on the internet needs to be encrypted
you're volunteering to join the quick
mafia are you alright thanks everyone
[Applause]
[Music]