okay welcome everyone to the identifier
locator addressing a la boeuf i'm
samhita Chakrabarti co-chairing with
Joelle Halpern and responsibilities
suresh krisshnan and IB Shepherd a CEREC
node mark we have mini taker Thank You
Marcin duty and jabber
scribe is evangelist thank you and we
have the online agenda Deborah miracle I
thought Pat on this slide and next is
not well so you are probably familiar
with all the notable rules and notes so
identifier locator addressing aisle
above basically this is a protocol to
implement over overlay you know without
an encapsulation
so using ila mapping in the ipv6 address
you can use the similar whatever you can
achieve the instant capsulation when
transporting the packets between the
nodes it has some additional benefits
control plane and data plane separation
as well as anchor free routing in many
use cases so there are so that's the
premise of this buff and the scope of
today's session is in for mostly
information exchange and this is a non
working group forming buff so we want to
make that clear
lots of work has been done in this space
in IETF I don't want to name them
separately and because I might miss
someone
some some protocols but basically
separation of control and data planes ID
and locator separation and address
mapping has been also worked out here so
today our purpose is not going to
compare those solutions are not going to
go into solutions in any way so we will
ask the crowd to just understand the
problems the issues that ila addresses
and they use cases so just for the
informational purpose and then why it is
needed that's the purpose of today's
move yeah it's discussion of the
problems the scoping in those aspects
and specifically not well you could use
protocol foo or protocol bar we're not
debating that today the agenda is simple
we will have Tom presenting Tom Harbert
presenting a problem statement scope and
the issues I believe he is also dis
going to discuss the data center network
use case at during the same presentation
and then Kalani buggy Nene will be
presenting on the 5g user mobility use
case and then we will do that Q&A we
request that during the presentations
due to the short the shortage of time we
would only accept the clarification
questions and then at the end of the
presentation we will have enough time
for Q&A so with that we say that there
are number of ila related drafts that
has been discussed in various working
groups such as interior DMM and maybe
separately in side meetings so and then
so with that we should start
today's presentation and after that we
will ask separate we will have Q&A so
Tom please okay my name's Tom Herbert
I'll be talking about in the background
of ila this will be mostly the general
aspects of it and then we'll go into
specific use cases with Kelly Hani I
would like to thank the chairs maybe for
organizing this that's much appreciated
never had this so identifier look here
to addressing I'll start with a goal so
the goal is to provide seamless mobility
for multiple use cases using highly
efficient identifier locator techniques
that's a pretty short statement that's
actually packed with four different
components seamless mobility multiple
use cases highly efficient and
identifier locator so we'll look a
little bit at those the use cases so we
have multiple use cases it's inherently
mobile protocol so anything to do with
mobility actual mobile networks which is
first use case and we also have use
cases in data center virtualization
network virtualization I only was
actually born from the point of view of
network virtualization and in particular
container virtualization as a more
efficient means of doing encapsulation
so you can also consider that as we move
there may be converge networks that have
one more than one of these kind of use
cases inside the network hence we have
the possibility of converged use cases
so the problem statement so we what we
did here whereas we listed the problems
and the applicable use cases so this
goes kind of from the general problems
to more specific use case problems so as
I mentioned encapsulation is expensive
as a data plane protocol and the way to
think about it is when you're
encapsulating a an application that
requires high-performance encapsulation
basically becomes a tax on every packet
so there are certain circumstances low
latency high performance use cases where
even that encapsulation becomes
problematic and it also contributes to
bandwidth on the wire so every byte that
I'm putting into encapsulation is about
taking away from MTU for instance
there's a related issue which we see a
lot in IETF which are tunneling
considerations so in the network when
encapsulation occurs we consider that
tunneling and then several
considerations kick in for instance what
happens if your encapsulation exceeds
the MTU at that point do you fragment do
you not fragment so there is an RFC on
that just previously in PSV WG they were
talking about ecn and tunneling so how
do you deal with ecn and tunneling
disserve has an equivalent consideration
if you're doing UDP encapsulation then
you need to worry about UDP checksum so
the short story here is whenever
encapsulation or tunneling occurs in the
network there are more considerations
than just creating a new packet another
one that's sort of general and this is
kind of well-known in IETF also identity
is tied to location so this goes back to
the original definition of ipv4 when you
have an ipv4 address it exposes both
identity of who you're talking with and
also location where they are so this
coupling makes it difficult especially
in mobility to separate out those
notions so that's one of the one of the
things we are intending the
the next one support for alternate
protocols this actually has to do with
encapsulation what we found is whenever
we diverge especially in the data center
from using plain UDP plain TCP over the
network and start using capsulation or
extension headers inevitably some
network device will not like that and
usually this is not breaking
connectivity but what it does is it
reduces a number of optimizations and
that obviously gets us into the whole
arena of vendors trying to support
various encapsulations and an endless
endless stream of that so anytime we we
try to come up with a new encapsulation
or new scheme we do consider the effects
of existing network devices in the
middle of network privacy in addressing
so this I touched a little bit on in in
area discussion so this goes more into
what kind of addresses are we exposing
to the Internet and it's not so much
that this is a problem to be solved in
identifier locator addressing it's more
can identify our look at our addressing
kind of solve this or contribute to the
solution if we can split location from
identity that in itself already gets us
some distance to this mobile anchor
points this is an issue and mobility
there's a lot of design in 3gpp for
instance Franco Mobility Kayani will go
into a lot of the more rational how to
get to anchor lists and the benefits of
that and the last one low latency
applications so this is a kind of under
the assumption that as we go forward a
RvR new applications will come in low
latency will become more and more of an
issue in real networks so we classify
that as mobile it's it's already kind of
an assumption in data center network
just can you relate the or identity tied
to location to me parka textures I'm
just curious on that I'm quite
understand the point executing identity
tied to location
is it identity yes in the address so
your identity and your at location or
basically encoding the address so it's
difficult to split those out which
basically means the address the node has
to be static and tied to that specific
location so this is one slide that just
basically shows the process if if you're
not familiar with ila it is what we're
calling address transformation as
opposed to nate'll explain the
difference there but the idea is part of
the ipv6 address is an externally
visible prefix and when we go to send
that to a specific location we do
transformation of the upper bits in the
address to what's called a locator
locator is something that's routable in
the network to the actual location of
the node we're talking to so this for
instance could be a host that has a VM
that's running which is our location or
the know we're talking to could be a
device in the network where we need to
route to an e node B so there's some
concept here that the node has a
persistent identity and a location and
the the upper bits in the address are
used to express the location so to
transmit we transform those upper bits
to locator packets sent through the
network at a peer point the reverse
transformation is done so the important
thing here is that to the sender and the
receiver of the packet they do not know
this is happening it's transparent to
them so in that regard it's kind of has
the place of encapsulation it has the
same function out or at least a similar
functionality so some of the properties
of ila so as I mentioned it is an
identifier locator split protocol so
location and identity are kind of
separate concepts in the addressing it
performs network transformation it's not
NAT on the basis that transformations
are always paired so unlike NAT whatever
you transform into a locator address
will be reversed transformed to the
original identifier address at some peer
before you its receive the packet
it is completely contained within the
network layer there are there's no parts
of this that affect the transport layer
it's completely agnostic to the
transport protocol so can run with any
of them and it's transparent also to the
endpoints of the network and as I
mentioned it's also transparent to the
network devices themselves in the sense
that if I have a TCP packet that
undergoes an ila transformation it still
looks like a TCP packet it just happens
to have a different address any
stateless mechanism the network ecmp
segment all floats things like that will
not care that it's not actually a the
endpoints address so the scope of ila
there's basically two main parts before
we get into the use cases so the data
plane this describes all of the protocol
processing it does not change the on the
wire protocol it is only changing or
rewriting addresses we do consider
transport layer checksums so when we
modify the destination address for
instance in a packet that in theory
chain or invalidates a transport layer
checksum that's doing a suitor pseudo
header checksum we do want to keep the
checksum correct at all times in order
in order to satisfy say some
intermediate device is actually checking
the checksum so there's relatively easy
mechanism I think it was invented in
routing group was called checksum
neutral
simple idea look it up but it allows us
to keep the checksum valid even after
address transformation also data plane
has a different number of address
encodings when we started we kind of
assumed class 64 64 split so 64-bit
locator 64 bit identifier much like I
LMP over time we've kind of relaxed that
to allow different encodings the control
plane this has a lot to do with the
mapping system there's been discussion
on mapping systems in various groups the
idea of the mapping system is basically
it's a distributed database of
identifiers to locator mapping so this
is the thing that kind of the equivalent
of virtual to physical address mapping
in NV o3 how do you find
the location of the node that you're
looking for so the control plane that
can be managed by standalone protocols
for instance there is a list control
plane that potentially could be used
while with ila also we want to leverage
existing control planes for instance
3gpp has a lot of control plane that we
would also like to use so we want to be
a little flexible a little bit flexible
on the control plane so ila does have
some interesting limitations so first of
all this is ipv6 only we're not going to
try to somehow shoehorn this in ipv4
it's probably not enough goods it is
important to realize it's important to
realize that I la is not extensible in
that and from that point of view it's in
a sense it's anti encapsulation so
whatever we can fit into the bits of the
address in the transformation that's as
much information as we can put into ila
so if you really need encryption or
fancy authentication a whole bunch of
things Iowa may not be for those use
cases it is designed to be fast
efficient and have minimal minimal
impact on the network and the host
complexity of the data plane so one of
the side effects of it not being
extensible this may push backs some more
complexity in the control plane in order
to keep the data plane kind of very
simple it does not naturally support
multicast this is something we could
talk about as we go forward how to
integrate multicast but most of the use
cases initially really unicast is is the
more compelling thing to look at right
now
ICMP does need consideration the problem
here is if there's an ICMP error in the
network that's generated after a
transformation what's going back to the
host the address in the packet data will
have a locator address that's kind of an
issue because we want to keep keep the
whole thing isolated so the rule need to
be special considerations for ICMP in
order to avoid that sort of leakage so
there are a number of considerations
that have to be considered a lot of
these have to do more with any sort of
technique or scheme to build a large
scalable mo mobile network
it's a scalability security privacy
possibility essentially the four pillars
of a mapping system so in terms of
scalability some things to consider the
number of mappings in the system right
now we have maybe a hundred million
nodes in some network that could be 100
million obviously we want this to scale
with IOT coming onboard in the data
center we're going to be talking about
giving more and more things not just
task but objects addresses so the number
of mappings will need to scale in
addition to the number of mappings we
have to consider the rate of mapping so
everything if we assume everything is
mobile a lot of these things are gonna
be moving around that's gonna require
changes to the mapping system database
what is that rate and how do we absorb
that right kind of related to both of
those a throughput of the data plane
obviously we expect throughputs to go up
packets per second so that we have kind
of feedback into how we extraor at least
the mapping system and the data plane we
consider the the total state in the
mapping system how that's managed so the
protocols that you use to manage the
state those have to be scale of one
themselves and then one of the trickier
things actually will be caches and this
is a little controversial because we
know caches are inherently in some sense
they can be dust and things like that so
there's obviously a lot of history with
caches so we need we do need special
consideration if we need a cache in
order to scale say the number of
mappings or to get the latency down we
won't need considerations for that I'm
particularly concerned for instance in a
public network what are the dosing
thoughts mitigations on a cache system
so security
spec's mapping system contains
personally identify identifiable
information locators may contain
geophysical location so they need to be
hidden identity IP addresses could be
mapped to devices and devices in the
case of personal devices mapped to user
so this becomes personally identifiable
information so the mapping system needs
to be secure secure protocols we need to
limit the visibility the data I tend to
think this kind of precludes having one
gigantic global mapping database for the
whole world and of course we need to
consider law enforcement considerations
what are their requirements that has to
be part of the mapping system security
considerations inter-domain solutions
this is obviously a whole nother ball of
wax when you consider what happens
within domain we can fairly control that
but if you want to have two domains
speaking a protocol like this the
requirements is a security between them
become very interesting so those are
considerations I'm not saying that we
necessarily have solutions or have to
have all these solutions but in the
mapping system these will come up in
discussion privacy as I mentioned this
can be viewed as can we help privacy
like with identifier locator ila and I
mentioned that a to talk about privacy
and addressing on in an Ariane
on Tuesday so you may want to look at
that draft fundamentally at giving us
last 64 to a device that prefix that you
give that device becomes an identifier
for that device so there are security
potential privacy issues with that
privacy quickly becomes a balance
between scalability so in a perfect
world world if you want a perfect
privacy everybody would always use a
different address for every flow that's
obviously a scaling issue so there's
gonna be some interesting discussion and
trade-offs potentially their locator
privacy as I mentioned locator say in a
mobile network may actually indicate
physical location if that's like the
locator refers to and then you know B or
something to that
so this is another tricky thing how do
we prevent locators from revealing
identity to third parties doubts ability
I mentioned and so I think this is going
to have a lot to do with the mapping
cache if we have a cache in a public
network it will be target of attack
especially if it's being driven by third
party activities so this is one thing we
need to do my recommendation is to have
qualitative quantitative explanations of
why a dust mitigation works and
hopefully that that kind of narrows down
some of the issues so I will cover the
virtualization in data center use case
kalyana will go a lot more into the
mobile use case which is kind of primary
focus for this exercise but as I
mentioned for data center virtualization
the concept here is initially we wanted
to have every task in the data center
every unit of execution have its own IP
address there were several reasons for
that
one of those was we want a seamless
container migrate migration and that
would allow it but eventually everything
gets its own IP address one of the
critical things in that environment is
if we introduce this concept everything
having its own address that mechanism to
do that has to really be performant
applications really don't care if
infrastructure is changing for instance
infrastructures benefit so this is the
give the network more malleability but
applications already running with a
certain performance they don't want to
see a degradation so ila had that aspect
from the beginning that in that model
performance has to be really tight so we
have tight bound on performance
expectations network virtualization is
kind of similar I did present ila in nvo
3 a couple of times it does have some
different aspects because of the
performance may not be balanced may not
be so tight but there is aspects of
tenant isolation so we need ila to make
sure that it can convey tenant IDs
within the addresses there's also an
interesting application in ila using
ipv4 to ipv6 address translation where
we can allow say VMs or tenants to
contact
common data center tasks without using
that what's kind of a benefit so with
that I will turn it over to Kelly Ani
who will go into the mobile use case one
clarification question and before you
step away it's a clarification feel free
yeah the sister you did not go in to
identify her assignment which presumably
would be an issue at scale so I was
wondering what if that aspect had been
considered how identifiers are assigned
to either processes or own systems or
whatever because that's oh yeah that's
like clearly they need to be unique and
that B to me sounds like an large
administrative problem that needs to be
considered that's why I'm asking
yeah yes it is if you look at the ILA
protocol graphing the appendix we gave
some mechanisms to do that we actually
implemented something clever in the data
center we actually use a combination of
a timestamp and a registry number the
nice thing about ipv6 address is even if
you split them into 64 bits you still
get a big chunk to work with so the
identifier fits into 64 bits there's
quite a bit of flexibility to do there
I'm hoping we don't have to do anything
like duplicate address detection however
you would you would get that in the
mapping system kind of for fruit but it
is an issue yeah okay thank you
clarify clarifying question or comment
so I assume that you want
interoperability with kernel tv6 but you
didn't explicitly say that all right one
end can speak er la the other one speaks
for current our users yes but to to to
the rest of the world there shouldn't be
any difference right so for instance on
the internet somebody may actually have
an address that's going to be
transformed in a provider network but
they don't know it's stolen ipv6 address
[Music]
to change the battery link see this is
okay by samhita is trying to PDF version
the mobility use case is the one that I
will be describing we have had a lot of
conversations with several other
operators as well and I would like to
thank my colleagues within Verizon who
participate actively in 3gpp for
explaining the 5 g 5g system
architecture on the ranch side on the
services side on the services based
architecture side and the variants over
there and I also thank my transport side
because this use of ila for mobility
management which has two kinds of
architectures here one is a 3gpp mobile
core overlay as well as trying to try it
with the transport network that we have
underneath that so it was very important
for us to go through all of those in
order to see if this would work for us
Assam use case what I will cover is a
use case and why ila and how does the I
live fit into the 5g architecture anchor
less mobility is a topic that constantly
comes up so I'll try and explain
something and then maybe there is a
recommendation for the way forward the
use case is really looking at the
release 15 core architecture that 3gpp
has specified and this is using the
services based architecture as you can
see the top part of the diagram shows
the control plane functions and the
lower part of it shows the user plane
functions mobility management is there
on the radio side the left side you can
see the radio access network in AMF
those remain the same the focus of where
ila would fit in is on the core network
side the mobility management in the core
network that is depicted by the session
management
action and they use a brain function in
the middle that is blocked over there
why I lay one of the reasons I'll is
attractive is because it does not have
any encapsulation and there is the
promise of elimination of kernels and
why is it important for us to not have
encapsulation and tunneling is if the
packet is a 15 by type II packet 50 byte
overhead is not initial three percent
you can go ahead with that but if the
packet is a small packet size of hundred
bytes if you have an overhead of 50
bytes that that is significant and if
the overhead is reduced what does it
mean to us it means that there will be
requirement of radius backhaul capacity
and as we go into the 5g networks the
network densification is happening and
this means that we will have antennas
covering smaller and smaller areas very
distributed into the areas and we need
to have backhaul capacity that gets us
to the services and the control plane
functions as well as getting to the
internet and other applications so
reduce backhaul capacity helps us in the
5g network in operations as well the
second reason for ila is it promises i
anchor less mobility the current file g3
architecture uses the anchor point in a
way that makes it difficult for us to
offload traffic locally to support
education where we are trying to get to
the low latency applications we will
need to have a separate anchor point
closer to the radio access network or
some time since in the cell site in
order to make something like the 1
millisecond latency so having anchor
less mobility helps in simplifying the
network and it also reduces the state
information and this goes to the Third
Point when we have no encapsulation if 1
millisecond is a requirement on the
radio exercise they are trying to get
rid of many say microseconds and so on
and so forth but once we hit the packet
side we are having so many other
network functions and conversions and
encapsulations which does not help in
the low latency application so there's
reduced packet processing and no
additional network functions comes by
the fact that ila can be provided in the
Linux kernel and if we do it right the
you know DRG node B can be implemented
on that and that would help us get rid
of some network functions at the edge
this is the protocol stack diagram from
3gpp the bottom right the shows how the
encapsulation works there is the gtp and
all that stuff what ila promises is that
you can remove the encapsulation the
backhaul that I mentioned in the
previous slide is the entry interface
over there and the anchor point part
comes into picture when you see the two
ups in the diagram when you have to
offload locally the second UPF is placed
alongside the access now access to
network and you will also need to
support some anchor point over there in
order to support mobility then here is a
proposal architecture that we are
targeting for release 16 we took the
3gpp services based architecture what we
show here is the ILA mapping system
aisle in Odin ila are are connected to
the services based architecture and the
rest of the system remains the same and
what the proposal here is to have ila as
a network slice for some of the
applications that do need the reduce do
need the high performance benefits the
ila can be used if there are things that
need to go back to the gtp based slice
we can do that so the premise is ila
would be used as a slice in the whole
system and the gold-plated gtp based
high reliable system can continue to be
used for voice over I am as for roaming
and things like that the proposal here
is to have the control brain
interactions using restful api is
3gpp has done a lot of work or is
continuing to do a lot of work in
defining the services based architecture
for all these network functions that are
defined there and the ILA node and I lar
and I am the proposal is to do it in the
same format as that and this
architecture allows flexible
implementation and deployment options
which means there are some F and I am
could possibly be implemented alongside
the SML file Ian and I lar could be
implemented together and so on so forth
and so I will reuse a lot of what is
used in the networks today roaming one
quick clarifying question so in this the
way you are using oil in this mode
Kalyan you are not removing the anchor
right
ila R is still your anchor point correct
no I will get to that in the next slide
okay just one other clarification from
the previous slide where you show the
stacks yeah
in the PD you layer is there an IP
header the PD as defined in 3gpp can be
an IP packet it can be an Ethernet
packet it could be an unstructured
packet so this is IP and ila for a
normal ipv4 or ipv6 PDU session yeah G 6
only it's ipv6 no it's IP in ila the IP
packets could be anything could be
anything so when they say they are
dispensing with the encapsulation what
is being dispensed with is UDP and gtp
you to be clear the payload will be so
it would be put into the IP layer that
would then be try transformed XD UPF so
it's not so the packet have to start
with an ipv6 address so you can
transform it yes so it's got to be an
ipv6 packet behold the user packet is an
ipv6 packet they're dispensing with the
UDP and gtp overhead above the ipv6
packet no there
substrate here otherwise we'd be
encapsulating and Tom doesn't want
encapsulation okay so so this is why I
wanted to put ila in parentheses here
it's not actually a layer it is in this
picture
I guess the PD you would actually be the
IP at IP header from the user that's
what we're modifying so when say the say
we're sending in a packet to the end and
host it comes into the network as an
ipv6 packet we modify the destination
address traverses the network at a point
close to the the end host it gets
reversed transform there is no
encapsulation that also uese originates
er prefixes yes but they don't know that
all they know is they have an IP address
the IP address is assigned to you ease
use sir prefixes it's probably a better
way of putting and we do want to mode
where we can do a / 64 assignment also
okay so that high Irishman thief so one
question is even that we will have
always at the beginning at least a
mixture of ipv4 and I pay me for and
ipv6 mix at the beginning is there any
into working plan in the oil
okay so that's what thank you my name is
Margaret Colin from painless security I
used to be Margaret Wasserman I actually
wrote the NPT v6 draft with them Fred
Baker that uses the same I check some
neutral Mac mapping I think originated
it the issue I have a question but I'm
not positive its if it's for you or the
previous presenter but it came up and
looking on this slide
I know it's checks of neutral and that's
great one of the things I'm not
understanding is um I know you passed
the eye lamp stuff so that the other
side knows how to map it back to the
same address what happens in the case of
dynamic routing
or asynchronous communication and how
does it how does it handle using this
you don't getting the same address give
me one second I will go to that slide
let me finish this one I'll go to the
next slide and oh is it on the next so
yeah okay all right thank you okay so
what I have in the bottom part of this
slide is that for roaming we can reuse
the 3gpp principles because this is no
different then whatever the services
based architecture shows however there
will be some topology hiding things and
other kinds of aspects 3gpp has worked
with multiple mobility management
protocols in the past we may penci TP
and so on and so forth this is no
different if one Operator suppose one
mobility protocol and the other one
supports anything the common ones will
still be gtp and so those kinds of
principles can be reused security and
privacy today's mobile operator network
we have the same kind of issues that we
have to saw we have addressed and those
principles will be reused here regarding
scalability mapping and control plane
signaling again the network design
aspects from the fro G networks will be
used there if we have to deal with
trying to redirect the packet to the to
another location because a ue node there
are principles in the MM e to the e node
B how that takes care of there is an x2
interface similarly as you w2e not B we
will try to use the same principles for
the ILA nodes that will be used to
closer to the radio access network and
here is the bus like that talks that I'm
trying to depict the anchor less
mobility but it also tells you how the
operator network is designed so on the
left side you see the radio access
network and that's where you have all
the air interface but then you convert
it into the IP packet and then you try
to get it to the other side onto the
internet so this one is a very managed
to domain on the right side between the
internet and the
mobile core we do have the traditional
IP MPLS network in there so we have the
Peter two-speed outers and the choke
routers everything in there so the IAR
will be behind that one and what we have
on the radio access side in the past we
could not see the IP packet till we hit
the point where we are connecting to the
internet so it is a tunneled one but in
the low latency cases if you want to
break it out we had to bring the the
current architecture suggest that we
bring the Gateway down to the inaud be a
scaled-down version but this one allows
us to see the native IP packet as soon
as we get it out of the radio access
network so I try to show one of the flow
of the top flow is showing when you go
into the internet or UE request
something from the Internet when the
response comes back the packet has to go
to the place where the UE
is so it looks up the mapping table in
the il layer and then it directs it to
the place where the UE is located the
second one is UA to you via
communication and that one uses the
caching in the hi la nodes you don't
have to go back to the highway or the
anchor point and then come back in so
the iarge will really be located at our
peering points and that's how if I
understand correctly you're going you do
the transform at one edge and then if it
hits another transformer at the other
edge that one will have been informed
but it's conceivable that there's
traffic out on the internet that doesn't
hit another transformer and that's just
effective lean added then at that I
believe Margaret yeah I I think there's
an issue there worth exploring but I
wouldn't call that a clarification I
wouldn't let her get through one more
slide in how it works which I thought
was a clarification but okay I have
hypotheses but I think it's a good it's
a question but I need to let her get
through and we're running out of time we
would like to do is our focus is
mobility use case so we would suggest
that the ILS specifications even though
there are three use cases that take the
specifications we done in a phased
approach focus on of the mobility use
case and the deliverables that would
have to be done is do the ila Cole
protocol and we need some reference
control plane protocol that can be used
to develop the api's necessary to
connect the so to the services based
architecture and the architectural
considerations for the mobility use case
like what we talked about user switched
did you have a clarifying question on
this material yeah your name first -
national comment and you proposed the
solution can tests of the issue of the
mobility issue in the faculty but the
your part for another issue is not
considered for the Q s investments now
in the faculty we use the cure for I ID
in each CPU header for identify which
case follow this pathway belongs to in
such case the green cell and the anchor
I can decide how to do the suggesting a
sliced architecture this is not a
replacement of gtp for the whole
architecture so for specific application
specific needs that is the slice that
yeah I know it's inside you've such
solutions you use them may be only t4
occurs or some difficulty used if if we
did some enhance deepen a kiss for
Tiffin an IP flow then this this
solution maybe need a more consideration
and study okay questions so we have
tried to prepare some questions to shape
the discussion here on what do we need
and as soon as meter can get those up
for us thank you very much yeah there
the discussion at this point and Tom and
Kalyani are staying available because
they really can answer most of the
questions that are if you don't
understand these but the things I will
try at the very end to find out from
folks is do you understand the problem
space they're trying to address if not
ask questions about that do you
understand the intended scope if not ask
questions about that are there issues
that you think any further work on this
will need to address if so bring those
up so we get the minuted so we can keep
those in mind as we explored how do we
want to take it forward and similarly
did you understand the use cases if not
ask about that okay and it looks like we
have one from the Jabbar so evangelist
described a decline asks how does this
suppose you is getting / 60 force
allocated to them the supported you 'yes
yes selects a 64 allocation that's a
very good question let's remember the
part where I said that we had to relax
on the canonical 64 64 split the
solution for / 64 assignment is to use
an encoding in the upper 64 bits that
both encodes a locator and identifier
there is a level of indirection at the
locator node that we have that is
described in the ILA protocol draft I
believe so the question from the room
was how much does that cost I forget the
exact encoding but the idea was the
identifier is not global it really is an
index and they locator specific table so
depending on how many users you need say
in that particularly note that would
have to do with the size of that table
so I think we wanted 20 bits for that
plus some number of bits for the network
prefix it seems to work out so to take a
look at the the drafter I don't remember
the specifics but there is there is an
algorithm described there okay next
okay data on Ericsson tea I guess the
Keith's concern I would have is I
understand some of the problems ila is
designed to solve but I have not seen an
elucidation of the full set of require
for each of the use cases it is proposed
to address and until I see that and can
understand that mapping then I'm not
prepared to say that I fully understand
the problem space at ila is attended to
address in all of the applications it's
proposed to address okay so you want to
comment
yeah suresh krisshnan so Eddie all right
so the thing is to see if these problems
are real and there's like a community
willing to solve the problem right like
ila may or may not fit as a solution
like we don't know that so let's do the
first step this is not a working group
forming Boff just to see like you know
if people agree there's a problem
like what solving and then the province
can go and work at not the past at this
okay take on that yeah this is a
solution that would fit into a 5g
slicing framework is expected to support
the business of mobile broadband etc
there's actually a long list of things I
have not seen and and that does concern
me and I would like to see that before I
went I want to rush off and do this next
person please state your name please
Mason like that from University of Essex
I can understand the use cases you're
trying to address I'm not sure how
you're gonna do that if you don't
support multicast and you don't know how
to do any cost well so it's not that we
don't support multicast it's that we
haven't fully expected out there is an
encoding that does support multicast
right um so it could be support but as
Kalyani said it's like also saying we
don't support ipv4 but yeah that can
still exist in the same network right so
I think that would go under the the
requirements for that specific use case
right so what are the requirements for
that you exceed and it also depends on
whether you you have to support
multicast in this exact mode so you can
also say well you're using native
multicast anyway that already works so
how do you deal with with multicast so
it may actually be a slightly different
problem that's being targeted to but I
do agree as as a whole solution yes we
have to consider multicast so my
statement was native multicast is
interesting because it's the source
address that routes the packet and
for identifiers located were change in
the destination we would have to think
of it makes sense to actually transform
yes for said dresses my my feeling is
that's a lot of complexity but that
would be that would be something to look
at you do appreciate obviously the
importance of it yes okay is that the
same for any caste as on because you are
saying that caching is not as
straightforward it's a bit rate so any
caste is a little bit different because
I think in a sense this does support any
caste because you're directing the
packet to the specific specific node so
from that point of view it actually is
it's pretty good at any caste I'm doing
I can do the mapping and then instead of
doing encapsulation to get it to an any
caste node I can just do ila and that's
like no encapsulation overhead so from
that point of you would actually work
well and I believe that's one of the use
cases that that Facebook act is actually
deploying right now is any cast with ila
um
given the length of the line make your
answers shorter let's see I think the
problems faces is kind of varied I think
is a great fit in the data center but
there's a lot of things that are being
proposed here so I guess I'm really
unclear about the about the scope I
don't know you know because there's a
lot of problems that intend to be solved
and also can you go back to the slide
where we talked to the Internet no
unfortunately we cannot easily go back
to the other all right but that slide
doesn't work
all right there's like basically
insoluble scaling problems we've had
we've had conversations on the on the
five gang IP list and my assessment is
at three it's three orders of magnitude
away from the technology that we have
today in terms of memory bandwidth in
readers and forwarding table size so if
if that's the use case I think Kalyan is
prepare is proposing that we start with
that use case but I don't think it can
actually be made to work and so that's
that's sort of an important
consideration I had conversations with
my Transport colleague he's actually
sitting over there and we talked about
it so we do have the I understand what
you're saying for the facing to the
internet kind of a thing so
are the routers that are over there that
deal with that this one is towards the
access network side and we do not have
the you per user kind of router
advertisement going over there and then
we there are also the new kind of
routers where you can go to tables that
are 80 million and so on so forth even
if you let me paraphrase his concern I
don't believe the documents have
described a workable way it may well be
possible to make it work
but at the very least I don't think the
documents have captured a workable way
and it's important for taking things
forward that people actually be able to
look at common descriptions that's a
subset of my concerns yes I would
challenge anyone to make it work but yes
the documents it is a fact that the
documents do not describe how to make
this work yes but but it's important
before we decide to say we're gonna
start with this and make this the
primary use case like I said I
personally don't think we can make it
work this is Dino is inter working part
of the bath questions is that in scope
interworking of what with what a a host
that originates a Sur prefix talks to a
regular ipv6 host is that in scope I'll
sit down if it's not I think it has to
be okay so that means I can ask this
question okay question for Tom if a
surface is a source in a packet and a
destination is not and the packet goes
all the way to an ipv6 host when it
returns it's going to come back to the
locator address in the destination how
does the Isle a node know to translate
the destination address to surf prefix
and not the source because it only so in
that unicast model it's only ever
translate translating the destination on
the outbound path the source address is
not touched the source on the outbound
path the source addresses are address no
no you're not understanding on the
outbound path that is it is translated
because it's a surprise and you know if
it's a surprise
it must be translated the destination is
not but it's in the source address on
the outbound path you said I think
there's a lack of clarity on whether the
source or the desk is being translated
and in different directions you need
different translations I know that's the
only one that needs to be transformed
but how do you know that you have to
keep state well because the
nations clear in the packet okay we can
talk offline on that yeah I think again
it's something I think that one actually
you guys have an answer that's clear but
it's hard to extract it
okay that's question one ZTE and
actually I understand the problem and
escape and the issues the IAE is
designed to address as my understand is
the end is pretty much the same scope of
ICN so I my question is what the exact
difference between i io a and i sayin
trial a and what i couldn't i see in
from information centric network um
ICM works at HTTP header level that's
very different
let's move on to the next question i
really that's that's very different
we won't debate what problems they solve
remember we said at the beginning we're
not comparing with other solutions hi
Tony Lee Arista networks um so what
you're trying to do here is to change
the fundamental architecture of the host
and yet you're not changing the
fundamental architecture of the network
what are you gonna end up doing is
you're gonna end up with a mismatch and
you're starting to see that already
because of ICMP this is this is a clear
thing clear indication that you have
prop architecture problem why not just
bite the bullet and make an
architectural change so this is a first
class element in the architecture so but
I guess the question is what is the
architectural problem right so so if you
consider the 5g use case and I think
Kelly Ani articulated that the
architecture architecture problem is say
we want anchor less mobility how do you
how do you solve that problem and that's
where that's where the architecture
answer starts to come and I can also I
can also mention so if you look at the
data center use case it was it was
pretty clear the architecture is
for mobility was fundamentally pretty
simple we need to know where someone is
we know how to get the packets to them
as quickly as possible and they can move
around so in the mobile use case in data
center was very clear and I think
there's a lot of analogs in the mobile
use case so what we don't want to do it
it would be nice if we didn't have to
change the architecture completely but
we do want to evolve it at least to
handle as I said seamless mobility
highly efficient get those low latency
applications well that would be fine but
remember that what you're doing is
really fundamental more fundamental than
just dealing with the 5g problem right
you're trying to deal with multihoming
all mobility regardless of media you're
trying to truly separate the locator
from the address
throughout the stack well I mean
throughout this stack is it's kind of
limited right this is a network layer
protocol it also can be incrementally
implemented and I would argue it's it's
actually simpler than say we wanted to
introduce a new encapsulation because
there's a lot fewer moving parts to it
right and we're not comparing
alternatives but I don't
ok let's move quickly because I do want
to have a few minutes to take a home of
what people understood at least in the
room I'm not expecting resolution but I
but I do want to let the three people on
the line ask and yeah Maya IAB Shepard
gets to tail it I am I think I do
understand both the general problem
space and and the two use cases that
you're suggest well I can't say I
understand everything about the 5g one
but I think I understand the two use
cases that you're talking about and I
think I understand what your intended
scope is yes one of the things I'm
unclear on is pictures where this goes
out on the internet I think you're gonna
run into problems I wrote a similar I
started to write a very similar draft in
2008 it's called draft Wasserman Ram
trip and that draft used the same
mechanism and it tried to solve this
problem but I ran into intractable
problems that I don't see that you solve
one of them was ICMP one of them was
what happens when you have dynamic
routing the other was around nodes out
there that
don't have a translator and how you know
how they perceive one of the problems is
that you don't have the zones you say
you have in your draft you don't have
where an identity space zone and we're
in global zone you have we're in
identity space for my addresses and
global for everyone else all global and
identity space for somebody else's
addresses and global for everyone else
including the other end of the
connection and that has some some
ramifications that aren't really
captured at your drafts and I would love
to work with you on this if there's a
question about how to get how to make
sure you're hitting a trend transformer
the locator itself is an address of a
note so when you the packet has to route
to that note what you can't route
anywhere else because you're overriding
that with basically prefix that says
that's that's the note ICMP problem with
how do you find the transformer right I
mean which is a difference so that's the
mapping system I acknowledge the ICMP
problem ICMP is going to be tricky in
any state I mean imagine we know
tunneling has the same sort of issues
segment rolling has issues with ICMP
ICMP is a pain and the third thing was
about identifier spaces yes I and that
kind of goes back to my statement I
don't believe in the global identifier
space I think identifier is our gonna be
fairly localized which makes this more
like an optimization within within a
single Network I think there may be
opportunities to make inner Internet
work things but let's assume for the for
the beginning that's to be contained in
an administrative domain one identifier
space which is indicated by the upper
like the surra prefix which is the
externally visible prefix yeah and
unless you control the whole thing like
in the data center case you have to get
into the issue of what if this gets
mapped again and that I think it's not
entirely well understood we have some
options there hi um actually I have a
couple of questions so I I do
hi I'm Padma huawei one I do understand
the problem space
because we've discussed this at alliant
and I do see their intended scope I do
have a couple of clarifications you
discuss about privacy which was a big
topic last last a few months ago on the
mapping system I do see you put identity
and this was a big discussion so I'd
like to understand one of the questions
was about long lived identity and here
it looks to me that the solutions
proposed before on actually having the
identity of the skating the real
identifier is this what you're doing or
is this something so identity it's
always a little ambiguous to me but let
me say that we have identifiers which
identify something we can give multiple
identifiers x' to a note and to the
outside world if they see say two
addresses with two different identifiers
they should never be able to tell those
refer to the same note so identity if
identity expresses the who it cannot
specifically the who like that device my
claim is it cannot be in an externally
visible address for privacy you need to
obfuscate that somehow and I think that
is where ideas and things like that we
are on the same page because I think I
think I'm happy to see that because I
think now there's a real understanding
that identity is needed for privacy or
else it's very difficult to achieve
privacy especially if you're keeping
your IP address as one fixed everybody
who look up this so that would be one
and the second thing I wanted to ask was
I see that you're actually having a lot
of similar requirements that we actually
put it in our ideas can you confirm that
or no on the requirements of the mapping
system I would say the mapping system if
you notice we it's almost orthogonal
because it is a generic thing
potentially from any identifier locator
its kind of split through you know I I
don't want to go into that too much that
starts getting into comparing with other
work and we don't have time today we're
already over time okay
okay we can take it offline by generally
agree there are similarities quickly
so tunnel remodel is one of the key
objectives here right and I assume you
want to achieve that by just with the
approach of transformations or des
transformations right so now today if
you look at gtp U or GRE and that we
carry a number of fields right
essentially here the GRE key right and
now within this 128-bit space you need
to put the identifier you need to put
the locator you need to put the cost if
you want to do cost reservation you need
to the DAC will we be able to encode
everything within that 128 bits no
actually you don't even know the 128
bits because provided is given only a
part of this block right mobility use
case we are looking at it as a managed
domain within an operator network and
it's some cases there may be some hops
in there but most of the time it is like
trying to get everything from the
antenna or the radios to the one of the
centers where we can make it in convert
it into the packets so we are not taking
everything that has to have all the
advanced features that gtp or even but
somebody else was mentioning before this
is for a particular slice that is simple
enough that we can put some IOT traffic
or where we do not need all those
advanced features in there so most of
those features will not be supported or
cannot be some Eric not Mike just a
quick comment I don't think I need to
respond to this but you just want to
make sure it's on the list of things to
consider is yeah if you care about doing
ingress filtering inside the network
maybe you need to some additional
awareness that we have this si RS as
well as regular prefixes so something
dad to the list to go look at so you're
referring to
we have filtering within the network
that has to be prepared to handle both
types of addresses
yeah ingress matter that would be a
consideration okay we're now going to
okay surrett I was going to take the
hums and then let you have the final
word these are going to be I have to be
quick - I would like a hum of those
people who think they understood the
problem space that was described
a goodly number of humps those people
who think they did not feel they did not
it's not a question thing if you didn't
understand the problem space please hum
wonderful thank you okay
did people understand the scoping that
was laid out please hum if you did
understand the scoping not as many
please hum if you didn't understand the
scoping I'm noticeable hum
I'm restating this of the room I can get
these in the minutes um we've dealt with
other issues that need to be addressed
I'm not gonna go into the use cases
Suresh you get the final word okay
suresh krisshnan so the idea was to like
get the proponents to understand like
the scope of things they need to do in
case they come back here with like a
better proposal and I really encourage
people here to sign up on the mailing
list and send any concerns that you have
because I know you have a lot of
concerns looking at like the questions
that came in there's like still people
who have issues understanding like how
this is gonna work
so please send the comments on the list
because the the problems requested like
an hour for above and I granted the hour
but maybe we can certainly use more time
but we don't have the time today so send
everything on the list and we can flush
it out and and get the things out
because like the problems really would
like the feedback and they are willing
to work make this better so and then we
can actually have a discussion on like
whether we want to solve this issue but
like I was like really happy to hear
like a positive hum for the first one so
that's that's like a big step in this
direction so please contribute on this
like the email list is ila at idea of
their arc so it's not like difficult to
remember so just sign up and send
comments in thank you thanks for staying
extra I need the other blue sheet back
okay wonderful can you take care of
delivering the blue sheets thank you