hello everyone welcome to the interior
ietf 101 so we're gonna get started we
have a busy agenda this time so first of
all not well I guess you've heard that
there's a there's a new not well so
please take a look at it especially
there is a privacy policy at the end
that we encourage you guys to take a
look that is a new addition to the node
well all the rest pretty much the same
as I said used some reminders minutes
are taken minutes are the meeting is
recorded your presence will be locked
and we scribe please help contribute
online to the minutes we have the
etherpad
can we get some help from minute taker
yeah okay so thank you very much Ian for
helping but please do help um whenever
you can to get more notes or to clarify
your points if you see them jabber do
you have do we have someone that can
help us with the Java please thank you
thank you
perfect so moving down to the agenda now
we're going to give you guys a quick
update from all the chairs in the ad on
document status and some other topics
then we have the presentation from Eric
on the PVD IP tunnels quick update from
mark if he's around then we have a gooey
generic UDP encapsulation from tom some
presentation about iLab there something
there's going to be the debuff that we
also have our quick heads up here that's
going to be presented then we we have
the presentation about the privacy
network address
from Tom as well IP fragmentation from
Ron toxics from Vladimir and
availability of information in criminal
investigations from David sorry
here this okay could we increase the
volume thank you very much yeah
all right so moving down to this working
group status update so the privacy
considerations for i3 broadcast
multicast protocols it's now in the RFC
editors q re just a quick answer to the
to the jabber we did receive the slides
from the presenters their remote
presenters as well so privacy
considerations for IP broadcast and now
it's an RFC editors queue so hopefully
soon will become an IRC GUI we have the
presentation from that working group
draft the IP over internationally
partially partitioned links and that's a
trap type expired and we encourage
people to take a look for please if you
if you have interest in this topic send
comments make a review that would be
very useful for the author right now the
the draft is stalled because we haven't
had any any update on it and but we do
need the community feedback if we want
to advance that topic so please take a
look at that one probe nights now RFC
8335 so thank you very much
congratulations there and IP tunnels in
the internet architecture we'll get a
presentation so moving to the
announcements is Suresh in the room yeah
thanks isis krishnan area to do so we
had a like discussion in the iesg so one
of the documents that it came in through
the independent stream and it was trying
to update like are actually change
staying
and document that was done here which is
the recommendations for logging with
ports so what we did in the IES G is
like sent a note saying like don't
publish this because it needs to be done
in interior because we published the
original document so that's the last
document on the list over there the
draft divorce eg and logging so this
like personally me I spoke to the author
and he was willing to present remotely
the document and daddy has to see is the
recommendations like in the RFC's he's
talking about is like whether it's
practical and how he can actually go
about logging the boats properly based
on like what's in the servers and
everything so there's like this one
contains like a inventory of what's in
the servers and what's being done what's
not being done and some techniques in
there so I would really appreciate if
you pay attention to it and see like you
know how we can update our PCB thanks
yep so so we'll make sure that we leave
enough room in the agenda for that
presentation at the end so Suresh said
that is the the one on availability of
information in criminal investigations
involving large-scale IP address sharing
technologies all right so any bashing to
the agenda hearing none I guess we can
move to Eric please
by being here okay anyway so compared to
what happens last time we got a big big
news and we can show the next slide if
you don't know remember can the
discussion whether we can get already
anionic code point basically for the
option we have now so thank you to the
chair and Suresh I don't know s Eurasia
disappear so thank you for this it
allows us to make a multiple
implementation of sending this array
option and receiving this array option
to be compatible there and make more
tests we use this number 21 and I think
you know it's a fan answer with 21 but
at least we got the number it's late
right - answer 41 anymore anyway it's
like a guide is obviously not read in
this room anyway
so we use this number for di cottan on
this weekend next slide other change so
we make the things clear there were a
lot of section regarding using the PVD
additional information remember it is
the G is on file that we are fetching to
describe and the connection based on the
bandwidth of latency for instance we
completely remove this from the text I
think it's still valuable to F to use
the PVD JSON file to convey some
transport level information but for this
draft we remove it if we arm no interest
later let's plant for another draft and
maybe another document there thanks to
Bob the document was a little bit fuzzy
indeed whether it was for the network
layer or the application layer for the
author it was obvious that the JSON file
that we fashioned after the array is for
the application but it was not in the
text so we make it clear that this
additional information is for the
application we even think to change the
name into additional application
information to make it very crystal
clear we try to improve the security and
privacy section of course mostly we can
maybe improve it we made a mistake in
doing the padding you know all the
options in
our ASO actually in any neighbor
discovery message must be aligned on 8
bytes and we basically at the previous
one aligning on the four bytes so easy
to fix last time in Singapore there was
a huge amount of discussion about all
can we send different information to PVD
aware host and non PVD aware both so the
authors we got a design meeting in a
nice room in Singapore we considered as
an option such as using another specific
multicast group to send this array to
PVD away only at this weekend of dirty
and a few other one so we end up in an
idea not new code container next slide
you don't mind so that's the new option
and you see them in this option we can
add at the bottom additional option like
Pio array of a row deformation option
prefix information option a with other
options that can validly exist into a
route advertisement can be included into
the PVD option as we need as well
sometimes to include options like MTU
which are not per se an option but our
feeling to the array header itself we
have the option based on the bid a to
include yes or no a repetition of the
routing advertisement header so we can
add their next slide so example look
about this one this is the PVD ID option
it includes at the bottom two other
option this Rd at the NSS and the PIO
all of them makes for quiz 5 bytes but 4
plus 5 times 8 bytes the ID and the
header with example dot orc there makes
as well 2 bytes by 2 times 8 or 10 so
the full length is 12
okay actually I counted at least three
used it to make 12 so now we put 12 in
the lines there meaning next slide a PVD
aware understand deception no he is a
duty to look inside the option and now
you know that okay the a flag is not set
so after the name and the padding and we
know the name is finished because they
are lengths right is the fully qualified
domain name is expressed as a DNS
request name we have another option
which is our DNS s we got the length of
this one we go to the next one and so on
so for p video where they will see not
only the PVD ID it is used to bundle all
information together and present it to
the application but we they also got
this our DN SS and the PIO next slide
and non PVD aware do not understand the
type xxi that we just receive so they
say okay I skip it and the length is 12
so I'm going to the option which is
after so with this we can present Pio
aardeen SS or whatever you want to PVD
away oast while the options outside of
the container as simply use only by non
p video a host of course an array can
only contain if you want just the PVD ID
option okay that's not a problem
next line implementation status
nothing has changed compared to
Singapore we make progress on Nanak's
obviously next line and the hackathon as
I said we work together with two
universities relation Aberdeen got some
people from Cisco but Kyle is well from
San vine and another University three I
forget wenching from three Campari Tech
and basically it was the mix of pvd's or
9x a neat which is in another taps
project source address dependent routing
because we like this and Cal port it was
done by acharya
next
so it has really all the piece we touch
and all those piece were using the new
ini code next so we are not ready
room class cold for sure even if
the implementation exists and we are
working for this for more than a year
now but I would love to get a service
review by this group as well as I will
ask later to six men and v6 ops so
review are really important
I mean modern mp3 apply two questions of
course here and ring the week but you
can't commit to review this document and
it changed any volunteer okay done Ted
Michael and Yin I don't know who's
taking notes but you can put this into
our thank you don't forget to put your
name right and for me that's it that's
all I have to say today and thanks again
for your support for Unicode okay I have
a skip it is to know this okay
if you want okay I prepare some slide is
a backup in case I got the question
right so go on next so we provide into
the JSON file some information right and
we use a specific well-known URL so if
you know the name of the company you can
mostly guess the fully qualified domain
name and guess the URL it's well known
right as on purpose so you could
download from everywhere this JSON file
so my advice is that don't put anything
confidential here right because anyone
can igneel access and you can also
restrict the access on the web server
hosting this JSON file to addresses that
belongs to you okay working for Cisco I
will accept only request from prefixes
allocated to Cisco not to say another
company that's one aspect next now even
if we provide a PVD ID it could be
something like example.org
or whatever it's just information right
we don't provide anything more anyway
than array but think about a rock DVD I
don't know what it was really useful to
do as Montana Tech but we can F as I
said the black ed we can have the JSON
file server can be a black hat guy the
network can be of style and the first
device can be also hostile so they can
basically send you rogue route
advertisement if a fake DVD ID or they
can deliver to you a fake JSON file with
wrong information
so that's all we try to do it now next
so first one I am layer two adjacent and
I want to send you a packet pretending a
you are connected to cooperate comma a
regard block it right there's no more
dangerous than anything so problem solve
as long as you run a decent network next
slide so now in this case the router is
a bad guy so you I not spot somewhere
and the spot somewhere pretends to be
again cooperate or in this case good
calm so what you do you try to connect
to the JSON 5 server and this guy is a
wrong one as well right they affect you
DNS and they figure the certificate oh
but you cannot affect a certificate
right so when you try and download the
JSON file
TLS will refuse to connect and if you
have a look at configuration on the end
point telling a I only accept PVD that
retries the fetch of this JSON file
remember that's an option but if you are
configured to download this file and you
cannot get it because the TLS session is
not established because the certificate
is even valid cell sign or whatever you
refuse and you reject this PVD next so
now another one where again you are in
hot spot pretends to be good calm
this time it does not pretend to be the
JSON file server as well so you can
connect with a real SSL or TLS session
and don't know the JSON file now the
thing we have in the JSON file a
mandatory field key which is prefix
which is basically in this case vb8
beef I forget to put a slash for TX or
in the slide now when you receive it you
need to compare this covering prefix
from the JSON file with the prefixes you
receive as API or in this case the Pio
was including bed / 64 bed / 64 is not
including in B / 48 will reject it okay
so you need to deliver not only the
write JSON file but we need to deliver
the right Pio oh I'm a bad guy I am
allowed to do not next right so now I am
sending okay no not spot I am sending
you the array good calm okay
the flag is still there now I'm using
the right basically v6 address right Pio
I'm fetching the file JSON file and
indeed it would match right because
there is the route in the middle is
doing NPT and nothing between the real
good traffic's beef and the bed that is
used by the attacker in this case the
protection is very simple again pretty
much like the confidentiality the server
will only serve the JSON file to its own
address and the request after being
knighted or NPDES is coming from bed so
it drops the request it doesn't receive
the JSON file and again I'm configured
to use only if there is a JSON file I
don't get it
I refuse to use this PVD next now we
find a place and it's actually PA within
the room we find this which is can
intricate right we can fool everything
nothing is
really secured 100% what do we have now
we have a bad guy bottom left which
managed to get access to the real
network so his access in the beef
Network okay and you know that the PVD
is good calm now with a companion
somewhere and the victim is on the top
left the next router is sending a
sending PVD the name is good calm and
please use the address beef as well
remember the big arrow Janel whatever
you want is tuna right GRE or whatever
now the victim somewhere on the top left
receive oh is good calm let's do it
let's connect to the server and then
this is the small line going via the
dinner that's rotting decision proxy by
the bad guy in the good comm network
that goes to the server the server sees
a good sauce address is surveyed and to
NSSL works fine right because the right
certificate right address and then in
this case the attacker is able to
pretend is good calm but on your
honestly is already in good calm so what
can you do there right so basically in
this case we can do nothing more but we
never pretend to be a fully secure right
PVD are here not to secure erase PVD
sorry to give you more information and
the application layer and nothing is the
last 100 yes sorry privacy so obviously
there is some minor issue is that when
the goose boat would arrest even a PVD
a wants to get information about it it
will basically go and fish the error
right access your elevator LS so anybody
on the path can know that this v6
address is trying to connect to this DVD
right it is thus nice in the clear
you can even know who is there
okay but what's different than all our
device run now here going to captive
that example.com or whatever your
operating system use right now to detect
there is a captive Potter it's even
better because normally when here all of
us in the room except some exception
right we do not go to our own
cooperation to see what there is a
captive portal right we go to some other
vendors which is not Python the service
providers or the user what indeed when
you use PVD you stay within one Operator
say or support or whatever that's one
thing and we advise in the draft as well
it as soon as you have used your ipv6
address to fetch this JSON file you
change of a pv6 address and the other
one is no more no more used you throw it
away that's basically our status a
little bit fast explained its little bit
more explanation into the draft all we
can deliver some level of security and
we simply put and say that privacy
nothing is perfect but it's way better
than what we are using right now and I
see now that's the last one okay
question any questions so maybe we have
asked the the security Directorate to
take a look to give us another point of
view okay so hopefully they will provide
some feedback I guess they were swamped
by this he knows this meeting I mean so
not yet but hopefully we'll get some
song external point of view and take a
look at this answers I don't know if
everything is capturing the in the eye
wants to you okay perfect
okay so thank you and thank you for
asking Thanks okay next is mark in the
room No
okay so then I guess we can go to to Tom
hi I'm Tom Herbert I'm gonna give an
update on generic UDP encapsulation so
there's two drafts that we'll talk about
so one is base goo draft that's in
version 5 it is in working group last
call not a lot of comments in the last
call but we did have quite a few pretty
in-depth reviews previously the only
major change to the latest revision goo
version became goo variant so joke touch
had a concern that version implies kind
of precedents for obsolescence of
previous versions so variant gives us a
little more flexibility so it could be
kind of like a canonical version or in
the case version zero version versus
version 1 of goo they're really
different kind of variants version 1
happened to be a very compressed form so
just a couple of possible future updates
so one of the things we may do the C
type field right now if the control bit
is said in one of the goo header this
indicates a control type it occurred to
me that you will encapsulate any IP
protocol but there are things that we
may want to encapsulate in the future
for instance another UDP based protocol
so for instance we could have Lisp over
go a beer over go the reason to do that
is goo kind of provides some general and
capsulation features and capabilities
it's not really about specific use cases
so for instance if you wanted to add
fragmentation of go to something like
list we could do that so it's a possible
thing we could add another thing that
could be pondered as
I'm adding a private data so goo has
this concept of private data within the
header but we never really specified a
format for that conceivably we could add
a flag field that says what the format
is so it could be some sort of tlvs or
additional types of format could be an
embedded alternative protocol so one
possibility the other thing is goo is
udp-based however it's not really
inherent that it has to be in UDP
conceivably we can make it an IP
protocol in itself or Ethernet code
point probably a little easier since it
has a larger space the advantage of that
is would be kind of a common
encapsulation protocol similar to how
GRE operates in those three modes but in
case of goo might be a little more
extendable in the future so the other
draft is go extensions this is in
version 3 again in working group last
call not many comments it has received
some some review the current state is
there are eight extensions defined and
like I mentioned they're really about
encapsulation and an 11 of 16 flag bits
have been allocated so the obvious
problem here is we only have 16 flag
bits so what happens when we run out of
flag bits because we had extensions the
answer to that which is actually on the
next slide the antenna is at the last
bit in the flag field will indicate a
new set of flags as in another field
this was actually an earlier version of
good we removed it because the point was
that our definition of defining Flags we
wanted to find them contiguously so in
the future once we hit the limitation
that's last bit is intended to give us
another set of flag fields and then that
gives us 32 more the estimate that I
think is probably pretty accurate about
one flag bit per year allocated so 32
plus 5 so hopefully we have about 30
years of lifetime before we have to go
through that that again like I said one
of the reasons why we don't think
there's going to be a lot of extent
few extensions really are just about
encapsulation not specific use cases so
for specific specific use cases we would
want to put those in a different place
in the packet either the private fields
or inside like I said we could have an
encapsulation of another type protocol
and I forgot to mention so we didn't
make one major edition in the latest
version of the go extensions that's an
alternate checksum this is something
similar to UDP options in this case we
have a crc32 CRC 16 and CRC ccitt the
reason why there's two CRC 16 it was
really difficult to find which one kind
of has is more important they're both
equally used in different contexts so
UDP options for instance you is that the
latter linux turns out it has the first
one implemented so they're both there
the good news is that it's a
configuration thing so you can only use
this if both sides kind of agreed on it
anyway there was one important point and
I think this is actually coming out in
UDP options also if we make a CRC or
security field or anything like that
optional and it covers the header they
do not protect the actual option so for
instance if this were a TLV and we had a
TLV type it said this is a CRC if that
TLV type became corrupted it would turn
into something else the receiver might
not see the CRC so the value of having
the CRC goes down if this is one reason
why we like to have like TCP check sum
UDP checksum are inherent in the packet
so that's one thing we make a note of
that the answer here is it's a
configuration option if the receiver
expects security or expects the CRC and
doesn't see it then they should drop the
packet and make a note of it the GU flag
field extension like I mentioned it's
intended to be the last bit of the flags
so the idea is the I guess that the 31st
bit would be the e bit and that will
point to a new flag field so that
32-bits it looks like just like any
other Flags field but when we're
processing the flags after the initial
flags our process will hop down to that
and then continue processing flags and
then fields for those flags follow all
of that's fairly straightforward
thinking about new possible new
extensions
I think the OEM measurement bits so
there are two of them defined for 8321
that may be very reasonable to put into
goo flag fields also a group based
policy may be reasonable and as I
mentioned if we won't want it to format
private data the format type may be in a
in a field and that would indicate what
the type is of the private data so
that's all I had any questions Corie
Corie first I'm curious about why you
think you need three different CRC
formats it's like how long is your data
is that not the only thing that would
drive that the choices CIC into our
ability seems more key to having lots of
options here it's um it's a two bit
field so we have four we have three
combinations so crc32 kind of makes
sense because that's either at CRC but
the argument there is well that's kind
of expensive so what about a CRC 16 so
like I said it was it was kind of a coin
toss I did not have a strong opinion but
I couldn't find any good precedence
either with an IETF or with in general
networking community about which is
preferred I don't think it particularly
cost us anything except a couple of flag
bits yeah we also cost of and what less
interoperability here I mean this is
like creating options just for the sake
of it I mean and we chose a CIC
32 I think in a CTP and look at the SCTP
story and you'll find why and why we
think that's actually okay there are
they're not a normal CRC the earth you
can choose either CRC and 30 to depend
on what you want
what you think is better I mean it they
don't have that much different
properties there is a document actually
discusses the difference between the two
computationally it's not that much more
expensive than their CRC 16 I don't have
a strong opinion honestly if we can we
can chuck the CRC 16 if that's fine I
would point out one thing that we did do
all the CRC's the checksum that we have
and the security they all have the
length field so it's kind of like a UDP
light thing so we cover so it is
optional data included so I kind of like
that aspect of it like I said I don't
have a strong opinion it's that's good
feedback they've heard like verbal ink
CRC hurts you oughta hey you you're
trying to verify integrity you shouldn't
make it more complex
let me give if you want to use more than
one format let me give you a second
option and explain why it's cheaper and
why it helps the second option is to
grab the grab what's commonly known as
the I scuzzy CRC or crc32 see there's
two good reasons to do this one is the
polynomial is different so if you're
running over Ethernet you get added
cheque as opposed to running the same
polynomial over roughly the same data
and the second is that Acer processors
are a certain well-known processor
vendor and possibly others have
instructions that directly compute this
sucker
so it's cheap so the argument was we
have two men and I are suggesting
another I'm suggesting and not dropped
I'm suggesting a two-stage approach one
toss the 16s now you down to one if
somebody would like to go explain why
crc32 is too expensive in software you
could add crc32 C and require everybody
to do both because that one's cheaper
and software well I mean I would point
out that crc32 is already implemented in
the Selfridge and generally right so for
implementation wise that is you'd like
to stop and step one I'm not gonna I'm
not going to complain okay point taken
if there's a preference then you know
I'm more than willing to go with one I
think it's a it's a good concept to have
it in general so gory fascist is TS VW
culture why don't you just ask auntie s
vwg because if you want to choose a CRC
then I think you'll get some feedback
wait which one Oh ask about your chosen
CRC is it suitable on TS vwg okay yeah
on the transport area will give you some
fever a lot and different other prom
skills okay that's a good point thank
you thank you thank you very much
don't go too far away Tom Tom Tom Tom
you have two more okay hi I'm Tom
Herbert I'll get an update on I Elena so
we have the ILA buff on Thursday this is
a non working group forming boss the
intent is to highlight problem statement
use cases this is not intended to be an
in-depth discussion in of solutions and
we've had quite a bit of discussion on
the mailing list so since last IETF
there was an ila mailing lists created a
lot of the discussion gets down into
security scalability mapping systems
denial service threat and most recently
there's discussion on an Iowa Lisp kind
of control plane so the idea is to use
list control plane for ila that's a
pretty promising there's also been some
discussions on DMM and the five gang an
IP list those discussions tend to be
more specific to the mobile use case it
would point out that ila is kind of
trying to be a generic but mobile is one
of the use cases data center
virtualization network virtualization or
some of the others we're also looking at
the 3gpp steady item that they're
looking at perhaps ila could be part of
that solution
so that I'm getting a little bit of
update on the data plane discussions so
ila is explicitly not encapsulation and
that means there are no bits at it to do
transformations so we have no
extensibility no way to encode
everything in that sense it's kind of
the the opposite of generic UDP
encapsulation what that means is
everything needs to fit into basically
the destination address and the idea
idea viola is that we transform
addresses in order to get them to their
destination and before the receiver
actually gets the packet we always
transform back to the original address
so it's kind of like a paired address
modification so because everything fits
needs to fit into this small space we
have relaxed a little bit on the
canonical 64 64 split so for instance in
il NP there was this idea of a 64 bit
locator 64 bit identifier that's kind of
some simple architectural e but when you
start thinking about different encodings
and different things you might want to
do it's a little less flexible so we're
relaxing on that and that gives us the
ability to do some interesting
techniques one of the techniques is
locator indexing which you would use if
we wanted to encode / 64 assignments
into il a another one is chaining so
instead of just doing one il a transfer
transformation we may do multiple ones
on the path this is kind of a poor man's
segment routing where we can adjust the
destination address have the packet
visit certain destinations based on
hop-by-hop routing and at the very end
again the packet has to be transformed
back into the original packet so that
the receiver has no idea that this
happened this does represent a bit of a
trade off so in order to keep the data
plane simple that implies a little more
complexity in the control plane so
that's kind of the the ILA trade-off the
control plane pretty quickly gets to
identify your locator split scalability
type of issues and this has a lot to do
with mapping systems
an identifier locator split we do think
there's gonna be mapping systems so
imagine a large network everything is
somehow virtualized or mobile we need a
way to find out where where identifiers
are identifiers are basically the
logical nodes so for that we need a
mapping system this is pretty I guess
pretty accepted in the identifier
locator space so the question right now
is how to do this mapping system it's
little little independent violate I
think there are some things that ila
kind of implies in a mapping system but
fundamentally the mapping system does
have kind of four pillars the
scalability security privacy and das
ability aspects so I think a lot of that
will come out in the ILA Boff maybe a
little bit more detail but again the
solution it's about the problem of
statement right now and the use case is
a little bit less on the solution so
again that's Thursday 18:10 and discount
thank you very much so that's a teaser
for the buff that will take place and in
the interest of time maybe we can move
to the to the next presentation and
leave discussion for that buff that's
okay
next tom okay one more so this is like
kind of an out offshoot of some of those
things we've been looking at ila and
this is particularly looking at the
privacy and prefix assignment so I we
have a few caveats up front just to make
it clear so this is only considering
privacy at the networking layer
specifically in addressing privacy
itself on the internet has to be
considered every layer we know that this
is considering one aspect of that this
is also only considering risk from third
parties interpreting or inferring
information from IP addresses so that
specifically means we're not considering
network providers that have say for
mapping of IP address
device it's up to them to to secure that
data and I'm not sure we can do much
technically to solve that problem and
equivalent equivalently this doesn't
address law enforcement or authorities
who can compel say network providers to
release that information so like I said
those are caveats up front we understand
that and privacy is a multi-pronged
problem as we know so what about prefix
assignment so / 64 addressing it to host
is actually becoming quite common so
slack for instance is doing that and
it's actually pretty common in mobile
networks you E's get full / 64 this
actually recommended no RC 33 14 so that
gives us some properties and since the
prefix is being assigned to the device
that means there's kind of a 1:1
relationship between a prefix and a
device so given two addresses that share
the same prefix even if the ID is
different the interface identifier in
this scenario they actually would refer
to the same device and that becomes a
little more problematic in the case that
we're assigning to say a Ewing in a
mobile network like a smartphone then
there because of much higher probability
that that devices actually corresponds
to a specific user so now we have a one
to one relationship potentially between
the prefix and then actual user and
another issue prefix may contain fine
grain hierarchy for routing and that's
going to have to do become a problem if
that reveals location of the device and
hence the user so the privacy issue is
kind of implied from that the prefix
becomes an identifier for the device the
addresses are used in the public
internet so if a third party knows that
a site is assigning prefixes then if it
sees two addresses it can infer that
they are the same device if they have
the same prefix
so this exposes the risks of revealing
user identity and communicate
Shen's and location location of users if
location information is actually encoded
in the prefix so this specific issue was
actually raised in RFC forty nine forty
one seventy seven to twenty one maybe
some others and periodically changing
the interface identifier in forty nine
forty one actually is no help because
the problem potential problem is in the
prefix not in the interface identifier
so we could extrapolate from our C 49-41
to just change the prefix periodically
and conceptually that's possible we do
know that changing addresses if there's
only one and you change it periodically
will probably kill all the existing
flows and they have to be restarted so
assuming we solve that problem then the
real question becomes what is the
correct frequency to change addresses in
order to ensure privacy and it's a
tricky question I did pose this on a
couple of lists and there really isn't a
very good answer because someone could
say a day or a week or an hour and
there's no way to quantify what kind of
privacy you get out of that so the
conclusion that I posted it was anything
less than a different address per
connection or per flow theoretically
could have a privacy exploit and
actually gave an example in the in the
draft you can read it about a proposed
exploit that I could take advantage of
of that so any reuse of a prefix or
address could be exploited to figure out
identity so from that we can consider
what what are we really shooting for and
their privacy and addresses so I gave an
example of a couple criteria and this is
based on if I have two addresses and no
other information what can I infer from
these two addresses and it is obvious
that you can infer they're from the same
provider same organization so they will
share say a common network prefix that's
kind of basic and maybe also that they
belong to a very broad geographic
grouping so would be expected that a
large organization would probably want
to have some Geographic or regional
hierarchy but beyond that the idea is
the viewer of these addresses should not
be able to do this any other information
specifically they can't tell that the
notes that are associated with these
addresses are not the same node or in
the same rack or at the same location or
have any other proximity so that's I
think kind of a I don't think it's
strict I think that's just some criteria
for privacy addressing that will propose
now I would point out that network
address translation net can actually
meet these criteria
if there's a large enough address pull
because basically what NAT does is it
obvious gates the underlying addresses
of the network and what you get on the
wire on the Internet is the address of
the net device and some port number and
the port number refers to the specific
instance but external users they don't
see that so it turns out net actually
meets these strong criteria as pointing
on the document I do think this is one
reason why some some law enforcement
agencies are a little paranoid of that
because it does such a in sense such a
good job job of hiding identity so the
document does present a possible
solution and like I said this kind of
wasn't sub problem of NAT or not at NAPA
to vial a so with identifier locator
split the idea is that we can use
identifier locator split so the
identifier becomes independent of
location and we can assign multiple
identifiers x'
hence untrackable addresses to host the
address is still share a common prefix
but if this is done with enough
randomization they would share nothing
else so to address is assigned to a host
the same host would have nothing in
common except that prefix so that would
meet the strong
criterion and then add a privacy and a
dressing so for maximum privacy then
because of the the result that we need
to use an address per flow means we have
a lot of addresses potentially that's
obviously a scaling problem so looking
at some of the potential mitigations
there one thing is not everyone
necessarily needs his privacy so in some
sense this could be a service if
somebody really needed that level of
privacy in one of the one time yes
address this could be a way to
accomplish that maybe there are other
communications or aren't necessarily
that private they don't need that
obviously that's not a great solution
because now we're forcing the user to
make a decision and we'd rather give
them perfect privacy all the time so
another way to look at this problem is
what we're actually trying to do we
actually want to aggregate addresses as
being as belonging to the same host so
we can get the addresses to the right
host and that's the problem that the
mapping system has so there is
aggregation here so the question we're
pondering is can we do a sort of hidden
aggregation where the network can assign
a host a block of addresses and to the
outside world this block looks
completely randomized however the
network either through some sort of
public key encryption or some type of
hash is able to deduce that these
addresses actually aggregate to the same
node in this case so this is the concept
of hitting aggregation so the first
level would be local network has a way
to create these addresses assign them to
the hosts and only the local network
would understand this if that problem is
solved then the question becomes how do
I do a bulk aggregation because we still
don't want to have to give hosts
individual address theoretically they
could require thousands or millions of
these is there a way to give a host a
way to create a block of addresses
itself and whatever needs a new address
it can create an address say we give it
blocks of 64,000 IP addresses and it can
use them as needed and when it runs out
it can ask for new ones so those are
kind of some of the things were we're
looking at and again this is kind of
along the lines of how identifiers
locator may solve they solved that issue
any questions hi Tim Chan I've got more
points than I should probably make here
so to say a couple take the rest of this
so I think the first one is I think this
is useful having prefix privacy I think
if you compare it to the privacy for
hosts as it stands you're probably going
to want to be able to have persistent
prefixes and private prefixes so you
need to be able to somehow delegate a
prefix that's Marxist for use as a kind
of a privacy review first I guess so so
you we would we would do a block some
sort of block delegation where it's not
a prefix right it's actually a block for
for privacy that way is that what you're
referring to well if I was say for
example in mine something has been
allocated to my home network for example
then maybe having a rotating prefix out
of the ISPs prefix that I can use to
initiate new connections for movie good
thing while I've still got a persistent
prefix that I can have my services on
without running don't DNS or other
things to update and essentially have to
renumber my network every time you
continue and privacy prefix I think
would be important well I mean so I'm
not sure it's it's so much for numbering
right it's more temporary address
assignment I think is the best way to
phrase it so the addresses could be
requested on demand in some sense so
obviously if you want a persistent
prefix because you're a server then that
that might be a different story
yeah but otherwise it seems you were
potentially going to assign me addresses
that might be shared between multiple
customers or something and that starts
getting quite
I had shares lots of problems that we
have with cgn and so on today doesn't it
I think as a user I think a lot of users
are aware of privacy issues and that's
why they use things VPNs like hidemyass
or whatever other ones they fancy using
tor whatever so I think this awareness I
think what we're trying to do here is to
provide some more subtle privacy that
users may not ask for but I would like
them on my own network to not affect
things I'm running as services in my
network I share a problem with doing
this big block and giving a host Zeeland
addresses that it can use you are into
all sorts the other things that have
been discussed for things like nd cache
exhaustion and so on there's all sorts
of things that if you try and use an
address per application they're going to
hit you in in otherwise I mean there's a
lot of legacy towards this right I think
it's it's a really good topic well I
think there's because I think just
throwing a ila it is an answer but I
think there's more pragmatic things that
need to be considered first okay I'm
cutting the line now here we had someone
in mute ago I don't know if they'd still
want to have his place but I think
Lauren oh I think I think stating the
goals like you stated them is is sudha
misleading at the beginning you said it
is entirely out of scope to think about
anything that the ice P can do to attack
privacy or anything that sends anyone
that has the power to compel the ISP can
do you declared that to be out of scope
on slide one but it doesn't mean that
just by making it out of scope you can
there is a privacy trade-off there for
example a scheme like the one where you
assign let's say that the ISP assigns
you want ipv6 address for every
different connection right yes you can
declare ISP sort of privacy to be out of
scope but the fact of the matter is if
we build the scheme then the ISP has to
maintain a record of everything that you
did whereas in the case where it has to
keep every base essentially every tea
every TCP connection right whereas in
the ski
where the SP just assigned to your
prefix that rotates they don't have to
keep all that information about you so
yes you could declare it out of scope
but you're basically moving a slider
around where you know different parties
have different views of how much
activity of what activity you conduct
online and the solutions here are
basically all on the other side of that
slider because one side of its out of
scope but I think that's not a full
solution to the problem well so let me
ask a question so NAT exists today right
and that is not prefix assignment in the
sense so externally what you get with
NAT is something that apparently is
randomized so as far as I know most ISPs
are required to keep all NAT mappings
correct you know I don't know that well
but this the data is the same so nat
effectively gives you a different source
address per connection as far as the
outside world is concerned so if they
want to do an AB you know the down
mappings at that time I think that's
that's the argument that law enforcement
is making but it's not clear to me why
that or that argument is because it
seemed like the nat logs are sufficient
in which case if the net logs are
sufficient then the logs of address
assignment in this case should also be
sufficient at least that's my
understanding of the problem so it's not
clear even I mean it sort of becomes
free murky because it's not even clear
whether the the party on the other end
like the server actually keeps source
ports right so well right but but the
server is a different thing because the
server can be anywhere on the Internet
if you don't have the source port
there's nothing that can be tracked
right well no if I know if I know what
I'm looking at if I know then that
translation then I can reverse engineer
who was sending that if you're behind in
that if you have the logs yeah nothing
that keeps lux but so like I said I
think it was not necessarily a specific
suggestion about these points I think I
think basically I think basically
declaring that attack vector to be out
of scope is an error because it means
that we can like because it means that
any solution that entirely gives the ISP
with access TSP all this information
basically we're completely disregarding
that downside because the way we set the
goals right but they already they
already have all that information you
know it's not true well the people they
do they have that because they have the
prefix to device information they hope
they have that they don't have to track
every connection if you don't have to
track every connection here either what
we said is you can you can assign
addresses to device it they can use them
however they want it's not necessarily
for connection all right that's right
not necessarily but like I said the one
scheme that you proposed was different
address for connection that requires
100% participation for the person rit's
routing the packets to that address yes
but that is that my point is on that
last slide where you propose several
different arguments the only difference
between those is the amount of
information the ISP gets which on slide
one you declare to be out of scope so I
think that's kind of disingenuous that's
right but look at this way if I saw
assign an address now and they use it
only for one connection then they only
use it for one connection the ISP
doesn't know what connection they use
that for it's not it's not like NAT now
you actually have more information
because that is about the actual
connection this is I mean it I know it's
a subtle point this is just the address
assignment that's what needs to is what
needs to be tracked when the request
doesn't say I want to create a
connection to this destination give me
an address but you the requester says
give me an address but you would like
I'm said like I'm saying it's I'm
talking about the goals not the
proposals okay so you say their goal but
we have to track do connection tracking
is that the goal is that we have to
provide privacy and we can't just just
hand wave our hands and say whatever the
I species is out of scope because one
scheme that satisfies your goals
entirely is that the ice P logs every
five couple no no but but you're not
part of this well that satisfies that
too right so what we're trying not to do
now okay we can take this one to the to
a list maybe we go to the next one and
the line then we have me to go and the
last person hi i'm kyla rose this might
be a dumb comment but if we're giving do
to the 16 IP addresses to every host
could that actually lead to
ISPs with millions of posts run
out of IPs I know ipv4 his big but do
the sixteen pretty big two as opposed to
two to the 64 that they're getting today
oh so are we talking about handing out
like slash 96 or something won't block
blocks of to box of 2 to the 16th
128-bit addresses sorry ok not Creek
sorry that wasn't done before sensitive
Thanks so next we go to me to go Dave
hi there it's Dave O'Reilly here I'll be
speaking later but I just wanted to jump
in with a couple of points about and I
guess you could call it the law
enforcement perspective on this I'm not
a law enforcement officer but I do work
with them a lot and I understand their
perspective and the perspective on a
situation like this would be and that if
there has been some criminal activity
and that activity is associated with a
particular IP address what the law
enforcement officer is going to be
interested in is who was controlling
that IP address at a particular time at
the moment almost everywhere in the
world I can't obviously I can't speak
for the entire planet but everywhere
that I've ever worked it has been a
requirement a regulatory requirement on
ISPs to be able to identify their
customers and this touches on what I'll
be talking about later but it seems to
me that whether a whole block of 64 IP
addresses is allocated to a particular
person to a particular host or whether
the IP address has to keep connection
logs there are two solutions to the
ultimate problem which is that ISPs will
be required under regulation to be able
to identify their subscribers now so
that was my first point whatever way it
pounds.i that's gonna be the case the
other point that I wanted to make was I
am of the opinion I hope this is not too
controversial comments that for a
plethora of reasons connection logging
is a terrible idea and the main reason I
think is the risk
of loss of that data is is huge to the
privacy of the individuals concerned so
ISPs have data breaches just like
everybody else and if all my connection
logs got out they can see everything
that I was browsing at every moment and
so on and so forth which is why and I
I'm resistant to that idea so as long as
there is some alternative mechanism by
which individuals like ISPs can meet the
regulatory obligations to be able to
identify to subscribers that's really
the point that I wanted to make okay
those are good points but again I point
out that the this solution actually is
not connection logging it's more budget
address registration so it's effectively
what we have today with a prefix to
device but it might be a greater scale
so it'd be address to device but it
wouldn't be going as far as NAT which is
clearly connection logging so that that
wouldn't occur and I'm assuming that law
enforcement has to have NAT logs today
already so it's kind of like that that
component at least in terms of
scalability should already exist as far
as I can tell so that doesn't require a
connection logging you can't do that but
you don't have to port block allocation
so you're just you're just your tourist
boards horse address okay you don't have
to log all the connections just because
you're running that okay great so that's
less data you can but it's really like
the logging requirements just thanks so
let's person on the mic please I nicked
OD UC Berkeley and I'm coming a little
bit new to this area I work mostly at
the web level but and I'm particularly
curious about you're talking about the
timing of rotation of rotating
identifier z' and I feel like there's a
particular concern about like that if we
have too many AI identifiers that are
getting rotated at different times we
might lose the privacy benefit of
rotating identifiers so I'm curious
about like whether whether the Klein
has controller whether the clients like
or having some guidance so that we're
rotating all they identify up and diet
identifiers at the same time otherwise
all the end servers can just line them
up and actually sort of figure out every
change identified okay so real quick so
one I think the client should have the
control plane gets addresses from the
provider client should use them as it
sees fit so I think that's pretty clear
two please look at the draft because I
give the example a potential exploit
that could defeat any frequency except
once per connect or once one per flow
that example hasn't been refuted so it
may be may be accurate so if you have
any ideas on whether it could actually
happen I I've received this one thing I
think is privacy is probably such a big
problem that maybe HAP maybe the
attackers haven't gone down to this
level yet but I do think it's gonna be a
problem at some point doing it oh thank
you very much yep fine thanks a lot Ron
helooo ron Bonica the chairs have asked
me to shorten the presentation up a
little bit so I'm gonna skip over a
couple slides this this craft used to be
called ipv6 fragmentation considered
fragile and as we were writing it
realized most of our criticisms applied
to ipv4 as much as ipv6 so we renamed it
it's now IP fragmentation considered
fragile what are we doing in this draft
well we've known for a long time
fragmentation reduces the reliability of
internet communication in this document
we're going to talk about what
fragmentation is a little bit and that
we do it with document we'll skip over
it in the presentation we'll talk about
how fragmentation fragmentation reduces
reliability and we'll put out some
recommendations for protocol developers
and network operators now keep in mind
we're not talking about deprecating
fragmentation that just can't be done
what we're talking about is pointing out
how it makes it how fragmentation makes
communications fragile and strongly
recommending that protocol developers
wean themselves off a dependency on
fragmentation so there's some
terminology you need to know to play the
game I'll assume that you all everybody
in this room knows what an MTU the
minimum link MTU and PMT you is I'll
also assume everybody in the room knows
how IP fragmentation works I'm just
gonna point out two things one is a
small difference between how ipv4
fragmentation works and ipv6
fragmentation works an ipv4 you have
this thing called the DF bit if it is
set a packet cannot be further
fragmented downstream if it is clear a
packet can be set for the fragment at
downstream an ipv6 there is no DF bit a
packet can never be further fragment at
downstream it can only be fragmented at
its source
the next thing that fragmentation has in
common between ipv4 and ipv6 is when you
fragment a packet you divide it into
pieces the upper layer header always
appears in the first fragment it never
appears in subsequent fragments this
this observation about where the upper
layer header is is what brings half of
the fragility into the argument now in
an environment where only the source can
fragment a packet the source of a packet
needs to do one of three things either
restrict itself to sending packets that
it knows will never be fragmented that's
for ipv6 never sending a packet back
bigger than 12 80 for ipv4 and never
sending a packet bigger than some
arbitrarily small size so that's one
thing it can do another thing it can do
is PMT UD path MTU discovery so it
discovers the MTU of the path ahead of
it and the third thing is packetization
layer P MTU discovery and we'll talk
about each of those for a second PM tud
the source node makes an initial
estimate of the PMT you to a destination
that estimate may be too large it then
starts sending packets to the
destination if the packet is larger than
the actual PM tud of the actual PM to
you it will not be fordable it'll get
dropped and a downstream writer router
will send an ICMP packet too big message
to the source the source having received
that will update its estimate of the PM
to you now this strategy PMT UD
absolutely requires the network to be
able to deliver ICMP PT P messages if it
can't do that it's black hole time the
next alternative is PL PMT UD here we
push the problem up to the packetization
layer the packetization layer will say
TCP
in-band sends packets of different sizes
to its TCP peer what it's doing is
probing to find the PMT you it relies on
two things primarily it relies on
acknowledgments of its probes at the TCP
layer it can also rely on ICMP feedback
but then again it's perfect in PLM PLP
MTU D the endpoint is perfectly able to
ignore the ICMP messages it doesn't need
them at all
PLP MTU D is defined for TCP in RFC
48:21 it's being defined for some other
protocols and draft Fairhurst going on
in the TSV working group sadly it's not
defined for UDP and it can't be because
PLP MTU D kind of assumes a long live
session well a session not a one in dumb
packet the other thing about PLP MTU D
it doesn't rely on ICMP ptb messages at
all if they're all dropped PLP MTU D
still works just fine so we've talked
about the status quo now it's time to
leap in and talk about why is it that
fragmentation makes communications
unstable or fragile well one problem
well these problems all link back to the
problem that the frag only the first
fragment has the transport layer header
in it what are the impacts of that well
let's say for a minute you're a load
balancer and you're a load balancer that
load balance is on TCP ports if the TCP
port is only in the first fragment
you're bound to suboptimal load
balancing next issue is firewalls let's
say you're a firewall and you have a
rule that says block all packets based
on the TCP destination port well you can
configure that firewall two ways one way
is to accept all subsequent fragments
that's a little bit too liberal another
way is to drop all subsequent fragments
that one's a little too restrictive
there's no healthy middle ground other
middleboxes can have the same kinds of
problem because they need access to the
TCP header or the transport layer header
for instance let's say you're a middle
box that's remarking the dscp based on
the TCP port number it's fine for the
first fragment what do you do for
fragments to through in there are some
other well-known problems with
fragmentation that don't have to do with
the TC with the transport layer header
not being in subsequent fragments there
are bunches of security vulnerabilities
that have been documented over the over
the years overlapping fragment attacks
like the ROS attack resource exhaustion
attacks and many more we won't go into
them now they're in the draft but
there's an interesting problem around
TCP loss around ICMP loss PM tu PM tu d
fails when you are losing ICMP packets
ICMP packets can be lost for bunches of
reasons one is because network operators
are filtering them they shouldn't
there's an RFC that said that says they
shouldn't another is you know just play
don't packet loss or rate limiting those
things happen but they're not
insurmountable problems there is at
least one insurmountable problem and it
has to do with any caste I'll give you
this example from Jeff Houston's work
let's say for a minute that a DNS client
sends a DNS request to an anycast
address it's a common thing to have
happen that it arrives at a DNS server
the DNS server sends back a very large
response it's running DNS X so the
response is going to be big that people
are laughing that response gets to a
point where it cannot be forwarded
because of an MTU problem so the node
that could not forward the DNS response
sends an ICMP message back to the
of the packet the source of the packet
is in anycast address and it goes to
some DNS server that has that anycast
address unfortunately not the one that
sent the packet that's problematic it's
black hole time
another problem is network operators
tend to filter fragmented packets there
are two studies one by Fernando gods and
other by Jeff Houston that that
demonstrate this we don't quite quite
know why they do it we just know that
they do so okay we have some solutions
at the transport layer we've talked
about them already we'll go quickly
let's get to the recommendations so I
can yield the floor we have some
recommendations to application
developers that they should not develop
applications that rely on a PI P
fragmentation and what's more if there
were any that accrue shal to the
Internet infrastructure they should be
rethinking those applications so they
will rely less on IP fragmentation the
next is for network operators they must
not filter ICMP Petey B's that's already
in another RFC so it's not crucial but
the big one is for DNS and especially
when DNS is using DNS SEC they should be
finding ways to not rely on IP
fragmentation and anyhow they ask next
steps is to adopt this as a working
group document okay so can I have a
raise of hands how many people have read
this draft okay to be starting so as you
know we're running out of time so maybe
I'll take one question and then we keep
moving we'll take it to the list I think
before adopting as working group but
that's a good show of interest in it
David black I mean--the another transfer
area and I'm here to help you Ron I'm
going to say a dirty word tunnels please
make sure that what you do here is lined
up with the int area tunnels draft we're
fragmentation is used to solve some
nasty
problems with tunnels it we really ought
to have a consistent story across the
two of them thank you okay thanks a lot
so Vlad hi so I'm gonna give you a quick
update on our work on Sox version six
I'll start by giving you a brief
overview of where we're at so we've
trimmed down the are cheating the
overhead in terms of our GT down to 0 if
0 RTT authentication is used for in
order to protect against malicious l
parties we've taken a step back and
rather than having sox provide an
encryption
we've decided to run run it over TLS and
then handle whatever issues TLS has
notably TLS TLS only data is prone to
replay attacks and we have a mechanism
that mitigates such attacks now that
we're running we're also running stocks
over TLS plaintext password
authentication is actually viable and
finally we have added a new we've
leveraged stocks options to add a new
set saw copped and get saw cup-like
mechanism and we've used it to implement
some stuff related to MPT CP more on
that later
so stocks version 5 starts by
negotiating the method of authentication
then it does within the authentication
and the client requests that the server
the proxy establish some connection to
the server and then finally application
data can pass through Sox version 6 in
contrast sends as much data out front as
possible so we cram in the
authentication method negotiation
negotiation and the address of the
server and also some application data we
cram it all into the first message sent
over to the proxy and of course if 0tt
authentication is used the server sends
off and can send an operation
apply as soon as it touches the
connection to the through the remote
server
speaking of 0rt authentication this is
this is how how a password
authentication is done in a zero RTD
manner so draft so I see 19:29 describes
how password authentication is performed
for Sox basically we can just take the
the the initial message sent by the
client which contains the username and
password and place it inside a Sox
authentication data option now of course
there's a small caveat to that if the
username or and/or password I are
exceptionally long it simply won't fit
in that option and you have to do it the
old-fashioned way which takes up one
extra RTT however this is unlikely next
up we've got socket options there's been
some discussion on the mailing lists
notably David he brought up the point
that sockets are actually an OS
construct and connections are
necessarily TCP connections are
necessarily done using sockets so we're
going to rename these options in the
next version of the draft clients can
use these options can include these
options in the in the Sox requests in
order to request certain behavior from
the proxy and proxies can include them
in operation reply to advertise their
behaviors the fields I want to draw your
attention to are like level code and
data so the leg baker basically
indicates what what leg behavior reply
refers to it can either be a client
proxy like the proxy server leg or both
legs then the next three the next three
fields were actually inspired by sets or
captain gets a cop we've got left
operation code and data for possible
levels are a genetic socket level then
we've got levels for eye for the track
left three protocols namely ipv4 and
ipv6 and two more levels for TCP and UDP
we've used the socket options to handle
GFO
so that previously was a field in the
request which indicated whether or not
the proxy should attempt to use the fo
now we've removed that field and when a
client wants the proxy to use the fo it
simply includes this option as part of
its request the absence of such an
option means that the server must not
use must not attempt to use the fo next
up we've also used these options to
implement a use case called proxy bypass
so let's say that a mobile phone once
has both a Wi-Fi and the 4G interface
and it wants to take advantage of both
interfaces now most as you probably know
MPT CP deployment is lagging behind on
the server side so if you if let's say a
mobile phone wants to take advantage of
both of its interfaces it probably has
to go through a proxy now some servers
my template might start start deploying
MP TCP now in case in case on a server
does support MP TCP the proxy can place
an MP TCP option in its operation reply
signaling to the client that the
upstream server does indeed support MP
TCP then the client can forego the use
of the proxy and talk to the server
directly in further connection attempts
and finally we can use these options
which to change the MP TCP scheduler
used by the proxy so clients can can
place such a request to indicate what's
what's what packet scheduler they want
we currently support the packets
Jewellers available in the the lyrics NP
tcp implementation and proxies can
include them as part of operation
replies to tell clients what schedulers
they are using we found one possible use
case for this option namely low latency
services so if a client wishes to have
low latency it can tell the server it
can get tell the proxy to duplicate data
across all MP TCP sub flows such that
the delay is always minimal and with
that I'll be happy to take questions
thanks can I have a raise of hands who
has read the the latest version of this
draft ok who has read any version of
this draft ok so we definitely encourage
people to comment on this latest version
if you if you can please take a look and
send comments to blood thank you very
much we're ranking short of time so
we're gonna move being be moving on now
Thanks so next is Dave remote
yeah yes hi
okay so hello everybody and thanks for
the opportunity to present this I'll be
as close to five minutes as I possibly
can
so now next slide please
yep so I'd like to begin by describing
what the currently published best
practice is which is RFC 6002 on logging
recommendations for internet facing
servers okay so what that document
recommends is that as well as logging
incoming IP addresses servers also log
incoming source port numbers and time
stamps and transport protocol as well
but why and the answer is because of
large scale address sharing technologies
such as carrier grade math in the
presence of these technologies this
additional information is required in
order to attribute the activity of an IP
address two to two at the very least to
an ISP but ideally down to an individual
from a crime investigation point of view
so in the presence of large scale Nats
IP address is not enough you need this
extra information as well that's not to
say that if you did have all this
information you would successfully be
able to identify an individual from this
it's just the information that is
required to address the problem that is
presented by carrier grade nat and and
related technologies like ipv4 to ipv6
mapping technologies very similar
problem next slide please
can so I did a little bit of research
and what I found was that while stars
recommendation stats that's fine they
are what they are but they're not enough
and here are some of the issues that I
that I identified so somebody who was
considering implementing those
recommendations might find that their
server software might not support
logging of source ports and that would
prevent them from being able to achieve
the recommendations another thing that
has that I have seen is that certain
server software the only way that you
can enable logging of source port is by
enabling a ridiculously verbose level of
logging like debug logging or something
like that which you're never going to do
on a production server so whilst it may
be it may be technically possible it's
infeasible to implement source port
logging now practically no server
software enables it by default and
indeed no server software that I could
find a bar one even has a default
configuration sample that includes
logging of source port so so somebody
trying to do this is battling or pill
there's there's not even default for
them to enable now the next point that I
wanted to to raise with the existing
recommendations is the existing
recommendations recommend that you log
against some sort of traceable time
source or some sort of central time
source like an NTP server or something
like that
but there's a whole plethora of
deployment scenarios where that's not
possible
and nor is it actually necessary for the
requirement of the of the recommend of
the BCP of the the best practice which
is to be able to identify enough
information to be able to ask an ISP who
was using this IP address at that time
because I'll take a moment to explain
why you don't need to exact timestamp
it's pretty well-known in in the
forensics world it's one that one of the
first things you learn as a forensic
examiner that you don't need to know the
exact time which something happened at
all you need to know is what time the
time that was recorded and as long as
the time is recorded consistent
you can offset the time then to be the
real time so if you--if you are
analyzing a computer for example and
it's time is set one year wrong you can
look at the older times on those
computer compared them to real times and
then offset all the time so you you know
as long as time is recorded consistently
it doesn't need to be retorted recorded
against a reference time so I take
exception with that point in in the
recommendations in the current
recommendations and then the last point
that I wanted to UM to raise for for
whatever it's worth which is logging
information doesn't exist in a vacuum
people log information for a reason and
oftentimes people have all sorts of
scripts and tooling and so on that's
built based on their logs and by
changing log formats you break existing
tooling so that data point for
discussion it's another challenge to the
implementation of the recommendations
next slide please
good okay so I've only five minutes so I
just wanted to summarize and say but the
absence of primarily source port
information in logs is a big problem
from a crime attribution and a public
safety point of view and this was a
point that was made by Europol in 2014
and repeated again in 2016 in their
crime I forget what the document is
called some sort of crime problems on
the internet and and as I mentioned
earlier it doesn't logging of source
port wouldn't make a crime attribution
problem go away what it does address the
problem of these address sharing
technologies to a certain extent not in
all scenarios but to a certain it
certainly would improve things and I I'm
suggesting that the current best
practice needs revision to address more
of the practical issues with with
locking source port it's not just say
source ports should be logged but also
to make some you know a more
encompassing set of recommendations that
can actually maybe help make it
happen and then last slide please and in
order to move the discussion along I'm
being completely new to engaging with
the IETF I rolled up a document and I
published it which is now in its second
draft and the link is there for anyone
who wants to to read it or comment or my
contact details are there and everything
so and so that was everything that I
wanted to say thank you very much
Thanks so where the time limit but if
people were willing to to ask questions
and stay a couple of minutes longer I'm
going to let the mic open Christian it's
just a verbal question it's a question
of classification you you are are you
asking for this log in the just the
network that implements the nuts or do
you have also the same requirement from
cells that implement the information
processing yeah that's a fantastic
question and the answer is it's the
server's who are logging and not the nut
and the nut itself as I mentioned in my
intervention in on Tom's talk most
people who are running and that are have
a regulatory obligation to be able to
identify if if a law enforcement agency
comes to them and goes who was using a
particular IP address at a particular
time they have to be able to tell them
the problem is in cases of carrier-grade
NAT if the law enforcement officer
doesn't also have the time and the
source port they can't even ask the ISP
the ISP will say a million people were
using that IP address at that time or
you know some large number of people and
without the source port on the time
stamp we can't tell you so there's an
information gap between the information
that's being protect aend in that cenar
in psalm carrier-grade NAT scenarios
versus the information that is being
retained at let's say for example a
victim so for example if you were a
website and your website got hacked and
you would like the person who hacked
that website to be caught if you don't
have the source port on the time stamp
you don't stand a chance the IP address
is not enough thanks for thanks
education okay thanks but back there I
am I launched around I'm one of the
authors of oxy 6302 and I take your
point on the time stamp
maybe the recommendation we made at the
time was too restrictive we'll be very
happy to work with you to update the
documents now about the other
recommendation that you seems to be
calling for it was not clear to me how
they could be expressed in terms of
things we could put inside of a updated
version of a document that maybe we can
have an offline conversation about that
would be happy to work with you to
update the document okay and if I can
just very briefly respond I think what
needs to be done in that respect is to
broaden perhaps the scope of the
documents to include not only server
recommendations for somebody who's
logging a server but recommendations for
people also who are implementing server
software and people who are and you know
and so that could include something like
for instance server software should be
able to log source port and she would be
able to do it in a way that doesn't
impact the performance of the server
things like that when we wrote the
document we were expecting that people
were operating the software will go talk
to their vendors to do it but apparently
this has not happened or recommendation
was not strong in us and maybe we can
reward this yes
yeah and further there are also
scenarios for people who are writing
in-house software and we're trying to
comply with best practice might be
interested in implementing the
recommendations themselves not only
vendors but also you know end-users are
who are writing their own software
microburbs so I've been successful in in
using carrier-grade NAT port block
allocation so that one ipv4 address is
shared by 16 people and I just say okay
you want to know where that IPR is at
that point of time it's one of these 16
it's not millions it's 16 and I mean
police will immediately rule out most of
them and I'll say it's one of these
three and then then they have something
go on it
have to be millions if you do the
carrier great not right just spraying
the connections of millions of users
randomly across huge bases of ectopy for
others it just doesn't work does anyone
actually do that it's never done the in
one IP address well none obviously not
millions millions I'm being slightly
facetious but and I am aware that in I
think it's in Belgium they have a
regulatory obligation to be only allowed
to have 16 people right using one IP
address at a particular time and but
that's not the case everywhere and um
and yes I am aware of the situation in
Belgium and that there are and that has
as how did I guess a positive side
effect of they are now using ipv6 an
awful lot more than carrier-grade NAT
but and ipv6 also then comes with its
own separate kind of worms but that's
another description and I'm coming
through so yeah okay sorry thanks so
like responsible lady here so like I
wanna like not focus on the content of
the graph at this point okay so like the
idea of presenting this here is to
figure out if there's interest in
updating 6302 like you know Alan maybe
there's like stuff to be done and I want
the working group to own that work so
that's the first step we wanna figure
out like sit down and like you know ask
the working group at some point like on
the mailing list or if you wanna go hump
here that's fine but we are probably
running out of time you're asking the
mailing list like do we won't have this
date like 6302 to make it like more
practical so whatever changes then need
to get done so that's really what I
wanted to get out of this saying like
there's some feedback saying the
recommendations we made are not
practical
okay so the question is we need to
maintain our work so that's really the
reason I got like Dave to come and
present here okay I think thanks in
final lyric
everything this time a peach is
considered of Belgium it's not a
regulation in Belgium at all this is a
voluntary code of conduct by eyes yeah
and other parties that's okay I didn't
realize I didn't know what the what the
basis was but I was aware it was done in
volume yeah thanks
okay so thanks everyone for staying a
few minutes longer thanks date for the
presentation thank you I mean we're done
do you have some more blue sheets
somewhere there that you can pass by
please I'm sure what they actually say