okay let's start Andre we're starting so
good morning and welcome to IRT F open
I'm the IRT F chair Ellison and I think
it's Wednesday morning so we're already
like really tired and jet-lagged and not
getting up sleep so pay attention we
have a a new note well in the IETF and
the IRT F follows the IDF's note well so
this is our version of it which isn't
very different but just you should be
aware but if you haven't read this new
one because it's just getting rolled out
to take a look at it and in addition as
you know there's a photography how the
photography consent discussion and the
ITF has the IAS James made a statement
on this because we actually do have a
lot of photography in here because of
the NRP I want to make sure people know
that that if you don't want to be
photographed the there will be the video
but you will you're you have the right
to consent or not and you've got your
lanyards but also let us know if you
have any worries about that okay so I
just have a couple of things to say
about
I acted before we get started this is
the the sort of longer-term part of the
of the organization and we we definitely
have an interest in well focused
research that results in things that
innovate for the ietf of the idea here
is to give people the opportunity to see
their research get into action and it's
a time to incubate that and I'm sure you
know because you've been coming to
research groups that we have research
groups last time if you were here I
talked about how they're different I'm
not going to talk about that this time
and that we have an IR s G and their
names and all that information is on the
IRT F dot org page and I've noticed that
some people don't seem to know this so I
want to I've added it that our tip does
not produce standards we're pre
standards so to the extent that RFC's
come out of the IRT F they come out as
experimental or informational and
they're meant to say very clearly that
this is research and then one reason to
have them in the RFC form is that that
later they may evolve and migrate into
research into results that are used in
standardization but not in these
research groups so just that's something
and here's a list of all the research
groups the we have this concept of
proposed groups and the idea is that it
should be quite easy to spend something
up because it's not always easy to tell
when what's new and what's what's a good
thing to work on so they allow a group
to form very readily
unlike the working group chartering
process but it gets three meetings and
then the irst and I decide whether
they'll continue or not so we've got a
couple of proposed groups in process now
the the den group the
decentralized internet infrastructure
which really should be called deep it
subbed in and path aware networking and
then we have twelve groups all together
counting those two paths aware
networking had their third meeting
yesterday and we had a hum we do
actually
Humphrey can because who doesn't want to
hum but the and the agreement by the
group by the room was that should go to
our G and I believe it will so that's
something another bit of news is that
when our recent group gaya
which is the Internet access to the
internet for all globally is having
they've organized helped to organize
with the IAB the technical plenary
tonight so there are three gaya themed
talks and they're moderated by Jan
coffin who's one of the co-chairs of
Gaia
and then this week everybody's meeting
except the network management group we
we do feel that groups should meet with
research conferences as well sometimes
and they they regularly meet with the
noms conference and that's what they're
doing and then today you're getting the
first look at a potential new group
which is the quantum internet research
group and the goal here is to have you
eventually have to start calling
yourself the classical internet people
if you're not working on quantum so
we'll see if you're convinced of that
but we'll have a remote speaker on that
shortly okay so the other thing is I
want to advertise the the workshop we
have a workshop that tries to bring
academic research and and our and our
standards in the applied research we do
here all together it's been happening
for several years now it takes place
during the summer meeting and we have an
innovation this year which is that it
will take place during one of the IETF
days I'll talk a little bit more about
that at the plenary tonight the idea is
to try to bring more togetherness
between the people who come to talk
about applied research and the research
groups and working groups themselves
and you probably have something you'd
like to submit and it's due by April
20th so please think about submitting
it's really easy to find if you look up
in our W 2018 or look at the I RTF page
you can find it and the the good thing
is that you can either submit a short
paper like a couple pages of something
that says hot and new or you can submit
a previously published paper from the
past year so you don't have to write a
brand new deep 12-page research paper
you can bring to something that you've
done somewhere else to this workshop and
it was that they've been very good and
we're hoping they'll be it'll be even
better and even more exciting because of
the bringing it closer together to the
rest of the meeting okay
so these are some of the links if you
want to get more involved you probably
already know I RTF discussed and
announced and we have wiki links for all
the research groups that you can find
that irth orgs a mail we tweet and the
agenda for today is I'm almost done and
then rod Ben meters going to speak
Stephanie has a family issue so she will
not be joining us but we are hoping
these are the two proponents for that
research group and they'll rod will tell
you about how to get more involved in
that and then we have our applied
network research prize talks and I'm
very excited about those now introduce
those when we get there so I think we're
going to try to bring rod noise no let
me tell you about the NRP I'll use this
slide when when we come back I think no
let's do it now sorry so we have our two
speakers coming we are sponsored the the
AARP provides a monetary award and
travel funding and the sponsors that
make that possible are Comcast NBC
Universal and the Internet Society so
thank you and if you think you'd like to
sponsor please let me know get in touch
with I saw for myself match for myself
because if we get more sponsorships
we'll bring more people back for
additional meetings to allow increased
engagement
and I wanted to say also that we have a
wonderful program through the year we
have to each ITF we had the largest set
of submissions that we've ever had and
we could definitely have have made many
more Awards because we had so many good
submissions so I think you're gonna have
a good time with our presentation so and
that's it
and that picture is to tell you don't be
like that cat don't read your mail
engage during our meeting and it's
particularly actually for the art
research group chairs who who should
look around and if you see people being
like that cat you probably need to get
more discussion going that's my cat but
okay alright so let me see if I can get
us to rod now okay so let's see I have
it slides so rod can you speak yes
hopefully yes and I think I'm gonna be
showing your slides probably yeah I'm
told you you're the one who gets to run
the slides okay okay go for it I've got
your title page slide tell me when you
want to change okay great so thank you
all for having me and I'm sorry I'm not
actually there in person I would love to
be in London with you all but in
solidarity with the the whether you're
having there we're actually having snow
here in Japan actually in Tokyo - for
the first day of spring we planned this
presentation Alison asked us to give the
presentation based on the email that she
and Stephanie I had exchanged over the
course of the last Oh what six or eight
weeks I guess and I want to tell you a
little bit about what a quantum Internet
is and what we're thinking about and
ultimately why I RT F should care and
why RTI RTF should actually start our
working group
tell you how you can get involved in
what kinds of things that people in the
room there can do so as Alison said I'm
rod Van Meter I'm from Keio University
and the wide project so I actually
probably know a significant number of
you there in the room although I can't
say he's there very well and Stephanie
Vader is from the Technical University
of Delft this was actually originally
her idea and she used to work for one of
the the I believe for an ISP and the
Netherlands before actually getting
involved in quantum work so she and I
both have a long history with actual
networking as well as a quantum stuff so
that's where we are
Allison can you go to the next slide
please I have okay so the one other
person I should probably introduce while
we're looking at this slide here I think
somewhere in the room is shota Nagayama
shelter can you wave your hand if you're
there somewhere you may be around some
youth in that okay so was mine he is
actually also a participant in IETF so
he's one of the other people who
actually sits right at this border of
quantum and classical stuff so after I
go offline here in an hour so you want
you can track down shota there at the
meeting in London and talk to him about
it so first off I should say what is a
quantum network and I know a lot of
people in the room are already familiar
with quantum key distribution quantum
key distribution is a way to use quantum
effects to create a shared sequence of
random bits that the physics of the
system is supposed to guarantee you are
known only to the two parties at the
endpoints and then you can use that set
of random bits for a key a key for IPSec
or kls or what
that's the easiest way to implement qkd
is actually using what we call a an
unentangled quantum network so it uses
single photons but that you don't
actually have to have complicated
memories and a complete quantum computer
that serves as the equivalent of your
router if it works it adds to the
longevity of the secrecy of your
encrypted information but it works only
over a limited distance 100 kilometers
or 200 kilometers through fiber but in
theory also works over satellite in fact
there have been demonstrations of that
over the course of the last couple of
years it's sort of weak and multi-hop
settings but better for point-to-point
it's a lot easier than in time building
entangled networks at the physical
implementation level but it's still not
very easy so a lot of you are probably
already familiar with the basic idea of
qkd you've heard us or somebody else
talking about it at some point that's
only one of the applications that we
actually envision for for networks in
the long run but those other kinds of
applications that I want to tell you
about require what's called an entangled
network I'm not going to go into the
details of what's going on at the
physical level but basically it means
that that you're creating a shared
quantum state over a distance and so the
work of the quantum network then is to
actually create that shared quantum
state entangled networks are good for a
set of applications I'm going to show
you those a little bit more in the next
slide and in theory using quantum
repeaters which are not like classical
repeaters a quantum repeater is more
like what what in the internet world we
would call a router using quantum
repeaters we can in theory coupled
together systems that are as an
arbitrary distance apart within sort of
the normal limitations of networking as
opposed to the distance over which you
lose a single photon which is the
limitation in unentangled networks also
next slide please
okay so on this slide I've actually got
who of how I think about the
applications for entangled quantum
networks there are three large bubbles
there the purple one is reputed
cryptographic functions the blue one is
sensor networks and that yellow one is
distributed computation you can see sort
of on there on the Venn diagram that
there are a set of potential
applications qkd is in the middle on the
right it's sort of a it sort of sits at
the border between sensor networks and
distributed cryptographic functions
because really what's actually happening
with qkd is it's behaving as a type of
sensor and detecting the presence or
absence of an eavesdropper in your
communication channel so that's one
potential use another one or two in the
distributed cryptographic functions up
there you can see at the top in the
center are Byzantine agreement and
leader election and if you look at
Byzantine agreement and secure leader
election and quantum key distribution or
the point of all three of those reduce
our dependency on public key one-way
functions and computational complexity
as the basis for for security proofs so
that's one potential area for the uses
of quantum networks in the lower-right
sensor networks
besides qkd itself there are two or
three other good uses for sensor
networks and many more being proposed
clocks is one of the important clock
synchronization there have been several
algorithms proposed
for doing this using quantum effects
that would in theory gain us
synchronization of clocks over a remote
distance that add a much higher level of
precision than what we can achieve today
using GPS or NTP or really classical
mekin
so that clock actually is a form of
reference frame it gives you it tells
you what the time is in a couple of
different places it allows them to
essentially synchronize the the axis of
time but distributed quantum states can
also in theory be used as a reference
frame in the physical sense as well and
so people are investigating different
kinds of sensors for that and also for
what's called for interferometry which
is how large-scale astronomical
installations collect light from
multiple telescopes or multiple radio
antennas and combine them into a single
signal so at that level it's very much a
physical level operation that's going on
there and then in the lower-left the
third circle the yellow one is
distributed computation and this and in
this sense is largely like the ARPANET
this is an a distributed system in which
you actually connect to and use servers
over a large distance over a long
distance and the idea is that even if
you have a computer that isn't very
capable at your site that you can
connect to a quantum mainframe somewhere
else out there in the world and be able
to use that quantum mainframe remotely
over the over the quantum network now
why is that different from just being
able to do what you can do today which
is log on to IBM's website and use a
quantum computer that's sitting in
Yorktown high
remotely via the web well if you begin
with quantum entanglement between your
site and the mainframe then it's
possible to do what's called blind
computation and the blind computation is
a mechanism for execute asking a server
to execute a function for you
without giving the server any
information about the input data the
algorithm that's being executed or the
output data so it's like
gendry's homomorphic encryption in in
terms of its role in the ecosystem
although the underlying technology is
very different if you're familiar with
homomorphic encryption you can think of
it in kind of same use so those are the
three broad areas in which I can see
uses for a quantum network distributed
cryptographic functions sensor networks
and distributed computation okay Alison
next slide please
ok so I mentioned repeat a minute ago
quantum repeaters quantum repeaters are
the equivalent of routers in the
internet and they have four basic tasks
which are listed up there on the screen
first is to make the basic entanglement
the basic quantum state over a single
hop over a fiber over a free space link
the second task is to be an edge the
different kinds of errors there are
including loss of photons and
inaccuracies in in the operations on
your quantum states and the problem the
fact that memory has limited lifetim the
third task is to extend entanglement
across multiple hops so you know the
behavior of a network and then the
fourth task is to actually be part of
that network including dealing with
routing and managing resources and
security and those sorts of things and
it's in particular those last couple of
bullet points that I that I think
that are there in the room likely to be
able to make a positive contribution
George's next slide please
okay so that gave you just three minutes
on the the why what is it that we want
to accomplish by doing doing this the
next thing I want to do is to sort of
give you an idea give you a sense of
what's going on in the world and the
fact that this is in fact happening on
the right hand side of the slide there
you could read
oh just logos from five startup
companies that have been around most of
them for a while now but overall in the
quantum information industry there are
now more than 50 startups many of them
that have been created within the last
year some of them are hardware companies
trying to build quantum computers some
of them are software companies trying to
figure out how to use the existing
quantum computers and the some of them
are networking companies that are here
on the slide are all huge IT companies
as far as I'm aware of none of these
companies are actually working on
quantum computers yet but that may very
well be internal efforts that they're
not actually talking about in public so
it's happening in the startup industry
it's also happening in the big labs IBM
Google Intel the Microsoft are getting a
lot of attention for their work and
there's also event venture funding
that's out there there's also of course
a lot of support from governments and so
there's an entire complete ecosystem of
people who are working to create a
quantum information technology industry
and I think you can argue that that the
fact that industry already exists today
so the technology the knowledge and the
ecosystem are all reaching this point
where we are sitting right at the edge
where it where this whole thing is going
to blossom over the next several years
when you see
actually Zeus for now the Quadro
repeaters arguably the hardest part of
all of this and so it's been people but
while it's going to be a little while
yet before quantum repeaters are out
there in the in the wide world as
something you people can go and buy off
of the shelf that's what we're working
next slide please
so Stephanie's really the one who ought
to be able to talk to you all about this
particular slide because the leaders of
this particular project at the Technical
University of Delft just to come a few
hundred kilometers or weary well right
now a couple of years ago this was
published in October 24 pushing on three
years ago since the experiments we're
done
the folks at Delft tiny pieces of
diamond that were set about a kilometer
apart and coerced them to hold qubits
quantum bits worth of data in there
inside that tiny chip of diamond and
also to emit photons and then they take
those photons and they route them
together as in the diagram at the bottom
of the slide there and then they conduct
an interference operation between the
the photons there in the middle once
that's done then we just want them
entanglement over this distance of 1.3
kilometers in the across the the Delft
campus so this can be done today an
optical fiber over over modest distances
it's experimentally up and running and
the lat the group end Delft is arguably
the world's best but there are a lot of
people who are working on similar sorts
of things next slide please okay
so besides just doing this using fibers
that are actually in the ground or in
buildings in between there's also been
work on doing this using satellites and
you may have heard about this and made a
tremendous amount of news last summer
when China had succeeded in receiving
quantum signals on the ground were
essentially qkg between two stations on
the ground there they're separated by
about a thousand kilometers or so but
later they continue to conduct
experiments they had already prepared
for them there with the satellite and
they continue to conduct them and they
have actually generated entanglement
across that across that kind of distance
and they have also more recently used a
slightly different approach where the
the satellite is actually used as a
relay station
and so it performs qkd between the
satellite and the ground when it flies
over China and it stores the classical
bits it is created in the process in the
memory of the satellite and then when
the satellites orbit carries it over
Austria then they perform qkd
again between the satellite and Austria
and then they have created a secure key
that's shared between Austria and China
now this was actually in the news quite
a bit last summer where or last fall
when they talked about it and used the
the key that was so generated to encrypt
a conversation between China and Vienna
so it got a lot of press we can talk
about the actual security implications
for all of that and whether or not you
have to trust the satellite platform and
things like that
for qkd
but when you're actually using it excuse
me for creating entanglement over this
kind of distance then those kinds of
security arguments are actually very
different and so please if you're
already of a particular mind with
respect to a qkg in certain senses
realize that the arguments are going to
be very different with when we're
talking about wide area networks that
actually provide entanglement in the end
and China's not alone in doing work on
this there have also been experiments
from Canada and Singapore and the other
picture there on the on the right and
the upper part is actually a satellite
that when it's in orbit right now that
was put up there by Japan last year as
well so satellite work and also
ground-based work is going on in this
next slide please
okay and ultimately there's work going
on all around the world but Europe right
now is one of the places where that
where there's a tremendous amount of not
individual effort but very focused
effort so the in the EU has a quantum
internet effort that's known as the
quantum internet alliance there's a logo
for it there on the left and a URL
quantum - internet dot team and you can
see going back by going to that website
you can see the the list of researchers
were involved in this Stephanie again is
one of the prominent researchers that's
involved I wish you were here to tell
you more about it but it's part of the
EU overall 1 billion euro effort to
[Music]
develop quantum technologies and bring
them out of the laboratory and into the
actual market
my place okay so what does it take to
actually build one of these networks
this slide comes from a paper that I
wrote fully a decade ago on protocols
for quantum repeaters and you'll see
that there's there's sort of a stack
many of you in the room probably know
Joe touch Joe touch and I or argued
about this quite a bit over various
meals and and visits to each other the
upper layers everything except the
bottom is actually a classical control
protocol so at the bottom in the purple
box you see it says physical
entanglement and red letters they're the
only quantum that's the only part of the
entire system that's actually physically
quantum though everything else that's
above it is classical protocols for
controlling the behavior of this quantum
system in order to go from having
entanglement that exists over a single
link to entanglement that actually spans
end-to-end from your your communication
endpoints now the protocol stack that's
above it involves a series of functions
which are going to depend on certain key
design decisions from your your general
architecture from your your quantum
repeaters but this is a reasonable
example some of it happens over a single
hop some of it happens over two hops or
four hops along the path chosen through
the network and that some of it's done
to end-to-end and that's where the
argument with Joe touch comes in is all
right well maybe it's not really a
layered protocol in the sense that the
ITF is a customer things it's actually
much more of a distributed computation
because all of the individual nodes that
are in the path actually participate
very actively in the entire process as
you are
conducting your communications over an
extended period of time
so it's it's a very different approach
and the Internet's fire and forward and
forget approach to building a protocol
but this is an area where classical
protocol design people can make a very
strong positive contribution because of
the expertise in doing these kinds of
things and that's it yes so Allison
perfect timing to switch to the next
slide there so we are getting to the the
stage of wanting to take all of this and
discuss these kind of important problems
again any network how you deal with
routing and how you deal with
connections set up and how you deal with
resource management and how you deal
with Internet work interoperability and
security and all these kinds of issues
which are near and dear to the hearts of
the people that are there in the room at
IRT F and the experimental physicists
who are doing the work so far have no
idea how any of this stuff is done they
don't know how to go about setting up a
connection between between two nodes
across the network they don't know
anything about how you do resource
management and in a wide area network
you know know what multiplexing means in
a single channel but not so much across
an entire network for example so we need
the expertise of the people in the room
and we need a way to connect classical
networking people to the experimental
community that's beginning to do build
these quantum repeated networks
so Stephanie proposed two or three
months ago that we should create a
research group inside a by RDF though I
contacted Allison and we've been
exchanging some email about it and so
far the proposed is Qi RG the mailing
list is open you are welcome to join the
mailing list there were a couple of
dozen people on it
ready even though we're just beginning
the process of advertising it so please
get on the mailing list and Alison next
slide please
whoops okay this is not the all right
the will do will do this I did want to
mention briefly as well as we're
finishing up that there are also queue
can be oriented standardization efforts
both inside of Etsy and I Triple E and
of course inside of the IETF we have
been talking off and on for eight or ten
years about methods for incorporating UK
degenerated keys into IPSec and dealing
with other outbound out of be and key
management mechanisms for key generation
mechanisms so there's work that's going
on on that as well
next slide please and the the first task
if you join us in the in the queue IRG
mailing list is maybe perhaps somebody
in the room there can suggest a prettier
name than queue by RG which we haven't
even yet agreed on a pronunciation for
we're not sure if it's a turd or quirk
or what it is we understand some of the
elements that are going to be in the
Charter there's some of the things that
I mentioned on the previous slide a
minute ago but there's of course we're
to do to hammer out the actual content
of that and the tentative plan is for
qyrg to meet three times a year
once at IETF once at some sort of
quantum conference either queue crypt
which is a qkt focused meeting or the
workshop for quantum repeaters and
networks which is a a repeater oriented
workshop and then to have one meeting be
virtual so meet three times a year on
that schedule and that's it let's say
next slide please yep so the we will be
having the next of the wrm workshops
actually here in Japan in fall of 2019
and if you are on the mailing list of
course you will get the announcement
you'll you know ask to join up with us
on that and with that I hope that you
all are as excited about building a
quantum Internet as I am Alison I guess
we have time for questions
I think there's time for a few questions
if people have any and hopefully you'll
hear them well let's say your name when
you come up here at econo Cosima thanks
for a talk I have a one qualifying
question in one question about I
carrasco network and a contaminate oh so
the first name first question is so
according to your site page number nine
it's like there is no IP or TCP SciQuest
called network stack but but yours your
figures say it's like a that only a
bottom layer it's that quantum network
so I think we can there we can it seems
like there is a new different network
and we are trying to create the quantum
network instead of that cross car
network so is that my understanding is
after we will create a new network is
that correct
that is a qualify question and also the
second question is so if the quantum
computer cannot we cannot use IP or
those kursk or network stack so in this
case like it's it's a little bit hard to
connect the connector communicate
between the classical network and
quantum network so do use is current
scope charter has some kind of work to
achieve the communication between
classical network and the quantum
network yes I didn't how are you
so the those are good questions so
Allison if you can go back to that slide
briefly the one the one with the it with
the colored stacked by
is the yeah the stacks like tell it yeah
we are going to have to have a new
physical layer so there's there's no
getting around that that's going to mean
deploying new new devices with new
transceivers or the equivalent thereof
there is work going on to allow that to
multiplex with standard tcp/ip traffic
inside the same fiber that's been
demonstrated experimentally so you'll
need new load new nodes but you don't
necessarily need to pull come the
completely new fiber in parallel all of
those other functions that are on top of
that are all new protocols but of course
they also need a means to exchange their
their classical messages reliably so so
when I picture the the the protocols PC
and ES I picture those communications
actually happening over top of TCP and
then the application layer on top of
that is the it's it's a what's what's
the equivalent of an HTTP put and get or
I for quantum network what is a request
from an application to the network
itself what what is it that it that that
you're a classical application that's
running on a node that wants to take
advantage of these services provided by
the quantum Internet
how does it make that request what does
that contain how do you exchange that
and how do you agree on the semantics of
all of that so those colored boxes that
are on there I think largely will ride
on top of TCP in terms of the actual
communication that gets done but it's
building a large distributed application
on top of it does that help
yep okay thanks great one more question
West vertical USCIS I you know
originally I was thinking that that this
was a little bit early in the in
thinking but then I decided that I'm
wrong there and and we want to get this
sort of right from the get-go in terms
of Marie's output of something like this
could actually affect you know the
development of the hardware and the
technique so I think that's actually
that the timing is about perfect so I'm
excited to see this go forward I do
think that there's a few other topics
you can consider adding to your list of
things to explore such as the security
requirements for what's going to be
layered on top of it in particular with
respect to privacy concerns as an
example your satellite is sort of a
classic case of a store and forward
mechanism where you have to store data
at rest well it you know while it
travels or interplanetary networks have
the same kind of thing excuse my
ignorance of quantum stuff I'm actually
fairly ignorant and it may show but you
know so the quantum routers have a
similar property where since you're
essentially breaking communication
between in the middle between endpoints
then you're disturbing the privacy that
I believe is offered by quantum
generally so you know what's the
security implications of that so I think
there's a number of things that need to
be considered with respect to what sort
of technologies you need above that and
the requirements above that do you still
need to do you know sent what what sort
of encrypted traffic do you need to send
above that and what are the properties
are the protocols that you're earning is
on top of this whole system that you can
either relax because you have quantum or
you still need because quantum doesn't
solve them absolutely sign that man up
and seven person from a site myself I'd
love to have you on board because
that'll give me an excuse to go back I
as I&C the game okay one more question
shota yeah actually yeah certain I mean
speaking actually is not a question just
comments so right now the researchers
are canta networking requires
organization over time neuroses I
yeah because some papers started to
propose some different terminologies for
washing same concept
so I needed a I need a place for open
discussion for such things as otherwise
so you know various papers which use
these different terminology will lead to
a kind of help so to avoid that we need
yeah we need an open discussion so our
idea is a best price I believe so and
and now we can refactor network timing
of this property here and so another
thing is so one thing we needed to
discuss enjoy our tea is the obstruction
of the entanglement and you know the
entanglement is a very quantum property
and no Kruskal need talking it doesn't
the hub the counterpart for that so we
should carefully discuss the obstruction
of entanglement and at last
yeah so one thing so is a one benefit to
talk about continuity mean iltf
is that so julio administrate contem
network in the future so it will the
network engineer so like guys here so
yeah to involve such people for
discussion of quantum networking is very
important from this RT station thanks
actually I agree with with all of those
comments in particular you know that
I've had quite a bit of heartburn where
the the physicists reuse a term they
have picked up from classical
engineering and the way they're using
it's not necessarily wrong it's just so
different from the way we're used to
using it that it's causing a problem
multiplexing is one of them repeater
would certainly be another and of course
you're they are they also when they say
the physics of this meeting guarantees
that it's secure you know the
the the head of every network
administrator in the room hits the desk
because they know that that theoretical
factors of implementations are very
different from from the real-world
implications and so doing all of this
and discussing all of this with the
people who understand real networks is
the key to a long-lived healthy robust
extensible quantum internet architecture
and I think the IRT F has a lot of
expertise that's really required yeah
we've got one more question and then
we'll stop no more questions very cool
hi I'm Eric oh um okay I'm not so
familiar with this area and this is
comment ready to this community and I'm
not like I am sure corner computer and
computing is important for network
engineering and so now on the future um
but I think there is not so many people
who are familiar with this area so um so
if you will walk on this corner
computing discussion in this ayat if
area um how do how do you get IP network
engineers involved in this discussion
and also on how do you link on the
corner computer guys from outside this
community come into this idea community
um how how how about your plan for that
well the social you know that I'm I was
pleased to hear the earlier comment that
you the I didn't catch the name of the
guy from ISI that I don't know it was a
who said that you now he sees that maybe
now is the right time if we and and it's
a good opportunity for people to be
involved to prevent the physicists from
going down the wrong path
now convincing the physicists that they
need to be involved that's the other
half of the equation and we're working
on that one too but there are already
hundreds of researchers around the world
who are actually working on this and you
know
we have those two quantum conferences
that I mentioned the workshop for
quantum repeaters and networks we
restrict attendance to that to to a
hundred people so that we can have a
small conversation but we could have
twice that many people and the queue
crypt conference is three to five
hundred people depending on the location
there so there are a lot of people
around the world who are already working
on the technologies and the goal is to
bring them together with with the people
who really understand the the way
networks behave because I think you need
more um you need to enhance more people
for another area into these discussions
that's why I absolutely be the start
today so we should we should go move on
to our next talk but thank you so much
rod and audience yeah Matt yeah I just
wanted to say I'm using the ether pad
for taking notes so you might want to go
in there if you asked a question and
make sure I didn't butcher your name or
a butcher what you said thank you thank
you
and the the slides Alison yep which I
assume will get uploaded there are some
references in there that I didn't talk
about but you can look up those
references if you want to know more or
contact me and join the research and
join the mailing list they are uploaded
already so so that people can do that
okay so thank you that's great
bye I'm gonna switch off and we're going
to introduce our next speaker now so the
that we have the first of our NRP
presentations you want to come up to
here and let me get your slides up here
as well okay and I think
do you want to sorry
yep
this is the ones you gave me late in the
night but they are almost thinking about
making them larger but I don't think you
can it's probably about as good
oh you hear yes
okay um they're government
that's okay okay yeah yeah you should be
able to do that and see if it works okay
just tell me what's there
I think it's not working
I think I have the right attachment
yes okay all right
introduce yourself hi everyone Muskaan
I'm gonna present to you our work on
performance characterization of a
commercial major streaming service my
current affiliation is with Akamai but I
did this work when I was HDC that at
Princeton and interning at Yahoo
research so we all have had that
experience that remember watching our
favorite video and there is a buffering
and you end up wondering why and even as
the networking community we often wonder
what happened and what's the problem and
in this work we have an unprecedented
data set - for the first time instrument
and study the entire end-to-end video
delivery path and with video being the
dominant application of the internet
with making up more than 70% of the
traffic at least in North America during
peak hours it's particularly important
for us and we can uncover a wide range
of problems for the first time with this
data set because we have data from the
entire half so I'm gonna walk you
through a list of performance problems
that we have found them oh you must have
touched the registry it changed what
Nathan esterday Erica you are
it's writing to improve the same oh I
see
oops no that's not good I don't know why
I see what you say maybe we should just
sorry how about that okay so here's the
list of problems that we have found
don't worry about reading this because
what are we walking through this talk so
first let me start by showing you search
on on projection systems a yes
I can actually okay let's get her a
laptop yeah should we have a research
task force for the projectors and
displays yeah maybe by the time we have
quantum microphones you have that I
don't think it's the same donk Ozzfest
oh is it USB I dunno
oh you have AI HDMI directly good okay
yes okay yeah you got to restart your
time we're letting her restart her time
too okay they also get this alright
thank you for your patience everybody
all right we're back in business so
here's the list of performance problems
that we found but don't worry about it
I'm gonna walk you through this list
through talk but before that let's look
at the system to be instrument it so you
can get an idea what could go wrong
before we show you what did go wrong
so the system is Yahoo's video streaming
system and the way that streaming works
very high-level overview it starts by
the client which is your player
requesting and receiving the manifest
and it manifests it's the list of
available bit rates and then there's
usually an adaptive better algorithm on
the player that chooses which bitrate to
request for and then once it decides the
mid rate it sends an HTTP request to the
CDN to get that and in this system these
HTTP requests are sharing the same TCP
connection and it chunk in this system
is six seconds once these requests
arrive at the city and the city and
inspects its local cache if it's there
to the player if it's not there it's
called a cache miss and you go to the
back end to fresh check on it first
our Citians in this system the city
servers are using Apache traffic server
which is a popular HTTP proxy and the
caching eviction policies LRU and then
finally when these chunks are arrived at
the client side they have to pass the
clients download and rendering stack
before they can be shown to the user and
we will go into more details of what
these mean later in the talk when we get
to the client section so our goal in
this study is to identify performance
problems that impact video QE and in
particular make the users are happy so
you know reduce your revenue and if you
have only data from the players side for
example if you have here a data for
example the caveat is that you may be
able to detect some of these problems
you may be able to say there was a
rebuffering but because of the buffer
itself you are some of the problems get
masked because of the buffer so you may
not see an immediate impact on the QE
and also if you only have players like
information you cannot detect problems
that happen in network or the CDN and
looking at it from the other side from
the perspective of if you have only data
from the CDN for example server logs you
may be able to detect some of the
problems but you will not be able to
isolate problems that are within the
clients machine so fortunately for us we
are looking at this from a contra
providers point of view for example
Yahoo or Google could do this and what's
unique about them is that they control
both sides so this is an in-house CDN
and their own player and once you have
mu into the entire path of the video
delivery then you can find problems
everywhere and see exactly what happened
for each chunk that you had buffering so
our approach relies on three principles
one is n - an instrumentation we
instrument both sides of this path
including the player and is CDN servers
and this is important for us to join
this together to be able to construct
the life of a chunk but
and where the instrumentation unit is
pair trunk because a chunk is a unit of
decision-making in this system for
example the bit rate that the replica
algorithm chooses may change from chunk
to chunk but not within a chunk and
whether the file was a cache hit or miss
at the CDN also may change in the
granola tea or the chunk we did consider
subject measurements there are two
reasons that we did not go with it one
is that it is too expensive and this is
a production player CD and this is not
an experiment
experimental player or CDM and once you
start using too much CPU on the player
you can have a negative impact on the QE
and the users may start seeing the
frames may get dropped and things like
that but also going sub chunk it and
doing sub check measures can sometimes
be technology dependent because the way
that gm5 handles data arrivals different
from flash and we wanted the results to
be applicable to all internet video and
finally collecting TCP statistics the
statistics that we are collecting here
they're sampled from the CDN host kernel
there are some limitations here as well
this is an operational and large-scale
setting so there's a frequency that we
can collect these a prepare this
information is not high so what do we
mean by this end-to-end parent
measurement so the boat lines here are
where we are measuring things directly
and the dashed lines are aware we cannot
instrument things directly so
observations based on interference and
the life of the charm starts with player
sending an HTTP GET request writes at
the CDN the CDN has some processing time
and we showed that with d CDN if this
was a cache miss and back-end needs to
be involved to get the first byte then
there's a back in legacy everything that
is not measured directly is shown with
read and everything that is measured
directly in this instrumentation shown
with blue and then finally the first
byte arrives at the player the time
difference between when de should we get
request was sent
and when the first fight arrived is
shown with TFB first by the way and
there is also the download second I can
see shown with red DDS and similarly
when you have the last part of the chunk
of writing that's the time difference
between the first and the last is shown
with DL you'll ask why and this is
important because this is going to come
up for different kind of studies that we
do so before I show you our results I
want to point out that we are studying
QE factors individually in this talk the
factors that we choose this there is
this is a very rich area of research and
they have shown that most important QE
factors that impact the users experience
our video startup time the buffering
rate with your qualities such as
betrayed and framerate and we look at
these factors individually instead of
coming up with the QE score because of
two reasons one is depending on the type
of content that you have some of these
factors may matter more than the others
for example for a breaking news video
start-up time matters more because the
user just wants to see the news whereas
when you're sitting to watch a long
movie the start time we do not matter
that much or give you a quality matters
more and second is the length of the
video shorter videos users are usually
less patient you want to have the
results you want to have so you want to
start playing right away whereas with
the longer video the user is already
patient they have it in their mind that
they're gonna sit and watch to our video
so this is the outline of the talk we've
already gone through the introduction
I'm gonna show you the measurement data
so that we have and then what are the
problems that we found in server-side
network or client-side and then we're
going to conclude the talk with
takeaways on what can be done about
these problems
so today's that comes from Yahoo videos
they're played over a variety of sites
for example in news sports finance and
like I said this is this is the real
player that was used in a variety of
sites our dataset comes from 18 days
this is a video on demand data of 85 CDN
servers across the u.s. were
instrumented selected randomly we
studied 65 million video sessions and
more than half a billion video chunks
the users are predominantly in North
America over 93% and mostly non mobile
users that are not using proxy we're
going to more details in the paper and
how we remove users that we think are
behind a proxy and the main reason for
that is we want the TCP measurements to
reflect the path between the server and
the client and usually the proxies
terminate the TCP connections so it
would make our results not accurate in
terms of the video streams distribution
this is a popular heavy workload with
66% of the requester I mean for the top
10% of the titles and most of these
videos are shorter than 100 seconds so
let's dive into the first category
problems the server side problems so our
measurement in the server side comes
from direct measurement so at the player
we have such an ideal chunk ID start up
time to buffering in video and at the
city and we have such a tiny chunk ID
similarly we are measuring server
latency back in latency and cache
Pyramus so because we have this data
readily available we can show for
example the immediate impact of several
latency on startup time there is no
interference there it's just ground
truth so for example this is one graph
that we can do because we have data from
both sides and you can show the impact
of several agency instead of time the
x-axis on this graph is the several ACC
milliseconds the y-axis is the start
time of the video in seconds and you can
see how it significantly increases with
higher server latency so next we are
interested in knowing
why do I have these servers with these
high latency the first issue that we
found is the Apache traffic server
Vishal timer and cache misses so what
happens when an HTTP request arrives at
the CDN is that it first inspects the
memory and if it's not there you go to
the disk and if it's not there you go to
back-end however you don't want to
overwhelm the back end so when multiple
requests come for the same content
there's usually a timer there that stops
you from going to the next yearfor for a
while to not overwhelm the backend and
be fine and we found this miss
configuration that was that was still in
true between the memory and the disk and
it was impacting about 65 percent of the
chunks in our study but even more
important than that is cache misses we
found cache misses in this system
increases their relation significantly
the median increases by 40 times an
average by 10 times when your server
side has a cache miss and we also found
these extreme cases where several agency
was worse than Network and for those
sessions they were often caused by cache
misses the average cache miss ratio in
this data set is 2% for the sessions
that had more server latency than
network was 40 percent so it is often
caused by this significant impact of
cache misses on the server latency
another interesting thing that we found
is that server side problems are
persistent it means that once the
session starts having server-side
problems its persistent it stays and for
example like I said the average cache
miss ratio is 2% if you look at the
conditional probability of the sessions
that had a 1 cache miss the cache miss
ratio for those sessions goes up 60%
that means that cache misses are coming
in groups and that's usually because of
unpopularity of the title so once a
title is unpopular its chunks are more
likely to reside in disk or worse gate
work it in the backend and you start
having cache misses but every single one
of these chunks are going to go through
that
and in fact we found interesting paradox
in the system that it seems like more
heavily loaded servers seem to have
lower latency but this is a result of
the Cashbook is mapping cache focus
mapping is you're trying to have hot
caches so survey is sending the request
to where it was recently served from
which causes your popular content to go
to the same servers and your popular
contents have better performance because
of the reasons Asian nation but you also
have more requests for your popular
content so there's this there are these
servers that are less have less demands
because they're serving unpopular
content but have more performance so the
Connie popularity is even dominating a
server load in this case so the next
category of problems are network
performance problems so we're all
familiar with network problems that can
manifest themselves in the shape of
packet loss reordering high latency
variation of latency and so on and they
can be transient or persistent it's
important to notice and and separate
these two from each other from video QE
perspective because video does have the
adapter picture algorithm that you may
be able to adapt to some transient
problems but you can't avoid bad QE
forever when their problems are
persistent and the way to fix those is
by CDNs or ice fees actually taking
corrective actions for example
fixing peering so our network
measurements come from us instrumenting
or host care and also basically the
orange box here is showing what the
operating system is doing which is
there's this TCP infrastruc and os is
collecting we have this information
about all the TCP connections including
a weighted average of RT T's called
smooth Artie T or SRT T congestion
window and packet retransmissions and
what we do is the blue box that is we
pull this every 500 milliseconds per
trunk and store it and then later we use
it across chunks and across sessions to
see
what happened in a network of course
there are some challenges in collecting
in this way we're looking at smooth
averages of Artie T or s RT T's instead
of individual RT C's and that's not
sometimes a good idea especially if you
are dealing with these long connections
for video streaming because the SRC C is
not reflecting your RT t during this
chunk exactly but what happened in all
the previous chunks this network
snapshot frequency is also infrequent
500 milliseconds in many cases is more
than the RT t of the connection but it
comes from operational limitations and
how often we have you were allowed to
pull this and how much data we were
producing in terms of storage overhead
and finally because this is it this is
it operational at scale we can't collect
packet traces and in the paper be going
to more details and how we grapple with
these challenges but I'm just going to
show you they're interesting findings so
here's another similar graph that you
can do because we know that a network
latency and for example the SRT T of the
first chunk and we also know the set-up
time so if you look at the SRT T of the
first chunk that's the x-axis here and
the impacts on the start time of the
video the impact is visibly clear and
how it impacted their is a significant
impact on the video startup time so
let's dig in here and see what causes
this network latency to be so high so to
do this we are aggregated akiko fixes
the client IP prefixes in 2/24 and we
looked at them ones that are mostly
carrying in a 90th percentile every day
so we're looking at the tail of a tail
and among those we found 75% of them to
be located far from our CDN so
geographical distance or propagation
delays the main cost but surprisingly
about 25% of them are located in the US
and majority of them are actually close
to our city ends and but they further
investigation and we saw that there
there's also a high latency variation
which is a little bit different from a
high baseline it's just the variation
and in both cases we find that majority
of these prefixes
are in enterprise networks not
residential networks and what we
speculate is happening here is that
these enterprise networks are running
their middleboxes which are causing high
latency and high latency variation
despite the fact that they're so close
to the city ends now of course we do not
and we do not have in network data to
confirm it's just a speculation of why
we see this high latency in only in
enterprise networks and not residential
ones the second finding is the impact of
packet losses this is this graph is
generally what we expect to see in terms
of how your transmission rates or losses
impact we do QE in terms of your
buffering rate generally we see that
higher loss rate indicates higher
rebuffering rate but that's not all and
in fact we saw I'm sorry the timing of
the losses are more important than the
amount of your loss rate and this is
important for us as a measurement
community to be aware of the fact that a
loss rate measuring loss rate does not
necessarily always correlate with QE and
the location or the timing of the losses
matter sometimes more so in this graph
we're showing you the x-axis the chunk
IDs zero being the first chunk and the
y-axis is showing the percentage chunks
that had rebuffering and the blue graphs
are showing that amount so what's the
percentage of the chunks that hadley
buffering and it is higher for first
chunk and you may think because of the
loss so to take that into consideration
we calculated the green wore the green
plots so those are the conditional
probability of percentage of chunks that
Hadley buffering given there was a loss
at this chunk and you can see that if
there is loss the percentage of the repo
Franco is higher for everyone but it
goes significantly higher for the first
channel so this is because of the
existence of a buffer in a video
streaming fashion so when you have a
buffer in a video streaming session it
initially it's not full so it cannot
hide these impacts from the user but
later on in the video sharing session
when you're on a
haier chunk ids then there is enough
buffer to hide some of these impacts
from the users so here's an example case
he's a very extreme case so here we're
looking at two sessions red had
rebuffering and green did not have any
buffering and you're also looking at the
distribution of the last race this is
rich transmission rate in chunks and you
can see that the red session that happy
buffering has actually generally lower
lower row three and the green had
significantly higher rate transmission
rates but because they happened after
the first four chunks which is already a
buffering twenty four seconds of video
because each chunk is six seconds the
user actually never finds out about it
whereas the red session is very unlucky
it has losses in the first truck and
right there it has a deep offering so
here's an example of how the location of
the losses seem to be even better more
than the loss rate
unfortunately we found earlier packet
losses are also more common so you saw
they are more harmful but they are also
more comment this is because of the
bursty nature of packet loss in the tcp
slow-start but we'll talk about how some
servers like pacing can help but this
graph is showing you this graph is
showing you to arbitration especially a
chunk ID you can see this huge
difference in chunk IDs zero versus
others and finally we found throughput
to be a bigger problem then latency for
media streaming so here we have defined
a performance score which is a direct
charge generation in our case it's six
seconds divided by a first black plus
last byte and the first byte is a
measure of latency if you remember from
this graph first plague was the time
difference between when - we get request
was santander in the first boy drive so
it includes the network latency and the
serial agency and if you have back-end
if you have a cache miss also back in
latency and the last point delay is
basically a measure of three point
because
the difference between the first and the
last byte of this video so we have
divided the chunks in our data set into
two sets based on if this performance
scores more than 1 or less than 1 when
the score is more than 1 that means more
than one second of video is delivered
per second to this player and from very
simple queuing algorithms if you have
more than one second video delivered to
your player but the user is watching one
second of video per second you're gonna
build up buffer and when the score is
less than 1 that means less than one
second of video is delivered to your
buffer your users still watching one
second of video per second and that
means you're depleting the buffer
expected to have a rebuffering at some
point so once we divided our chunks into
these two sets we found that the
contribution of the last byte delay in
the bad trunks was orders of magnitude
higher than latency and this shows to us
that throughput seems to be having a big
contribution in these chunks that do not
arrive in time third categorical
problems are within the client so what
is the client download stack when the
chunks are arrived from the network and
before they are delivered to our player
they go through the download stack at
the client which is the neck the OS and
the browser before they're finally
handed over to the player and
unfortunately for us at scale we cannot
observe the download stack like you can
see directly because we can't go and
instrument these clients and see what's
happening at their browser or network
card so here we're relying on detecting
outliers so here we're doing some
statistical work to see if there is a
chunk that seemed to have been buffered
at the download stack so if a chunk has
been buffered at downloads that I expect
it to be delivered late to the player
and that means that I'm expecting the
first byte to be significantly higher
than others so let's say it's two Sigma
away from my mean but also because it
was buffered at the download stack and
delivered so late
to the player I expect it to be arriving
at the machines throughput not at the
connections throughput so it's gonna
have very high stint in es throughput
from the perspective of the player so
let's say it's 2 Sigma away from the
mean again but it should not have been
caused by network and server so it
should have similar network and server
performance so here's one example that
we found in our data set the graph on
the top shows you the latency matrix and
look at chung-kai d7 and you can see
that it has similar RTT and several
metrics server latency but it has a
significantly higher first byte delay
than the rest of the chunks so what we
expect this happening here is that this
chunk was buffered at the client down
the stack and deliberate late to the
player and then the throughput
measurements are at the bottom you can
see the blue line is connection
throughput and we know the connection
throughput because we know the condition
we know an RTT and the red line is
showing the download throughput from the
perspective of the player and you can
see that the same chunk seems to have a
significantly higher instantaneous
throughput almost four times more which
disconnected is not possible in this
connection as we are approaching this so
it's important to be aware of these
problems that we can only find with once
we have data from both sides because if
you don't have this each side is going
to blame the network or the other for
these problems and this can be very
dangerous in the video streaming world
because if your player makes incorrect
assumptions about for example agency
from their first graph and if the
adaptive bitrate algorithm is latency
sensitive it can cause undershooting
because it may freak out and think the
latency had a spike where reality it
didn't or if your player is sensitive to
throughput and it's using the lower
graph then it may think the world is so
much better than it actually is and it
can cause overshooting in it after PA
algorithm so it's important for the
player to have some view into the
network path that in our system the
player didn't because we only had these
TCP measurements at the server
so we found these the adonis-like
problems they're transient problems that
are that I just described to you
you found them to be more common in
their first chunk and in debate where we
going to more details of how this could
be a possible side effect of Flash and
we also have persistent down low psych
problems the persistent download psych
problems are not very common but what's
important about them is once they happen
they they often are the most important
factor and they are higher than network
and server latency and there's more
in-depth conversation about them in the
paper if you're interested in that and
finally the last category of problems
are the rendering stack performance
problems so what is rendering stack so
the chunks have finally arrived at the
player but they're not ready to be shown
on the screen yet and here we have a
rendering stack these chunks need to be
D MUX meaning the audio should be
separated from the video and then they
have to be decoded and finally render
and this can be done by CPU or GPU if it
is done by GPU it's called Hardware
rendering if it's done by CV it's called
software rendering
now if the CPU is busy and you're using
software rendering the quality may drop
which causes high frame drops but also
if your video tab is not visible your
browser's do optimizations to reduce
your CPU consumption so they
intentionally drop frames so to detect
these problems but to separate them from
browser optimizations we have introduced
boolean variable which is this player
visible or not and also we're measuring
the drop frames and then for each
session we are also collecting what OS
and browser it has and there are some
interesting findings here first one is
that good rendering is actually time
consuming we found that the multiplexing
decoding and rendering takes time and
you have to provision for that if you
want to have a good frame rate and so in
this graph we're showing you the
download rate of the chunk the average
download rate of the chunk and x-axis
and what's the percentage of the drop
frames and you can see the drop up to
about one and a half second per sec
and that's what we recommend to use as a
rule of thumb please in this system for
avoiding having higher drop frames next
we found kind of a paradox again higher
bit rates showing better rendering so
higher bit rates put more load on CPU
and as I explained to you a software can
be expensive so we're expecting them to
have worse frame rate but we actually
see them having better rendering
framerate and if we need further
investigation you can see the numbers in
the paper but in summary we found these
high higher bit rates coming from
connections that had lower RTT variation
and lower assurance machinery so they
were often requested in better
conditions and as a result they had they
were able to provide the one and half
second per second rule more often and
had a lot of extra time to process this
and the impact was hidden from the user
and finally we found some very unpopular
browsers that had a really bad rendering
so here we're looking at chunks that had
already good performance so the rate the
arrival rate is more than 1/2 second per
second and we know the player is visible
because we're filtering on the only
these chunks that have visibility so the
user is actually watching and we divided
the chunks into two major platforms
Windows and Mac and this blue guards are
just showing you the percentage of the
chunks in each platform for each browser
and they're sorted from more popular to
this popular and here you're looking at
the percentage of the drop frames in
each of these browsers combinations you
can see the trend is the opposite and we
found so in the paper we further break
down the other category which are the
least popular each in each one of them
and there are some interesting cases
there that have really bad rendering
despite the fact that we have made sure
that ever I've already is good and
everything else is similar one of the
interesting examples are Safari is
actually really good at Mac but it's
among one of the worst on Windows and on
Windows other section there's
there's some less popular browsers like
Yandex and see monkey that we found that
had huge problems in terms of rendering
so I walk you through all these problems
but let's see what are the takeaways I
mean what can we do about all of these
problems that each one of these places
so let's start with the CDN I discussed
three problems with you about the CDN
one is the impact of cache misses
so in this workload we're looking at
popular heavy workloads and I told you
we are using the LRU cache eviction
policy because of the impact of cache
misses that are so high and the workload
is popular have you proposed using other
policies that are more tuned for these
kind of workloads like GD size or
perfect all of you in terms of the cache
miss persistence we propose prefetching
subsequent chunks this is the problem
that I discussed with you that once the
session starts having cache misses it
every one of its chunks is gonna have
the cache misses because it was most
likely an unpopular title now it's not
very it's not that simple to just
prefetch the subsequent chunks because
in many cases the CDN does not know what
bit rate is going to be requested in the
next chunk but that's a whole other area
of research but it talked more about it
if you're interested for the low latency
paradox that I explained to you we
propose better load balancing we're
partitioning the popular content if you
remember 66% of the load was for the top
10% so even if you balance that better
you can get better utilization of the
servers the network category of problems
disk I discussed for problems with you
there there are more takeaways and
problems in the paper if you were
interested but the first problem was we
found some nearby clients with high
latency it's important to know this even
as a CDN because sometimes you want to
do you want to know what you can do but
sometimes you should be aware of what
you shouldn't do so in this case you
should avoid over provisioning servers
for these near about clients because the
problem is not that they're far from you
or
of presence and in case of prefixes that
have persistent high latency or
variation as a content provider the
options are limited what they can do
about this problem but the least that
you can do is adjust adaptive algorithm
accordingly for example you can start
with the more conservative bit rate or
increase the buffer size to handle these
legs you see variations better in terms
of the earlier packet losses that are
more harmful and unfortunately more
comment I discussed using server-side
pacing and finally the throughput is a
major bottleneck we think that's
actually good news for ISPs because it's
easier to fix by establishing better
peering points their latency the
takeaway is on the client I discussed
the download secretary teensy problem
with you and we think that's an
important problem that we could only
find it because we had data from both
sides and we could confirm that this
problem is not being caused by the
server or the network and I talked about
how that can be dangerous for that
appetite algorithm we can cause
overshooting or undershooting and what
we propose here is incorporating some
server-side TCP metrics or some
awareness of the network path to the
player and I have these discussions with
the path of our networking folks
yesterday and the second problem is that
rendering is resource heavy so you
should provision for that we propose
using 1/2 second per second video rubber
raid as a rule of thumb this is
particularly important if you are
streaming videos that people care about
frame rate for example sports that
there's usually that one frame that has
whether or not it was a thought and
finally rendering quality differs based
on OSF browser and I showed you some
example browsers that even in good
conditions and similar network and
server conditions they seem to have
worse rendering quality it's important
for a content provider to know this to
avoid premature optimizations for
example rerouting this client while the
problem was that the clients own down
the stack is not helpful
so it helps Citians a nice piece to know
where when the problem is the client to
avoid premature optimizations there
so in conclusion this in this work we
instrumented both sides for the first
time the client and the city and server
and it allowed us to uncover a wide
range of problems for the first time we
have data per trunk and per session
which allows us to uncover where their
problems are persistent or transient and
whether they lasted throughout the life
of this video streaming session or not
and our findings were used to enhance
performance in Yahoo and with that I am
happy to take questions we'll take about
five minutes of questions hi my name is
Stuart Cheshire from Apple thank you for
a really interesting presentation as you
said most of the traffic on the Internet
today streaming video so clearly
something people care about and I think
we're all frustrated by seeing that
little spinny wheel waiting for it
buffering I had one comment you talked
about client download stack late nurses
and working for Apple that's the area of
this that I'm more involved with I think
I may know what's going on here so I was
happy to see Safari scores best so thank
you so much no you were talking about in
the pipeline the various delays in the
CD and the network and you when you're
talking about the client site download
stack right ah as far as I know there is
no networking API on Windows or Linux or
Mac that will just sit on data for no
reason and not deliver it I think this
is a consequence of the api's in order
delivery of data yes if you miss in a
common Network setup now unfortunately
we have lots of buffer bloat so you
could easily have a two second queue on
your cable modem link and you lose one
packet and far
we transmit fills in that one packet
really fast but it's at the back of a
two-second queue so you've got all this
data arriving piling up in the kernel
the sockets API can't deliver it yes and
then the one missing packet arrives and
it says here you go here's 200k all at
once and of course that looks like this
blip that you've had zero throughput for
a couple of seconds and then suddenly
200k delivered in 0 nanoseconds is
infinity throughput instantaneously so
we have definitely seen that with things
like the Apple TV products that we get
very we get plateaus of no data at all
and then suddenly a spike where it
apparently all arrives because the one
missing packet got that yes I completely
agree with you actually we have more
data in paper that we confirm what
you're saying because we collected like
timestamps at the knick and you collect
the timestamps at the browser and it's
usually the API the problem here is that
our player sitting on their black box
right and we can't it's probably the way
that they're handling like and there's a
buffer there and how they're handling
the data delivery that causes these
problems but because it's a black box
and it's like a footnote in the paper
that we can only guess this is what's
happening and we confirm it is not at
the OS for the browser it seems to be
there but we can't really measure what's
what they're doing in that API I think
you have a good point there with the
current api's you can't tell if there
was just no data or if there's lots of
data with one missing packet exactly
yeah good point our West heard occur USC
is I am excellent presentation and work
very thorough and I really enjoyed it
having said that you killed my dream and
I've had this dream that that with the
advent of you know users can go out and
find the things that they want and and
it would they had helped us discover new
things
unfortunately sort of your caching
results kind of indicate that video
streaming services are
it's in their desire to bin everybody
into popular titles where you know they
they won't give you as many suggestions
sideways of other things that you're
interested in they're more likely to
give you suggestions that everybody else
is gonna watch too because it's cheaper
for them give some better performance
and thus you know better ratings and
that that's sad but thank you yes that's
exactly that's true and I think
everybody does that hi this is Tom I
just wondered whether the system is
intended for VOD or live streaming or
both thank you so the data set that we
use here are from the video on demand
the data set that I discussed but the
same systems are used like the same CDN
and the configurations that we found
they were applicable to the live
streaming events as well okay thank you
all right this is this is from the
jabber room on Simon Pietro Romano asked
if I be curious to understand whether
all of this has been carried out with
flash-based clients in such a case is
there any updated study with MPEG - yes
I think we mentioned ok the codec yeah
ok
okay I'll be a symbol for last fall okay
come on up do you want to try using your
own machine that's probably safer yeah
oh this is yours here we go
all right change of topic but not really
change of area so you want that in
there's your clicker oh these nice new
Macs okay oh there's no signal up
looking better yes okay yeah okay so
introduce yourself this is our second
day in our piece speaker hello hello
everyone good cool okay so good morning
everyone my name is Vasco I'm a third
year PhD student at the University of
Michigan Ann Arbor this work is
originally appeared it is the sitcom
2017 last August so today I will be
presenting room a new solution to
optimize web performance
this work is a collaboration with Ravi
Mohammed and my advisor Harsha so let's
get started so as you have experience
using a mobile phone connected to a
cellar network it's very very common
nowadays right we have our used phones
to surf the web all the time now I study
have shown that this is in fact the case
mobile web usage has been increasing
over the past few years the year 2016
was the tipping point where mobile web
usage has surpassed desktop devices
usage to browse the web but despite all
of this increase in mobile web usage as
you may have speery ensure self-loading
many of these pages are actually pretty
slow
no systems founded it takes almost ten
seconds to load the median mobile retail
site and on the other hand double
clicked founded it takes 14 seconds on
average to load a page over a 4G
connection so we also confirmed this
ourselves using a nexus 6 phone a
reasonable high performance phone at the
time connected to a good LTE network in
the Ann Arbor area to load the mobile
optimized popular pages so one thing to
note about the results that we found
here is that these are heavily optimized
popular pages so the numbers that we get
here is on the better side of things so
this is a bar chart representing the
page load times measured in seconds of
the Alexa top hundred sites overall and
Alexis how 50 news and 50 sports sites
the top of the bar chart is the median
page load time and the whiskers are 75
and a 25% house at the median page load
time for the Alexa a top hundred sites
overall it takes five seconds to load
the median page this is actually pretty
slow considering the fact that some
studies have shown that a five second
page load times has 25% bounce rate
which means that these pages are
actually losing some money right and on
the other hand if we take a look at the
Alexa top 50 News and 50 sports sites
things are far worse the median page
load time in this case is actually 10
seconds and the reason why things are
much worse in this case is because news
and sports sites tend to be more complex
than the Alexa top 100 sites overall so
in this talk I will be first digging
into why web pages are slow to gain some
intuition as to why that's the case and
then we will use those intuition to
improve web performance then I'll use
the intuition with that we get from the
first place to explore room our solution
to make web page slow faster and the
last part would be the implication of
workroom now let me take you to into why
webpage is slow now let's take a very
simple example let's say we load one to
load a page from a calm and this a calm
contains only one image so what would
happen when this page gets loaded is the
client will send a get request to a
dot-com era comes in smack their
response find parts that discover the
image and then a facial image if you
take a look at the network utilization
and also the CPU utilization at the
client as you can see here the bars with
the solid colors are times when these
resources are being actively used as you
can see here there are no periods that
the CPU and the network is being fully
utilized and the crux of the problem
here is that the client has to parse or
execute a resource to discover
additional resource to fetch so in some
instances CPU it will get blocked by the
network waiting for a resource to arrive
so that it can start parsing and on the
other hand sometimes the network will be
idle because it needs to fetch because
it's waiting for the CPU to process some
resource so the idea that we want to
make page load faster is by making
either the CPU or the network to become
fully utilized but before we jumping
into how we can do that we first have to
understand whether the CPU or the
network is the main bottleneck here so
what we did was we conduct an experiment
to find the page load times when either
the CPU or the network is a main
bottleneck in order to find the page
load time when the CPU is the main
bottleneck we use the phone connected to
a wired network so that we have a near
zero latency and also almost like an
infinite bandwidth and on the other hand
if we want to find the page load times
for when the network is the main
bottleneck we remove any processing from
the page load process as you can see
here from the results the page load
times when the CPU is the main
bottleneck is actually much higher than
the page load time with Network is the
main bottleneck so in this case the
medium page load time is 5 seconds in
the case where the CPU is the main
bottleneck so that experiment implies
that CPU is the main bottleneck in most
of the cases but is this actually the
case everywhere sure there may be cases
where network can be the main bottleneck
for example a developing country where
they have 3G connection a much slower
connection than 4G sure network can be
the main bottleneck in that case or on
the other end of the spectrum if you're
using a flagship phone maybe your phone
is much faster than a network so the
network is the main bottleneck but if
you consider it a technology trend
network is getting faster and faster
every year right network will have
higher bandwidth and also lower latency
but on the other hand CPU is only
increasing at a number of course the
clock speed itself is not increasing but
how is this trend affecting page load
times so what we did was we also perform
the same experiment but instead of using
all horse in the page load time when the
net CPU is the main bottleneck we
disable one of the horse to see what is
the effect of this and what we found was
that by disabling one of the horse the
distribution of the page load times went
and CPU is the main bottleneck it's very
similar to
using all the horse and this actually
stems from the fact that browser
processing is largely serial there's one
main process that keeps doing everything
there's not much leverage in multi-core
for multiple horse so the implication
here is that the CPU will become the
main bottleneck in the long run so just
to recap what we found in this first
section of the talk so the reason why
web pages are slow right now is browsers
needs to discover resources from parsing
and execution and we know that browsers
are largely serial in discovering these
resources and performing the page load
and with the CPU becoming the main
bottleneck in the future this process of
discovering resources from parsing and
execution will not become any faster
so we have to somehow think rethink the
way page load should work so our main
idea in our project is to somehow have
the server to become more proactive
during the page load we want servers to
eight clients in discovering resources
during the page load and that's the main
theme of room so now that we know why
paper web pages are slow and gain some
intuition I'll ask you how we can make
web pages faster let me walk you through
room our solution that uses that
intuition to make web facial faster this
is a very high-level architecture of
room so we have a lion a mobile client a
web browser unmodified and now we also
have these web servers like what we used
to have like right now the clan can
start by sending a get request to phu
kham foo.com
since babba hg responds none of these
are modified everything
the same as the status quo right now but
instead of only sending back HTTP
response broom also used SGP to push to
push resources down to the client so
that client can receive many resources
before it needs to actually fetch it I
discovered them from parsing our
execution but push itself it's not
really enough because HTTP push only
allows you to push down resources that
the origin owns right so but we know
that a lot of these pages contain
third-party resources so we are missing
out on a lot of resources to make web
page load faster so what we also include
in addition to HTTP to push is also used
some kind of dependency hints resource
hints one way to do this resources is to
use link rel preload HTTP primitive
where the Kleinman see this link rel
preload it can start the fetch of that
resource as soon as possible now in
order for the server's to push or send
these hints back to the client the
server has to have some kind of module
to discover these resources right so we
have these dependency resolution module
running at the web servers so these
dependency resolution modules are just
simply trying to find resources that the
client will need during the page load
and at the client we have some kind of
scheduling mechanism so that the client
can use all these resources as
effectively as possible now that we know
an end to end work for all of room in
order to make room our reality we have
to answer these two main questions so
first how web servers can discover
dependencies in the first place and on
the other hand how clients can schedule
these fetches of resources or use these
hints from the server effectively so
that it maximize the benefit that it
should receive
so let's first turn our attention to the
web server let's consider this strawman
approach in discovering resources for
the client so the client can send a get
request to the origin write this web
server foo.com
can start a page load a foo.com itself
at a route at the web server now because
food comes web server is a server it has
a much more powerful CPU and also a
highly connected network so it can
perform this page load much much faster
than the client so what foo.com can do
is it sends back the response as well as
push everything and also give hints
everything on everything that it
discover during this page load all this
sounds pretty intuitive and hopefully it
works unfortunately it doesn't so there
are two drawbacks with this approach
first as we all know web pages by nature
is very dynamic there are a lot of
resources that is dynamically generated
with some randomized token in the URL
and so on so by using everything from a
one particular load and hint them to the
client or push them to the client it
means that we are pushing or hinting
something that the user will not use and
by that we are first going to waste
clients bandwidth next even worse is
that by having the client sending
fetching these resources we might be
delaying some important resources which
make the page load slower in some cases
now on the other hand as we all know
many of these pages contain many
personalized resources so in order for
food calm in this case to account
correctly account for personalization
it needs to get a hold of the clients
cookies they're party cookies but we
don't food calm doesn't have that so
food calm will never be able to
correctly account for third party
personalization so how can we overcome
these two drawbacks so what we did was
we use an intersection of offline loads
to overcome the flux in URLs so at the
web server we load a page periodically
and then take the intersection of these
loads so it means that anything that is
randomly generated per load will be
filter out by the in because of the
intersection but this is not enough what
we found was that by only doing this
intersection of offline loads we are
only able to discover 70% of resources
that can be discovered so what we did
was we augment online parsing of the
HTML on top of intersection of offline
loads and what we found was that using
these two combined online offline
resource discovery we were able to
discover most of the resources so now
that we have a way to discover it
resources at the web servers
let's turn our attention to the client
and see how the client can effectively
use these resources from the server so
let me walk you through the very
high-level architecture of room again so
room sends a get requests to the web
server web server uses sends back a
response with the HP to push and also
dependency hints uses the dependency
resolution module to push and to get
resources to push and also hints so one
approach for this scheduling would be
have to
server just push everything that it
could from the dependency resolution
module and then for hints just use all
link preload lingual well plate preload
- hint all of them so what essentially
this do does is the server will push all
the bytes that it could to assert to the
client and the client will fetch all
hints immediately at the beginning of
page load this sounds great as well
because we are discovering resources
much earlier in the page load and things
should work well unfortunately it
doesn't work well either and this is a
pretty serious problem because by
pushing and fetching everything in the
first place at the beginning of the page
load this leads to contention in
bandwidth and when there's a contention
in bandwidth sometimes the important
resources are actually being delayed for
example a blocking script or some CSS
will get delayed and by and because of
those resources getting delayed it has a
cascading effect throughout the page
load and it can end up hurting the page
load process so what we found in our
experiment was that by using this
approach we don't see any page load time
improvements and even worse sometimes we
see degradation in page load times so
what we did instead is reprioritize
pushes and fetches of resources that can
potentially have children for example
HTML CSS or JavaScript and one very
important detail here is that we have to
prop scheduled them or hint them based
on the schedule that they will be
processed we don't want to fetch any
resources out of order so that because
if we fetch things out of order some
resource that gets processed earlier
might stop waiting
after some resources that gets processed
later
so now let's take a look at how room
scheduler works in action so at the
beginning of the page scheduler fetches
all HTML Javascript CSS this can both be
in the form of HTTP to push or link
reload after all of this fetches is done
it will start fetching other
dependencies such as images fonts on in
other words resources that will not have
any children and that doesn't require
any processing while these two fetches
are going on we also allow the browser
to parse the HTML CSS and also execute a
JavaScript if you discover any resources
during by processing these resources we
also allowed them to go out now this red
line in the timeline is a very important
time in the page load process this red
line is the time when all the bytes that
needs to be processed at the client is
actually local at the client already so
what this means is that from that point
on when the client wants to process any
resource it can start processing that
resource without having to wait on the
network and from that point on this
implies that the CPU can be fully
utilized so now that we have the two
components of room let me sum up room
and then we can see how well room works
compared to the current state of the
page load so room start by Senate get
request to the origin origin sends back
there she P response pushes important
resources and also didn't provide hints
of other resources room uses room has
these dependency resolution module and
also we use combined offline online
resource discovery
on the client side we have the scheduler
which we schedule them by prioritizing
pushes and fetches of HTML CSS and
JavaScript so now that we have an
end-to-end working components of room
let's see how well room works so what we
found was that brooms dependency
resolution is actually very accurate and
because of this room was able to speed
up page load in many of the cases we
have a hub of results in our paper but
today I'll only be talking about how
well room works over the stay as quote
if you're interested in other results
please refer to the paper before jumping
into any numbers let me first tell you
how we evaluate room so we used an ex SX
phone connected to a 4G LTE network to a
web record and replay environment so the
reason why we need a web recording
replay environment is because room
requires server-side changes so ideally
we want to use a live experiment but
unfortunately getting adoption of all
tests would be very very challenging now
that we know how we evaluate room let's
take a look at the numbers
so using that evaluation setup we
evaluate room on the Alexa 250 news and
50 sports sites and this is the bar
chart representing the page load times
measured in seconds as well the top of
the bars are the medians and also the
whiskers our 75th and 25th percentile
page load times the status quo load is
for this set of pages is 10 seconds like
we saw earlier so when we enable step2
on all domains we saw that by only doing
that we are able to take the median page
load time down to 7.5 seconds but if we
enable room at all domains
we are actually getting doubled of that
improvement in page load times and right
now the median page load times is
actually five seconds down from 10
seconds and this is in fact very very
close to the lower bound where we
defined a lower bound ratio times as
when the page is either network bounded
or CPU bounded
now as we all know on load event is not
the ideal metric to use to get user
experience right so we also evaluated
room on visual metric so if we evaluate
room on the above the fold time which is
the time where all the objects appear on
the screen and this is the bar chart
representing the above the fold time
measured in seconds so the status quo
load takes 12 seconds to load at the
median site and when we use broom broom
was able to improve the page that above
the fold time from 12 seconds to 8
seconds so that's a 4 second improvement
in above the fold time so now one
assumption that we made in all of our
evaluations so far is that we assume
that everyone adopts room but as we all
know adoption is challenging so what we
did as well is we evaluate room when
room is incrementally deployed so in
this example here broom is an enable at
all the domains right
so what we did was we consider first
party domains so when I say first party
domains let's say we're a SP n com yes
PN comm also owns ESP and cbn.com right
so we also consider ESPN cbn.com
also part of the first party domains
because we assume that if they are going
to if say ESPN are going to deploy room
they might as well deploy room
everywhere on their domains so what we
found in this setting is that most of
of benefits that we saw in the in the
case where we enabled room everywhere is
actually still achievable from only
enabling room at the first party domains
and that means that we actually don't
need full adoption to make web page look
faster so now that we know how room
works and how well it works let's turn
our attention to the implication of room
so broom leverages HTTP to push and also
link rel preload to enable server-side
edit resource discovery right currently
every web site wants to use any of these
it needs the knowledge of the developer
to manually add h2 push or link preload
into the responses but room shows that
there's actually a systematic way an
automated way that you can actually
include these pushes and hints into the
response but that actually comes at a
cost
as you if you recall room requires
offline dependency discovery to
construct a stable set of resources this
actually consumes a lot of CPU cycles
and network at the server's imagine if
you have thousands of pages running
serving at your web server by doing
periodic loads of these pages will be a
huge pain so what we think that we could
do is maybe the client can help the
server discovering these offline
dependency resolution
so maybe we can crowdsource all these
URLs during the page load that the
client sees and then send it back to the
browser you may thinking we you may be
thinking right now that maybe this is
violating some privacy issues so let's
take an example so this is a dependency
tree off a website
in a very naive implementation you can
send all these resources as a list back
to a.com but this is obviously not good
because let's take a look at z.com slash
a dot HTML so that is an ad so anything
below that can be personalized or
targeted to the user so sending all this
to a.com
means that we are giving up privacy to
of the user so what we could do instead
is sending everything in this screen
encapsulation and this is in fact enough
for a.com to discover offline dependency
resolution because a.com if you recall
from the offline from the strawman
dependency resolution a.com cannot
discover personalized resources
correctly anyway so by sending anything
everything in this screen in caps
encapsulation is actually enough and
then anything below c-calm can actually
be sent to just see comm and this is not
also not violating privacy because see
Tehama is the one serving the ad so
sending you back to see comm would be
fine another very important lesson that
we found in Froome is that when doing
these pushes and fetches of dependencies
using link rel preload we shouldn't be
fetching out these resources at the same
time as we saw that if we do this we
don't see improvement in patient or
times and worse we are seeing
degradation right so just to recap what
we did in room was we group dependencies
in different varieties so higher
priorities are resources that require
processing and then we perform fetches
of these resources based on their
priorities so maybe one thing one branch
that we could do regarding these person
prioritization of preloads is that
include some kind of priority to
the link rel preload so that the browser
knows that
oh this preload is actually higher
priority than some other reload so that
the browser can schedule the load of
these resources better in fact this is
an on a draft already in the w3c
community so I hope to be discussing
this more with them but just to recap I
think that having a priority would be a
great addition so to conclude my talk I
present at room an end-to-end solution
that fully utilizes either the CPU or
the network
vrooom was able to do this by decoupling
dependency discovery from parsing and
execution by leveraging the server to
aiding dependency discovery at the
client because of this room was able to
decrease the median page load times by
five seconds for the popular pages and
with that I'm happy to answer any
questions
[Music]
Alex may offer thanks for interesting
presentations really really nice to see
that someone actually tries that out in
practice other than just an association
of it I have a question do we employ any
mechanism that you avoid pushing the
same resource twice to the same client
I'm not talking about link reload
preload because the client would decide
whether it has that resource already but
if you like push the CSS on each and
every page that sounds wasteful or are
there any technologies employed you mean
pushing having push like size 8 a CSS
twice in the same yeah so the user loads
the home page get you see the CSS pushed
then he clicks on a sub page she gets
the CSS pushed again uh-huh are you
doing anything against that or in this
word I am not doing anything to prevent
that because we have
control of all what we push so we
insured we're not pushing it twice does
that answer your question yeah okay can
you give us a little bit of an idea on
these sites which have been optimized
for mobile
how many URLs are in a page and how many
of those URLs actually changed the page
and are not just the spyware so I know
the figures for regular web pages and
it's tremendous numbers of URLs I just
don't know if people who are optimizing
for mobile are actually giving up some
of this overhead which was always
understood to be you know people
basically we're designing web pages
thinking that CPU and network is
unlimited and that's not the case for a
robot all right um
so your question is for these set of
sites I'm looking at what are the like
say the number of resources on top Asian
so we're talking about hundreds of URLs
or dozens or just yeah so what I found
in these set of sites at least the
number of URLs that I found a new set of
sites or at least 50 for sure for news
and sports sites it's in the order of
hundreds so yes right which means that
actually if the people serving these
sites really thought of their user and
what the experience would be they could
cut down on this and maybe you wouldn't
need your solution as much I'm not
saying your solutions not a great idea
but if people instead with trying to
force down our throats lots of
advertising and spyware actually thought
of the customer and his quality of
experience they could solve this problem
without needing more technology right
yes I agree
so since how from hallway and thank you
for your talk and worrying system work
and you know test set my question is a
new test set we have any data reflecting
how many website use the domain sharding
technologies using what sorry I can tell
me
don't whistling yeah okay so number of
sites that are using domain sharding
most of them are using domain sharding
at the time that we used now we perform
these experiments hopefully that is less
common if we move to sp2 but when I was
doing this project like a year two ago I
could see that business common okay but
because your inside is that the CPU and
either the CPU or network is only
utilized but using domain sharding it's
kind of a paralyzing parallelism and you
can make better use of a CPU either CP
or network right so I think that's a
separate issue right now browsers are
absolutely designed right now is that
there's one c1 main process that is
doing all these tasks sure you can have
another process that can do like preload
scanning but that's separate but the
main thing that is happening is one in
one process so by having that only one
process you are able to only execute or
deuce doing something waiting on the
network on only one process so sometimes
they see sometimes the browser will have
to wait for some processing to happen in
order to utilize the network later in
the page load anyway so domain sharding
will not help in that case okay thank
you hi you're Vice I'm participating or
leading like participating in the
priority hints work that you mentioned I
think it would be extremely interesting
to integrate the concept of the
JavaScript scheduler into the browser's
resource scheduling process and in that
context the red line you showed where
you know which separated the critical
resources from the non-critical ones
do you think there's a way from the
browser's perspective to determine that
in a deterministic way that doesn't
introduce a gap so trigger those
non-critical loads in the ideal time
seems like a complex problem how did you
solve that I don't think I have a good
answer to that on top of my head and the
reason is because like you said it's
very tricky because even though we say
that rooms resource discovery is very
accurate we are not claiming that we can
detect all resources many of resources
that say a JavaScript that has some kind
of randomized token we still can't
discover those so the CP so from a
browsers perspective I think it's gonna
be really tricky to say that oh these
are all the resources that it will need
to process and then yeah I I'm sure
we'll still need processing but just the
the part that I'm interested in is in
determining in real time determining the
redline determining the fact that
everything critical or most critical
things finished loading and we can start
loading the nonverbals like defining
that red line would be extremely
interesting yeah I agree
Thanks yep Thanks hi Alma Cherica I had
a couple of thoughts one of which is did
you do any research into seeing how many
unnecessary resources actually were
downloaded that you had pushed something
in advance and then it turned out that
the browser didn't need it I mean one
obvious example would be high DPI
graphics where you know the browser's
deciding which resolution to download
unfortunately I didn't do any study on
that like what are the resources that
are push and not being used so one thing
to note here is that all of our
experiments start from the assumption
that none of these sites are doing
actually doing any push or anything like
that so what we did in our work was that
say if in the best scenario if we try to
push everything that we know off and
then we'll be used in the page load and
also hint everything without having out
thee the worry of and using what will be
the best case that we could get I mean I
guess another way to ask the question is
how many additional bytes were
downloaded using broom then were that
would have been downloaded if the page
had just been loaded normally um there
shouldn't be more bytes right so sure
there's certainly some more bytes in the
signaling so there there will be more
bytes in like saying the hints and those
stuff um so I don't know the exact
answer to that but I would think that it
should be relatively low compared to the
whole size of that HTML or the page and
another thing that just comes to mind is
this seems like a way that if we had a
better way to organize our HTML and
JavaScript in the first place so that
the browser could identify that critical
resources earlier in the parsing then
perhaps this server-side trickery
wouldn't be necessary but now I'm
telling you it would know so I'll leave
you thanks Matt Mathis I sort of had a
continuation of that thought it feels
like this is very good work very cool
stuff but it feels like you're
optimizing it the wrong layer in the
sense that the content providers should
be optimizing better ahead of time and
they're not for some reason and I was
wondering if you had any speculation
about some of the incentives for it
things like domain sharding for instance
fills me to me is an example of a
technology that works the same way that
excessive choice in the grocery store
works it has the effect of crowding out
competitors because you can provide 14
different flavors of chips to use for
ten times as much shelf space
and what this means is is it underlying
somehow underlying some of the people
have inappropriate ascent incentives and
you're optimizing away some of their
incentives but the real problem is
they're optimizing against you did you
look at any of the sort of the causes of
why this stuff was done in ways that it
was you could fix it in the
post-processing so to speak
so just to rephrase your question so
basically so basically did I so what I'm
optimizing is actually Adam had maybe we
should be optimizing at a different
layer then and HP layer it feels like
you're optimizing something that
somebody else optimized towards a
different goal
I see yeah I guess maybe did when
someone tries to optimize something they
have to keep in mind that they might be
hurting someone else's performance and
so we should be more inclusive between
the two all right I think they were the
ones being unincluded why do you choose
Nexus 6 why not some newer phones so at
the time it was a year and a half ago or
two years that was the best one that we
could get so you started experimenting
yeah a while back okay thank you okay
let's think
I left the slot in case anyone had any
questions or wanting to make any
observations but we could also wrap up
early we're gonna give certificates up
to motion and and basketball now and
honoring their their prizes and there's
no reason why everyone has to watch that
but but I'm very grateful to you two for
giving these talk I think they were
really great and really thorough and
inspiring so thank you and thank you oh
I are TF open okay we have a observation
from Dave Wonka
oh I'm hi Alison I wondered if we might
spend a few minutes talking about or
catching the I heard you have community
up on what's going on or how er NW was
formed the the research workshop first I
want to say thank you and to the iStock
people and they see and people to put
putting that together the last time I
looked at it we know we didn't have a
committee there was no call and all that
stuff so a bunch of people did a bunch
of great stuff to get that in order and
um in I guess in the spirit of sort of
transparency I was wondering if you
could tell us or one of them could tell
us how the committee was selected what
was the reach and diversity goal and did
you meet it I see there's an invited
talk that's one of the people that's on
it's on the program committee that
that's an unusual thing could you speak
to that or who's responsible forward so
either I think neither of the people the
program chairs are here so it's really a
better question for them but the and in
fact I so the invited talk question I
think is an interesting one because
there's quite a bit of variation between
committees and workshops as to whether
that's a reasonable thing to do or not
it's of the conflict of interest whether
it's okay for people who are on the
committee to also be speakers I think
the reason they see that the invited
talk so early was to try to
give a strong a strong representation of
some of the topics in range with respect
to the program committee I think it's
possible that that committee could could
grow some more so if we if you were to
raise a question about its composition
to to Sharon and Dave it would be timely
okay I mean the overarching issue is I
love the way that a nrw is different
from the from the academic conferences
and I love the idea of running it during
IETF because we're already multitrack
yeah ITF so that's gonna be a huge
improvement and the competing idea that
was floated last year was having an hour
W being a continuing workshop where
people could keep like solving the other
problem at academia that you keep it's
hurry up and then wait like you hurry up
to submit your thing you wait half a
year so I love us having it different
than you like this but a couple of the
things just looking to improve is we're
still inviting now in a or W we're
inviting already published stuff there
we already do that for an RP so sure he
had a venue to do that and and I think
that we should like raise the bar for
ourselves to say how did we select the
committee and and things like you know
that got that kind of stuff but I'm
really happy that it's all in shape
already and it's looking really good
the timelines that walk through a
workshop in July we've got a month to
submit and they've got two months to
form it so it looks really good mostly
I'm happy with it if you care about it I
think there's also I mean there's a hope
that there will be a fair number of
these kind of lightning talks they're
short and I think it remains to be seen
and part of what everybody can do here
besides submitting yourself is to
encourage your researching friends to to
bring up papers I mean if everybody in
this room submits something and gets a
friend to submit what other amazing
choice but I have had in mind that
perhaps the committee should should
expand with respect to the kind of
continuing versus one-off once-a-year
thing we're thinking slowly about the
idea of a of a about a bunch of those
types of ideas and I'd like I'll get you
involved in that conversation but also
people in this room we're looking to try
to increase the amount of
applied network research that there is I
mean like you've heard to beautiful
applied network research topics today
and and also rods topic but many times
there's a very big gap between academic
research and what we could then do
something and build in in the real world
internet and see deployed so we're
looking to just enhance those
relationships in every way we can
okay and that you actually hit on
exactly the last thing I wanted to say
was to remind people to solicit for it
one carrot you can use for people one
thing that's nicer about in our W that
say IMC is the talks are recorded and
we're having building this huge library
of awesome presentations by those people
so some of the students that I've
solicited to come to IETF format Margie
or something to say they end up having
this talk that's on their you know web
page afterwards where if somebody can
see them in actually write stuff I'm
also asking IMC to come up to raise the
bar for themselves to start doing that
you should actually mention that you are
one of the two chairs of the map RG
Research Group the measurement and
analysis for protocols so this is a very
parallel case to the yet the rest it's
sort of like a recursive the IRT F
contains another IRT yeah that's just
the measurement subset of well yeah it
could be Eddie in our death yeah and
then oh the last thing is the program
committee I it looks really good it's
like a there's a third women on it maybe
there's looks like a lot of third of the
people are ITF participating academics
already so it's looks like somebody did
a really good job but we should tell
people how we're doing it okay sounds
good okay anything else anyone wants to
bring up before we send you off to lunch
okay all right well thank you for coming
see you see you on our mailing list
see you tonight I'm going to give
another little bit of an overview
tonight hopefully more successfully in
the analog Department oh and there
should be another blue sheet if someone
can provide the other blue sheet that
would be helpful