yeah yeah why not because I have this
thank you where you looking for me
please wait because this crappy laptop
doesn't have so here is everything okay
yeah just
yeah I'll use it okay
I started from where successfully I have
everything here's that
oh you want to copy it really you I
didn't send a little message well maybe
I was run this here I turn off the
chatty chatty chatty yeah
so he used to just mention now of air
pollution say okay sorry guys for the
delay
hey we're let's get started okay so so
the this is the first session of faith
to a OAuth sessions um and here's that
not well so hopefully you're familiar
with that already
um so can I can I a-any minute takers
kind of anyone can help with that
somebody that is not presenting today
normally takers
blue sheet or
yeah yes yeah probably one hits
Wednesday on maybe it's a that previous
right day so okay thanks
so a can we get a jabbers card and a
mini taker any anybody can help with
that many takers nobody no taker we need
somebody okay thank ya okay anybody
anybody else with mini take her please
thank you and somebody in the jabber
[Music]
thank you
okay let's say talk about status here
I'm so device slow a we will talk about
that later today in discovery yeah
Michael talk about that - a the jot a I
think we had some may open issues a I
think that sent a an email response and
closing those questions so I occurred do
you think we're we're done with that or
satisfied with the yes my understand
this is the this is jar right yeah my
understanding is that you guys have it
resolved those issues and I just have to
like go through and make sure to like
there's nothing no more nitpicking
floating around and prove it I brought
the ball okay thanks I think there's
nothing makes it right and just it's I'm
here I guess tokens change if I remember
correctly there were some back-and-forth
and I have to renew document yep it's
waiting for me thank you
okay BCP will drop BCP we'll talk about
this later until s same thing security
topic and talking binding all of those
will be discussed later okay so let's
just quickly update on in the interim
meetings so we we had to inter meetings
to discuss distributed earth and
reciprocal auth it used to be called
module off M distribute earth will be
discussed later a Wednesday and they for
with regard to reciprocal off a we
discussed this would occur and they we
have an approval to move forward with
this so that's a that's an update on
that on the result of that discussion
yes published on the mailing list
already long time ago
okay well chopped so we had an hour the
latest our security workshop last week
in Trento here's a picture from that
wonderful place there we had there's a
separate workshop webpage and I
encourage you to look at the program
which links the slides as well as
position papers that had been submitted
to that workshop we covered a number of
different topics like in the previous
workshops we talked about formal methods
we had researchers coming along who did
form an analysis shared exp experience
we talked about regulatory activities
that impact o us um there was a Dawson
spoke for example about the financial
ABI in the work on the PSD to the ideas
we had deployment experience related
talks new ideas also Mike for example
did absorb presentation on log of or log
out we also had a crypto related
presentations so overall I think it was
very interesting for me was why that we
did this workshop and it's a good to get
the researchers into the same room as
standards people to have an exchange and
I was advocating for them an increased
use of formal methods in IDF security
protocols as well and played around it
myself or one of the hours variants okay
they're on the agenda so we have Brian
at the beginning to talk about MPLS and
token binding we have the Torsten to
talk about security
Dennis had few three topics to talk
about here so and we're hoping if we
have a then we have some time five
minutes will allow Justin to talk about
the HTTP signing if not we'll we'll talk
about that on Wednesday okay so i'm
brian thank you
all right be sure to read from thank you
that is London from some years ago and
we are in London yeah - does photos in
here but yeah let's get started so um
just want to give a little bit of
context since I know everybody reads
every single draft before they come in
here when I give it a little bit over
you that for someone that maybe hasn't
so what is the mpls draft it's two
things two primary things one is doing
mutual TLS client authentication both
client authentication to the
authorization server and we've got two
main methods of doing this one is PK I
based where you check the certificate at
the end up to the you know to a change
route and the other is a self sign
method and then there's also a mutual
TLS sender constrain access tokens for
protected resource access another way to
think about that is just these are
certificate bound access tokens side so
why why are we working on this mutual
TLS auth client authentication which is
something that obviously provides better
security characteristics than the shared
secrets in the normal Oh F is something
that's been done in practice for OAuth
from a lot of vendors and
implementations for quite a while we've
never actually had a standard to support
it
mutual TLS sender constrained resource
access is something that binds access
tokens to the client certificate so they
can't be played or replayed by any other
entity without the private key this is
you know actual proof of possession
access tokens which is something that's
been a little elusive to the to the
working group and the community at large
I'm told that banks need these for API
use cases being driven by a variety of
new banking open banking regulations
they want stronger forms of security but
they won't also be able to use OAuth and
this draft even in its draft form is
currently referenced by the Open ID
Foundation's financial API working group
fappy in their reading
API security profile which is a higher
sort of higher security profile around
off as well as being referenced in the
UK open banking API security profile so
despite being a draft they're already
being referenced sorry
you can jump ahead ok so how does this
actually work the mutual TOS client
authentication is obviously to the
authorization server typically the token
endpoint but also any other endpoint at
the authorization server that might
require fine authentication works the
same way the client let's see the TLS
connection that the HT request is made
over is established with mutual TLS
client certificate authentication the
client also includes the client ID HTTP
request parameter and all requests of
the token endpoint to to identify itself
upfront and the authorization server
verifies that that certificate is in
fact the right one for the client and
that's based on configuration and or
dynamic registration information around
that that particular client that das has
and then there's some metadata
supporting this that would be used in
dynamic registration and/or as I think
we all have come to learn the metadata
basically implies the client data model
so it can be used even in the case that
you're not actually doing client
registration so there's a new for the
the PKI method there's a new
authentication name
that's TLS client off that could be used
both for the client to indicate what
authentication method it's going to use
as well as the server to list which
methods it supports and then in client
metadata there's this TLS client off
subject the end which specifies the
expected subject distinguished name of
the client certificate and then there's
metadata also supporting the self-signed
certificate method and that's an
authentication method name
unsurprisingly of self santi less client
off and then the existing Jenny bouquet
S&J DB case URI
really an or metadata parameters can be
used to carry the client keys and
certificates or hold them
and just uh maybe it's not clear but the
difference between those two methods is
that in the former the PKI method the
client presents a certificate the
authorization server
you know validates that that certificate
is signed by a trusted authority that it
trusts and then checks the the subject
DN against that which was configured so
sort of more of a traditional PTI
approach to authenticating the client
whereas in the self-signed certificate
method on the client just presents its
own certificate saw itself signed and
basically the the authorization server
has trust chain validation turned off at
the TLS layer so it proves possession
the key but it doesn't actually validate
the certificate chain and then the
authorization server just matches up the
the Rockies or the certificate to what
it has configured for itself okay next
slide thank you okay so how does mutual
TLS sender constrain access work it's
hard to find a right name for this
because token binding kind of means a
something else entirely
as tourists in this you mentioned to me
a few times or misstated but basically
this is binding the access token to a
client certificate so either sender
constrain access which I think was a
term nak came up with or certificate
bound access tokens the wording is kind
of used a little bit interchangeably in
the draft hopefully in a clear way so on
issuance of an access token the
authorization server associates a hash
of the certificate with or into the
access token
thus binding the access token to the
certificate the TLS connection from the
client to the actual protected resource
is over mutually authenticated TLS and
the protected resource matches the
certificate obtained from the TLS layer
to the certificate hash and the access
token and obviously if they don't match
it's rejected if they do then in proof
of the corresponding private keys have
been proven and this token bound or
certificate bound access token has been
used successfully in order to carry this
information in jot we've got a new
confirmation method which is the x.509
certificate sha-256 thumbprint
confirmation method x5t pound s2 five
six this just carries the sha-256 hash
the certificate itself and then there's
a confirmation method also for token
introspection that's exactly the same
looks the same same name same same
semantics it's just conveyed in the
token token introspection response
rather than its jot itself and one I
think benefit or maybe not obvious side
of this is that the the token binding
piece of it that binds it to their
certificate it doesn't vary based on the
client authentication method so the
actual access token is bound to the raw
certificate itself and the resource or
protected resource doesn't have to have
any knowledge of how the actual client
authenticated the server it just needs
to verify that the key indicated in the
access token matches the one that the
client presented in the in the TLS
negotiation and there's just examples of
the two here I'm not sure Museum very
well but it has the confirmation method
with that particular what do we call it
confirmation method name or member
inside of a jot as well as inside of a
token introspection response they looked
at similar unsurprisingly all right next
one so a few changes since Singapore
published draft six and seven not sure
which was just in each but a sort of an
overview of all of them updated to use
the RFC 8174 boilerplate which is just a
little bit more wording around the the
normative language that is being
recommended pretty much everybody now so
I went ahead and did that to get a head
start on it references updated including
the authorization server metadata or
discovery document and move the security
considerations up before the ioniq
considerations I'm not sure how I got
those out of order in the first place
but it looked really weird in the
document most people stopped reading
when they get to IANA and the security
considerations here are actually pretty
important so it ought to be better for
it to be with the rest of the text I
talked a little bit more about
certificate access certificate bound
excuse me access tokens in the abstract
that part was not not really conveyed in
the access in the abstract very much I
thought to be worthwhile to to spell
that out more so someone reading the
beginning of the document could know
there's sort of two
main components to the document itself
did something similar to the title I was
just called MPLS profiles previously
which I guess is accurate but kind of
meaningless so this the new title goes
on to basically say that's for client
authentication and certificate bound
access tokens added a tiny little bit
more text in the security considerations
around certificate spoofing or
preventing certificate spoofing based on
you know a constrained set of cas into
the security considerations i was
suggested by someone home at the last
meeting i did add an explicit note also
from the last meeting this came up that
the implicit flow is not supported for
obtaining certificate bound access
tokens and finally added an appendix
section describing the relationship of
this back the MTL aspect to oauth token
binding since there's some overlap there
i tried to explain the situation and why
they both exist and why at least you
might consider one or the other and
those are all the changes so next slide
so what are the next steps looking at
the minutes from Singapore
there was this statement that the
working group last call will be issued
in December after clarification that
clarification was actually that note
about let's do it a little fast and not
wait till December
[Laughter]
and so I with that I'm sort of asking
urging that we we consider working group
last call at this point yeah that's what
we're thinking right now and and we
wanna see if anybody objects to that or
you have any issue with that like I
think there would probably are ready to
go to work or plus call on this one
we have the technology all right Justin
richer
I actually don't object for this -
coming - last call - you didn't give me
any other option I want to talk anyway
but no I do think this is ready for last
call we actually just over the last two
and a half weeks or so have gone through
and implemented everything in this draft
so both authentication methods and the
sender constrained access tokens the non
bound TLS bound access tokens whatever
they're called right we implemented all
of those in a in what's going to be a
forthcoming product for one of my
clients athletes so that's so there is
going to be you know at least one
implementation in the wild I know paying
has some implementations as well I don't
I was for drunk on the ball on this yet
guess not
yes there's another implementation it's
the Nimbus library and they connect Ont
product we used it at yes that come and
use it into two ways we use it to
actually secure all micro service based
architecture and for our directly for
the open le connector access for line
parties so my perspective that's that's
ready to be used another another note
besides the two references you you gave
on the first slide from the Pepe working
group and they making you okay also the
Berlin group's API specification for
payment service directive to directly
references this draft I did not know
that thank you
okay go ahead no god yes so so we just
had a short discussion I think we we
will start the working group called last
coil today even because it will give us
a opportunity to hassle some of you to
actually do that during this week while
you're here next week you will be super
busy catching up if your company
internal work so if you are interested
or if you have time to review this
document I think that would be please
come forward it won't take too long
I did look at it for the last meeting to
see at what state it is and and with the
clarification and you provide it I think
it's very good that's what we're asking
for last time so and would obviously
work with eka to get this through the
process as quickly as possible given
that what we learned at the workshop
that there is a dependency from some of
the bank open banking initiatives that
want to use this work so definitely a
new field where OS is used and and
hasn't traditionally been used so so we
are spreading out oh us in all sorts of
new domains which is excellent thank you
Brian more documents are Justin you'd
mentioned you had maybe an it on an
understanding you can be on the mailing
list in the last call yeah we can do
that in the mailing list or I can just
tell you it's it's minor potential
wording clarifications nothing normative
purely editorial of I garden path on a
couple of things during implementation
but I pretty sure I came up with the
right answer so the information is there
yeah if it can be clarified then who of
you could be who is willing to take a
look at it besides just in doing this
week to actually or next week to provide
some some review feedback apparently
I've been volunteered so okay well yeah
you have already looked at it so I have
and III will do a closed comb over the
donkey
and and come up with knits and things
like that hmm
Mike Jones it it matters so read it
Torsten should read it to ya okay you
should still read it yeah what's the
most in bright only mode if do you have
time to take a look at this document
good okay next topic okay yeah I was
confused so this one's gonna be
hopefully kind of short because I know
there's some other things out did the
agenda leave some time for it is what it
is all right Oh off to youto combining
that's also London here we are again
yeah next slide please so just want to
give a little bit of an overview of what
tow combining is for those of you that
may not be familiar and having followed
that working group it's something that
enables a long live binding of cookies
or other security tokens that part the
other security tokens are the ones that
are interested into this working group
to a client generated public/private key
pair the use of token binding is
negotiated in the TLS handshake with a
with an extension and then assuming it's
negotiated on all subsequent HTTP
requests over that thiele connection
possession of this client generator the
key is proven by signing the TLS
exported key material the ekm and then
sending that along with the public key
basically as an HTTP header and every
request cookies and tokens can be bound
to that key I think I said that already
and the key at least in the web browsing
case the kiyah scope to the effective
top-level domain plus one so there's not
a privacy issue necessarily at their
scope basically the same way that
cookies can be scoped so they're not set
any broader it's not like a super
checking cookie or anything and then
this idea of federated or cross domain
use cases like OAuth where the resource
server might be in a different top-level
domain than the authorization server are
supported via this thing called the
referred token binding versus what's
normally called
provide a token bonding which is a way
for in in that HP header to send
actually two different token monies to
keys and prove possession of them so
that the issue token can be bound to the
other key which will be used for
connections to some other service like
the resource server next slide please
so just really quickly in a nutshell for
context here
what is this document it's basically a
way to provide an oauth 2.0 proof of
possession mechanism based on the
underlying technology of tow combining
that's the defeat you know replay or
play of tokens by unauthorized entities
including a resource server replaying it
or a lost or stolen token being played
by another you know personated client
all these things are prevented to the
extent that the private keys are
protected there's a few different types
of tokens and OAuth turns out there's
actually a lot of tokens and OAuth so we
try to bind them all the the most
interesting one is binding of access
tokens using the referred token binding
ID so when you request an access token
when the client requests an access token
it presents to tow combining keys and
the authorization server binds to the
second one which is the key that will be
used when making actual protected
resource requests and we also have a
representation in jot for this based on
we're not based on but as an additional
confirmation method member this being
the tbh token binding hash member and
it's just a hash of the the token
binding ID which in turn is basically
the public key and that also is
available or will be registered for
introspection responses
we also talked about how to buy and
refresh tokens to the normal token
binding key and there's two ways to buy
an authorization codes one for native
app type clients and one for web server
clients and then finally went on
recently to add binding for JWT based
authorization grants and jadibooti
client authentication and so in summary
the changes since Singapore
Jeff six was published also using the
new boilerplate really trying to get
ahead on things with that exciting
change updating some references to the
draft tow combining the discovery I
think one of these is already out of
date and made a few maybe just
two really minor editorial fixes so if
nothing really substantial has changed
in the document but it's still there
next slide and so we're trying to look
ahead the the underlying three token
binding drafts should be going to RFC
this is I think the third time I've said
that there's one name I think they're
close buzzer so as I recall it happened
is the that did the non HCBS ones were
fine and I was done with them and then
Dirk had produced an HTTP one that came
in about a month ago
so I usually have finished that and then
we good microphone IETF last call has
been completed on that and it's waiting
for your write up oh okay thank you and
then you know beyond that we really need
implementation experience and feedback
on this stuff and I think maybe just
appreciate this stuff should be really
easy once all the really hard parts are
done and the really hard parts are that
this token binding itself sort of
crosses over layers that aren't
typically crossed over by your average
developer so you need access to pieces
inside the TLS layer then that aren't
always easily available so there's
really sort of either some really really
heavy lifting hard work to be done to
make it work or a waiting game to get
lower level platforms to surface the
api's and expose the functionality
needed to do this and I'm hopeful that
it's tough progresses at RFC status
maybe that'll become available more soon
but without that actually doing
implementations is is really difficult
and it's it's an unfortunate state where
I'm both sort of a chicken and egg
problem if you will or rock and a hard
place
I don't know your favorite cliche there
please insert it
so let us get it and get an idea where
we are Biff this so you've been working
on an implementation and used so you you
have gained a lot of experience in that
regard but unlike many of our other
specifications which had lots of
implementations also product
implementations and even deployments
that seems to be a little bit on a
different level now I mike are you you
guys have for the Microsoft has and is
has deployed implementations of parts of
it and it's working in in production mmm
that's fantastic man ok so that's at
least um it's something something but we
had cases where we had reported in our
in our document write-ups and like 10 15
plus implementation so we are at no huh
this is definitely and even the work
that I've done has been largely at the
lower layer are trying to make that
happen in the platforms that I use and
do we know how we how we could improve
this situation or get there eventually
because you you know better what what is
needed from TLS attacks and in different
environments and so we could reach out
to those guys who actually make this
happen also largely I think there's
there's a need for you know the various
sort of TLS layer API is to expose
mechanisms to do arbitrary extensions as
well as expose access to the exported
key material which is that's in some
places and not others in some places
make it very difficult Mike Jones at
Microsoft from my point of view the
biggest thing that we can do to
accelerate this is just get the token
binding specifications to RFC's yeah
currently different implementations are
implementing different draft numbers and
therefore the one that's on by default
and edge is not talking to you know the
same services that chrome is because
they're different numbers and so once
you know Eric does is write up and we
have one oh that unblocks a lot of
developers from feeling like
this is real we will do the library work
I know that inside Microsoft you know
some things are happening but some
things are waiting till we have one out
thank you Eric
you're a good man okay thank you that's
all I got thank you hi
Anto sniper vs comm and I happen to be
the editor of the security topics
document the security dope is topics
document is basically an update to RFC
6890 that's the security threat model
considerations document for off to the
dole because we figured it was time to
together and capture all the all the
security threats implementation issues
security relevant implementation issues
and the lessons learned over the course
of the last couple of years
next slide please so basically the
document tries to give an overview on
the on the current oh of security topics
open security topics and tries to this
systematically capture and discuss the
threats and respective mitigations the
goal or the objective of the working
group is to turn this into a security
best practices back to best current
practice document and to provide
implementers of OAuth client side as
well as server side with recommendations
how to implement a wolf securely or even
secure next slide please
so this is how the document looks like
the majority of the after sections
describe different threats
implementation issues and give different
options how to mitigate on this threat
so for example there isn't the innocent
section on access token or leakage and
there is a comprehensive discussion
what options exist from our perspective
to actually cope with this kind of
threat so for example send the
constraint access tokens all the
instructions and so on and then in the
end we distilled a section containing
recommendations that we give to
implementers for example in this case
regarding token leakage the working
group decided that send the constraint
access tokens either by our token
binding or M TLS would be the way we
would recommend because this is the most
reliable way to to cope of this kind of
issue next slide please
but we nevertheless we gave the whole
discussion so everyone can can can give
it a read and and come up with his or
her own idea all right so this is a
selection of the recommendations we we
are giving to implementers it's just a
selection so the redirect based flows
are a very important part of the of this
document so for example we recommend
exact redirect URI matching this is
something that Open ID Connect required
implementers from the beginning but all
offers it but bit more relaxed regarding
that perspective which in the end this
flexibility opened up a lot of a lot of
issues regarding oaktree directions and
so on and so on and so on so now we
decided it's better to go that way to
recommend exit video at URI matching
because this is a good good foundation
for having a secure solution and there
are other other recommendations that we
give for example to mitigate code
injection armed attacks implementers are
advised to either use pixie challenges
or the nuns in case of open ID Connect
or peace to prevent this kind of attack
next slide please
okay what happened since Singapore we
published a new revision actually I
published a new revision yesterday and
it's complete now from our perspective
so we completed completely reworked the
section on code leakage
and completed a section on axis or f3
for headers and so on I decided to
remove the section on refresh token
leakage just because there is nothing
new to report
right so refresh token leakage
prevention is already covered by the
security consideration sections of our C
67 49 so we don't need to update that
and we added a section on open
redirection based on a draft that John
has published previously so for me you
copy that text India from that draft or
what what did you do no I took the
liberty to - in entering a distilled
version of that just brief description
of the thread and a recommendation how
to cope with that because the the open
redirection draft also gives additional
threats that we are already covered in
other sections of the document so I mean
I would hope we will have another review
round now potentially a working to risk
also people can can check it and give us
feedback on that what we also did is we
removed all the text around this being a
working document helping the the the
working group to keep track of the
current status of the discussion of the
different security open topics because
we think we are done for the moment for
the moment I mean we decided to make it
a PCP to be able to update it to update
it too frequently and I hope I hope we
will do so on not not again wait for how
long five years okay yeah I think so
yeah so it's a PCP so we are radians or
it I hope it will become a BCP so we are
we are well equipped to to update the
document or no no more frequent basis
from my perspective the document is
ready now for Warner Bros Cole and yeah
I would ask you to
I'm so obviously nobody has read the
version that you just posted that would
be a stretch but Android and John writes
the version brilliant okay that's very
good
how many of you have read the earlier
version or the latest version raise your
hand
all right sir five six seven eight
if we wait a little bit long it probably
that's pretty pretty good so I guess we
should we should have a few guys
reviewing posting or doing the review
posting something to the list before we
started working here and following that
one and there's some new stuff in there
so I do we have some some volunteers to
review this document Tony William okay
and if not and someone knows
Brian pan you aware yeah
the name please want to get home okay
Travis Spencer was like thanks Sam
perfectly thank you okay hi everyone I'm
William Dennis I work on Google cloud
here to give three updates today the
first is the device flow this will be
the shortest one so let me just quickly
recap for anyone that hasn't seen the
device flow specification this is an
authorization flow designed for devices
that have an internet connection but no
browser or limited input options so the
classical example is like a TV a TV app
like the YouTube app and in this flow
the user actually reviews the
authorization request on a separate
device and they can approve it there
like a mobile phone or a laptop so the
TV or the device would show a screen
just like this directing the user to go
to an authorization URL and enter a code
the user then loads up that URL on their
separate device such as their phone
typically types in the code approves the
OAuth request and then the device can
get its tokens there's one additional
optimization which which we've added in
the standard which is to allow for a QR
code or any kind of non-textual
verification technique this is presented
separately to the
and of manual instructions allows the
user just to scan the qr-code
and then typically they wouldn't have to
actually enter the user code but they
might confirm that it's the same code
just to avoid kind of phishing risks so
what happened since oh seven since the
IETF 99 presentation I think we did an
update the last one but I missed that
one
but what we have done since then is we
standardized on the complete form of the
verification URL those who were there
may remember a discussion we were
debating whether or not to have a kind
of composed a URL where we would
actually add the verification URL and
the user code kind of in like a sort of
structured composed way that was
rejected in the end and we've just
adopted this simpler kind of option
where the authorization server can just
provide the complete verification year
all for that like QR code optimized
option we also added some security
considerations around spying that was at
Nats request so that's just covering the
case where there could be someone you
know behind you watching all your
interactions you know given this is on a
TV they could be like in the back of the
room or something and we added some text
to explicitly require that the device
code is actually not shown as as part of
this just in case that wasn't clear plus
the text regarding the minimum poling
intervals so we don't Dawson take down
Justin's server again huh and then I
just posted this morning but there was a
diff posted approximately two weeks ago
just a minor clarification around the
entropy guidelines for the user code so
this is this is an interesting code
because because it's actually part of
the user experience there the length is
kind of constrained by what what you can
reasonably expect the user to type and
the char set likewise so we just added a
little bit of a clarification around the
trade-offs there that the authorization
server needs to take your account and we
also document you know the risks of a
low entropy code there if someone were
to be able to kind of brute force that
user code it kind of puts them in this
sort of reverse takeover situation where
like normally if you brute force
standoff
you'll gain access to that grant in this
case if you actually brute force the
user code you have given the victim the
grant which would be to your account so
it's kind of like a reverse takeover now
it probably doesn't make sense for kind
of like the the Play Movies YouTube type
flow or make much sense because then the
victim would actually have to buy things
with your account but there are
certainly you know very valid concerns
still with with that attack such as the
the attacker still may be out actually
control that device and there's also the
privacy issue that the attacker could
see you know things of the user is
actually then doing so it's definitely
worth considering so yeah so that text
went in on version ojeda which I believe
resolves every single outstanding
question and I think we have already
concluded yeah so this is already with
with Ecker so but we're gonna update the
draft version with this one just to
address that comment the last commit
that that we had but at the otherwise it
would be with that crafter so I actually
sent some comments about this and I just
got an email from John like 14 minutes
ago I'm struggling to assimilate so yeah
I guess I'm concerned about whether or
not there's an attack pattern here
and so I I guess after authors so I
guess I'm not sure the best way to
resolve that now central assimilating
John message in the middle of like
listening to this um do you want to
discuss it should we have a side meeting
shall I read it like tonight and come
back to you what we must they do so the
the very short answer is yes you did
actually identify a confused deputy
attack gold star so the the attack is
only possible if can you explain the
attack for those people who hadn't seen
that right so on so the idea is that if
so the device does is an OAuth client if
it talks if it's set up to talk to and
server and that wot server is
compromised ayiiia well it is
compromised her inherently bad
so assuming just for the sake of
argument so that people understand the
attack I'll use real company names but
that isn't to infer that there's
anything nefarious about them so if you
had a Roku device which uses this kind
of flow for binding media subscriptions
to it so if Netflix were compromised ie
their own server had been taken over by
a malicious person that server when it
receives the request from the Roku when
the person clicks on the Roku player
clicks on the Netflix picture and the
Roku would then you start off the flow
to Netflix Netflix would then go yes but
now I can go to Amazon Prime video and
get their highly prized access token for
this user at Amazon Prime so it would go
and create get the challenge get the
user code etc pass that back to the
device the the Amazon 1 back to the
device the user would then see on the on
the screen please type in an amazon.com
slash Prime slash authenticate or
whatever the URI is and they would go
there and they would put in their Amazon
credentials and then they would see a
box that came up please enter the code
that's being shown on your device and
they would put the code from the Roku
into Amazon which would then enable
enable the bad Netflix polling to then
get the appropriate access token so
essentially the user would think that
they're logging in to start off the flow
thinking that they're logging into
Netflix and if they weren't completely
on the ball they may wind up at an
Amazon screen put in their Amazon
credentials at Amazon so Netflix
wouldn't be getting their Amazon
credentials though since they've used
the same username and password both
places it's probable
moot they they would get the access
token for the net for the Amazon Prime
service so I mean it's unlikely that
Netflix is going to attack Amazon but if
you could easily see how that would work
with other services so yes essentially
as good as the least the lowest common
denominator
the weaken the weakest guy that the
device manufacturer has allowed you to
login to because right so I have John
work on that text that you got 14
minutes ago I added the point that for
this to happen either the device
manufacturer is the attacker in which
case you probably didn't want to buy
their device but that or they are
trusting an authorization server that is
the attacker or became compromised well
you know all of which is possible but
there's reputational things where you
know you would get a bad write about it
by your device now William wrote some
text and security considerations earlier
about trying to inform end-users that
what you are doing now is authorizing
use of your Roku device the reason you
want to tell them that is if software
has men in the middle of the whole thing
or something and they don't actually
have a Roku device maybe that's a red
flag and we made an offer to be bub two
of the security consideration
subsections to discuss this confused
deputy situation yeah I mean my sense is
that like this is done constantly and we
don't know how to fix it other than what
you said and so like not writing it down
it's not helpful
like not publish the document because we
have this problem is not hopeful um so I
think like what I was expecting
um even I understand it correctly um is
like for you doing for the security
concern so makes it clear what's going
on and then we could move forward I
don't think like I don't I mean if I
know how to fix it like I've you know
fix it but I don't so like there we are
um yeah I think we'll do that great
thank you
so in terms of running code there's a
bunch of examples now and the most
recent one I I heard about was Yahoo
Japan and the air stick 4k which I've
implanted that adds to the The MITRE ID
open source server implementation we
have a client here proof of concept and
and of course Google actually implements
the server one as well yep Shepherd
right up also contains four examples but
we'll update that okay thank you
which one do you want to talk about next
incremental device posture all right now
for something new well a little bit less
move you if you're here at ITF no no but
um okay so also incremental auth let me
just give a bit of a recap in case you
haven't heard of this before so the
problem statement that incremental
authors trying to solve is that
effectively asking for the kitchen sink
of scopes upfront is a bad thing and
users should have the context of what
they're authorizing when they authorize
it so a good example here is if you have
an app that say combines you know an
identity related scope such as with
O'Grady connect it might combine like a
calendar scope for some kind of calendar
integration and you know say I'm like a
email scope for some email integration
the user shouldn't be presented and
authorized
and request at sign-in time asking for
all those three things they should just
be presented with the the thing that
they're doing at the moment so scream
like this is kind of the antithesis of
what we're trying to get to you know
these apps really shouldn't be asking
for all these things even if they
actually need them to kind of implement
all the various features in the app each
of these scopes should probably be
requested separately when it's actually
needed in the context that it's needed
so the definition of incremental auth is
the ability to request additional scopes
in subsequent requests that results in a
single authorization grant representing
all the scope granted so far
so without incremental auth you would
effectively just have if you did
multiple authorization requests you
would just get multiple authorization
grants that you would have to maintain
several and so the the benefit of
incremental auth is that emerges them
into that one single authorization grant
representing all the scope that's been
grounded so far so typical orientation
of this would be where the consent
screen would only display the new scopes
so if the user has already granted scope
a and the app would ask for B it would
typically show the new scopes go B or at
least it would show that scopes a
differently and then a cigarette fresh
token is issued for the union of all the
granted scopes so this is actually
possible today with a confidential
client you know auth what I call the
kind of de-facto increment auth and the
reason that's possible is that Earth
actually doesn't stop you returning
authorization grant with more scope than
what you requested so in the case of a
confidential client if the user has
already granted access it's kind of
plausible that you could actually return
that access on a subsequent
authorization grant now given that the
the client in this case is actually
authenticating however no such thing
existed for public clients so what this
specification really introduces and the
kind of key point of its existence is a
public option a public client option for
incremental auth are also called up
Kragh mental for which I apologize this
consists of a new token endpoint
parameter called the existing grant
and how it works is that if you've
already done one authorization grant
with some scope you can then do a second
authorization request requesting
different scope and then when you're
going to when you go to exchange the
authorization code for the tokens you
can actually pass in the existing grant
at that time and what you get is kind of
emerged authorization grant that's why
the parameters called existing grant
here's a sequence diagram just showing
the the first request the response the
top half is very typical all affair and
then the bottom half is again very
typical or just with that additional
existing grant scope the existing grant
which is the Refresh token from the
first part being passed in now it's
really very simple set 3 it's just you
take the grant a and the grant B that
we're done as separate authorization
requests and unions them together
nothing really nothing more than that so
if you didn't have this specification
the native app would be sitting there
with both grants separately they'd have
to maintain those to refresh tokens that
have to refresh the to refresh tokens
and just keep keep track of things with
this they get a simplified view of the
world and they just get one so in terms
of running code this has been
implemented on Google's authorization
server so you can actually try it out
today I have a proof of concept code
there using a port it's a fairly minor
modification we also have a demo I don't
know if you want to run the YouTube
video here one minute let's go full
screen yeah so here the user has
performed the first authorization
request the user granted access to
calendars we do a token exchange
let's introspect that token and you can
see here that the scope was created to
calendar within to a second
authorization request in this case it
adds the blogger scope
user has allowed that we're going to
introspect the resulting token and you
can see that both scopes are included so
this is running off that proof concept
code I put a link up to earlier okay and
so in addition to the public clients the
specification also also documents some
best practices around confidential
clients it also includes this new
parameter for confidential clients as I
mentioned it is possible to do
incremental auth with confidential
clients already but perhaps that
behavior of returning more scope than
was requested is is not always expected
so this extra parameter just allows the
the user to actually control whether or
not the request will contain the full
scope that's already been granted or not
alright so what's changed since IETF 99
basically based on the feedback then
added a whole bunch of sections security
section
privacy one on usability and also
documented some alternatives
so that's incremental auth and ok and do
we have people that reviewed this who
have any anybody that reviewed this
document any comments on this who
reviewed that document any anybody here
one two three oh wait I just and I have
not implemented this one yet I did read
through it I think it generally makes
sense
I think that there's ways that it can be
clarified and stuff like that I don't
think there's done but that's not what
you're asking
it is I think an important concept and
it's something that people are doing
today in weird proprietary ways anyway
and I think that this is something that
we can do to encourage people to not ask
for as you put it the kitchen sink or I
think as store stood I used to call it
the uber token right up front what was
Issa as a better know chess and I just
said you amended this term token okay I
thought I thought you did anyway so no
more uber tokens I think is a good thing
or at least minimizing the uber tokens
kitchen sinks whatever if the metaphor
is so yes I do think this is a good
document that we should move forward
with John Bradley I think it's a good
document we should move forward with it
there's probably additional security
considerations that we have to dig into
like was that refresh token actually for
the same subject our resource owner as
the new one so there are things
implementation things that people may
get wrong that we have to sort of think
through some of the the new issues it
would be better with token binding
obviously so that the Refresh token was
actually bound to the client so there's
a few things that need to go into it but
other than that I think it's
functionality that we did have can
largely replicate with confidential
clients but this allows us to have
public clients do the same thing which
unfortunately some of the OAuth
implementations do do and it causes
incremental auth currently with public
clients causes all sorts of interesting
side effects because you wind up
authorizing a client on one device for
something and all of your devices all
this with the same client ID wind up
inheriting that privilege which is also
unanticipated but I've seen in the wild
quite a few times right I guess I guess
I should have explained that that was
why you can't do incremental auth with
the public client at least you shouldn't
I guess you can but you shouldn't for
that reason
okay is there anybody that thinks this
is a bad idea okay so so maybe we'll ask
for hum I go for a hum and see if a the
group is willing to adopt this draft
right now so I'll ask if you're willing
to adopt it and if you're against
adopting this draft so a if you are a
for adopting this document please hum
now if you are against please hum now
okay thank you
that was good yeah so so summarize
people are in favor of adopting this um
can I can also write down a few
reviewers so will obviously have to
confirm it on a mailing list talk about
milestone changes few hence the review I
see just in tour stones John Sean as
well
excellent thank you
oh it's a bet oh maybe it's dead testing
[Music]
okay so thank you for your attention so
far this is the third topic and this
one's device posture so I think John may
have presented there's a couple times
previously I'd like to give it to give a
cracker and and and see if there's some
interest in this document let me start
with the use case so this document is
designed to address a specific use case
and that's that's this BYOD phenomena
mean enterprise bring your own device so
this is where an enterprise wants to
allow its its workers to just bring
their own devices you know Android
iPhone whatever into the enterprise and
use their personal devices with
corporate with corporate resources at
the same time users sometimes will be
hesitant to allow kind of these invasive
mobile device management certificates on
their devices mobile device management
is sort of traditionally how the
enterprise could secure those devices
once they're brought into the enterprise
environment but it has a significant
drawback that the the enterprise can
typically remote wipe that device so
this is kind of a very uncomfortable
feeling because you know you've got your
personal data on there like your photos
and you don't necessarily want your
company just to be able to wipe that and
secondly there are there certainly
privacy concerns as well in the sense
that it gives the enterprise the ability
to read certain data off the device
which varies case-by-case but it's also
less than ideal
despite that the enterprise typically
only really cares about three things or
they at least care about these three
things they care that the user has a
lock screen enabled on their device
they care that the operating system is
up to date they care that the phone is
not rooted or jailbroken the reasons
behind this is that for the first one
they want to make sure that if the user
just leaves the phone at a bar that the
next person that picks it up can't
access the company resources they want
to make sure that the operating system
is up to date to make sure it's patched
against vulnerabilities and they want to
make sure the phone is not rooted or
jailbroken to ensure that the software
on the device can actually be trusted so
rather than the heavy weight mobile
device management solution that gives
the enterprise control over the device
like remote wipe and and being out
access certain data device posture
signals are an alternative to that that
can be used to communicate the devices
compliance state to the authorization
server and it works like this the device
posture signals are simply bits of
information they get sent along with the
authorization and token requests and it
allows the authorization server to make
informed decisions based on those
signals as to what the user can access
of the corporate resources the spec
creates and ion a registry for the
common signals that we're defining which
are then sent in a JSON DC area like
this example here as you can see that a
lot of the data it's just bullying's and
streams it's kind of very simplistic
there's a missing slide here so this
this data is then sent in the
authorization request as a hint called
the device posture hint this allows the
authorization server to guide the user
into a more secure State so for example
if the user requires a lock screen and
the signal on the authorization request
says they don't have a lock screen
because the authorization request is
like a user agent flow in the browser
the authorization server could say
display an error and say hey you need to
go set up a lock screen that's in on
what's called the device posture hint
then on the token request the same
dictionary assent again the reason it's
sent on the token request is that unlike
the authorization request this one can't
be modified by the user in the user
agent so it's a little bit more safe
from their perspective and then it's
also sent that that same jason
dictionary is sent on every token
refresh to ensure that the devices
remains compliant with any of the
corporate policies so from from an app
adoption point of view the good news is
that not every app would actually need
to implement this for it to be effective
uuugh as long as you're actually using
RFC 8252 news style authorization where
you can actually tie all of the devices
grants to a single session then you
really only actually need one to buy a
one app on the device setting this these
signals for it to be effective it can
apply to kind of every app or can apply
to the session on that device so that's
the good news as far as adoption is
concerned you really need like a handful
of apps to implement this of the
enterprise suite for it to be effective
in terms of what protection this offers
you probably noticed earlier that that
these words kind of unsecured strings
and bullying's there's no kind of
cryptographic security around it so what
good is that right well it's this the
the goal here is to protect honest users
who may be hapless but but they're
generally generally honest so this is
the user that that is not trying to
steal corporate
but they might leave their phone in a
bar it can protect against that use case
because the user is not lying about
their client state is not modifying
their clients and this will help them
get into into a good and more secure
state it's not designed to prevent
authorization tokens being issued to
dishonest users someone who's actively
creating like a spoof client and trying
to obtain the authorization token that
is not the goal here however it might
actually possible to create a robust
unforgeable system if you combine some
advanced techniques such as token
binding along with device out of
stations like safety net this is
supported by the spec because the spec
is just defining key value pairs of
signals so it is possible to encode this
type of information in the spec it is
technically out of scope we're not we're
not trying to establish the exact way to
do this and John Bradley has all the
details if you're interested to learn
more about that baby okay so that's
device posture signals and and the
reason that were so let me start with
asking on who has looked at the document
read the document so I guess did you try
to implement this it sounds like a very
simplistic
implementation but it was useful
information that you included which we
haven't heard about last time of
regarding sort of like what What's in
scope of the document what's not and
specifically last and there's a little
bit of confusion of like how do you
manage to get these attestation
information but then there's nothing
said about it but I think that should be
much clearer by now good I also me to
clarify that
have you hear that yes I think we have
implemented something like this it's not
this spec exactly but it is this
technique yeah I guess we need to get
reviewers for this document I think
that's the only approach so okay sir
yeah so so we may actually need to pair
this with a BCP that actually digs into
the operating system specific stuff so
you so having a BCP that says how do you
get a safety net attestation how do you
get a Windows attestation what do you do
on iOS so the core spec that that we're
proposing here is focused on how you
transport it to the token end point to
the authorization endpoint and how you
would possibly further pass it on and
open ID connect to to an author as a
authentication server because you may
want to know what the app is something
about the app when you're doing the
authentication separate from the
authorization in an enterprise scenario
but that should probably be kept
separate from the operating system
dependent stuff which changes every 12
months so like we did with a pause where
we have a BCP we probably need to have
an implementation vcp how to do it but
that shouldn't stop us from initially
adopting the course back and moving
forward with that yeah so so do behalf a
few people who could they can look at
this document do a review and so we can
see any any what it is I see Tony and
nothing not in the wrong way so I will
reach out to some of you doing this week
and do some untwisting and great I think
it's a it appears to be a useful
mechanism so one other quick point as
ekor pointed out we have this
problem of how do I know if I'm talking
to a fake app so this is the first thing
that we've actually talked about that
may actually be able to address am I
talking to the app that I think I'm
talking to which means that our ad
should actually be quite keen on us
making progress with this all right okay
well thank you everyone I appreciate
your time thank you thanks a lot we have
time for Justin to talk about
hdtb signing I am yes you should read
the title of the slide with a sigh okay
so I wasn't planning on talking about
this but I saw an interesting draft
yesterday that kind of brought this
thing back around and also there's been
some discussion on the mailing list
about ja sind introspection responses
and things like that so anyway the topic
of HTTP signing we've talked about it
before and there's this draft that I
wrote years ago it's functional it's
been implemented by several different
people it works it's flexible but it's
also expired and completely unloved by
this working group so there's also this
other draft the cabbage HB signatures
cabbage apparently has moved on from
this and somebody else has taken over
editing it but it's kind of resurrected
in the last six months I'd actually
didn't know that until this morning when
I was pulling this information together
but there's some more stuff in there
it's got a lot of problems in it I you
know humbly say that it has more
problems than my own draft but you know
whatever but it's it's a similar kind of
approach tries to be a little bit more
Universal and therefore runs into a
little bit more Universal problems we
looked at it in this working group
decided back then it wasn't wasn't
really what we were looking for and
having skimmed the new version not read
it in depth I still don't think this is
quite what we're after
you can always just use draw for
everything we already made the mistake
of soap once let's not make it again all
right
the new draft that I just found out
about literally last night at the RFC
lightning talked things is you ask an
HTTP origin signed responses now this is
a draft that adds a signature header to
the HTTP message this is not something
that is bound to any kind of like access
token or particular style of API or
something like that this is something
that allows you to sign an HTTP response
it does have some amount of crypto
flexibility in that you can use bear
elliptical curve keys or x.509 certain
signatures with multiple signers which
is important in a lot of HTTP systems
because you've got proxies and all this
other stuff and everybody's gonna want
to kind of do their own thing along the
way the problem that this draft is
trying to solve is especially in the
world of HTTP 2 when you've got a
provider like Google that's serving a
page they want to be able to do things
like HTTP to push and include a bunch of
little stuff that's actually from
somewhere else but they've cached it on
the way through and they're sending it
to you and stuff like that you want to
be able to verify the content and all of
that the interesting thing about this is
that the signature is also over the
request but it's only included in the
response which is to say the server that
is serving the response generates the
signature but it includes like this was
the request that made me give you this
response as part of that so some really
interesting mechanisms there downsides
is that this is response only it is
written in such a way that it's only
signing the response it is not the
client the HTTP client signing the
request which if we were to apply this
to the OAuth space that's the part that
we really want you know we want to have
a signature protection and key proof of
possession around the client that is
making the request to the API in the
first place this doesn't do that but in
my reading of it and I sat down and had
a conversation with the author of this
draft earlier today it could be adapted
or really the same structure
be reused in this space now there is no
body or payload protection this this is
all like headers and URLs and stuff like
that
but there's another draft which I'll
talk to in just a second that allows you
to do that kind of stuff it is tied
generally to certificates in PKI there
is kind of this little additional thing
on the side that says oh you can use a
bear key if you're doing elliptical
curves it's still a very early draft I
think that the flexibility that's
already kind of built in there would
allow us to have more bear key use cases
and of course most of' bound keys token
bound keys which is nothing to do with
token binding of course but we've run
out of words most of those are going to
be bear keys anyway and not certificates
with chains and validation reading
through the draft itself most of the
complexity that I saw again coming just
brand new to this was in the certificate
validation which is kind of not
surprising is you know making sure that
the certificate gets valid and it's in
the right window and there's all these
like cache timeouts and stuff like that
if you're just doing this with bear keys
it's pretty straightforward it's
generating a signature getting in the
right format putting in the right place
with the right identifier the draft that
is referenced from that in order to
allow for content protection is giraffe
Thompson HTTP mice and this is just
basically a really clever way to use
merkel graphs and digests and things
like that to protect HTTP bodies in a
not exactly in a streamable fashion but
in an ependymal fashion you can kind of
chunk it up and incrementally know
whether or not you've got integrity
protection over the body it's an
alternative to like the HTTP like
full-body message digest thing not
digest authentication but the other one
downside of course is that none of this
supports OAuth because they're all
solving their own things and honestly
that's that's kind of okay I never
wanted to have to solve HTTP signing in
the OAuth working group but it was if we
were going to be doing proof of
possession tokens which we thought we
were a few years ago we were gonna have
to come up with some way to do that
other people turns out have this HTTP
signing problem and have for years
that's why we have the cabbage document
that's why we've got a bunch of
proprietary implementations AWS has its
own weird fragile thing I see Anna
nodding for that and so people are
trying to crack this particularly tough
nut I think these two drafts have some
interesting promise in the way that
they're approaching the problem and I
think it might be worth while for us to
look at that and if we did what we would
really need to do is adapt the sign
responses so that they can cover
requests it's all HTTP structures it's
all based on structured headers and all
that kind of stuff it would be a fairly
straightforward to define a request
header that would be analogous to the
response header and how those two play
nice together and all that how that gets
bound to the the keys to the tokens and
how that gets represented to do the
signing and we can still send our access
tokens like we always have because now
we're signing a header and we can sign
like you know we can sign the access
token header we can sign the the date
header we can sign a bunch of other
things that give us the types of
security properties that you like in
addition to having message level
signature protection around that request
that proves that you have a particular
key that is bound to that token and we
can also use the token confirmation
methods that have already been started
to be fleshed out in job and thanks to
Brian we now have a field for that from
the introspection responses due to the
MT LS work we can add in ways to say
like from the authorization server to
the resource server hey here's the key
that you're supposed to be looking for
when you're looking at validating this
message which was the pop model if
anybody remembers that document from
ages ago
that was kind of the intended model of
this all along so I figured the group
should know that these things exist like
I said I just found out that this is a
thing so I just want to let people know
this is here and is this something that
we want to pick up again
Thank You Justin for making as a way of
this work one of the questions I have on
what the problem we ran into packed in
with this work was that we had these
intermediaries and also for application
frameworks that munched around with the
headers and and the payload somehow that
rendered the signature invalid we also
had as we focused mostly on as the
document same signing hdbuzz signing it
sort of literally not encryption and so
and maybe back then we focused on
symmetric as well as a symmetric keys
and our question for me is are we still
trying to accomplish the same things or
did we maybe change our mind in the
meanwhile that we saw it's from your
torque it appears that some of the guys
are more looking at the use of
asymmetric crypto not in a meanwhile
with literally digital and digital
signatures and not use symmetric keys
anymore or you mentioned the encryption
format in Thompson maybe that's a
another data point a finalist is that
that's that's not encryption that's not
Egyptian no it's integrity protection of
the HD message part okay there's a
Christian one okay so that's that's news
to me so apparently there's an
encryption okay okay it's so for on Mike
that it says just do a IDI with that
same key okay
yes no there's already I think it's I
think it's actually in our C or in the Q
now Thompson draft about doing content
encryption with pre shared key metric
key um presume we would give you the
because they ATO the integrity property
she we shall have as well I mean so you
wouldn't I don't know it curves the mice
does the header
was just how did the mice adjust had to
do a signature as our call that allows
you to progressively verify the data as
it comes in rather than it verified it
through yet right otherwise it's just as
exciting right um I think you're wrong
with the asking graph to discard that
the askin draft does cover the body I
can I think this is the point since the
point is this is the point of it is to
allow you to is allow you to have data
which is in the origin of the person
who's signing it and if you didn't cover
the body that would not be very useful
that seems unlikely
so my understanding was that it covers
the body by outsourcing it to either the
mice draft or the body digest header
header yeah yeah so yeah it so so to be
clear this this the Gaskin draft does
cover the body if you use another draft
that covers the body and then spits out
a header and then you cover that header
using this okay so this is basically
this this does the the verb URL and
headers okay right and then the mice
draft basically does a progressive form
of a signature over the body okay and
spits that into a header so maybe what
what we should be then looking into is
how to how we could tie this into the
proof possession work with us for use
with these existing documents that's
what you're imposing yeah that's what
I'm proposing if we want to pick up
proof of possession with HTTP level
message signing this may be an avenue to
do that this is new work this has not
been adopted by the HTTP this working
group at this time I know there's going
to be a presentation on the ask and
drive tomorrow I I don't know where it's
going and I can't predict where it's
going but people are trying to solve
this as well and if there's a general
HTTP mechanism that we can then say oh
instead of using you know a PKI search
chain use your access token and
associated key to generate that same
signature that would really be the wind
that we're after
yeah so I don't think it's like super
likely that like this is going to be
adopted so in particular the focus on
origin substitution that is allowing the
the the the web peaky isert to sign the
data which doesn't accept that is it for
HTTP responses like not like super
popular so um I mean maybe possible is
someone like will do some trimmed-down
version that just is tied to a pre
shared key to like a rocky so I don't
know quite a thought exactly but I know
that the use cases Google wants like
include meeting their like origins of
solution feature so there was some
question but there was a there's this
meeting today it's or some of that stuff
um so I don't know what's gonna happen
but um I think if what you guys want is
a digital signature over the system that
is just tied to a key which is
established them independent fashion
that is not tied to you know would be
high origins then probably tell me she'd
be that and and and maybe not trusted
digital signature variant but also the
symmetric key variant
yeah so I guess you didn't is that you
need to cover the headers I guess for
brick Chris so funny you should mention
that on I think so since they're using
AED I suppose as possible you could
modify it on the Thompson RFC to treat
the headers as the ad keep me much but
again like ah you know it's a little bit
of work it's always working it's it's
definitely work to adapt it into this
space
it is solving a different but related
problem in a different but related way
so it's it's you know it's it's not a
simple turnkey kind of thing but it
might be something we want to pursue
that might be an interesting topic for
dinner conversation doing this week so
we're centimeter around not like
independently having a dinner among the
most folks I would be useful anyway so
we could put that forward as a
discussion topic thanks Justin for
bringing yourself
awesome thank you guys do you have
anything any other topic that you would
like to raise that we should maybe talk
about at the second session maybe on how
we could actually get the AC turned up
to a level that I don't I'm not freezing
it in front of the room apparently not
there's a microphone jack just come
forward if we have five extra minutes
tomorrow maybe we could just give a
quick overview of our assistant token
propose you want to do that now do we
have yeah I'd rather have some slides
okay and some some rest after travel
yeah exactly
oh we actually ran over time didn't yeah
we're done okay yeah I also fought 5:30
so we ran over them sorry about not you
what is he has slice or did I act I
think he will it is called here terrible
cold