I know I guess we have sight no no no no
Jerry there's no it's just
and then here II we have one hour of
this like on the timetable
I really have which obviously we're not
gonna fail so I think it's officially
time isn't it so hello everyone I think
it's officially time but you know seeing
as we're in the Metropole will give
people a while longer to try and find us
because some yeah like a week or two
[Music]
I do not know it's just a okay I mean I
realized that it's the same behavior but
see ya okay who trade penises let me try
and umm yeah
the okay taking it off that's exactly
what look that's a sound engineer right
the lights didn't turn off there take a
look yeah
I'll push reset any push buttons
randomly Tara maybe not
I predict failure yes sir so the
operation CRA is having slight
operational difficulties
I'd still like them so I get if I get on
again in case that somehow made to
renegotiate
they got a picture on it on this side
what it's all because I can find a knife
because that's always there we can try a
different machine at them yeah which is
just because because that's not mine
that's a Chinese stuff he knows about
them yes choice again we do not
understand your character sense at least
it's different behavior
last time there are also two lights on
now there are four lights on I don't
know what any of the lights you know
they myung yet you know the output
circuit it's not it's no it's not
working for us we are we I don't like
from there to fight this money as okay
you're gonna get to go into display
settings let me get a Mac yeah sure
maybe you need to change the monitor
7:20 Shenmue dojo try 1080 yeah which
one means we'll just tryna kick changes
it wasn't no nobody intersecting uh run
it up may I try yeah please do because
pickles
hey Cesar you excellent
ok once I get up here the slides on my
machinery yeah let's try it
it misses I think I can runs again I
also need like close all the hundreds of
[Music]
keep telling people Mexico where are the
slides okay come on yes and there are no
fights is just a medium
bb-but lesson materials go faster good
thing we padded the meeting by a few
minutes
[Music]
do we have a yes River not a USB Drive I
can see that make it Marat sharing
options in menu bar arrangement
woohoo technology
why am I
[Music]
yeah that one that one as you can tell
I'm not a Microsoft okay okay then so
that only took us nine minutes serve
them stuff good things were good thing
we're not an ops group or anything so
hello everyone welcome to the UPS area
part of ops area and ops AWG we here is
the note well it is the new note well it
is fairly similar to old note well but
has other changes so we are going to
need a minutes taker and a JavaScript
taker and a Java scrap
so we are going okay
who it's amazing how like nobody makes
eye contact when when setting up at the
front being like who would be willing to
be a minute taker whis cleverly took
Jabbar because now I can't you know
force him to be a minute taker Joe Clark
I know is working on fixing something
but I figure right now he's probably
fixed it and and rancid I'm sure works
fine now
and so Joe will you be minute taker oh
hang on you might have issues for later
on in the meeting with you because
you've got an excuse
Eliot Lehrer I saw there's earlier
we're not actually looking for best at
this point just anyone else I noticed
that Rhoda guess at me drinking hissing
and shaking his head okay so I guess we
will be having some minutes with some oh
I see an L Martin hiding in the back of
the room crouch down L Martin sir if we
ask you nicely you would you please okay
I see how this is gonna work so we will
have two sets of minutes then with small
sets of gaps and hopefully they don't
don't miss a line too badly okay then
that's how we're gonna do it it looks
like so somewhere in the room we have
some blue sheets they are slowly
circulating please make sure to actually
sign the blue sheets the Secretariat
gets mad if we don't and they can be
kind of scary so this is our agenda
does anybody have any bashing of the
agenda that they would like to do great
so first off we've managed to figure out
our that and now let me stand up and go
to the big Mike
actually I can do this sitting so as
everyone presumably by this point knows
Benoit is stepping down and yes no need
burst into laughter at this point I know
you're happy about it so yeah Benoit is
stepping down on Wednesday and he is
counting down the hours and minutes and
seconds till then but you know I would
like to personally thank him you know
very sincerely for having been an
awesome awesome ad to work with I
arrived knowing absolutely nothing as
I'm sure he'll be happy to agree with
I'm no knowing absolutely nothing and
Benoit has been
truly awesome in terms of sort of
teaching me how the should all work
answering a lot of truly stupid
questions and then answering them a
second and third time because I forget
the answers the first view and just you
know generally running the management of
ups and management for a large number of
years in a very dedicated and thorough
manner and also more importantly sort of
keeping the culture alive
and showing how stuff in the IHG should
be done and the right way to run things
and so seriously thank you a huge amount
for for that it really means a lot and
we also have a small token token of our
appreciation both of us you know and
surprisingly it is alcohol we have at
the end at the end of however many
errors how could you not not need large
amounts of alcohol so this is actually
ad fuel a correction this is not an
alcohol direct it's ad whew thank you
thank you very much our sponsor would
say you know make right choices and when
I see that calorie that 25 years old and
octomore I mean these are pretty good
choices so proud of you so yeah it was
quite quite a fun ride six years you
know normally you always do with term or
two and then you know there was this
young stuff that I wanted to finish so
it has been fun challenging sometimes
but I don't regret it I learned a lot
and you know with the question that you
are asking what I learned after six
years is that the more I know the more I
know I don't know because there are so
many things that was happening there
it's always like learning so actually I
learned a lot from you guys and thanks a
lot
[Applause]
so you wanted to say a few things about
the ad transition yeah all right so I
want to be more formal here when we
prepare discussion that is reeling with
with Agnes and Warren we're thinking
that maybe it would be good you know
from time to time I do like a young
State of the Union and maybe in light of
this ad transition it would be good if I
would cover a couple of points there and
you know where we are what we've been
doing which problem we'll have we'll
have in the future
or maybe we'll have an a question which
I've been receiving multiple times which
is like is the next day the still a
young lady and the question is should he
be right so and maybe I want to maybe
during five or ten minutes
exponentiation so for four years ago we
made room in the iesg for someone to
focus on onion right it means that I
gave away a couple of working groups
like observe you GE and then radius and
ya meter and L map and because we saw
this tsunami of yang modules coming
right and we were right
there are many yang modules so somehow
its success for what you guys have been
defining and yes there are many yang
modules right if I look like we had like
six new RFC published this week with
yang modules we still have like 250 yang
modules coming if you look in the the
yang catalog in which were working in
hackathon we have as of this morning
3214 yang modules unique ones right so
what you guys have been defining it's a
is used and you know it's a good frame
to have now we are on track I believe
with you know yang right so the idea was
to say we're going to solid ice of
protocols and the encoding and you know
if you see this yang catalog and this
logo there
with all different yang modes used the
idea was to say let's try this on dice
maybe the 200 yang modules or 300 the
ones that are ki-44 for everybody now I
still believe that we're going to have a
couple of challenges and I'm going to
just throw them on the wall and see what
sticks
what stick and and maybe this would be
like where you could have an impact
right so in terms of what needs to be
improved right because the solution is a
perfect
we are inhalation where we are running
current consensus which mean that by
definition consensus takes some time and
you know for operators sometime it's not
fast enough right so in terms of the
problem we might be having we have right
this is like how do we update those yang
modules
that's one big one all right we we know
that you know by definition by with the
yang rules we need to have the perfect
module they want because they must be
within a backward compatible way but we
know also that this causes delay right
because they have to be perfect they
want so as we learn more about those
modules and we need to update them right
the last case was from a difference do a
hackathon where you know they realized
they made a mistake right so they need
to be updated so this is where for
example will need to have something like
semantic versioning where we say it's a
major minor or patch upgrade right and
also next to what we've been doing a
hackathon those health metrics about
young modules right because regardless
of how good we believe we are in the end
isis were it's used because it's
compares there is some maturity it's
imported there is called etc so maybe
we'll have to think differently about
the problem there and the next big point
is maybe we want to focus on the what I
call the product of the RFC as opposed
to the RFC right it's great to have an
RFC number because you could have it in
RFPs and the vendors would implement it
but in the end they care about like in
this case those young modules or
anything could extract from the from the
the RFC and it means that if we focus on
this those young modules then the
process could be changed that we've run
the process directly on those modules
and from time to time we go and prison
RFC number the next big one I see is the
examples right we start to have many
examples in those in those modules and
this is a good thing but how do we
validate those how do we make sure that
they're fine right somehow it's done by
the inductors but we should automate
this we should have you know if we speak
about github for example next the yang
modules we must have the examples but
also the way to validate the examples
and a longer time have more and more
examples which mean that we'll have two
different life cycles one for an RFC
number and one for all the modules and
the examples and the metadata and and
all this so that's quite a big one as
well and and the other one is maybe
where are where is the source of truths
for all these modules right so people
still extract is from RFC's right but
you know working with Ayana it could be
that Diana
the source of truth now sorry if we come
up with Diana
then sometimes we have like in one of
the examples you get an RFC I yang what
you and a bug or surprise right there is
something to be corrected now word is
this young module with this new
correction right now we're asking people
to extract the young modules and to
apply the errata so it means that we'll
have to think differently and maybe have
this in Ayana with the the book applied
so what it mean there is this time zone
database right where we have a
coordinator so it believe at some point
in time we will need to have the same
thing where some members the committee
would be in charge to say this is the
yang module this is the latest version
and if we combine this with the house
matrix have been mentioning it validates
and as we learn more there are more
varied
there are more features etcetera we'll
have to correct thing so this is maybe
another thing that that will need to be
done now again maybe it's the long list
of problem but these are good problems
to have we went away from the face where
we have to sell a technology to it's
known it's used to the phase of
optimization so maybe it to answer the
question I'm being receiving multiple
times should the next ad be a young ad
maybe not right but we are in the
optimization phase and you will have
your own set of challenges
so welcome hi Elliott Francisco first
Benoit thanks very much for your service
for these many years and for your
commitment to operational excellence and
in all different ways it's very much
appreciated by me personally and having
a level head in the room always always
helps I wish we have more of them and
I'm glad to say the ops area is
generally and pretty good about that we
have three great level heads there as
the person who organized the TZ database
coordinator I have some thoughts on that
and I think there are some it's an
interesting idea but I think there's
some interesting differences problem
with Yang is that there's code
associated with it and lots of it
it'll be write to a young ma module just
to have a young module there's actually
no there's no compiled code into
products and so as we think about this
problem a coordinator might be the right
approach right the coordinator might
need to be a bit of a policeman and as
it happens I know a man would have badge
sitting next to you and the reason that
I I think about it in these terms is it
could be that if someone wants to bring
something for through the ITF as a yang
model in particular
that may be what we're really looking
for is a little bit of commitment from
that individual or maybe a group of
individuals saying yeah we're not going
to step away from this once it's built
we will answer
Arata we will answer we will show
operational excellence and it could be
that you know I'm not suggesting that we
have a section in the RFC for instance
is how we're going to show operational
excellence but at least when they sell
the idea into the IETF they should
answer that question so that that means
that they're not just going to come here
get there RFC number and leave but
actually show some sort of commitment to
me to maintaining this stuff I think
that's very important and I think it's a
little different from the TZ model where
you have a bunch of volunteers who come
and go and we really have two
coordinators who honestly have been
doing the job and it's sort of thankless
way where they've been sued and all
sorts of other things for their for
their efforts and now I'm not saying we
should you know use this the lawsuit
model is the way forward but in terms of
your thinking I would say you know think
about the you know the man with a badge
and how to how to get gained that
commitment for operational license all
right so um Thank You Benoit for leaving
the state of young as it is and for me
to try to take that over so a few
comments on on the view of the other
things might continue from my
perspective so my view is that the core
work on young language itself the
protocols is mostly done not necessarily
done but mostly done it's stable and so
sustainable we certainly need
maintenance of that but the bigger
bigger work area is in the modeling and
modeling from the practical point of
view that now we don't develop models
just because it's another fashionable
trend in the technology we develop the
models which address the actual
operational needs and in a way how they
are actually being used
in the field so it's about operational
workflow and more on to operational
workflow and usability of the modeling
and less so on the protocol mechanics
and other things that we are typically
used to work in IDF also the outreach
into the industry and especially the
operational part of the industry is an
important part IDF is mostly from from a
perspective of young ITF is mostly a
closed-in organization yes
every when dealing here understands that
technology and builds on that but if we
look into the actual field into the
deployments yang is still not there or
at least not up to the level that it
should be given the amount of work that
we are investing here in IDF
so from that perspective the focus
likely needs to shift more into modeling
using yang becomes more of a tool not
and go but this is just a tool in the
process of defining how the other
technology components which are being
controlled by a family of young things
can be used operationally and in a
practical operational way so at least I
have this as as a goal for myself and
then you understand that talking is easy
but trying to do something here involves
a lot of moving parts and a lot of other
entities outside of IETF so basically we
we need to focus on the requirements for
the users the users of the technology
the users of a young and less so on the
requirements which are coming only from
other working groups and other
technology domains within the ITF so I
think that work phase is complete
young stable relatively mature now it
needs to be brought into usability
any questions or comments on that in
particular or shall we go into our open
mic / performance on section Joe Clark
Cisco
first of all Benoit I've known him for a
while
thank you were at Cisco and I joined
back in 98 already we went through some
hell with SNMP together some hell with
our own products together and I guess
some hell with yang together and we've
you definitely got me a lot more
involved I appreciate that
you got me a lot more connected to Yang
and solving some of the problems and
hopefully avoiding some of that hell for
people to come specifically on this
operation of thing one of the things
Benoit that you kind of brought to the
forefront and I think Ignace to your
point about operationalizing Yang and
you mentioned the product of the IETF
shouldn't just be the RFC number and
Elliott said don't just get your RFC
number and go it's about how do we move
faster to help operators adapt or to
help the operators consume the products
that we're putting out how do we move
more into that open source model where
we're producing yang models and
iterating over them to help solve the
problems that the operators are actually
facing and in a timely manner so that
they don't have to go and look for other
ways of fitting say a square brick into
a round slot for it so I'm hoping that
we can keep some of that momentum going
and that we can be better about
producing products that meet operational
needs at the velocity that it's required
to do so
so you know this job but for the rest of
the audience what we've been trying to
do to address Ignis point is that you
know even if I mentioned me times yang
in in my talk alright maybe too many
times in the end we want to have an
users not caring about yang so what
you've been doing with the catalog is
that you just select something you want
to manage a vinum for example you select
it you found the right yang modules and
they're plenty of ones then you look at
the house metric there which one is the
relevant one there's a maturity based on
validation based on code whatever and
there you just click and then you just
produce a Python script that will go and
configure real villains this is what we
need to do more and then the second
thing I want to add is you know we did
that during ITF hackathons for many
meetings now we want to move this in the
next level and we're trying to get like
I sock money to have one person assign
full-time for a year on this right
because if you want to have this like an
introduction right really for operators
to offer them a service we need to have
someone like dedicated and I'm still
hopeful that is going to happen so
whenever we have that then we have the
full story and we have like all the
revision of young modules but all the
metadata we've got the usability so this
is my hope that we'll get that funding
already so I guess let's go into the
open mic session for ops area and I
believe there will be another they've
been mic session for up say WG in a
little bit so going once going twice
and this concludes the ops area part of
ops AWG and ops area already seeing as I
seem to be the person with the working
computer I will I guess
continue printing I mean presenting for
ops AWG pot assuming the chairs would
like that and assuming I can turn off
full-screen mode
let me also close my chat program I'm
impressed that nobody thought to to mess
with that yeah we're the presenter sure
machine can sure okay we have some
administrivia yes yeah so and I think I
first got in there so first off we have
some final up Syria administrivia we
currently have three chairs for ops AWG
and ER one of them is Ignace so the plan
is Ignace will be stepping down as ops
AWG chair and he will end up becoming
the responsible ad for for UPS AWG
instead of me so you know thank you for
your service as ops ADG chair and haha
sucker for becoming becoming ad so
thanks a lot for that
and this this will happen sometime
during this week and this interesting
use case for a data tracker that ones
formerly 80s which ever happens then
we'll try to do the chest which over and
the person switching is the same so
we'll see what goes with the data track
it's a test case for that so then op cwg
will move to be a and I will become the
responsible area director for the ops
AWG the rest as of say the Balaji was
continuing with a focus they hopefully
will continue doing exactly the same and
now we are moving to the ops AWG meeting
and as I'm no longer formally a chair I
will leave the stage for you but there
is to be a to large of concentration of
chairs of both physical chairs and
chairs as roles at the same table so so
begins the ops area working group
session of our meeting does anyone still
need to fill in the blue sheets Wow Alex
does yes the slides are up Elliot and
how will you continue to act as minute
takers I fully understand that hopefully
how you'll fill in the gap you escaped
okay unless you're still on jabber okay
uh hide the clicker as was pointed out
by one the note well has changed a
little bit
please note well in particular it has
been updated to be more you know in
accordance with how the IETF operates
and so you can see all of the various
items there it has not changed however
between when Lauren first introduced it
not that I know of at least as for who
we are we've already gone through that
I'm Joe Clark joined by Ken run and
Ignace at least for the time being
we've set up all our slot scribes and
minute takers and we'll move right into
the update section of our meeting you
want to talk about after last meeting
the service model explained the document
has been published as RFC a3 on I now we
have five active working group document
firstly the Capricorn external document
has finished or the working group
procedure and now is he waiting in the
RFC queue and we also finished the first
or last core for the I fix BGP community
document the major problem is about the
use case and and the motivation later
the also well reports the latest the
revision we really hope more input from
operators can help this document and we
also send an a-t-m model and the maher
walk to the ASG
Joe do you have any details on that
so the first would mud we're gonna hear
an update from Elliott
on that I believe that the there's a few
changes that might need to be made la
will touch on them and it might have
gotten pushed back a little bit from a
telecheck standpoint due to some other
cueing yeah just scheduling in terms of
the NAT draft it is gone through its
Shepard review by me it has been
submitted for publication as shown
but again hasn't hasn't had a chance to
be fully reviewed by the isg again do
this scheduling and the last why is the
attackers protocol it's in good progress
the authors have adjust the most open
issues they've addressed a number of the
issues but not although they're not
engaging not all of them I I can see
almost most of them is that list my test
is still in the document with no so I I
don't know what's going on it's a
serious problem so I agree on the
engagement
I reviewed the latest the wait and send
email asking them one to summarize and
to I had some some points and I have not
heard back in terms of the accreditation
you're you're in the contributors the
acknowledgement section and the initial
cut-and-paste of my text was verbatim
with no excuse for it come on this isn't
high school people know to give
acknowledgments for text that you're
kind of in a state there's still no
acknowledgement that a good section of
the security considerations text was
written by me if you want updates if you
want engage I would be happy that
/ editorship and do whatever the working
group wants to get this done but waiting
months and months between the reviews
sorry between the releases dropping a
new leader that running away it's not
engagement hi we do need more engagement
of you heard I know you were amazing
with some of the yes for the 0-7
revision I was in discussion of authors
and since then there were no major
changes to the document so my suggestion
in this case would be that again instead
of trying to escalate this as a possible
conflict within the working group to try
to lace with authors and simply explain
I had all kinds of detailed reviews of
the document more than anyone else in
the working group more than is normal
for this kind of document and the
response from the authors has typically
been ignoring I can't wait anymore it's
their responsibility to engage okay that
that is understood I cannot answer for
our other office I'm not a whether any
of them is present in this meeting and
this document is not being presented the
only thing that I am stating as the fact
that I did lies with them at a time
frame or 0-7 and since then there were
no major changes from this particular
topic were to address my reviews which I
do appreciate
but some parts of my reviews were no I
responded to and did not result in
changes in the document so I mean anyone
can write a document and throw it over
the wall occasionally the point is to
get consensus
whether you want to see that happening
so if the author's repeatedly for the
past 40 years do not engage and do not
move towards consensus that I have to
question why this document is here or
why the working group cannot put someone
else in who will move I mean I look
despite me doing radius I'm not here to
shut this down
it's I read the document and I had no
idea what to implement and three years
later I'm still pretty sure I have no
idea what to implement we can't publish
a document like that the security so
there are two questions that you are
asking first why this document is in the
working group at the time when the first
document was adopted there was a
consensus to adopt it it was long time
adult is working why are the authors not
engaging why is the working group not
pushing before so I cannot answer for
the office the way they were contacts
with them yes
the process is not going that that fast
as it could but I'm not one of the
office I cannot answer that on their
behalf okay Eliot here I I sympathize
with Alan if the doctor is not moving at
a reasonable pace then it's worth the
chairs getting involved to start to
figure out how to get it to move I think
that's a perfectly reasonable request I
don't think you can solve it here I just
think it's a work with worthy to mention
it and and then let's move on it's my
suggestion yeah no we failed is it
summery it's basically either publish it
drop it or get someone else in yeah we
noticed this is a serious problem and we
will bring you and the others together
and discuss this how to solve this
I and unless you Jake I'll take a
personal AI to follow up and get this
moving with the author's yeah that's a
continue with the forum presentation and
our speakers we still have the magenta
tape where you must stand in order for
our remote participants to be able to
see you so please try to contain confine
yourself to the mocks yes mud status
hello its Elliott again alright so this
is a brief status on mud it's where we
are and where we think we're going to go
for next steps so mud was a its
manufacturer usage descriptions basic
idea is to miss for the manufacturer to
be able to communicate various aspects
of a device to the local deployment
particularly the network side but it
doesn't necessarily have to be limited
to that of what the device is how it's
supposed to behave next slide please
so this document is passed last call
several times actually the thing that
has slowed it down is that it is
normally referencing the ACL model and
the ACL model essentially took a year to
go rework because it's been through five
last calls and so one might get a little
tired of the last calls and I hope that
the net mod working group is tired over
their last calls and they're down to
little issues like whether a
non-terminal a node in the yang tree
should be called access lists or ACLs so
that means that some of the examples in
the mud document will probably change as
they finally wrap up we can handle that
in all 48 as as we're moving on
I discussed with Warren there's a one
error in the current draft at least
which is that system info is currently
listed as a URL that's a holdover we
just got that in this working group it
should move from URL to utf-8 the
reasoning the reasoning being that the
applications people in the reviews
basically said you really don't want to
do a lot of HTML processing too many
bugs and that too many opportunities for
vulnerabilities so don't do that
especially on your first time around and
so the other thing they said is and stop
messing around with the URL that's what
they basically told me you have to not
constrain it and so we had a fairly
lengthy negotiation about that basic
issue is that be CP 190 says you can't
impose strictures on the form of the URL
on the other hand it was written at a
time when you phasic aliy had a web
browser and a web server and you don't
want things in the middle monkeying with
it we don't have a web browser on one
end of this discussion I'm going into
this connection we have something
putting out DHCP or lldp or being pulled
out from a or information being pulled
out from a cert so our model is a little
different than they envisioned in any
event we've come up with some text which
is advisory which says look just leave
the query element alone or we advise you
to leave the query element alone because
we might be standardizing that in the
future and we haven't decided we're
going to have that conversation but
we're not going to have the conversation
in last call of a document we're just
gonna we're gonna say well that's future
work and let's move on and this is where
we've left things with them and the
applications area director in particular
Adam that seems pretty happy with that
approach and then he wants to actually
have the conversation which is really
good because we should the tell a chat
chief for that is April 19th my one
regret is that benoit won't be able to
yay or nay this but I was hoping that
things would finish so you could do that
then while but hopefully it'll happen
soon enough and as Lauren told me the
stack of documents in front of us is
quite substantial which is why the date
is what it is
all right next slide please so
as a reminder you know what that what
all this is about you know the the thing
that mud started to tackle was that
middle green one which is how do I
protect it on my network and also the
only one below it which is is it doing
what it should be doing and so we've
been focusing on that and so for the
other stuff like what is this thing
we're talking about using mechanisms
like E and a 8o 2.1 AR and other things
to identify the device unit to the
deployment and then we're looking at how
to broaden all of these answers for
various different forms of technology
like 802 11 like 3G 4G 5g and across
different markets or different segments
of markets next slide please
oops just a little bit back if you would
there you go okay
so one of the things we didn't touch
with a ten-foot pole was in the first
round was how to handle sort of
bandwidth expectations of a device one
of the reasons is that I still have
scars personally from dealing with QoS
in the early 90s between the early 90s
and late 90s and wasn't quite ready to
start with out when we had some really
low hanging fruit just on access but now
we really have this question so you
installed a you know device and you
don't really know how much bandwidth
it's going to take out of your network
nor what it's designed to take out of
your network and maybe it's a fire it
may be sort of like a little temperature
sensor to detect fires maybe it's going
to do you know it's going to need like
yeah you know a packet every five
minutes maybe a packet every minute
depending on how it's designed and no
more and all of a sudden it starts
spewing well it could be that a there's
a fire and it's saying hey there's a
fire or it could be that it has a noisy
transceiver and so something's gone
wrong with the device but you don't know
because you don't know how it's been
designed that's the question in the
question before us is can we provide a
description or can the manufacturer
provide your description oh that sort of
behavior both when it's a nominal state
and maybe when it's an exceptional state
and such that the deployment can have
understanding of how the device will
behave in those two states from the
bandwidth utilization standpoint and so
this is sort of research II in that
we're not sure that the manufacturers
are actually going to be able to do this
but it's been put that we should discuss
this and so I'm raising it with you as I
mean as a point for future work so the
way that we're thinking about this is
that you know when we talk about
bandwidth utilization it can go in two
directions conveniently the mud model
thinks in both to the device and from
device already and sort of thinking
about extending it extending the two
device and from device containers such
that you could add some sort of
description about this and the idea also
is that you could use this for other
purposes like for instance provisioning
purposes so if you have a bunch of
devices that are say cameras it might
all be chattering at the same time at
say HD speeds you could have some notion
as to add up the amount of bandwidth
that you're that you might need in those
environments for provisioning purposes
over time now what did this is not
talking about is how to duplicate or how
to create QoS in the network that's
already been done not going to do it
again have the scarves next slide please
okay so I've covered a bit of this
already one of the questions that we
have right is if a device is sort of
pinging out there saying you know here's
here's how much I'm going to use right
over what period of time should we do
those sorts of measurements and by the
way it's not just packed it's not just
bandwidth but maybe packets per second
or something else
and so we're pondering what the right
measurements are for in order to
describe these profiles so it's this is
sort of again it's a bit research heat
to figure out exactly the right elements
to describe utilization but it's not
that researchy because we've done this
before you know their context whether it
you know it's a net flow where we've
looked at how net flow or how ITV III p6
has handled flow information we can
probably learn a lot from that all right
so next slide please
so the other problem that we're working
on which is sort of separate from
is more of an onboarding problem and
this I'm going to talk a little bit
about an emu later today in more depth
so this is sort of a little teaser for
if you don't normally attend EMU and why
would you because this is op sorry
working it's sort of a security thing
question is how do we we now gotten to
the point where we can describe a
profile of a device we even know how
devices can connect and be intreated
have a trusted introduction say between
them and a local deployment that's what
annum of ruski is doing but for Wi-Fi we
have a little we have two additional
problems problem number one is how does
a device choose the right network to
join in the first place and problem
number two is how do they authenticate
initially so we're gonna leave that how
do I choose the SID problem essentially
alone because that's probably closer to
an I Triple E or a Wi-Fi Alliance
question they're not so much an IETF
issue but I just wanted to note it for
completeness because we have to solve
the complete problem next slide please
ooh boy this is some of the slides
didn't come out quite right okay so the
the problem though with Wi-Fi in
particular with trusted introduction is
that you want to join the network even
if you know the network right um and so
the way that the anima brewski flow
works is you basically have some restful
calls and you do a little restful dance
with something called a registrar but
how do you do the rest will dance if you
don't if you know if you're not yet
authorized to use the network as is
required in a Wi-Fi environment okay
that's a chicken-and-egg problem that we
have to go sort so we're looking at
several different ways to sort that that
is to say we'd like to use this animal
flow and we want to also but we don't
have an IP address well that's sort of a
fish right in order to do that and
there's this whole thing called teep
which is relatively new which is new eat
method which seems roughly speaking to
be what we want but there's not a lot of
deployment there which makes us a little
nervous so there's a new draft that own
feel and I and Michael Richardson wrote
on this to go look at these different
models and we want to actually try and
take a swing at this
all right so next slide coming back to
mod we have some open issues as I
mentioned earlier the apps area people
had some be CP 190 issues that we wanted
to discuss and why would we care about
URL composition well right now if you
transmit a mod URL if you if a device
outputs a mud URL say in a certificate
that's the manufacturer asserting what
the device profile is but a device can't
change that URL say if it does a
software upgrade and so you might want
some of that posture information well
conveniently NEA has done a lot of work
on posture information so maybe we want
to communicate some of that back to the
manufacturer so say a device is running
version two of a particular piece of
software in version two has more
capabilities then perhaps what you'd
like to do is communicate that to the
manufacturer so it can provide a more
tailored might URL that's just one
example of how you might want to add
stuff into the URL say at the mud
controller level and we didn't touch
that initially in them in this document
but we're now thinking about it and
we're trying thinking about what's the
right way to go about to go forward one
way is to append stuff into the URL
another is for instance to create an
HTTP header and stick that stuff in
there and pass that to the mud file
server which is basically an HTTP server
we didn't really want to do the latter
early on and the reason is that we
thought the simpler the HD that the the
web server implementation the easier it
will be for manufacturers to implement
so this is one issue that we're thinking
about as well the next thing that's left
over is sort of a lifecycle issue next
slide please
and so suppose you've got a device that
you know you bought in say 2018 and then
you pulled out of the drawer in 2050 and
wanted it to work it just happens to be
an old light bulb now this may sound
crazy and I've chosen the the time
frames to be a little bit extreme but it
could be instead of 2050 you could say
well we pulled it out of the box in 2025
or something like that
you still want it to work and you think
that's crazy consider this example the
Formula One team McLaren all their
control functionality for their racing
car is on like Windows 95 and what they
did is they bought a stack of PCs so
they'd never have to upgrade the
software in the car
while they're running out of PCs now
well this is sort of the same problem
which is things do tend to there's a lot
of stuff that tends not to change and
companies do go away and with them go
their names so I was talking to Hank
about this at lunch and he said oh
you're just going to run your internet
simulator in 2050 you need to a query
for this information it's like yeah
that's a way to solve them this came up
apparently at the S Shack meeting it I
can violate because they're thinking
about long long lived names as well now
we you know people keep saying what
happens what are you doing these
circumstances and my first answer you
know my first order answer was you're
screwed the names gone and that's that
but we don't really want that to be the
real answer so we actually want to put a
little thought into name lifetimes and
mud URLs so these are the things that
we're thinking about working on I think
that's my last aside if memory serves
and hank himself is thinking about mud
URL composition and how do you how to
leverage that in her that that I that
classifier for other uses and he's going
so far as to say you know over time we
don't really want to use yang for these
things we want to use something else we
left open that possibility but exactly
how we do that has to tie into the
classifier itself and so as we get more
operational experience which is why we
brought this to the ops area working if
we want to get operational experience
with this stuff we're going to will
examine in challenge every last
assumption that we've made in what is
about to be a proposed standard and it's
only a proposed standard because we do
want to get a lot of operational
information as we go forward so that's
about where we are with mud comments
questions
oh good Alan's coming to the mic because
I was thinking about you Alan when we
started thinking about eep-eep
yes I spend a lot of time working on
teeth among other things at least on the
standards later almost no one implements
it I've heard rumors of implementations
but all the people who were very
enthusiastic about getting it done and
working on the standard yeah they got
the standard done but none of the
implementations similar things happen to
me I was involved in its my frustration
with a lot of us work it's good it can
solve problems and it sort of languished
after the standards phase I have heard
recently there's more interest in teeth
but I don't really have any thanks Alan
you know one of the the fundamental
issue we know we have a problem with you
know with with these things up there or
any particular device that doesn't have
a direct user interface and wants to use
Wi-Fi they have that they have to go
through some sort of dance to get
connected whether it's or whether it's
something else I personally think using
something like eat is a useful mechanism
because it's there in a tremendous
number of deployments already et isn't
we're not wedded at this point I'm not
wedded nor any of the co-authors who
wrote the draft I reference wedded to
any particular mechanism we are however
wedded to solving the problem and so
we're looking for collaborators on that
point and so if you haven't read that
route
please take a few moments and read Owen
fields draft on this Owen is around I
don't think I see him in the room oh
there he is okay and so any Olins got a
problem he can talk about it he does
collaboration devices at Cisco so he's
hitting this problem today needs a
solution today because it's stopping us
from selling stuff so there's money to
be made as it were okay any other
questions all right thank you for your
time Thanks
I do fix me to be Comanche did you want
to run the Sloane's hello everyone I'm
Jin Chun from t-mobile today I'd like to
reports current status of this draft is
both b2b community information in IP fix
this document passed the working group
last car a few weeks ago
many thanks to all comments and
suggestions from the adverse of readers
and the early real of the related to
working routes we have solved all
comments and suggestions in this murder
here are the second even a significant
comment the first one is about the
purpose of this document we all know
that ethics is the protocol used to
collect the traffic flow information
from the if Potter's running as routers
based on the
network practice to analyze the traffic
to do traffic engineering or to the
deployments quality of services we want
to know the traffic the network traffic
generated from our testing to some
canceled customers services or the
geographical regions based on the
network operators Bennion PTP communing
here attributes are used to represent
such country information so we can so we
know the information we want away you
weaken and analyze the traffic and the
network traffic in ETA community partner
leverage however at present that no PHP
committee information can be exported in
effects so we introduce introduces some
information elements in this document
she meets the gap the BTB community
information related to a specific flow
can be exported together with other
fluid nation in a prefix please written
new introductory part for the youth plan
for the detailed explanation and such
three for the use case we don't want to
[Music]
we do not define any new PGP community
attribute in this document the the
information element introduced in this
document I ought to - if thought the
already defined bgp communities such as
the standard
particularly the candy at community and
the large community and this document is
not used to replace the HP monitoring
Patoka either for the effects collectors
are not running BGP and BMP protocols by
supporting the information elements in
the Austrians a document they can
analyze the network traffic in each big
community when you are ready directly
because you know both Beach P and P NP
are very heavy running those can do
protocol and correlate him the traffic
flow information with HP information are
not trivial for the effects platters the
second comment is about the processing
of the youth Potter
we added some tests in this version when
the activated father receives the
activates temperature continue the
introduced information element
requesting to report the pacific melody
information that obtains the
corresponding beach be committee
information by correlating the traffic
flow information with the PDF measure
and then the order in cos h in the
relevant information elements and report
yet together with other free deformation
to the effect
crackers for the
that comment that is about the
processing of the collector and when the
collector is if that death died at our
hands that bgb community information
encoded in the introduced in for me
elements the appeared collector should
ignore the information elements when the
Assizes are not correct and then their
collector accumulates the traffic at the
BT community granularity and reports
results or or does the traffic
engineering based on present for the
next earth first comments are
appreciated is especially the comments
from the abrasion community and I hope
you all are happy with this version and
the working will may may consider to
move it forward to be palette published
that's all thank you burn what I so I
haven't read the document in the last
call because for me it was so obvious
that it was something to be done
specifically because we lightly fixed
structure information elements you could
have gone to a Liana and request it
directly it was better to document it on
how to use information elements okay
this is good
now when I just checked it now there is
one small mistake in there you say that
you update the RFC 1712 which is the
information list of information elements
like effects actually you don't you
don't need to update that RFC you just
using the ionic procedure in that RFC so
the updates in the header of that of
your draft doesn't need to have you want
to remove it you don't need update 7012
that make sense okay thank you are you
mad
okay thank you all thank you how many
people have read the latest bgp
community draft hands one two three four
okay thank you four people in the room
we would appreciate more eyes clearly to
spot some things like that thank you've
been warned for noticing
please read please review and comment on
the list and then was gonna say
something else one good question
I see the version which is not from
March 5th it is the one is the latest
one or are we expecting a new one it's a
latest version now or expecting a new
one all right the answer is that to get
it soon so I reviewed that one ok did
you wanna yes this is optional in the
next 10 or 15 minutes or so I will talk
about or initiate on building a
framework for network telemetry
telemetry has become a very popular
mainstream term in network community but
people may have a very different idea on
what LM tree is and how it's related to
ITF and how and how it's used in a tree
network to help that were operation so
the Greek rules of this world telemetry
simply means remote merriment so in this
sense we believe telemetry is actually
about Network visibility so any
technology that help network took in had
better visibility by collecting data
from network and do an analysis and a
moment uh nate is actually qualified as
a telemetry so in this sense all the OEM
our techniques arm or motor coast
published in the ITF is actually can be
considered telemetry but as a network is
evolving and we also see the new network
requires a lot of provide a lot of new
requirements to telemetry and also ask
new telemetry to bear some new
characteristics ok as we see the network
is continually evolving pasta Sdn and
now is toward a more automatic intent
driven network so such Network has aimed
to reduce human labor and improve
Network agility and the performance also
help to optimize and other networks
resource utilization so you can see in
this a network architecture natural
reason visibility become more and more
important
after all if uh you know you don't know
what's happening in network in real time
no effective network control and the
operations can be applied but now I
think people just don't put enough
attention to this technology and you
know we believe that the telemetry
should be promoted as a first class
citizen in the network technology and
the protocols also if we look at current
status of such technologies we see it's
pretty much a frakkin mint
fragmented um we believe we need to
unify and consolidate and integrate the
existing solutions and also guides the
future work in a unified framework to
help such technology three more
currently on so we believe the existing
OAM solutions are efficient and also
insufficient to sustain the future
intent driven network architecture
because technology such as SNMP still
used in network but it's a place down
the low frequent polling technology and
also the use in the command line
interface but now we need the technology
can directly talk to machine our rather
than human and also the old om
technologies our lack of coverage and
the timeliness and accuracy also this om
mechanics are scattered throughout ITF
our working groups and our lipid are
organized and there are many piecemeal
or tico solutions it's a very hard for
users to compose them into a complete
cohesive solution and also since people
don't work under the same framework
there are occasionally repetitive and
redundant work is happening and this
also lack offer collaboration and the
consolidation between them and in many
times you know om is not considered you
know it's just considered a afterthought
patches to the existing solution also
it's a work on a case by case cases and
there's a lack of a holistic and
systemic view therefore we believe a
framework is actually needed to
normalize concepts terms and technology
standard to help that technology and
standard development with the IETF so
what's needed in new telemetry since the
telemetry will be data where we consumed
by machine are more than by human
it means the data quantity is large and
it happens in real time the the network
need to continuous monitor the network
in a more dynamic and interactive way
for example the application need to keep
refining was to look at and also are to
refocus is monitor point and also the
data will be collected from many
different sources
I see in different locations in the same
network nodes also throughout the
network and the data from multiple
sources DDP need to be correlated and
there are already different techniques
like sub passive and active measurement
to the network but we believe we also
need to support the environment to gain
the first hand experience offer that for
flows and also we still can't to look at
all the data all the time and that's why
we cannot collect all the raw data we
need to customize what data to collect
which means we need to rely on to rely
on the network to pre-process some of
data as guided by the application and
another important thing to think about
is that the telemetry should note
interfere with device may function which
is a folding packet fast so for example
you can note by a monitoring network you
reduce for any performance that's
acceptable there are many applications
existing use cases the first is about
intent
you know verification or enforcement the
intend energy may apply different
policies or have different service layer
layer agreements with users and services
but the telemetry is used to
ensures that actually meets the
requirement also the network filius
happens all the time
so the network needs to use a telemetry
technology to find the root cause of the
failure quickly and you know it even
batteries need to based on some existing
symptom to find the map of to predict
the failure and so the network can be
fixed in the once another big group or
application is about to optimize a
network by monitoring the network status
so the some intelligent auguries can be
applied to why the congestion and to
utilize network bandwidth more
efficiently
the last very important application is
of course the network security for
example the intrusion detection and
prevention and also some other malicious
attacks can be attacked and identified
through the telemetry technology so all
these applications require some new
characteristics the first noticeable
wines are the push based technology will
replace the poor based technology such
as was used in SA mg and the since the
data quantity is a huge it requires very
efficient data encoding and also the
date need to be sent through the
collector in a streaming fashion for the
for better machine consumption of the
data other model is needed and also all
as I said so the data crashing need to
support also the in band data and since
a data plane or device and becoming more
programmable now is feasible to support
the customer and on demand data which
means the the controller can define or
specify what data need to be collected
and using some programming or
configuration waste to
would to download that data request to
the tip lane and just gets the exactly
what data they want so this is a new
characteristics and last the telemetry
must support to be better integrated
with the big data analytics or other
machine learning tools that are very
important therefore we can see based on
there's different planes in the network
clearly there is better to a partition
that lamp entry also in into three
different planes namely is a data plane
telemetry now manager management plane
telemetry and control plane telemetry
right but between this different planes
you know they're also some interactions
between them for example the many
playing telemetry can also collect data
from the control plane and the date of
name and in each plane we can further
partitions our telemetry into five
unique components the first one is the
data source
it tells ok where data should be is
available is accessible and the second
component components is a data
subscription it cares about tell the
application you know how you can
subscribe what protocol or what's
interface you use to subscribe data and
the third component is the data
generation it's about how the data
because the application may ask some
custom data or the data if we pre
process in data plane or encoded or
filtered all these affections I belong
to the data generation and the
preparation and another components
important components is a data export
which cares about how you deliver the
data to the application who consume
consume the data and the last the top
components is a data analysis which is a
actual applications who are consume the
data extracted from the
network device so pace on this a
partition we come up with this
two-dimensional matrix and we already
map many different technologies in this
figure most of them are from IETF
existing work there are either already
standards or some recent proposals but
only under the data analytics part you
can see most of them I still open-source
project or some open source tools but
later that might be also some standard
requirement in that in that area I don't
have time to go through all this each
piece of technology if you are
interested you can read our draft to see
how and why this fits fit into this
picture
so from this picture we can see there
are already a lot of existing works but
they are might come from very different
working groups a different area we seem
to be the better if we can map them
clearly it can also guide us in the
future how we are max maps the new work
into this picture and for the system
designer and it also can help them to to
figure out what's a best suite of
technologies you can collect to form a
complete solution from this figure so
therefore I think is a very useful so
finally just a recap or an intention for
this draft we want to promote the you
know the significance of telemetry work
in IETF
we want to remind us to keeps a big
picture in mind because we believe the
intent driven an intelligent network is
coming and we need to better prepare for
that it's better to avoid you know the
separate standalone piecemeal solutions
rather we should consolidate all the
telemetry work and provide the unified
interface to
Action Network architecture and we also
want to ensure that to make ietf still
the leading standard organization in
this area and in this document we want
to formalize other telemetry related
terms and the clarify the technology
clarifications in ATF which can
consolidate the existing work and also
help us to get the future work of course
this is just a very early step we call
for more helps and collaborations from
other operators and the vendors to
finish this work so that's all so any
questions or comments comments from the
room get the feeling that you are trying
to boil not one ocean but multiple of
them at the same time the scope of this
work is not that it is huge it's it's
more than huge but at the same time you
see that majority of the components and
the other work areas is already being
covered and that was a idea and to me
what you're describing is much more of
network designer actually product design
question than a protocol engineering
what is typically done an idea and the
goal to have a one universe absolutely
universal interface that covers
absolutely everything that's directly
contradicted to how the net from
operational point of view works there's
a differentiation between different
operators for a reason because they are
trying to build the different products
different interconnection products when
activity products therefore trying to
build one really nice all-encompassing
this might be a nice academic exercise
and I don't mean anything negative by
the word academic but is it really
practical
we are clearly talking about multiple
years of heavy work in all of this if we
if we want to convert these the surface
of what is described ENS Co but is is
the result
it's an end result going to be worth
that so what for example what is
fundamentally wrong with the current om
and yes ATF spends a lot of time working
with different om aspects in different
protocols different working groups
those things are deployed they work and
there are not that many complaints about
specific components you know a.m. so is
this is this really such a big problem
that it requires a completely
engineering of the whole of anatomy of
the whole of Internet the my impression
is that the scope here is let's range
near the internet began because because
it's broken
yeah I agree is is very hard but in the
past you know for every piece of new
protocols or technologies people come
out commands in their own way to do
their Oh a.m. and they solve their
particular problem but here I'm talking
about if in the future we have this
intelligent network automatic network
you know he keeps a human adopts a
control loop then you need to present
it's really I think it's a required to
present a unique uniform interface to
the intent engine are you it's better to
avoid a lot of different incompatible
interface protocols to talk to the
controller so that I think the
motivation for from this a big picture
and we released
in the matrix are several technologies
and we can see actually the key
components here is a you know what's
needed to communicate with intend
engines actually just a data
subscription and the data export you
know I think there's a good chance we
can come up with one unified solution
everybody will grieve is and then we can
support such kind of a network
architecture so also I don't think
universal control to control that
attention that's an ambitious goal I
mean I'm not saying that at this wrong
goal but it's it's ambitious yep I'm
channeling large from Guerra and she
says about your components of telemetry
slide specifically some functions seem
not to be addressed like data transport
/ distribution data storage and the
respective optimizations if you go to
your slide called components of
telemetry yeah yeah the comment is is
that some functions seem not to be
addressed data transport / distribution
and their respective optimizations Oh
India storage so data transport /
distraction marvelous storage data
transport and did a story or storage yes
and their respective optimization and
respective optimization optimization
optimization awful
a data export and for the storage is
actually in the data analytics you
you're you have two ways either you
directly consume the data in the stream
fashion or the data should be first put
into some kind of database for later
analysis so in my understanding that
should be also covered in the data
analysis components and last one about
the optimization I think you know
optimization campaign happen everywhere
particularly in the data generation okay
that's I intend to do some data
preparation as there's a lot of
optimization happen there it's like the
data t-tube a filtering and compression
encoding and also the August
optimization algorithms can also happen
in the data analysis components so yeah
III think all of this should be covered
by this on maybe we can have a better
description of each components but I
think you know every key components
happening in a telemetry system is
already covered here yeah I just want to
say a couple things one I want to
reiterate the fact that you boiled a big
it's probably too big to boil what
you're trying to do question about the
transformation in those elements yeah
that can be part of the data and that
analysis components but it's a big
component right you got enrichment and
everything else that you have to go
through there and so to just say I'm
gonna have a miracle cure occurred here
called data analysis I think would
probably do a disservice to the industry
I did see that as you were going through
here that you said let's keep our eye on
the intent framework and it looks to me
as we went through this that you lost
you lost your you took your eye off the
intent framework so if you take into 10
right and you realize all these sources
that goes to the one protocol piece
you're going to realize real quick that
the tank gets realized in many many
different ways right and that many many
different ways are gone
have different sources of data that's
going to come up to you and they're
going to come up to you different ways
so there's not going to be one protocol
that you're going to be able to capture
these elements so there you have to
expect that you're going to realize that
intent in multiple different
environments you've got the three
different control for this air that you
know are there they are the largest
pieces of it and in those elements
themselves will be going down and being
collected through different protocols
and different mechanisms that's just
going to be a fact of life the question
is how you correlate that back into an
intent I think now that probably has
some value right and trying to figure
out how you would correlate the sources
themselves into an intent framework
right but to to say that you want a
single protocol going into an intent
control engine night I think I don't
think that that's going to be a reality
probably before I die so so so in my I
might be too ambitious to try to unify
all the technologies but here the main
intention I believe is try to you know
organize the existing work to have a
career understanding how what's the
scope of this problem and how we can
partition the technology how we can map
say existing technology into this map if
we all agree with that then later even
we develop new technologies we know
where is fate and how is fit into this
at this picture so if you take every one
of those some of those I just protocols
framework you know let's say you take a
framework let's say or something like
that right you realize that those
frameworks when they give realize they
they are built with the realization that
there's going to be sources that are
going to come from the spirit place
that's right and so there's not any
framework that going to say I'm gonna
have a single protocol and it's going to
be the only thing I'm going to support
you're always going to have something
that's it's going to be able to collect
for multiple sources and in that piece
of it you're gonna do the appropriate
transformation enrichment that's
necessary to meet your intent your tank
Frank right and so yeah I think that I
don't think you ever going to get to the
point where you only have one you only
have the ietf ones here I can go to you
know maybe number of other organizations
and they're probably got their other
horrified that they're doing to collect
stuff so I just don't think it's
probably something that that that that's
ever going to happen in a lifetime and I
think you have to look at how you would
then be able to set up an appropriate
framework that would be able to map and
transform the data that you get from the
various realization sources into into
the intent and then I think you have a
chance you try to do something like that
but I wouldn't try to do it as a single
protocol yes sir I'll be in front of AVI
I want to add some comments about the on
the presentation
so first the draft is not to try to boil
the ocean as I see the first comments
since the but I think that that the
intention has appeal explain this a
response for Howie I think our progress
the first ayah 21 to sink the you
Christine om work you IKEA easily enough
because every time we introduce some the
new mechanism at the same time you too
will also introduce some shortcomings I
think this is the fact user accurate
deployment so we're seeing that user you
hear that we mainly data related we
assemblies the some elementary work
related with the data plane some the new
om you can mechanism reintroduced and we
also wanted to item if I have water
should be cope with so this is our the
first a purpose second why you that that
user this relationship element we in the
user is a new error is related with the
filter data will be collected a fear
from the network and the YouTube will
support in
enemies the network or network
immigrants so that user was is mr. I
know what we should be done so we will
set up a clear you walk to that attend
our work in the to be done in the IETF
so I think her that is our major purpose
but I agree this work will relate it
with the many many work in the in the
IETF so that's the you know why we
present this o-p-s WT and our kitty WT
laid her in routing area so that we
anyway this is that point we the open to
the other possible comments and would
like welcome your suggestion
mic off no no so but I did read the
draft and speaking on the chair I think
you've heard a lot of the comments that
the scoping everything you show here is
in flight it's already out there I I
think maybe the the suggestion is to
listen to the comments that you've heard
here and please do read if you haven't
read this strap read it comment on it
and and you might have to refine some of
the scoping and clarify what you're
after because you say make telemetry a
first-class citizen I think people are
waking up to the fact that it's needed
but then you also say correlate or
aggregate or I can't remember the exact
word you used I don't think every people
here in ops OGG in general have the
visibility across everything to do that
and I don't think we should be that the
one true gatekeeper of of of telemetry
so focus on the intent and maybe there
is a way to refine or sharpen what
you're trying to do with this draft so
that it does fit a gap that you perceive
or that's more actually that's real with
what else is already going on and work
that's already in flight in in ops and
in other areas thank you thank you
next up is Kasim your weapon
hello everyone my name is shir come form
of Italian Telecom it's my pleasure to
give a presentation about
Kasim cadre to the address space
management as we all know that address
space management is integral part of any
network management solutions the network
may be based on some Lexy ones or some
new kind of networks such as such as
cloud-based network so here I want to
give some two cases the first one is
about operator network
Natsuki operating the work so operator
need to manage the address space magic
addressing needs of network elements
which is right now mini goes to some tea
tree solutions and configures a manually
for some matter skill network which is
labor-intensive and time-consuming the
second use case is for and prior users
some and prior user may use tools such
as FM to manage the address with sausage
often used often with some proprietary
database in the universe so there really
need to develop a general architecture
for the address based measurement too
many use cases to you know either
whether a killer use cases so the Scopes
is draft in this traffic chasm is the
general and synchronized architecture
for automatic address based management
it is intended to be used a wide array
of use cases
hopefully it can help to reduce the
workload of manual combination which is
very popular in currently Network and
also we hope to improve address resource
usage improve the efficiency in the
future so this draft can also be a basic
document for us works such as scene of
his modeling and workflow design the use
cases of use cases of chasm which make
our automatic address allocation and
release every applications work based on
the actual usage and at the import from
input from user intent in some for some
service so all the indicators we know
has been discussed in the ITF laminates
in each cargo such as address
configuration for PNG the virtual has
been G's transition activity trusted
devices dressed configuration or at hand
i PRI FM esteem controllers and
interface to a PKI so since it has been
discussed the ATM 98 so I will not give
the detail them again this figure shows
the architecture of the chasm it is
composed three Lea's application here
and the continental layer and as a
device layer the application is a
function entity which maintains operates
the custom coordinators issuing commands
issues a policy or requirement to the
coordinator so the typical example of
education is some such as OSS SPSS and
esteem controllers and all any other
party applications so with this
application operator can operate all in
cry users can access the address usage
information
marks etc for the the coordinator is
synchronized functioning and each in
which many used to maintain overall
address resources and processing
request from Lord Leo devices you can
post the three components such as
address poor management address
management and address database so the
subtle ear is a device layer the device
agent in a device will we are processing
we are distributes address from which is
received from the coordinator
configuring the device the the type of
ative that have a device may be various
or may be virtual of physical it may be
servers or or in the points such as PNG
virtual entities and the affair was and
some other devices in the swamp so when
device needs IP address poet it will
issue a request to the coordinator the
convert the condo later will compute and
educate specific address block to this
device so when we address block is not
used anymore it will be released at the
retainer to this 2000 kilometer as well
as who so to improve address usage here
will give some general features of chasm
it is it is designed to be a single
solution for y the Raju user cases such
as a network device and a secure device
server in the new points of this call
virtual of cost this solution should
have meat food me to the address should
be to miss the wide variety of address
tab such as private public IP address
ipv6 address and not cause of your IP
address the second is synchronized a
dynamic combination model so here the
coordinator can mix the TCD IP address
based on the available IP address
resources and as a user you put the
importer from from the devices
another that's one is that
it is open until you'd be in each
greater ways as a management service
such as legacy it radius and DHCP server
and some new ones such as OpenStack and
SD in networks
another important features of chasm is
that it used that interface modeling so
standing interface will be defined
between the chasm applications and as a
coordinator so the technical Hayden you
know no network will be technical detail
will be hidden to the operator users
interface morning will be a future work
based on the progress of this document
so here we only give some general
requirements for the interface such as
functional requirements general optional
requirements and the interface modern
requirements actually we have
implemented as a field of trails of
synchronized address management for most
of my year on following the chasm model
we dealer develop a synchronized address
management system and the deploy eight
in our product network for vendors John
is for the trail and the the equipment
include a virtualized PNG and physical
being jeez
so we system we can manage it we can
coordinate and manage the address
centrally dynamically so about the next
step and the current document will be
further refined based on the comments
and we are also considered to Tozer
due to the interface deflation in other
new drafts any confusions are welcome
and I hope that you guys can join us
work if you have interest to this and
also and also don't to know whether it
can be adopted as a working item I've
got before we open it up for comments
you had a ball
while back under the ietf meeting number
98 ACOG okay and I looked at the mailing
list recently and and kind of
conversation died off there so I'm
curious what what's bringing the work
forward now what has changed since the
Boff what have you learned out of that
that directly influences this work
actually we have a draft update based on
the comments you know in a both in
evolves and we serve a document has been
voted into wine for this package draft
so you think so you think there's no
open issues left no major issues okay so
John Florrick is a contributor I've read
the draft it does look like two drafts
that have been fused together UNIX
terminology you reference drafts that
have been expired it was really
confusing to read I'll be honest with
you because you mentioned chasm in the
second part of the draft but in the
first part of the draft you have
different either acronyms or you refer
to the same text in different ways so it
was a little bit confusing to read I
don't disagree with you that the problem
space is interesting and should be
solved but I think more refinement is
needed yes I'm to really hone in on what
you're trying to propose and then
emphasize on what you want to
standardize okay okay I would like to
know the interest er from the working
group first story how many of you have
read these documents please raise your
hand four or five oh six okay and then
how many of you have interest about this
document please raise your head let's
discuss more in a medalist so one
comment on this topic while ago at Nanak
I had a discussion with Enterprise
operators and while the topic was
different but it naturally came about
address management and when I told that
at some point of time in 90f there was a
document trying to address that there
was a big interest from that group I
approached them again asking for a
review of your document you probably
haven't received that because I haven't
seen anything but one suggestion on open
network users group is an entity which
covers many of a special enterprise
users and enterprise users in the domain
of containers virtualization and then
similar type of things they do have
certain problems with identifier
management not only address management
but identifier management in general not
only IP addresses but that might be VLAN
numbers might might be a MAC addresses
might be other things it might be good
to extend the solution to cover these
type of use cases and in fact that might
then start addressing a much broader
problem space than you are just looking
right now into that thank you so please
read and then comment on the list thank
you I think last step we have virtual
virtualization overview sorry the yang
model for virtualization yes and and can
I just say we're running
I apologize running a bit short on time
so anything you could give back timewise
would be great we have five minutes left
so okay
hello good afternoon everyone my name is
Hugh the top guy I want to introduce
it's about a new virtual edition overlay
resource model this is actually R is
also facing model so why we propose each
other actually as we know actually ITL
proposed up quite a lot of young beta
moto mozo actually device level model we
also have a few service level model and
male make a CUDA progress recently get
published and based on eros we SM piece
actually is obviously 82 949 actually by
mapping the service model into the
device level model we can actually
provide a service delivery fulfill that
service creation but what it missing
part is we think actually we cannot do
actually provide quite like a service
monitoring several insurance and when
you get a networker set up and the
server is created how do you monitor the
surveys how do you expose the network
performance of the network to the
management system so this is a gap we
want to face we want to feel so we so it
proposes
results and facing model and this
resource in Phase II model is translated
from the customer facing model and as
they were walking together with service
model to provide a not only service
creation but also
is pro-beijing as service monitoring
assurance and also we can use these
service monitoring information to choose
a network optimization so why so why the
service model and network enemy model is
not in love actually we we can say
service model is a service a perception
is a kind of top-down
a it's kind of a top-down model so so
Cosmo only interesting is the service so
they can program the service into layer
one layer two layers to a level four
seven security service and they can do
the mix match and but the customer don't
care about how you realize these surveys
how how what kind of resource you can
use that you realize these service so we
have no enemy model they actually
focused on the resource abstraction so
we can have what happen model is
actually try to abstract the fundamental
negative technology for example layer
one layer two there's three technology
and typical wines like topology model
and PGP model and some other model and
so so so what do we try to do actually
we can map of service level model into
the network element model and actually
they will use food on board service mode
as input and and and into the automated
control confirmation application they
can generate the many congregation
parameter they can go to different
narrow animal model and welcome citizen
together using some like a scream among
or some other mechanism to assemble all
of these model together and we can
populate it this model into appropriate
and then what device but that's is that
or is that enough actually I think what
is the missing part is how do you expose
some subset apology to the operator
itself is some in some cases you need to
really want to know how where or how bad
the Nano is operator so you need to
report it and then with performance or
the network data to to the to the
operator or to the management system
they can manipulate these kind of
networks data to choose a network
reorganization so you can actually form
these close to over live life cycle the
service and management so there's basic
idea so we're seeing that we have to
approach those crunches you can extend
like a surface model airway SM model but
we this has already been discussed in
our choice and what can go but we sink
early to add a lot of complexity since
you introduced a quite a lot of Stata so
the second way actually you can you can
actually create another model separate a
model we call the resource efficient
model this resource in facing model is
translated and instantiated from the
service model because the service model
will tell you how many sided you want to
create what what is the location of this
site and what kind of connectivity you
want to create in which is which side
and some SLA requirements associated
with connected service so you you can
actually based on these locations in
which information and unconcern anything
and you can select appropriate like PE
or we call this enquiries device or
egress device and and you can create the
service topology based it's a surface
topology
what do you need to do is actually
choose a service bounding
so we gave the idea what do we try to do
is foster you can establish this
topology so because you have allocated P
II device information and maybe say T
information you can replace the location
information in in the service model with
these just selected a P information so
you can create a surface topology and
pieces of service topology you really
want to know for W have several side
they located in different but
freaky location so you need to establish
that you said about setup of the path
between this site so you need to pay
some choose requirements so so we you
should establish their service bounding
to bound as a service follow ways to the
past
well after you do that you set up the
paths or set up a tunnel you can
actually monitor performance over the
tunnel
maybe the town rapture is a Marty Hawk
so you need to maybe monitoring each hub
the provenance and you can put them
together you can aggregate all the all
of these calculated the entering a
tunnel performance and the pistes tunnel
performance so you can actually to try
to do some reorganization so you can
actually provided a closed-loop service
management so here they show the like
service topology creating and yet we
already discussed this and so we can see
the resource model actually it's just
translated from the service model or
instantiated from service model the
difference is actually we need to pick
the the selected @p to replace the the
location information in the service
model so the found in between the
service and past Sony uu because in
resource facing model you actually you
already you you actually you can keep
the same cues parameter aspect there
from the service model and you can face
this future apartment that you calculate
the paths for each II follow and you can
find it finer the service follow ways
the pass and and then you can actually
actually monitoring that the past
performance on ton of a performance and
and you can report this to the
management system and and you can enable
to the record optimization
so we for the performance family that we
can have like a facade and metal
performance parameter also we have some
proponents and I meter associated ways
multiple sided we call this end-to-end
publicity parameter so when you use all
of these prophets parameter as the
network performance criteria to to
calculate that the path basis the
performance parameters so that's my idea
thank you um we're over time but please
how many people read this quite a few
actually
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten
please comment on the list where the
blue sheets floating around
excellent so thank you very much for
attending ops aughh will comment on the
list on this last draft on all of them
and we will see you next time
Warren wants to say something and I want
to apologize the presenters if I'd known
we're using my laptop cutterhead stuff
more moral and ice but we had maybe one
more for Benoit yeah
[Applause]
you