okay let's get started this is quick if
you're not here for the quick working
group please leave although you may be
missing some fun this is the note well
this is the new note well if you're not
familiar with this the best thing to do
is to use your favorite web search
engine while you if you can read that
that's great or you can use your
favorite web search engine to search for
ietf note well it's about these terms
under which we participate regarding
things like intellectual property and
anti-harassment procedures and lots of
other stuff that we do take seriously so
please make sure that you are familiar
with this the agenda was Monday now we
have Thursday the blue sheets are going
around please sign them when they come
to you
we have a scribe thank you very much
Tommy we are now about bashing the
agenda so we're gonna have a fairly
brief discussion of ecn a presentation
of discussion that we hunted from Monday
before that actually in the slide and
one other thing we want to double check
that make sure that we're good with the
invariance we started the workgroup last
call if we have anything to discuss now
is a good opportunity to do that
and then the main event we're going to
discuss the spended proposal and we're
sorting up a presentation about it and
we're going to conclude those questions
I really hope so yes we're never
presentation and then clarifying
questions and then we're going to move
to a discussion phase on it and at the
end we'll try and use moms if we have
time after that we'll have some issue
discussion any agenda bashing Martin are
you in at the bashing line you're in
this okay so let's get started
Martin invariants discussion what do you
have so mom told me the issue of
extensibility for the version
negotiation frame has come up oh yeah
conclusion to that before we get another
good one please proceed so do we want
one yes
this new back up a bit the payload of
the boat of negotiation in packet is
currently a list of version negotiation
versions back to back to back build the
entire packet there's no length on that
there's no way for us to add anything
else to that packet that was semi
intentional but I don't think we ever
wrote down the fact that it was
intentional
and I don't think we ever really we
discussed bad so the question is do we
just stick a length on there and say
that the rest of the the packet is TBD
Joey acknowledge the fact that it's not
extensible and move on Mikal suggested
that you might want to sign these things
which i think is not particularly valid
use case but we have to there may be
other things that people have and might
want to do with this thing so Rizzo
would just be be like TLS 100 with
here's a length and there's some crap at
the end and we're not gonna say there it
is if it extends past the length okay
that would be the idea yeah so but I
guess I mean generally um
just there's some interaction here with
whether or not we're going to modify the
way the first negotiation works to be
more like the to be to have the VPN be
mostly obfuscation version how they
interior version negotiation if we did
that that it really doesn't matter with
that we do this fail it does because
only really negotiates one thing if
we're not going to death and things of
our tractor to have a tangibility so I
don't know like unfortunately I felt
like these issues are intertwined which
um er that pretty soon but like we
stopped the decides want to take it so I
don't know I'm pretty reluctant about
how to link them which like it was like
wah at the end that didn't work out well
in in one out yeah so so to sort of roll
back a little bit more the the purpose
of the version negotiation is to allow
both client and server to agree on
two things and we sort of pile a bunch
of other things on top of it at the
moment but fundamentally it's really
only two things and the first thing is
the the way in which you obviously the
handshake packets and the second one is
the the handshake protocol that you're
actually engaging it and that's actually
it we pile a bunch of other things on
top of it and workers body yes we could
do we could layer another layer of
version negotiation on once we get to
beyond that point but um those are the
two things that were protecting and if
those are the only two things we're
protecting I think we're actually okay
with what we have and if we can do a log
once we actually get into version
specific stuff and so I'm comfortable
with the current design but I would like
to make sure that other people are also
comfortable with the current design Jake
do you wanna um I'm not sure that this
is
either you haven't had enough time to
think about this at each ourselves sure
and comes around conclusions and given
that this was raised yesterday and given
that even people have thought about this
quite a bit still stretching that
scratching their heads and thinking
about it sure I would suggest that what
we do is simply talk about it for a
little bit and make it just another last
comment and you'll see what we turn up
in the next two to three weeks so I
wasn't suggesting we we humph to decide
it now are suggesting that we're in a
room together now we're gonna be on a
mailing list next week we're gonna
discuss con the mailing list the
question is is it useful to get some
sort of sense of this room right now
maybe see what request that queue is is
budding into my purchase in bit time so
I'm going to close it right now let's go
yeah I think I have the feeling they're
adding the lengths people would actually
get us a little more to safe site just
to be future proof but on the other hand
we also have eventually UDP options so
it's kind of stuck with anyway it might
end up with so don't have hard feelings
about it
um Martin can you remind me do we commit
to whether there was or was not a length
along had
did we commit that as an invariant but
no I understand but is that just in the
this is all who knows what this is it
that's in the undefined region right
right so if we needed to we could deal
with this by putting up but by having a
like a parent life field right um
without breaking the variance I guess
that's true I mean so this is what
happens when you try to fly a car did
you find the box before to find anything
in the box but I mean you know so I it
so we're never a light resist this but
you know then if you imagine that like
this protocol assign five years ago and
we might find ourselves in this position
like you know we'd be like okay the
versions did be you know ffff and you
know zero zero zero zero put together me
like lately and means that at the end I
mean like we do that like this a fault
we do have this all like desperate so
you know I hate to go there like this
early the design phase you know but I
mean I mean we couldn't figure it out
that's very similar to the point I was
gonna make the quick and dirty here is
as long as the it's a list of versions
the interpretation of whatever comes
after the version link and sorry comes
after the versions is going to be either
completely uninterpretable or just very
very crusty very very fast
I don't it's worth doing in the version
negotiation packet at all I'm Jenna and
I'm gonna go for Dekker and that just
said I we have a lot of extensibility in
various other parts of the protocol and
I think this is if we really really need
to do this at some point in the future
there are ways in which we can do this I
don't think you need anymore
okay so we have a sense at least from
the people who came to the mic that we
don't need this it sounds like and maybe
people on the mic put this into the
their feedback into the issue the ticket
so the header three
of discussion continuing there it'll be
nice if that we reflected in in text yes
okay okay thank you thank you mark
okay any other discussion of invariance
okay
okay next up we have ECN plural that's
not the intent here so we had had the
Melbourne interim the people in the room
at least had consensus that we wanted to
add so there was a different extends to
which ecn could be added to quicken I
think in Melbourne the consensus was
that we want to add the full flavor is
the end support in Creek v1 and an
Ingemar was tasked to sort of do a
write-up of a PR and and I think this is
sort of an overview of what that PR
might look like um before it sort of
formally hits hits kit before maybe it's
already and I've missed it
let that's the purpose of the discussion
so first we wanna sort of reconfirm that
I guess that this consensus from Miller
and still stands um nobody it sort of
objected on the list at least that I
know of so my current stance on is that
that we still believe that's the case
and then you know we want to keep back
on whether this you know way of doing
easier new quick is the one that should
be going into the documents in the near
future
yeah okay I know it will be probably a
pretty short one I can take the next
slide and we sorry I do it like this and
study we have some proposed additions
with a quick transport or recovery drost
and you can find it on the links here
and they're sort of written in almost
sort of a shape that should be possible
to include them as is with reviews of
course and there are action this was
presented in the last interim in
malleable and
and there was some the main discussion
was about on connection migration and
that thanks to : and Gauri and we try to
clarified those parts and makes that
more clear how that should be the sort
of work with is Jana and then there was
an email discussion around the feedback
for not in the occasion frame and I
believe you have rough consensus that it
should be that proposed protocol for hot
that only counts packets is good enough
and it should work with both the classic
Andy and Alvarez based easy on and know
if you're in the comments media yeah
okay and that's about it and we can take
the next slide and the way forward here
is that alder nearly any open issues and
another one is to with the blessing on
this group and create pull requests we
proposed additions to the transporter
recovery drops remind me is there not
any indication in the handshake that I
mean like you that you can actually send
feedback or not that's the part that's
interesting I mean if you receive a idea
is that if you receive easy an easy easy
team or package easy t0 is it you wanna
see you then you should use that lee
seong frame to feedback such information
that you do some probing at the
beginning of the connection yeah instead
of just telling you what you already
know and just like if you're the
receiver and you know you cannot access
the bits you could just tell the other
right yeah I believe that ideas that
theory if you don't tell support for
instance and you're stuck to being able
to really read and write these en bit
and you don't send
then you don't set that set those are
the easy easy team flyers
is it a bit satellite the header the
other sender needs no yeah I know but if
we receive doesn't access it then it
doesn't then feedback normal like frame
yes dad I but I don't understand why you
didn't just provide the information why
do you have to test it because that's
something you actually know why do you
don't know because if you know anything
that could be a discussion table where I
believe in and we wanted to make it as
simple as possible with alternative
flags on what's a barber dr. stone I
know where there's another very early
abortion already stopped over had this
extra for a negotiation stuff I'll have
to indicate the capabilities what I mean
testing is definitely more complex than
just telling the other I know I
understand that you have to test anyway
because the path might be not supportive
but it can still give you an advantage
that if you already know that you can
use it anyway you don't have to do the
testing right nervously but I mean it's
new you're not testing it it's actually
just trying to do it if you don't get
any response back useful use case or
stop marking the practices other side
and that's what procedure directors yeah
but there's a wiki page in the base
drafts repository that has the details
of the proposed PR it's not a PR at the
moment so I guess the ask is that people
review that I think in terms of the
design team that we had to look at GNN
quick this is sort of their proposal for
what what what they believe was it's the
best way forward and now we're basically
trying to figure out whether this is
this proposal has you know enough
consensus that we can continue it in the
PR make sense yeah okay um and I think
it probably so how close are we to
landing in Levin do it so do we have a
timeline for landing eleven Martin is
sort of looking like any day would work
huh okay so just when do we want to see
a PR to be wanna see this in in the
eleven because it feels like I mean you
need to give to some time do we want to
do this in 12 12 so even saying eleven
already has a bunch of long hair changes
and other things and there's also ten
that we haven't implemented yet so okay
a quick segue so I think for since we're
on the topic so I think we're gonna do
11 pretty soon 11 and the now final
version of TLS 1 3 will be the basis for
v implementation correct and we're going
to probably do fifth implementation on
line 4 as an inland interrupt a between
now and Stockholm and I'm guessing in
Stockholm we're still going to 50
limitation draft okay yeah I don't
expect to have any time after spending
it now okay so basically um this will
probably do not land before or it isn't
we know expectation of the
implemented before June okay that gives
us some time to review this agar so
large I don't know the other vulnera
sanentur one three are but we're not
planning to ship with the RFC version
number to the RFC issues so it would be
28 it wouldn't be RSA yes I misspoke but
so this 28 will probably between they
have editorial changes on them we can't
we the same send with a version number
is 8 we're just not playing the ship in
Firefox to like we'd RC issues like we
can't take it back yeah fair point on
this book so we're gonna do 11 and 28
until 28 becomes an RC vehicle even and
I just wanted to make one more comments
as a testing part is actually not great
Civic it's actually something that could
also be applied by other protocols so
I'm wondering if if you want to have it
in a document or if you want to have it
somewhere else so if you may want to
have something very simple like simple
default testing in the pic document and
then we could think about more trends
testing something else as well maybe one
comment for me I believe could be good
to have something in a quick documents
on because in probably you know many
people doesn't read the all new document
you know in other areas on yeah yeah I
would suppose an individual suggest that
we try and have something self-contained
in the quick document so that the
quicken homeowner can read that and
implement and not need to read histories
of ECM that we've had in the past one
yeah so mom Thompson I'd I'd suggest
telling lies spend a little bit more
time polishing this I noticed a few
grammatical things in here and a few
questions
it's a little bit easier to iterate all
the wiki than it is to you know write on
a pull request and for something this
large pull request is tends to take a
little bit of time and
in raw if you machical requests where is
this one wrong so get it do it and once
we get eleven out if you shouldn't be
that much longer I don't know how long
we're gonna see no we have a couple of
issues to talk about today maybe we will
try to run some of those into eleven but
I anticipate and if we're not planning
on implementing anything like this for
Stockholm we can actually take
significant track of time in Stockholm
if we still need it and finish it and
then get it not be our form something
the only reason well so I fully
anticipate that people won't be
implementing this even after it's in the
document for various reasons right it's
it's difficult for people operating in
New Zealand to market on whatever else
so and people just a slow right we take
edges too much work to do so it's
actually not hard
whether it was oh it's work yeah but but
yes it's not it's not something that
sort of critical for me one Jenna I'm on
a second
Martin's of India I think this is useful
good to have and we should we should
make sure the text that we have on the
wiki this solid and we will get it in
there's just no urgency because I don't
think any of the implementers are going
to rush to test this yet so we can get
to it and we should get to it and they
will get but it's okay for us we control
at least the people should please take a
look at the Box on the wiki and and talk
to Ingemar and the other folks on the
design team I think there's a list of
people want to really get involved you
can talk any more and you'll be put on
the list I'm guessing um the goal is to
sort of keep our fingers on the wiki and
then get it near PR our time frame with
the understanding that it may not end up
in 12 but it will end up in a version
shortly thereafter
thank you
okay Brian so what we're going to do
here is Brian will give a presentation
it's okay Brian let's say it's safe it's
safe I have royal interpretive dance for
later so Brian's gonna give this
presentation we're gonna ask for
clarifying questions afterwards then
we're gonna move into a discussion phase
where we talk about whether the working
group wants to address this use case and
whether this is the right way to address
it yeah and then we're gonna do some
hums and and I'll note that I there's a
bunch of stuff in back up here so I may
be narrowing slide slide references up
during the discussion sure let's go just
sort of foreshadowing that we will
probably ask everybody to be very short
and the microphone because I expect um
the discussion to take a while I'm not
putting that mic in here okay all right
so try to make your point as possible
style you can even go back into the line
you don't have to say everything the
first time you make it to the front of
the line um and and we will try the time
manage this pretty aggressively if we
have to okay and one more bit of context
we've been talking about this for a
while our intent as chairs is really to
try and get a direction on this and get
us something we can confirm on the list
today we're getting the point where we
can't install this decision much longer
so please keep that in mind in the
discussion we're trying to get to
closing this issue in some fashion and
the reason we specifically didn't
schedule this discussion at the dinner
room because we wanted to have sort of
the broader participation that we get in
the general ITF but that is the reason
why we didn't do it in Melbourne for
example um but this is what Zoe's we've
kicked this around long enough and we
really need to decide what we want to do
on this topic so that we can sort of
move on and free and punchy cycles for a
bunch of people okay go take your labor
hi I'm Brian Trammell I'd like to see a
show of hands who here doesn't know what
the spin bit is
Wow okay so there's a lot of instruction
here that is actually gonna be useful
for like six people great next slide so
this is in a PR 1046 basically what we
want to do is we want to take this
little red bit right here from the quick
short header and we want to make it spin
there's a very simple algorithm for this
every time the server sends a packet
it's it's the last spinach saw on the
packet that it sends but client thank
you very much the clients it sets um you
know the inverse of the last bin it's
all on each packet that it sends so what
this does is a very simple distributed
algorithm it creates a square wave
that's on this one bit that's visible on
the packets in the flow with a period
equal to the application experience
round-trip time why do we do this
so we're preparing for a post TCP world
we've seen in map RG anywhere between
five and seven percent of quick I've
heard on some links that the amount of
quic is much larger than seven percent
of the traffic that's crossing that link
there is the ability based on the
information radiated off of TCP to do
lightweight efficient RTT estimation on
arbitrary aggregates of traffic as quick
traffic replaces TCP traffic this
visibility goes away we got a lot of use
cases enumerated in the spin bit draft
draft from a quick spin zero one basic
Internet me and intradomain
troubleshooting home network
troubleshooting buffer boil mitigation
for mobile networks or to actually want
to note that in the the hackathon this
week we actually built a real buffer
bloat mitigation simulation emulation
that shows that this actually reduces
our TT for all of the flows over some of
these links significantly and internet
measurement research how does it work
I'll do the slides versus the
interpretive dance I can do the
interpretive dance later if it's not
clear the client starts sending once
they start sending of short packets with
short headers it puts spin zero
the server basically just reflects spin
zero as soon as the client starts seeing
spin zero packets it sets spin 1 the
server reflects backspin 1 the client
sees that spin zero so basically you see
all of the packets in flight in the flow
kind of pulse between spin 1 and spin 0
and the period of that is the RTT so how
this works if you're doing
unidirectional one point measurement so
the observer is at this point here the
observer sees some zeros and then it
sees more zeros because the zeros are on
the the back side it shifts to one you
see the edge boom and that's where a
wave is the round-trip time of the flow
with bi-directional one point
measurement you can actually compare the
square waves on the upstream and the
downstream side and you can separate the
components of RTT so you can know how
much of the RTT is attributable to
between the observation point the client
in the observation point in the server
does it work yes it does um our student
Pete do very has implemented this in
minke we've actually had three other
implementations of this at the hackathon
the implementation effort is trivial
basically so Pete's a pretty smart guy
but he'd never seen go and he'd never
seen mink and within the first 45
minutes he had a working spin bit
it took him another couple of weeks he
had mink running but that the spin bit
was actually spinning the spin signal
you get really high resolution
information about the RTT experience by
the end point applications one of the
things that surprised us is due to act
timing and quick the information that's
available at the receiver from the spin
bit is better than the information
that's available in the AK screen from
the spin bit as a with respect to the
RTT you get more RTT samples from from
this method does it work in networks
that are not perfect yes it does the
signal will start to overestimate RTT
slightly when you see heavy loss and
when you see reordering you get on some
loss of fidelity where you get edges
back and forth this is a clear fun
question yeah I read the slides I'm
sorry oh sorry what
can you go back oh yeah okay yeah yeah
oh so alright it's difficult for me to
point from Iran so I'm gonna have to
leave the box you take off the standard
oh yeah okay so basically the the spiky
orange stuff here is so what we have is
a client connecting to a server and
uploading data right so it's it's the
reverse of the way that this usually
works but you can just switch the things
this is the art this is the spin bit
information available at the sender side
and the moving minnow and so this green
line underneath here is just a just a
minimum filter right this is it's like
the the linear smoothing filter that TCP
uses right so like the the the unsmooth
TCP RTT is spiky like this as well down
here this is the server so the data
receiver side extreme information about
its RT T's and the green here is the
moving minimum so you see the resolution
is lower Z as you don't have a true the
true number okay
the true network number in this case is
40 and then it goes up to 80 okay yeah
oh yeah so this sorry yeah this edge
here was making sure that it responded
to changes in the path RTT and just so I
understand because this isn't clear
executive information is available to an
inspection then point on the wire this
this inference so the this RTD
information is what's available to
anyone who can see the practices wait
yes and um I think why the children
client differ I'm just stupid
yeah um I actually have forgotten why
this wise so it's basically because of
how it's I think it's because of how
acts are called mariya do you want to
answer that question yes is flowing from
the client to the service we have a lot
of symbols a lot of packets and from the
server to the clients you only have X so
you just have this packet so it's like
this Eckerd right and so what is
the network instruction point C so the
network inspector client sees this great
so it sees the yellow the spiky yellow
stuff pretty like we're walking around
it looks if the perspective is different
from the client of the server right
especially the ones in the middle
somewhere right what is it it gets it
gets the kids the better estimates okay
yeah so in the world with the sort of
the current - ten version of the draft
the packet numbers are still in the
clear so it's very easy to use packet
number information to reject reordered
edges and to detect Lawson - to reject
the edges where there's loss so if you
have packet numbers that increment by
one per packet and are in clear-text
then this signal is very robust if we
encrypt the packet number we can talk
about that in the backup
so yeah in conclusion we've spent about
you're talking about this we spent a few
months implementing it and getting of
experience with it in real networks as
well as an emulator network so Pete has
a stack of paper about this big filled
with plots with various sort of loss and
reordering models it turns out that this
actually gives you pretty good RTT
information all the way down to the
point where you drive the transport
protocol into the ground we actually had
to disable flow control and congestion
control in order to keep it to get it to
keep sending packets in order to to look
at some of the points in this this
network impairment space it's minimal
overhead we have one bit if we're
grouping the packet number we can talk
about other options it's very high
fidelity it's an explicit signaling
approach that replaces an implicit
signaling approach it has minimal
privacy impact as we saw from the the
RTT DT in was that frog or Singapore
yeah so from a while ago
it does what it says on the tin it
replaces on path visibility into the RTT
in a world where removing from TCP to
quick clarification questions yeah so to
go away if you don't think this is
clarifying does this change at all when
we do multipath it depends on the
multipath architecture but basically
this would be so a purse up flow the
this the spin state would have to be
kept on a server sub flow basis in order
to get it to work if you're if you're
mingling the spin State among sub flows
then you're not going to get a usable
signal no you're not you do not yeah no
you do not have to link the sub clothes
in the clear in order for this to be
useful because you're basically what
you're measuring is the network RTT of
the five tuple so Google did you have
any numbers for like you said you you
kind of drove the transport to
destruction all right could you have any
numbers for how like how it degrades as
you build with numbers like 5 percent
and 10 percent 20 percent um we we do
occasionally see numbers like this and I
would so so if your so are you talking
about 20 percent random loss or 20
percent burst loss that's usually a
packet pleaser and okay yeah so when you
see burst loss
it goes from sort of the gray line here
to the blue line here you you get
essentially overestimation of the RTT
because you're just missing the edge
right so yeah the edges the edge that
you see is delayed there are so the edge
bit and status bit things here actually
you know I should probably explain those
so these are things that we started
looking at in order to prepare this to
be useful in an encrypted packet number
world
the status bits essentially reject all
of the edges that are lost you can also
do this with packet numbers and then you
get basically up to the redline the
reason that the redline looks better
than the vanilla without loss line here
is it's actually rejecting some of the
edges that are further invariance right
like so the
when you start rejecting lost edges you
get fewer samples which means your
variance goes down so you get less um
you get less this error okay so finally
you just so if they know what that loss
is with the packet number not encrypted
as quick as today so vanilla without
losses actually without looking at the
packet number okay yeah so if if you
have a good if your if your network is
running well you don't need to look at
the packet number you can basically just
look at the the raw series of edges and
you're going to have you know few enough
of those are going to be offset or lost
that it's not going to affect the
aggregate that much in as well what is
imagine a hello yeah hello I'll give my
question is why you say that it
overestimates just because well so if
you lost the packet you you get an edge
later
okay so arte be estimate comes up
because the edges delight okay but
normally you you need so much chance to
to to loss exactly the packet in the in
the age right so you get one edge per
RTT so yes you do have the loss rate has
to go up so you know like around one
percent before you start losing the edge
packets of course that's EBP dependent
rate so this is no so much great yeah
okay thank you
Colin was first on the back Mike all
right Colin Punkins to quick
clarification questions have you run
into any issues with reordering and very
low TT where the signal described yeah
looks like this um so basically what
happens is you and so with very low RTT
we did pretty much everything with forty
milliseconds that was sort of a baseline
with lower RTT you actually get less
absolute error because the only like if
you do like a single edge reorder um you
just get you know the you get a you know
a spike of one back to zero and then
back to one you get the an RTT
measurement which is pretty close to
zero it's the inner pocket time great we
40 millisecond or RTT if you have a fair
amount of so there's really without
reordering which is sort of a great line
that's underneath all of the other lines
if you start reordering it you end up
with a lot of these very short these
very short RTT estimates it turns out
like a really stupid heuristic is just
to you know reject everything that is
unrealistically short and this was a
static heuristic and you see it reduces
the error quite a lot but so two-bit
spin and some of the other the valid
edge stuff that replaces the packet
number when the packet number is
encrypted rejects that you can also you
get back down to vanilla if you're
rejecting based on packet number
reordering good texture unrealistically
short heuristics would be like so you
you take the expected RTT and I think it
was divided by if it's like less than
one tenth right it was a multiplicative
heuristic well you would just take your
you just take your tiny or DT and divide
it by ten right yeah this is only for
short header packets right B the idea is
the long header packets are one you have
like you have the handshake you can just
basically to your handshake RTT estimate
the normal way to you don't have any of
those of those packets three what we
really you know that the point of this
is to create samples of the rtt either
that you can use for a running time
series analysis of a single flow if
you're doing Diagnostics or if you're
doing base lining or measuring you're
gonna take these RT t samples and you're
gonna put them into an aggregate you're
gonna watch them move together great so
so the the long header it's not at all
worth the complexity to add this to the
long header just a reminder we're still
on clarifying questions christian bland
when i look at your numbers here i have
some kind of fear and and the fear is
that this
killing beef measurement will work very
well if the network is working well and
will start to work less well if the
network is having problems and I am
concerned that this kind of behavior
goes against the idea of having a
measurement tool that there is you some
information when you have a trouble so
with the so thank you for leading into
one of my one of my backup slides so
this is an enhancement that we looked at
called the edge valid signal so what
happens here is that each so okay first
of all I'll say if the packet numbers
are in the clear um the entire path has
enough information to detect upstream
loss and reordering of an edge so it has
enough information to determine
completely whether an edge is good or
not when you have heavy loss and heavy
reordering you tend to get many fewer
samples but for any flow that is able to
keep set if the network conditions are
such that the flow is able to keep
sending we've never seen a situation
that it that we have to drop all of the
samples right we still have visibility
into what's going on to that flow the
sample rate of that flow is itself like
the number of good samples versus the
bad samples is itself an indication as
to how much network difficulty that flow
is seeing great with the valid edge
signal which we looked into more because
it looked like the we were moving toward
consensus on encrypting the packet
numbers so we spent some time looking
into this one with the edge valid signal
there's a counter that goes it counts up
0 1 2 3 every time an endpoint sends a
good edge so if an edge gets reordered
or lost the what the the measurement
point will see is what looks like an
edge because it went from 0 to 1 but the
end point didn't think it was a good
edge so the valid edge counter is at 0
so it will say ok this is not a valid
edge so you can easily reject you can
encrypt the the packet number and easily
reject edges just as well as if you had
the packet number if you add two bits to
the signal what we saw in this case is
we had two
like I said we had to disable flow
control and disable congestion control
and send it a constant rate in order to
get it to keep generating traffic at
some of these points in the space
because we were doing like 10
millisecond RTT with 10 millisecond
jitter so random
packet delivery order that you know the
transport falls over at that point right
the diagnostic is the network is so
screwed up that the transport stops
sending rate so I we shared your fear
when we look at this originally but we
have a fair amount of data that at least
I'm less afraid
Pete's thesis on this should be
published in about two weeks and we can
send that to the list so my
understanding and I'm gonna summarize
summarize is that if we have a
combination of this mm-hmm yes one two
okay so with an encrypted packet number
a 3 bit spin bit is indistinguishable
from from the one bit spin bit with a
clear text packet number there is
another enhancement this is courtesy
is this still clarifying your can I keep
going we need to see a clarified right
now okay
there's another enhancement where
basically you have a two bit spin that
counts up one two three and any time and
so the end points of course know that an
edge is valid or not because they have
access to the clear tox packet number so
they know whether or not an edge that
they're seeing is is valid or not
you can use this that spins one two
three and then takes an additional code
point zero that it sends for an entire
half RTT to say the last edge that I
sent was bad so measuring this is a
little bit harder we have not yet shown
that it gives you data that is as good
as the three bit spin but it's in the in
the ball
thank you we're discussing of the team
elements but didn't miss it or we didn't
get to it yet
characterizing loss and loss patterns
using skill bit without a plan so that's
out of scope for this disgrace out of
scope for this discussion me I may I may
I may push an idea though
Somaly V the edge valid sick we have we
haven't done the work yet but we have an
intuition that the edge the series of
valid and invalid edges will give you
some basic information about loss or
reordering it won't give you information
about which it is but it will if you see
sort of the the valid invalid edge
series you can derive some information
about loss reordering from that we
haven't done the work yet that's that's
future work but it won't give you
information about very low loss rates
like if your loss if your edge loss
probability is below a threshold you
don't get any loss information but if
your loss probability is high enough you
are losing edges you will see that in
this three bit signal but this is just a
this is not the goal of this of this
proposal it just just it it's a it's a
side effect so clarify coming you never
again to say three bits pinned it okay
okay so so what we we actually we were
Europe and they all know thank you Acker
um there's a so this is a spin bit and a
two bit valid edge counter or vac is
what we've been calling it Marlboro this
is very basic Estonia is their
assumption that this requires continuous
flow of packets the work for the one bit
spin bit hold on do I have that in and
for one bit spin winter without packet
number if the sender is application
limited then you will have over
estimates right when the sender stop
sending you're going to get one over
estimated edge
at that level the edge valid signal if
you add this edge valid signal you can
have a very simple heuristic at the
sender side that drives the edge VALIC
the valid edge counter to zero when it
is sending an edge in reply to a packet
that came in more than 0.1 times RTT ago
right so the sender can expose whether
or not an edge is likely to be valid
through the valid edge counter and that
reduces all of you overestimation of
bursty traffic the second bit helps you
but even if you only have one bit and
you know that you're sending a traffic
pattern that it's useless your measure
around room time you can just set the
bit always to view and say like this
flow is not helpful for you because in
the network if you have enough other
flows you just meet break information
yeah so if we if we go with a 1 bit spin
bit there are ways to reduce
overestimation from from bursty traffic
does that first pick in the multi path
case does that bursty traffic case
become more important because it seems
like if you're switching back and forth
through which path you're sending things
on then you may want to be careful not
to be having people observe stuff on
because it'll each of those paths may
look like it first you for some great
can I can I reek lip can I reclassify
that as a research question as opposed
to a clarifying question yeah I mean yes
it seems like that we haven't looked at
it we will as long as you send enough
like more than if you send for at least
one round-trip time you get one sample
rate but if you're doing if you're
basically doing flow spreading where
everything is designed to look bursty
then yeah you're not going to get good
signal out of this so but I clarified
question I was even have some map
between the path and the architect
midcity q what is the key for that math
using so for all of this the key for
that map is the 5 people hopefully have
common packets one hopefully doesn't
clarify in question this is in the clear
but yes yes sorry I neglected to say
that
any other clarifying questions okay well
thank you all for coming today one that
illustrates it before yeah yeah and you
can always help yeah yeah all right so
now we're gonna go into the discussion
face the non clarifying phase so just to
give people a little context as Brian
said we've been talking about this for a
long time it's been somewhat contentious
than working group for a fair amount of
time good positioning Brian we spooled
up a design team to evaluate especially
the privacy implications of the spin bit
a one bit spin bit and the the result of
that was they came back and they said
they couldn't identify and he concrete
privacy issues with the one bit spin bit
we had some concerns about whether the
data generated by the spin bit was
usable Brian's just gone through the
experimentation and the research they've
done around that and so now we're in a
position where the working group needs
to decide do we want to add this Ben bit
to the specification in some form and so
that's the scope of discussion now we're
not going to talk about loss for example
or other aspects of things that networks
might need to understand about the flows
we're just restricting this discussion
to the spin bid proposal and the use
case that it tries to address so Brian
yes do you leave the the shape of the
tenor D I didn't hear the question so
I'm not ready to give it yes or no
answer but I am perfectly willing to say
that having gone through the exercise
with the design team on the the
potential privacy implications of this
that I'm pretty confident that the bang
for the buck we're getting out of this
is very good the amount that this seems
to me to leak compared to say the the
information already available on
geolocation is just extraordinarily
small in my opinion for the threats that
we considered and this does seem to
provide a very very useful set of
signals in particular I'm very pleased
with two design points here one that
this is in the control of the sender
this is designed so that the sender does
all of the the setting and all the
server does is reflect on the advantage
of that is that the sender remains in
control of whether or not this is on and
although the receiver can decide not to
reflect those set everything to 0 as
well there's a good bit of of agency in
the right place in my opinion the other
thing that I think is a very good piece
of the design here is that there are
ways as we move forward into multipath
or into other other mechanisms to
continue to use this on a per path basis
but it's not trying to be so complicated
to incorporate all of the different
potential measurements that you might do
at once it's it's clean in its one year
so I'm definitely in favor imagine Ted
before you go because I know that's high
cost operation you said this a lot are
you referring to and everyone in the in
the queue I'd like to focus a little bit
on are we talking about the single bit
if we assume we're going to encrypt the
packet number how do you feel about the
two or three bit solution 1030 so I was
actually evaluating in terms of the way
draft 10 currently has it which has an
unencrypted packet number having looked
not nearly as completely at the beck I
believe I believe it is quite similar my
intuition is that by encrypting the
packet number and going to the back
we're actually making an overall privacy
enhancement but as I said that's an
intuition I actually haven't done enough
of the research to make that as
confidently as I believe he has been
able to make the assertions he's made
today thank you for by the time the tail
of the queue is out of the room we're
gonna move the front Micra forward
so the guys could stay inside go ahead
and do that
yeah that's a good thing we can see you
better
Daniel con Gilmore selu so my main so I
appreciate that this has been whittled
down to a relatively small number of
bits I would prefer to keep it as small
as possible zero would be great if we're
forced into having one you know I I do
appreciate the engineering with its
funding here I want to point out that
it's not clear to me the discussion
earlier was about bursty traffic as
opposed to like a steady flow there may
be other traffic patterns where this
doesn't work as opposed to flow you know
typical flows that we see today
particularly if we start looking at non
reliable streams that don't require acts
and it concerns me a little bit that we
may be designing something that
encourages network operators to make
decisions about flow paths based on
assumptions that we currently have about
reliable streams which may have a cost
if we want to use quick in the future
for non reliable streams if the network
operators are doing bad things to
traffic that doesn't match what they
think is the RTT estimate so I want us
to keep those ideas in mind if you think
quick is going to be interesting for non
reliable streams as well think about
what we might be doing to ossify the
network stack if we include something
like this um Jahangir I actually agree
with what dkg just said I I think it's
important to consider what happens in
the ACK rate goes down specifically that
is a significant value that we can
provide but I stepped up here to say
something broader and I will do that
I've basically spent the last year
listening to arguments and I'm her
them from all over the place in its
yesterday has taken the better part of a
year has spoken with many people
including operators vendors important
implementers about the incentives
benefits and deployment stories for this
bit and I've considered all of these
carefully from where I'm seeing it now
we need to make a decision now and I
think of this as an engineering decision
not a theoretical one or not a research
one my informed opinion based on all the
conversations I've had and all the
thinking of done is that we should not
include this bit in the core
specifications for v1 I'd be very happy
for it to be an experiment that
demonstrates that there's value and
there's interest and deployment I think
it'd be very value to have an internet
wide experiment that actually shows some
of these things and I think this
mechanism is a great starting point I
think there's some interesting data here
but there are also a lot of open issues
as we can see and that as the design of
quick evolves that will challenge the
assumptions that are being made in this
mechanism here and all of that points
towards an excellent starting point for
experimentation but I don't think this
needs to be in the core specifications
now and I don't think it should be Kevin
Smith Vodafone so first point is I heard
an earlier in a week about quick being
measured at about 9:10 percent on
cellular networks certainly we've
measured it much much higher probably 40
to 50 percent in many of our operations
and so a privacy aware or previously
compliant spin bit which helps us track
and monitor and measure that he's very
welcome to the extra bits
one driver dollar to put forward is 5g
radio so we want to as that evolves we
want to get a feel for how that's
performing new new wave lengths etc we
want to see how transport conducts
course I know the extra room in extra
bits for the purposes of measuring
latency or extra bits for the purpose of
measuring other things Advent
so they go elsewhere that specifically
Devaki exactly so that that's all drive
it is 5g radio and how the transport
practicals accent thank you so we
implemented unpretty browser spin bit
for our network and it provides us with
enough information to be able to make
troubleshooting with Dakota me so you
know which side is a wrong side on which
side is a provider right today so now we
don't make any investigation with an
additional bit so this I don't have a
new opinion so you used mink or
something come out of stack that was
enhanced with a single to spin bit and
you run it yeah a network and you
validated that you've got information we
shall attack reviewing the Thanks I
contacted so I I think it's fairly clear
that there is no meaningful information
leaked from having this bit so from that
point of view and this is worth
including I think if anything with those
two little information here and I think
we're gonna I worry that we're going to
find it works in the cases where the
network is behaving and we don't have
sufficient information to use it for
debugging the difficult cases whether a
network is starting to misbehave so I I
lean towards thinking this is worth
doing
I am unconvinced it will turn out to be
as useful as we think it is but I think
it's worth doing as an experiment I
think we should perhaps consider
arranging the business so that if the
experiment turns out to be useful it can
become part of the invariance because if
this is something people are building
measurement infrastructure around in the
future then we want to guarantee that
where it's going to be but I'm not sure
we're at that stage yet and it's not
fair to me that it will become useful
Praveen Microsoft so we have a general
use case today in the cloud where we
want to measure what's happening with
tenant traffic
and we're doing that with TCP today and
having such a bit would be extremely
useful to be able to continue to do that
with quick if we are looking at quick as
a replacement for TCP I genuinely think
that this will be useful for us the
other good part about this proposal is
that it's not compute intensive so
setting this bit is not a big problem
for an implementation also looks like
the implementation effort is pretty
small but as to the you know discussion
of experimentation versus not yeah I
mean we could make we could consider not
making this part of the invariance if we
want to but putting this in version one
would at least unblock the experiment
and allow us to find out if this works
well in practice channeling Ben Carrick
security ad from jabber who's in another
room he echoes a John's point would it
make sense to use a quick version to
experiment with this bin bit or are
there finer grained ways to indicate
that to the path Patrick McManus lines
moving pretty well that's good yeah so I
will take issue on the other side that
this does not leak any interesting data
I think what it leaks is obviously RTT
and when I mentioned that to people they
say you can get that out to client
handshake client handshake why do you
need to spin it right because it changes
over the duration of the flow and this
is relevant in an HTTP world which often
implements requests for patterns of
single messages in each direction and we
are building a protocol that is
otherwise multiplexing and obscuring
many of those interactions and they can
of course change your with lifetime of
the connection for how long that takes
and this bin but actually brings that
fundamentally as a signal back into the
clear and I think that probably has some
traffic analysis proper so I usually
don't think this is obviously harmless
as it is sometimes presented I guess the
second point I would make is I think
doing this is actually also fine around
the behavior of existing pieces of the
TCP echo system for properties the TCP
never delivered you know the fact that
acknowledgments were in the clear is
simply an artifact of TCP
- signal to the network those are
designed to be in signals and I think
making the minutes actually preserves
our ability to innovate in all ways
around that so I I opposed to any number
of bits on those basis and you know
finally and with respect to you know my
product it's fairly unlikely that we
would participate I think we have
compelling evidence that this works at
least in some scenarios I think for this
to be you really need useful we need
first implementation to support and we
have that signal from Mozilla and
secondly we need to make this part of
the invariance otherwise we can't rely
on this to two dimensional there was a
comment about the fidelity of the signal
in loss hearing order with environment
with high loss in high order but for
example the mobile network you don't
experience that much ordering or loss
but you have high variance in RTT and
this is a very very valid tool to
actually can grab that signals out of
the network
hi I'm Brian Trammell well-well stating
my my general deep deep skepticism about
anything about the success of traffic
analysis resistance in the Internet
there were three issues raised actually
I didn't put names down so I'm assuming
Jonah was one of them sorry I'm picking
on because right there so there were
issues raised about the spin bit on
partially reliable or non reliable
streams where there's no extreme back um
ACK elimination I don't want to say
compression or a coalescing right
because you know so basically where the
acknowledgement scheduler is using a
different algorithm than the one that
TCP is working right now these are valid
concerns but I don't think they're a
problem because as long as so your
sampling rate goes down right
the sampling rate will never go to zero
as long as you have some sort of
acknowledgement driven congestion
control and if you don't have
acknowledgement ribbon congestion
control then you don't really have much
of a network left to measure so to
Patrick's point
so it basically as long as you have as
long as you have a situation where you
will during the lifetime of a given flow
identified by five people so these would
be these are not connections these would
be subclones in a multipath environment
we don't have to link this up close to
multipath environment all you need is
occasionally a low delay between one
incoming packet and the other packet
where an ED transition would occur in
any flow that would contribute to
measurement you're going to have enough
of these to generate samples right so if
you're if you're trying to use this on a
non TCP acknowledging flow to do per
flow Diagnostics yes in certain cases
you might get the time series will have
too many gaps in it for you to be able
to see the evolution of your TT if one
instead you're trying to do is aggregate
these by link so you're trying to do
passive measurement of all the traffic
on a link and you're looking at
residuals and you're looking at how that
moves together in order to diagnose the
link you're still going to have enough
samples in order to be able to generate
some signal out of that so the in that
future world the applicability may
reduce but for you know the cases that
we're looking at for sort of like
Network health yeah I don't see a
realistic evolution of quick for which
that would go away with respect to
leaking or TT yes of course that's what
it's supposed to do if we don't want the
path to be able to measure our ITT at
all then we should not do this I think
that we do obviously because I spend
about a year working on this
presentation in one form or another um
as far as the information that's leaked
between streams um I I want to dig into
that a little bit more I don't see it as
a problem in that if you're doing
multiple streams together you're
basically um uh
sort of obscuring the size and tiny
relationships of those streams but
you're still going to get this pattern
where you're going to send a packet
that's going to be an edge and then
you're going to get some sort of
acknowledgment or thing back that
pattern I don't see how that would
expose it I actually Africa not your
problem we talk offline because they
don't really understand his concern
there so that's everything I happen to
go back to the line go back to the line
Brian before you riku cuz we know that's
what you're gonna do just one clarifying
question in your proposal yes this is
always opt in the end both have to opt
in it is so I just want to make sure
that people realize that even if we put
this in the invariance is not a
guarantee that is going to actually have
a wire yeah and I would actually so
there's been some other discussion about
um the relationship between this and
greasing and for um for the common case
where you're basically just trying to do
generate some RTT samples so that you
can look at aggregate s-- individual
flows can probabilistically opt in or
opt out of this you don't need to
negotiate it basically if you have a
probabilistic off in on either side then
you multiply those two together and
that's the probability you're going to
get a signal
um once you have the vac you can also
probabilistically draw samples you can
basically say here's an edge I have a
valid solid edge I'm I only want to to
expose my RTT you have a target RTT
exposure rate and you can drop the
ballot at the valid edge counter in
order to meet that target rate so
there's a lot of things that we can do
there's very fine grained endpoint
control for how much information gets
exposed and I think that it for a
creasing standpoint if you don't want it
to ossify around you always get a signal
otherwise hey there's something this is
not a quick flow then that probabilistic
enablement is a pretty simple way to
achieve that sure I was speaking of
something slightly different which is if
no one else in because of whatever all
of the if all of the opt-in
probabilities are 0 then the number of
signals that you get is 0 obviously
thank you so it's 1037 so we have a
little less than an hour and a half and
we still have a very D
q so keep that in mind Gabriel no good
Montenegro Microsoft yeah I wanted to
emphasize the nature of Upton and Brian
Murray did a much better job than I
would have done on that I like to add
though that we would definitely opt in
to that I like the probabilistic nature
just just so everyone knows when you say
we well in Microsoft okay with our
browser in all of your application yeah
so whether we would always do it or not
that's different but we would definitely
take part in this and if you think it's
important we see it's useful the one
very important reason why I'm saying
pretty confidently yeah for this we
would have support interest is all the
very extensive privacy analysis it has
been done I would like to see similar or
now what's going on for the back before
saying anything about that but for this
one you'll feel pretty confident it's
jet formation so I'm one of the guys
like some good year to who our kind of
thing because I have been following
watch the discussion happening around in
bit and now that we have implemented it
in at home and did some testing I think
much this online screen more about parts
that so I'm more convinced if this is
useful now and looking at what a
detailed design team had doubt whatever
privacy and more concept for okay with
with what it leaks the RTT and I had
worked with service partners network
operators and they kind of see the point
of network measuring entity and making
the network help keep okay so this is
useful and but I also think we should
discuss a bit more about this unreliable
mood but having seen like what's
happening around the idea like which is
kind of becoming the general-purpose
transport you know you would like to do
some media over quick
maybe unreliable may be partially will
good will work and I have my colleagues
who believes like
similar I know collision control could
work for more more reliable and
partially herbal kind of transport I
don't see that's the big issue but I do
concern that if it is not invariant if
it is not in Russian one then we might
not get the test we want to do and as
this is the opt-in I don't see it as a
big issue so if it is a Russian one we
do testing we see how it's working and
we decide what to do if it is there and
if it's Achtung if it's not feasible if
leaking more information plans can
always say no tree so I think it's fine
yes what it Google so I wanted to
reiterate the point about how sending
fewer acknowledgments might actually
increase the RTT signal and introduce
about a 25% noise
currently we are running a lot of our
clients at ng quick with a only sending
acknowledgments four times per RTT
there's no other data descent so just
like to be aware there's this pear bit
of noise from a technical perspective if
we if we do this I personally want this
to be good enough that we actually think
it's a useful signal so if we do this
either we need to not do packet number
encryption or I think we probably need
like two bits is the last thing I want
to do this is add one bit and have it be
like really noisy in the in the cases
when the network really degrades it's
complete junk so I don't want to add
this and have it be a detriment actively
detrimental in obvious ways that were
aware so I was coping with a lot of
influencers and a fair number of
operators and people seem to have very
mixed opinions in both camps so I spoken
with obviously Microsoft said that they
would implement it I can't give you an
official answer for Google I've talked
to a bunch of different people and
people have different answers but I
think we're leaning against probably not
initially but maybe it will run some
experiments but I think we're kind of
leaning known and then on the network
operators I have talked to a lot of
network operators I was in a Northwest
month and I talked with a bunch of
people there about this
and some people said this sounds useful
and some people said I don't know why I
would ever use that to monitor and run
my network and so even in that community
I got very just four responses
um I think one of my biggest concerns is
even if this is not part of the
invariants if it's in v1 it's gonna be
an ever-loving pain in the butt to
change in the future and I'm actually
it's much concerned that this is not
enough as it is too much
so my personal preference is that we go
along the direction that John that was
kind of indicating but I want to be even
more specific at one an experimental
draft I want Brian to use more bits I
want him to try to incorporate loss and
I want you know there's like I think
five bits available use them all like
try to get as much information as you
can and provide it to the network and
try to figure out and run some
experiments what is actually useful like
and try to figure out if we don't do
this bit or if you don't do that that
what do we lose and I guess I feel like
this feels a little server pushing to me
this feels like a cool idea that what we
think could be useful
sick burn just like serverpush we should
have included it in version one and I
think like I think there's a bunch of
stuff we could have done in serve
approach to you like a sperm with with
it and make it awesome and we just
didn't do the work before we shipped it
to like figure out what we needed to
make it awesome and I think we're still
at that stage today where we almost like
over constrained ourselves down to one
bit because like no one wants to leak
anything but like it's possible that is
not useful so like we shouldn't do
something that we're not like really
sure is useful so I would rather the end
points that think this is could be
useful Microsoft included and cloud
environments and the operators that that
think it's useful conduct some
experiments with an experimental RFC and
we meant an experimental version and
they use all the bits figure out what
they can do with them and come back and
in version two we'll figure out what we
want to include in version two but I
think we put it in version one we're
stuck with it forever
Marcus Lila Eriksen I just want to make
some comments on the usefulness and
simplicity of this so we were a bunch of
people at the hackathon taking quick
stacks we haven't looked at before and
we managed to implement the bunch of
running versions of the spin bit we got
them to interoperate we got really nice
measurement results and we could even do
some interesting buffer block mitigation
techniques using this so we did see some
some usefulness already here and I also
think one extremely important thing here
is what we call the probabilistic opt-in
because as I think we should do this and
I think we should have probabilistic
opting because me as a middle box
developer will be forced to do the right
thing from the start right I will have
to have to take care of the cases where
where where it doesn't flip as expected
from the beginning because this is how
the protocol would work - II didn't
intend I think so I understand this from
the point of view of an endpoint like a
time and I think this looks useful but
this is not the only way to do it there
are other ways to understand quantity at
an endpoint it also looks like only
information so I would suggest we spend
more time understanding it and
understanding the value of it before
making it a requirement for a
graphically high
um like that ignorance so um I guess
syriacus like Ian said my understanding
from Brian's presentation was that if we
do encrypted sequence number basically
we need the back or even the physical
because that summer front there's a mic
in the back if you want to quick thank
you we use the tenon
yes the if you encrypt the the packet
number on you get good signal as long as
the network is is operating well the
signal degrades rapidly when the network
starts operating poorly it's less useful
for Diagnostics right unless you have
the back and pour something like it and
presumably the time you won is in the
network is behaving yes well there's
there's - I mean - so I mean there's
base lining and then there's Diagnostics
and those are two different user shares
but yes okay um so right I mean I think
if I if I have to if if I were given
only two choices you know the the spin
bit with fear Tech's packet numbers and
the back plus spit you know the vac plus
spin bit with encrypted packet numbers I
would definitely choose the latter that
seems like clearly like has like
superior like you know properties um so
I I guess if I must internalize this but
were this ability choice is this what I
think I would pick so um I you know I
took a little look at where just would
actually go if we had the back maybe I'm
missing something but ready used in
rejiggering so we have effectively in
the in the short header we have five
fixed bits the first one zero I was
thinking is gonna have to stay zero the
second was the Cape in which we actually
need we have this one one zero which I
understand some of those things are
being used for game box and maybe
whisker around some movie could screw
around with and then we have three tape
type bits which we don't need them all
was only half like three types so
probably could go ahead for your bits
but we still need at least two of those
bits and we could have one back but that
um so like but the bottom line here is
that doing the back does pretty
seriously cut into our sensibility story
for like you know for like that first
one right and um so doesn't say it's bad
idea which is to say like like it cut
pretty cuts him pretty seriously and it
makes it pretty hard if you know if we
discover that for instance the you know
that that does not you do not lose your
space you know or I'm going to do four
bits or need two more bits somewhere
else like for your quick version to
we're like you know we're kind of like
not a great situation so
um if we're gonna include if we're gonna
include the back like we better be
pretty sure that the thing kind of works
before we do it this is chewing off like
a lot of our reading um so it seems to
me that the back is kind of like unbaked
at this moment um so I personally I
personally find it like pretty hard to
think about like humming yes or no
unlike it proposal includes that because
like if like it turns out of the kind of
just like sucks and like you know it
Johnny
and Ian kind of suggests that it might
be bad emissions then we're gonna be sad
we like using space for it but if it's
like really good then we might be happy
to use the space for us and so I so I
get I understand this feels like kicking
the can down the road a little bit but
it's not required for the invariance
that we know the answer this question um
and I wonder if there's somewhere we can
get more information about whether like
this technique really works like before
we like make a decision about what we're
gonna do it or not
like I think we have some like I think
one thing we could say is we have like
we understand what the worst-case
scenario in terms of like the privacy
story perhaps reasonably well at this
point and we can decide like were you
willing to accept that privacy loss and
and then this basic assume the header
assuming the technique basically worked
really well and then we can like charter
Brian to go off the pilots very well
like we mean like is it not gonna take
more than like 10 minutes to modify the
specification to put this in if we
decide it and it's not the Marion's so
like it's not like a whole up our
schedule the flight wait till November
to decide like if this there it is the
thing goes yet right so I'm sorry to be
like hey kick the can in the road but I
find it very hard to make a decision at
this point oh that's a good segue I
think - so good can I answer really
quickly to one point okay eighty
override fine okay
well Brian I'm going to ask you to
answer that
okay so Spencer Dawkins responsible area
director who has been mostly hands-off
with the largest group in transport to
the - up to this point but I do want to
ask a couple of curious questions it's
different and I was expecting to ask
most of them at the end but I think this
one is probably appropriate I'm
if you please hum if you think this is
research
please hum if you think this is
engineering brian is the chair of the
path aware networking research group in
the IRT F so I'm going to ask Brian to
answer this question no matter how the
hum comes out but first you do want me
to I want me to prime the room okay
century is read the question one point
in one room or another decide which room
you'd rather answer it in I think
putting the signal on the packets is
engineering
I think sunk deep basic measurement that
we can do with it is straightforward
enough that I would not be able to sell
it as research I think some of the
things that we can do with the VAT are
research I will not ask my snarky
question I will move directly to my
serious ID questions before you go on
I'm going to to say and I have an answer
for you that's slightly different the
choice between whether to let the path
do its analysis entirely with implicit
signal or to move to explicit signal is
architecture okay
we have a lot of as we do here is the
rabbit and Brian is also on the IAB so
there are a number of rooms that this
question might be answered in and that
we cry patients are in all of them Oh
Brian asleep right yes I'm gonna ask you
to return to the queue all right I think
it would do you a service to not have a
special place back there so the only
person who can override is our glorious
ad I wear shirt so people can find me
I'm here for another 48 hours after I
walk out of here do the right thing I'm
going to try to could you hum if you
think you know what's going on here and
you think this is engineering
can you hum if you think you know what's
going on here you think it's research
say there's an absolutely fascinating
home outcome now I will return the room
back to your illustrious chairs who as I
said in the earlier meeting
I picked knowing that there would be
days like today
thank you very much Spencer someone down
here has a real talent for humming that
was projection that was just amazing on
that music classes I know who it is
[Laughter]
alright that was the the engineering was
quite strong the research was certainly
not trivial but I think the engineering
was stronger yes but they were both
strong not up here so there's a distinct
for frontal through back of the room
thing going on
right we've been overridden and we
returned to the queue a comment from
Jabbar from Tom Peterson I'm in favor of
having consensus in allocating n bits
for experimentation like spin rather
than baking spinner Horton yes so I want
to look at the broader picture here
quick is not the only udp-based protocol
out there and the only thing that we
have in this for Terror to identify a
quick method is a zero in the first bit
that's all we have connection vibration
and multipath will will be a thing with
quick-connect migrations version one
modulator
so the path would not necessarily see
the handshake so only the middle box can
do is and say oh this is zero must be
quick this is just wrong so where the
middle box then look on every every
check it like this and look for farther
for the spindle and but what does it
mean for other particles that that also
run on UDP this is Sanjay Mishra on
Verizon so first of all I want to
applaud Bryan for the work that he has
done and the hackathon implementation
it's really commendable I think the
amount of exhaustive work they've done
in so far as the deployability is
concerned you know we're already seeing
increased traffic on the network which
is a good thing you're seeing real quick
and but I think some of the things that
we're really missing in in being able to
come here in three years on the road
instead of the mic here and say that you
know what we were glad that we had it
spin bit because we actually have
measured it and and we can look at it in
the last three years and we can say that
if quick has done very well and we have
numbers to show that so I think that's
kind of where we need to we want to be
at and in order to do that we really
need to start with release one now and
make sure that spin bit is added it
clearly has the value and I think we
have to spend enough time Braun is spend
enough time in trying to lay out the
value of it as well as I know privacy
has been kind of assured but you know we
can say a 100 percent that it's all
covered but I think from more or less we
can see that the privacy issue is is not
as as you know if you look at the
benefits and the end the advantages and
the disadvantages I think the advantage
is kind of weighing towards the favor of
spin bed so we really should consider it
and I would really like to see that in
release one and also look at back as a
potential for release - thanks Mia
kudamon so yes this is an experiment we
as the University we've already tried to
look into this as much as we could but
that's a test bet
so we simulated various traffic
conditions which are quite unrealistic
today but might become more realistic in
future hopefully not but you never know
and we can say it does work it gives you
the information we're expecting together
so that's
a research question for many more the
question might be is this a useful
signal what people use it will people
deploy it but we cannot answer that at
with our University testbed you need the
an operator you need to deploy it to
figure out if it will get deployed and
also Microsoft will not be able to
answer this because they don't have a
setup where they can actually change
both the client and the server so if
Google is willing to deploy large scale
and extra mint whether I'm happy if not
then we have to bake it into version one
because that's the only way to get the
experiment that we want because we need
deployment for it and I don't really get
the point about extensibility if we
figure out it's not useful and version
one let's rip it out and version two
that's what we have versioning for and
we can we can't like we can't even fit
publish a worship to with where this is
the only change like this should be done
really quickly that's the extensibility
story we have so really we should put in
a version one the other point I wanted
to make is that there's not a limitation
from the spin bit unlike the egg
mechanism or whatever the dependency we
have is that if a quick is congestion
control you need egg feedback you need
at least one sing up around your claim
or rather like four and that's like
enough for the spindle but this is
dependency to go to congestion control
and I can tell you quick will not go to
the IHG if you don't put congestion
control in there so that dependency you
haven't that will not change so we have
an hour left and if everyone in queue
takes four minutes we will consume that
hour if no one else gets in queue so
please keep your comments brief and I
see the people standing up we will be
closing the queue soon but not quite yet
because you hope how the whole lastly
why I feel sympathy to having this kind
of serve ability I prefer keeping
screaming outside of the protocols
because not having from the spam bed
will help us ship quick oli
for example consider the interaction
with packet number option and especially
because it can be an extension it is
easy to detect with a client implement
spam it or not by looking at the flow in
packets if you see a square wave its
participating in the experiment if you
see a white noise its
so it's simply the detective with a few
quiet implements it or not so why not
make it an exhibition an interpreter at
Google for various reasons I've been
looking a lot at nonparametric
estimators of distributions of various
quantities where this falls in here is
that I suspect there's a lot more
information you can get out of the Vic
about what's happening in the network
and is immediately obvious some of these
estimators are essentially the same
computational cost as an e WMA and we'll
track a given person Tolliver
distributions are very very nicely the
other thing is the same estimators work
even if you don't hit the spin but it's
just more expensive so really what this
pimping gets you is a cheaper way of
getting a slightly worse measurement of
the ITT otherwise have got by Auto
correlating list the string so the
privacy argument is just not there you
can spin the resources which is not
infeasible and what I call it the
straight stream and figure out the ITT
anyway it's just too expensive to do
that in a monitoring system for the
network the monitoring system the nearly
can afford to do the distribution
estimators and derive quite a lot of
information out of even a single bit
spin but the big it can get a lot in I
suspect a pretty good measure of loss
and reordering induced badness and what
do you think the working group you
should do so that maybe there's the
question extra for everybody right so
we're trying to get a sense of the room
we're gonna do maybe hums or show of
hands later but but if the people in the
my clients are felt and I don't want to
put you in a spot right if you don't
want to say then that's fine too but so
if I think that's the question we want
to hand sorted a right and I'll go ahead
and put this on the screen it's this
captures what we think the options we've
heard so far are so if you want to speak
to these or you want to add to the
possibilities please do let's not get
too fine-grained we want to keep this
relatively coarse grained for the
purposes of a decision I believe adding
anything out to the V doesn't no harm
Playtex packet numbers is clearly worse
than the big
hi I'm Amy from orange so we pretty
proud this pin bit on our networks and
one benefits for our customers is that
it allowed us to detect bad behavior of
network before the connection fall back
to TCP just to say that I support one
bit for the point - on - bit for the one
one in the background but it's an it's
an either or three or four jeopardy I
have a couple of comments but first a
question to the chairs when do you
expect to call consensus on whether
we're moving to encourage in sequence
numbers would you like me to give my
comments while you work that out but
yeah that'd be helpful it looks like you
might need a little moment here we're
starting a second stream over here okay
Elka wants my comments then possibly at
the end we can return to my question one
thing I just wanted to point out related
to the comments that Patrick McManus
everybody remembers Patrick his comments
were some time ago now about the art
Roger time implications
I ran the design team for that and we
could not find privacy implications for
them but I want to to be clear that what
the design team was asked to do was to
look for those implications not simply
to examine whether or not this leaked
because it was an uninteresting question
the answer was yes that was the intent
if somebody has a different question for
example whether the Beck leaks more or
less than a sequence number I'd be happy
to send up another design team if if the
chairs wanted that I also wanted to note
that many many people here have offered
work to Brian and I hope you're also
offering in money my personal opinion on
what my my beloved colleague Ian sweat
said about it going into v1 baffled me
because there's an
giant b0 that we've changed enormously
and the idea that anything we put into
d1 will be with the road be with us at
the end of time seems a very very
strange conclusion to draw from that
experience and in fact I draw the
opposite one I also wanted to go
slightly into the question of
ossification I do think there is a risk
of ossification here but I don't think
it's the risk people are seeing I think
people are worried that if they put this
into b1 it will be hard to rip out and
will ossify both the expectations of the
network operators and the expectations
of the stack I think the bigger risk
here is that if we continue to push
things into the network without explicit
signal as an architectural choice people
will also fly into staying with TCP
instead of moving to them when they
would otherwise gain benefits from doing
so so that's there for TCP according to
Daniel Gilmore who definitely was not
applauding for TCP let me just do that
and I have stalled enough do you guys
have an answer to my first question
sorry we're working in are interrupted
so you're giving some up give us moment
turn it over to Daniel con Gilmore to
stall for a while we so we just we are
about to announce the formation of a
design team on the packet number
encryption took a little while to shake
out the the participation I think the
email should be coming as soon as one of
us as a second to type um so there's
there's a people that basically have
started to work on this already we're
going to form one of those things that I
can come back with something looks like
at PR um my guess is that we would try
to land this PR sooner rather than later
because it obviously impacts the
variance and therefore my guess is that
we would do this within the next four
weeks who's Martin says it doesn't
impact the invariance okay well the -
right right so
my answer to your question here is
clearly number two it doesn't belong in
the very to this section but it does
belong in p1 and just to give a little
context around that so far from what
I've heard in the room it seems like
there are warm feelings about the Veck
it also seems like people haven't had
enough time to look at it and we need to
examine it the designs we might
immediately write as I came around that
I am happy to spend some energy on yeah
lack for the deck thank you thank you
for offering to do that Ted well we'll
definitely keep that a mod genuine
Gilmour so I will answer this question
that wasn't what I got in mind for I
prefer to lead us in bit for v1 so that
means for which also means three I don't
see the difference between three and
four because there's nothing stopping
anyone from a negotiating session if we
don't put it everyone I think the
difference just what maybe others have
done missing the distinction the
differences that option three means we
would publish an experimental RFC as if
you wanted to experiment with spinning a
bit here's a good way how you would spin
a bit so pick what is that this is the
right group to do to produce such an
experiment RFC so sure yeah but that is
a foreign tourist and basically we are
not spending cycles on even doing the
experimental RFC out of this group
that's the difference between three and
four okay well I mean if it's gonna
happen out before it happen in this
group this group has the expertise for
it so right I actually got in mind to
respond to a comment from Brian few
years ago Wow just in particular he said
that he was unconcerned about traffic
analysis countermeasures because of the
inevitability of traffic analysis on
Internet traffic and I well well I share
his fear I want to encourage people in
this room to not share his nihilism if
we if we your comment was it was was a
form of traffic analysis
nihilism and I don't think we can afford
to do that certainly we don't understand
it very well but Brian I want many
meaty research questions for you to be
gainfully employed in four years and if
we give up on traffic analysis now then
that will not be possible so yeah so you
want to inject just really quickly is
that not sure what hat I'm wearing I've
heard in a couple of the recent comments
of the assertion that if we put it in v1
that well if we don't like it or it
doesn't turn out well we can just go and
mint to v2 that's very true except that
we are have agreed that v1 is primarily
about HTTP so we're gonna mint a new
version of HTTP that uses quick v1 it's
not clear if the HTTP community will
decide to adopt a v2 that's not a
natural transition potentially just
wanted to highlight that right if I may
if I may do an ad interrupt just to say
something that may be helpful to focus
the discussion since we just used the
words a few years ago at the mic line it
seems reasonable to say that there are a
number of possible answers for when the
working group might make a decision and
today is part of that possible set my
decision to charter quick was made at
the same time that we made the decision
to not charter plus so I made the
intentional obsession that we would not
wander around through that space in the
IETF for a while and it is not okay with
me to have the Plus working group as
part of the quick working group after we
decided not to make the plus working
group that doesn't make sense to me now
you know this is a big room and almost
all of you are now come eligible which
means you can sign recall petitions but
that's the way I'm seeing it doesn't
have to be today but if we're having
this conversation after a while I don't
think that's a win
Thank You Spencer sorry conferring with
the referees are a
I missed that point there was a there
was a mention of 20:26
um I first want to apologize to dkg for
encouraging nihilism about traffic
analysis for anyone I just please don't
let me discourage you I don't have any
money to pay you to do the research
sorry I'm pretty firmly on to here big
bits and quick v1 um I heard a lot of
people volunteering me to do work um if
there is a an indication that comes out
of this that there is work that will
lead to experimentation with this
signaling and scale I am happy to do
that work if it comes down to three or
four I don't know how many cycles I have
for that so just in terms of you know
people volunteer community some of them
just want to let you know I tend to also
agree with it Becker I'm leaning toward
um spin plus fact plus encrypted PN is
the right way to go I mean I know we're
not calling that right now um I think
that seems superior to me because there
looks like there's information the
signal we can use for other stuff we
haven't done that work yet
it's like I said what can we get out of
the back of that that there's still some
research in there um but the
explicitness of this signal I think is a
gigantic win so okay going to close or
can I run back the fact you can run back
one more time Brian I'd like folks to -
Brian did something very nice there
which was he expressed what he preferred
but also what he can live with oh look
it's the screen so if if if everyone
else can do that we just got a fairly
strong direction from our area director
that he did not want this to be on our
critical path for shipping our
deliverables I need explain why so
especially if you can you know talk to I
think probably you know the option three
here option for option one putting the
variance is something that is very much
on the critical path so we need to hear
why that really needs to be beyond we
think it gets it
more sir please go ahead only event so
my preference is to have a clean version
one and mechanic depends on solely on
the encryption of the packet number
which we might want to do is this case
in pride systems okay now about the
usage I mean there was some comment
about the network operations and I can
agree that not only I mean it's not all
network operators we don't go and
network operators and asking if they
immediately depends what are they
managing because if you go to someone
just manage the interface he's not
interested in TCP at all and not about
this is it just is a little later but if
you go to someone who manage the
operation of the network and the
relation whose other network which he
analyzed on TCP he is interested in
being able to measure our DTN on the
network so it depends we are asking in
the networks are excuse me can we not
have the side conversations in the line
please Thank You Ronnie go ahead okay so
the other point was about there was a
comment about being able with this only
zero to figure out if it's quick and I
think that's tied also to the issue of
the de multiplexing that we had or that
I think we have to consider how to put
these bits worse if we put them in order
still to address I mean of course the
moment we take orders
it's out the other bits out there we
need to look at what are the right how
to put how to build the first respite
anyhow if we want to support a de
multiplexing document that's also in a
wiki the last the last point is is about
okay sorry no thank you running the
queue will be closing in 30 seconds no
hi how mortem but the race begin I'm
always shorter than like the
- - Ronnie's point - basically to Ian
and others yeah I experienced the same
thing you've go to Nanog they'll talk to
a lot of guys who are peering experts
and bgp experts they won't really care
about troubleshooting user funds that's
important when it comes to the pattern
that's changing like the unreliable
streams the a production all the things
that can change that's kind of like just
describing the day in the life of
passive measurement designers if it
changes we have to change it tomorrow so
I think that's that's that's the role
that we're in following what others do
you have to make the measurements work
if they're gonna work for all who want
more study
Brian's slides did not cover the entire
gamut please read the memo one of the
things that was studied in there is one
of the things that Andrew brought up
this word autocorrelation where you can
just look at inner packet times and
tried to tell what the round-trip time
is from that Andrew it's really hard to
make that work and the draft
points to a reference for that it's
probably even harder to make it work
with quick where we don't understand
right now what the inner packet dynamics
are gonna be so let's not I mean this is
the alternative where we don't get a
spin bit if we just look at blind
packets can we measure anything probably
not but that's research not engineering
oh yeah so my choice was being number
two
quick and v1 I can live with encrypted
packet numbers and the back thank you
thank you if folks if if you have the
profits for quick view when I would
really like to hear why it needs to be
v1 rather than a negotiated extension if
you want to speak to that briefly please
do let's get the large-scale experiments
going that people would like to see sure
but but that presumes that people will
actually deploy it in v1 so yes
okay so the queue is closed back there
at Brad got in just under the wire the
folks in the queue 1 2 3 4 yeah you've
got 2 minutes each and absolutely no
more I will be timing go Thompson in his
comment I think we've been sold the
limit before in this case we don't
moving out the shape right women is so I
have a slight preference for for three
Thank You Donna I would support the
additional speed in the R&D one these
can allow the network operator to
measure not only the end-to-end on three
but also by using the FSC 8321 also the
performance measurement of it so
important portion of the network of the
complete terror activity so this can be
useful for to expect thank you
we're doing really well Praveen I wanted
to clarify a question the comment that
media made we do run some large online
services and we will be able to do such
experiments at scale the other thing I
want to point out is that the primary
use case was the cloud where you know we
could run quick in the data center for
other use cases other than HTTP because
it's a choppers transport
so it's certainly useful from that point
of view as well and we can do those
measurements in terms of preference out
of these options to is the preferred but
we could live with three thank you
suppose I are I think the option one
into a facetious because they're
actually joined together the version is
not in the short header and the
experiment that Brian is running uses
the IP address is the key it is very
very possible that we're going to run
multiple versions even before we deploy
an RFC version of quick or as bad
versions the second point is that I
don't know how it could be option three
either because to have a supported
extension the middle box would need to
be able to peek into the initial box and
maintain more state per connection
that would also infringe upon maybe so
it must maintain a map for a connection
ID and that might affect the design
decisions in maybe changing connection
ID each and every round trip time if a
like a servant and client wanted to do
that as a as a privacy preserving method
I have other points as well they're
gonna make it brief I'm concerned about
the differential behavior based on spin
bit that might be offered by network
operators I'm not sure what the
implications is that our network
operators done things like deployed
these be middle box proxies before which
I've kind of sped up TCP I'm not I don't
understand that well enough and I don't
think that's covered well enough in the
draft and I don't think this meets the
engineering bar either of including a v1
right now this was tested for example
limited situations like flow control is
disabled version control is disabled I
would like to see it kind of test in
real-world traffic environments like
HTTP realistic h-2b flows among multiple
concurrent requests with HTTP to
transports before it actually can be
included in V button so I don't think
either of these options are actually
like real options
it's about before you go just a
clarifying question if the extension was
not negotiated it was just you know each
each side opted into using it with an
extension in the extension framework
would that address your concern you
don't think that extension framework
exists right now in our packet format so
we would have to design that extension
format I just for this particular spin
but which might push us back like along
and so I think this has privacy
implications not because of the fact
that hey we had we need it's exposing
our TT but it prevents us to from doing
all these other things in quick based on
like the fact that we middleboxes want
to be simple and use an IP address a v
double as a mapping proposal whereas
we're considering connections is not
quite doubles and there's a mismatch
between the endpoints what the endpoints
consider as a connection identifier and
what a middle box considers an eye
connection identifier so it is not
possible to remove the
because short headers are supposed to be
small and is efficient and so they will
never include the version so there could
be multiple versions on one pipe that
ball and I think that and it could be
multiple connection IDs and five one
five double as well so five double does
not make sense okay thank you Jonah I
see you back in the queue ago when you
get to the front can you as put your
editor head on and speak to how this
would integrate as an extension I'd be
interested here your perspective and
you'll get extra time don't worry please
go Eric nygren Akamai I think actually
following on to something so I said at
the end I think it's worth thinking
about adversarial and kind of what some
of the consequences could be and I'm
curious what vendors are thinking about
in terms of when they might start
looking at using this for controlling
flows and trying to optimize flows
rather than just using it for passive
Diagnostics cuz I think the risk there
has a significant ossification risk they
could turn this putting this into v1
from being something that's kind of a
research experimental what happens with
it into something it really becomes an
engineering question and that kind of
pushes me along with Ian's quest
perspective towards thinking we should
really experiment more and figure out
exactly what we want and therefore I
think I'm leaning really strongly
towards option three even if we don't
know how to do the extension part yet
thank you
next scroll first I would say Christians
that I email the lists this opinion
which appears to be that we should um
that we should reserve the bits in this
back so first let me say like the cost
here primarily is I guess three things
the bits having to rearrange at this
little bit to make room for this the
cost of like doing anything the D
editorial or working group work to like
actually do the specification and of
course the potential privacy loss if
it's a problem um so the second thing I
would say is like this entire project is
like like some level experiment what I
mean by that is like you know we're like
we're designing this protocol and then
we're gonna feel pieces of it and to see
if they work properly and like get
things don't work properly then we're
gonna think about so like um and and
then that could still happen between now
and v1 so I don't like actually like III
feel like a little bit like the you know
like we don't this works like if our
objection to know if this works the way
everybody thinks it would be good idea
if it did work the
the weight is even with that is to like
actually it's like put in the protocol
and like I'm like lucky old acquaintance
even worked or not um so I mean like
yeah otherwise you'll never know if it
works so so I guess it seems like if
you've just she needs is like bad idea
in principle that's one thing if there's
actually we don't for works we should
like do they think we're doing
everywhere else um um I guess one thing
I hope Brian will say when he gets up
because I'm actually not particular
clear on this point is I don't
understand I'd understood that basically
if clients didn't participate that
Brian's measurement framework was able
to process that that fact properly and
was able to nor the clients won't resume
or participated and if that's true I
don't see why we need negotiate
extension clients either do it or don't
do it was over as your do or they don't
do it and like rise measurement
framework figures it out it that's not
true I'd like to understand that point
but if it is true then these questions
and Russia extensions are irrelevant and
the only question is do we define the
submit do we make room for the bit and
and have somewhere to find the semantics
of them Mike they ship Akamai I'm
actually here to make two observations
about the short header and the first
bite first off the signal is quick
actually is not just for that structure
to 0 you have 0 something 1 1 0 as
currently defined in v1 so the signal
that it's quick v1 is 4 bits out of the
first byte of those remain ok so we will
get rid of some of those or be able to
assign them other uses then we have the
3 bits of the type field currently the
only thing we communicate with type is
the length of the packet number and as
part of the existing packet number
encryption proposal we were going to
move to borrow it for that anyway so
we're not doing anything with those type
bits I would I'm kind of leaning toward
3/8 that we block those bits off as
reserved and let's do an experimental
RFC if people want to play with it bond
and wool room we'll figure out if it's
something we want to make into v2 in the
future so to be cool when you say block
off you don't mean put them in the
invariants you mean just have them
undefined in v1
thank you and I think would be a very
bad idea put them in two variants the
ability AT&T
it's been a long exercise but I think
there are a couple of things that I
wanted to say one is related to
architectural principles that discussion
took the right direction basically with
the opt-in and with the explicit
signaling and I think it's it's the
right way to to avoid guessing in future
protocols and the second one is more
process between the between the
experimentation and in the the ability
to to do the privacy analysis I think
these were two things that kind of gave
proof that that this thing makes sense
so I personally think that we should opt
for spin bit in MV 2 we should we should
put it in V in MV 1 I'm sorry in V 1
with the even if at the risk that we may
do a little bit of a privacy analysis
for an extra bit or so I think it really
needs to be in general I will at least
take what I was going to come up and see
was my opinion which was going to be
number three at best and not for would
not sorry not not two or one because I
think two and on both put the spin bit
on the critical path and now with the
Ender hat on I will say that that's
actually a real issue yet still trying
to shoot for November and it's become
increasingly clear to me as we go
through this conversation that there are
common cases here and there are edge
situations that as we start writing this
up the shoes list is going to explore
again and I'm terrified of that we just
spend a whole week trying to really trim
it down and really get it under control
and if you have to repeat the exercise
again and again that's not a farm
well it's gonna happen anyways but I'd
like to not add more fuel to that
explicitly the on the on the you asked
about the negotiated extension the
believer is now off go sorry I turned
the timer off the the we don't have a
well specified mechanism yet we have we
agreed in Melbourne in the rule that's
something like that would be useful to
have but we don't yet know if it's going
to be I don't know yet if it's going to
be encrypted or not we haven't decided
on that VM decreed on that we don't know
if that's going to be interpreted
subsequent versions of quake or not any
design that we put in here will have
implications on what we end up doing so
again if we put if you go to number
three I am again I'm starting to get
concerned that we end up poking other
things that we want to do and it's going
to delay all that other work that we
need to do it's not have applications
for sure and and and can you speak to
the idea from an editorial perspective
of reserving the bits for future
experimentation is that feasible I think
you can dissolve the bits I don't think
that certainly doesn't mean issue doing
that we preserve them increase them
Nissan Easton ok it sounds like Brian
wants to address that so let's keep on
moving
so yeah the Decker's point yes if the
one end point it opts out it's extremely
easy to see that that happen in the past
there's no points but this is negotiated
extension it's just yeah it's onerous
all right if we're looking at going too
far in packet numbers aren't encrypted
packet numbers we have these bits in
type that v1 will not use for anything
anyway and we will have to grease them
and if you want to grease them you can
spin them to grease them right you can
probabilistic this is this is useful
grease right this is one way to look at
this with respect to I can I'll read
that is there a clarification question
from the chair I thought as an
individual I disagree that that spinning
is greasing but keep okay yeah right
yeah great so we can have that
discussion over if you're um the I
continue to
believe that the two is the right choice
here um again spend it back encrypted
packet number with respect to well three
would be an extension that's not a
negotiated extension what I would want
to see with 3a is for thingy the chorus
back to essentially refer to the
experimental document non normatively
to say this is the experiment that we're
using this foreign v1 um if we do an
experimental but the document with
reserve fits otherwise you know there's
no reference to it and basically the
people who are going to know what's
going on about that other people in this
room the other thing that I would like
is through a wiki or some other thing or
maybe on the list is to get a feeling of
how many people would it would
participate in the experiment in three
because I don't need an experimental
extension to do it myself I do it myself
right now just by hacking people's
implementations right so so Brian you're
off the clock
um yes I keep on hearing people say we
should put it in quickly one and my
impression is is that they think that by
doing so they'll get deployment of the
spin bit and I don't know that that's
the case
so I need to know I'd say yeah I am NOT
stating that putting it in quick v1 is
guaranteeing deployments I think that
putting it in an experimental extension
guarantees less deployment than putting
it in quickly what I think we should
well once the queue drains well maybe
it's yeah but that's right that is mine
it's not deployment guaranteed it's that
these two are in an order right and I
believe one of them has less deployment
right so so you know chair head on so
far I've heard a number of people say I
prefer quick v1 but I haven't heard
structured are even as to why I have
heard a lot of people also say I don't
want it to put it in v1 and the
arguments seem to be more structured for
for not putting it in there so if we can
explore that relationship that would be
really helpful to help us make a
decision yes I mean that's my answer
okay yeah thank you that's helpful we
couldn't just let me on it on to that
one say one thing is more deployment on
the endpoints but the other thing is
also what support says like you also
need a way to actually know where the
bits are in
read them otherwise the experiment is
useless given we don't even know how the
extendibility wood frame would look like
I don't think that it's actually an
option it's not an option I understand
at least I also don't really understand
the difference between three eight and
worship one because if you reserved the
bid and then you have another XE that
defines the bits I don't think that just
writing the word experimental on top of
the VRC actually changes a lot for other
people and even if you put it in v1 we
all know you can still set them to zero
so that's the same as they won't be
reserved what I was hoping our everyone
really is that the RC would say the
server-side should or must support the
spin bit so you give the decision to the
client chrissteele Hutchinson Mike
reference I'm not writing the preference
is option 2 main reason is I wanted just
like Brian said I want a reasonable
sample size and it because to
experimental would be there won't be
enough and the reason we actually do
this now with TCP X and we use it for
early detection of congestion and that
in turn then feeds upgrading the network
so suppose the point is if you if you
make us blind
then we ever have to it's sort of just
in time you know efficiently cost
effective management's of a network is
about just-in-time upgrades if you if we
can't we don't know that we need to
upgrade until it's too late it's about
customer experience if we upgrade way
too early then we've deployed capex when
we don't need to thank you thank you
you're going I want to come back to this
point that was just made about what we
can gain from TCP sequence numbers and
some of it could occurs to me that if
you had if you look at a flow of TCP
sequence numbers and X you are inferring
it signal directly from stuff that
happening that is making up the extra
data exchange
whereas spinned it is an independent
signal
irrespective of your other sexual
connection progress so you can tweak
that way more independently
it seems so and so it looks like we are
all assuming well-behaved clients that
don't try to game whatever the operator
does think about people looking at oh we
are going to do measurements but
probably you're not just going to do
measurements and say oh we have this RTT
but you're also going to have certain
assumptions or maybe reactions so I'm
wondering whether we could take us take
some time to investigate what in the
video flow can do by lengthening your
period which is easy to do maybe short
shortening this to chortling you're
expected RTT is more difficult to do but
if you have one or more one client one
connection is the set of colluding ones
how they can actually manipulate or
drive at work behavior I don't think
this has been investigated and so we are
just making too many positive
assumptions at this point so this is why
I will probably for my site even though
I don't have a strong feeling it I don't
have any any bets in here I probably go
for option number three for three a the
main question is if you reserved bits
now and you need one of them later how
many bits would you want to reserve and
would you take this back so I'm not sure
that we drilling the bits of a three a
is necessarily future proof okay thank
you you're it's one of the mentioned
when we set up this conversation a few
months ago that was one of the items
that we called out explicitly was you
know how can this signal be gained what
are the systemic effects and we didn't
really see any response to that
so I share your frustration that that
wasn't explored sorry you have a slide
of course you do
oh well maybe maybe in a little while
okay thank you go ahead Ian I wanted to
comment on the negotiated extension and
the exact approach that I am proposing
we we use we have a way to change quick
it's called person ago she ation this is
an excellent opportunity to use it right
out of the box opposed to waiting and
like trying to MIT B to and realizing it
doesn't actually work so I actually
think this is an excellent test that our
version negotiation is actually
functional and so I'm specifically
saying we should like define a four byte
quick version that is run concurrently
with quick v1 and
you say that you are using that version
which is in the clear and like very easy
to look at assuming you actually do get
to an intake from a middle box
perspective then that means you are
using the spin bet and define our bits
and defines how you are using them very
clearly so there's no none of this like
we might be greasing it we might not be
yes it's just like these four bytes
means like we're using the spin bits and
this is how and that's kind of like what
I have in mind in what I well so none of
these things work good connection okay
well I mean worried that it doesn't work
any better or worse with connection
origin it is this effectively what
you're proposing three be sorry I'm
saying that's my embodiment of how I
think three should work okay that's what
I intended three to be yeah I want I
just want to mint to version and say
what it means so the next part of what
this is like from the version you can go
yeah I mean in many ways you can say
it's like very very similar to the
quickly one option but now I have a
version that defines how I'm using with
it which means where yeah it actually
exercises the first negotiation
capability and I think it's dead center
do you have a clarifying question you
you said earlier that if HTTP was
defining a version to run over quick
would in a case like this it'd be
defined to run over all versions of
quick of this type because that makes a
serious difference on the points the
operators have made about the sample
size that's necessary for this to be
useful for them to do their work Mike
Bishop editor had on I think wouldn't
start guide Mike I think what it
currently says is that it uses a version
of quick with TLS was the handshake
protocol so that is a set of quick
versions that would be supported by the
draft I want to make one or clarify and
comment that if we if we do do this and
we
as part of quick v1 I prefer the
reserved the bits in the transport dock
and actually I separate oculus privacy
goo
I got up to say I think Google Mark said
I don't think there's much of a
difference between gonna be one and and
not making experimental in terms of how
much dependable yet I don't think if
being in v1 will influence our decision
to it so my preference is for three a or
three B or something around three L just
want to make one other point is one one
of my big concerns is when we get beyond
measurement and try to actively manage
based on this and how that will mess
with flows that aren't standard send and
receive AK flows you can very briefly I
would like to reiterate the observation
during the talk that these bits are as
our all header it's Liberty protected so
a lot of the fear that we have about the
meddling that happens in TCP just we've
already built away to make that happen
so the space of things that you can do
is way smaller so we have 20 minutes
left
Spencer's reserve a block of time at the
end I think for me personally the the
Marius comments combined with the ins
were quite illuminating and the way I'm
thinking about this and I'm happy to
have this shouted down is that it's
either we would would spin bits and
quickly one now see how that experiment
goes and with the understanding that it
is an experiment they might get pulled
out before the end of quickly one port
shipped but the more viable solution I
think is is along the line of what Ian
was talking about where there are two
quick versions one with spin and one
without and we see how that goes
because potentially that means that the
one would spin but is not on the
critical path for the one without spin
bit which I know makes our ad a little
bit happier so
how do people feel about that what what
I think Ian has roughly proposed very
specifically me accouterment so the
difference is that was using the version
number you actually also give the link
assuming where someone would be the
server has to support it then using the
version number means the the server can
be chilled and say I want to use the non
spin bit version but that also might
cost you around return range okay I want
to just interject one thing there in all
of our discussions so far we have not
talked about mandatory support the
assumption has always been that it's
opt-in on both sides so I'm just as a
chair I'm scared that this is gonna
knock us back several steps in consensus
said I think the the difference between
those proposals it's really just a tiny
the details that's you there is not big
no big difference okay first of all
there's there's actually an observation
here to this whole thing I think it's
cute that we are pretending the quick v1
itself is not a gigantic experiment I
really like Ian I like the more I think
about it the more I like Ian's proposal
separate version was Bend it's because
one of the things that scares me about
quick v1 is that we are going to have a
lot of version ago she ation experience
with the implementations that we've done
here because we're doing first
negotiation as part of our Arab testing
and there's not going to be a lot of
exercise the first negotiation next
mechanism in the wild so having to like
I've been saying for a while we need to
have two separate versions I thought
those were quickly won and quickly too
but maybe they're quickly won and
quickly one spin right like so we get to
kill two birds with one stone here and
that's seems efficient to me um was
there there was another question yeah
Ian going in okay I think one of the
things that Laura's mentioned on the
side that that we should at least
consider is is that it does this set up
a marketplace where a network operator
could decide I'm going to block any
quick that doesn't allow spin and I'm
one of the network operator who is
deploying boxes that will
let through quickly one spin and knock
quickly one who actually wants um the
visibility that you get by looking at
TCP and isn't just walking quick to go
to TCP is not doing the right thing for
their goals right I think the the risk
of blocking quick v1 in um in favor of
quickly one spin is so much less than
the risk of just saying at one
block and go with zzp that it's not sure
yeah
sorry thing to do okay we need to get
some hums and some ad comment so we need
to keep all these comments very brief
that I'm going to cut the cube go quick
question to the chairs we can separate
out this quick version does that mean we
change our goals at the moment of what
we are doing in terms of driving towards
p1 by November because v1 is version 1
yeah this is this would be a secondary
in the separate version yes a separate
document yes I believe so and my hope is
that this is after v1 not along with our
eyes that see em as long as that's I
want to make sure that we are in
agreement or at least we talked about
that very quickly because it's gonna
cause again us to have to do it must be
it can't be before us because it's
requires we want to be done but so if we
want needs to basically be done and then
because this is going to be a dip that
says you know you take you gone this is
the new version that then you spin stuff
so therefore you know it's in hand or
effort so I guess I'm still confused
about what's being discussed frankly
yeah amazingly enough I mean if it's in
so we've already agreed that it if it
were to be in v1 it will be optional to
actually execute and so if it were in d1
then you would like only have a no wire
signaling you either send spin bit so
you would not sense movements and so
there's a question about whether you
wish to have an explicit network signal
that what you're saying spin bits or not
and if you do then we should have one if
you don't think we shouldn't have
if we don't need one then there's no
point putting it in there's no point
having a sever version and if we do need
one all arguing a second that a separate
version is stupid but um but to make
that some perverse to me even to make
these other versions can be plausible we
have to make sure that we remove the
header to flip those bits and will not
screw around with those bit we don't
like colonize those bits in you know if
you want and so I like just don't see
much material difference between but
between the more the worker will have to
do in the like in the case where it goes
in v1 and the case where there was a
separate version if no one gives a
about you passing alike at all because
specifying that these the bits is not
difficult um separately if we do think
it's important to have a new tab i
solicit I mean indications on the wire
like please let's not do a separate
version like the idea we have to have
like orthogonal like if like a comet or
explosion two versions of your
leadership feature like is if I got
trivial features is crazy
that's why we that's why we reverse
reverse the extension sorry an extension
negotiation mechanism in the first place
this is a classic use of why you want to
set your negotiation if you want to have
like if we want to do exercise the
version negotiation function let us
define quick one and quick V minus one
okay one minute each row Gavin first of
all 3b is still experimental and I was
not sure if I understand that because it
I is it a regular version understand
will it be different transport version
or is it be an experimental RFC that's
why is it creepy and not a separate I
didn't that's just to preserve the
numbering so people don't get convulsion
no so from our point of view two and
three be are okay the reason for three
that the experimental I think that I
will talking about the transport but
this transport is typically some other
stuff about they are defining what
transport are used in a network and they
will reference such documents and they
can reference the document that we have
without being bit or we spin bit but
they need the document to reference for
them and and I assumed that Winfrey
being we means that people they will
progress they in parallel and not
see Quinn should be well thank you super
tiger um so I think that 3b is there are
a lot of dragons lurking in there which
like it seems quite simple as its
described but it's actually like
probably way more complicated it's not
as simple as the mechanism Brian
described his captives like just look at
the five double and you're done you've
been making a lot more state for that so
like before anything you need to see
what the solution isn't find out over
guys dragons and I think that anything
that we do even for a separate version I
think if the if a metal box is going to
look at it it will practically have to
be an invariant and since it has to be
an invariant I'm kind of opposed to the
idea of putting an experimental thing
inside an enduring and so this is like a
circular argument here but I think that
as heads proved like this cannot be this
cannot be a separate version and this
cannot be made birdie there so we need
to come up with a separate version
mechanism we need to put in the work to
do that if we are if we want the propose
of this and this might push back other
work in the long header format exactly
what a minute congratulations hi I
wanted to address Marie's comment about
the extra round trip I was going to
exhibit in in practice I expect most
experiments at least initially to use
the L surfers advertisement mechanism
and so the peer would just learn about
it by HTTP and then like do it the first
time basically we just not do it once so
I don't like there be actually any
practical hit on user experience and
then on the the idea of negotiating
extensions the extension negotiation
mechanism that I have in mind is
encrypted because above most the
extensions I want to do are I want to be
entirely encrypted and so I don't really
want to use that extension negotiation
mechanism to negotiate something that is
outside the encrypted envelope that
seems weird to me so I mean we could do
that but the point here is to like
actually give the path information so
why are we trying to do that negotiation
in an encrypted way when the whole point
is to give the path information thank
you so we mean from orange so I suppose
done should result in two because it
really is the word
- we forgot to participate to the
interrupt day on so on but currently we
have a separated code for the spin B and
so it is very tricky to make interrupts
just this is the result of jacket on
here you can see by the table running so
we were trying to put the spin it in
order aversion enjoy at the same time
the developer or in committing a new
ocean on the big table it's a waste of
time for hops apart Thank You Sanjay
Mishra Verizon some are going back to
your question about earlier you add that
you're not heard as much about this
structure around by you need in v1 so I
think really the the question is that
the deployability and municipality they
cannot go hand-in-hand so if you are
looking to standardize quick and divide
in the network that allows operators to
maintain the same level of service as
they do today you really need to
consider that the immense ability aspect
as we did by quick so if that goes with
v1 then we stick with v1 and I'm not
really sure of having a 3b option really
helps so I think I would stick with
where we are and as Brian earlier said
that you know the implementation itself
was not a really big sort of adding to
the structure of the of how long it'll
take to add this thing so we should be
we should be able to add this into the
current release I'm not really sure
about 3d and unfortunately I'm seeing a
big divide here between those that are
develop designing quick and those
actually would be managing and running
the networks so I you know the dividers
actually increased much more before the
call started and where we are right now
it's unfortunate
thank you so we're gonna take a slightly
different tack
can we see a show of hands in the room
of who is implementing quick now okay
keep them up if if if the spin bit were
to magically appear in our specification
tomorrow would you would your
implementation be emitting and honoring
that part of the specification if it
would please keep your hand up if it
would not please take your hand down
okay
so there's some wavy hands that aren't
sure good there's a hand back there and
there's a hand here which are the same
hands kind of you two are sharing hand
in that sense right and there's a kind
of a wavy hand here so three wavy hands
and one combined yes or implementation
and one over here okay oh that's a wavy
hand too and oh okay the we tried to
filter that out we I think we mostly
filtered that out so there there's some
interest from implementers in at least
experimenting with this we had a back
and forth about you know how we would do
this with it as an extension it sounds
like there are more questions that that
brings up where we're not really sure
that that's a viable path forward so I
don't really think we can make a
conclusive choice about that now if we
were to land Brian is your poll requests
still clean okay all right so one thing
we could do is land your PR and have
some experimentation see how many people
actually emit and then work with it in
the next few months and make that part
of the implementation draft goals and
then evaluate that later on and make a
decision about whether it remains in the
draft and I want to so I want feedback
to that approach now I would that seems
like a good approach going for a hike
Ryan Trammell that seems like a good
approach going forward one other thing
that I heard in the room is that there
is um tied to the emerging consensus
around encrypting the packet number
there seems to be a lot of support for
Veck and I would volunteer to do another
PR to add the back we write when when
the encrypted packet number man for
purposes of sanity I consider that you
set for discussion yeah okay that's fine
yeah and I'm happy to I'm happy to clean
up and land one bit spend I'm trusting
the people in line to be as brief as
they possibly can it's just addition to
your poll of who the implementation
implementers if it wasn't in b1
just experiment sorry we're on the pole
if we did we really improvement in the
future if it wasn't in v1 okay so same
question if you're an implementer and we
did it sometime in the future would you
admit these bits
I see wavy hands from from the Google
gossip front and a wavy hand from Akamai
still and still a strong hand from
Microsoft and a wavy hand so I same set
of hands I don't think that change it
moves the needle please go quickly wrong
even I think I think that the problem is
that the ones who are once it are not
the one that implemented the client-side
the one to transit the vet work and
eventually they will ask for that fro
from the product either by specifically
asking or by blocking I mean that's what
will happen so you can say you don't
want to implement it doesn't mean much
it depends what will happen actually in
the networks once it started to be multi
pro-german got editor hat on this will
make life very difficult
not not just in terms of managing the
text but in terms of mechanisms we I'm
really hoping that after the ITF we
start you know getting into the packet
number detection issue and try to land a
solution to that this sort of stalls
everything up until we can resolve it
and I we're talking about resolving it
today no app affected like the ones a bi
was landed the document has to be
self-consistent yes yes and we have to
figure out how to make sure that
everything else that lands after this is
going to be handling standard okay I as
a chair I have every sympathy and I want
to do everything I can to support you as
editors but we cannot make editorial
convenience a gating factor for the
decisions we make I'm sorry
Barton yeah mom Thompson the spot what
you said I agree with with general Islam
we're talking about polls this one would
be another one of the ten it's not a
long one I agree I understand and I
don't see any problem with a separate
document frankly if I could make a
statement really quick just to inform so
that everyone it knows what the chairs
know I asked for three minutes
if the hums were not going well in one
minute if they were I believe we have
five minutes and we haven't taken
these hubs do the right thing
sensitivity I bet your poll had an
interesting results that would be also
interested to hear the results of you
asking the people in the room who run
networks
how many would use the signal to measure
RT t if it were available that's a good
question who in the room runs a network
try not to do try to duplicate
yourselves if you can okay and put your
hand down if you would not use this to
manage your network in some fashion okay
couple hands go down must then stay up
okay Lars Lars I get from the floor and
others chair but sort of what you
proposed but I think what I need you for
both of you changes how we work right we
we don't land the arse and then on land
we try hard to get consensus for the VRS
and once we have consensus we let them
in just because look Martin and John are
ready it becomes really difficult to do
the unlearning and so I object that we
change the process that we have in the
working group that's worked quite well
in the past just because this is a hard
topic so one thing we could do is to
address that one thing we could do is
leave a couple of combination approach s
suppose we could reserve a few bits have
a separate document that describes how
to use those bits and if at the end of
our process we agree that this is indeed
useful and is actually getting implement
our take-up we can incorporate that into
the spec before chips as we want more
consider just want to say that not
implementing end points but an
implementing measurement devices that
use this now we'll be happy to to
contribute to any any work at least be
done now in the short term to get this
moon okay so the most recent genre you
went on very quickly though very very
quickly this just changed equations on
my mind because I think this means that
we're gonna actually disgusts in the
issues now but we now know quite a bit I
just want to make everybody middle my
bed of that act you're gonna have to not
just identify shoes with this particular
proposal you're not trying to solve them
right so I think the two as I understand
it the two possible pairs for
and defer put in a spin bid in v1 or to
reserve a few bits have a separate
document with the idea that if we prove
it as a viable thing that gets
implementation support and and and we'll
probably have to have a rough consensus
further down the path we'll fold that
separate document into quick v1 does
that sound like the two options we have
I'm looking along dr. fector so those
are certainly options also I'm not so
I'm I'm not anything so I'm not any
clearer
really unfortunately than when we
started this morning right so it's it's
welcome to me I was sort of hoping that
we were concluding on this today and
it's very clear that we're not going to
conclude this today it seems like and
and therefore um so I don't Spencer who
when it sometime has questions and his
mind that would help him are you kidding
they might help me too oh okay so I
think I have one minute so that means
the house must have gone well enough I
want to say a couple things this is a
way this I think this is the most
positive conversation on this topic that
I have seen since the public since the
RC on what we learnt pervasive
encryption being an attack was published
I would like to thank the working group
for that and I would like to thank the
chairs especially for that because even
though all the transport working group
chairs take a lot of crap these guys
managed to still stand out so I would
like to thank you all for that
I want to say
one other thing so you know so I got the
I got the you're not have a real fuzzy
feeling about the direction yet do you
do you to have a real fuzzy feeling
about the ability to close on this by
theorem let's say you on the mailing
list having out some water so I would
summarize this me today as sort of it's
it's very clear that there's enough
interest from a variety of people to use
the spin bit and understand what it's
good for and and and learn more about it
that I think sort of the option for
right no spin whatever I think rather
than those the minute we want I think
that is out I also think the option
wants the midden invariance is sort of
out right so that's that's nice I would
agree with that um if we haven't added
three other options that would be I
think so we're looking at an approach to
manage give people the ability to
experiment with spinning some bits in
quick um as it gets shipped without
delaying the rollout of quick v1 and as
the great sort of trying to find an
approach at an ad hoc manner here and
I'm at least not coherent enough this
morning to to propose one there to hear
that that you have proposed if people
think those are concrete enough ways
forward that we should have a hammer or
some some show of hands or something on
them we can totally do that
they said a or E or a and B a or b or c
yeah okay let's just let's hum these out
and then I think we're gonna have to
cuddle come it out and then we're gonna
have to talk to our ad and then see
where we go for clarifying questions
very very very quickly option a is is
that we will not put a spin bit in
version one of quick what you put it
maybe in a future version but that's a
separate working group or or a separate
consensus it's not now
mountaintops can you clarify the
difference between a and B in terms of
what it is this working group will do
between now and the end of the year
that's a great question so if we choose
a this working group will not talk about
spin bits in our current scope of
discussion because we're talking about
v1 right now if we choose B will
instruct the editors to reserved some
bits I think Brian was if he's willing
spin up a separate document we will talk
to implementers and then put that the
use of that document on the
implementation drafts as a a goal not a
required goal obviously but we'll try
and encourage the implementers to
experiment with it and we will at some
time
you