[Music]
[Applause]
I have sown everybody welcome to our
working group meeting please take your
seats and we'll start okay good
afternoon my name is Jen and I remind
you about working group draft about what
Enterprise multihoming and I really hope
I it's the last time I'm talking about
this because I've been we've been
talking about this for a while
so the problem is how enterprises could
use provider assigned address space and
be multihomed and connect to different
providers history so first we presented
this draft and Berlin and I'd have 96
and you can find the link of the 40
minutes presentation I think I made and
they can remember quite interesting and
quite long discussion on Berlin and the
drafts had been updated and it was
adopted and here we go
it hasn't been like many changes since
the draft since then and the last few
times I sent updated drugs to the least
I couldn't recall like real feedback so
the last update was done before
Singapore because yeah we found some
issues with logic of generating source
prefix code forwarding tables which
potentially could have caused loops so
the logic was updated and now the draft
agrees with what so destination source
routing says so because this draft has
been around for a while I believe but
I'm a biased here that it's good enough
so I have a question to the working
group like any other comment suggestions
how can we improve it and if there is no
comments or suggestions maybe we can do
call and obviously because half of the
draft is actually quite a lot overlapped
with v6 subspace I assume we need a v6
ops to review it if you go for the last
call
so since Chris's culture I'll be running
the document from my opinion it's ready
for a new plus call and unless there are
objections I think out started after ITF
so if you have any objection questions
please let us know thank you
next up is how you song talking about a
network telemetry framework
it could have to everyone and today I'm
going to talk about our new initiative
on setting up a framework for natural
telemetry now network TM tree has become
a mainstream term in network community
but perhaps many people still have a
different understanding on what scope is
it and how to map the existing work into
it from its a Greek root telemetry means
remote merriment right so in this sense
we believe the main purpose of telemetry
zucchini network of visibility so any
technology that collect data from
network and analyze are made to some
mermen donate it's qualified as
telemetry in this sense conventional OEM
techniques uncovered in ITF can be
considered a telemetry but as network is
evolving we seeing we sink we need a new
telemetry which will also have some new
capture characteristics associated visit
the the key motivation of this works
that we are seeing the network is
evolving toward intent driven and
automatic with aim to reduce human labor
how to improve natural agility and
performance and also optimize and
natural resource efficiency in in this
new network texture that natural
visibility is a very key to it
therefore we should promote telemetry as
a first class citizen in network
technologies and protocols and also we
think that telemetry work should be
better unified consolidation solidarity
and integrity to support the future
network architecture currently the OEM
tools we have such as SNMP are is a
phishing and insufficient to support the
future intent driven Network because
it's based on the are low frequency
polling and the command-line interface
is also lack of
courage timeliness and accuracy that's
required by the you know the intent
driven Network also there are many works
existing works in idea but they are
mostly fragment fragmented and scattered
through different working group and we
have a many different piecemeal vertical
solutions which are hard to compose into
a cohesive one to support the one single
integer even ng
there are also some repetitive and
redundant work so we need to collaborate
and consolidate the work together and at
least we understand what's up okay
apologize but for interruption but I
think that your characterization of
existing om is very subjective because
again for example if SNMP is is an I
agree SNMP is not the right vehicle to
export om metrics or measurement results
then we have yang models and yang models
for being developed and almost complete
for BFD and yang models being complete
for performance measurement mechanism
defined at ITF and other organizations
yeah if you're looking at either
yesterday I acknowledge those works I
qualifies that those are new telemetry
technologies this perfect our new I
don't say they are outdated or they are
not useful anything about that this work
is just so tried to summarize was
available and map it into a clear
framework to help us understand and then
we can fill the gap maybe then I would
suggest not to use characterization like
inefficient insufficient scatter it and
unorganized Greco let's wait till end of
the presentation okay okay
so yeah
that's why we want to set up a framework
to normalize the concept terms and all
which can help for the technology and
the standard development so basically
the new telemetry requires to
continuously monitor the network and
also dynamically changes the monitor
point and refocus on moenay's point we
need to correlate the data from multiple
data sources and we need to support in
bandar measurement in addition to the
passive and active environment functions
we have and also you don't we cannot
afford to collect all the raw data we
need to take advantage of the program
ability of the network's data playing
devices to support customize and approve
masala data
excuse me I have to interrupt you are
you know because it's inaccurate it is
wrong please are you implying that
active measurements are not in band what
what's the question no you say you are
saying that in bent measurements are in
addition to active measurements I'm not
saying they are not you I say we need
all of this and there are some existing
worker has already addressed this I
acknowledge that and ok finally we need
to make sure that telemetry won't
interfere with a data playing device
performance
there are many use cases I want them but
there are many doing the intent
reinforcement also the fourth analysis
and prediction and the performance
optimization and finally for the network
security some new characteristics
including the push based data collection
instead of a poor based and streaming
data base efficient encoding as model
based for better our software on
automation also invented the connections
a new emerging
technologies and that also we need to
support custom and on-demand data and
the tools also the protocols technology
need to be better integrated with big
data analytics and machine learning
tools therefore we want to set our
partition our telemetry into three
planes namely the data plane telemetry
management plane telemetry and the
control plane telemetry and in each
plane before the partition but
partitions our telemetry into five
components starting from the data source
to the data subscription and data
generation data export and the data
analysis based on this partition we form
this two-dimensional matrix then we can
map the existing work in a ETF into into
this map we can see some are already our
standards but some are just the recent
proposals it's on this figure we can see
what's a you know what was missing and
how we can map I'm sure I miss a lot for
existing work here so they they will be
eventually filled into this figure and
also it helps the system system
designers to understand how they can
integrate a complete solution so to
recap so army proper size here is to
promote promotes the significance of
telemetry work in ATF and we need to
keep when we design the new technologies
technologies we need to keep in mind the
big picture in the future we need a more
automatic of network architecture which
requires we have a you know a better
interface with underlying tools also we
want to make sure that ITF becomes the
leading standard or organization in this
area so we try to formalize all the
telemetry related terms in ITF and do
the proper technology classifications so
therefore we can consolidate the
existing work and get the future work
of course it's a very early step we have
and we need your help too to finish this
work so thank you very much question
Mahesh Jatin and Lonnie is orient so I
definitely support the effort that
you're trying to make to try to
consolidate the work I would highly
encourage and this is with my chair hat
on on the net count working group where
a lot of the work is happening as far as
telemetry and yang Bush is concerned is
for you to take your presentation and
bring it to the net Khan working group
because you will find a lot more people
there who can probably give you more
guidance in terms of the effort that's
already going on there
yeah thank you given multi area focus of
the framework this is the intention so
our routing is not the only area was
being presented and worked on agreed but
I think in general since from a
technology perspective it would be at
least on an informational basis informed
a networking group even if the work has
happening other places Rick Tyler um
plus one I was actually going to say
exactly what Mahesh just said I think
this is important work but it needs to
span all the areas we're not very good
in the IETF at collating big topics that
span many areas and and somebody owning
it and and making the documents come
together so it is always a challenge and
I really hope we can come together and
say these big spanning visionary areas
of work need to happen I know some of
the language is contentious but that's
what you sort through you know so big
plus one thank you and Greg mercy City
I really wonder why we started using
telemetry rather than OEM because om can
exist on different layers it can be data
playing control management plain but if
we prefer there
refer to this telemetry fine in a
document I would encourage not to use
any marketing or any drawn conclusion
comparing different technologies and
making conclusions that one technology
is better than another and I would
suggest to look into their more
requirements site rather than evaluating
technologists what we have today because
I you probably will find that
requirements are more needed especially
to fill the gap requirements and gap
analysis rather than saying that this is
better than that but in term of so om
and telemetry I think minus 10 is a
telemetry will be a more broader term
power different aspect of the entire
data collection this consuming loop so
but maybe if we use our OEM and maybe
that's a how some is a narrower meaning
that's why I think we needed to at least
to normalize the language we are using
when we talk about the term we both
understand what we are talking about
right this is Linda dumb problem wahwee
I think this is a good work and I think
IETF said earlier when you think from
bigger picture and the loss of network
being deployed today is not just one
segment of VPN one second of this can be
many many elements involved and like
like oh not that Enterprise is talking
about everything beyond my Java is
network problem and we have issues and
some some like for example the traffic
am seeing are from CDN so the source
address are different and going so net
by the time I need to monitor my network
the source address doesn't mean anything
anymore
so having some kind of bigger picture
view of how to look at the entire
end-to-end telemetry I think is very
useful I am all highly saline so in very
large environments were we've deployed
forces this has become a niche for us we
are very good at this we so please
consult with us when you take your next
steps okay there's a lot of mechanisms
that we built in into the data models
into the protocol itself the
publish/subscribe that thresholds how to
describe events that can be subscribed
to etc yes I can watch that let's see
that we have the help we need
thank you Thank You Linda okay so today
I'm gonna talk about some general
problems we face and when enterprises
are moving the workload to different
places and here we call network to cloud
cloud here just want to clarify this
quantify this cloud means my workload is
running on somebody else infrastructure
meaning that I don't have control of the
physical infrastructure and so this work
is combined with memento from Verizon
Christian from Orange and Andy malleus
and myself okay so it's just a little
bit introduction the introduction maybe
to brown so bear with me I'll talk to
you about more nerim scoped IETF work so
so the work is driven by the challenges
facing by enterprise in today's world
and I've been going to own odd for last
year and most of enterprises today need
to move the work load into the cloud
simply because the availability of the
location and here oh and II see cloud it
doesn't mean AWS cloud it can be the sd1
endpoint and which is moving
basically the reason Enterprise is
putting together sd1 is because they may
have some locations very close to the
end customers and they need to network
to interconnect them and those endpoint
they don't stay there very long they may
stay there for a short period of time
and how do we interconnect them together
so own arc five years ago they created
this sd1 so allow the enterprises to be
able to interconnect together but after
many years of deployment they find out
actually sd-1 over shorter distance
works fine you put your end devices
together you can have the IPSec tunnels
and utilize some other network and be
able to utilize all the resources
together but when you have endpoint
cross city or cross continent the
quality of service is getting
unpredicted right depending on whatever
network you're running over so so that
that they look at more and more about
utilizing existing network like
enterprise today they may have like VPN
network service provider network already
interconnected together many branch
offices and on-premise data center and
now they have some dynamic locations
either insert party cloud data center or
maybe the sd1 they need to integrate
integrate together um here is an example
of like in Oh knock twice a year they
have enterprises communities putting
together their highly desired use cases
and they put vote which one they think
is the most important to them and only
the end-user
enterprise users are allowed to work
together on those use cases and vendors
being like on a different community
being able to support that requirement
so well the highly voted use case is how
do we interconnect the existing network
that which is already connected like our
own Prem data center of partners data
center or branch offices
interconnect with some dynamic locations
which can be in public cloud or maybe
it's sd1 in some remote location
temporarily so the goal for that is
because they want to push them the
workload closest to their customers like
some of the enterprises today already
moving 40% of the workload into the
cloud but those cloud actually is
temporary only used for special purpose
most of the key data storage key
application as to stored on prime like
for example Identity Management the key
essential data they're still managed
outside so so this is based on this use
case
here's talking about when we talk about
cloud services there are actually you
can see distinct two type of services on
the top is an example of AWS service is
a cloud operator the offer service
directly to end-user to consumers to
enterprises you can create different
kind of services you can create network
service you can create database service
and another type of service is managed
service the managed service meaning you
have third party which can be network
operator or could be Amazon's partner
they manage the resources for the
enterprise they can also utilize some
other cloud operators so for this I'm
here if I just give people an
introduction started this work for
example here on the left side is about
how do we integrate our MPLS network
with the last mile being the sd1 ok and
second projecting I'm EF is the cloud
service architecture meaning as a
service provider managing getting the
resource from different cloud data
centers and be able to offer that to the
end-users utilizing existing network so
it's pretty big project but the key
takeaway from the
and from the previous use case is really
about the MPLS Network Tuesday and they
have large deployment they have proven
to be scale and have quality but this
kind of network do need to be augmented
by some dynamic part of it like sd-1 and
especially in them and that free
environment and then there's a need to
be able to connect dynamically the
tunnel points so so let's go back to
like enterprise using last mile as the
one to connect to that the neck dynamic
point which can be in the public cloud
of partner cloud so using them thus sd1
approach you'll end up having many many
s t1 tunnels and those tunnels when you
have just one branch need to reach the
clouds it works fine when you have
shorter distance it works fine but when
you have multiple locations you have
your own prime data center you have
partner data center you have branch
office only to reach to those dynamic
locations the number of tunnel you have
to manage is getting really cumbersome
doesn't scale so a better scale scalable
position solution will be integrating
existing a network Enterprise are
currently using
they are currently already
interconnected by the provider VPN which
can be leased line which can be out to
be here are three VPN and using those
Network leverage this network to connect
to the dynamic location which more
scalable or they can have this kind of
SD well aggregate kind of thing be able
to aggregate bunch of locally sd1
tunnels and using their either leased
line or provider network to connect to
the cloud this example just show another
variant of the traditional SD one the
traditional SD one is more about two
endpoints and be able to utilize all the
resources
available aggregate them together but
when you have workload in dynamic
locations being third party data centers
and your workload can be shifted from
one location to another location and
also you can connect to your workloads
through multiple ways like using AWS as
a example they allow you to connect to
the workloads through Internet gateway
allow you to connect to their workloads
through their virtual gateway which is
IPSec tunnel terminated at the gateway
they also allow you to connect through
the direct connect so you can connect
them multiple ways so that means the sd1
becomes not symmetric anymore as the
traditional sense of sd1 ok quickly
I'll just go quickly um so basically um
in many ways here I'm just talked about
a little bit proprietary implementation
OSD one not many vendors several vendors
I should say extend existing OHRP for
creating dynamic tunnels among the sd1
switches st-1 HRP originally was used
for IP address ATM address resolution
and when used in the sd1 environment is
is try to resolve your VPN address your
public IP address and your IPSec keep so
that's the extension by different
vendors have different way to extending
that on HRP and for the cloud
interconnection or reaching the dynamic
location then the resolution is added
with the third dimension not only you
need go through the VPN address to your
public IP address to your IPSec key and
you also need your private address
within the third party data center so
this resolution become another dimension
and the another key part is when you
have different locations you have
different applications the remote had a
node actually many of them are built
with application-aware so
they know what kind of application there
are for example for the voice IP
application you can resist reside in
different locations and depending on
different scenario they may want the
traffic to be routed certain way and but
the first segment
maybe's sd1 is the internet you can now
control how the traffic around it but
once you get to the provider domain and
and we can have segment routing or we
can have some other method to traffic
engine in the path and using some kind
of method to distribute the key a label
to the head end or you live with lots of
problems in the provided domain and be
able to allow the traffic go through
certain paths already talked to some
people in the Senate routing group see
that being the use case for the sd1 in
second the routing okay here's my last
slide okay so why we do bring to idea
right a couple of reasons one reason
just to bring you the some of the
discussion being down at an own arc and
some of the trained and what Enterprise
want and breaking down to detail the
problem what IETF can solve is mainly
about how do we do the resolution
protocols properly maybe we should have
a standard resolution protocol instead
of each vendor enhance their own
existing code and HRP protocol which was
that many years ago
I think Andy was the chair for that two
decades ago and also allow those mini
data centers located in different places
to route with each other
agree that evpn has been there to be
able to route all those mini data
centers but here is the case where you
have many of them and many of them can
be floating and how do we route them
with each other and to determine there's
any interest here so I'm here I'm
standing here just many two can advocate
this kind of issues and requirement and
gaps and whoever I interested please
talk to us thank you
George and next up is Stuart Bryan
talking about enhanced VPN well if still
standing the box and all right so I want
to give you an update on the work we've
done on enhanced VPNs known as VPN plus
so the purpose in this discussion is to
explain that version two that we've just
released is it was an editing past aimed
at producing a much more coherent view
of the problem and the solution so we've
tidied up the English which I did up the
structure of the document and we think
it is a much easier to read and
understand what we're proposing we're
now actively also working with two
service providers and we've been taking
some of their input as well we're taking
any of their input so the purpose of
this slot is to discuss some of the
issues that were raised at the last IETF
that require some discussion amongst the
working group so remind you what the
architecture of the solution is the
underpin of the solution is an enhanced
data plane so something that's
supporting flexi or TSN or deterministic
networking or a sophisticated cue
architect qmq priority architecture what
we want to do is to create VPNs that map
onto a specific and dedicated set of
resources that are set aside to support
that Pacific that specific VPN so what
we are trying to do is to do a tighter
underlay overlay integration then is
classically done with a VPN on top of
that we will need a control and
management system that's sufficiently
flexible and scalable and in particular
capable of doing individual VPN
measurement so management but we are not
focusing on that in this document what
we want to do is to get the data plane
such that it can certain can serve the
needs of these new services so the as
with all things there's a spectrum of
requirements in particular one of the
key ones we're dealing with is isolation
of the traffic that that's running on
the different VPNs so we want to provide
better isolate what our customers wanted
to provide better isolation that allows
new applications to be deployed rather
in a packet network rather than needing
a dedicated network so if you look on
the Left we have ordinary statistical
multiplexing if you look on the right we
have the absolute isolation that you
would get from a dedicated network for
example a flexi network or a completely
allocated network we're looking for a
pragmatic solution somewhere in the
middle and I kind of like to to think of
this in terms of what we did with pseudo
wires with pseudo wires we took the view
that if you wanted a real absolute copy
of the type of network you wanted then
you bought a real one but actually for
most applications most of the time you
could be not quite that's not quite as
perfect as a real dedicated network but
nonetheless solved the problem that the
customer had in an economic way so we're
trying to do the same thing with
isolation which we're trying to design a
system that is good enough for most
users but doesn't have the expense of a
dedicated network again in terms of
performance guaranteed latency and
enhanced delivery there the the scope of
deterministic networking but
deterministic networking isn't is not a
good story yet in terms of integration
with VPNs so that's one of the things we
need to do a short bandwidth is commonly
as provoked
short bandwidth is something that is
commonly provided with VPNs but we think
there's some scalability concerns so
we're trying to get the best of all
worlds and Lou
go ahead Lou Berger
I completely agree with your statement
the only question is is where do you
think it should be done well I've got a
I'm going to comment about that we don't
care where it's done we've got to
comment about why we think at least a
framework should be done here let me get
to that slide and then we can have the
discussion okay but that's I'm not I
don't mind where it happens okay so the
next thing that we talked about is
segment routing with resource allocation
and identification so CID allocation
based on resource requirements is a key
differentiator for this work so we want
to tie the the SIDS to resources
detailed resources so for example
specific cues and and virtually so going
forward we plan to document the resource
allocation and identification based on
service requirements we've got a draft
in spring that describes the the the
enhancements we think that need to
happen we're sour it's really
unfortunate that that discussion clashes
with that the deterministic networking
discussion because I think both
communities need to be need to be
thinking about this
we're also anticipating do some Riddick
o wind protocol work probably somewhere
in LS are scaling so we are SB TTA an
MPLS TP we would need to set up a
complete end-to-end path of reach
service that requires unique resources
that is to say a label per path on each
node in order to bind specific resources
on a particular node to the service now
that's not needed with ASR but currently
sr has no resource allocation sort of
service and we need that to be in place
so what we're trying to do with VP n
plus is to add the resource reservation
to to to SR it we in the context of this
type
go so this allows us to mix resource
reservation with resource aggregation
along a service that is to say at some
point along the service you may need a
specific resource in another point along
the service you may be quite happy with
taking the general pool of resources
because a relatively crude aggregation
is good enough so what we're trying to
do great um okay so with this statement
adding resource reservation to the
segment ruling so does that changes the
paradigm segment ruling creating the
state specific to the segment ruling
channel that is resource context yes all
right and indeed if you look at where
this ends up if we need to have resource
at every hop for a particular service it
really becomes folds back to a single
end to end
LSP with all the reservist also is that
it so but we think that actually you
won't need to do this because in some
cases you will require a dedicated
resource great year we have to do this
in other cases we think that it can be
it can be shared at some level of
granularity and in other still other
cases it will depend on where you are
along the path whether you're able to
use common resources or or
dedicated resources so for example if
you have a very lightly loaded
high-speed sector it may be perfectly
adequate to just take your chances with
the with the pool whereas in other
places you may need specific dedicated
contention sort of basis help so where
does the framework we don't remember but
at the moment we're just writing a
framework to describe this problem so we
can all get our heads around it so the
end of the day the chairs and the ad
zone the decision but here's how here's
how we analyzed it we don't think it
belongs in spring because the design is
broader than segment routing all right
it includes other potential types of
method of delivering the the service we
don't think it belongs in debt net
because it's
not simply about determinism and we
don't think it belongs in T's at least
currently because the current T's
charter specifically says MPLS and this
is not exclusive to MPLS so what we do
need an incubation group to start this
work in which is why we have brought it
here and because this is an incubation
working group so we're not quite ready
to ask for this to be given a formal
home we need to do another pass on the
document but we think we're close to
asking for this work to be given a
formal home in the IETF and then to ask
for working group adoption so that we
can work on it collectively and I don't
care which of your working groups or
this one it goes in okay I didn't know
if you're already first blueburger key
go back one slide back one so I think it
would be great to find this a home I
think it's really good work I think it's
important stuff I actually agree from a
technical side with everything you've
said
I think debt net needs the the function
yes and needs to worry about defining
how it does the encapsulation and I
completely agree with you that there's a
larger discussion yes here and it's over
our chain I think it's great to have the
only thing I don't agree with is that it
doesn't belong in T's I I think while
there's clearly a debate going on right
now about the intent of of T's that
probably should be clarified when I when
it was described to me at the time and
babies who describe it they're both in
the rooms they they're welcome to
disagree with me it was that this is was
supposed to be the central point for
traffic engineering architecture in the
IETF so that we do things that are
consistent and reusable and that's
that's why the main purpose of the group
I know it's important to find this
protocol at home and we know that it's
diminishing in terms of importance so
we'll put it here because we're not
gonna have much work in that area so I
think it it's squarely in belongs with
my understanding of what the Charter was
supposed to say
well we have to fix it we need a
discussion about this because when I
read the Charter the very first thing it
said was MPLS and we need to be able to
deal with other yeah so I think I think
there's an cleanup there but I think
everything the the resource control
piece fits in very nicely with the work
we're already doing there so I just want
to work where the experts are if and I
think with the chairs and the ATS can
suggest which one we go to we will go
there do it to los comment oh so in
routing space traffic engineering has
very particular resource regression has
very particular connotation what she
meant is really soft resource
reservation so you don't do one pass the
reservation is done off bus on the
controller level so which brings tears
Jesus I heard - it is the big tent you
want to do reservation through
distributed signaling great you want to
do it through central control great you
want to do it even maybe through other
mechanisms which is imposed that's great
certainly the aggregation piece is a
fundamental notion of hierarchy that
we've long worked on and it's I think
you got the description exactly right
and but sometimes you need to do per
flow state whether whether that's done
through an orchestration mechanism a
management plane or distributional thing
that's all that's all part of the Big
Ten my point to us there's close
cooperation between two working groups
if we decide to work so I mean do I have
to go and present it in both from now on
then I'm absolutely fine with that I
just need a hope Greg Merson is the
everything that that is great and it's
long time do you I'm probably would have
changed a little bit
this statement about reservation in a
segmented routing domain probably we'll
put a question mark saying that may need
because again that's something that
probably now at this time is too early
to say that it's requirement it might be
one of the solutions are other solutions
we welcome the feedback on the design
yeah
but at the same time that working group
chairs and IDs to figure out where and
we can start the work thank you
in in in concurrently I don't have to
wait for them to decide correct Telecom
um if you link a resource to a label and
I think you're talking about
Els piece and LLS piece I think that was
what they differentiated in the early
days of MPLS but this is not related to
spring thanks sorry just what's the
difference between this VPN Plus and
let's say is a slice so I say that again
what what's the difference between the
CP n plus and is in a slice I was slice
yes what they're very very similar and
we've kind of been skating around this
because we didn't want to get involved
in the net slicing debate and argument
because we think that this is a universe
yeah useful technology in its own right
whether or not next slice thing ever
happens
so we've deliberately skated around this
this could be a pert is a perfectly fine
underpin for Network slicing it's also a
perfectly useful technology if next
slicing never happens nothing of you
were speaking and routing ad question
for clarification in case that work was
going to result in multiple documents
being produced to you plan or what are
you intention to prague has them in a
single working group or are you open to
i wasn't clear to what was your position
we will need we will probably come here
with an is is document next time that
clearly will happen in LS are we I've
already got a spring document to explain
that relationship that would clearly
belong in spring what we need is a whole
for the architecture document which
brings all the shows how all the pieces
fit together so my view has always been
you do the work where the expertise is
and I'm looking for the correct home for
the expertise to work on the framework
to start with okay thank you okay thank
you okay next up is Karsten Rosen hallo
and he'll be talking about some testing
results for of ti RFA implementations so
I don't know who of you know the NTC
we're an independent test lab and we've
been running multi vendor inter ability
tests of transport network innovations
ie ITF draft for the last 15 years and
so this year we've we finished our we
focused our tests around segment routing
PCE EVP ends obviously and we created
like a mock Network right area network
data center network peering and services
connecting all of these and the hot
staging just finished last week so I'm
happy to report some of the results here
that are related to actually one draft
two drafts that are related to this
working group we had 21 Venice joining
us so there was a good group
representing the industry and total of
75 engineers working to get this test
done in two weeks and the results will
be published soon at a conference in
Paris so what we care what I'm covering
here is two drafts regarding
segment routing topology in independent
loop free alternate and macro loop
avoidance and in in total we were able
to test 12 vendor combinations in this
environment of course we set up segment
routing domain we had like a ring in
topology in each of these cases we
tested both MPLS based segment routing
and as our v6 data plane and in each of
the cases we used is s with s our
extensions to get the routing done so if
you look at this diagram so basically
there are four nodes involved in our
ring topology and if we create an
emulated link failure between node 1 and
node 4 of course there needs to be some
rerouting in the traditional fast
rerouting case which we also tested over
segment routing it's fairly
straightforward only one segment ID is
required in both directions to guarantee
a loop free alternate and ntil fa
because you know the way the protocol
works to SIDS need to be introduced node
3 and node 4 need to be inserted so that
traffic is forwarded correctly so this
is the test scenario set ups one and two
and a third one was testing shared risk
linked groups as our LG so we basically
set up a cross paths between cross link
between node 1 and node 3 but and we and
then we connected to 2 in and it's SR LG
and so like link to shall only be used
if link
what's the number link 1 is also up and
running and then we failed link 1 so
that note 1 had to decide okay I cannot
use link to anymore because it's part of
this shared risk link group in that case
as well it was necessary for node 1 to
insert s IDs for node 3 and 4 to prevent
any loops and link to was not considered
so these were the three scenarios and
that's what we asked the venice to
implement or
the other way around that's what we
discussed with the vendors in the last
few months since we started in November
to prepare all this and not surprisingly
all winners participating supported FRR
so that works pretty fine over segments
routing only half of them supported the
topology independent solution and only
one of the vendors supported TI LFA with
sr v6 so across all of our tests not
only in this specific case but across
all of the segments routing tests we
found that s our v6 support is very
limited at this time and it seems also
maybe service pilots are not asking for
it so much outside Japan so only one of
the vendors also was able to test the TI
LFA with this shared risk link group so
that doesn't seem to be implemented so
so much yet verification however SL just
signal towards a statically configured
of the device SLG signalling how was it
done I was oh I don't know I don't know
how it was configured other multiple
options okay yeah so we were also trying
to get author of the draft to include
SLG specific information in the draft
and it's still being discussed okay so
we're going to publish a very detailed
report by April 10 and I'm going to get
back to you with an answer if you could
publish the link to the report the list
would be great it's it's here on the
next slide on the last slide so so only
one vendor supported the FR LG and we
had test equipment vendors two of them
who actually supported all of the
options but of course they couldn't
function as transit nodes because they
cannot forward traffic they can receive
traffic they can send traffic but they
cannot forward as a kind of transit
through their devices so that limited
the number of test cases a little bit
and I hope next year we'll have more
combinations to be tested and we'll have
the chance especially to see more as our
v6 so the report will be published at
this URL shown here and
we have quite a number of other draft
coverage from spring from the mpls
working group from six men and from
other working groups here as well so are
there any questions a cylinder Cisco
Systems I was just looking I missed a
little bit of it but it looks like for
your scenario with the SOL G's the the
the point of local repair could just use
local srl G's so an act in answer to
Jeff's question you really wouldn't need
to single them for this specific
scenario
that's my question yeah well I think
since only one when I supported it I
guess you know it's of course it's my
team who ran the details of this test so
I guess they actually started with the
most simple scenario so it could well be
possible there was no signalling
involved any more questions thank you
for taking the time coming here we would
love to see you more and possibly with a
bit more data so now it's policy of indc
not to disclose who supports what but at
least a bit more Jesus what didn't work
would be where you will disclose
everything in terms of especially for of
the positive test results we've never
disclosed failed test results because
what's the point you know people should
go back to their labs and improve and
not be punished but we always disclose
by name the vendors who do support
things positively but currently with a
review process or the timing was a
little unfortunate by 10th of April the
report will contain all the vendor names
thank you and looking forward to seeing
you again here thank you so next up is
Igor Lewis chef talking about an idea
for ingress filtering for asymmetric
routing name is Igor Akamai first I
would like to thank the chairs for
finding the time for this talk and such
a short notice my goal here is to talk
to you about some
early work that we're doing it's
flickering nice so I'll start with
presenting you with a problem that
everybody here or most people probably
are very familiar with but it's still a
problem after so many years so I guess I
have to continue with trying to
encourage people to solve it and I'll
conclude by proposing a possible
solution it seems to work to me but I'm
definitely not particularly committed to
any pennies one solution it's just
something that as long as a solid all
right ingress filtering we have here
each of the routers is actually at
separate AAS we have a yes X its
originates prefix P it's probably a
customer of B and C and ABCD are all
peers although they don't all pair with
each other
so X advertises P to B and C which
advertises it forward to a a uses
decision process and somehow comes up
with B is the net hub it also talks to G
but no prefix P is exchanged there all
right so BC p38 says that you run a
secure network and for that you shall do
in grass filtering and BC p84 give some
alternatives what to do for multi home
network which X is and most of the
complex networks are the alternatives
are configured all manually and that's
very nice that's one of the alternatives
it's probably very labor intensive very
error-prone will not work alternative be
used strict RPF and in this case so if
we're looking at a able only allow
traffic from B because able to see that
or B is where it would forward the
reviewers traffic that interface
obviously
work so feasible path is another
alternative proposed by DCP 80-84 which
says I should look at any announcement
and use any of the interfaces it has
announcements for as valid interfaces
for ingress for P and that works well
very nicely
there is also lose RPF which basically
says if anybody announced be anywhere
then it's all good in that almost not a
filtering at all so it was all very
nicely because it's a very symmetric
symmetric routing here
so let's look at asymmetric routing what
does it mean X wants to receive packet
only from B it does not want any ingress
from C at all but it wants to be able to
send to see and to be the only reliable
way of doing it is don't announce to C
because if you do you may receive
packets and that's not what you want you
don't know with policy seafarers and
even if you try to convince see that
they really should consider to allow
outlet to make an exception for you so
you may want to do may do it and they
may want to help you but they probably
have a whole ton of peers and trended
that they will have to have the same
conversation with so basically
asymmetric routing is not a good sign
for RP basically única unicast RPF and
the main reason is we use the same
signal bgp announcement for two separate
purposes one is please send your traffic
here and to allow me to originate to
basically send from here from the same
interface and those two could be
separate purposes so what ends up
happening in the internet is well
it doesn't want to screw his customer so
maybe no no ingress filtering their a
doesn't want to mess with traffic from
seed so no ingress filtering here and
that means that anybody anybody can
spoof traffic from P and our little
hacker here and that sending traffic
from D is very happy that's kind of the
state of much of the Internet today and
that's not good now for people who saw
that well just announce always a noun
that's a good idea and say you could
always prepend which is already which
already had a danger that C will send to
you it's not really a solution in this
case B and C do P R and C is considered
for configure to actually honor shorter
paths so it sees that pass through B is
shorter than directly from earth because
it's gasp repents so it does not
announce to that not advertise to B and
that means if X does send traffic
through C B will not be able to apply
feasible path or a filter okay so first
I want to encourage people to look at
this problem again and it is important
we do want to run a secure internet
solving ingress filtering for more
people will first reduce operator
headaches and I mean for people who
actually don't care about operator
heydays well that's what Talia Noland
Scotty for the Belgian and your medicine
it will in lead to wider ingress
filtering deployment if it's worth for
more people that means the most secure
internet and now the headache is and the
bad guys there is some work happening
right now in parallel in absurd group
where is enhanced European proposal
it's a good proposal it does solve a
number of cases it doesn't solve all of
them by far its basically works on a
very very high level by not meshing
pair two interfaces but trying to get
paths belonging to a a sense on customer
interfaces it doesn't really work for
very large networks with lots of lots of
customers and it doesn't really work on
peer-to-peer traffic so the problem is
still there
I promised proposal for a solution so
the proposal is creating a new ingress
only saving code which would basically
act as a ingress on the advertisement
it's and it's like a normal
advertisement except it's never ever
used for actually forward in zero error
router it's only used for feasible path
RPF calculation and those advertisements
are transitive and if there is a
covering route so same prefix or shorter
that is advertised to appear a covering
route could be another ingress only or
irregular advertisement then you do not
need to advertise in in the responded to
that appear because a regular
advertisement means bi-directional
obviously because it's a new society
only routers that do support this I will
get the announcement and in terms of
originating the things the rule is if a
customer advertisement is not read
vertically be hippie peer any other any
kind of BGP peer transit peer another
customer because of whatever reasons
like I said knoweth no expert prefix
paths link capacity business goals
whatever you want then porn advertise
ingress only to those behaviors
and of course if you have your own
prefixes that are not advertised to a
BGP peer than advertising as ingress
only and that's it I would love comments
I would love see if there are people who
are interested in working more on this
in this area next up is Fred Templin he
should be presenting remotely via MIDI
echo and he'll be talking about BGP
based mobile routing for the
aeronautical telecommunications network
I'm online now do you have me you look
great we can give you very good things
okay thank you what I'd like to talk
about today is what we call a simple BGP
based mobile routing system for the
aeronautical telecommunications network
next chart please
so some background on this the
International Civil Aviation
Organization is currently building an IP
based networking system for worldwide
air traffic management and and this is
for civil aviation for managing all
flights that happen worldwide they want
to build a service that that provides
ipv6 capabilities for air traffic
controllers to talk the airplanes so I
they're developing what's known as the
aeronautical telecommunications network
with Internet Protocol services and
again this is an ipv6 based service it
will be all ipv6 from the start no ipv4
it's under development in a standards
body known as ICAO working group I
working group I as is kind of like the
IETF of ICAO again it's ipv6 based in
mobility capable
and one of the key features is what's
known as multi-link because aircraft
will have multiple data links attached
to them they may have SATCOM links a new
link called L Dax which is an L band
cellular link technology VHF links and
others that are going to be available to
the aircraft they're in different phases
of flight it could be that some links
will be available during the Continental
domain cruising other links will be
available during oceanic domain when we
don't have any cellular coverage and
still other links will be available to
an airport runway on the ground
situations next chart so I came up with
a bility sub group solution discussion
they're currently looking at three
candidate mobility solutions mobile ipv6
proxy mobile ipv6 ground-based Lisp and
the BGP based overlay approach which is
the subject of this document and we call
it a simple BGP based mobile routing
system for the aeronautical
telecommunications network it's based on
a BGP overlay network that's separate
from the global public internet BGP
routing system but may or may not be
linked to the global internet BGP
routing system with with filters to keep
up with to keep undesirable traffic off
right now I'm having pixelization there
we go
the it's based on a hub and spokes
arrangement with regionally distributed
stub autonomous system border routers
and centrally located core autonomous
system about border routers the stub out
system system border routers advertise
and withdraw airplane mobile network
prefixes and the core autonomous system
border routers are in the hub autonomous
system and they forward packets between
the sub autonomous system where routers
proxies connect datalink sub networks to
the overlay and clients our aircraft
that may connect to multiple sub
networks and then we have route
optimization that removes the autonomous
system border routers from the past when
they don't need to be in the path next
chart
so here's what it looks like
diagonally we have the the aircraft our
clients and those clients can attach to
one or more subnetworks
again during different phases of flight
the sub networks are are connect the
airplanes and the Internet work connects
the sub networks so we have native ipv6
routing within the sub networks using
standard routing protocols like OSPF or
what have you and then tunneled ipv6
across the internet work next chart so
in terms of the BGP details each stub
autonomous system border router is a
stub autonomous system unto itself all
core autonomous system border routers
are members of the same core autonomous
system the stub autonomous system border
routers advertise their associated
mobile network prefixes to the core
autonomous system borders routing using
the eg PE BGP and in the reverse
direction the core autonomous system
border routers originate default only
but they do not advertise any mobile
network prefixes to the stub autonomous
system border routers and once again I'm
having pixelation problems with the
charts there we go it's back again the
Cortana system border routers discover
all the mobile network prefixes in the
system using ibgp
and they can connect the overlay to the
global public Internet in which case
they would advertise only as short and
unchanging aggregates like 2001 DB 8 : :
/ 32 instead of the dynamically changing
more specifics for example / 64 next
chart so then we have the need for route
optimisation so hit space once please so
initially packets go from
the source to the target by traveling
through stubborn and core autonomous
system border routers which is a dogleg
path space again please
so the proxy for the source can send a
neighbor solicitation message to toward
the destination to get a neighbor
advertisement message back from the
target its space again please
this Hargett sends back a neighbor
advertisement message in next Chuck next
next place and then future packets can
go directly from the source proxy to the
target proxy without involving in the B
BGP routers and now we have a route
optimisation next chart please
so in terms of draft status this is
actually the second time we've been here
at the writing working group we were
also here for IETF 98 be a draft has
been presented at the idea working
good-by mobility subgroup and it's
active under active consideration there
as a mobility solution candidate and
what we would like to do is identify an
IETF working group to take this work
forward and that's why we're here at the
writing working group to get some
feedback from the community on that so
I'll take any questions
so this is Chris Bowers so just in terms
of just to kind of share with the the
working group are you looking to
standardize the architecture is there
any protocol work or is there protocol
work that would need to be done so in
terms of the BGP routing that piece of
it I'm thinking would be informational
because standard BGP with no protocol
work needed the route optimisation piece
is is some protocol work needed but it's
based on standards like ipv6 neighbor
discovery so I guess it's it's kind of a
mixed answer some would be informational
other aspects of it would be potentially
a protocol okay thanks AC Wyndham but as
a co-author but Fred this document does
not have those details in it so this
document is purely informational on how
one would implement the ATM network
using BGP that's correct yes so it would
be good I guess to as we try to figure
out what working group to put this in
understand like the full scope of of the
work moving forward so that it can be
you know we understand what we would be
getting into or you know what's the full
the full scope is so we will we'll
discuss that with both AC and and you
and the other authors and try to figure
that out
that sounds good thank you thank you
it's me love the color my apologies for
those people who have to see this again
they threw me out of the LS via our
working group so I went down the street
to this bar this was done the white room
no that doesn't have legal implications
that just means I was stupid um there is
no IPR here and this presentation is
designed for bgp SPF at the top a
different north could be centralized
could be other topology mechanisms for
instance dr. bugs which he presented
yesterday so bgp ALS format bgp SPF need
length neighbor discovery liveness and
addressing information lldp
unfortunately in is not only an I Triple
E protocol and complex but it's got IP
are above 1500 bytes and I'm overweight
and eventually this protocol will get a
little overweight due to the fact that I
believe we want to add some security to
it so the 1500 byte limits annoying so
still want something simple so this is a
new ether type and I'm just gonna
describe these are payloads etc not
framing and dirty or details this is
dirty enough ok the general topology is
an east-west protocol ok at the ether
level with a fee Saffy's pushed down and
try pardon ok sorry me deco boys ok with
ether left right a piece a fees pushed
down and then northbound
- and this as I warned in this example
bgp SPF okay so this is the east-west
protocol it's essentially PDUs over
Ethernet frames
the idea is to transfer link inter
device link state okay PD you can be
multi frame and it has some glorp in it
to allow that okay
and because SPF and the IGP payloads go
over the same wires what we need to
watch out for congestion okay so um the
basic TLV is got the stuff for
reassembly okay and continuation there's
a checksum because of paranoia length
and here are two basic types
hello keep alive and the capability
exchange there's checksum for the
obvious reasons here are some
suggestions that Russ Housley and Steve
Belvin threw at me and in the draft
you'll see the code I know that I have
I'm in the NOC as the media cowboys are
too so we have a conspiracy they know I
walk um so anyway the basic handshake
you get hello and liveness okay are you
there you can negotiate timers you can
move a fee Saffy's v4 s v6 s and MPLS
labels somebody shouting at me no okay
nope so um you'll excuse me that this
particular as I said was designed for
bgp SPF so the identities being
exchanged our a SNS the draft should be
cleaned up and changed so this itself as
a TLV so you can have the other kinds of
identities okay a multi-point
apologies just point-to-point and you
learn each other's max from the hellos
so we know each other and we know each
other's AES ends and we can start doing
high-speed keep alive so you don't need
BFP and then we can negotiate some
capabilities okay we have requests we
agree etc what are the capabilities
here's timer negotiation for example so
you can to tune to keep alive timers you
can say how many you're willing to miss
etc okay and you also have a timer for
the a fee Safi exchange okay so now we
know max link state a SNS so now we can
start talking a fee Saffy's there's a
general frame for it it's an Fe Safi
capability yes I'm willing to exchange
them and here are the ones I'm willing
to exchange and of course this will be
extendable now we know the a visa fee of
the neighbor MPLS label etc so we can
announce and withdraw them of course
it's over an unreliable transport so
there have to be sequence numbers and
act acts to provide some reliability so
there's a wonderful sequence number
there's an ACK so here's an ipv4
announcement sequence num number Fe
Safiye and as many v4 prefixes as you
want each one can be announced or
withdrawn or marked as hey by the way
this is the primary on my interface okay
v6 surprisingly enough 96 more bits no
magic and these prefixes are just for
the interfaces they're not right I just
want to make sure that you still not
changing tables doing I'm going to push
up to SPF or whatever's above for all
that right
just the interfaces okay MPLS it's not
very exciting you can use multiple
labels to allow one label to be
associated with multiple v4 v6
bah-bah-bah okay so you've got labels
you've got liveness you've got some
Athey Saffy's what do you do with them
push him north okay so if the ethernet
layer we don't want to do topology
discovery etc etc so it goes to bgp in
this example SPF going up to the
Dijkstra layer don't I don't go all the
way up because you might want something
other than RFC 7750 to the BGP LS shim
hi Rick Tyler didn't mean to interrupt
in the middle um talking about the
information you're pushing across it's
not routing information it's in I
understand trust me I've worked on very
similar protocols and everyone keeps
asking me about the routing but the link
information do you want to push up any
sort of metrics about that link coming
off the PD use as well as just address
you know i'm my duplex information that
kind of stuff could be useful going up
point okay so BGP LS specifies in 77 52
format for how to feed this to SPF okay
so how do we shove it upstairs you're
within the device notice each one of
these is within the device so we can be
optimistic and hope that there's a
reliable intra device transport so no
acts no sequence numbers etc etc we
assume nice fat PDU and we can cram a
lot into it
okay so we solved shove everything we
know about our neighbors up north and we
can do incremental updates so 77 52 shim
says tell me what you know
the link layer says hey here's a piece
of transfer here's a continuation etc
etc here's the count of links etc again
the ASN is the identifier may want to
change this have it be a separate TLV
okay so routing is done in the upper
layers bgp SPF is the one that this
presentations targeting towards okay so
those will talk between the devices and
discover the topology provide routing
and Bob's your uncle so I had a question
Chris Powers about is there an
assumption about point-to-point links
here or does this expect it to work for
a point-to-multipoint um as I said
somewheres back in slide 42 multi-point
is presumed to be multiple point two
points okay so it can handle broadcast
interfaces but doesn't try to do
anything nothing special
okay hello this is my solid I from
University of Essex I just wonder in
here how is that different from OSPF
link estate discovery sorry how is the
protocol you're presenting is different
from OSPF link state discovery sorry if
it's a silly question but I just fail to
see the difference actually I am NOT a
no SPF expert I'm at is is addict um but
no multicast for instance you can
can they see literally sees a ceiling of
Cisco system this is a discovery
protocol right now routing ya know
routing know what you said why is it
different from OSPF discovery hello ah
somebody actually went to the mic in LS
VR and suggested taking the hellos out
of either OSPF ania sites but and just
taking that part like and and there have
been going back to the early 2000s I
remember I think it was people at
Stanford and Inman a they have
decomposed routing protocols into you
know different you know three frameworks
yes did have the different layers yeah
yeah you're having discovery it's it's
and what yeah the three three pieces and
doing them separate and plug in and play
different ones so there's many ways to
solve this problem
Rick Taylor again I really like this
work it's very similar to some work
we've just completed in many but instead
of discovery on Ethernet its discovery
across radio systems but it's the same
problem and I just to reiterate
including some metrics in there is
really useful because although you know
the BGP might not be using it at the
moment one day we can start to get all
the traffic engineering stuff tied
together and this goes back to the early
presentation in this is it's all about
intense the more information you can get
up from the bottom layer at source the
better we take in for the other example
for the top is in BGP by the way another
example is June June Jupiter rising
where the control centralized so that it
can use very much so point very thank
you okay or who are you killed just just
to say more on is his point one should
think of this protocol pretty much like
as how BFD is to provide a generic link
level liveness
to all the protocols that can exploit
once you have the liveness detection
this is something similar from a
discovery standpoint
he should confess that his co-author
question you've mentioned label
distribution one of your slides
Eric was that an accusation no a
question yes
[Music]
why would you do sir pardon why would
you just sir
I mean it control/play an exchange
typical go unlabeled anyway because I
want to know what neighbor label you can
handle
you mean the local labels I mean what
what's the meaning of so a single label
we don't understand the use case for
this like typically you would send you
know multiple labels received by a given
router would have different forwarding
implications right so so what does hen's
you can pass multiple labels okay then
so then it starts to look more like
you're doing routing in this which we'd
like to better understand not intended
I'm just saying these are the labels you
handle with what a theis a fee label
lots of all what's the meaning yeah what
what does it mean that the router
advertising this what does it mean when
it advertises a given label for a given
prefix cable again it's a simple binding
that says a prefix has on a interface
has this label value semantics it could
be probably used from a layer 3 server
to just announce it to the first off
router or it could be used from a router
for its locally configured interfaces
it's not meant to announce an over
length of his information there's
nothing deep here and it's just one
point hop-by-hop it's not meant to take
that information and send it over other
link from this protocols perspective
there would be a job of routing protocol
this case is still unclear but we can
discuss define if he meant to use it SLO
ability protocol i would advise to use a
flag similar to beef luck in behaved a
where you start flow slow and after
you've resolved each other you could go
faster than one second yourself
sure
okay next we have dr. awesome talking
about service router routing over path
based forwarding thank you so thanks for
accommodating us and you know think of a
better day before a bit of background
for for the slights we organized the Bob
on Monday evening and one of the
outcomes of the Bob of course to the
suggested earlier mate for maybe
presenting the thoughts here at the
routing working group to say you know
what is it you know where could be a
potential place what are the potential
of work items to you know to work on and
if the story you know in a way it makes
sense but so that the debuff us and
Monday evening at 5:40 so the starting
point that we that we behalf in this
work is to start from existing PCT based
approaches that usually say what we call
a path based forwarding things like be a
bo te for instance or to the reference
as we make in draft in the sse working
group is Sdn but it field based wild
card matching which allows you to
describe the encode of paths with a
network and then have relatively simple
constant states which again with flow
aggregation which which is different
approach of doing that the the
architecture is very similar you know we
try to abstract this with a slightly
figure on the right we have some sort of
ingress are we have a control plane
communication to the PCE for the past
determination and then it walks it sent
across the network between the
forwarders to the egress on the right
hand side the paths of the benefits and
I'll come back to those later because
some of them have have been demonstrated
in in realizations is what we call ad
hoc Malik house which which is the the
creation of multicast relations at the
inquest are based on existing path
information potential paths a direct
path mobility repointing pass very
quickly and therefore you know no anchor
points in the network predictive
mobility we saw presentation on Monday
in the Bob of unpredictability where
where information is disseminated to or
sent over Canada is flickering quite
funny it stopped the resource management
that can utilize things like the pro
coding for multi-source multicast we saw
presentation on this on Monday as well
but where the resource management is
done between the interests and the EQs
or a fast redirection of upper layer
protocols through pass repointing this
redirection scenarios come from some of
the ongoing 5g word for data center
based control plying in in in 5g
networks for instance they're so
existing work the only one I list here
there is stuff that we we have an SS
India so see working group we have in
applicability use case in beer itself
which is called HTTP multicast sorry
like I should know that mm-hmm yeah good
thank you grant mercy City what is their
roles of pce if you plan to use beer te
the the the path calculation part
calculation in pc yeah but if you use PC
for path calculation why not to
calculate for example segment routes and
then use beer without beer tea because
Beauty gives you path control so you
don't need then calculation of the path
you can use create traffic engineering
underlay and then use beer on top that's
actually how they so we we used to be
air to ear here as a reference could be
a different scenarios either PC with
that engineered underlay and beer or
beer tea that's that's going in their
ability use case that's based on that
would have say normal beer
thank you that's that's correct sorry I
should have I should have listed that
one as well that's that that's correct
so the the problem that we addressed in
in in the bobble in Monday was how to
realize where we call service request
routing on top of those are technologies
that provide quantitative and
qualitative benefits from doing so the
definition of the word service here is
relatively wide
and and starts from relatively high
level a layer 7 technologies HTTP and
co-op down to IP multicast IP unicast
and we apply the benefits across a
number of these services if they if you
take that very wide definition and I'll
come back to this in the in the in the
layer slider on the next slide we also
would like to identify the architecture
components and this is why we we came to
this working group to present this that
would potentially require
Standardization if he if he if you think
that way so the nodes and the layers of
the various messages and these obviously
are relatively high level they're not
all of those on there that we see is so
again you recognize on in the middle is
the same ink of Equus PC and let's leave
the even if you were using normal be a
bit out PC in the middle and we
introduced on on either site we have the
actual end points or peering networks on
the far left and the far right and in in
between the ingress and the and the end
point is what we call the service router
which applies different service mappings
either on L 7 on L 4 and L 3 and and
puts this into a message format which we
abstract that they are slightly
different obviously per service but
abstracted at the very bottom where we
utilize a path identifier which could be
either in the in the Sdn case we re
utilizing because of SD and matching
field the mutations were utilized ipv6
source destination addresses for the
past identifiers be a house is its
representation of part identifies a hash
of the of the service identifiers and
the potential return identifier for
protocols and for service like HTTP
request identifier and as well as the
actual service fragment which is the
actual payload itself either encrypted
or decrypted depending the the example
deployments that we've seen this is one
example how this is currently being
deployed as a monolithic solution is
over an infrastructure as a service
provider which is in in in in crane with
a typical type of technologies like you
know one of the diplomas we have is
based on OpenStack
and using floodlight for the s
controller interaction at the very
bottom and the the the red bid which are
the service rate versus the so-called
education provider this is a mobile at
computing scenario which is which is an
NFV provided softer solution at the edge
of the network and then again on the
left and the right hand side are the
application or service providers one of
these deployments is done in an
eu-funded project which deploys in
Bristol as well as in Barcelona it's
it's a fully orchestrated platform that
utilizes at semana orchestration to to
deploy the software in a pristine
municipal scale infrastructure and these
are a couple of Sdn switches and the
number of micro data centers in the city
it takes a couple of minutes to deploy
over a pristine of which tech
infrastructure it uses Sdn based based
on the the at the moment we do not have
any availability of peer components
which is why we are using Sdn o preset
for compute and it utilized the benefit
of the service routing approach shown in
two slides down it's deployed in Bristol
Barcelona as mentioned this trials
planned as well at the year so this
thing it kind of works but what we came
here for is is to see ok if we take some
of these things apart where what need
for Standardization would be potential
to see and so let me go back to the
slide before so the needs for in the
operation so all of this at the moment
is one monolithic software solution if
it took this apart into the the actual
SR so one SR in go into operating with
another SR from a different vendor we
would see in operation needs for the
general message format for the ability
for specific services for HTTP pemalak
ask or these have different service
framings the part ID mapping on to the
particular technology we know how this
would look in beer we know how this
would look in st and bid field but they
are differences another interesting one
at the moment is how they should would
look in p4 it makes it significantly
simpler what are your expectations
regards the control plane this comes in
the second one so I started with I said
I was taking the SR support right and
and so there are you know particular
things in the exchange between the ice
on the data plane that we'd say you know
a need for Standardization
on the on the control plane is the DSR
PC protocol to map the actual service
identifiers on the path ID working on a
young model for the resolution in the
past update and there's also an aspect
in particular for the rerouting
capability to update path and at run
time and therefore you know that needs
tending from the control plane side and
obviously the so the resolution request
in the past updates just for clarity
when you use SR you are not talking
about technical service right oh yes um
I used to have the acronyms on the first
slide so they've gone lost during the
other slides
some people are rather sensitive to this
a trainee sorry it's we change the
acronym in the interaction with the ITF
three times because you always found a
tow to step on it's it's and I think
that that but that's the case every time
you go somewhere the the other aspect we
see in the resource management so how
does the error and flow control looks if
you look if you talk about reliable
services like HTTP for instance now is
the nth mapping being done has to flow
setup and the security mechanism being
handled so these are all things to agree
upon if you take the source apart and
and and interoperate between different
different as ours
what are benefits that actually would
demonstrate I wanted to highlight those
because the different things that
dependent they're they're different use
case there were different trials of news
cases they are not obviously all in one
we demonstrated the the actual resource
management which allows for optimizes
management by still being TCP friendly
there are some benefits from the edge
that a resource management when it comes
to cheating at the at the at the end
point which means establishment of you
know hundreds of TCP connections for
instance we also work on network coding
and multi-source retrieval solutions
which have direct benefits in terms of
latency and and and and utilization in
the network the multicast for HTTP
response delivery which is the
applicability use case in beer has been
demonstrated in a number of demos so the
the scenarios here are video delivery
database synchronization software
downloads anything that is some what
kind of like time synchronized and it
can be kind of like time synchronized
because the the multicast relations per
response are ad hoc so therefore if
there is a
out of sync you just get unicast vitami
demonstrated it several times the
typical video scenarios either
statistical multiplexing over a large
catalog somebody is always watching more
than one mode always more than one
person's watching a popular video other
use case we demonstrated our VR a
virtual reality augmented reality in
spatial concurrent scenarios which means
you're looking at the same thing headset
therefore you have the same content
you're pulling from the server for the
event that's happening there's also by
the way which reflects in server load
reduction so the same way if you do HTTP
request suppression the same gain you're
getting on this on the multicast you're
actually getting as a civil suppression
and for services like impact - you can
suppress requests because they're
stateless fast servers where request
routing there's a use case that comes
out of 3gpp in the latest release 15
3gpp proposed to move towards a service
based architecture finally using HTTP
for calling control blind services and
we can use this to very quickly
reroute load balance to other data
centers for for service requests control
and request that pass mobility I set the
presentation on Monday for matrix
University on repointing path not only
does pass mobility but also predictive
mobility which means use that for coding
to actually have several paths split
splice the path up into pass to the
candidates and then use network coding
to to diffuse the content you can do
things like seamless HTTP session
transfer if you switch from one service
route to another one the session is
automatically continued and therefore
you don't lose what you've already a
partially downloaded we've demonstrated
secure Condor delegation without
triangular routing because it removes
the original server in the initial
request the southbound integration
that's something for those who are
interested in the Sdn it equation I can
explain that separately but give the
cute thing is it's a flow independent
state and therefore the the the T camp
requirement is constant with respect to
the to the number of output ports that's
quite neat and we can do a lot of easy
quality of service support there there
are a number of demonstrations there
so the next steps and again this is why
you know we we was suggested we come
here is to get feedback from the writing
group on the motivation does it sound
does it is their need for
interoperability just the proposition
makes sense in itself what are the
various activities that would require a
standardization the ones to be presented
around these three areas and but it most
importantly the place of work for this
what would be the right group to
petition we do have we establish
identified relations that we presented
also on Monday very briefly and be
continuous of the existing ones most
notably the SOC working group the be a
working group there are discussions
ongoing and maybe others we would
potentially identify as an outcome of
today and we will obviously continue the
implementation efforts get any questions
comments
a selenium I think you need to uh uh do
you have a document this was added late
right this one this yes okay okay it
seems like what is different here then
routing to anycast address for services
and and and all the variations of that
you know what what more is this than
that okay okay so if their work is to
happen in ATF it would be scattered
across different working groups Oh beer
extensions and applicability of sushi
girl to beer you would need PC
extensions which don't exist today so it
could belong to PC where you map the
name entries to beat strings should be
defined as well so significant amount of
work and very interesting thank you hmm
you think yeah I think about discussions
officer the be I couldn't be at the beer
meeting yesterday but my colleagues were
because other commitments I think
they're discussing around the
applicability use case they only
presented HTTP beer but the only present
HTTP beer yeah okay thank you please do
continue working it's really interesting
yeah thanks okay well thanks a lot that
closes out today's session and we look
forward to following up on a lot of
issues we were discussing I believe the
blue sheets are if you haven't signed
the blue sheets please hunt them out
they're probably near the back and
signed them so we can continue to get a
reasonably large room it would be good
yeah yeah and we look forward to seeing
you in Montreal if you can make that but
certainly participate over the list
[Music]
you