or unable to make it to London so here's
the brief agenda we're going to briefly
go over some in see too OE M we Frank
some work on om for path consistency
we're then going to look at an
alternative handling for dynamic
chaining and service in direction and
then an update on the SFC in fog
environments so a more detailed agenda
here with links to the the drafts that
going to be shown today or all the talks
and then in terms of a working group
progress summary we've made quite a lot
of progress since ITF 100 RC 8300 which
is the nsh encapsulation was published
as a standard track RFC we worked on a
new working group charter so thanks for
everybody that helped us to do that so
that we that recharter and has now
happened and approved Adrian's SFC
convent draft as a proof of publication
so that's another piece of work as well
as the higher arc OSF see submitted to
our the iesg for publication as well
we've adopted a few new documents into
the working group primarily the type 1
metadata documents one for de the center
one for broadband allocation and also
the type 2 which is the the tio V's
document that we talked about a lot of
times and then we started to make a
little bit of progress on the OEM
framework updated when we think it's
supposed to a working group last call so
encourage people to go and look at that
and provide comments so with that
I love the unison so it's it's Frank
first yeah yeah
so Frank Europe they can kept track
first yep doing it there it is
this is actually a nice focus ooh sorry
ed money to a screen is a nice thing
that they're doing these days um okay so
quick update on what has changed from
the zero zero to the zero one version of
the nshn cap draft for IOM just next
slide um so the main change that we've
done is reflect the changes that happen
in the data draft that's been progressed
in ppm and what we found was well that
it is very helpful from an encapsulation
perspective for IOM to have a structure
that only requires the parent protocol
to give us a single call point that is
sometimes a nicety so in an SH we might
be able to ask for three Co points maybe
or even four point echo points for
individual types that we're gonna go
carry in IOM in other cases it is a
mandatory thing and so if we're
encapsulating for instance into GRE you
need an either type and the UH triply
we'll only if it was one so what we
decided doing is we consolidated the
data structures in the data draft so
that you have a type field for all the
various options that are your IOM as ie
pre-allocated tries incremental trace
proof of translate and edge to edge
options into individual type fields so
that from a parent protocol perspective
we only need a single type and that is
really what we changed and reflected in
the draft here and the update so that by
now we only request a single code point
for the next protocol in nsh the other
thing that we had and we had that
discussion back in Singapore was should
my OEM mean that the traffic needs to be
kind of flag with the öbut and look at
looking at 8300 it's very clear on that
customer traffic must not must not set
the öbut and well just by adding the IOM
metadata to the customer traffic we
don't make the customer traffic suddenly
something else then custom traffic ie we
cannot set the obit for that I probably
evolves into discussion whether we want
to go and do something to go and help a
SFF to eventually then hmm still look at
is there anything else for me do we need
another bit well I think that's an open
discussion okay that's where we stand so
two more points can I just go through
this and then yeah but we're doing it
well if you want to speak up speak up
now okay thank you so you're saying that
IOM is not interested in using obit and
that's not what I'm saying if active om
is not interested in using orbit either
so why do we need orbit I'm not saying
that I'm not interested in the obit what
I'm saying is that IOM does not change
what the meaning of the obit is ie if
we're tagging I um if you're tagging
traffic with IOM and its customer
traffic the obut must not be sad if
there is om traffic that would also be
tagged with IO am the obit would be set
for anyway so we're not torturing the
meaning of the obit here and I think
that's the only thing that ups know but
what is om traffic let's use strict
nology there is active OEM there is
hybrid ilium which is in case I am what
other om traffic you employ there's been
a lengthy discussion on the obut backin
was at February 2017
that didn't really conclude the
confusing text is still in 8300 and I am
the wrong person to resolve that okay
but you are saying if there is om
traffic what do you mean by om traffic
om traffic per the 8300 Draft by the
8300 document is traffic that carries
the obut why the obit is there that's
somebody else's the session no that's
what I'm asking why oil orbit is there
do we need OB I'm the wrong person I
don't think Frank's the right person to
answer that that's that that's a
different question different question
it's not really a fair question to Frank
so let's move on it's a question you can
raise but not relative to Frank's
presentation I think it's a fair
question to the working group right why
do we have the obut I think you you
raised that question it's been raised a
year ago it wasn't really resolved yeah
so the only thing that I'm saying is
we're not you're not using we're not
changing the meaning of the obit if
there is traffic with öbut it's gonna be
set if there is traffic without öbut
it's not gonna be set next one so that
just the next slide just shows what the
header format looks like with the new
IOM type that's been defined in the data
draft that means we have an IOM type
header length and then just max protocol
so it's a very clean shim by now and we
are only asking different from what the
original version was we're only asking
for a single code point one thing that
well I wanted to go bring up again we
had that discussion
not really but briefly the draft still
discusses that there's two options that
we can go do in ons H one way is to
capsulate I um metadata into Mbita -
apparently that's also what the early
implementation in VPP is doing as open
source from an efficiency perspective
the many Hardware people that we have
supporting this graph and that are
implementing the thing like the next set
of approach why because it doesn't
really mean that unity won't go through
all the various TVs that you might have
in the NSX header because there is no
ordering there is no priorities of
individual metadata in there so the next
set of approaches cleaner and simpler
for Harper to progress because we want a
flat structure as much as possible so
that's a concern but I wanted to go and
race that question again because well
there can be devices that well are more
easily going with metadata type - they
can just skip that they might not be
that easy on skipping something that is
in the next header tell um so I wanted
to go race that question again and get
kind of feedback from the room on that
particular one before we contributor the
the I'll important somewhat subtle but
very important point about this the
difference between using next header and
using TLV the important there's two
kinds of differences one is the
efficiency which you've correctly
pointed out but particularly for
hardware but even for software it's more
efficient to process io am if it's next
header i don't disagree with your
assertion there that matches my
understanding but there's a
compatibility drawback if you have
existing deployed SF FS that need to do
ecmp
and so are looking for the pocket
they're not currently expecting to go
skipping they're going next header
packet right and more importantly if you
have existing service functions they're
expecting the next Tanner to be the
packet they work with when they get next
Tedder they have to look at it there are
only there are two possible behaviors if
they haven't been uh pretty to do this
they might not have realized they can
get multiple kinds and they would get to
just completely the wrong thing or they
did properly understand they could get
multiple kinds they would not understand
this and they will promptly drop the
packets on the floor causing us to drop
user packets and having existing service
functions drop user packets for a
feature that we want to be able to
incrementally deploy yeah for a
Greenfield financial that's going to
install this everywhere and make sure
everything does this because it matters
but even for the financials you describe
me they only need to actually check some
of this stuff at a couple of places if
you use next header existing functions
they need as far as I can tell will
break and I think that's very important
so I wanted to make clear the trade off
and now I want to hear from the room
yeah and anybody else wants to speak up
okay please yeah I apologized to the
note-taker that I didn't present myself
at first time Gregg Mirsky zt2 points I
want to make we have individual draft
multi layer active om for a subsea
networks that proposes for active om to
use what we refer as a header which can
be it set as a shim for a message I
think that there is a reason to try to
converge these two encapsulations for
OEM so that there will be a single type
of encapsulation that can be shared by
epithelium and hybrid at the same time I
pull into the earlier work of overlay om
design team that produced the OEM header
work and this will be presented later in
in their three group and called for
adoption so again I think that there is
not much difference between active om
and
hybrid to em and it's worth effort to
try to come up with a cinco
encapsulation for om can be used by
hybrid and active I am in overlay
networks in general
Kyle eros and vine so I mean you could
just have the next protocol being
incompatible with a network be a control
plane is he right if no if everything
doesn't advertise it supports this next
protocol don't add the i/o am kind of
sucks but speaking about compatibility
it's already an implantation of an in in
the metadata is it crazy to support both
for networks which haven't been updated
to support the next protocol send it in
the in the metadata incur the
performance hit maybe some things that
support of maybe some things won't but
incrementally we can move towards the
more efficient next protocol over time
maybe that's just too much at work but
it's just an idea yeah well we always
end up with this it depends right I need
to make a choice right so and that's
where we why is that we we started with
and beat up to then the hot where people
kicked in and say well alright and this
is where into yeah I want to point out
another thing I in terms of what I just
heard from various people since the
format's don't seem to be the same now
I'm imagining what happens if the packet
has both OEM information as a next
header and IO am as a next header we've
suddenly lost the implementation
advantage we wanted for using next
header because now no you've got to go
skipping through next headers to see if
there's a next header you want and now
you don't know when to stop skipping
because what are you in a special case
TCP and UDP and know that it actually
gets Messier if we start having multiple
next headers we define that are useful
for us
I can undo the advantage you get from
using next header yeah and that's all
right missing something again Greg
murski ZT Joe if I don't see the
possible scenario when we have active om
in hybrid om present in the same as a
message okay either activate om doesn't
include hybrid in which case I've got
I'm really confused or I can have hybrid
with proof of transit and something else
and all of a sudden wait you have
several next headers and and I my head
is exploding yeah I think that we can
avoid that by stipulating that hybrid om
and active am should not be used in the
same package so we can limit this one
extra header and have only one either
but Greg if it happens to be that you're
using your follow-up packets then well
the follow-up packet might just be how
do you classify the follow-up at it
wouldn't it be an OEM Holland but
follow-up attack it doesn't carry
customer data follow-up deck it is a
hybrid OEM that's it although it doesn't
carry customer data yeah of course
doesn't have to it carry information but
it doesn't carry customer data that's
why but again we introducing something
that we not discussed
I didn't present their hybrid to step
here in this group but so people don't
have a context
it's the home from Hawaii I'm just a
little bit confused in this h itself is
not a transport protocol and so wow it's
already been defined many ways to
encapsulate same header into different
transport protocols so is this some
duplication effort or this om Heather is
a mean to be consumed and processed by
the service functions so I think we're
touching on one of the use cases and we
can probably then progress to the next
presentation yeah I think touching on
one of the use cases that what I would
like to do at this point is ask the
minute taker to minute that we need to
continue the discussion of next header
versus t.l v4 IO am and o am so that we
don't reprieve reprieve this thank you
Dhruv I see you nodding so it's in the
minute so it will remind Jim and me that
we need to make sure this discussion
gets taken to the list and we drive
clarity quickly we do not there's no
point in dragging this one out but we're
gonna have to continue around the list
anyway we're not gonna resolve it in the
room right now yeah but it's dragging
for quite some time so in order to at
least they had a sense where people are
leaning can we do something like a hum
or something because I can't form a
clear enough question right this moment
sitting here as chair to get a hum that
I could interpret from the room and we
would have to confirm it on the list
anyway yeah we'd have to confirm it but
I'd love to get some indication where
people are remaining okay how would you
what question would you like a harm on
I'm willing to take a hum from an
encapsulation perspective should we go
with metadata tattoo option one or max
header approach like we haven't in the
drive okay so we're just this is a home
for preference for something like if
when carrying information like OEM
information do we want first prom will
be do you want to carry it as a TLD
it'll be a single md2 type TLV we're not
talking about disassembling there OEM
stuff no no it would be a single blob
just in the
Elvie and then the second of the
alternative will be would you like it
carried us in next ten would those who
would like to see it carried as a TLV
hum now please okay with those who would
like to see it carried as a next terror
hum now please okay that help doesn't
really help thank you like we're in
limbo and that point for quite some time
and it doesn't really easily resolve the
thickness there's good arguments for the
lines but thanks for that what we don't
want is two options what doing it both
ways seems like a recipe for trouble
then everything has to implement two
different mechanisms and know that
that's what we complain about itu-t do
it we're not gonna do that um so next
thing was really I think it's discussing
one of the use cases for IOM and well we
have it here and we've looked at proof
of concept for a couple of times let me
just quickly recap the concept and well
then discuss what we changed from an
overall an obscure perspective next
slide I think the question we did that
we do want to answer is as my traffic
gone through a sequence of service
functions and I can I prove this not say
tell my management but prove it to my
management which is an ask from the
financial community for instance where
it came from and one of the co-authors
that we have Steve he will really
pioneer that particular concept because
he's Wes well there is a sequence of
firewalls that traffic needs to make
make it through and any Duke very fine
and I'll prove that to my management in
a cryptographically secure way um so
next slide well I think you get it
traffic needs to go through ABC that
means it's compliant if it bypasses B it
would be not compliant and the
responsibility person would have trouble
so how do we do that from a concept
perspective next slide
we take a secret we split the secret
into multiple portions we get every
single node a piece of the secret and
then as the packet progresses through
the network it picks up pieces of the
secret and they'll Iran we can either
assemble the secret or we can't and that
way we can prove that the packet made it
through the various hops that we want to
go and verify or not if you look at the
draft next slide there is two options in
there from a algorithm perspective one
users shimu secret sharing it's very
light on computational effort so it all
stone from a verifier perspective or a
perspective to two additions one
multiplication and one modular prime
operation there is another mechanism
that it sort of preserving but requires
nested encryption and so the chip needs
to go and support something like a es we
have the two options one cheap but not
all the preserving the other one more
expensive but order preserving in the
draft how does it apply to us of C I
think the natural point where you do
prove of translate is in the service
functions itself
those guys would well apply or update
the the proof of transit metadata that
we have there in order to well tell you
that the particular packet visited the
particular note there is so the service
functions themselves would take care
would participate in in P ot they would
also receive the secrets update the
secrets and alikes from a controller the
results in another mode that you can go
and think of which is harder to
implement but possible if you go to the
next slide where a service function
folder or well somebody else in the
chain would go and work on behalf of a
service function that does not yet
implement prove transit
a little bit of an art operation because
well you got to go prove that it makes
it through a service function why should
somebody else do it on your behalf
well maybe you have a trusted entity two
sets where you trust the service
function folder and the link between
that and the SF so that you can have
somebody act on behalf of the SF that is
a bit of a difficult operation because
it would mean that we would need to go
and cache the traffic though and and
well we would need to cache the Quixote
metadata for the time that the traffic
traverses the SF and comes back and then
reapply it it's been doable we've done
IOM caching and again there is open
source code on that for another use case
where we hand the packet to the
application when it comes back we'll
reapply that metadata but well it's a
use case and we can go and document that
as part of the draft so next slide so
what has changed well what has changed
is the scope and the working group
Charter so that well the working group
by now is to go and also focus on
privacy aspects and security aspects and
proof of transit is definitely one and
it's been even outlined if you go to the
next slide and RC 8300 there's been a
hidden trove of transit already and as
part of the review comments that we
received when 8,300 was progressed to to
RFC there was a notion of well you guys
need to go and fix security that is a
portion of the puzzle it's obviously not
an our entire and comprehensive solution
Jim what you might go on to the next
slide hello so we've done this thing now
a couple of times so everything
everybody should be familiar with the
concept 8300 references P ot security
privacy are part of the Charter so
question is can we adopt that what we
can do we have these two slides we can
add a deployment section and just say
well
this is how would you use it and that
would answer the question that was
earlier race on the floor what do you do
with this how does it apply to SFC but
well personally I think we're ready to
go and progress that so questions war
humming more humming with 50% each
that's also more harm in coming up
gently on should I start humming now
sorry right I haven't read this one but
uh since your thought about the use
cases I think there's value here right
to to have this verification I guess um
the thing I didn't see is that this
works if it goes through all the
services basically in the service chain
right in either direction you can verify
what happens for the traffic that is mid
path basically and goes back the other
direction I'm the same how can you
verify I guess or differentiate the two
different types of traffic is that one
of these cases as cover here or is there
a way to distinguish the two cases I'm
not sure if you'd card so I think right
now the overall thing setup is
unidirectional right so the return
traffic would have its own set of
Secrets yep and would be just considered
an independent flow yep so it's not
really that you do this on a per session
basis you do that on a per flow and
direction basis yep okay got it
so but the key is that I think it
depends on the type of services that's
in the chain right so you're right in
census I'm by the way I'm just kicking
in on that we can use the same set of
Secrets both directions right so if you
want that you can absolutely do that and
say well neither whether it's left to
right or right to left I think I can go
in very much I'm gonna do however you
want see I got that but maybe we're
gonna take offline but um I guess my
point is that in the case where I guess
it's the mid path the case right
chocolate goes to a service change my
service function - and then we're
passing it back so now the packet go see
the direct
and service functions are 2 & 1 so now
you're verifying that direction you
don't have two parts of the so-called
secret then you know it's a legitimate
is the not legitimate I just
I mean maybe something's discus well did
I say that it's not a headache if you do
and do proxy behavior it is a headache
yeah yes but well people said well it's
a it's a use case it's a bit of a corner
case but go and at least mention it
which is why we go and mention it
ok ok but I I agree it's a mess and you
need to go and keep session state you
need to cash that information and if you
running this whole thing at tens of
gigabits you better have a pretty large
state table not nice what do you do if
the thing drops if you need a row go
recover state
there's loads of questions with that ok
I just want to clarify so so one of the
use cases you're thinking about is where
you've got to receive only SF in the
path right and you want to be out of
verify that that's I'm only thinking
about that specific case I was actually
thinking more the Pazzi case were you
know like a PCP foxy ok so ok I mean
we're working oh we're chance to uncheck
basically a birth verify that so but
like you said there are different cases
too right you know I just wondering that
when a transits out right now I know
what we're doing is verifying that it
went through but the key side sometimes
we may not have so I just want to make
sure we're covering some of these yeah
Greg Merson CT I apologize
what would be their intended status
attract for this document
sorry Sega intended track would it be
informational experimental or standard
okay because again yesterday in I ppm
working group we had a discussion and
unfortunately Jakob stain is not here in
the room but he not mentioned that he is
intended to bring another solution so it
would be good if
both will go in the same track that's
all that makes sense
Illya sorry
oh yeah Alice um I'm very happy to see
this work coming back we did we charter
because security and privacy and
specifically this particular work is
critical to the functionality deployment
and security right for the technology
that this group is developing as such I
hope that it's possible to have it
mature enough and gain enough consensus
that we do end up with a standard track
solution it doesn't have to be this one
drug but we need one and also to the
previous hum and such I mean we need to
get agreement and consensus towards one
approach right it we can't keep trying
to do multiple things for some of this
stuff it just increases the complexity
of the solution and there's already so
many choices there that I think hooks
you really think how about consensus in
the meaning of it and there's the
technical objections of things we just
can't live without you know if there's a
serious problem with something that's
one thing if it's not your favorite
color of the week that's an entirely
different thing thank you Andy malice
one thing I found interesting when I
read the draft is there was no real
mention of IO am anywhere in the draft
so just to confirm this could be
implemented as type 2 metadata
without IO am correct yeah yeah sure if
you just need a home where you can carry
two times 64 bits to get late and if you
want to go and refresh secrets more
frequently even 2 times 32 bits might be
good ok cool thanks ok so the whole
point where we go and what we decouple
that right so it's like I'm not
requiring that this metadata is framed
in a certain way so good point
samandriel from fi just picking up on
what came to us saying it just occurred
to me in many of the higher-order
services there is no correlation between
packets
services rendered so that means I might
get back at one two three and produce a
completely different packet because of
transformations right so if the
verification process acts let me let me
say a TCP tu a handshake is a perfect
example where if flow is kind of broken
so that some packets can be aggregated
and then new packets can be produced but
it's not breaking anything as far as the
graph is concerned or services or
arranger so it's just wondering I don't
have any objection or anything I don't
know but it might we might have to look
at that how this verification process
work because not all the packets are
actually going to end up through the
firewall farl is a bad example in some
ways because viral is typically packet
this you put a load balancer you put any
of the transformation engine that
assumption is completely broken okay I
think I'm not fully following because
the audio here is really sucky but we
can take that offline yeah I think
that's better just a thought I mean
maybe we could have a second class of
packets that are generated and you
indicate the point at which it was
generated somehow in this trace and you
work for that you require that through
transit from a generation point back to
the exit from via the chain says well
speculating here huh yeah so I think we
could take alkaline because I think
they're a different cases but when
there's epoxy and wants a little balance
there epoxy different things but I think
certain cases you still go through the
entire service change even though if the
it's been partially on both ends right
so I think when you take offline and
maybe work out some more deep yeah and I
think in certain cases and as I said the
audio here is not what you hear but if
you low balance there is nothing
stopping you if you have a sequence of
service functions they're all
implementing the same thing to go and
share the secret across these service
functions so that well if the ask is you
go through a firewall that does this
particular task it can be any instance
of a particular firewall and all of them
and share the very same secret and apply
the very same action on a packet so that
that's been accounted for and that's one
of the things that we even do so upon
part of what our area director said are
very helpful but now outgoing Thank You
alia for all your help before and I hope
we'll continue to see you as a
participant in the future but one of our
points is we're going to want to move
this forward now assuming that the
working group is interested in moving
this forward in order to fairly ask the
working group for adoption I think we
need some sense of what the working
group wants in terms of one versus two
solution and which one the I do not want
to get us into a situation where
everybody agrees we need one answer what
we don't agree on which one that's I've
seen that I've done that let's not make
that mistake so I want to ask a three
branched question and not a four
branched question right now I just I
want hums we will be taking it to the
list for discussion people can put
elaborations unwise and all that which
we need because the reasons matter more
in many senses than the preference but
we're looking for a sense of preference
I'm going to ask do we want the Mac the
low computational cost mechanism that
verifies transit but not order only do
we want only the mechanism which at a
somewhat higher cost and I'm not going
to get into a debate about how much but
it clearly is higher cost clarifies both
transit and order only or do we want
both which would people prefer to see
and when you hum you're welcome not if
you don't care but if you hum hum loudly
because it's a big room with bad
acoustics so those people who would like
us to adopt a single solution which is
the low computational cost proof of
which things you have transited but not
their order please hum now okay those
people who would like us to adopt this
single solution that is more
computationally expensive but also
captures order please hum now notice we
last
and those who think we should adopt both
solutions please hum now that's candor
and that's important because I have a
preference but the working groups nuts
matters we will take this to the list we
know where we stand
thank you all right thanks guys and good
morning everyone I'm king of from TTE
corporation and this presentation is
about the service function Ching past
sisters om this leastwise is about a
street street comes to present the
destructor so the representation is many
focus on the update of the new version
but in case you and this is the first
time to view this structure so i'd like
to introduce the civil and first and the
sea Salem is the past consistency check
om so for every SFF England's SFC and
once it received a um request message it
will take two actions
why is to send it back say um reply with
the service function information in this
repair message and anon action is chosen
as um request to its nest SFF so once
was correct all the comm repair message
it the local so is function
has can be confirmed from last meeting
we received some comments of this
chapter
thank you for all the comments and the
most important documents is how does SF
with multiple SF SSX respond to Salem
request so we update the chapter in two
parts
why is to update the formation of a
service function information sub theory
in an insecure way we add a service path
identifier field in this field to
indicate which service function has the
serum is checking and we reorganize the
location of other fields in SF identify
our fields we confirm that the service
function identifier can be lists another
part we add a new section about how to
construct a service function information
sub theory and English in this section
we many analysis the situation that
multiple service functions attached to
an SF f we are to scenario English
situation
why is magic multiple service functions
as hopes of SF key and that means these
multiple service functions attach to one
as there are several hopes of this SF
key so the service intent of this F is
they are different and service function
types of this service function heads of
these service functions may be may be
different
so all these service functioning
information included in one cell and
message Siem Reap a message every SF
information should be listed as separate
F information sub tourists in sale and
reply message
an Anderson scenario is a little more
complex
it's is a multiples these these multiple
service functions are followed balanced
that means these multiple service
functions are attached to one so SFF
follow the patterns but only once this
function will be transmitted by
particular traffic so this this might
post those functions have the same
service function type and the service
index and the under the service
identifier of all these service
functions we have been listed in the
service function identifier field in a
single in a single service function
information subtree away the number of
this service function can be calculated
according to service function identifier
type and the value of lansfield
in a subshell week before you go on to
the next slide can you clarify something
on this slide because there are two
different ways load balancing can be
done at least and there probably are
more because we allow a fair bit of
implementations like flexibility it may
be that the service function forwarder
is aware of the multiple instances and
doing load balancing or it may be that
all he sees is something he thinks is a
service function but which is actually a
load balancer talking to multiple
instances using any number of instancing
technologies who are you expecting is
going to know how many things and why do
you think it's even it may not even be a
stable number why is that a number you
want to return I'm missing something
here because it's consistent no matter
whether there's one or ten it's still
consistent with the part may Greg mercy
City since that would be SFF responding
than only information that is visible to
SFF would be returned so if there is
some other
entity that proxies processing and it's
not and SFF is not aware of that
processing if they're a proxy but I get
another proxying but again doing
something which SFF is not aware of then
I think you need to be very careful in
the wording you put in on what the
meaning of this multiplicity information
is because unless we're very careful it
will confuse people instead of helping
them okay thank you very clear then okay
meaning but we appreciate their any
suggestions and comments to the document
thank you Cattleya my understanding
after hearing this is that um yeah you
know either Joey you bought two cases I
want is s FF slow balancing to a bunch
of s FS right and I think this is trying
to say here the SSF instances you know
it's responses where if it's a little
bouncer as an SF happens to be a little
balancer that's a little balancing other
that's to me s FF perspective it's only
just the SF right so it's always from s
FF perspective right so I think that's
how I just would interpret this
particular case right I'm just asking
that we're gonna need to be very clear
about that I do have a question myself
though um just to clarify this um I
guess what I'm not quite clear it's been
a while um as in this message does it
have to flow information as well because
in the SFF load-balancing case right if
it's a for a particular flow maybe the
OEM aspect maybe I want to know which
one you hash the to alright for example
so there might be two cases I once I I
dunno
you know what are the SS instance that's
behind you the other ones that I'll have
this flow I'm trying to go where is it
going right and you didn't want who's
doing the hashing for example
so maybe you should return that as a
instance with a subtype I mean I wasn't
sure if you cover that case this seems
to relate closely to a question she has
on the next slide
Kairos and minun maybe it's the cover in
the next slide but if are we actually
carrying the identifier of every SF
every SF that could be reached on that
hop so suppose that you're low balancing
to 100 sf instances well I mean
particular if you're doing load
balancing across SF FS which is also
allowed then you're only going to hit
one of those SF FS and you're not going
to report all of the SF FS and that's
part of why I wonder about the load
balancing I guess my concern is if we
actually are carrying every if when the
packet we return carries the ID of every
SF we couldn't low balance to it could
get very large consider the massive SF
would follow the balance sickness
scenario okay
the idea is that as a point that in a
previous diagram that each SFF responds
to the query so if we have a hundred s
affairs
then the responses will come not
aggregated in a single response but
rather in a hundred responses but that's
what that's only assuming that all this
s ffs are honest SFP okay so if you need
to do something else to select
particular SFF are that performing the
same SF type of SF function then the
needs to be done somewhere in NSA SH
encapsulation not in this consistency om
back thank you my concerns actually for
not for the SFF to SFF case but for the
SF flow balancing too many sf case the
SFF could be low balancing mm of SS and
if the ID is 4 bytes 8 bytes that's
that's a lot of space to carry in a
packet and that's where fragmented or
segment it's on out okay I hear you
so now idea is that all SF will be
listed in the same reply so if that's
something that concerns you we'll
definitely think about it how to
split would it be possible and since the
load balance scenario is a little
complex so we have some issues and open
to discuss in in working group why is I
said I identify our type and follow the
panel scenario and the scene or at least
this function have seen have seen
service service functioning identifier
type in current in current job we
assumed they are the same so all the
service so is functioning identify our
lives to share the same service from
service function identify back
the second issue is the city is the sale
m4 as a POS T and in current chapter we
think the CM should be for SF key so we
suggest to add all the SF Philip
belonging to the load man's group should
be added into the service function
identify list but it is still open to
discuss well so the point is if you want
to measure the RSP you have to have the
flow identifying information in the
packet because the RSP is what path
would this packet take and if you want
to identify that you have to have the
information that the SF FS need to make
that decision now sometimes in some
implementations SFPs and our SPS are
always 1 1 well then then the question
isn't meaningful but when they're not 1
1 it is specifically because some of the
SF FS are paying attention to the flow
identifying portions of the packet
header and you need to include that
we're not going to get I would hope
you're not going to get into those cases
where reclassify errs look at metadata
produced by other service functions and
then choose to put you on different SFP
and you want to cause this
check to actually check that consistency
case I'm sorry that makes my head
explode at least but if you have to
decide what you want to accomplish and
if you want to check the RSP you need
the flow identifying information somehow
that's the definition of the RSP when it
is different from the FFP
okay okay and although it's a time to
present we are we still welcome any
comments and feedback and we hope wasn't
working consider adoption jumped I do
think you guys need to go and clarify
some of the issues that were raised
before we can issue an adoption call
okay and questions
okay thank you next one is dynamic
service chaining we're just pulling up
your presentation
who did this might take a while
okay here goes yep thank you
hello everybody I'm going to do the
quick update put me in full-screen ah
casaya
yeah okay thank you I'm going to just
give a quick update on this on this
draft version zero two on the F of my
quarters
next slide please so just a recap in
this draft we introduced as a function
service function called SLR to handle
what we call dynamic chaining it
decouples the service consumer and the
service provider and it basically
creates a chain when the service is
requested
using name based identification of
service endpoints and this function also
uses and I would say this is just in one
of the example which where it uses HTTP
as an application layer transport to
realize the name based identification so
it is based what it what it describes an
extension to the SFC framework where URL
based addressing scheme is used and
yessir are uses this name based
relationship to route for specific
instances of service function next slide
please
so in this slide we just recap some of
the discussions or questions that that
we received one of the question was is
nsh encapsulation is utilized or
forwarding between the service functions
so the in this draft also like whether s
our our function can be embedded within
s FF though it is not explicitly
described in that way in the draft but
that is of course can be done so and
also here though NSA is not described as
explicitly being used because this stuff
mostly exposes the SRR function but the
SLR can be interpreted as an extension
to the s FF and in that case the name
based hoc information will act similar
to the SRR and the level of in this
drive the level of abstraction for
service function path is has been raised
to that of name-based change rather than
address based one and another question
that was also is how is name based half
is referenced in the data plane so to be
to Allah berate on that we can use this
n SH that path ID and the index as the
lookup to find the next name in the path
and then resolve the name to an IP
endpoint and this is also an alternative
to dns resolution where the end point
will have a given fully qualified domain
name and the request is being forwarded
over maybe an l2 network using path
forwarding and not what is excuse me
I understand all two networks we do
allow transfer net as a transport for NS
h that's l2 networks as i understand it
people use them no argument
what is path forwarding that's not a
term I've heard in the IETF or I Triple
E mm-hm so you're referencing it as a
way of doing something but there's no
there's no reference for it okay so what
the path forwarding is identifying end
to end path and basic and basically
forward based on those end-to-end
identification of the so in this update
we introduced another use case which is
basically they use the deployment of
third-party cloud service providers and
also the deployment of micro data
centers specifically we see at the edge
of the network and that reiterates the
need for flexible and dynamic chaining
and also some clarification on flexible
and dynamic changing has been also added
there so what is basically what what why
do we need this some of the triggers can
be load balancing and user or service
mobility or also optimization due to
network and conditions and also this
flexible and dynamic chaining is can be
viewed as as as a late binding compared
to the static binding of service
function chain
and third clarification is about this
HTTP as a transport and how it helps in
achieving flexible and late binding of
service function chain if we go to the
next slide please
so in the just to give a brief snapshot
of the use case the use case that we
described here is is mainly specific
localized use cases more at the edge of
the network which requires on-site data
centers and this is due to emergence of
new of real estate owners who are
willing to deploy edge clout resources
and basically they are turning towards
deployment of micro data centers at the
edge and these data centers are
typically deployed at multiple internet
point of presence and what is happening
due to this multiple point of presence
deployment now there is a trend of
composition of service and at the edge
which is basically composed out of this
multiple data centers and this kind of
implies that there will be data exchange
and collaboration is expected among
these micro data centers we go to the
next slide please
so so continuing from the previous slide
as we see like this service composition
over many micro data centers is
basically may be impacted and we do to
various conditions in the network and
some of the examples are like load
variation in the networks and service
and points been migrated mobility of
users so in order to maintain the same
level of service continuity for
end-users
SFC can support this what we call also
as flexible chaining so chains instead
of defining statically at the time of
service ability to create chain at
runtime is desirable and also dynamic
chaining as Network condition changes
user location changes this bindings
needs to be redefined frequently if we
go to the next slide please so now the
clarification that has been added as
what is being meant by HTTP as a
transport so I think the first bullet is
just a is an existent disclaimer saying
that it is being it's an example of a
named service
and the solution can be applied for
other name service also given IP and
when you say HTTP is a transport we just
basically say that we are kind of
abstracting and using HTTP as a common
transport or name based URI and
end-to-end communications and in the
context of SFC and service function what
we have done is we have used our
abstracted the HTTP request and response
as service request and we are basically
trying to do this routing and in
directions of this service request are
nothing but are abstracted at the HTTP
level if we go to the next slide please
so and then how it helps in realizing
this flexible and dynamic chaining so
this HTTP request such as get put in
post now are routed based on the URI
associated with the request and these
URIs are I are basically the name of a
resource or the invocation point now if
service functions could be identified
using URI or this name so the HTTP
request to an service function would be
routed or directed used using name based
routing and HTTP becomes an application
layer transport service and by updating
this naming relationship service
requests can be redirected easily and as
and when required next like this so okay
so I think that's the that's the kind of
the summary of the updates in this and
so the question is does this kind of is
in the scope of this working group and
is it something you know to be can be
considered like and also the next is
this an ongoing work that we are
involved and we expect some more
experiments on this h 2020 flame project
so that's the end of it so
sumantra away I did not read this drop
so sorry if I am asking question which
is obviously explained so bear with me
so in Jam some observation first in
general I am personally opposed to
seeing yet another resolution point in
network
it look like you are saying is er can be
replaced by DNS if that can be done by
DNS I would prefer to be DNS it's just
yet another component in the network
never really works secondly you're one
of the example said the URI best cut
based on your I figure out the path I
guess right so so typically e something
called page routing it has been done
before page routing used to be used by
Facebook it is still use it they used to
use third party devices now they have
written their own and the other way to
solve would it be if each node is
actually a classifier then every node
can make its own decision and point to
the next graph which is similar to
programmatic graph so I'm kind of
confused exactly are you just providing
an alternative or one should expect to
use it because it had certain advantages
over other approaches yes so translator
question it is definitely one of the way
to implement flexible and dynamic
chaining and you have so with respect to
the page based routing like them I don't
know like that I mean most of the any l7
processor engine that's third job
typically looking at URI and figuring
out where to go pretty common Cairo's
sent mine it wasn't clear to me whether
we're talking about a control plane
solution here or a data plane solution
so when you say we're trying to resolve
hops with you our eyes are you saying
that in the control plane we say that
this SF has reached at this URI and then
the SFF is responsible for mapping that
URI to an actual layer 2 or layer 3
address
than 40 dan nsh packet to it or are we
seeing that we're encapsulating out of
states within HTTP and in 40 HTTP
packets through web servers like it
wasn't I wasn't quite clear on that
could you elaborate yeah so I would say
like as its mentioned about the control
plane handling like so we can
encapsulate as we as I say as I as I say
the service request which is in this
case HTTP request is a service request
and we can encapsulate it within the nsh
and based on that naming we decide the
next you know service endpoint yes am i
understanding code when i read it was
and I could be completely wrong but my
understanding was instead of you program
in the SFF with path ID index equals
next-hop you would program the SFF to
say path path ID index equals name and
then somehow you would resolve the name
to a next hop through this HTTP
mechanism well that's how he doesn't
resolve names HTTP relies on DNS
resolving names i'm stanbow there was a
slide where you said no but we have an
alternative name resolution and then in
your slide that says HTTP transport you
induced Kyle's question because you seem
in that slide to describe the case where
the underlying original packet is HTTP
and the routing is based on the name the
URL in the HTTP well we're not doing an
application specific protocol yeah no
but that's a different problem from the
one we have here yeah but but the thing
is that if you see we have a disclaimer
HTTP and examples and we can apply it to
any name based approach but we're not
going to be specific we're not gonna do
things specific to applications which
run on names ICN or HTTP that's our
problem space is supporting user packets
we're not supporting user applications
for the problem space NSH is working on
so let's let's try to keep ourselves
focused on problem the question of what
are the entries in an SFF point to is a
question we can discuss yeah I have
trouble getting my head around why I'd
want a name
there but that's a different question
from what applications it's got to be
generic to the application let me maybe
given I can give an example like a
simple use of that I so that would be
you I say that at your path five pop3
the packet goes to IP 10 dot 0 dot 0 to
1 right and then are you saying that at
is your in your example its path 5 pop 2
packet goes to some URI so yeah if I can
say that so in the SFF it will be like
say basically as we say it right on the
change will be based on those names so
say for example example.com 2 goes to
example one common example 2.5 so now
what the SFF or if we think is a that is
an extension of SLR so that will be
resolved within that what is example one
comm means there so so that will be
resolved in this are are what example
one.com mean and based on that so I
think part of my confusions coming from
the introduction of almost an entirely
new architecture on top of SOC like I've
seen many many many terms that are
similar to but slightly different from
the terms in SFC and it's making them
very hard for me to understand the
document so if we could just describe
discuss a document in terms of s of C
would make this working group understand
it much more easily so again instead of
talking about an SR R what is the SFF
doing is when a can a team just describe
how a packet flows through the SFF in
terms of SFC functionality it would be
like it would be great the packet
arrives you look up in the forwarding
table you know the the SPI and the si
and what does that result in how does
the SFF actually map that packet to the
next hop it does it do a DNS lookup and
that gives you an idea and that gives
you an IP address and you're right the
IP header and you do an ARP and then you
fire you don't you do an arc look up and
you find the next top MAC address you
send it there is that how it works
or do you do just yeah
just to follow on from the other thing
the other thing at least from my
perspective was exactly it's Karl said
but it would be nice also to really be
clear on the problem that's trying to be
solved here you know in other words the
way that the SFF currently works there's
a lot of background in in you know why
all of this edge computing stuff's
coming along and it's not obvious to me
as to why what's being defined currently
in the SFC working group is not
sufficient for that new environment in
other words the problem that you need to
really be clear on what the problem is
and why what we've currently done won't
work in that environment and then
describe how your you know solution
actually works in the day and I think
like in kind of where I was going with
this as there was a slide that said the
path was an address and I never thought
of the path for like a specific s of P
referring to addresses you know there's
a you could easily refer to names and
this is really just a property of your
control plane and how you tell your SFF
about the service functions and how that
s FF is required to map those service
functions to actual physical devices I
tend to prefer not to do DNS lookups on
as I get packets coming into my line
rate forwarders but you know I mean like
if the control planes talk I mean you
can you can optimize these things right
like you you you update them once a
second or something and have that do
anyways but so I think if we're talking
about defining any control plane that is
you know a standard you know you maybe
there's a yang model that describes how
to use you our eyes to represent service
functions and then we talked about how
to render those down into SF's maybe
that's useful but I don't like this idea
of it doesn't seem like we're doing
something that's not that's incompatible
with SFC or even really an extension of
SSE it just seems like it's a specific
implementation of SFC like it really
feels like that to me and I'm struggling
to understand how it is something unique
uniquely distinct from SFC such that it
requires all this new terminology and
it's it was a question of the back there
on the front yeah another place in
probably clarification
dr. Austin in the digital one of the
court as a matter of fact in the
discussion with Jim actually the we Jim
you brought up something around
integration the SFF that we didn't want
to write in the draft originally so
that's probably reason that that costs
the confusion we outsource all of these
functionalities and the dedicated SRR
which creates quite a bit of the
confusion part I think the discussion
goes in the right direction to be more a
little bit more integrative with the
ideas that as I've said describe what
we're doing as either an extension or if
it just boils down to a particular
implementation of SFF then that's
probably it right the background to that
is an explanation is not an excuse an
explanation is that a realization as an
external function came out of the work
where this the the project work that
Debbie she's referencing in the last
bullet item where this work comes from
so the first realization we had done is
to be completely outsource the behavior
into into this SOR and that's the one we
are describing and a craft but I think
the discussion is initiated through your
email and at the the meeting here really
points us towards thinking much more
integrative in the you know how could it
work with the SFF as it is at the moment
and what's the required extension if any
or is it just implementation specific do
we just have a very good asset that that
could well be there you know that could
well be true but that's just it the SFF
that we're creating is just particularly
good compared to others but so that's
kind of it does help to actually scope
it down so it wasn't a question with
just a common and that's appreciate it
Thanks okay can't say I'm I think that
kind of hid a lot of my points to you
know I think it has this has a bunch of
things in the job sorry I haven't read
it to you know it has a palm statement
it has the whole srr architecture and
whole explanation which is good for
background I thought you after you
presented I can't get where you're
trying to get that right so the whole
dynamic flexible I would say servers
abstraction it's kind of what you're
searching for that you know in line so
so I get the idea but I think how we
achieve it I agree with the earlier
point achievers you know you can
come out straight out what you guys are
even talking about and you know and we
can pretty much I in my head I think we
can pretty much implement okay it is
today but you have the general
abstraction as are two dynamic
resolution basically right which is the
way you're really at it trying to write
each hop how do i resolve it and the the
key question I have here is that and
there's a fundamental assumption here
that your SFF has to be staple to be
able to ensure this works properly
because you know once you resolve but
you have to pin basically what you
resolve to and maintain that service
path with which it will ends up being
the RSP at the end of day that you've
resolved everything along the way right
so I'm not sure if you capture that
because I know that you said that this
SR becomes SFF you know blah blah blah
but the reality is that you would need
to be saiful to achieve what you want to
achieve from my understanding because
baseline you're a whole resolution
aspect okay know that move on to the
last presentation fog discuss discovery
in the fog
okay I'm Carlos Barnardo's and
presenting this on behalf of my cold
sores so this presentation is mostly
kind of prana statement one basically we
we are exploring how to discover service
functions in in a cog environment so I
will basically describe what I mean by
fog environment the motivation for that
kind of discovery and then some
potential ideas of how to do this or how
to perform that discovery
next slide please so the motivation is
basically that we are now seeing that
the visualization is becoming or is
getting closer to the final user so we
are not just restricted to the data
center model but we have resources that
are very close to the user or even are
at the user devices so don't resources
may be mobile may belong to different
stakeholders so this is what we mean as
the tallgrass the edge or as a smart at
this kind of terminology so basically
sources that are more volatile monetary
unions and are closer to the to the
final user so the idea is that in this
environment
the user can benefit from or a device
may benefit from using those resources
or functions running on those resources
that are close to the final user but is
a much dynamic environment that the
classical data center we entered in mark
so in this environment we need that
discovery of what is available and not
only the Escorial borås available but
also the characteristics of those things
that are available because this is the
same thing this coordinate function that
is meant to be like more static than
being something that is gonna be wallet
there's gonna be gone in a few minutes
or in a few hours so this basically the
idea of the motivation from this can I
ask you to verify who you intend the
discovery to be used by because in the
deployments we talked about for SFC the
end terminal simply addresses his packet
to the end service he wants to reach he
doesn't worry about these it is all
about transparency
and services so can you clarify because
the way the bullets are structured it
looks like the mobile terminal is
discovering the services and I had
trouble putting that in SFC context they
are here is basically it's a very good
ponies in our case or in the scenario
that we are addressing is the terminal
being a key I mean an active participant
so we are trying to explore extended SFC
to a terminal so we will we will see
this in the next slide you probably
should on the track in the draft make
really clear yeah you're you're talking
about a somewhat different use case
where the end user is invoking the SFP
yeah that's an than a classifier is if
you read the NSA the SFC architecture
we're very clear there's a classifier
who drives this and you're talking about
a different case okay yeah please next
slide so basically this picture tried to
to show that scenario so we are kind of
we have this continuum from the data
center to the final use end user device
and the fog is this continuum where we
have resources even at the run or at the
end user device and DNS functions in
general can be run on any of these
devices and in the next slide please
basically we go into your point so I'm a
while terminal in this environment can
benefit so it's a mobile terminal we
play in that role of of discovery in the
desert service functions to enhance the
the assisting applications and the
performance of the applications of some
examples is the terminal getting some
function for doing video transcoding or
to do prevent previous engagements or to
do locker breakout this kind of things
by the end terminal discovering those
functions and doing the whole service
function say so and this is useful for
many different reasons
that's what is covered in the second
part of the slide that is this may allow
the device to increase the battery life
or the mobile terminal so we are really
looking to a mobile terminal
centric scenario to the reduce to reduce
the communication latency from the the
mobile device by using local backup
servers or gateways that are available
close to the
use the device to benefit from functions
that require a benefit from information
that is local at the at the access so
there may be some functions that require
information from the radio access part
to to perform the function right did
they intend to do so benefit to benefit
also from context information that is
only available at the at the very local
access so these are examples of
opportunities brought by using these
functions close to the end user device
next slide please
so what we are trying to look into
mechanisms that allow to discover these
satisfactions so basically the
characteristics of the function which
pssc aware or not the type the IP
address of those service functions but
not only to discover the functions as I
said at the beginning but also to
discover the characteristics Association
associated to the resources hosting
those functions so for example the
mobility if the functions are very
battery power or not if the functions
are meant to be more volatile or not the
price if there is any associated to
using that function the migration
capabilities of those functions if we
can move those functions to an area to a
different place if the user is moving
all these kind of things that allow the
mobile terminal to decide where to use
or not unavailable service function next
slide please
okay so this figure basically represent
a couple of use case examples so
basically in the first one on the
determined of the slide we we have a
terminal that is attaching to the
network and in the network there are
service functions available and the
terminal basically requires some
mechanisms to discover those service
functions so there's a very simple
diagram basically based on a request or
basic on very big advertisements from
the network to the devices that are
connected but in our scenarios it's not
only based on having a fix or an
available infrastructure were they
device connect but also between mobiles
we may have like a vehicular scenario or
other types of scenarios in which
different devices interconnect and those
devices have service functions available
that can be used by other devices
that are nearby so that's the the
diagram that we have at the bottom of
the figure next slide please
so as I mentioned this is basically more
like a pronestyl main kind of slide or
presentation so we want to to first
understand if the working group is
interested in looking into these kind of
use cases as assumed very well mention
at the beginning is a different use case
from what has been addressing necessity
so far and if so we will continue
working on describing actual solutions
here we are just describing the the
overall picture and that's that's it if
you have any comment please that will be
very appreciative hi Carlos and vine
this is pretty cool and I just had a
couple thoughts so I think you're George
and Mike ever who exactly it was touched
on this earlier so is the terminal
actually acting as the classifier here
so inserting the sh encapsulation yep
have you considered maybe moving that
into the access point and just having
the negotiation of which serious
functions you want applied communicated
somehow or the control plane or do you
think that it'll be too challenging for
the classifier to actually identify the
particular chain you want to go on
that's that's a pretty good point we we
are now open I mean we are spoiling the
solution space that's a potential
solution it also depends on the day
Dynamis City whether the the suction
access point is going to be always the
same or we are changing so that's the
panels on the on the particularly say
that it's a very good point that's
something that we could explore some
other thoughts
okay really just had one other side have
you thought about the multiple uplink
case may be using pvd's or something to
discover the information I know it
doesn't give it gives you information
about gear up like bit unnecessary about
yourself to the wider network but that
might be something to consider I know a
lot of people have been thinking about
what happens when you have multiple ways
of accessing the network those what
we've been learning in those groups
might be worth considering there too
yeah that's also a very good point
related to this it's not exactly the
same thing but something we we are so
exploring is but it's maybe not for SFC
but in general for these environments to
actually when you have multiple points
of attachment where you can connect to
deciding on which
connect based on the availability of the
functions that that point of attachment
brings so this is something that we are
considering as well maybe it's not for a
subsea volcano but is so so in this code
and that's why I was thinking maybe
pvd's would be a good way to get it to
get this information but then if it's
really dynamic it might not be
appropriate so okay thank you very much
very good people thank you if anybody
has not signed the blue sheet please
come up and trying otherwise thank you
for your time Adrienne what is it can I
just say to the the working group that
there's this MPLS SFC draft that you may
have noticed I mean I'm here if you want
to throw vegetables at me Stewart is
going to be presenting it in MPLS
tomorrow to try to level set what we're
trying to do that the message and I have
presented it to the working group before
yeah my message the working group is we
are not trying to piss on n Sh
okay n sh exists good
go for it work on it hard we are trying
to totally reuse this working groups
SFC architecture we're not trying to
rewrite any of that and we're looking at
a niche deployment Thank You Adrian not
still there in route
you