tee's we're a little more cramped than
usual but it also looks like we are a
little lighter than usual in terms of
number of people so it's gonna all work
out
blue sheets are going around as usual
please sign and as I mentioned before we
have a etherpad
link on the bottom of the slide here
please
join it and help us capture minutes of
what goes on usually we don't take notes
on what people are presenting but more
of the conversation we have a new note
well we have a new note well for those
who have been here for a while it aims
to more clearly state what I think most
people already know basically whatever
you say in a session becomes part of our
public record please familiarize
yourself with the the note well and the
related documents we are doing our usual
audio and video streaming when you make
comments at the mic once it shows up
please make sure to state your name for
the record
I am on jabber right now we don't have
anyone on it but I will be trying to
watch the Java room to make sure that if
anyone wants to add anything remotely we
we get that read into the mic and the
questions responded to nothing has
changed with chairs and secretary we
appreciate Matt's help even though he
continues to be remote he continues to
be very helpful and helping us put
together agenda I get the slides posted
and capture minutes where do we stand on
documents we have one new RFC thank you
to those I'm sorry two new RFC's thank
you to those who contributed to
work very much appreciate that and
appreciate seeing that we are actually
getting documents out we have two more
documents in the editor queue and
notably we have quite a number of
documents with that are in publication
requests including one that went in
yesterday we had been working on that
teehee topology for quite a while and
there was one section that needed a
little cleanup it took us a little bit
to get there but that got there last
month and now that's in publication
request so that's that represents a fair
bit of work so we look forward to new
RFC's hopefully before the next IETF on
all those publication requested
documents we have one document that post
last call there's a little bit of
cleanup that's being discussed between
the document authors and shepherds it's
not expected to be a significant change
but it's still something we want to see
cleaned up before we submit to the IC
for publication we have a few new
working group documents some of them are
in the agenda some are not but that
represents good continuing new work for
the group it's important to if you
haven't read those documents please read
the new documents and comment on them we
have one document which is a little bit
coming to the group a little bit
differently than most documents this is
the RMR document this document was
headed towards the adoption in the MPLS
working group and through some
discussion with the chairs and ad we
agreed that it's actually belongs not an
MPLS but in t's so we expect this
document to come in and be adopted but
of course we will do our normal adoption
poll but I think we'll it's just
surprising to see a poll without having
it discussed before and that's because
it has been discussed before it just
it's moving into this working group
do you have a question we have an MPLS
working group chair coming up
I don't think you should overestimate
the amount of discussion we've had on
that document in MLS actually the only
thing we discussed was where it lost so
we haven't discussed it technically
aurélien same goes for the LDP one so of
the story so are you suggesting that we
have more discussion here before doing
an option I would at least allow for it
you should holidays to see if there are
reviews they I reviewed the document
halfway through before we had to decide
that this is please and I sent that
those comments to thee to the authors
but that's all the view the document has
so far okay they didn't go through your
normal review team I thought it went
over the normal no no we we were about
to okay we need to share where this
document belong okay
that is gods and ended up move it to T's
so we haven't created done any review
alright then we'll certainly we'll talk
about that offline and then come back to
the working group on the list and
suggest out of receive a thank you
thanks for the clarification
we have one incoming liaison this is a
typical liaison we've received from
itu-t over the years it's very good to
see the synchronization of activities to
make sure we have a common understanding
across the different working groups this
actually came in to not only tease it
came in to I think CKD came in to came
in to see camp MPLS did also get a piece
of PCE okay in the past C camp has taken
the lead on responding to itu-t this
type of liaison we haven't talked to the
chairs if they want to take the lead
doesn't necessarily require such a
formal response but
thinking we'd proceed the same way I'm
seeing a sea camp co-chair nodding his
head so we'll we'll proceed as we don't
really do his liaisons in general please
feel free to send comments to the teas
working group and in this case on the
liaison also please see see see camp and
thank you whoever fix the mic as a
reminder we have an IPR process that we
follow which includes pulling both
before adoption and last call please
follow our process this is part of
what's captured in that note well if you
need references on this go look at the
note well slide or the note well page
off the ietf top page as always we
really appreciate the discussions being
brought on the list this is even
including authors I think we've seen a
good example of that with the work
that's been going on with yang and TE
topology where there's a lot of meetings
that are happening and the reports are
sent to the list that's a very good way
to keep the the working group and aware
of what's going on and provide the
opportunity for those who wish to
contribute who may not be authors that
allows them to contribute to the to that
work and the consensus building process
so that's really important please use
the list and as always we try to
allocate time based on list discussion
so if you want more time in this session
have more or less discussion and with
that we're going to move on to the next
slide
good morning everyone will now quickly
look at the status of the working group
documents we currently have 23 working
group documents there are 11 that are in
various stages of the publication
process 6 or on the agenda today so that
leases at 6 and those are listed up here
the first couple of documents listed
here but adopted last month
there hasn't been any progress on these
insert options I will skip those jump to
the one that's listed third that's the
PCC see use case document we did not
receive any status for this
there hasn't been any change to the
Darkman since April of last year
this is currently an expired document
and based on a prior update there was an
indication of intent to make further
changes to the document we haven't seen
that happen
is there anybody representing the
authors who like to come out of the mic
and give an update on this
thank you next is the tea metric
recording document the authors were kind
enough to send a status update late last
night there haven't been any changes to
darkman since November when it was
revived and brought back from the dead
there are still some outstanding
comments in the list that need to be
addressed and in the previous update
authors did say that they would like to
align the procedures in this document
with the ones that are specified in IRC
8001 so I'd like to see those two items
get addressed before we have any
discussion on moving this to the next
step is there anything that the author's
would like to add to this since it came
in just last night I don't see anybody
coming up to the mic so let's move on
next is the l3t topology yang model this
was adopted last month there was a
revision published for this early this
month the changes were primarily done to
address some warnings from the yang Lin
tool there's still some work that needs
to get done before the author's can say
that they are ready for the next step in
the meantime they're requesting the
working group to review the model and
reach out to them if there are any
specific concerns
next is the SRT topology model update
for this is quite identical with the one
that we saw in the previous slide
there's still some work that needs to
get done before this can progress to the
next step
in the meantime to be good if you could
if you could get some thorough reviews
in for this model that's all we have in
this slide deck next is an update on the
tea and RSVP modeling efforts that would
be given by tarik
thank you
get they will in a minute
alignment remember yeah well good
morning everyone
kappa is it working
no is the mic working it was working
[Music]
they're working
did you give me well okay this is a
short update on the working group Russ
the three of them I'm listening here I'm
I'm awkward I am a big
I don't think I'll take all of its all
people I've tried to give back to all
the time for other spots we did it
I am presenting on behalf of the
equalities here I don't review of my
slide deck well I bought without these
talk about the open issues and those off
with next time before I go to the
updates a little bit of document our
organization we have at the moment three
documents as I was presenting on the
first slide
the first document terms of organization
of the module it covers the RSVP
the data modeling for RTP protocol and
an extended module for that at Bates and
it's ended so that this is being driven
in one document separately the second
one so the second one is basically an
augmentation of traffic engineering that
RTP protocol and it contains or seats
two modules the RSVP and the compare das
bitte please initiation of it and that's
being driven a separate document and the
third document that we have the the PE
Yankee at the moment it is seeding a
multiple module including the generic he
made a famous mastic modules I have them
highlighted in green here basically the
key fellows module leader faint agnostic
the and the device specific video and
the e-types module for reusable grouping
and so on and then there's the MPLS
specific module the e MPLS e sr kirisaki
types MPLS they're all seated in one
documents at the moment we've got some
advice to split it up into two documents
one containing the data plane agnostic
part and then the other is MPs part well
that's an action item on us we are
planning to do this in the next update
before we push for the working group
last fall and obviously we will try to
split it into two parts the stuff of
this this part about the organization of
these pockets I will go out of marketing
here first
the patronage and terms of summary I
have to start by hanging all the all the
team that is continuously meeting and
driving this work to completion
I'm not mentioning anybody in specific
but thanks to all terms of the changes
we
added RFC references many places in our
model so that was one big update that we
had we have several updates in the T
panel model of analysis
lastly I have some editorial of these
tarik thank you for the just going back
to the previous slide thank you for
those updates really good and it's nice
to see those references there's still
some I took a quick look through and
definitely notice the a big change but
there's still places where the there's
an element that's being configured that
doesn't refer back to the base spec you
know whether you're talking about to 205
or 32 and I in order and it would be I
think it's important on those in
particular to know what the right
reference is for those so it definitely
is a big step forward but there's still
pieces that don't refer to the default
lean of the base and as long as it's not
sort of that the base I think we have to
have a reference there and in some
places I know there's not good
references and in that let's just make
sure to have a good description yeah
it's good it's just that sometimes
there's pieces there that you know we
all we all know because it's in all
implementations but for someone new they
don't have if they don't have the
reference they have to know what to do
with that and we just want to be clear
there next time all right thank you
we have an explicit route this where we
specify the house we noticed that we
needed a hint when the permutation
element for the engine is trying to
expand a new spot we want to we want to
like a hint to indicate that it should
stop on a link as incoming so the
computation will enter the note
specified by the hop or it should exit
in the outgoing case they come
kitchen will exit the note at the
specified Park currently this is not
even in the specific object of object
that we have in our CP there's no
indication to say that this is the
computation of ship spa from incoming or
exit or the egress of Toledo so we've
got in the modeling we needed this in
and we added this direction for the
numbered top case as well as the
unnumbered objects the second update to
the same explicit drop list that we have
in the model was for the label and we
added a label direction so in the list
we have an option where we can add a
label on a specific link and what we
wanted to indicate that this table is an
upstream or downstream sign legal so for
the forward direction or for the reverse
direction again this applies to the
label hop in our explicit about this the
the third update we added for production
restoration several actions that can be
involved on advance difficult actions
like freeze so basically if you have a
working in a production path you don't
by freezing you don't you ignore
basically reaching from one working for
protecting you don't act on any action
invoked by the user
once you've reset and then the second
action is the clear freeze does the
negative off freeze action block block
out of normal basically it locks out
normal traffic from using the protection
valve and then leading a block out of
normal the next action would be lockout
of protection which this allows extra
traffic and normal traffic from using
the
affection confession path and we have an
action force which which forces switch
over from the working that our
perfection about regardless of the state
of the protection path so basically
there no additional checks for the
validity of the very top so the
description we try to make it as as much
as descriptive on stone hopefully yeah
please do go through the description of
this monthly or ambiguous let us know
and the next one in the manual switch so
the difference between a force which in
the manual switches there are some
additional in the manuals which case
additional checks of for validation on
expected from the device and the action
exercises is it before please do go
through the actions that are there so we
defined the action now we are defining
the RPC itself are in the model on a
specific on the RPC will take input the
action that we it will take a location
where the action is being fought it is
among the ingress egress or even on so
there is there no idea where you can
specify where the action is expected to
be involved and there's a path reference
so it is you want to switch over to a
specific path you can supply that
reference and action will be taken
switch over to that path and lastly what
type of traffic action is applied do we
have multiple types of
the next update here is well while going
through the you know the the elements
that we needed to model we discovered
that when we're computing with
constraints we wanted some constraints
to be relaxed at all so in certain cases
a strict constraints that will produce
infeasible paths are not desirable so we
wanted a hint kind of with the
computation region so that they can have
a fallback option and and relax certain
constraint so these constraints we we
thought are applicable to include and
exclude broad objects they can be
applicable to other ones so but the
first one that we address are include
and exclude type of constraint so we are
introducing an optimization metric the
computation engine will try to optimize
the number of includes obviously if all
of them are possible to be included the
computation engine will allow but
include all of them and another one for
exclusions optimized excludes again the
the computation engine will try to
exclude all of them and if it is not
possible to be explored all of them it
will fall back and exclude as many as
possible in the case of includes there
the order is independent as you would
think of the order of listing the
exclude resources so it includes
resources but in the exclude case the
order is not significant you just want
to exclude them in any way possible
so this this metric is just another
metric in our objective function and in
we're introducing the exclude lists and
they include this that will be
applicable to those optimization metrics
so obviously when we optimizing a higher
number of resources to be included or
excluded is preferable and the
computation that's the gist of it
next I have the other two drafts that
we're driving for those in terms of the
changes we have mostly done editorial
changes adding references and aligning
with augmentations to the other model he
model
there isn't any major changes that we've
done for those two models in terms of
next steps trying to wrap up updates to
the tea tunnel we are promising more
examples and news cases to be documented
in another draft that we're driving the
draft references right there
so we'll be adding use cases and
examples of how we use this model that
he tunnel model with the tea topology
model as well and for several use cases
of protection and restoration and even
many others we're hoping that that will
you know clarify many of the elements
that we're trying to model and if why
we're adding them a detailed definition
is also going to be in that tutorial or
modeling modeling we are document into
Oh into two to two draft separate drafts
and and after that we're going to
working group last call the last two
drafts as I mentioned there were there
ready for working with last call sorry
you're having problems yeah yeah I'm
trying to adapt
in real time that was it thank you so
much for listening and if there are any
questions I'll be pleased to answer any
questions yes oh this work has been
going on for a while it's clearly pretty
foundational important work it's really
good thank you Tariq and a machine and
we'd really like to try to wrap it up we
do have as you mentioned there's a few
things going on there's the this the
split piece I know that also there's
been a net to go through the models to
make sure that we have a good split of
generic and non-generic I actually found
one little myth and going through it
again I had talked of a lot about it if
if people in the room could take a look
at the document now and the models now
and start doing if there's a lot of work
here so start doing your review and
seeing if you can find any anything you
think needs to be changed because we'd
like to really wrap it up because once
the split happens I think we're going to
be ready for yang doctor review and
moving to the last call right right yeah
so that's so we really want to start
wrapping this up so now if you haven't
looked at this in a while now is a
really good time to do it if you haven't
looked at it before even better the
splits gonna be editorial you know some
so the models are gonna move and some
words are gonna move around but the
technical content really isn't gonna be
changed yeah the team can start and take
a look at the current draft as is and
when we split it'll be easier also to
take another look
yeah and and my expectation is as as
soon as the split happens we'll go for
early and doctor review just to sort of
smooth the process along agree okay
thank you thank you very much
extra Seger
good morning everybody my name is igor
brisk and i will present this document
basically as you mentioned to have a
publication request ability to poetry
model and we are very close to come to
the last call for the eternal models and
it is important to understand that
apology and animals they are not very
complex model just very complex model to
fully appreciate the complexity of
motivation ambition of this work
one might think as I do about this work
as an attempt to produced like as the
inversion of jumping was basically no
more no less
to alleviate Jim Palace on the next
evolution of stage and took our pretty
much all other aspects that Jim Palace
has produced including like topology
discovery abstraction multi-layer multi
domain considerations of computation
traffic engineering application and so
forth right but we also bring other
aspects like for example telemetry
collection we added we were adding
things that never existed in Jim fellows
like Jared mentioned protection commands
switching commands and we also solve a
few problems that we knew about Jim bill
is and we do the discussions will pick
up and say oh this was a perennial
problem for us let's fix it like for
example the directionality of the
inclusion elements that Eric mentioned
on time to say is that this is extremely
important look because if you think
about all the documents produced by
seeker BC you know with respect to
gender less you would get the idea of
amount of all kind of definitions
explanations
you know motivations use cases and stuff
that needed to be sound somewhere
documented and if we would just put into
these two models which also contain the
entire source of the models it would be
extremely difficult to actually finish
this book so what I'm trying to say that
our the success of the apology and
tunnel model in particular with respect
to the transport networks very much
depend on the success of this work
presented already it twice and it's it's
been adopted as working group document
and basically in many ways is just
beginning on this book there are many
definitions and explanations that are
required by many people including even
her office of the models sometimes there
is very unclear what exactly we meant by
this of that basically semantics in the
model so there are also great need of
use cases that will explain how this
model work the different guidelines how
these models could be invented so both
so over-smoked we are trying to put into
this document
basically there were no much progress
since the last 80 around that because we
were focusing on finishing the topology
and on our models but there were certain
changes that that happened for example
it'll a bird use of the contribution
upon explaining what protection commands
are what shed protection is and
basically this is our goal or where we
start to get more and more definitions
with respect to all kind of aspects
including Park complication optimization
and an use cases that involve all that
people would ask what does it mean for
example transitional link that was not a
package it all has to begin with so all
these things will be defined in this
document well I I will not try to
basically repeat what was presented
already but this document has like three
parts one of them is dedicated to
definitions for the poetry model the
other maternal model and then use cases
which basically describe how these
models could be used separately and in
combination with each other
because it were beneficial to use them
in conjunction but it is also possible
and we consider various use cases where
each of the models are used
independently from the other regardless
whether they are those used for not okay
this is unlike usual you have more time
if you would like it
well I just want to encourage people to
risk questions with respect overturn on
topology model this question come quite
frequently during discussions but not
outside of their design teams or
basically we would want to hear them so
that we could put more definitions in
different sections and provide you know
like very you know rigorous definitions
you know which leave no room for in
misinterpretation we also are looking
for interest in use cases that could be
also put into this document you know the
the document is very helpful
particularly for people coming in to the
work afresh and there's a lot of
complexity here in the models because we
support a lot of different functions and
so having this type of documents really
important and if you are reading the tea
topology dot it model that we're talking
about before the one that's gone to
publication requests are you reading the
other modules and something isn't clear
come look here and if this doesn't help
ask questions and because someone
thought that the next reader is going to
have something similar and it'd be good
to capture the answers and this is the
right place to do that but just one more
think that I would recreate so Derek
mentioned that we introduced like a
correct unusual elements into how the
paths could be computed for the terrace
for example we allow for optimization
and both just constrained for inclusions
and exclusions basically you can specify
strict inclusions and or you can specify
a desirable inclusions that would be our
computation would follow as much as
possible but also a in in relation to
other optimization criterias so for
example the the path computation can
produce the best possible trade-offs
between how many inclusions are
to a fault with another optimization
like delay and and course stuff like
that so basically those things are not
conventional they are not part of
current PCE and basically we would like
to have an opinion as to how this could
be aligned how this work could be
aligned we allow for customized
optimisation for customized objective
function which I'm not well defined but
basically you can pick up a various
metrics and assign various understand
whereas weights so that the best
possible trade-off could be achieved and
I can get not shortest and not a
shortest delay path but something which
is the best good compromise
this is just one example yeah this to
Fanta so I'm trying to help you go to
use of sometime okay so you know
actually I think this job it's very
useful and helpful for vendors and also
operators to understand how to use term
you know I give young models for
transport networks but you know actually
in the CEM we also have another similar
chaffed
that it's a transport MPI chaffed so I
think from the motivation of this to
Jeff they have the similar motivations
they both are trying to describe how to
use ITF models for the transport
networks anyway I think for the eCos you
have to just focus on that he a generic
generic young like heat apology and he
tunnel but I think anyway on this two
jobs the job the authors of this to job
should have more discussions and
coronations and this to job should not
be progressed independently from each
other right yeah no just good
to make it where we do participate in a
mutual design team course so I've been
personally taken part in the MBI and
answering questions that Ito and serger
generated okay so and on the other hand
they're little and serger and deter
they're like a quite active members of
this design team that are considered
constantly on our calls so so so we do
cooperate
basically yeah the hope is is that the
the folks contributing figure out the
right split I mean these are these are
two informational documents we're
looking to the authors to figure out the
split and if for some reason they decide
that it makes sense to combine it that's
okay and we'll figure out how to run the
working group process if the authors
think it that the split is artificial so
please continue on and continue
coordinating now if it makes sense to
come to see camp and have C camp here
this work we can do that or vice versa
have the the NBI presented here we'll
look to the C camp chairs to provide
some input there and some guidance okay
other comments questions Thank You Ari
next was the young model draft for
requesting path computation surgeon good
morning
in sahaja yoga Lottie I am presenting
the status of but computation FPC on
behalf of authors of authors and
contributors first credits about people
that helped in his work thanks to
Cardiff and Jessica from erickson with
the extensive review comments and also
proposal for enhancement thanks to
Michael for his review comments and
thanks to all the people Tareq New York
thanks to Frank and Pavan for the
coordinating activity with T a model
that help us also to resolve a common
issue between computation and tunnel
model okay this is the summary of the
changes from version zero zero when the
document has become a working group the
draft has been modified based on
comments coming from Michael and the
draft has been restructured according to
this comment with a new introduction and
a start with the new terminology section
and a structure of new chapter with the
motivation of path computation so why a
young model for a path computation
request the interaction with the a
topology connectivity matrix concept and
stateless and stateful computation
analysis and description of the
difference and the pro and cons then
there is the path computation and
optimization for multiple paths section
and then there is the young part with a
new introduction of the new section for
model description and new features and
then the okay this is a specifically
about the young model the modification
has been done particle has been
introduced in synchronization for
multiple part has been added the matrix
we used the dimetric coming from the
eternal definition but is a specific for
single individual requests and we added
the specific metric that can be adapted
for in case of multiple multiple
requests there is the new there there
the cap ability to return the value for
computed matrix that is help comparison
or they select the best solution for the
path by Orchestrator and it's then there
is the introduction of iox
row using a grouping coming from eternal
and we clarify an issue regarding the
endpoints with the in in case of
multiple part but in case of multiple
domain you have a multiple choice of
ingress and egress and so the part
computation as to select the best choice
make path computation with all the
couple the pairs of ingress and egress
and this is an issue that was already in
the in the Jetta
here we synthetizer the situation of the
github repository in which we can track
the situation of the drugs and basically
we we remain eleven open issue about
there are eight of out of out of these
open issue that is in common with the
tea eternal and we proactively work with
them to solve the issue this is a
instead a specific point to be discussed
a clarifying the context of that
computation so the using of a crude
exclude topology so if it is useful or
not to have this type of possibility in
which you can choose what is the best
apology the the best solution between
among different apology for the optimal
path so the the structure of the
Eternals
are set up in a given topology so the
topology makes the contest for all the
entities topology entities the particle
computation can be used to select which
topology then we have two possible
options that we have multiple requested
one for each topology and another
solution at the one requester attorney
multiple part one for each topology
obviously they did the option a is not
very good in the de contas include
exclude for the B for they off shall be
the advantage it could be that the
included screw topology could be used to
select a sub set of available topologies
but problem is that
how you can reference the various
topology entity in the different
topology so the type of thing defier how
can be relate to one to the other
okay next step that we plan to have for
this draft is obviously work to resolve
the open issue and in particularly we
continue our cooperation with tunnel
mode guys and try to have more comments
from a working group and after a further
cleanup of the draft request a young
daughter review and so we would like to
be ready for a working group last call
after next IDF excellent thank you for
the update are there any questions
comments so another document that would
be really good to take a look at if you
haven't looked at it recently or looked
at it before those are here it's going
to be progressing but a little bit
behind the the prior yang models but
still it's a good time to look at it and
send comments to the list
thank you comments also well you can
invite them yeah so if you if you see
areas that you don't think are
adequately covered that's particularly
important to to mention also we don't
have a for mic so feel free to come up
here if you have a comment thank you
very much usually
okay morning everyone this is a short
update on the applicability of all the
wonderful models that you have just seen
- Tracy Tiana this is a drafter that has
been recently adopted as a working
document as I said motivation of the
document is to describe how to use that
well actually it's a double double scoop
how to apply existing models to a city
Anna and define what is or better was
missing to meet actn requirements in
fact in the next slide you will see
which models apply to which interfaces
and which new ones have been been
defined this is a zero here zero one
version so some changes with respect to
the version that the working group
adopted main changes are the
catification about telemetry performance
management and abstraction these
sections have been updated and fixed the
victim and then there was well a CTN
mostly focus on the m VI on CMI
interfaces where we have network models
not device models and there were
references to device models and those
have been removed because they do not do
not apply to the CTN interfaces and we
added also references attuned the new
work on the transport MBI which is the
technology specific extensions of the
MPI interface and Ethernet models so
these are the two interfaces the CMI the
MPI very shortly kappa the CMI is the
one that is exposed exposed to the
network user scenarios in which it is
used
provisioning event and
and vehicle networks inter data center
connectivity and so on and so forth as
you can see here the one in red is there
is a water we added to the CMI basically
one of the requirements was to be able
to set up services with de and water
services constraints we added a model
called the tea service model tea service
mapping that will be presented a later
orna which allows to bind a given a
service to a given infrastructure in the
sense that it is possible to buy the
service both either to a tea tunnel or
any city on a beautiful network their
interface there is the one towards the
PNC the MPI this one is the one that is
heavily based on the tea topology tunnel
model path computation API and Swarna we
have so we have highlighted all the
technology independent models the one
the ones that you have seen and all the
technology specific models because
between the PNC and then the mdac where
abstraction cannot be a can possibly be
not yet done technology specific
extensions will be there for example
related to OT an optical and so on and
so forth to conclude summary next step
summary this this is a document that
says that says if you wanted to build in
a city an error in interfaces these are
the models that you should use next step
sir most of the models mostly the one
the ones the MPI models so he topology
t-turn and so on are becoming very
stable the draft is becoming quite
stable too and any comment on how to
progress the work out to improve it our
modern work
I'm sorry for the voice yes it's great
comments so I think I think one area
that's still a little unclear is how
working on the upper interface to CMI
and I think there's some disagreement
among participants of whether or not
that needs to be the a CTN service
models or whether we can just reuse the
other models and so that's something
that is reflected in this document is I
think going to be discussed on the next
couple of presentations on the
individual documents and I think we
still have to work through that what
you're referring to with a CDN service
month yeah and I particularly so the CMI
right now you're referring to the VM
yang yes a document and the service
mapping document well the other
interface you might yeah thank you
you're referring to the yang models that
we just talked about right and you know
this there's a perspective of I think
the folks working on those other models
that they could also be used for the CMI
yeah and that's me so this this is sort
of something that's still open I think
for discussion a document and we're
working through and it would be good to
get other people's perspective on it so
read this document but also read the
documents that are coming out of it
you'll see in the next presentation that
we we made the huge step forward in the
VM the mother that's great the robot
will be relaxed page Thanks thank you
expedition
hi this is true from Huawei and I'll be
presenting the ACD in VN yak the draft
which was just was talking about and how
it will be used at EMI and what are the
updates that we have done based on the
feedback that we got from the last
meeting we have a new co-author Igor
helped us reviewing and integrating this
work better with the existing yang
models so what is this this is the yang
model for virtual network services at
the CMI level it is aligned to the
customer service model description
that's been defined in net mod and other
working groups it works on VN level so
it does be an instantiation VN
computation real life cycle as compared
to doing it on a path or a tunnel level
so it acts on the whole VN as an entity
it also has information about the access
point and the V and a P what is the VM
VN is nothing but a list of various VN
members so it describes how that
grouping is done now we have some things
like VN compute where we can compute the
whole VN as a whole and also have
interesting things like multi-source
multi destination problems which has
been put as a requirement in the a CDN
requirement document and also discussed
in the framework so this young model is
basically achieving those requirements
and those frame those things that we
highlighted in our information documents
so what we did basically in this update
look we try to align ourselves to the T
topology model as much as we can and
since T topology model had a lot of
constructs that already exist so we
simply use them simply refer to them and
simply aligned to them as much as
possible and anything that was
duplicated which was also defined in the
a CT and VN model was completely removed
so what were the duplicated things we
have the OPCON set of assigning
constraints
king of optimization criterias setting
up explicit parts all of that has been
removed and we simply relied on the T
topology yang model right and then we
also simplified that doe we have of
multiple types of VN we can have VN type
1 which is a single node topology or we
n type 2 where you may have an abstract
topology at various levels grey white
black but to this model
things could be simplified so we have
will talk about how we have done that
simplification and how using a D
topology single node abstraction helps
us to achieve that so what were the key
things in our model we have the access
information which is nothing but a P and
V and a P which kind of maps to T
topology ltp we have the concept of a
virtual network which maps to an
abstract node in the T topology model
I'll show a little bit more details
about that and then we when we have a VN
member which is how the two endpoints
are getting connected that's nothing but
an entry in the connectivity matrix
matrix or the abstract node so why are
aligning ourselves to the D topology in
this way we have kind of removed a lot
of things which were we were defining it
again in our model and this kind of
works in our opinion like it works well
with the existing model so how does that
look this is basically a pictorial
definition of what I was just talking
about you have a PV and AP information
that maps to the the LDP information
here you have a whole VN VN maps to a
single abstract node so that if we have
a reference to that abstract node we can
define the various properties of this VN
using the abstract node attributes which
I will further explain and then when we
have a VN member which connects a
particular ap access point to another
access point that's represented as a
entry in a connectivity matrix and any
specific information about that Wien
member can be put inside
thirty matrix entry and this young model
also had a concept of connectivity
matrices and their connectivity matrix
ID a connectivity matrices is a global
container so when something is
applicable to the whole VN as a whole
and doesn't need to be repeated for each
VN member can we put in the connectivity
matrices but when we have a specific VN
member detail that goes and as an entry
in the connectivity matrix ID so why are
this concept which is already there in
the gate apology model we could simply
refer to simply ref put a reference to
the single node topology and try to
achieve that information and why are the
single node topology you have the
connectivity matrices which also have an
underlay contrail container and why are
that underly container whatever
information that we wanted to represent
about the about how the path is set up
what is the path what is the properties
those things can be achieved by that so
this is an overview of how the
restructuring and the major change that
we have done with this update this just
shows like the our old model so our own
old model was there we were repeating
some information like how to set the
constraints and what will be the
optimization criterias so those we have
completely remove now and this is the
connectivity matrices which is a global
thing applicable to the whole VN and
this is per entry which is nothing but a
VN member so we maintain a reference to
an ID here and a reference to a node in
an abstract topology that's nothing but
2 BN so when we are talking about
setting a particular constraints those
constraints goes here when they are
global but when something has to be
applied to a particular v end that comes
to the connectivity matrix ID so why are
this alignment the model has got
simplified quite a bit and we are not
duplicating any information across
models so how did we do that by
maintaining a simple references to the T
topology model so we expect that we
would have a CT and VN model as well as
the T topology model being used in CMI
together and we would have a reference
to the abstract node and the tea
topology ID in when we are setting up a
particular VN and when we set up a VM
member we will have a reference to the
connectivity matrix ID which will have
more information about how the path and
other things have been set up right and
we already covered the concept of
putting global information and pertwee
and member information so all of this is
handled so now let me just show you
about how we did do this in VN type 1
and the we in type 2 and okay so BN type
1 the VN type 1 is basically an
edge-to-edge
collection of VN members which are set
up as tunnels in the underlying network
so as we earlier said basically what we
will do is when we create a V and 1 in a
CD and VN yang model we maintain a
reference to an abstract node in the tea
topology model when we have various VN
members those are also linked to the
connectivity matrix IDs inside the
inside the tea topology when we have
some VN properties so these million
properties are set why are the
connectivity matrices parameters inside
the is inside the tea topology model so
this having at this single node single
node mapping to a single node in te
topology has helped us to simplify the
model and now let's talk about the more
complicated case which is the type 2
topology in which the customer expect to
see an abstract topology the VN topology
which is exposed also to the customer
but to simplify the mapping we anyway
always have a single node topology a
single node created this can be created
automatically it doesn't have to be set
by the customer or it could be set by
the customer but the concept is the a CT
and VN model will always refer to a
single node abstract as a single
abstract node topology and uses the
connectivity matrices and connectivity
matrix containers inside the TA topology
to maintain the reference so dual the
customer may see this topology the a CT
vn model always referred to a higher
level single node topology which
maintains a relationship via the
underlay to the real VN topology and the
VM topology might further have underlay
to the physical the physical domain P
topology so why are this hierarchy which
is very well defined in the d2 polity
model anyway by reusing that we could
simplify the VN type 1 and type 2
so for irrespective of what is the level
of information that is exposed to the
customer via the T topology model the a
CT and VN model always rely on a single
node topology to maintain references and
get further information about the paths
and how the VN is set up what's going on
and VN status all those information and
one more key thing that we wanted to do
in VA while we are setting up VN member
is we want customer to give us direction
on how the path should be set up so that
for example we have a VN member say L 1
to l 8 and we suggest that the L 1 L it
must go through this this abstract node
so this can be set via the underlay path
in the connectivity matrix ID for this
particular VN member and by using the by
using the existing concept of the
connectivity matrix underlay path we are
able to do that so the actn VN yang
model doesn't have to worry about type 1
and type 2 that also simplified the
model quite a bit and then we had like
some of the things like VN compute and
multi-source Martita station as some of
the innovative things that we can do
with the a CT and VN yang model so this
problem basically is when we may have
multiple we have a choice between
multiple destinations or multiple source
and the customers can see NC can set
that oh go ahead and set up a b and
member and you have a choice between
resource and these destination and from
the network point of view you decide
which is the best B and member to set up
right now and that can also further
change so by setting a simple a simple
leaf that oh you are apart
a group of multi source or a multi
destination it is the job of the MDS C
to decide which one gets selected and
the selected one only gets a actual
reference to the connectivity matrix
because that's something that's actually
getting established whereas the
intention from the CNC can be put in a a
CT and VN yang model as a part of
various VN members but the VN members
that actually gets selected is the one
that has a reference to the connectivity
matrix ID so this has also been
explained clearly in the in the document
with some JSON examples of how the
interaction between the a CT and VN yang
model and the T topology model is
maintained so just to us to summarize
what's the role of our AC T in VN model
well we still want to maintain a
customer view of the VN have a VN as an
entity so that the service model aspects
can be easily satisfied you could still
do some innovative things like VN
compute computing the VN as a whole
rather than using us a set of path
imputation and and or a set of tunnels
but having the VN as an entity still
helps giving the customer of view of VN
as a single entity we also have things
like when we are mapping to the services
which is going to be discussed in the
next slot where how do we when we are
setting up a VN for a particular service
like a little you know a seamless MPLS
case how a mapping between the tunnels
that are being used by these services is
maintained which is very useful to show
to a customer that what his intention
was with the service model and what is
being realized by the MDS C so that
mapping also gets simplified if we have
a CD and VN young model and also the
information about the access the
customer access and when the customer
access is being shared across V and
that's where the concept of V and AP
comes in so those things should be
mapped in the ACD and VN young model so
this is the simplified a CT and VN young
model you have the access points and the
V and ap a reference to the T topology
model which is the abstract node and the
TV apology ID
this is the VN you have the source the
destination and then a reference to the
connectivity matrix ID in the a topology
model so this is just the AC the VN part
you also have the RPC called the V and
compute which I have not put in this
diagram because it's almost a similar
idea with setting up of a configuring of
Ian and multi-source multi destinations
is also handled via these leaves right
here and the selected one is highlighted
via this leaf call if selected so this
is also explained in the document we
still have some global properties here
like admin state operational state and
some other VL level diversity
requirements so those are still here in
the AC DMV and young model so this
update we basically the feedback that we
got from the last last meeting we have
tried to handle that with this update
and we feel that now we have much better
align with the T topology model and the
T topology model has of course a space
at the CMI because you need to expose
the topology to the customer but how the
AC t + VN yang model works well with the
existing T topology young model to give
VN as an entity as a customer service
model entity for our customer to look
and visualize so that's what we have
tried to achieve and I hope that the
working group feels that now we are at a
good shape for adoption thank you any
questions
I'm dieter Bella nokia yes yeah we found
out that there is another graph in the
operations area working group addressing
also virtual networks I'm just wondering
whether you are aware of that crap
because it seems that there is quite
some commonality between this draft and
the route in the ops our working group
it's the ops our working group threat
and the updraft has tightly and they can
model for network virtualization overlay
overlay resource management I feel that
we are talking about two different
things if I were if I am if I remember
correctly that document was talking more
about network slicing and and sort of
like what that it was not of course in
the AC T M VN as we define in the case
working row that's something that those
guys are like no coming at this problem
in a different way but yes we need to
coordinate it's an idea we have to yeah
defines a traffic matrix it also defines
connectivity etc so it looks like
there's a then I think that's so more
like a tea topology people to handle and
this is good you brought into these
working group this if this getting
bigger you define I think yeah we need
to check in addition to that I guess
that doesn't deal with traffic
engineering I'm sorry I'm not sure
everyone I didn't hear your comment
about your everyone else it
no I just didn't understand it I mean
the ROP s ops area draft I guess it
doesn't deal with the traffic
engineering and if it does it's in the
world working group okay well it sounds
like a good discussion to have with
those chairs and as well as the 80s I
actually was not aware of that document
so thank you for bringing it up so can
you go back to the model sure
so what's the significance of the
bandwidth fields here saying you those
are the only in the AP AP disbandment so
are those the only constrains that you
would those are the things which are
likely to the customer facing access
links so sometimes they were not part of
the T topology model if the T topology
model is only the provider view of the
network and if these are other things
which are being set by the customer
because these are the links that are
owned by the customer so we wanted to
make sure that they are somewhere if
there is a better place to put this
information we are completely okay with
listing tools but as far as I understood
that it was not possible to put this in
the T topology model you can confirm if
I'm if I'm misunderstood this any of my
co-authors can correct that parts and
that would be helpful as well if there
is anything that needs to be changed
yeah this is young yeah this one is not
possibly defined by T topology because
access link is only one entity here we
are talking about a T and B n AP and the
partition of that so I think customer
need to maintain the bendiest partition
correct yeah yeah we'll take it offline
I still have concerns about using that
here any other comments
so this is this is obviously a pretty
major update reusing mechanisms rather
than redefining mechanisms is definitely
a great step forward how many I'm
interested how many people have looked
at this version that's that's a
reasonable number
how many think that there is still more
work to be done so it's ready to be this
is ready for publication well if there's
no more work to be done there's nothing
for the working group to do that was a
trick question
everyone's hands supposed to go up so
clearly this is the type of work that we
should be doing here is I was looking
actually I was hoping for people to be
interested in working in this so maybe
I'll ask that directly can't these trick
questions
rephrase things how many think that this
work is a suitable foundation for the
working groups activity in this area I
would say it's about the same number as
who have read it so that that's good
well before I say the next statement
keep in mind that were this is an
individual document if we adopt that
it's a starting point so it's okay for
there to be open issues when we start
working on something that said is there
anyone who has reservations about taking
this document in as a working group
document good answer don't want no hands
up all right so I think we got
reasonable responses to the the first
two questions about reading and interest
in taking this document on we'll talk
offline and of course anything we don't
make any final decisions here we confirm
on the list thank you very much yeah
thank you for the the big step forward
we will before we take an action of
moving the document for it here we will
have to go off and talk to in the ops
area folks and just make sure that we're
not running into a conflict this is the
six
good morning this is Jung Lee I'd like
to present traffic engineering and
service mapping young model this is
actually related to ICT and VN young
model we had pretty good good feedback
so I hope this one also make some
progress tea service mapping young model
is basically a creating on mapping
relationship between various service
models that have been proposed in IETF
layer 3 and I think that's already RFC
right and then layer 2 sm and layer 1 c
sm has been proposed in CPM as well so
basically this model tea service metal
model in the middle are basically create
a mapping relationship between this
various service model and the traffic
engineering true or a CT and VN model
because group explained HDTV end model
has a good relationship and a reference
point to tea topology model as you see
here and then tea topology model as ego
explains always work together with
eternal model so that whatever in a
service model need to be connected
seamlessly with the traffic engineering
we need key service mapping model
instead of specifying some T specific
policy or binding relationship how
service should be bound to at eternal
for instance isolation mapping you know
I want my service to be isolated from
other VP other tunnels for instance as
those are information that we conveyed
or you can do it at
a service model but service model
doesn't have that so we think that it
might be good to have one focal point or
the shim layer so to speak or to buy
doll a very assassin I send models
together in one shot so desktop the
purpose of this tea service network
model so for example if we have a layer
3 sm basically a customer arm will
inject layers really a model to the
provider so customer basically
configures layer 3 VPN service using
layer 3 as chain model say I want to
create new virtual networks or VPN so
that's the you know request coming in
and then a layer 3 sm model at the mdac
basically I pick up what customer wants
and then also generate a CT and VN model
which group just explains it so that a
CT and diem model interact with Thea
topology model and tunnel model to have
the cross reference as to what customer
of endpoint is connected to and which
the eternal model as well and then are
basically also T service network model
so basically are glued together a
service model and the T model and using
a tea service network model after the
mapping is done basically customer read
this tea service metal model at the
operational state as to what is my
binding relationship with my service to
LTE and then as such an AC T n VN also
you know can be read by the customer
about operational state of my service
connected with the T language so that it
can refer to which tunnel model which
tunnel is referred to so that customer
can understand clearly how their service
is created so this is a the young models
there
that we put together as you see here we
have a service mapping here to the
access point services with a solution
mapping and then site mapping as well as
supposed to provide it with the proper
site mapping but one of the important
thing is a map type which is applied
whether we choose layer 3 or layer 1 or
layer to this map type is very important
in terms of isolation or not for
instance we kind of specify some example
map type you know customer wants to
create VN a new VN but I don't want to
share with anybody else for instance so
it's called hard isolation do so
requirement has to or intent has to be
conveyed or I don't care whether I share
with other a tunnel and output I'll just
give me any tunnel for instance so they
can be specified as a TN TN selection
and then or you can be I just don't want
to create another tunnel but just modify
the advantage of existing tunnel for
instance so those are kind of example
map type that can be you know
facilitated using a tea service model
tea service mapping model so this one is
actually dependent on the progress of VN
young model and I hope I see some
positive feedback from the working group
and this is kind of the last clue that
will really facilitate service model to
RT and topology through a CT and VN also
so it's also worked on this quite a
while and actually this is driven by
operator requirement and and we believe
that history could be a good base for
the working group adoption and of course
the map type we haven't defined details
yet and also
had a comment previous ITF meeting we
can add to the most specific map type
which may not be covered by here so we
have still work to be done but we
believe that this might be a good start
starting point any questions can I can
you come to the mic Parvati Akane
if you sherry we are actually planning
to use both IETF models the work that
you've a good thing in own app so that's
good news we are also working with math
LSO so I'm trying to figure out is there
an overlap between the two or you guys
you have been looking into meth lso
versus the model that you're developing
here
just a clarification yeah I think of LS
so if I understand correctly they have a
got or I got to interface I think maybe
CMA is kind of similar but I don't think
they have clear you know walk progresses
for as I know you know there are
modelled edges information and
architecture and this is another step
further but we are ITF and then we have
all the service model defined here young
models already so I don't think we need
to eat much concerned about any F but if
MF wants to have the other relationship
with us we can actually provide young
models for them so that ITF mother can
pro you know progress further into other
fields and like Crimea four levels here
same model service definition they
actually make a liaison which she can't
and sitting has young mother also that's
work-in-progress like that so I think
this might be another reason if they
want to use our ETF model
but in some Jeff said they're not
talking about young data model yet they
talk about info model so I know where
they are coming from there's another
more fundamental problem any app models
are not open for people who don't
participate in India and eventually I
think they'll be using IDF models
because someone has to write the mother
in general I I do think that this
working group should look at working on
a charity service mapping function at
this point I'm still trying to figure
out whether this needs to be done in a
generic fashion I don't see the reason
why this needs to sit in one of the actn
umbrella but let's see how the previous
document is nice to tune umbrella it
does but use the duck if you read
through the draft it's very much tied to
a CTF but let's see how the other
document progresses and then they can
revisit okay yeah that is helpful fit
just makes it clear that it applies to
all te it's okay if you reference a
document that has a CT at in the title
but if you go back to the slide that ice
goes yeah can you go back to the slide
where you do where you have the
functional blocks for keep going back
yeah this slide here yeah I'd I don't
understand the box with a CT and VN in
there I think I was true explain that's
a very simple way to connect say yeah
man I understand that this is saying
that this is how you map on to an AC T
and V n but I but I would like to see a
generic discussion on these arisen okay
yeah that's fair yeah I think one
confusion here is that when we were
writing this document we were focusing
on the CMI side so where we are seeing
the actual l3 SM model and the service
model being
to a single thing but at the other level
what will happen is when you look at the
device side and maybe you have
configured a vrf and you want to bind it
to the tunnel so that model is little
bit different because that needs to be
looked looked at your mapping is on the
device
what is the tunnel that I'm actually
using and how it is not to VR so I think
it's good to differentiate for us when
you are looking at the service model
level and whether we are looking at the
network and at the device level that's
where our thinking was so maybe let's
see if there I mean right now the way
the draft is written is very specific -
yeah so I think this goes to the
disconnect that I was talking about
earlier where some CTE topology as
equally applicable as a service module
model as it is on it as a device as
device and I think we have a difference
of perspectives here and that we have to
work through as a group
but I think that that's what's going on
here is is that we have that disconnect
of perspectives so we can have more
discussions here that's good no no
continue come we can we can have more
discussions here so let's continue with
that and then but also I expect that
some amount of getting together offline
hopefully this week might be necessary
but I wasn't trying to cut off the line
we actually have time to keep discussing
the topic if you don't want to go why
are the ACP Indian and directly want to
refer the tea topology abstract looking
at mapping at the l3 sm that has to be
at the higher level and the mapping that
we have at the VPN and the vrf level
just make sure that we are not but your
other PP bar we can look at how we can
map directly to the a topology okay
that's good no this is forward
so I'm small I agree with you on the
service mapping problem it has to be
solved in the
general way we have for example we have
like a lot of discussions in ethernet
layer and how to map say EPL services
EVPs or I said we're on the tunnels as
well and it's almost you know they're
back on the same issues as well as you
have here and I would say that their
teeth are not sent apology it's it's
something which should be in my opinion
decoupled from the services and I would
follow for example what layer three
services that free service model has
produced right so basically you have one
model which is service model which is
network white model described in the
service like layer 3 VPN network white
then you have another model which
describe a device specific model how to
map for example service on a particular
PE with respect to the tunnels and then
there is a totally separate model which
is a tunnel model which basically
ensures the services and you can map
whereas services on those tunnels and
see pollicis is just one part of a
service mapping there are other police's
which could be also considered as well
and this is not our job to discuss but
for example how do you constraint the
connectivity you know what kind of
length on weapons on the edges stuff
like that
right how you for example translate the
LAN ID is coming from customers into the
LAN ideas going onto network this those
are very generic issues that needs to be
actually discussed as a separate issue
it would be good to have like some some
kind of service independent agnostic
model that provides like various you
know
divisions like key policies like
connectivity limitation support but but
but I would strongly suggest to actually
decouple the T tunnels from the services
the tunnel so that's something that
infrastructure that source
thesaurus like for example there should
be a layer 3 VPN which is delay
constraint okay so and the customers say
I want to have left the end which has
like this kind of latency the only way
to produce us before that creator is to
come up with the Chicanos which are
properly optimized them to state so that
the role that these will be connected
these certain panels right certain
constraints but those tunnels can sue
yes I think I agree with you so this one
is basically basically what Larry Pengo
I said I want to have which are latency
you know service say you know 10
millisecond and then I don't it has to
be deterministic for instance without
any variation of Q delay and this one
accepts and then make sure that the T
eternal will be created as a such such a
fashion and then the custom will be able
to monitor in a closed loop through a
telemetry model so that they understand
you know what they have requested its
instantiate in the proper way
so those things actually are this one
actually provide that glue so the
customer can understand what is going on
so yeah so one thing is that sometimes
it sounds like duplication of what you
specify as a TV policy with us
what do you specify as a key constraints
optimization but in fact it's not that's
not true say the customer may say I want
to have our saved 99.99 percent
availability or or basically the
diversity of these two services and this
could be translated but you know to say
SLT to join right but customer doesn't
know what the seulji means right he
doesn't have no clue how several G is
assigned what does it mean whether it's
a single cable or single building or
single geographical area he only cares
about you know like availability and
this is something that we can common and
choose a operator or violation of this
right and it's the joke of service
weapon into map into particular
constraints and optimization as to how
the tunnels could be actually set up on
the provider network Adrienne Farrell
so I think either nailed it there and
the the generalization of that statement
is that service is not aware of the
service model is not aware of the
content of the network and and somewhere
you need a model that is aware of the
content of the network but there may
also be a little loop around in that as
you stack networks which is what attn is
about the te tunnel requests one level
may become a service if you like a
point-to-point connection service
requests back down to another network
and then the whole thing reverses yeah I
think you know that's exactly why you
know key service mapping is needed
because service model doesn't address
how te should be constructed that's why
this is gluing between this two world so
their customer can have a visibility of
underlay and monitor monitoring
capability in the closed loop so there's
a purpose to review to rephrase it map
service level just ensure nothing puts
it it it Maps service level objectives
in physicality path of network
right that's what it does yeah it sounds
like there's been some there's an
opportunity for some really good input
into s document and so if you can try to
work with people who made the comments
capture capture that yeah we gonna work
with Eagle provide was a Adrian I think
Adrian actually you know he had a point
that I always go to is recursion piece
sure
so these are really good things to
capture here and really important right
and and with that I think we'll have
some really good work to reach over okay
okay thanks thank you very much eagle so
we're still just a little bit ahead of
schedule
egor actually we have he has up for two
slots but he's only going to be using
one of them so Igor you still have you
you could take the 20 minutes or you can
take usually we cut Igor before you jump
in where are the blue sheets you see the
blue sheets who who needs the blue
sheets so if you can pass them back to
those people thank you very much we'll
get a bigger room next time thank you so
this is the work then I'm personally
very excited about and so do micro
office and we have a new co-author which
is Jeff in surah who is also we're
excited about this work but
unfortunately our people outside of this
group we feel kind of to get the the
same level for excitement so far okay so
that's why our basically we have no no
any progress on the model that we
actually wrote before Singapore and it's
fully it's actually written and it's
it's quite good in my opinion right but
but we need to obviously some other
comments on that and I think we have the
same issue I hope that we'll have the
same problem as steam engines right
which we are appreciated not when they
were invented but when the era of the
steam engine arrived right so so what
we're hoping that you
of software at apologist is rapidly
arriving in the form for example as
Network slicing and stuff of that okay
so so we basically are concentrated on
the use cases to bolster our story kind
of right and to get some more excitement
from from people yes so basically just
to remind what what is the whole idea of
this work twenty years ago if you look
at the network it basically it was just
a topology that would explain how the
connectivity services could be provided
on the net or how to get like
information from point A to point B
across the network and then it would
have some kind of T parameters
attributes that you can constrain the
past Alexis stuff like that but
everything was limited only to the
connectivity right so and network today
is a very different animal so network
provides not just connectivity services
but many other services service function
Network functions and for the client it
is very important to see not just the
network topology but also what is
available what kind of services are the
client can outsource you know and it
sees the service not just like a
connectivity a connection or a tunnel
but a change for such tunnels which are
properly constrained and optimized and
connect appropriately selected network
functions so so that the data is not
coming from A to B but experience
certain processing and so forth right so
so we see it's important to provide
information about not just topology
illogical elements but also the service
functions available on this network and
importantly how they are related to the
topology where
do this service function leave or can
leave and so that the user can have a
say as to how the service function chain
not just a tunnel could be created and
optimized so things like that so
graphically the service function where
topology looks like it is on the picture
now so it's it's you can see it for
example like IT topology with 18 nodes
are hosting various service functions
and then we find some components of the
basically topology very useful to
describe for example which service
functions are available on which nodes
and employing connectivity metrics
concept to describe how they and whether
they could be connected at work course
just to remind the connectivity matrix
basically is used to describe that nodes
switching limitations and capabilities
alright so how you can connect say LTP
you want well in termination point one
layer LTP to and the detail connectivity
method basically augments this
information with the weather of course
at what price
this Delta T's could be connected so
that path computation can include
penalties going through the nodes in in
the evaluation for example and using
optimizations on based on different
Beatrix's so what we decided is why not
to employ an intuitive method and in
particular detail connectivity methods
for service functions and describe which
service functions could be connected on
a given node and at what cost for
example what kind of delay would
introduce connect an SF 1 to SF to what
kind of bandwidth limitations how they
could be protected stuff like that and
then we also can provide the similar
connectivity matrices to specify which
service functions could be connected to
nodes
Lync termination points and tunnel
termination points so that various
service functions could be
interconnected not just on the node but
across the network right yltp to the
neighboring node and why TTP's service
fashion could be connected located
anywhere in the network so now basically
what happens is that the path computer
having this knowledge can do what we
call dual optimization and optimize the
selected service function chain on two
criterias on the location of service
functions as well on the tunnels
interconnecting them so and there could
be a pretty good idea how what kind of
end to it to add delay could be for
entire service function as well as for
example between the neighboring service
functions okay
and as we discussed as we present that
in Singapore right there could be
various interesting use cases like for
example how can you or say do proper
optimization of teton also so that the
proper constraints could be satisfied
between the two neighboring service
functions and end-to-end how can you
protect our satisfaction if a node or a
function fails you know how can you go
from how can you do a lot of balance and
and things like that so it's it's pretty
interesting concept and in my personal
opinion it's a it's almost perfect start
for networks why so I I cannot see of
anything better than to describe network
sliced and so forth function who were at
the pole of it now young one of
Kawarthas came was a interesting idea he
said why why stop on service functions
who are not to shoot us into the
and strata okay and basically described
applications can make use of information
about tu they work on and there are
various applications that that could be
considered including for example where
as web caches are like a content network
distribution right like I see a CD ins
and and my personal favorite it's a high
frequency trading application which you
know since I have a bit of luxury I can
entertained a little bit more on that so
so basically imagine that you have a
multi-layer transport network which is
optimized to absolute extreme on time
okay I was shocked personally to know
how much money you can make if you have
the advantage of several microseconds
okay then imagine that you have multiple
applications like for example brokerage
which originated various trade requests
and then and then exchanges running
matching algorithms which find bias and
CLS according subtle algorithms right
and then you have also what they call
duck pools were just like a constraint
exchanges for only constraint users and
then you have application which define
fair market price which you know put
certain constraints a regulatory
regulatory constraint as to how this
mission should be done and so forth and
obviously the name of the game is speed
so how quickly you can learn information
and how quickly you can react on that
right this would give their client for
example the idea aware to put the
application to begin with there is a
very expensive but very profitable
potentially service that exchange can
provide to a client by allowing to what
they call collocate collocation to
collocate there for example brokerages
next to exchanges right and then you can
have you can know how to optimize
your transport network some people for
example replace lambdas with microwaves
just because why can we have speed of
light and fiber doesn't right it has
only a fraction of that so things like
that right so and basically the whole
idea is that there in in ideal world are
this prices and these trades are done
instantaneously but there is always
discrepancies between the current price
and for example on one exchange and the
other exchange and the the price of a
stock and it's derivative like say
option and and future and people are put
in you know morale aside okay but it's
totally legal to exploit these
discrepancies and loopholes and the
client can get a lot of advantages just
looking and optimizing this network and
use the knowledge into what they call
their route in applications that route
there are three requests and distributed
in the most optimal way between
available exchanges so this is just one
way how the model would be also if I'm
high for example for a frequency trading
I would actually you know promote this
kind of model to to work on their own
the advantages and basically how you can
get this model okay so
[Music]
right so so as I said we did erode the
moon the young model for that and but
there are certain challenges that we
have for example we'll rely on the HC
definitions of the services okay so far
we we depend on them and we try to be
dependent on them as loose as possible
we just use service IDs and source
instance IDs like a big numbers but
interested client might want to
understand what the services are
especially to understand their in extent
of mutual substitutive for example if I
want they have a fella on one note of a
certain function and I want to go to
another node so I need to understand how
similar these functions and to what
extent they can substitute each other
right so the problem that we have it's
basically the egg and chicken right so
on one hand we are told that we cannot
define the services ourselves because
that's the job of get see but for
example on the other hand se is not
quick enough right so the progress is
very very small so what can we do about
this so can we for example issue license
as we do to ITU or top of that or on
water but in order to get to this stage
right we need to have some sort of
interest in this call so and I hope that
Network slicin will actually produce a
sufficient interest and sufficient power
that we can leverage such instruments
right so one of the courses Louise I
don't know whether it is in the yeah
yeah he mentioned that he would bring
this Moodle Internet wise and
environment and yes we will try to do
our best to actually use this as a very
important use case for for this model
and once we get to this point there
obviously though the various comments
and
recommendations as to how to modify
augment our model that's a question
question Tarek Francisco hi your yeah if
you go back to one of the figures that
you had your show us a previous so the
the service function the way you've
modeled it is a property of I know yes
do you think the service function can be
in a standalone and a function element
in your model not hosted on a routing or
switching switch or another outing or
switching node yeah you understand that
note is not a switch it's basically it's
it's a it could be anything from a
domain or it's it's an absurd node okay
it could be a physical switch it could
be a part of a physical switch as we
discussed right right and the reason why
we make it properties of the note that
when we use connectivity methods which
is by the way a property of a node right
we use like a several connectivity
matrices one of them to describe how the
service function could be changed
locally on this world right
but also very importantly how this
service functions could be hooked to the
link termination points of a node at
tunnel termination of a node so that
they could be connected across the
network
okay so in order to combine for example
tea links right with the service
functions and their course right so we
had to go this way if it would produce
like a separate note it would be totally
different picture and personally I don't
see an advantage to let right I would
actually add even applications as
attributes to the north so the note
could be for example a data center I see
so the node is not specific as a routing
or switch no no it's any abstract no yes
in particular and most important it
could be as a data center okay thanks
this is a fact I'm comment verification
so I tell some examples on the service
function you listed in this chapter
including for example firewalls epi
I think they a they are all applicable
for the Paki network so my comment is if
the service faction of where technology
can also be applicable for the chance
for Network OTN
yeah excellent question so in the draft
we actually have use cases which try to
illustrate that the service functions
and network functions in particular may
apply to transport network for example
you may think about service for the
network function as three re generator
right and you can and normally people
put through our generators in like
strategic pools like I said
strategically replace all the network
and this would make for T application
very interesting to your application
with you can assign dynamically
regenerators without having operators to
explicitly specify where they for
example based on optical environments
consideration okay so this would be one
a use case for like layer 1 layer 0
network function the other there are
other examples like for example certain
thorium capabilities they require
certain hardware support or the Indian
network which is not readily available
on all devices this also could be
modeled that what Martin results
actually suggested they also could be
modeled as network functions which so
basically only certain but not all
network elements will have such
possibilities and then you can route
your tunnels in such a way that
oi'm will be like a most feasible and
most efficient
yeah okay thank you so could you add
this kind of examples in this job to
make people have clear yeah there is
there are use case that there are use
case are I believe six and seven I don't
remember which describe each such use
case separately amount you from Siena so
you have an SMC with the T constraint
what about the service constraints
themselves so you know the replications
of the services of ability of the
services and things like that yet
does that affect apology no no the whole
point is that we're trying to build this
Moodle as an augmentation to cheat on a
tree topology model right and this model
will provide the identity of the
functions that available on the network
as well as the constraint as for how
this functions could be connected
locally and the course in network right
but you say for instance you have a
firewall but that particular firewall
and a particular node is utilized ninety
percent and you only have a 10 percent
of ability now there could be other
places where the firewall is available
was your topology change based on the
service of ability and the percentage
utilization or the viability of the
service itself not you know that you
have a key constraint you know how
quickly you can get between the services
and delays and all that stuff right now
but I'm talking about the service itself
is that taken into consideration
point so basically so far we haven't
considered their attributes of the
Souris functions per se because we hoped
that by looking up like definitions
defined by HC and the models like Tosca
Moodle support that we could get such
information but we might get actually
the resources that available on for
service function basis
partially we consider that because when
we say connect source version one
without ammunition point we specify at
which breathless it could be connected
okay obviously could not be more than
breakfast available on the function
itself right yeah but but but it
probably could be a problem could be a
good idea to have that you know to
separate the connectivity versus the
actual resource a way above the function
right I think they will consider what
yeah
IV sigani future we yeah this is
interesting because we are looking into
separating the service layer and
primarily our information model I don't
know you Korea looked at it or not the
information model includes the service
function and this topology graph and
that graph will basically primarily
tribes their service layer connectivity
nothing at the network level now there's
a separation of the information model
from the data model describe the actual
network are you planning to separate
those two layers because because someone
mentioned that if s service function is
the attribute of the node or my opinion
to know that service function that layer
is different from the actual network
connectivity if you and really connect
those points together you need to define
like a data model you mentioned task
area so you have want to map the toss
about the service layer into a data
model at that data model could be
specific to your underlying network okay
for example if you say layer 2 network
where they are trimming is that
separation is already I have yet you
draft yet but is that the part of your
desk over your draft or no oh well what
we are trying to achieve is that we want
to decouple service models from from
basically the topology models right and
but we also want to combine them
together in a way that you can do this
dual optimization so it doesn't matter
for us whether it's Bosco no postcode it
have produced service models as far as
their should could be some IDs that
could could be used to interconnect this
models I personally do not like very
complex Eon models which you know with
more man porn stuff out there
I prefer much better to have a simple
models that could be interrelated based
on like IDs rather than full say X
passes and perfect and because one
reason is that some clients may be
interested for certain things but not
others and they don't want to bother
with a lot a very large and complex
models so if I am only interested as to
how service functions could be connected
but I'm not interested what exactly they
are doing that's that's that's possible
but if I want to also understand what
they're doing that also possible but
only for intercept task lines right so
so so keep keep in mind where we are
right now is looking at the use case
document not the solution document so
before we even get to solutions we have
to agree on the on the use cases and
we've actually managed to fill up both
time slots we had one more question from
the floor Jeff if it's about a solution
don't talk about please
so just there's difference between
network view and application application
driven networking and you should look it
from perspective of network doing
application so imagine it's front hall
and a particular constraint this where
it's going to play we don't want to mix
viral capacity with you know what
dealing right and that will be very good
to capture in the use cases no in the
use cases if that's what we want to be
working on please then we can't then we
shouldn't talk about it no please answer
that offline yeah so we
keep in mind that we're talking about
the use cases here and the question for
the working group is does this working
group want to work on this type of these
types of solutions and if we do talking
about identifying what the use cases are
is a great place to start so the first
question for the working group is do we
want to be working on these types of
solutions that Igor has been talking
about I think we've got some good
support on that how many people think
that the document that was presented is
a reasonable place to start the
discussion on what are the use cases I
would say the same number note that I
did not ask how many have read the
document so I will ask that now how many
of read the document slightly more than
the previous two but the previous two
questions had I think had good support
thank you very much well we'll talk
offline the chairs and I assume you'll
see it on the list thank you and eager
thank you for putting us back on time
with that we're gonna jump to the next
slot oops BAE
beer te furless
and if we can take to 15 minutes instead
of money thank you
so okay um we've got this be a working
group what we've been defining you know
new multicast forwarding and I wanted to
give a quick background of that so the
state is that we've basically finished
the definition of the shortest path
forwarding model which we call beer and
have adopted the forwarding plane model
for the you know hop-by-hop
controlled forwarding for traffic
engineering and with the working group
going more towards an attract now we are
also asked to follow the standard track
way of you know splitting up the work
into the appropriate working group so
for example any future IGP work which
we've done in the past in the beer
working group itself would now be an LS
R and likewise the you know architecture
for the anything about the control plane
architecture of traffic engineering in
beer te would have to be in T's and then
obviously spread out into PC Els R or
any other working groups where we would
want to have the specific drafts done in
so next slide you have a right so let me
give you quickly the background here a
traditional multicast problem so why are
we doing beer the problem multicast is
that instead of simply having prefix or
seat forwarding entries that are the
size of your network topology in
traditional multicast you have
forwarding and control plane state that
you need to build on every transit hub
in the network which we call multicast
trees and the number that you need is
you know the possible number of sources
by the possible number of subsets of
receivers in the network you have 50
receivers worst case until tenant and
source you have ten by the power a two
by the power of ten times two by the
power of fifty different trees that you
need to build right and you know
operators weren't really so keen and
managing all these trees in the network
so that's basically the root cause for
going to a model which you know similar
to segment routing tries to avoid having
stayed in the network
and it's even worse in multicast because
in you know segment routing it's still
only about the path topology and the
number of pests you want to have so it's
really independent of most of the
application specifics while a multicast
it's very naturally based on how many
applications you're running so this is
basically for later reading writes I
didn't wanna show all that stuff so with
beer proper there is no state in the
network anymore right so basically I'm
not sure if it's appropriate but let me
try to explain it in terms of segment
routing right so imagine that instead of
simply having you know the LD pre fee
pre LD P LD P free network with you know
a single label to indicate a receiver in
the network now basically in your packet
header you have just you know a sequence
of all the possible receivers you want
this negative received it right so
basically you want to send it to p2 p3
you basically put the seats of p2 p3 in
there and let me see if we can actually
have this so in p1 you're looking at the
packet and you're saying oh wait a
second so I need to send it to p2 p3 so
let me make one copy to every interface
where I have from my routing table at
least one receiver there that's pretty
much what beer does on every hop it
basically looks at all the destination
addresses and figures out okay which
interfaces do I need to send one copy to
every interface where I have one or more
receivers behind it and basically you
know it's you it's just routing on the
shortest path okay you say but if I have
20 or 128-bit for every address the
header gets fairly large if I want to
address something like 50 or 100
receivers which is why we're simply
addressing every receiver by a single
bit write our address space is from
address 1 to address 256 or could get as
large as 1,024 if your header is a
thousand 24 bits and that's basically
what we're showing down there right
you've got the beer header and here you
see two red bits so bit number two okay
this packet needs to go to p2 bit number
three green right two three and four and
five right so basically you know you can
compress addresses down to bits
if you don't have that many and well if
you now have something like maybe a
thousand peas in that you need to target
and you only want to you know have an
overhead of 256 bits well what are you
going to do you're simply going to send
well maybe four packets right so yes
multicast originally you said one tree
is good enough but when the trees
actually become a problem maybe it's
less of an overhead to basically instead
say well I'm still getting a benefit of
twenty fifty six times less data to send
so why do we need to do more so
basically that's why you know the bit
string language support typically 256
bits for beer is seen as good enough and
otherwise you'll send more packets so
this is basically you know the typical
shortest path architecture so the path
engineering that you can do in this
environment is typically based on a
really nice ecmp architecture we have
there and based on you know using all
type of different topologies of an IGP
and engineering your IGP but it's of
course doesn't support the typical
explicit path set up that were known
from rsvp-te or that we can do in
segment routing with specifying also a
label stack with intermediate house so
that is exactly where te comes in beauty
and so in beer to e the bits are not
indicating only the receivers but
they're simply indicating the interfaces
on the path themselves so for example
with the same type of trees the the red
one as one g1 going here basically you
would need the following bits right from
the sender you would basically say okay
this interface here is bit number two
this interface three four five and you
would basically just set to three or
five those bits in the beer header to
get basic you need the packet passed
over this non shortest path here and
then replicate it here likewise the
other examples right you just assign
bits to every interface and again like
in the beer case one bit for every
address you need the big forwarding
difference is simply that in beer you're
looking on every
hop in all the destination address and
trying to figure out where to send it to
and the logic in beer te is very simply
that you simply need to look only at
those bits that you have direct
adjacencies right P one would never
bother looking into whether there is
another copy going up here overbid three
four five four so it's simply ignoring
all the bits that it doesn't have direct
adjacencies for but otherwise it also in
peril looks at all the bits and
individually creates copies for every
bit that is being said and that's the
direct adjacency so that's basically the
simple rule now obviously there is a
good discussion about what is the bit
overhead that we have how large can the
topologies become the forwarding
architecture has a lot of details about
that and so there are a lot of tricks to
reuse the same bits in different parts
of the topology I was just here showing
a simple case that obviously on a
point-to-point link both sides can use
the same bit right so you just need one
bit in the same way a LAN can use one
bit a ring could use two bits for you
know clockwise and counterclockwise so a
lot of options to optimize the number of
bits you need for intermediate hops to
steal the traffic through the topology
so maybe we're getting up to if you have
twenty 56 bits maybe you still get you
know 5200 copies being sent out over the
engineered path and the rest would be
the path bits that you're interested in
so two more things finishing up the
architecture so the routed adjacencies
and there is a picture later on the
presentation to give you an idea is
exactly to even further simplify the
number of bits that you need and that's
really if you want to build an overlay
topology where you're saying I really
only need replication a few points in my
topology that I want to steer traffic
true and basically in between that are
not going to do hop-by-hop path with
beer but i'm just going to build for
example segment routing tunnels between
the different replication points and
that's what we call routed adjacency you
have some bit you replicate but you
don't send it to a direct neighbor you
send it through you know an adjacency
which you have predefined to be a
segment routing town the other part is
that one of the interesting use case
areas that were targeting with the beer
te is that net and in that net there is
a functionality called packet
replication illumination
which basically is about the fact that
you want to have traffic engineering to
build dual non-overlapping path through
the network to sent the same traffic
twice and on the receiver side eliminate
the duplicates and therefore creating a
highly resilient architecture so there
is in the drafts that we have up for
this in the working group some
interactions between beer te and this
and obviously you know given that the
resilience and not only the path
selections to keep heart of the dead net
use cases we felt that for the framework
of traffic engineering wanted to include
this a resilient functions as well and a
proper to figure out how to basically
provision and manage them okay so how do
we do the traffic management in terms of
okay how does it work from from the
traffic perspective and so I was trying
to show here the starting point there is
not that much documentation about this
in the zero zero version of the draft
but if you think about it right in beer
how do you create a bit string you
create a bit string by knowing on the
sender what are the receivers I'm
interested in each receiver I have a bit
for and I'm just oaring the different
bit in the bit string and then I send
off the packet into beer right so
basically it's getting replicated to all
the receivers one bit per receiver that
I need to remember now in beer to e if I
do pre calculate paths that I want to
use ultimately what you're ending up is
you have from a particular source to a
particular receiver just you know a bit
string with the individual hops that you
need to go through and you can equally
or them right so if you say oh I have
pre calculated on my PC controller you
know for one particular set of
applications the set of paths then it's
basically one path from every particular
source to receiver and the source can
basically or these paths together to
basically multicast the data so from
that perspective there is a really nice
easy way to basically create pre
calculated path where then the sender
can individually still you know if one
receiver joints and leaves the multicast
group he doesn't have to necessarily go
back to the PC controller subject to
bandwidth management of course they're
really fun you know minimum overall cost
they're called Steiner trees which means
you remove one receiver you need to
recalculate the whole path obviously
somewhat different but if you try to do
the same thing with rsvp-te
point-to-multipoint well you have to do
a lot of reasoning and here you know in
gear two it would simply be a local
calculation on the sender and Evol are
you send up a new packet with a
different bit string and get a different
tree cost two-minute warning yeah that
sort okay so this is basically the the
overall architecture that we're
proposing with all the underlay here is
basically the beer stuff and basically
the signaling to a PC controller
provisioning system let me quickly try
to go through that so what we've been
trying to figure out in the 0-0 draft is
how to provide a framework where we can
use the PC controller for everything or
just for the provisioning then using the
IGP to disseminate the information for
diagnostics for basically automatically
overcoming inconsistencies and then also
to enabling the sources to actually
calculate paths if that's desired so
just the framework or these different
things and so one of the next steps is
then figuring out you know what type of
data models do we need to build out in
yang so what the rest of the slides here
is and I think we're running out of time
so maybe taking up next time or maybe
you know in the PC working group world
presenting so we can go into more detail
there let me skip through those details
but here's basically kind of two slides
about the data model that we think is
going to be the target for whether we're
going from a PCE controller or the same
information to put in an IDP and yeah so
we basically would like to start you
know going forward with the framework
figuring out what pieces are missing in
the framework and then basically
identify what the next product call
steps are like the yang model the
Eleazar extensions and yeah get the the
guidance from the t's working group on
you know how to how to do that work in
you know the process that the IDF
established right so running around
between all these different working
groups how to do that correctly to
process right so any guidance yeah it
may be a little quick
because we didn't have a lot of time and
appreciate you cutting a little short
there's actually a lot of commonality
here with what we're doing with any
controller based path selection and
control it's just that the way the
control is instantiated is in the data
plane rather than through control plane
signaling so there actually is some
really good overlap with the work that's
going on here so it's definitely worth
looking at this document if you if you
haven't and I think you'll be surprised
to see the the common eye ideas how many
people have looked at this work but
that's actually a reasonable number and
how many more if you didn't raise your
hand before interested in hearing more
about it or pursuing it in this working
group so a few more hands so you know
the the it looks like there's some some
good interest here maybe it's a little
early to try to go for adoption but
you're not asking for that so that's
that's okay so you know I think that
there's good alignment and the technical
side there seems to be interesting or so
thank you for bringing in here
hi this is true again and I'll be
talking about her Ikey or IP controllers
so basically this is not something new
the the idea here is basically to kind
of capture how what we have already
developed in the T these working group
with respect to a CTN and the various de
Young models how they actually get work
in a real IP controller where you have
key components and the non key
components and you have various other
protocols that are running you are using
PCA on EGP there's so many different
things that we have been working across
in various different working groups
within T's and outside T's working group
as well so how they come together how is
it in a CTN framework that we have
developed yet applies in the IP
controller case so those are the things
that we have tried to capture in this
document and it's an informational
document it covers basically various
interactions talked about other protocol
considerations talks about the services
that we offer the IP services and how
are they realized and also notes if
there is some missing pieces that's
something that we need to work on which
is not currently captured in the
existing solutions there are so nothing
new here you have like you know the
domain controllers you have somebody
like a super controller a super
controller receives the request from the
customer breaks down into tasks that
each domain controller has to take care
of and it does the coordination function
something that we very well know in the
AC T and in this working group so the
main thing that we wanted to capture was
that what we define in the AC TN
basically is are some functional blocks
and these are the functional things that
any controller needs to our needs to
implement so within the controller you
may have various other functions and the
actn part is just the functional block
which is nothing but our MDS C and P and
C and those are the functional block
within the physical controller that
packages multiple other functions so you
have your empty
interface which is focusing on the
teapot and the actn part but you would
also need various other non tea
interactions to actually get IP service
established so this was usually because
there is when we talk about a CTN there
has been some confusion with respect to
what is the real value how does it
actually helps in setting up IP services
so don't those words that's why we
thought that writing this information
model and capturing those things also
would help to realize that inside the
hierarchy of IP controllers how it is
being used and we also try to cover the
interactions between the nandi parts so
for example is there any interaction
with BGP what are the set of other young
models how do we do ohmmm after the
service is established all those things
we want to capture this is just a 0/0
version but that's the vision that we
have with this document and focus that
when when we say mdac and PNC we really
don't mean the full controller but only
the functional block which is doing the
ECT and functionality and then you would
need lot of other things this is not new
even the abner and the other work that
has captured that that even the PCE is
just a functional block within your
controller which does the path
imputation but you would need multiple
other things to actually establish a
service using this architecture so in
the next slide I am focusing on some of
the key concept this did not change this
remains exactly what actn described we
we can implement it it why are various
different mechanism the PNC we very well
know can take part in ICP and learn the
topology it can learn why a BGP LS there
has been other proposals like piece F LS
as well as yang based the T topology
model mechanism to learn the topology
but the topology between the PNC and MD
SC and the domain controller and super
controller would also need to worry
about the abstraction and this level of
and we have the other document which
talks about various level of
abstractions that could be there which
is why topology great apology
like topology and all those things are
already well supported with the
protocols that we have so for example in
VG pls case or P sub LS case we could
carry abstract topology and Mark that
this topology how it is being abstracted
and of course the Yankee model captures
this quite well but the job of the MDS
is also to take care of the end-to-end
topology that it might be exposing to
the customer so we have just tried to at
one place try to list all the different
possibilities that is there with respect
to the top topology building so you have
your tea the yang based work that we do
in this working group but then there is
some other pointers to other things that
are happening which are outside the
working group as well similarly with
path computation and instantiation
completely aligned to the acct and
framework what we have already captured
and again it list is what are the
possibilities for us to actually do this
work
it could be yang based there as well we
have two options we have the tea tunnel
compute only and other options as well
as to instantiate a tunnel why the tea
topology model we have the part
computation yang model which uses the
are pcs so these are the set of things
which are yang base and of course via p
sub based work that we have been doing
in the PCC working group which is how
stateful HPC could be used to do part
setup from super controller or the ndse
to be NC so nothing new here this is
just to list what are the possible
options that we have when we are
implementing this next we are we move on
to some of the services that we offer so
we are focusing here on the IP services
so seamless MPLS l3 VPN l2 VPN etc so
what are the various interactions that
needs to be done when we have to
establish a service so in case of a
seamless
MPLS what are the jobs that the
controller needs to do what would be
done why are various interfaces so that
we have tried to capture that one of the
key thing that the super controller
might have to do is selection of what
are the boundary nodes or the ABR s that
I need to a
use of course you need to do the service
model to the network model to device
model translation which has been
discussed in the ops area as well and
apart from the configuration part there
is of course the tunnel selection and
the AC TM thought that comes in that
what are the parts that needs to be set
up how do we set up the domain parts and
stitch them together to form end to end
an SP so that part we have tried to
capture another key thing would also be
is there any role of running controlling
protocols like BGP between the domain
controller and the super controller in
form of RR functionality that the BGP
provides and what else how we could use
that information at the super controller
to make some intelligent decisions etc
similarly in l3 VPN this is actually
covered in the service model part as
well maybe we are talking about how the
mapping between the service model and
the and the a CDN and the T would be
done so this kind of captures that and
though sometimes we may receive the
service in form of a service model we
need to decide based on the QoS and
policy requirements what kind of tunnels
that needs to be actually established
what are the set of boundary nodes that
I have to use and what is the map type
for example this is something that was
discussed in the service model so that
is captured here the dear mayor might be
a requirement to bind a tunnel or to
reuse a tunnel or just make some
modifications so those things are
captured and what will be the mechanism
used so if you are using a CDN
interfaces we have a choice of what's
the job of the the MBI interfaces and it
can be implemented by a piece F or it
could be implemented by the yang
mechanism but apart from that we also
have the configuration translation from
a service model into the network model
into the device model and something that
we we are highlighting is that the
network model is some piece that is kind
of missing you know we have the service
model we have the device model but
representing this at the network domain
level is something that needs to be
worked on and what's applicable to l-3
sm is also applicable to l to SM for
giving L to
B&R evpn services then we move on to the
protocols and the models so those were
the services what what are the choices
with respect to various protocols so we
have some control plane protocols that
could be used so we have tried to
capture PC and BGP and possibly if there
is a role of BMP there that's something
that needs to be investigated further
and with respect to can management plane
what are the various sets of yang model
and what are the roles that those young
models are playing so PC has a lot long
history that this is the ladder that the
PC working group has worked on and we
are very well aligned to the
requirements that we have with respect
to this hierarchy of IP controllers now
with respect to yang models the service
models are well established something
which we need to think about a little is
the network configuration model where
from the domain point of view how do we
represents what is the service that
needs to be implemented which gets
translated into the device model which
is the V RF and the actual instantiation
on the border nodes the work about
topology and Tunnel that's well
established the VN and the service
mapping is what we discussed and how we
will do another thing we you need to
worry about is how do we give the status
or the OEM functionality to - while we
are establishing these IP services and
how we link them with the with the
service part as well as the network
tunnel part and how do we give us
unified view to the customer so that's
something that's missing and I'm sure
there are other yang models that are
being developed at other places that we
would like to capture so that like you
know we can point out to how if we have
to implement this these are the set of
things that you need to look at some of
the things that we we are highlighting
is as a possible features or extensions
that can be done and of course depends
upon the protocol choice and how based
on that protocol how do you implement
these things the image initial
configuration right now when we are
establishing various controllers and you
have a domain controller and a super
controller or a PNC and mdac how is this
relationship established how do we learn
about their individual capabilities and
the role that they are playing
and how do we work with when you have
multiple instances of the same
controller a different level for
reliability how is your protocol taking
that into consideration so those are the
things that some thickness that we need
to think about and highlight while we
are also working on this topic so aim
for this presentation was basically to
get some feedback on whether this kind
of work is useful and what what else are
we not thinking about what can be added
what's not in scope and that should be
removed we still of course agree that
this is just the starting point there is
a lot of things which are missing so
some of the things that we know that we
have not added is about yang models more
details about BGP om etc so if this is
something that interests you please help
us and join us
and I'm done thank you any comments all
right thank you very much this ends the
our teas working group session at in
London we do not have another session we
don't have a joint session thank you
very much for contributing look forward
to seeing contribution on the list blue
sheet there's we're missing a blue sheet
does someone have the other blue sheet
[Music]