I have all the slides yes and I
what about Russ's well tell us in detail
is to connect my dear old everyone so
we're gonna which orders what's the
water again reordering look us in is
that upward No
okay so connection - are these in the
right or in an app okay folks this is
the tos meeting we're gonna get started
in about a minute what's matter
you need a welcome to the second session
of TLS this week once again you should
be familiar with the note well the blue
sheets and are going around the room so
please sign them and as always when you
come up to the mic please state your
name and keep it professional so we have
a pretty full agenda today but it should
be stuff we can all get through a little
less controversial than yesterday on
Monday yep so okay excuse me one of the
things that we do typically at an ITF
when we have a change of leadership
which will happen later tonight as we
present a gift to our outgoing Area
Director we have such a thing so
Kathleen's please come to the front
we're gonna provide you some wine for to
drink after Monday there you go thanks a
lot
[Applause]
thank you all for the work that you do
all right we're not going to do the
document status because nothing has
really changed other than a new version
of TLS 1.3 popped out and it's been
pressed for approved so it's going the
are theaters cue we're very happy about
that
Brice if we find anything we're pulling
it back that's been the deal all along
so everyone should remember that however
to commemorate that we did make some
stickers so we're going to give out some
stickers and you can you know take some
and pass them around add some other
things planned but it's stuck in customs
so that's life all right do you want to
go ahead kind of hand these out there go
from there
don't take them all we got a lot but
just in case and so that's about it 40s
1.3 quick minute and a half so now we're
gonna move on to detail s and connection
ID yeah we should be done alrighty
a career
so it turned out so it turned out that
like the only thing I want to talk about
with DTLS 1/3 was the same thing one
higher connection ID so we're just gonna
glue this together so I'll let you
figure out which part of the talk this
is next slide please
so the when we showed you so when we
first did it like to tell us one point
three we found up to a pressure ID in
and then like people like we're sad
about that specific actually you draft
out and then people were like why don't
we do a cash ID draft that does detail
s12 and details when with right and I
was like sure not that I really care but
sure and it turns out that like I should
I wanted the man for detail offs one -
can I show you yet today
gallant DTLS one two now and they're
gonna have to heal from with me later
but like you know they can wait a little
longer for that but like knowing them
now they're kind of sucks with one two
so buy anything gets the little stock on
exactly the right way to encode the cash
ID letters and so I this ID yesterday
which was basically there's like a
little bit of question about whether or
not the deals 1.3 headers that were
posing or like exactly we want and and
also has a bunch of conversations are
correct about like maybe we should heart
still some of their stuff or or you know
whether they should be the same or
whatever on and so me whenever I scroll
down a little bit
um so keeping with that is good um but
on the other hand like dragging down
details for a new connection ID while we
think about two or three cash ID like
not great so next slide that said there
is like a sort of tactical issue and
principle we need resolved that we need
to do if we're going to do this so um if
you're going to have connect so so like
in quick there's always a connection ID
but we have other big install bases GL's
1.2 and that does not have a connection
ID and so a server client or so but most
likely a server may find itself in the
position where it has client support and
do not support the connection ID you
know extension and so now they get
packets and they and they have to
determine with that fisheye in them in
order in order to like rock them down
the right pipe
on that is affordable writing or to do
cie base writing um and um so it was
suggested that one way to do this an
obvious way to do this it's definitely
indicate a bit ahead of your president
could actually absent as I'll be
splitting in a minute this isn't like
necessary you can make it work without
this but it like is convenient for
various kinds of like packet parsing
it's particular convenient if you're
like something passive is special like
Wireshark where you don't know exactly
the server's behaviorist um this might
be a little less necessary in 1/3 than
1/2 because in principle you have like a
1/3 1/2 C ad no C ad server and like
refusing to go she 1/3 if like they
didn't do say that I D so I might help a
little bit but regardless it's it's a
real palm for 1/2 on so the in 1/2 and
1/3 the 1/2 and the ones we learn header
there's like a lot of wasted space so
you know you're allowed to have a length
of up to 64 kilobits in principle enough
bits for it but you can only have but
like 2 of those per set to be zero and
we don't and there's like a full play
for content type but like we have like
20 content types
there's like a lot of space there but
when we just do some 1.3 short header we
like packed everything really hard down
there's actually no extra space at all
and in fact as I'm about to say in a
minute there may actually be a little
less space than you'd like to have so we
didn't know what we're gonna do like
enough with 1.3 1.3
to make sure that we're not like taking
a path than 1.2 that screws everything
up for 1.3 next slide so they're
basically two technical options here
which I've been calling implicit and
explicit connection IDs worth noting
quickest side is do both in the quick
long header it'll be explicit connection
IDs and the quick shortcut it'll be
implicit connection ID so Merry
Christmas
the so if you're ready to implicit but
as I say in quick that's easy because in
quick you know where the thing is
present or not so so it's easier um so
important remember that in details 1.3
and now in quick
the receiver controls a connection ID so
you have an opportunity to stress the
connection ID in a way that's easy to
deem ox in the eye this is everything
here should say DTLS instead of TLS I
like I've written TLS so many times I
just like Oh alrighty TLS but actually
true story like I I took TCP as TLS lots
of times so anyway um so regardless in
the current headers the connection ID
goes right in the lonely header and
details 123 and in the Choson put do
better the CID was right for the length
and so all you need to do is determine
where the next byte is length or CID
so because links going to get into it
create an equation to the 1404 forbidden
if you just set the high bit in the CID
then you can like look at that and you
know it's the length for a CID now maybe
you have no box problems maybe you don't
that's your fault that's your problem
like we're cars less you go to detox the
so that's a big us a very
straightforward um the short header is
harder because there's no length filled
the d-max and so the thing of doom I
saying against is like just a random
trash but that gives the opportunity to
which is basically you fix the first
inputs of the connection ad to something
and the server knows that something is
and this is the first n bits of sefar -
no random then if you do a chance of
collision is 2 to the minus M right and
so you can pick any error rate you
please by like the cost of n bits and
then you if there's somewhere to - send
rate of false positives and if you get a
false positive try to decrypt and if it
fails you can here to score the packet
or you can be like oh now I'm going to
fall back to enter port running um so so
this is my argument that is not in fact
necessary to have any any extra
indicator indicator bit in the protocol
proper um that said one might think this
was nasty and particularly for like
Wireshark guy you might think this is
like really nasty because you don't know
you know because server a chooses the
magic string FF and sort of each use the
matters of string like you know dead
thief and that you don't know how to
parse it so so you might think that you
want like a bit um next slide
so like yeah again like so it's like the
thing we got stuck on is like the bit
like for the one two in the long header
this like seems like an aesthetic choice
namely it's like you know there's a bit
we got some rooms like really like just
aesthetic right put the short hair
because I have no room it's actually
like we have to pay for that somehow and
then the crappy part is like be an
entire plate for hit because you have no
room and we're not gonna like you know
we're not gonna have the like safer text
not beat it not be biologics that would
be crazy so to me redesign on email
Thomas suggested expanding by one by
using something bits or flags um now
separately it's occurred to me that we
may have crammed the header down a
little too hard and the details won't
put your sequence number in the short
header is like 12 bits and it's like
it's actually quite possible to have a
situation where like you're referring
that 12 bits and you're forcing the long
header just because you don't have the
ambiguity about the sequence number so
like I was sort of against this and then
I sort of think it's sequence every
t-shirt and I started getting more for
it so what about to show you is like one
of a number of options for basically
trying to like make lemonade out of this
lemon that arguably like makes the world
better
on several problems and also get some
space for the CID bit um it's important
to note this is not the only way to do
this um there's a number options um well
I'm hoping to get your sense on today is
like we think this is like worth being
in principle and we can discuss how to
pack the bits lit next slide so here's
like one design we drop the first byte
for we take the first bite and rumor has
to answer our 1000 won for deconfliction
reasons and then we assign two new bits
C which means the caches president l
which means the length is present and
then the next three bits are just are
just xxx so just um they're just all
reserves um we probably have to grease
them but that's easy enough to do and
then the epic and the sequence are
packed together in the innovate
arraigning two bytes so three right
headers those who um the so
this gives you to attribute expansion of
the sequence number which is quite a bit
more room than probably is enough room
for anybody because pretty hard together
I get that far out ahead of it this is
not the most optimal packing on this the
packet is most flexibility there's
another alternate packing next slide
which I can actually show but I guess
late play out this gives us 100 format
not too because you don't need to have
the detail on say for these know short
staff vertex this can carry both because
basically you have enough room and
you're enough room for the two but Depok
bits which is why you needed the long
version and you had out form to the
light and you can have lengths be
optional so you can do the piggyback
you're not PD back at your discretion
because to Marisa seeks number and as
you see we have three more of these
three months like this if you want them
um another possibility if we decided we
wanted a longer sequence number a stash
of the two epic bits into the go back
for a second into those two xx's and
then we have one more flight that
remaining if we wanted it and then we
have a fixed 16-bit sequence number
there's now a variety of other things
you could do to you could like you know
you can also have one of those bits be
like how long the sequence number is you
could have like a like a rather I got
like an 8 and a 16 or 18 or 24 like a
lot of stuff you could do here right
depending on exactly how how much
flexibility the flexibility versus like
compactness Draft at the stages again so
nice Lovelace so so I certainly again we
don't need to exactly this um we might
did that in a day decide to rip off the
quick headers which have other merits or
key merits so I think the question I
want to ask is is like if people like
sufficiently persuasive to people but
this makes them comfortable with having
a CID indicator bit in which case we got
to see the indicated bit we can close
the T to tell us where to issue and
spend a little time by shedding about it
about the structure um next slide I
think I just to say I just said right so
I mean I guess that's the question I
think we should focus on is do we want
this bit at all if we do want a bit if
we're doing a bit then like we can just
publish the CIT you're after and we can
be finished if we if we do in a bit then
we can just basically define this piece
of details and point you right away and
then there's some question about whether
or not like is best used a common type
of length I'm one argues there's best to
use the
Piper to think he's probably right about
but you might think about the length
where other spits another place and then
we could spend a little time tuning the
details we play three format but there's
no actual like there's like less urgency
for dealing with that so I guess um I'm
eventually I was eventually persuaded
this was the right that the right answer
was to have the bit and to go that way
but I like the other people um so I was
previously more in favor of implicit
approach but now I'm leaving today
explicit one that you proposed I think
it's just Tina I also like this new
headed a sign I don't care much on what
I we encode the information in in the
content type or in the lens to it I I
don't have an opinion about that also
that sort of splits are having a
two-stage approach first trying to do
something for one or two appears to be
better because that's where what people
are currently deploying and you're
seeing and if we could get them to to
support this functionality as quickly as
possible apathy that would be very
useful in 40d less one two three they
have a few months additional months time
to do that so um so I think it's a great
idea
Thank You doc are there any privacy
implications you want to talk about
about having you see any business not we
probably should mention Sony with that I
think generally my sense is it's pretty
obvious when the see the attacker can
generate I want to see ID as far as I
can see is constant so I think it's in
it I think I think it's I think it's
like one of these things that like it's
extremely annoying to parse but actually
doesn't have like any privacy impact I
mean the CID existing is a privacy at
bat but like I don't think I don't think
is like what doesn't tell you much our
secret that's there
I mean favor of exclusive as you already
for all the reasons that have already
stated only million links to me offline
I think this this design is is fantastic
it destroys the phone sticker to me
between short and long it's just
fantastic
so you found the error your phone and on
opportunistically
times up for this
to be a STONER wowie
I'm in favor of the explicit version
mostly for the same reason as Hannes
mentioned because it's cleaner and like
I'm really scared of things like metric
number type of approaches the first one
has that kind of feel and this potential
volatility about unpredictable behavior
so I think that's better
the second Pro second comment I would
make is if we can see that we can do
this relatively soon as that would be
very good because there's a lot of need
out there that's really waiting for this
to be finalized so one person to do is
all split the data to pieces 1/4 1/2 and
1/4 1/3 and we can publish the
one-to-one this is if every issues
resolved and the 131 we can maybe
emotionally to you too but like that
with them we won't have to then we can
spend more time think about that in
Thompson I've previously been pretty
strong advocate for the implicit one I
just like to make it clear that the
getting what we gained in this case
really largely accrues to middleboxes
Rather's load balancers tools and
whatnot
and that's not a bad thing I I think
based on the discussion here and and
talking with people I think that this
this is probably the right design and
plenty of paint if we want to talk about
yeah well we're painting later there are
only so many options
that preserve a reasonable balance
between size and the universe the size
of the sequence number against the size
of a header but that's that's something
we do I don't think we can steal quicks
design simply because this democracy
optim-ox yes right I do think there is a
piece of quiz design we're gonna
probably want to steal which is
encrypted sequence numbers yes that will
be an interesting discussion based on
the private discussions I've had a very
encrypted sequence numbers in quick
right but I guess what I would say is I
would think that I think the TLS de
lausanne quick should agree about other
than curtis sequence numbers because of
the city zapping the same setting and
yeah
gonna be fun died great Thomas there's a
there's also the point about feature
parity between 1/2 and 1/3 in terms of
seat updates I think we express this ok
looks like so I think Oh sounds like
people are okay with this way forward
yeah does it does anybody opposed to
explicit alright yeah I think that's the
way forward okay right so second issue
is if you have multiple C IDs and you
chip in you and you do and you like do
you like you know you know change your
path change and the sequence numbers
just like a linear doesn't like you
instantly like there's no point home
with little C IDs because like is like
oh this is like you know ff01 and this
one's FS 0 or 2 and like CID is random
but I can't doesn't matter it's like I
what came next right so when you do
something and in 1 2 we so something
like in quick we're currently quick has
this thing which I think I think I
invented which is like random skipping
based on the based on like a digest of
the current traffic seekers and so the
idea is that like basically when you
when you move to the next the next CID
there's like a there's like basically
you communicate EF and that tells you
how much to increment sequence number so
for one to like like let's not get
clever we can use the same track now you
don't like a Martin yeah someone
Thompson I think the the skipping trick
from quick is kind of annoying great and
we can come up with with I think rather
than use the skipping trick where you
you effectively skip seconds numbers I
think we should probably move to what is
effectively brought 13 and so that every
connection ID has an has an additive
factor that you add to the the sequence
number and you just remove that so that
addition we need to cook so I certainly
I could imagine doing that I guess I'm
I'm trying to be good for the minimal
change in one to less of a burden for
implementations
why those yellow people's eyeballs mean
about did
so I guess more ingesting is essentially
you do uh each I mean I you can compute
it the same way you computer-based it
you basically you compete instead of
competing a skip you compute a random
random add and then you'd and you add it
modulo two to the or to the 48 in this
case and so like these are two
approaches um I I think you know I'm not
certain idea I'm not sure so the
advantage of doing that is that you
don't have to worry about the strict
sequence of connection IDs as they as
they come out I say and that's that's
the primary advantage so so the come
quick design requires that you guess why
all the secret over connection IDs in
strict sequence because the yes is skips
accumulative yes I think you would you
would simply just say that every
connection ID has a corresponding add
and then you just carry on sure it's
it's I think they have ended yeah yeah
that's what you can read them out I just
wanted to be mind not in and you about
why we don't like is CID base dipping in
a quick is that if you have any kind of
overlap between using the old CID and
the new CID then you can very easily did
use that what the skip was and you have
a no policy I agree so I think I think
this is like far from ideal which is why
I think which is why it would this is
far from ideal which is why the
president each else from a three we go
much further so I I think Martin Martin
persuaded me um so I think from the
amendment well I suggest to all right up
the addition trick instead of the
skipping trick they're actually quite
similar mathematically so for one three
however I think we should agree with the
sequence numbers and this is gonna take
a little time to work out we I think we
need to figure we should we should use
the same like again quick and easy less
are harmonized I think with the sequence
numbers either they should two hundred
on to it and they should approximately
the same way so we're still screwing
around with that in quick so I think
like I suggest was like this it's like
all the same people
hey it's me and Martin suppose
it's like intervenes are like like we
get a hike in sweat so I think like we
can just like figure it out and like
they come to book places the same answer
yeah so boats gonna tell you this is a
bad idea because he's gonna change
everything in quick are you some
different planes abode not have secrets
embers related points this might just
reread the draft of the connection I
didn't I didn't notice this before but
it seems like the details connection ID
is not not in the authenticated part of
the header oh no it will be it will be a
one through well someone to we could do
anything we want
and one three will be part of a header
because I hire you won't you want to
write that down but thanks remind me to
be asked on role Malawi and I think I'm
gonna say something stupid now from a
from a minimalistic approach the most
simple thing that we would need is just
a mechanism to update the CID doesn't
doesn't have to have it doesn't have to
be continuously updating whatever it's
like I mentioned the device calls only
once per day either slide on that I have
another slide updating by the way I'm
sorry I have another slide an up gain
it's my neck slide okay because if you
just if you if you are able to update
that fulfills the privacy no unfortunate
doesn't because they sequence numbers
are high entropy values and so that's
really hide repeat values but say but
say you have like say you have a
trivially say you have two devices right
one of which is sent a thousand packets
or one if it's at five thousand packets
if if you then randomize the see IDs and
look at the sequence numbers or just
race to see IDs then then you can tell
which ones which by looking at which one
goes 2001 which goes to 5,000 won okay
so if you have lead to a mechanism to up
to it I decide then I'm happy either way
yeah this man acts like what what I was
hoping is if I were to tell you is we're
looking at having different sequence
number spaces in in quick or they some
people are anyway which would remove
some of the problems you each see
ideally every connection ID would have
its own secret on his face
and so the analytic trick would work
again there because he wouldn't as you
switch between the two of them you would
you pick numbers from those spaces so
that's a that's an ongoing discussion so
I mean I mean I this week the other trig
worked in either case the B put that
doesn't work with the alternating case
if you if you alternate between two of
them you can correlate the gaps yeah
yeah I agree so I guess like we can tell
it as a word but like I strongly perform
courtesy with numbers it conceals more
information yes yes that one still shows
linear just the linear sequence for like
any given flow constitute so it's okay
again like I think like this seems uh
something the ITF wanna be able to agree
about as a general policy matter and
then implement I mean if you like two
protocols like a few similar like
conceptual wire images we really don't
know agree with those two protocols do
look like the same data values given the
like I'm pretty sure the people who care
like exactly the same people okay so to
recap what I proposed to do is do what I
said here I stepped across out skipping
track and right adding trick and I'll
write that up okay that's like okay so
last point and my decision in the
opposite order is C ie D update curl the
draft has a DT Ellis 1.3 post an
investor VI D update which like as far
as we can tell works fine it doesn't do
anything for TLS 1.2 there are three
options for 1.2 as far as I can tell one
continue to nothing I think we've heard
of the people don't think that's a great
idea
though by the way if it was a good idea
then like we could not have to worry
about the additive Trek the the second
is during the Rehan shake which
ordinarily like we hate we handshake and
I still continue to hit rien Jake but
their hand like to finding the
mechanisms also I hate and the third is
to put the appreciate check messages did
you tell us one point two I'm not like
super enthusiastic I like I'm kind of
frankly leaning toward a handshake even
though I ordinarily despise it so
previously when we've had people try to
request backporting all of the issues in
the previous versions of protocol we've
shot them down pretty strongly so I
think maybe we have to maybe eat our own
dog food here I think I think you have
to require EMS
this is acceptable so Thompson yeah I
I'm leaning towards three and shake to
the same sort of reasons there is no way
I don't want to implement all of the
acknowledgement mechanisms necessary to
get this to work
that's a really good point it's like a
huge lift and none of the machinery
exists it's true you need yeah yeah yeah
so I'm either do nothing because well
renegotiation sucks or required those
are actually these are actually the same
thing it turns out right well yeah I
mean normally we do nothing before magic
or the same thing right it's basically
all we do is you're right the extension
they say the extension applies in me
away and then we're done success
anything I think you probably have to
say what it what it does in the case
yeah you go traction do frankly but
that'd be fine right
hey one thing that's worth noting is
that is going to have a somewhat
negative impact on privacy because
you're not going to be able to you're
not going to be I mean what would be
hard to conceal I mean so if you if you
Rehan shake and then you start using the
definition of you right away basically
doesn't do anything so I didn't thought
about that thought through until just
now so so I guess the point the point
here is that the the reason you do the
connection ID update is primarily the
break link ability and if you have to do
an entire handshake at the point that
you need to break quickly you're kind of
boned so I think I think we can say that
you can change the connection ID using
this technique because we're not going
to stop someone from renegotiating but
you should also point out that it's
really not going to help them in the
case that they want to break my ability
so cool okay then that common okay
Tobias gone on my way that Cowan just
need to get my head around this so do
not really I think it's not acceptable
like if we can't update the idea that so
why do you want to see ID well he has
that privacy concerns so is this a
strong constraint how to tell but the
ability
preserve privacy that is probably a
strong requirement for some people
whether whether it's actually happening
is a different question and that the
cost is maybe a would be a rehab shake
that would have to be acceptable but I
just read is that actually that will not
protect you in Lincoln so the problem is
you need to promise you near supply a
PID I connection a unpack a for later
use I'm happy right if you don't take
the pass right so so in in quick and in
the one pre mechanism what happens is
you can supply a pile of ones and then
the idea is that uses the next time
right
despite underlies useless right and so
that's the handshake completely right
the lab multiples in the handshake you
find a new extension that says span
connection IDs yeah and you pop that in
no no I think I think what you do I
think what you do in I think angels like
you I feel no track I think I think what
you think there's a simpler a simpler
way to do this which is like even quite
eager but like what we call spare will
be a great recalls um or we can call or
we can call it many but the bottom line
is we just make the cardinality the
fashion of these more than one and it's
and and then you offer and they in the
offer in the extension and now I
understand but then when the rehand
shake it is encrypted and and then you
can offer as many as you want today and
they and then you and then you're good
to go so I know it's like repulsive and
we just say you can't do that in one
three you sell out for one on one person
so I think we have an answer on to recap
the proposal Martin and I'm one of my
core test proposals are following which
is we change the we change the minimal
extension that does the offer answer to
allow more than one connection ID and
then with the semantics that they're all
co-equal basically right and then in the
initial hanges no no reason not for more
than one week even perimeters but in the
rehand shake you can offer a shit-ton of
them and then you can and then and then
and then you now have
enough that you can change when you go
multipath quick we're trying to support
a mode where quick client can kind of
trying the new path that the Eric uses
it and suicune and the new back when it
does that challenge requested could
potentially get a new connection ID but
it won't use it immediately so so we
would like a concept in Europe for I
don't know maybe it's useful for ETLs as
well that is primary new path yeah you
want to do so then you can store get
ready for a bath how did we make that
work I can write that up this will give
you one so I think that should work the
the embarrassing part is I don't
actually even know how many end users
will really demand this but I'm facing
with the demand that oh if you're not
able to previously then you're kind of I
mean the other thing it's easy it's
easier to implement in a cheesy way by
just sending one and ignoring anything
for the first one so I mean like it's
not actually it's not actually well
importation class unless you want this
so real aim for Victor I am confused
about privacy concerns I thought the
main reason for backporting CID to
detail s12 was not rebinding from IOT
devices and such those implicit
migration scenarios keeps the IDS the
same the victor that sort of it's our
Google Google Ritchie came from like
this
well I think that we need to support
update you said in the second
I think we care we handshake is not good
porn since you said in the LT scenario
such as what a matter if your message
one day and think it will go to sleep so
we can shake really cost the energy very
much so I hear you I mean I guess but
the point Sean made for how my pants
make more sharply is we're not really
working on details weren't you at all
and like like even doing this much like
mate details when do case work is like a
big hood as a big arrest for working
groups is trying to divide it do you
tell some points right and so like given
that we don't know how to do this in a
like efficient way in one to I mean if
people like like if you were like well
the rehan shake is useless then we won't
do it right there like that's fine but
if like people were like the Adrian is
annoying
well like that can you choose right I
agree victor who mentioned that the main
news kiss was the natural timing and
they're the private persons are
different than the ones discussed in in
quick where you have Deb's moving around
I think we should aim for something that
gets gets done fairly quickly
we handshakes are not really that common
in the IOT case to begin with and so if
you have something even not doing
anything for one or two and just have
the basic functional in India I think
for me would be would be enough and then
move on to one that's free to actually
provide the full functionality via
because here we also have additional
privacy
mechanisms for the initial handshake
because for example with the client
authentication in one or two you're
actually exposing that at a client for
example a client certificate as well
which also is a risk on its own so I
think the plan should be moved it one
two three as soon as possible so another
int voice here so
as as Hana says this is we're seeing
basically habit every time the known
concepts through to the mothership the
path changes because the because the the
nut box
loses the binding so yeah ideally we
should have a different seat for him to
support that right I mean you could you
could sort of bang that into the one
three mechanism I suppose but none of
these Becca's that I support that I
think like we true like I spent I spent
hours and hours of my life trying to
figure how to build an efficient
rotating CID mechanism and just gave up
um so I'm working with Mike I was hoping
to use it yeah like I say III would I'm
gonna ask the chairs any matters this is
like like I would he was like I mean so
at the end of the day right if we end up
trying to like get all these great
features we're redesigning 1.2 to look a
whole lot like 1.3 so I think what we're
looking for is a sweet quick win and
then we move on and actually like try to
do 1.3 the right way and then we just
kind of have to like a little bit what
the implementers decide right magic
message and specifically some of that
features in 1.3 and if you back bought
that into one or two it's not a small
change to the DLS stack yeah I know
there's whatever that's that's really
people so like I feels a little bit over
the edge to me yes to be askin on huawei
so do nothing I think that that would
not be okay as I said actually even just
for my idea of perspective we need to
address the privacy considerations so
all that so for 1.2 I don't I don't
actually think that's true we're kind of
dancing on a line here right we're
charted 21.3 we kind of we're doing this
kind of like as like a strong favor
that I I think if you go with the
require we handshake that should be
minimum change because basically you're
doing nothing to just say you do a new
handshake that that would be hurtful for
IOT devices but it yeah okay if you want
to privacy okay you have to pay a price
I like the idea that you mentioned
before with the set of ID's if that's
too much okay I think
yeah so Thompson I think I think we've
kind of hit the sweet spot here
Tobias objection it's not withstanding I
think that yeah we're doing this because
yeah it's gonna take a little while to
tell us once we do deploy and people are
kind of out there hanging for this
anyway so it fixes the the net rebinding
case rather well I think yes which was
original it was originally the driving
really was the drivers mechanic fixes
the primary driver and we provide more
incentive to go to DC all s13 if we do
nothing you know like that
wait that's why I am - no I think
Martin's assessment is I just stand here
may I just ask one more question then
because maybe I'm not getting it so the
rehand shake would that be a major
change if we say you have to do a reason
no I mean so it's easier for Savior
through Rehan shake what's what's not a
non-trivial change to display multiple
connection IDs in the in but then I
think I mean really actually does
anything that's not we're saying yeah I
mean we're happy to you know we're
letting it leaving it in is fine like
we're taking it out considering that the
consensus around me is against doing
anything so then every handshake would
still be better than that
I won't III wanna make clear that you
could Rehan Janet changes Yeti
that's it that's our normative change
just excellent okay
I mean knowing that this is like not the
greatest thing but we are working on 1.3
does this sound like a way forward that
we can kind of like live with before
going to if you're in violent objection
please get on the 1.3 design train okay
I will revise this draft why do I need
your people to make a second draft I'll
make a second draft like scrim up and I
mean we'll have to approve it but it
sounds good that's that that's all I'll
have all right we're shockingly ahead of
time good we're gonna need it for this
one
all right zoom on so so Sean thought
occurred that we might actually have
enough reason particularly with the
intrusive changes to the short header
here to actually just move the
connection ID to the DTLS 1/3 spec so
might be worth considering that there's
an option as well yeah
all right folks so this is a draft
that's been lingering in the working
group for a while got all the way to the
is G and then we had some discussion so
we're basically bouncing it back to the
working group to try to deal with the
questions and the open issues and I know
that Victor has probably remotes so when
he little Pacman comes up please let us
know because I can't see the thing and
then we'll walk him in the button oh
there's all right so thanks thanks Jimmy
folks so we're going to talk about the
remaining issues with the DNS SEC
authentication chain extension so this
has been through is G evaluation there
were a number of comments and discuss
issues raised we believe we've resolved
most of those on list with the exception
of one of them so we're almost ready to
push out a draft oh seven next slide
please
so this is the remaining issue there was
an inadvertent keyword discrepancy in
our description of the mechanism for TLS
1.2 vs. 1.3 so it says servers receiving
a DNS section extension in the client
hello and which are capable of being
authenticated by Dane may return an
authentication chain that's what the
original wording said for TLS 1.2 at
some point we did version specific
descriptions of the mechanism and for
the 1.3 description I think just
accidentally it said should right so the
question is I had suggested on list that
maybe it should be should in both places
and I think Eric pushed back and saying
we need to figure out what their working
group consensus is so that's why we're
here I think we were waiting for some
feedback from the working group shares
an ad about this specific issue yeah so
the reason why this came back is
obviously because we chased the 2119
language so we can't just willy-nilly do
that from under you guys so discuss just
speaking is ad I don't care what it says
my position is or who has to decide so I
like yes that that was clear Thanks
okay yeah thanks not in Thompson this is
not a matter of interoperability
requirement you can say can and
everything works so the fact that the
fact that the extension exists makes it
permissible but that this is not a
choice that you make on interoperability
grounds are simply a choice that you
make as an implementation choice
basically do I choose to paint it red or
do I choose to paint it red so I think
we just okay yeah we can do that but I
want to come back to this issue later
because of the point that Victor raised
which may actually have an impact on the
wording that needs to go in here the
average reports there's no special
wording there like if you want to use
the feature use the feature if you don't
want to use the feature don't use the
feature my practice it's like dude if
you want don't if you
and Daniel Gilmore it strikes me that if
you're writing a TLS stack that complies
with the RFC this will produce then you
should return it if you're not writing
something that complies with this RFC
then this Aria doesn't apply so just use
shoot in both places because you're
describing what someone should do if
they're implementing the feature in an
interoperable way okay
followed us I think maybe you're talking
about whether or not you can stopped
using this extension at any point in
time which is unrelated to this fight or
so that's coming up later I think that's
part of Victor's diss okay discussion so
let's hold that until then you get
individual I mean again I just don't
care what this language says but like
the tenant the attempting the standards
like exhort people to do things that
like either do or they don't want to do
I just like seems like so I mean
literally you could drop the word and
say via Dame returns a sterilised
authentication machine because it is
what it does right okay so I guess
that's one possibility can reword this
to remove these 2119 keywords yeah okay
all right did you have another question
the next one is shower water next next
slide please
so we kind of thought we were definitely
this raft and then a couple of folks in
the working group brought up a new issue
so that's I think why we're primarily on
the agenda today so the first one was
raised by Paul routers and that's the
data format in the chain extension he
was arguing strongly that the format
should be a complete DNS message rather
than what it says now which is a
sequence of wire format DNS resource
record sets I believe after some
back-and-forth on the list that he has
been successfully persuaded that full
message isn't needed but I'll stop here
for a few seconds too in case he or
anyone else has any comments on this
issue
yes I'm convinced you're right okay all
right anyone else yeah so like going
once going twice
someone's getting up here we go okay
someone's got out
Solar implementer it seems to me to be
okay just sent to our arsenal from
message because we use basically okay go
on with this version okay thanks
next slide please all right great all
right so that leaves the last issue that
was raised by Victor hopefully he's in
attendance remotely via Mike and that's
vulnerability of this extension to P
kicks downgrade attacks so I want to say
that this issue was well known to the
authors and actually documented in the
draft with possible mitigations and it's
fundamentally tied to the fact that this
protocol as it's written today does not
provide authenticated denial of
existence and what that means is there's
no no way for the TLS server to
cryptographically prove that it does not
possess a signed TLS a record victor is
suggesting that we need a more robust
defense okay so I have a few more slides
but okay go ahead all right
next slide please so in case you haven't
been following the list I'll briefly
describe what the attack is concerned
about is a TLS server has a valid deign
record but an attacker has fraudulently
obtained valid PKK's credentials and
then manages to induce the client to
connect to it we have you know spoofing
or met in the middle somehow ignores the
DNS SEC chain extension and offers just
plain PKK's authentication with the
fraudulently obtained potentials next
slide please so our the position of the
authors on this was that this was
preventing this these kinds of attacks
was not an original goal of this draft I
remember in the very early days of this
draft when we had discussions with some
web browser folks who were interested at
the time and implementing this that
there was a debate about what it means
to publish a TLS a record is that
actually a policy signal that compels
the use of Dane or is the use of Dane
entirely a client specific decision a
local decision right so so the extension
as it stands it provides a mechanism to
use Dane if you correct to the
able to connect to the danger has no
facility to mandate the use however in
the draft we described mechanisms by
which the client if it wants to be sure
it can use Dane how it can do that and
the two methods that we offer the first
one is a kind of a trust on first
contact mechanism where if you connect
to a server offers Dane you remember
that fact for some specified period of
time and then you enforce Dane on
subsequent connections and the other one
was to just whitelist known Dane servers
that follow us so first I'll channel
myself I think if the server removes a
Dane record it should in the extension
put the denial of existence of that Dane
record in the extension so you just get
the insect change again sick three
change let's say this record is no
longer there and then so if if the
server violently removes the TLS a
record because they change their mind on
the policy of using this extension they
should run for a while with this
extension with no TLS record in it so
that anyone who's contacted the server
before it now knows that there's a
validly cyan't answer saying I stopped
doing this and then it can do local
policy in determining how long or when
it decides that it can accept the
connection without a TLS extension at
all I do think that when a client
connected at Eli's extension suddenly
magically has disappeared that it should
do something but I'm happy that I've
it's a local client policy it can decide
oh well you know I will go use the real
DNS instead and see if I can get the
denial of existence answer there if I'm
not under attack affirm under attack and
the DNS is also blocked you know I don't
know I'll tell the use of this looks
fishy I'm fine with all of those
solutions now putting on my hat of
victory company he is saying he really
wants some sort of time period
associated with this exchange so when
you feed his extension it means like you
know you're pinning it for 30 days or
for actually he's I think he's thinking
of a year or something he wants it to
okay he can channel himself okay all
right Victoria okay so I just want to
highlight the fact that the extension it
could be adopted has to
useful for something and uh presumably
at scale rather than just a few niche
you know cases where you know a priority
that you can do day and and because it's
not currently in the field most servers
are not going to have it the only way
it's going to be useful is if it's
useful incrementally right so some
servers have it some don't and the
question is what advantage to the
servers who have it gained by publishing
this extension if it can be trivially
stripped and the client just you know
right on the spot for each connection
says oh well that server doesn't do it
now so I'll just proceed as normal the
NICS tension offers no security
advantage right so either pickax is
secure and then it's secure and why
bother with this thing or there's a flaw
in PKK's but then it strips dein
potentially so I'd like to see some
purpose for this and so the client has
to have some sort of sticky mechanism
now I heard Schumann mention that you
know clients will decide for themselves
how long to pin implicitly pin the
extension but I'm not convinced that
that should be a solely a client-side
decision I think a server operator who
is deploying this for the first time has
a much better idea of the likely length
of their commitment to continuing to
support this in the comfort level that
having clients remember that this
extension is promised excuse me have
recalled some servers will be able to
the awesomer operators will know that
they're committed for this forever and
definitely whatever they'll do it until
they provide a veil a valid denial of
existence and we need to make sure that
the packet format supports denial of
existence you know in Sec records as
Paul mentioned and other servers may
only be comfortable initially for days
weeks months but it would be good I
think if that signal were there on the
other hand if there is accept you know
if everybody likes guidance which says
something like six months or three
months or whatever and we think that's
long enough
protect most clients that you know if
they haven't come back in three months
to a site perhaps they'll never come
back then maybe you know some fixed
period can be recommended but without
any recommendation to store the server's
deign capability and insist on it and
reconnect until the server provides
denial of existence I think the standard
is kind of useless
well I agree with victory security
analysis I think this goes to the very
heart of the very part of the rationale
for this documents existence which is
identify ourselves as doctors resistance
to be as certain people didn't want to
get PGI certificates and they wanted to
find a way to authenticate from the
server to the client via Dame rather
than PGI and that the composition of PGI
and Dane temporarily was effectively
like a a stopgap that would let you get
the way they you prayed for people who
thought that sort of the temporary
period where clients ostensibly maybe
had both on this particular visit but
there you are if the rationale for this
for this the feature is that is that
it's only useful for and hence all of
that sort of thing if the rationale for
this feature is it intended as a to stop
except red hairs compromising PA
certificates like a musical entirely
back to the drawing board and you know
and not I have this stuff tacked on at
the very last minute after a tea review
with that said the idea that my clients
won't take the clients are gonna take
the existence of Dane and then refuse to
not accept Dane for any period of time
is like easily out of touch with the way
web server point so I have a big farm of
web servers and I turn on Dane on 10% of
them and then clients come back they all
hold the same domain name the same
origin their clients come back server
and now they just can't reconnect
I mean we're in the process of work
people that lost her rip out HTTP which
is a much much better story about not
working or stuff than this does but even
so as too terrified to run
it's like simply not lie
the situation in which the clients
you're allowed to decide that just
because you just play Dane they're not
accept PGI in that feature it's just
like not gonna work and in fact they I
don't think it's going to work I don't
think the mechanism were like where the
server says that is gonna work either
but I certainly have a client Yolanda's
eyes not only is pulling the one Richard
then Tiki Jian and Victor Lawrence we
heard when we put two distinct things
under the same label date so Dane does
two things that are pretty different
categorically you can restrict the set
of certificates that are acceptable for
domain and it can add to the set of
certificates that I said well fortune
and as Eric pointed out those are very
different cases this mechanism works
just fine for the additive case you
don't run into any of these issues your
own pinning it's just another way to
deploy a certificate have it be trusted
by clients you still have incremental
deployment issues because your clients
well can currently support this but in
the case where you have clients that are
capable you can it works just fine you
have none of these issues it's only when
you go into the restrictive cases that
any of this comes into play so I would
suggest that perhaps what with a way to
address these issues that Victor's
raising is to just make that decision to
explicitly scope to the additive case
and say this is an additional
authentication mechanism a way to assert
additional certificates that you may not
trust natively with your PGI stack and
the restrictive uses of Dane are not to
be used with this extension and you can
you could add some 2119 language in
there to restrict the you know whatever
that I forget what the name of the code
point is it says whether you're in the
restrictive or assertive cases but you
could restrict the code point in the TLS
a record to say this must be an
assertive Dame record if you want to
make it real clear on VI I would suggest
we rule the restrictive cases out of
scope at least for this talk I'm not
saying we shouldn't we should never do
it for sure we could just copy and paste
most of the mechanism we have here and
add some extra policy considerations
maybe add some denial of existence can
mechanisms what if we want to address
the restrictive case later but we have
right now something it is shippable for
the asserted case
so let's restrict it down to that and
okay yeah so I think you know since
one of the target audiences for this
extension was the web we originally were
trying to be sensitive to the way that
they see positioned Dana's
authentication mechanism so the TAC we
were taking was a model where pickax and
Dana authentication coexists rather than
Dain Trump's pickax or vice versa or
Dana's used to constrain things right so
that's where we were originally Daniel
can't Gilmore is he'll you
I think it would be a mistake to try to
attack client policy onto this draft
similarly to what Acker said this jacket
is concretely useful not just in the web
case I certainly think that the further
deprived work would really oh yeah yep
the idea that we're gonna hold this out
by child like I think that if you want
to do try it context specific policy
that policy needs to be done in the
place where those clients the client
policy is being decided right so if we
define the mechanism this as a mechanism
for transport and get the hell out of
the way of the places that actually want
to use it those places can decide
whether clients should have policies
about caching or rejection or deferral
or whatever so let's get this thing
standardized and then the place is like
deprive resolver to authoritative can
make the can make those policy decisions
independently of us yeah yeah and I'll
mention that some of the DNS over TLS
deprive implementations are already
deploying this stuff right yeah I I have
a few things to clarify the first to
Eric's point the the specific reason I
want the time are in there is in fact to
address this concern that you can't
deploy it if you have a maid deployed at
ten percent of your farm and the clients
decide to make it sticky so if we
provide a TTL in the server response and
the server sets it to zero then the
client must not
- this and you can deploy it on your
farm and you know once it's 100%
deployed then you can start raising
energy so I think an explicit extended
TTL from the server is better than an
implicit one where some clients will
foolishly more wisely or whatever you
know make the decision for the server
and get it wrong in some cases so I
think actually adding a single byte TTL
to this you know it's fairly cheap and
it allows the server to commit in a way
that allows the client to expect them to
be there the next time it connects no
matter which server it connects to or
the server could say sorry I'm not ready
to commit yet my proposal specifically
addresses that issue now Esther Richards
comment about additive versus you know
restrictive I think that's completely
orthogonal to this extension I'm looking
for the extension to be able to be
deployed on the web incrementally
opportunistically for just the servers
that have it and you know it other news
cases sure deprive you know great but it
should also be possible to incremental e
deploy it on the web and get some value
from it and if the expectation is the
only value you get is that you can be
authenticated by some clients that have
an incomplete CA bundle but otherwise
you're not having any value and you're
not protecting against compromised PKK's
creds you know given that most of them
are domain validated whose strengths I
you know I'm not that confident about
then I think we're we're we're fumbling
this extensions value we're not we're
not using it thoroughly gained it you
know proper security in the weapon it'll
continue to be ignored in the web now
maybe that's the idea that we really
don't care we'll never be done in web
servers and clients and I should just
give up but I think it's worth making it
possible to use it in the web in a way
that actually offers some protection
which requires downgrade resistance and
as written there's no downgrade
resistance it's simply not there unless
the client is in you know knows
that it will be there maybe with d-pryde
excuse me yeah but that moment is just
not happening for web clients and web
browsers and I think it's it's a mistake
to not support it potentially you know
let's do the experiment and see if it if
it can be used and used for something
real so before taking the next question
can I can you advance the slide can I
just discuss one more point so the other
way that I have suggested on this is not
in the draft by the way but I suggested
it on the list to prevent the pickax
downgrade attack is to use pickax
defenses to protect against pickax
attacks such as you know checking
certificate transparency logs I think
someone on the list who my idea insane
but I don't really think it's insane
because we're talking about a situation
of incrementally introducing Dane in a
pickax environment so you need to
service deplores need to be worried
about pickax threats so you may have a
server that supports both Dane and
traditional pickax in which case are
probably paying attention to CT logs and
even if it's the Dane only server the
operator of that service may be
concerned that other attackers are not
able to impersonate their service to
Dane unaware clients so then you're
going to have to look at pickax
solutions to this problem anyway so
that's there's another mechanism that I
offered by which you may be able to gain
some downgrade downgrade attack
protection so can you advance next slide
so I'll just but I think we've already
discussed what Victor's proposal is but
I'm just going to leave it on on the
slide so you can look at it in detail
and then we can continue with the
questions after projects is ethnic
Victor very nicely summarized what I
wanted to say so I strongly support
Victor's idea that there should be one
integer which says I'm committed to
doing this for next and seconds and if
it's zero the server is not committed
maybe it's doing the roll-out
incremental rewrite then the server can
use some longer value and then if this
every size oh this was a horrible idea
and I'm going
to something else and I want to rip off
this extension and never see it again
it will set it to zero again and it was
significant signal to the clients that
this is going to be you know ripped off
don't cash it anymore
so I think that one integer costs
nothing and will improve the left a lot
so I start mr. Poulos yeah so I imagine
that the change is proposing is not only
introducing that integer and the and the
the pinning commitment period but it's
also introducing an implementation that
requires the server's to send a full
authenticated denial of exchange or
non-existence of the TLS a record which
it doesn't do now there is some
authenticated denial stuff there it's
related to wild card proofs and stuff
right but not for an X domain responses
so that would be another change yes
specifically the text about the negative
proofs of non-existence it's very very
vague and I'm hesitant to say that it's
complete and okay right now so I think
that we need to go to that part anyway
so it's okay thanks I
Sriman sir I had some questions on sort
of this extension with regards to
large-scale rollouts so troubleshooting
large-scale rollout so is their ability
to turn it on in passive mode is there a
way of getting from the clients some
logging for example with the content
security policy or a tea mark they have
sort of reports URI to return
information there and then it provides a
little bit more signal so we understand
that organically this works over time
right so I mean that's something that
the clients could passively inspect
today there's no explicit pledge or
anything that tells this is report mode
versus authentication mode today yeah
lines could examine the presence of this
extension without actually using it to
perform authentication of the server
that's that's always possible sure but I
went for the server to say here's a
report your eyes I see the logs back
here so I know if for example there's a
setting where an issue I know that
browse
all over the internet have broken
because of my deployment and I need to
do something about it
right so I think the way servers will
get some reporting about the use of this
mechanism is by examining whether the
client sent this extension to you right
so then that's that's the mechanism that
we have today yeah okay now I'll think
about we'll think about that yeah if it
finishes the handshake that's it that's
the other thing yeah thank you so I just
want to get back so the reason we wanted
to do this is because we have
information in DNS with the intersect
protection that's where you get this
information that's where the owner of
the information can publish that this
information is updated removed or
anything so so in a way we don't need
pinning because all the the information
lives authority in the DNS and it should
be updated there and it can be updated
based you know we've got TTL values that
deal with all of these conditions of you
know migration from adding or removing
this information now we're putting it
into this DNS extension and this TLS
extension as an optimization and a way
of making sure that we can obtain this
information even if our DNS path is
unclean and even if you know in order to
avoid extra latency of doing these
lookups
so this is just an optimization of using
DNS say let's let's be honest here so if
you're if this optimization cannot be
used because suddenly you know you're
under attack and someone that someone
has taken another peak exert and put it
in the server you know your fallback
method is not to use the optimization
and go look Indian s and if you cannot
look it up in DNS separately from a
separate path just assume you're under
attack so so to me I think we do not
need any kind of pinning in this
extension because we have we've got the
exact lifetimes and validity in DNS this
is just an optimization where we need to
do this so the draft only needs to say
if the if it's removed from DNS we must
make sure that this optimised path is
also updated to put in the information
of non-existence so that's to me is the
only thing that should be added to the
draft then everything else can become
just
behavior right yes I understand that so
the problem is introducing full
authenticated denial in this mechanism
is difficult because then it imposes a
barrier to incrementally deploying the
extension in the field because it
requires all TLS servers to understand
DNS second be able to build negative
proofs for the fact that they don't have
a TLS record
okay let's say a record so if we can
answer that I'm so so you have something
the reason we use DNS format is that the
extension can use Dinah's libraries that
support all of this so also eating these
extensions should be easy for all those
kinds of do if you're talking about the
the way how you deploy it as
incrementally in some service to and
some servers don't support this
extension then again you can say in the
client they can remember IP addresses
and if yeah sure if you have like ten
ten surface on the same ip then if you
do any guess that you should just update
them in groups like it these are just
standard deployments of any extension
that you do like yeah yeah well we make
a record something like a substantive
point and they will reiterate a matter
of metaphor yeah I think we've got
experience in the web so for the web
case we have experience with incremental
rollout of features that restrict
authentication got HP KP is ekor
mentioned it got CT both of which had CT
especially much more momentum and
deployment than date and still we've had
to be very cautious in that mechanism to
be because people expect CT is still
pretty controversial
even as the universal requirement is on
its way and so talking about things that
are restricting authentication making
deployable and has all pointing up
coming up with a fallback story when
when things get interfere with it's
super complicated into this lots of
subtle edge cases and deployment cases
and you know if we're going to launch
down that it's going to be a big pilot
work um so back to the meta points let's
not snatch defeat from the jaws of
victory here let's take the thing that
we've got that can deploy in certain
circumstances
it's dkg points out can be used for
things like deprive let's polish it up
and and get some use out of that and
then if there's interest in history
restrictive case later by all means
let's let's do the work and get
something degage I'll just bust one that
I just wanted to respond specifically to
Peter Peters point that it's just one
bite the one bite doesn't doesn't seem
too painful the bite doesn't seem
painful what the arguing about it sure
does I really would like to then work
closing the line so and victors in the
queue as well yeah I think so
as I said um any mechanism which
requires you to update to arrange that
the client experiences the same thing
has a consistent experience across all
your servers like as a condition of
employment is like total non-starter and
I need and any and any and any like an
even one that requires the servers that
have deployment to serve Dane records
and the servers that don't have
deployment to serve a non-dangerous so
that the design of the Thank You
existence is also complete non-starter I
peel deploy the web servers it works
just incrementally and what you're
saying is I don't feel to do that like
you can't serve here any caster IP just
doesn't work that way so the mechanism
video describes absolutely technically
but we have like enormous more
experience now with like several
mechanisms which like have this property
and like every single time there's like
a lot of hand-wringing about exactly how
you avoid per here yourself and given
like the be frank relatively a little
enthusiasm on both clients and sort of a
browsers and servers for like this
functionality in general like Mickey it
and and and the and frankly the
extremely low level of like additional
security its providing I you know from
the from the server's perspective given
the like apply it like you know to to
require that is really another negative
impact on deployment of this
functionality we know how to add that
functionality later if we want it and
and as DG said we have a number of
situations where clients cuz we
configure themselves to require this
like
this is not gonna be like you're gonna
write this down and then you're gonna
like you know be a mess call again in
two weeks this is going to be like than
a year doing this Erica Negron Akamai
and kind of add on to that I think the
the if the peak keep pinning stuff pH
PKA stuff makes you be the really good
thing to look at in terms of how badly
that's failed and all the problems with
it and in particular it's not just the
canyon brick yourself which is a huge
foot gun but it's also the security
vulnerabilities associated with that
it's being used for ransomware attacks
and what you can see here is once you do
this is even as a restrictive mode the
state of DNS SEC is not great right now
like those map RG talk was talking about
how many new people are using
non-rotating RSA 1024 bit keys is you
know get into a situation where people
just start pinning compromising the keys
pinning and then trying to UM pin these
records in Tobruk to brett people um who
aren't really to Folly go ahead and
deploy things and that seems like could
make things worse rather than better
even for the restrictive case right yes
i agree there's a danger that i just
want to clarify the pinning we're
talking about here is not pinning keys
it spinning knowledge of the existence
of day and but i understand some of the
same issue but if you have someone who's
totally not prepared to do gain or going
and pinning into a hey hey you must use
dane is it's not a maybe not either
ransom or one but it means it a
third-party Brantly brick someone sure
yeah point taken
hello so Eric I think you know it
completely misses the boat here it does
the recommendation in the RFC to servers
can say you know says hero or a long
time kill you already the there is no
there's no bricking involved here
regulates what are likely don't indicate
time from the server because clients
will make the wrong assumption because
they need to right if the server can
explicitly said you know no to cache
that I'm not ready then the client will
know the server is not ready as to pause
comment
that you know you can fall back to DNS
unfortunately that's completely wrong
because the the reason that that clients
don't do the DNS lookup is because it's
it's too slow you're not going to do it
for every server that fails to offer the
extension you know right the web
browsers have avoided this precisely
because the cost of all the extraneous
lookups too high so the web clients are
not going to you know do the fallback
for every single server on the web
because it looks like all of them are
under attack so that's all back isn't
going to happen and the pinning is just
a single bit it isn't there's no
breaking risk here we're just asking the
server to not stop offering the
extension for a time of its own choosing
and let's be quite clear on that it is
not the client that decides the time if
we don't specify that in the extra bite
then the client will in fact incorrectly
make assumptions some implementations
right let's future proof list and make
it possible
later desirable in the servers to offer
a nonzero cache time we can in fact
write the recommendation that initially
servers should always put 0 there for
the moment that we'd gain more
experience with it and then later that
it's right when they're ready and then
clients could start caching it but let's
the future proof is to make it usable it
locks out all kinds of use cases by not
having the element there so we are gonna
break the protocol letter seem to be ad
talk and then we're gonna cook I mean
just sort of as a as a process question
if the objection is for a totally
speculative use case we have lots of
space in the extension code points and
if it the speculative thing wants to
happen later it can get a new coke money
so I think the what I'd like to do is
get a sense of the room if it was kind
of brought up that we have the the
current draft is sort of additive in its
authentication mechanisms versus being
restrictive and like to get a sense of
people think that this additive you know
authentication without any sort of
pinning or does not denial a big
non-existence I think out that right
yeah I think will do a home to make sure
that to see if if people think they're
still value in the additive case in just
an additive authentication mechanism so
I'll ask two questions and we'll do it
based on on this draft to make it a
little bit clearer so do you think that
the current mechanism in the draft is
useful and sufficient it should go
forward or do you think we need to make
a change and the second question would
be no you do not think that that the
draft is sufficient to go forward and we
need to make some sort of change for
denial of existence I find the question
rather confusing because if I like this
extension so we're not restricting the
other option from being worked on in
parallel or but it would be in a
different draft right go ahead with that
or if we're saying don't say like don't
put any restrictions on the current
draft if you put a little bit of
guidance in the current draft that says
note that if you put restrictive things
in there clients may not make mint it
may disagree about what to do with them
right there's a difference between
saying this is
be possible for pudding and I wish I
could remember whether it's Dean
two and three year game one and order
they know right there's four kinds of
day and we're and Richard proposal was
we only allow this draft to ship two of
them whatever those two are camera yeah
it's two and three so uh you're exactly
which which direction like are we saying
we should add that explicit restriction
or are we saying just put a note that
says we encourage the use of this with
with zero and one and you know there be
dragons with two and three
let me say it was just a slight
different comfort her the fundamental
question is whether we wish to have any
painting mechanism whatsoever or stopped
into this thing so like weather weather
weather weather we especially the case
the clients and force continual use of
Damon or some circumstances and see if
do you mean any kind do you mean the
insects feed an effective I mean the
situation is that like the the null
hypothesis is that clients may be
configured to require otherwise they
don't like learn that they ought to have
they just they just they just take it as
it comes and I agree that a consequence
of that is it's not usable first to
diffuse cases but that's not like that's
that's that's that's taxes not and so I
think we should first decide whether we
want to do whether we want to do
anything along those lines and if the
answer is yes then life of working
request like spent much time very or
some other grant and if the answer is no
then we can then discuss whether whether
it's document ought to be more pointed
about how these cases are not actually
okay I think that would be better so the
question would be do you think pinning
is required or to make this at all
useful or do you think we can move on
without having pinning in this draft
okay good
all right so first question will be on
if you think pinning is required to make
this useful so if you think paying is
required to make this useful please hop
oh you supported pinning I didn't hear
all right so if you think this draft is
useful without pinning the way it is
please hum okay so that's pretty clear
so you can get up to them I'm sure I'm
sure
humming but we couldn't hear them so but
yeah yeah so in summary you know the
general feeling of the room is that this
draft is useful without pinning and I
think well that's kind of the direction
we're going to try to take it on the
list and you know this doesn't preclude
us from developing a painting extension
and and if you know people think that's
really critical then that work should
continue should be you know started and
continued would that definitely be start
it in a different draft or might this be
amended right because then there's
different drafts so in effect there's
been no changes to the strap and any new
work to it would happen in a different
draft anyway
yet the discuss is cleared should this
be approved today if new work would
happen in a different draft in any case
the new work might not have to do with
this particular draft at all it might be
a client context specific draft right
when you're using this for a protocol
foo there's this kind of pinning that
happens right it doesn't need to happen
in this jacket if you happen somewhere
else so that's my point so is there any
reason to hold this up no right sorry I
think we're gonna try to move forward
and I think we yeah I think we have we
have gone through the other issues that
that were needed to be cleared yeah so
again I think if the if there's text
that said you if you've put in a TSA
record before and you remove it you
should put in a denial of existence
proof would be extremely helpful for
those people that already want to do
more I want to think about pinning later
I don't think it actually harms that
people who don't want to do that so it
would actually be a really good feature
add to the it's just to intellectual
thing could I ask the authors to post a
revised version of the draft immediately
following this that removes the one word
that was agreed and with that one it's
it's a removing a normative so I see no
issue because if we were increasing then
that might be the case right yeah so I
think we're ready to push one out today
right post that today yeah thank you
very much early in the day as possible
okay yeah my discuss pursuing the basis
of not claiming this was standalone so
as long as you fixed that I trust
Kathleen to menders it all for my
disgust now just okay thanks right and
then so I for the subsequent version
that includes authenticated denial
possibly in a new draft I'm happy to
work work with Victor and Paul on that
as well right but I guess you know we're
advancing this one as it is right okay
thank you all right cool thank you
um so one of the reasons the exported
authentic areas were the kind of sitting
on it is waiting for some formal
analysis and now we're gonna get to hear
about that so thank you hi
so what's are they very briefly they're
a post handshake authentication
mechanism that's supposed to replace TLS
1.2 renegotiation and provide a more
versatile version of post handshake
authentication than the post handshake
client authentication that's already
there so how is it more versatile it
allows multiple identities for the
client and the server next five please
okay very brief version of the protocol
either party is allowed to send typical
requests and they get back an export
Authenticator or the server can just
send an exportable Authenticator
and the expulsion Authenticator is
certificate if you could verify finished
which is just copied straight from the
TLS handshake and because that's really
been quite well analyzed so next slide
please
so what are the actual security
properties we want if I receive an
export Authenticator I want it to prove
that the the person who created it has
the private key of the certificate and I
wanted to prove that the person who
created it knows the master secret of
the of the TLS channel to which it's
bound how they actually transpires that
those two properties aren't enough next
slide please
and the property that we actually end up
wanting is compound authentication so if
I have a run of layered authentication
of layered authentication protocol and
at least one of those one of my peers
identities has not been compromised to
one of the peers secrets is unknown to
the attacker then I know that the peer
agrees with me on everything
all the identities and all the bindings
so this is a bit of a counterintuitive
property it's actually very powerful
property but basically it says that in
our case that the as long as either the
TLS channel is good or the private their
private key of the certificate is
uncompromised then we've got what we
want next slide please so what we did
was we did a two-part analysis we did a
manual or by hand proof and then we did
a tool supported proof so our by hand
proof used channel bindings which I'm
going to talk about in a moment and we
used it to prove compounds
authentication as defined in the
literature and then we built a memory
model and use that to explore the
specific security guarantees we can get
from draft sullivan which is the
exported authenticators draft next piece
so manual proof so we use channel
bindings as a frame
to analyse exposed authenticators so
channel bindings refer to the
cryptographic binding between in our
case the exposed Authenticator and the
TLS channel but between any of the two
layers of any of the multiple layers
essentially of the protocol and the the
thing is numerous examples of layered
authentication protocols in the
literature fail to achieve this
compounds authentication guarantee and
it's really easy to get wrong and so we
used contributive channel bindings which
are defined by our Cabana towel to
formally verify whether we achieve this
quite powerful property of compounds
authentication and basically it means we
can prove that the TLS channel and the
explosive authenticates are bound to
each other and we then did a
tool-assisted proof and so we did this
secondary proof such that we can explore
the guarantees that we get so the
compound earth property as defined in
the literature says under a particular
threat model you achieve a particular
property so we used tamarin to explore
what happens if we change the threat
model and what happens if we vary the
property and try improve this sort of
in-between thing and another benefit of
tamron is if it says no' then you get a
counter example that says here is a run
at the protocol that breaks your
property next slide please so the
results of our overall analysis is that
yes the TLS channel and Explorer
Authenticator are securely bound to each
other and achieve compounds
authentication so what that means in
practice is to forge an exported
Authenticator some attack would have to
know the master secret of the TLS
Channel and the private key of the
certificate so you know basically the
attacker knows all the secrets and you
lose but otherwise you're fine but what
that means is if the master secrecy
uncompromised so if you don't have a
threat model that considers the master
secret being compromised then you have a
join to authentication
between two aids so if I receive two
EA's over the same to your last
connection I know that they were both
created by the same person
next slide please so this was you know a
little bit I'm exciting from a formal
analysis it just said yeah everything's
fine
so I thought how far can we push this
right can we get even stronger
guarantees and actually you can how far
can we push this for this breaks you
actually have to have a ridiculous
attacker model before things break which
is if the attacker can compromise of the
master secret and knows some private
keys because the Explorer authenticators
are not explicitly bound to each other
you can't guarantee that they're all
created by the same person and that's
what we're trying to prove that all the
exported authenticators are created by
the same person
and we're working on potentially
stronger version if anyone wanted it so
is this a threat model that's actually
plausible well potentially if something
like draft green or drafts are HRD had
been taken up or even if the industry
decide to just export the server keys to
enable visibility that could potentially
break exported authenticators because
the overseer or the monitor or whatever
you want to call it could insert exports
authenticators onto a connection in
either direction and they would be
indistinguishable and I think that's I'm
saving my one more slide if anyone asks
into a question yeah Chris but thanks
for doing this this is great I'm just a
quick question about the camera model
yeah is the source available I can make
it available if you want I'd be awesome
yeah thanks oh yeah my last point is if
you want the stuff email me yeah a paper
is forthcoming
thanks for doing this
you know we were what concerned about
what the proper eases system or II so
yeah it's just good it's good it's good
to know that at least we have some of
the proper age but I know that I guess
the difficult question for the room here
is whether or not we care about this
throat model enough to do something
about it now I'm talking to Johnson
about this quite a bit and there is a
fix right there's a yes there's a fix
for this and it simply means some
modifications to the program now these
modifications can be essentially
voluntary in a sense no but there's some
value and having the counterparties
actually understand what's going on such
that they can extract this information
use that information concretely yeah so
there's two versions I guess of my fix
one of them is doesn't require any on
the wire changes it just changes so a
one at the moment there's a requirement
on the certificate request context have
a particular have a particular form ie
it's less than a certain length and
that's the only requirement and so we
can use that to pack some other stuff in
it or this could be done as a TLS
extension and then that requires on the
wire changes but it and you can achieve
yeah
bindings between different days so
myself I think that it would be a
reasonable tweak to the formula to
actually add this I suspect that we
might be able to do it as a separate
document mmm and so if we do that then I
would rather have it be explicit rather
than the yet something with certificate
request contexts but if we if we build
that little extra piece then we can get
some sort of assurance
not only do we have this property in the
case where the master secret or
resumption secret or anything that's
derived in that particular path is
secure but also we have the property in
the case where hey someone decided that
with the master secret somewhere and
it's built in races but it you see that
little bit of extra short even about how
things are operating and it doesn't
appear to cost all that much so - for
context you put the finished message
from the last one in the next one
and you're done and that's under number
yeah there's a there's a bunch of ways
in which that fails and you have to deal
with that particularly in the usage
model that we envisage HTTP but
essentially that's that's the intuition
that yeah yeah it's pretty
straightforward really quite simple and
it can fix a bunch of problems you can't
make it inclusive unfortunately which
would be which would have been a great
way to do this but we're not quite there
yet we don't have reliable protocols it
turns out been Caidic so Martin just
asked you do we care about this threat
basically and you're just to make it
really clear any attacker can get a
certificate and the private key for it
so this sort of degenerates to the case
where the master secret is leaked and we
have examples where that happens so yes
correct with superior and yeah the but
it's whether you're worried about an
attacker who has a certificate you care
about because all you can do is an
attack anybody can get on any particular
certificate whether they can get a sniff
that you're worried about right well I
mean there's potentially the semantic
load you know I get the master secret
for some connection to Google calm and I
have the certificate for on the stock
med and now I can give you some
Authenticator that seems to indicate
that honest Achmed and Google are the
same thing yeah and you're depending on
how the client interprets that the
problems could be pretty bad yeah
mike moschetti Akamai so I had a
question about the the joint and the
proof that they're bound to each other
yeah the draft currently says that
having seen one of these you can't make
any assumptions about them being related
to each other in the future like if you
do it with some Sun and you get and you
have a new session you can't say that
well this got bound to the other thing
or so it's must don't be there and do
you think we need to who do you think
that we could or should loosen that
based on this proof or do you think
that's still a reasonable restriction
and so actually you'd have to completely
redefine the draft because if you do a
resumption them master secret changes
and so you actually do lose the binding
completely but you could do some fancy
stuff to try and achieve achieve across
most secret binding but I don't think it
would be very easy thank you thanks for
doing this
where's Nick he was one he didn't want
to do anything to to accommodate this
useless he's he's he's hiding so to be
clear Nick put him up to this so some of
the gray already that this is not insane
which is why further than we were before
sir yeah because that mean that was the
reason why we yanked it out of the base
draft in the first place right so yeah
thanks thanks for doing this Nick
solving parlors thanks for the analysis
I'm not entirely convinced that the
compound authentication adds hoo-wah and
at least in the use case
additional certificates hb2 best draft
the threat model seems a little bit
bizarre in that you have a connection
that you've established now you're going
to be using to try to send these
authenticators and it is compromised
partway through where the connection has
been compromised partway through and the
exported authentic air had been put on
the wire before a key update mechanism
so otherwise you can if you do manage if
you compromised the certificate all you
need to do to sort of chain them up
these two hash the previous certificates
so if you have the traffic keys you can
see previous certificates on the wire
and construct a joint authentic errors
I'm not true I I don't think so and I
think you'd need to know you need to
know the rewrites keys but you also need
to know the the exporter keys right so
you compromised the connection you have
the exporter keys yeah and you have the
read/write keys yeah and therefore you
should be able to instruct a chain of
expert authenticators you can less you
only compromise the current set of
traffic keys of after a key update the
the guarantee you would get in the in
the joins case is actually only until
the last good certificate so if I knew
that a particular certificate was
compromised
I could still and I so I'm you know
whatever CloudFlare and I have I know
one of my stiff it's been compromised
and then I have another certificate that
is now good then I can join those
together as long as they there's only
you only get the guarantee for the last
good certificate and all ones before it
so if you're worried about a future comp
a future compromise within a session
then yes right so so I think
from the analysis it seems that the
current draft is written is relatively
robust with respect to being able to add
a certificate to and associated with the
connection not necessarily with other
certificates yeah that's very long and
my recommendation would be to go forward
with that and then have if if if there
was the demand the need for the stronger
compound authentication in it had a
specific use case that we'd go forward
with a different draft on that that
would build on on it explicitly with the
TLS extension that's why I I think
Moschino crazy D backer so I mean I'm
not to change it here it changes here
I'm I guess I'm I see a lot of work for
the past couple years and people trying
to like Creeper choice three situations
reports are compromised like they
properly
I mean CTLs like that is really about
that and my experience is the answer is
typically pretty terrible and that like
if you couldn't a lot of trouble I try
to like you know design for them in
those cases often in order to issue
their pulse so you know if there's some
and certainly you know if you'd if if
it's been published if we published this
document right and and and then you
discovered this property like this would
not be like Oh TLS right though it's a
really does analysis so like it was just
a trivial make change that Macy's better
I'm like like like okay with that but
like I don't want to leave jump through
a lot of Hoops to make it the case like
master secures compromised like don't do
that answer that question right yeah so
the I mean the answer to that is
actually as the draft is now you could
also use my stronger version because the
draft says pick any value as long as
it's long enough and unpredictable and
so I can just say pick that value to be
this shape and you get the guarantee so
you
you don't you don't actually need any
changes if you don't want them or you
could define a second like I said
sometimes I'm not quite because
unpredictable is not the case if you're
picking a finish from a previous one so
there's a change there and so I'm
inclined it'sit's a shirred
unpredictable not said last time
predictor yeah I think it probably
should have been a must because
otherwise you have replay problems there
he was it was intended to be the reason
why we had value is precisely wish to of
course to ensure that this review had
the property at that moment as post I'm
home in the past right well yeah it has
to be fresh but it has to be no the
fresh is enough let's imagine imagine
what I did is I just use a counter right
yeah that's fresh but the problem is the
attacker
the attacker compromises the key he's
using the sine the EI at time T and he
has temporary access right and then he
generates regenerates in da right now if
you have a random value that just
happens to work but if you have a non
random value even if it's fresh that
fact does work so that's why that's why
I would if it Isis in there yeah someone
so in order to do this properly you need
to have both the the random value the
unpredictable value and the previous
value you yeah so so so my my crc
packing change has a sub-sub crc inside
the crc but yeah it all works the same
yeah so I think I think your your design
which you should probably share with the
working group at this point yeah sure
just so everyone has a little more
context does actually address this this
question reasonably well if I actually
putting both values in there that's fine
yeah but I was actually gonna suggest
that what we what we might want to do is
given that there's this self-service
option available to people that sort of
want to do this we we leave the
self-service option as as a possibility
and we leave open the possibility of
adding an extension to have the explicit
communication about the fact that the
self-service option is there or have
some sort of explicit way to bind things
together in the future but I think we
can probably proceed with the draft as
is based on the feedback on fruit that
would be is as I understand it because
the way you're designing but it's the
way of because of binding who is a
previous you know finished right now you
created a new application in variant
which is these they've got an order and
they sent in the portal right so right
now the application in Burien they don't
give in an order you could do you could
make two per customer cart you it you
can like do two for to the nikah doors
and they could be delivered in either
work right and so and so like if you
have like two tokens those not good like
kind of happen right and so if you apply
them to this way it was a linear linear
structure then they have to be done
order so crazy location invariance or
thought so yeah I actually share my
talking with you I discussed that I mean
that TLS sort of provides in order to
delivery within one direction TLS price
over delivery but doesn't mean that the
client right and so so it's not like
strictly straightforward yeah so what it
basically boils down to is you you don't
actually build a linear thing you build
a tree and if the if you have
certificates across a TAS crossing in
midair
yeah then you at you might end up with
to a tree that splits and then each side
has to process one more EA and now we
get back to might might think about like
this game for garnish yeah yeah I mean
oh well I can reason about it fine yes
right I've been K like so and just you
know similar vein you could imagine an
endpoint that says you have to stir the
connection I know I might need to
authenticate with these certificates and
let me generate the authenticators and
then throw away the exporter master
secret and mystery
all right so I think we got to wrap up
here so I think what basically I've been
hearing is that we can progress forward
with the kind of draft as is and then we
want to have a more stronger mechanism
we need to do it in another extension
and you're going to happily provide a
paper for us right sure it'll be great
all right cool thank you very much Vicki
who's next
all right certificate compression
CloudFlare I'm one of the authors of the
certificate compression draft along with
Victor from Google that's like a bit of
context first for those that missed the
previous discussions we want to compress
certificates for couple reasons one is
quick quick Sanjay combines both TLS and
chicken connection establishment in the
same mechanism so it reduces the amount
of round trips required to establish a
connection compared to TLS over TCP but
it also makes it very easy to mount
reflection attacks with a fairly big
amplification factor so quick provides a
an optional source address verification
mechanism which adds an additional round
trip to the end check but if we can
reduce the amplification factor then we
can remove the need for this address
verification and the additional round
trip at least in some cases the other
reason is that sending fewer bytes can
be advantageous for Kaos over TCP as
well your pockets are needed that can be
lost and would need to be retransmitted
and that's right so it turns out that
compressing certificate is actually
quite effective Victor presented some
measurements he did that idea 90
eight from a sample of a few thousand
certificates he measured at 30 percent
size reduction at median and almost 50
percent at 95th percentile using broadly
and of course fewer packets than are
needed to send those chains and that's
like the draft went through a few rounds
of discussions already thanks to
everybody who participated we now
support both compression for server and
client certificates for server
certificates the client advertises the
algorithms
it supports as part of a client hello
extension called compress certificates
and then the server if the server
decides to compress then it sends back
compressed certificate message rather
than the usual certificate message this
message contains all the information
needed to decompress as well as the
compressed certificates and of course if
the server doesn't want to compress or
doesn't support compression and it just
sends the normal certificate message
that's like for client certificates the
server advertises the algorithms
it supports as part of the same
extension but this time inside the
certificate request message and then the
client sends back either compress
certificate or the normal certificate
message so the main point here is that
server certificate compression and
client certificate compression can be
negotiated independently next slide one
change that we did was to only define
this mechanism for Kilis one point three
one reason is that extensions as part of
certificate request are jealous one
point three feature but also this
prevents middleboxes from intercepting
compressed certificate and then get
confused by it because in TLS 1.3
certificate and compress certificate
would be encrypted next slide so we
think the design is mostly done so
there are few changes needed to the
draft mostly editorial I think so we are
at the point where we can actually start
implementing and deploying this
mechanism and we ask that chair for
early code upon assignment to make this
so the basic premise of this is that
they think they're ready
we've asked enough questions they've
changed some things around are there
other people that are planning on
implementing to experiment with this so
that we can actually start the early
coop what assignment this lot that does
not mean that the draft is done but do
people think it's clear enough and
staple enough to actually get an early
couplets on that that's that's really
the question now there I think we are
between Firefox and SS would be
interested in experimenting this I I
guess my my expectation is that actually
probably you know another assignment
later I mean the professional right so
you get in for a year to say is like you
know it they just based on my previous
appearance oh that's kind of stuff like
we're gonna probably find some stuff we
don't wanna learn we have to change a
lot of code points so I think the
earlier point assignment you know
mechanism is not really great fit for
the kind of work we do here but given
some we got I think if the chairs or
chairs an ad you're going to bend the
rules a little bit I think you know it's
fine to do a complete assignment that
you know we squat on here right I mean
like this is I mean the too many our
basic like we just write something down
in the wiki and like then we squatted it
well we do a couple assignment we squat
in it and either case you know the thing
that they're either we are see that
fuzzy version or at the case within a
year and then eventually eventually came
you see in a year or two so this thing
just be the same to me so I'm Baker as a
general thing I think that we shouldn't
make Kurt point assignments a barrier to
innovation because if you do that you'll
never ever be
able to experiment because you'll never
get good like to do the experiment right
so generally that's why we're doing the
eye on a registry draft update right is
to kind of lower the bar so we can do
this so that's I mean I'm kind of like
our people violently objecting and if no
one is then great we can just get that
process started at some process thing or
I send a message the mailing list and we
go yeah yeah yeah so the abies has
something to watch yeah I do have one
question though
you said that it was 30% less bytes you
know compression how much is that as a
reduction in bikes because I mean like
if I'm doing an RSA certificate versus
EC DSH I mean like RSA keys and
signatures ain't gonna be compressing
much so it's the number of bikes that
I'm interested in I'm not sure the
number of bytes Victor did this but the
compression is over the whole
certificate so of course you could for
example use ECDSA and compress that and
then you would get a higher compression
well yeah but RSA random numbers don't
compress yes it's the all the other
stuff in the certificate that compress
right
ian's when Google I'm very supportive of
this as a person who operates a bunch of
servers that i don't want to make them
play attacks and i also don't want to
make all my aunt HT to our titties so
obviously like yeah thank goodness
because i mean if people looked in
Victory's numbers my memory is basically
without this something like half or more
of Surtur large enough that under the
current with guidelines you would have
to have a 2 R 2 T n Sheikh he didn't
have a resumption okay firstly I think
that we would be interested in having
terms with this not that I'm not sure we
will you know deploy channeling a bigger
vessel again it's fairly off in a
reduction on the order of a kilobyte or
more
Chris would Apple yeah we'd also be
interested in experimenting and doing it
around with this as well
Connick Ritz Facebook is also interested
its parents this one come and they have
the certificate from us and type space
is just one bite right now
we might want to consider making that to
rights to so we're currently really only
up to algorithms I think we might
consider it I'm not convinced that we
need to buy it but so one has to be my
in the future wants you yeah do some
mistakes so one point is that right now
we don't do compression dictionaries so
to actually add dictionaries we would
need to allocate more code points so
that might be I think I think given that
we're now at the point where we're
talking about deploying it and there's
some cost to us to like to do to grab me
another code point I think probably be
worth making that to our deaths as kind
of suggests the compression dictionary
if you might you might have known if you
like a brush dictionaries yeah of course
I guess do you also do this is a
treasure for the ad do we need we don't
need some other provisional mechanism
for registering these good ones right
because you're just like these are since
I inside their conscious of this code
registration right so we don't need we
don't need like a really components I'm
in for Bratva you've height there'll be
a registry with two initial values for
broadly and with another one is a and
then go from there so that's the idea if
they're gonna add a dictionary it'll be
at another point in that so the point of
third for colon or whatever here I think
this is very good work a lot of the
discussion in the you you started
working was about the size of the large
certificate changed in the problems that
causes for EOBs and I'm also very into
interesting experimenting
comic Ritz just be clear I wasn't asking
for it it's not code it's just all right
thank you thanks that's great we'll get
that administration stuff started on the
list shortly Christian you're up
we got three presentations in 30 minutes
so ten minutes of shot that's great grow
back on time good morning I am Christian
Adama
I am presenting here the state of the
sni encryption draft the SNI Kushan do I
have to walk started about a year ago
written bit less than that we went
through a presentation effectively what
I did back in last May June was to get
old early all the reason why we come to
sni encryption and put them in the draft
and then collect two plausible
candidates and put that in the same
draft and the list of reasons was first
corrected in June in an evil drafters
with a doc divided walking group and
here we are now I have had some feedback
but not a whole lot and why because
that's where I assess what we have that
the dwarf has basically five parts this
first and an introduction which provide
the motivation why you want to do that
and why you want to do that is that
effectively there are two pieces of
metadata that are sticking out on the
Internet today outside of the encryption
domain one are the DNS names that you
send in DNS queries and the other one is
the sni that you send in
TRS heroes and it turns out that we have
a good ender now on DNA on DNS
encryption the several solutions are
available so
the SNI in clear-text really sticks out
and as sweet the motivation we have to
have a way for people want to be
discreet
to encrypt the sni or hide it somehow
that has wisdom a good consensus the
list of attack recommends both the
motivation and the list of attack I
think a good consensus from what I read
in the email and in the in the list we
don't have that much consensus on the
proposed solutions and one one of the
solution when the HIV solutions of your
solutions documentation of stuff that
does exist in h-e-b today but the
proposed solution using either tunneling
or session resumed of basically low
consensus so let's be clear my
proposition is that we want to make
forward progress there and that what
progress will mean discussing the
solutions and to do that I would like to
first I mean least provide this list of
attack in some kind of information or
RFC by excising the solution from the
current draft and just publish that that
we can have a reference and then I've
separate to are progressing normally on
each of the four solutions jessy kehling
we already area director i think what's
lacking is a list of how this might be
used by others so you have a balance to
the draft by just listing attacks it's
not a balanced approach so some some are
using s and i yes how is it being used
in non attack waves oh you wanted to
tell you on why do we have a sanaya yes
yes well we can write just on the
attacks then this is not balanced we can
write that we can thank you so yeah
thank you know D I make
normally TLS doesn't we haven't done
these kind of things where we split it
out but like the kind of analysis over
here that have other documents that
explain the protocol it's just not
something we've done a lot so it's the
kind of question is are we okay with
that would be okay like separating it
out and having behaved you sponsor the
first part and then we just work on the
solutions and that's kind of the the
range of questions I was hoping we could
kind of like track down so it's mostly
like we're still working on this but you
know how the documentation goes so
that's kind of what I was hoping we're
gonna figure out this is somewhat of an
exceptional case a lot of the other
things that we're doing there is a
solution and we just made a bid on it
till everyone's happy with that solution
but here no one's really unhappy with
any of the solutions because all of them
have various costs and there's various
trade-offs that you might make in a
particular deployment there would move
you toward towards one solution over the
other or maybe you just can't deploy any
of the solutions and you know it's just
too hard a problem for you I think I
think this is a reasonable strategy for
dealing with that having having the
description of the problem statement and
the requirements and some of the reasons
that people do SNI in a document helps
establish a bit of a bit of a footing on
which we can then talk about solutions
and the solution was honestly each one
of those is gonna be yeah take it or
leave it this is this is awful for the
following reasons but you might be able
to deploy it in this situation and and I
expect to have a number of them over
time and I think Christians proposal
here is are there any violent objections
to that this proposed way forward if
there are please get to the microphone
it's the why now sold thank you
back on time excellent okay hello Nick
Sullivan this is a proposed draft that
Eric and myself and a few other people
have discussed which is about bringing
back the idea of a semi static
diffie-hellman negotiation handshake
mode to TLS 1.3 as an optional extension
so the TLS 1 3 key schedule it it has
almost all the features that that were
in the earlier versions of the TLS
drafts except there's one additional
mode which is the one RTT semi static
mode in which this was in earlier
versions of TLS in the draft and it was
was eventually removed due to complexity
and due to the fact that there were two
methods to do the same thing which is
resumption so what the semi static mode
is it is rather than when you do a
resumption using a PSK that was
established from a previous connection
you use a diff in public key that's sent
from the server whether as a as part of
the the session ticket or through other
means and one of the issues we had was
what does this other means mean there
are suggestions of doing it through DNS
and and other mechanisms but none of
them really made a lot of sense versus
versus a PSK there weren't so many use
cases to justify being part of the main
draft so the technically speaking the
way that this would work is rather than
signing the entire handshake as a
certificate verify what you would do is
you compute a Mac over the transcript up
to that point using the server's
diffie-hellman key as well as the client
ephemeral diffie-hellman key next slide
please
so the motivation for the straf is
there's multiple ones
one of which has to do with with
tracking or with the the idea that if
you do a resumption the server knows
exactly what the first connection is and
this is this is trackable and there's
certain influence certain applications
notably DMS over TLS where you're most
likely to just have one interaction with
the client and server during the
connection so in likely will be used the
zero RTT mechanism so you end up having
a situation where this first connection
is actually every every request to the
server although it's one RTT the
entirety of the the protocol it is
linkable from one request to another so
it's desirable to have some unlink
ability from one to the next another
motivation here is the simplicity of
single primitive protocols if you have
Diffie if you have TLS and you have the
ability to have divyam in certificates
or diffie-hellman authentication from
the server side then you can implement
TLS without implementing any of the
signatures and in some constrained cases
this is better because then you only
have to implement if you Hellman you
don't have to have multiple algorithms
it makes a smaller piece of smaller code
code based on either the client or the
server side and on the client side if
you have key pinning or more things like
this it helps there's another thing that
this contributes to is that you can mix
a long term server key into the master
secret so this is this is another thing
that some people are concerned about is
potential PRNG failures on on the server
side question for clarification
you had one RTT involved in the previous
slide but now talking about zero RTT are
you are you looking to restore the semi
static 0 ICT mode or are we talking
about something else we're sort of
talking
talking about both the the draft is
currently written only describes the
one-hour teaching mode but it could be
extended to potentially a zero RTT mode
and the the goal of the draft is to
support potentially both maybe at Curtin
I think so I'm not sure L agree um
I mean so I think the current draft as
Nick says really supports a somewhat
about B TLS and easy except for sweets
with replace the signature we the part
of the reason we have removed the you
know further is removes the 0tt
sort of easy th mode was we had a lot of
reasoning about it and it was in
duplicative so I I guess I'm less
excited about that they were prepared to
sort of engage with it I think we would
PR for me or PR from from from Chris
about that so I think like on death for
things we're thinking I think frankly
there's also a lot of questions about
whether or not you know without any will
redistribute the keys that you need you
made that work what other reason we
initially did us at that so I think like
and I even the final professional is
like we're not quite sure how that
composes because that was definitely a
source of like potential security
problems we do with the house no thanks
oh yeah that's right
Kenny contras and I've only just seen
this for the first time so I'm doing
kind of live crypt analysis here as well
so isn't it honorable to KCI attacks key
compromised impersonation sites where if
I have until they're on a client
ephemeral then of course I can somehow
impersonate that client they suffer but
now it can also impersonate the server
to the client because the keys only
derived from thy feminine a long-term
what did I misunderstand maybe your
maybe you should get like you get the
actual yeah we'll get to the diagram for
the key scale if I can learn so I guess
oh it's just so no I don't think so so
you to be clear
I mean if you were quite ephemeral then
um see so I think suicides they say
jørgen is a good climate control then
you can push the server but you look
kind of ephemeral you can merely you can
really a start and he merely allow this
connection to go through and then and
then and then sit in subjects after
things are quiet I don't think I don't
think that I don't mean the fellows
never security values I don't think I
mean sorry has no authentication by you
don't think I mean yes it has I think
there's a different from from the
ordinary set this was actually a lot my
hope is that the figures later will help
clarify this so yeah when we get to the
diagrams of where the new keys are put
into the key schedule that should help
clarify though I'm not sure I understand
the attack because this this server
ephemeral does have to be incorporated
as well as the server law I think it's
okay okay for his attack so this wasn't
this is ugly visit I've used to don't be
TLS as well but um um Amir so they if
you know the plan if I'm world right so
so say so say the client like say you
completely guide to your private server
you've been now generate a transcript or
client will accept like dependent server
because you can pair the client
ephemeral
with the cert with both these services a
republic you are right I'm saying that
it's true but the primary different but
as I said if you like your alternative
would be to take two along the clients
reaffirm local server capsule the rustic
capsule the server server side the
transcript so imagine chills porters is
now you a lot of client services the
message that's a surfer you capture the
server's transcript and then you just
gagney servers are transmitted directly
so the primary difference between these
two is in one case you need to certainly
outline their case you going to survey
online unless I'm asleep and I think I
believe he is that not is that not in
fact real quite is then upfront right is
that I've had to copy police to feeling
systems I think it depends exactly how
you mix the different key components
together so you can't avoid them if
you're careful if you're mixing long
term and short term or long term
more components together in various
different ways there's like a bunch of
literature on this which we should yeah
I guess guess what this is really saying
is this is going to need some security
analysis which we already absolutely
that yeah this is this is really a very
early stage idea and so we're trying to
gauge whether there's interest in
actually person that finds a bunch of
game leaving in here about like exactly
what makes it right next slide please
so moral motivation so one of the one of
the other reasons that this
diffie-hellman based TLS 1.3 wasn't
possible was because it's very unlikely
that TLS certificates for ECD age shares
would be practical in the near term
where this construction called delegated
credentials makes this possible and time
bounded key swap is is sort of a it says
echo what is this but this is a this is
a Richard bounce way of explaining it
basically it's whatever the key is used
to compute the certificate verify is
swapped with what's in the delegated
credentials this is an adopted draft
that is still being worked through and
also if you use something like this then
you can do you don't have to do the
expense of RSA signature operation in
the handshake so this this helps with
server performance there are some semi
static heat distribution scenarios such
as IOT and replacement of pre-show keys
that allows you to to mix in the client
ephemeral rather than just a PS PSK and
you know there are some other
theoretical ways of fishing semi Static
keys all right so this is the current
key schedule at least for deriving
things deriving master secret and here's
the if you take one step forward next
slide
here is the place in which it's proposed
that the semi static negotiation is SS
is the client ephemeral with the server
semi static it gets mixed in
other than the zero into the the extract
for the master secret next slide please
this would be practically implemented as
a set of new signature schemes and these
would be TV home and signature schemes
it's not technically a digital signature
but it it takes the form of a signature
because the certificate verifies a Mac
derived from a diffi Hellman with with
this key the obviously these should not
be in the signature algorithm
certificate scheme so the split in TLS
1.3 between certificate algorithm since
Jeff Gallagher algorithms for the
certificate is is is good here because
certificates are not typically signed by
him to thielemann in trace so in the
next the last set of these are the set
of open questions should we keep a
certificate verify message it was
suggested that potentially the keys
could be rolled into the eventual
finished message and rather than have a
certificate verified be rather than
having to max in the middle handshake I
think probably have some comments on
this but um you could potentially have
just one finished message and can client
authentication can it happen the same
way can you do diffie-hellman keys this
is not fully fleshed out another open
question is if you're doing semi static
diffie-hellman it's semi static you're
not using ephemeral keys so if you have
some sort of diffie-hellman group that
can only be used once this does not work
with those compared to the signature
scheme so we we usually work with and
and then again the question is the semi
static key should be part of the key
schedule or should it only be looked
into the certificate verify the this has
different effects on the analysis the
analysis that we have currently of TLS
1.3 wouldn't map really closely to this
if the semi static he was only mixed in
two
certificate verify message rather than
the actual key transcript so but it's
it's not clear if if these what the
exactly right
consideration is for this so we just
need to keep it short done next slide
please
all right so there's also this is a pull
request for as we mentioned mixing it
into the early data and where that would
fit essentially that that extract value
right there rather than going directly
to the early secret is an extract from
the ephemeral and semi static a small
request this morning after talking about
this yesterday basically get rid of that
nonsense in the row with the SS and just
replace that PSK with the diffie-hellman
of the my role and who just kind of fall
out yes okay so for this diagram and the
play this one would says PSK just
replace up with the SS next slide please
so again there's there's a couple open
issues about semi sat agrees you know
you have to do a public key operation to
read early data now rather than a
symmetric one is that a problem for das
how do you choose a PSK identity there's
some definitely some some issues of our
own presumption that need to be sorted
out and these were difficult ones in TLS
1.3 which we decided to punt on in favor
of the much simpler PSK so on next slide
please
so these are generally the questions
that we wanted to raise for the group is
is this something people are interested
in pursuing should the this is an
extension should this hand extension be
able to radically change the handshake
there's you're significantly changing
the key schedule here and you know
removing signatures from the algorithm
and also our people are there anybody
out there who's willing to review the
draft and provide comments
idea because from the very beginning we
thought that we could be able to bring
back semi static into it TLS means to
show so you can I'm like Kenya has like
a week to think about the captain says
I'm not doing this like so from the
viewpoint of all the proofs they have
already been done using the semi static
key to generate the PS k40 RT t even in
the first message that'll be completely
fine using it as a Mac key in the
certificate verify or be completely fine
you can even use it it's all client
authentication that'll be fine there is
a KCCI attack there but it is almost
inevitable when you make this from an
asymmetric signature based scheme to a
more symmetric demon whisky whatever
that's mainly for the handshake at the
record layer anybody ever forced so
that's ok but the moment you mix in the
key into the key schedule the proofs no
longer works so we'll have to redo all
the proofs that we did for that
particular case so and I don't see what
the big advantage is for that and I'd
like to understand that a bit but I
believe that the main advantage is to
keep a linear key schedule which is
maybe not a very strong one the primary
advantage of Sookie go back Lots that
the show then the change to change the
key schedule for where you're injecting
the key right so the primary advantage
of making this change the nominal
primary admittedly has changed is not
keeping the ER key schedule but is um
requiring compromise have both the
server static sorry is requiring
compromising with a server static and
the server run rule to compromise the
connection so in the in the current tool
supply crate mode you you don't need
you'll need to compromise the server
signature key to come right to
compromise that was I thinking and so
the not being the same preserves that
property and mixing it in makes this you
have to compromise call so the long term
piece of the hypothesis is say say
you've had a really bad period a good
pair of G's make your long term key but
a bad one you made the ephemeral key
then this would be suppose that's that's
the only run all the work
although I think recovering from a PRNG
by mixing in additional stuff is not
necessary I think you could take a semi
SATA key use that as part of your island
of a generation and get a nice ephemeral
that you could you know hi Tyler
phenomena I think you've probably
already covered this but could you
quickly clarify and remind us why we
abandoned semi-salic zero entity to
begin with and the reason I ask is
because at the tls really or not
workshop I think some of the car fix
work actually raised problems with the
zero RTT mode when we still had semi
static zero martyt and I know you're
proposing one RT semi static but you
also save potentially there are two T's
any static so the question is why we
abandoned semi static in tell us the
working group I think Eric stated that
earlier on it was a matter of it's
potentially duplicative and it was more
complex to analyze versus these simple
PSK based resumption it's my
understanding is really or not as it was
I remember there was there was some sort
of issue with semi static and but many
of those things have changed a lot now
and now without really composing those
things in the same way anymore and
similar attacks actually hold for PSK as
well but we fix those using the binders
that's what the binder state so
hopefully the binders will solid in this
situation is well word analysis to be
done right and and to be clear of the
strife only it does not support a
signature mode it's it's stiffie Hellman
Rusli I like this work however I'm a
little concerned about reusing the PSK
slot it's pretty clear that we're gonna
run out of time before we get to my
presentation today but I I had a
proposal to use that for the external
PSK
and so I'd like to come up with the way
work the two could both live and I think
that we can probably come up with a way
to do that some additional hash or KDF
or whatever but I I think that we do
want the short term quantum resistance
by enabling a external PSK to be mixed
in there so I'd like to I guess I'm
offering to work together on that thanks
Russ I feel how big yeah I I like this a
lot it's always seemed wrong to me that
we use signatures in TLS in the first
place because it provides a proof that a
key was involved in setting up a
connection that is unfortunate and maybe
that's some piece of information that I
never wanted to give away
I think yeah obviously we need to look
into the security of this like we've
looked into the security of everything
else but at the end of the day it's not
my DSA signatures entirely without
security issues I mean you've still got
the issue of if you screw up doing DSA
you screw up really badly and so I think
that that needs to be weighed in and I
suspect that when you get down to it
it's the same sort of effect that is
driving all these vulnerabilities under
the covers Chris would she wanted to
comment that we're trying to look at
modifying Casas Tamra model bird in
draft 23 for 1/3 to incorporate this
every sect just to get kind of some more
assurance and we're also working whether
it be boys early to China get some more
formal analysis of this to maybe a text
like those that Kartik mentioned alright
the Trump workshop don't come back to
bite us so I just wanted to address
Russell's point about the PSK so just to
clarify the one arti chemo doesn't
implicate the peace case not at all only
the 0rg motive case the vsj slot on the
Larkin mode implicates the zeroes lock
which we are which is already 0 which we
left in there for this purpose
so the only time that the PSK slot will
be implicated with ladies you are cutie
and then presumably they give a separate
problem because that's also where you're
cutting your pump using the PSK slot in
be like in the handshake also to
indicate where yeah which PSK you're
using so I think you think that you're
already overloading that so I think what
you'd end up doing is having some
structure in there that said I want to
use you know this you know this divvy
home accommodation Plus this PSK
together and then don't use I might and
as you say it is hkt have to end up in
this P it's case law so I think that's
very doable okay yeah can you hop ahead
two slides for a second or two the next
diagram there we go open yeah so
something like this where the
potentially the zero would be the PSK is
that we were saying okay I was actually
saying was you probably have a VM go
left where you basically say you say you
treat you treat you basically said what
you offer in that I mean this is like
just hand waving but you offer in the in
the PSK extension you offer a structure
which consisted of the diffie-hellman
which consisted of basically identifying
the server the server chefs that if you
wanted to use and also the PSK you
wanted to use the server would accept
them jointly and then we have a function
to turn those into those into one thing
you jump on the PS k slot but this would
work typically okay Oh secret that
stroke and server and other protocols
like noise framework and stuff they're
able to use the semi static secret
without using a signature based scheme
like a Mac it would be really nice if
you could get rid of the if check so max
Chen they come with like you have to
check a Mac those valid or not at the
end of it so it'd be really nice to
design a protocol which is exist without
having any it checks at all those
securities bacon tellurian
at the end you drive the key and that's
it so that's actually so yeah so it's
actually worth it so so the that that is
what happens if you mix it if you mix in
if you if you mix in the
very end the thing that they guided
where you mix it instead of the zero
that you also I mean yes sorry you get
that property and formally on valuable I
do not to get the property formally but
informally of the property that like
basically then just art dating boys I
don't know however if you get the
property and then they in the CK said
sort really at the property respect the
traffic use yeah I would prefer that way
of doing it than macking like actually
having them that my sister over time at
this point so I think we have to take
this to the list that there's obviously
some interest since there was a lot of
people that don't like so I'd say keep
going on the list and go from there
there wasn't one okay one other
presentation that got bumped
unfortunately a restless draft to p s
kzo most certificate authentication so
also take a look at that I take it to
list and thanks for your time folks
oh yeah where's the blue sheets and if
anybody wants some stickers come to the
front yes thank you