I
[Music]
because
well I guess we'll get in their way
I'm Donna least like with hallway and I
guess I'm acting this chair for this
meeting in the absence of the chair
since I'm working group secretary so
people should be aware of the note wall
some people have seen before but there
are rules concerning IPR if you
contribute to the IETF in any way so I
guess it would be desirable to have a
jabber scribe or something no anybody
willing to volunteer to do that okay
Aliyah its willing to do that so other
than that update nobody else asked to
make any presentation to this meeting
which is likely the a plan to be the
last row working group meeting so I'm
going to have a presentation on trill
history and stuff like that
anybody have any agenda bashing topics
they'd like to add there's not that much
to the lead I guess not so I shall start
by going over document status I think my
I updated these these slides are almost
up to date under document status we do
have the one RFC it's been published
since the last meeting we have a whole
bunch of documents that are on the RFC
editors queue including one more that's
not shown here of these centralized
replication was added to the our
theaters queue a while ago and it just
really is in auth 48
it needs a little bit of work but we
have we address flush let's set our
bridge tell another our bridge to forget
some learn to back addresses centralized
replication is a way to slightly
different way to handle the distribution
of multi destination frames you know
active active case the directory
assisted encapsulation uses a directory
feature to control encapsulation at end
nodes but doesn't require any change in
the standards for our bridges let's then
do the D capsulation ecn support adds
ecn to the trill header it's fill header
extension had some spare bits in a multi
topology should be pretty
straightforward as multi topology
routing multi-level also this is a
multi-level which has unique nickname so
all the nicknames in the troll campus
including across all the level one areas
have unique nicknames
there was point to multi-point BFD in an
OEM extension troll transfer over MPLS
is an informational document about how
to transport role or MPLS and then their
channel allows vendor specific
extensions to be provided to the
arbitral feature communicating between
our bridges you can look at any of these
to see what they have to say
there's also smart end nodes which has
been added to the RC editors queue in
the past hour or two
its uses its modifications to end nodes
and modifications to the edge our
bridges so that the Eden nodes can do
not only encapsulation but also can do
the D calculation so we have one draft
trill over IP which has been deferred
and I guess we consider it the next iesg
tell a chat in April I guess at that
point it status will be ad sponsored
and we have some other grafts so there
are two draught ITF trilha multi-level
single nickname which is a nickname
aggregated version provides for even
larger scaling because different level
one areas and the multi-level routing
can have duplicated nicknames between
them because they're aggregated to a
single nickname that represents the area
when they're in level 2 or in other
level ones there's a trail parent
selection is an informational graph that
in quite get through or group consensus
so I it depends on the new area director
who may want to say some words at at
some point which will hopefully be ad
sponsored there's also two drafts
concerning group keying and group key
profiles these are ways to do group
keying for for over IP multi destination
packets and group keying for multi
destination our bridge channel messages
actually add the route keying draft is a
very general group keying algorithm and
the one in profiles profiles of those
two particular uses there also are some
yang grafts which sue hairs has been
primarily handling who is under the
weather's about as a health problem so
she is not here and I'm not sure what to
report on those I is a bubbly she does
plan to complete those is a basic
Trillian graft and one on om and one on
performance management I mean there are
our FCS on how to to do am and
performance measurement in drill but
needs to be the yang documents for those
and lastly we have a document in IDR
which is how to send Trillo link state
through bgp so that's been an ID are
working with last call for a while so
I'm not sure what the status on that is
but
you may need more support if people want
to look at that and support it in my dr
that might be a good thing or comment on
it or you know if you don't like it
oppose it but with more comments on it
an idea would be a good thing so anybody
have any comments or questions on me
that stuff ah okay hi there speaker oh
that's my job again I just heard on the
parent selection draft you mentioned
it's not really that's okay actually
you're breaking up with it so yeah I
just had a question on that parent
selection draft I mean you mentioned
there's no consensus
can't hear you very well I got okay it's
breaking up a lot you want to type
instead yeah yeah yeah perhaps
Oh under parents election got an
admission of our election draft so is
your question how it would profess I
imagine that would be about it is the
right so what's going on is we had a lot
of work to finish up in drill to get
things done and in fact after this
meeting I haven't expected I am planning
on closing 12 after the meeting we've
gotten all of the documents there that
we interested they're getting through
this working group for the pair
obstruction documents if you have good
enthusiasm for pursuing that you have a
couple of routes one option is to bend
it to Archie's uwg and talk about that
and that's the case for any of the troy
documents just like we do that for VRP
documents and things that don't have
their specific home and oil also speak
with margin who will be able to talk to
you about that baby sponsoring there
does not look like does that answer your
question
okay good so the only piece I wanted to
say this is it is you know we've gotten
an amazing amount of work through with
trail and there are deployments and as
an if there are needs to do more work
you know as I said the routing area
working group will be available
I am expecting to close in about now and
has the mailing list remain open for
conversation
there is one document which is the troll
over appeal which didn't make the cutoff
as we talked about there are certain
issues with that one and is going to so
I guess I have this presentation I sort
of took what presentation I gave on
trill a while ago and I extended the
just on time perhaps the we have a a
cake and back unfortunately people who
are listening remotely will not be able
to partake of the cake that was just
rolled into the room but I think maybe
we could take like a real brief recess
because I want to take a picture of the
cake for any pieces are cut out of it
and other people are welcome to take
some
so
[Music]
[Applause]
Thomas booth
[Music]
[Laughter]
well we can we can just send a message
to the attendees list at the end of the
session saying there's still some cake
left in Paulo si
come and get it
[Music]
as I have this presentation hey I took a
presentation I've made on trill some
years ago few years ago and I tweaked it
around several has way too many slides
but I'll zip through the ones that are
um people should already know but it's a
few of the ones are kind of interesting
to think about again so what is true
either that's interesting
why did it's not mm-hmm
maybe I should okay well I tell you what
I will solve that problem by using the
wrong working room if I use the oh
that's not here because it's over there
well okay
it has animation in there but apparently
that's not quite compatible with the
okay so there's a 3d F okay so what
we'll do is we'll go over and get the
PDF version
that'll be faster because there won't be
the animation that's not what I wanted
to where I want it to go okay so now I
need to smash this to be against this
over here let's try doing that there we
go okay so so basically troll is very
simple idea in a calculate the famous
with a hop count route from via eius
eius and d capsulate than when they're
on it rates all these great features so
the reason that this wasn't done before
was that when bridging was first
designed they were all these constraints
that people hardly remember these days I
mean you couldn't first of all were the
Ethernet couldn't you couldn't change
the frame there was no bit you could use
and early equipment really rigidly
enforced the Ethernet length limit of
fifteen hundred and twelve White's if
you good the address or 1500 data so you
couldn't encapsulate it wasn't it it
would not work
and he was able not to change any of the
end node so bridging had these enormous
constraints suspending for you is a
great solution but it's really pretty
brittle you know one of the differences
between driving bridging is the routing
only send stuff out if it gets enabling
messages on a port so it's
sort of fails in the safe direction if
the camp process or else to process
control messages whereas rigging send
stuff out all reports and bless it gets
messages that indicate it's unsafe so it
fails in the unsafe direction tends to
melt things down with beta loops the
drill is designed to combine the
features of both routers and bridges has
lots of other features so which are now
possessed by other protocols but there's
tables grow only with the size of the
number of of throw routers to our
bridges not with the number of n
stations it's compatible with our IP
routers so there's the troll canvases
transparent two routers like bridges are
sports the VLANs and so forth as MTU
support active active connection at the
edge padded directory features and
molding topology and of course like
spanning tree I mean unlike every other
protocol
besides been in Crete it has a poem
which is algo I'm version 2 which
actually written by Ray Pro Maria's son
the radio wrote the original algorithm
for spanning tree so I won't burden you
with reading this but it's here also I
put algo I'm the problem for spanning
tree in the Supplemental slides at the
end so it's an interesting because
there's sort of this hierarchy of things
so bridges don't see hugs or repeaters
and do you have hubs and repeaters and
stuff it just sort of looks like a
bigger cable like multi-drop Ethernet or
something but the fact the hubs and pre
Peters repeat everything that's that's
that mode of operation is terminated by
a bridge which looks of the stuff and
might decide not to forward it or or
whatever then full switches are above
that to them bridged lands appear to be
transparent but they terminate the
spanning tree algorithm so a spanning
tree is never sent through it through a
troll campus you can take it make a
bridge land you can replace the bridges
one at a time by troll switches and as
you do so it gets increasingly efficient
and the spanning tree domains get
chopped and come smaller and smaller
which is a good thing a spanning tree
doesn't
work very well when you get large
domains people control switches run the
troll protocol and in routers where
three at the top level everything below
that troll canvas looks transparent to
IP routers but IP routers terminate the
the tro protocol and don't forward there
they drill things through through them
and this is mostly determined by how
they treat various multicast addresses
so this really all happened because in
November 2002 Beth Israel Deaconess
Hospital in Boston at a total network
meltdown they had been purchasing
various other hospitals and clinics and
his kept sort of plugging all these
layer 2 networks into each other and it
kind of worked for a while until it
exceeded the critical length therefore
spanning tree though the hop limit just
kind of an arbitrary limit in spanning
tree and suddenly a whole thing melted
down and I if I should mention who the
manufacturer the equipment was but
anyway it took a while for the equipment
to get upgraded to stuff which would
solve this problem and them to chop up
that our network into pieces so a
spanning tree would work in the meantime
for like days or all the paperwork in
this major hospital was being done by
hand like on paper and pencil which
other I mean even the new favor article
specifically says spanning tree you
don't find newspaper articles mentioning
spanning tree very often so radio
decided to do something better about
this so this is the main history part of
this so I went back a little ways
you know 64 1964 packet switching
mannered eating that invented the link
state routing invented in 85 was when
spanning tree was devised in 87 radio
design and decnet phase 5 otherwise
known as is is as much minor tweaks to
make it more itu issue five years aria
15 years later this problem occurs and
radio designed something which basically
uses AI as is to provide a more bridging
like interface so that the ends agents
think they're talking to a big Ethernet
when it's really being routed and that
she presented this 14 coke Infocom
initially and
why Tripoli 802 and it wasn't met with a
very welcoming reception there so she
presented to the IETF and a working
group was chartered so initially that
just had to share a Burtonwood mark and
margaret then Wasserman coal Kong was
the internet ad when it was chartered
fairly soon thereafter the internet ad
was changed to mark Townsley Margaret
didn't run again and fairly soon a
little bit longer boycott e the year
later I was added as co-chair so it
looked like in a 2008 that it was like
done you know was about to come out when
a semi fatal MTU problem was found with
the protocol so a whole bunch of MTU
features were added to it including I
Sai as probe in act PDUs and various
things that can AMT you feature to to so
if the feature means you can be safe
with we're somewhat reduced empty use it
also makes it possible for it to sort of
know what the MTU is and be able to take
advantage campus-wide if you happen to
have all your links support jumbo frames
so icky you can use jumbo link state
protocol messages and so on and so forth
with it the only things you can't do
jumbo are things like hellos because you
want to do hello is to discover a new or
bridge to find out maybe that our bridge
has to lower empty you because if you
use using anyway so there it looks like
for some reason trill didn't meet in the
July 2008 or 2009 meetings every other
meeting in this entire interval that
fill working group met at least there's
no minutes arrey in the Proceedings so
there's this problem ineffability
statement finally came out which i think
is slightly out of date then there's
another change in internet area
directory to ralph groms
that was convenient because of the time
ralph groms sat about a hundred feet
from me so right needed ad attention I
could get up I was consulting to Cisco
at the time and it was very convenient
yes for me yeah I I don't think he
minded so much I mean you know I feet
me to go away or come back later I
certainly would do that anyway so why so
this could be Solis MTU probably cause
something like a two-year delay was
somewhat less less but it moved to 2008
to 2010 so find the a base protocol was
a publication was requested and then it
was I took a while for her to get
approved and on March 15th the base
protocol is approved and at that time
the ether types have been allocated the
block of multicast addresses was
allocated III the time wanted to use
IETF multicast addresses IETF has a no
you I yam I can allocate multicast
addresses but the working group wanted
to take them out of the block that's
used by 802 del one so we submitted an
application and got a clock allocated
very low multicast number it's kind of
adjacent to the ones are actually used
by bridging and I've seen unhappy
expressions on the face of some people
when reading this and looking at but
anyway so we had an OP in 2010 very
early just control plane no data was
passed but you know exchanging hellos
and establishing adjacency and stuff
like that and in lieu took because the
approval it took a while to get through
the arcs the others queue is in 2011
when the base protocol spec 6325 surely
a foundation of stuff got published it
was held up I guess by the use of is is
which went through the eius eius working
group and at the time there was some
friction and it's decreased with time so
now I don't think there's any real
problem or anything if drill wanted
something from the ice ice working group
now I don't think Joe would have any
more or less difficulty than anybody
else would getting anything out of the
ice ice working group and very early
there was a very earlier was a RFC it
fell over PPP on a different link
protocol 12 a ppb doesn't have any ether
types uses PP beep code points and
everything like that sort of established
the architecture for trill link usage
and we got recharger we got reach
charted periodically in
2012 there was a second control plane
Interop at that point John Hudson was
added his working group secretary we did
but a burst of documents they're
agreeing amid OAM requirements directly
assistance high-level design then the
internet ad for troll changed again to
Ted lemon and there was the third
Interop in 2013 and that one actually
passed data and I was there with qua way
equipment and it all kind of worked and
everything and you know people could
send you to cast a multicast and
everything pretty neat then I say we get
me chartered so then to a lot of stuff
happened 2014 so early in 2014
Phil was moved to the routing area and
the Lea became the area director Eric
would mark left as a working group
co-chair and John Hudson who had been
secretary became the working group
co-chair and sue Harris became working
group secretary there was also this sort
of massive burst of documents and if you
look at this you'll notice the whole
first bunch like all but the bottom two
are consecutive RFC numbers and that's
because they were all held up on the
7176 trill you serve is is changes as I
recall anyway there was a normative
dependency which so these things are all
piled up and can plop they all came out
at once a whole bunch of stuff in here
very formative improvements and won't go
through but PFD support
there's clarifications Corrections and
updates city from experience yeah at
these interrupts knew just to say there
were especially the early ones there
were some questions people had about
what the spec mentor where it might be
ambiguous or something and there's only
was there typically there were people at
the Interop you know with the source
code and hey we we discuss how would you
work and they would like patch their
code at there to recompile and the sorry
statement problems have a back to act
around this you
first of all of C's came out turns out
most of these are standards for the
standards and I was on an author on many
of them which was made some people
unhappy so I would be I swapped with Sue
hares and she became a co-chair and I
became secretary 2015 is the the
basically that Trillo am graft welcome
it was published 2016 we sort of have
more documents coming through
where's way see the implementation of
active active active work and started
very early we took a while to get
through on our way mmm so on and so
forth
various extensions and sittings and in
2017 we had some of these RCS it was
obviously to earlier trail RFC's when
we'd found additions or improvements or
clarifications to make and so far on
2018 only one RFC's come out which is
the ARP and they were discovery
optimization there will be more in 2018
what would suspect from the huge list in
the artist at risk you
so is it if the I think this is complete
I'm sure it cumulative lists of the
companies that participated in the trill
and reveal the events at the mercy to
Hampshire in her on bility laboratory a
couple references one is an article in
the Internet Protocol journal on Trello
relatively early but still and then also
the reference to the original paper
presented by Radia at infocomm 2004
actually before the word trills sort of
been invented just referring to them as
are ridges or routing bridges so that's
my trill history presentation okay say I
threw on a couple of the algorithm for
spanning tree and a bunch of slides
explaining how troll works and how multi
destination works why did phony claims
why is is was selected as opposed to is
a OSPF
etc how Mac learning Weirich societies
that are are on the end
so right so does anybody have any oh yes
I'll go get the any other things they
want to bring up for this meeting
I'll wait time yeah 6:20 no it's about
so if not I guess I will you know add
run this here meeting which is the last
the last row meetings oh there is our
blue sheets up here I assume everybody
in the room is signed up okay thanks
thanks John for
there is a YouTube video of presentation
I made yeah presentation to nanog
was quite a while ago I think I did that
but there was a survey it was cold the
debate debate I don't know the thing I
didn't like so much about it I was there
I presented trill and several people
presented shortest path bridging and you
know I felt kind of outnumbered and
stuff biased so I'm not sure I did a
particularly good presentation but
anyway I think you can find all that on
YouTube or at least a in the nanog files
it's not on YouTube for some reason and
that arcing thing keeps videos there
presentations for past meetings on their
website so should I post a message to
the attendees list saying this cake
[Music]
a chain on that way we'll have that
maybe I have what you're the original
top so I should come up with such a list
of double-checked remark allophones
is Philippe to make sure so they were
all sure people who gave it earlier then
had yeah stop present my management
stuff sent getting remember the end of
the card Cisco so yes all right fine
huge number of people would think
because at that bigger mob but
you