and also reasonably meet my phone's I
know that most people in the u.s. waking
up evil like me and he always
speculatively reading every presenter
when they're halfway through just see no
actually it's a BCP about that until you
walk it's silence kingly I am because
that's another thing that's really
embarrassing
Oh Jung ah yeah a little pop up that's
it what rubbish is this person talking
that's me wrote those two doing anything
anyone's presenting to my embassy
don't panic folks we will start soon
we're just sorting out a few issues no
one in this room should be surprised
that Adrienne and I have issues so hi
I'm Adrienne that Spencer we are going
to talk about writing good internet
drafts hopefully that's why you're here
and you're not here because you got
trapped in this part of a Hilton and
couldn't find your way home so why us
who are we
Spencer is is the Wonder hamster and I'm
the old dog for legacy reasons of our
own internet domains and so on
Spencer is currently serving as a
transport area director and has done so
for the last five years and that means
he reviews all of the internet drafts
that are produced by the IETF so he's
got quite a wide view of that and he's
been around even longer than me which is
why his beard is gray and mine isn't
he's done lots of stuff in the ITF on
the s3 he's in the internet research
task force and here on the OAB as well
weren't you previously yeah yeah I have
just been appointed as independent
streams editor sorry in submissions
editor and that means I'm responsible
for RFC's come outside the ITF process I
was six years on the s3 as the original
area director and I've chaired working
groups
across sort of half of the ITF together
I looked it up we have co-authored a
total of 85 rfcs so that is one tenth of
all RFC's no 1/100 1% of all RFC I feel
better our fault and obviously because
of our time on the is G we have reviewed
literally thousands of internet drafts
so what's the point what's the point of
being here what's the point of posting
an internet draft maybe you've got an
idea you won't do a tf2 a dot maybe it's
something you want to get published as
an RFC to influence the standards that
govern the internet maybe it's just some
thoughts that you want to share it's
it's like a discussion document whatever
the point of it is the implication is
you want people to be able to read it
and understand it you want the process
the publication process to run through
successfully and that may be through the
is G or the IRT F of the IAB or the ISE
and so you actually need to get that the
people responsible for that publication
process to agree yes this has to be
published and lastly you want the RFC
editor team to actually be able to
publish it so there's a publication
process that says here's the document
now let's turn it into proper English
and format it correctly and get it out
there the document has to be in a form
that that can be done without the use of
magic so let's talk through the basic
process steps take the microphone out of
here so I can see the side
which I can probably read and you
probably come from the better room but
there we are the slides are online if
you want to follow along that way so
anyone can post an ID right anyone
there's no membership no requirements
all you have to do is format it and give
it to the submissions tool
there's no checks on the quality or the
content of what's posted there is a
retrospective check if you post
something that is defamatory or illegal
then your internet draft will be removed
but otherwise anything having posted it
it just sits there so if you do not ask
people to comment on it to read it then
nothing happens the best place to ask it
for that sort of comment is on the
appropriate mailing list so it said go
write emails as it progresses you can
ask working group chairs to adopt it so
it becomes an official IETF internet
draft usually the working group chairs
go and poll their working grit and say
do we want to work on this are we happy
and some working groups have teams of
reviewers to vet the documents and
obviously the chairs review it once it's
adopted the working group owns the draft
and what that really means is that they
are responsible for the content so be
aware you have your favourite idea the
best idea in the whole world you bring
it to a working group they say yes we'd
like to work on this they adopt it and
then they change it that's that's how
the HTF consensus process works so live
with it or don't bring it to the atf at
some point then it's judged by the
working group to be complete or complete
ish and they go for a working group last
call which is for people to raise any
in issues its then given to a designated
shepherd often motion grip chairs but
not always and they produce a short
writer and asked to publication which
means it gets handed to an area director
who reviews the document often sends it
to their own Directorate review team
when they're happy it goes for IETF last
call and that involves a review by the
community by more directorates by I
honor and ultimately by the whole of the
iesg and then finally it goes to the RSC
editor who performs the rather important
copy edit function i short note about
copyright in IPR when you produce a
draft and submit it there's an automatic
requirement that include a piece of
boilerplate text the boilerplate text is
something you need to read and you may
need to show it to your sponsoring
company's legal team because it says
stuff about IPR and copyright I am NOT a
lawyer and I've never played one in a
television series but I do know that
this text says that you are making a
personal declaration and statement to
the IETF about IPR so you are personally
responsible for what you say your
company is also carried along with that
so you're making a statement about them
and that means that your company's
lawyers need to know what you're doing
and be advised the copyright is also
there as well in the boilerplate and you
are agreeing to share your copyright
with the ATF so that means you post it
and in the ATF can
use that text for other useful things
the copyright text can be varied under
special circumstances but it's pretty
rare to do so if you want to know how to
do it read the the RFC s that describe
the process or talk to an area director
Hadrian couragous add one of the
definitions of not political and so
favorably is that you're not you're kind
of saying this is not going to be
considered for standard is a for a
standards track so this is now that this
isn't this will not be a standard if it
you know you're basically that's the the
bus you got off of by doing something
different um so the the standard
approach in the software industry and
hopefully is now properly taught in
computer science courses is that the
later you find about the more expensive
it is to fix
so finding above it specification is
half the price of finding above design
and it's half the price of flying
reading code and finding it in the field
is really expensive so we want to do the
same with our documents we want to get
the bugs out early before they've caused
damage and before people have become
emotionally attached to what they've
written it's remarkable how often
something comes up with a late-stage
problem with the document and the
authors really really don't want to
change it because it's their baby well
if they introduce their baby to the
world much younger it can be molded into
the right shape don't and that really
means don't leave it to the last stage
don't rely on the iesg to catch
technical issues and to fix things talk
to people much earlier in the process
avoid the late surprises that cause pain
that's kind of like setting the scene
and now we can actually get into the how
to do it how to get a good internet
draft the first thing is get the format
the layout and the mandatory sections in
there right up front that way you don't
have to do any reformatting later you
don't have to make excuses there are
some tools which you can find off the
RSC editor web pages that help you know
it so if you use something right XML to
RFC it puts in sections for you it can
put in a boilerplate as well read the
RSC editors style guide the style guide
talks about two things it talks about
the sections you have to have and what
information has to go in each section
and it talks about some basic do's and
don'ts about how to write the text out
of deep Jannetty of bullet points
whether to write in slang or not
so the mandatory stuff for sections that
are in there all of the the boilerplate
that's about IPR about copyright about
the the fact that internet drafts expire
every six months that's got to be
present to be honest the way I do it is
I go and look at the most recent draft
that was posted and passed all the
checks and copy it but you can get a lot
of it free with the tools you have to
have a security consideration section
you have to have an eye on a
consideration section and we'll talk
about those in a minute
it's really really strongly recommended
to have a manageability consideration
section as well
and I wrote an RFC on manageability
considerations and
there's an even better one that is on
another slide as well there are other
sections that may be helpful
implementation status telling people
you've already written code and it's
already in the field helps people know
how to take what you've written other
sections that people might say are
needed are not really needed so if you
read RSC 40:41 it suggests you should
have morality consideration section you
don't have to do it you should do it
you'll be struck by lightning if you
don't so security it's built to be there
and it has to be meaningful it doesn't
have to be there from day one or it can
be empty from day one but by the time
you're asking for working group last
call it's got to be real it's got to be
what you think is right
so don't just write what you think you
can get away with the security police
will read it and will tell you you're
wrong
think about it think about attacks on
your protocol and think about attacks
using your protocol are you using an old
protocol in a new way
if so relying on the old protocol
Security's not enough think about it
privacy has become very very important
so could your protocol be used for
snooping could your protocol expose PII
for people really work hard it's your
protocol you want it to be secure and
safe so there's lots of relevant
existing security documents that may be
related to your protocol you can go out
and you can look at if you go to the
MPLS working group and search for the
word security you'll find a number of
RFC's that are relevant for MPLS so
that's it
approach talk to working group chairs
they should know existing security work
related to your area of work and then
look at some Pierce's there are there
are number of RFC's that give guidance
on how to write security sections how to
think about security and privacy go to
the security Directorate a security
Directorate is a group of people who get
security and they have volunteered their
time to review stuff so when you've
written your draft and it's yeah the
basic protocol is there you can go to
the Directorate and say help can you can
you point me at what sort of security
things I should be doing with this
document and you can always ask for help
pass for help on mailing lists are asked
for help from working group chairs ask
for help from a deer's people want to
get security right Iona Iona is Ayana
considerations is another mandatory
section and you cannot be clear enough
ok the text in this you should treat as
if you're giving formal protocol
instructions to a protocol engine even
though the person who's consuming it is
a human because if this goes wrong your
protocol is broken so you have to say
which registries be precise which
registries are you talking about use the
name because that name of the registry
don't just say there's a registry for
protocol bits that you know nail it down
write down exactly what you want the
registry to say when the changes have
been made don't say oh allocate via a
value say allocate a value saying this
is its name this is its purpose is the
reference basically cut and paste from
the registry that exists into the draft
and then fill in what you want don't
include other stuff
if you put sort of general discussion in
the owner considerations section then
Ayane doesn't know is this stuff they
should put into the registry or is it
you just chat in if you want to chat put
it in the rest of the draft okay big bug
better do not use explicit values when
you write an eye on a section for an
existing registry don't do it unless
you've done early allocation or you're
actually creating the registry it's not
your job to put values in there it's
Iona's job and if you put values in
there you've run all sorts of problems
because somebody else might have written
draft also putting values in and now
you've got contention the whole point of
Ayane is to sort that out so use tags
conventionally use TBD and identify
which one so if you're asking for three
code points have TBD one TBD to and TBD
three and that way it's all nice and
clean and then we've got a bunch of
resources talking about how to write
high honor considerations in 8126
and some discussion of experimental code
points as well if in doubt ask your work
in group chairs for help
manageability considerations it's not a
requirement that you do this but you
know honestly you should because you
want your protocol to get used you want
it to get managed properly and be usable
you need to think about these things at
day one an absolute classic is om om
tends to get left out of protocols right
the way through until they're in the
field and then it has to be reverse
engineered so a good protocol spec
starts talking about manageability early
bunch of ref
is there there's also an Operations
Directorate they are also volunteering
their time to review your document and
make suggestions okay implementation
status which is in is talked about in 79
42 really helps people understand where
your document fits into the world and
that makes them reviewing a lot easier
is it an idea you're pumped in is it an
idea that's widely deployed it's a it's
a proof that the document describes the
protocol that works it's a proof that
there is readability and comprehension
of your document and it's okay to say
that the end of this nobody's
implemented this yet but two people have
told me that they are they're really
planning to it is just dealing extra
information interestingly this status is
stripped from an RFC before publication
because it's reporting on on a snapshot
it's saying this is where we are in the
process the draft is here this is what's
been done when the RFC is published it's
archived forever and so this would get
out of date immediately so it's stripped
out you what else nits and gripes so
when I was in an area director I would
find that documents kept coming to me
with the same sort of thoughts and these
resulted from from a number of things
but most importantly the document hadn't
been reviewed widely enough so when
there's a adoption it needs to get
proper review in the right working group
and that maybe multiple working groups
increasingly we're finding drafts Span
working groups it's easy to get
attention you send a mail to multiple
mailing lists done
if you're doing writing a document about
a special subject that crosses areas get
the reviews and the examples that I've
given here yang security management
there are special review teams out there
to help get this right so you may be
living somewhere in the internet area
writing a young model there's nobody in
your working group who understands the N
that's fine go to the young doctors say
help I need I need help with this a
classic is the must may should etc etc
language it looks kind of trivial but
it's actually quite important to get it
tight because this is this is almost
legal language for the interpretation of
the implementer and that the classic is
if you write should when you receive
this packet you should do this you are
also implying that there is a may do
something else you could have write it
down otherwise people will just say oh
it's assured I don't have to do it if
it's an experiment if you've gone for an
experimental RFC then you have to
actually describe the experiment how
will I know if this experiment is a
success what are the parameters if it is
it in a closed garden is it in the
Internet at large and then lastly in my
pet knits and gripes is backwards and
forwards compatibility if you're
extending a protocol or you're writing a
a new protocol to replace something talk
about how that interacts with what's
already there if you're writing it any
protocol talk about how it can be
extended what are the future going to
look both directions and you can
explicitly rule as well you can say this
just does not work with bgp 3 but if you
don't say it people don't know it so
there's some resources here there's that
there's a checklist things to think
about make sure you've done several ADEs
have written their own checklists and
those live on the ITF wiki and there's a
tool my lovely little tool called idean
it's if you post a draft without running
it through ideal it's you're wasting
somebody's time so it's really easy to
do it's online you just going to click
done English it's really easy for me to
say right good English it's not too
difficult for Spencer as an American to
say right good English but it's I I
understand that getting English right is
pretty hard if if it's not your native
language and and frankly don't ask me to
write an ID in Swedish or Chinese
because I challenge so you know I know
I'm lucky here but you want people to be
able to read your draft you want it to
be in clear English and you want it to
be comprehensible really you want that
at the review stage the RFC editor team
will try to fix things as as they do the
properly edit they will ask questions
did you mean this when you said that but
there's a big risk okay
they can only guess what you mean and
they can ask you then is that what you
meant but you might not understand what
they're saying so there's a there's a
real danger that you introduce technical
errors right at this very last stage of
edit and some of that is because when
your copy editor says this word should
be that word you say Oh
I didn't understand that because I'm not
a native speaker so let's change it and
then you actually change the meaning so
use resources colleagues if you're
writing the draft you probably have a
colleague you can say to them could you
read this through and tell me if it's
clear they don't have to fix it they can
just tell you that there's something
wrong that allows you to keep those
issues private you can talk to other
people in the working group and there
are actually usually in working groups
quite a lot of people who are keen to
get involved they want to help so if you
say well I've got this draft I'd like
somebody to review it for me for English
then you'll get answers and then look at
the RFC editor pages for various working
workshop outputs and advice on writing
ideas and there's some links there and
lastly there's an online spell checker
for internet drafts it's not got a
perfect dictionary but it's pretty good
it catches most of my typing with errors
and why wouldn't you use that I did not
know that I'm learning something too
it's good I do spell and I think it's
another of Henrichs
wonderful tools excellent so I've got
just a few more slides before handing
over to Spencer diagrams okay it's your
writing text but do diagrams diagrams
really help make them simple diagrams
it's nice and easy to understand a clear
diagram modern artists is harder to
understand ask the art actually drawing
pictures in ASCII is not a natural thing
some people can just do it some people
can't don't worry if you find it hard
get somebody to help my key advice would
be
trying to use boxes squares are easy to
use doing ASCII circles are really hard
to do in ASCII and normally resulting in
a road crash the new rules coming to an
internet draft near you soon are
allowing SVG for figures and we have yet
to discover how well that will work but
that's going to allow you to do colors
and circles and familiar animations
no no animations right but I actually
like ASCII art and the reason I'd like
sv art is that if you find that you
cannot express your figure in 55 columns
so 55 rows and seventy two columns and
your figure is probably too complicated
break it up zoom zoom in and zoom out
and do little little figures because
once a picture is really complicated
your reader is probably going to
struggle if you want to see what that
future is going to look like with SVG
and so forth there's a FAQ on the RSC
editor web page which which tells you
all you need to know so I went and
looked at a random picture I might know
how this looks from the back of the room
yeah it looks as bad as it looks on my
laptop so this is this is a really good
example of you know what not to do there
are circles there are kind of where all
the lines made up of zeros or o's
so why why is that that's just not a
simple line and then there's some random
floating characters in there as well so
if when you've drawn it it doesn't look
good you know what it's not good but you
can do
as RFC 81 14 shows you you can do clever
things in ascii and they look fine
there's probably not a lot of need to do
uniforms except in the transport area
but said the formal routing area ad who
carried a unicorn in every ATF meeting I
saw him it they keep talking yeah mine
are real uniforms since it's just a
two-dimensional one right did you say
what you meant to say okay not just is
it clear but is it clearly what he meant
to say so a knowledgeable reviewer and a
friendly one willpower's confusing texts
sympathetically and if you wrote it
yourself you maybe don't even notice
it's confusing because it says what you
really you wrote it so you know what it
means try to think about it from the
perspective of a newcomer somebody who
doesn't know the topic very well and has
picked up your draft for the first time
will it be clear so sometimes the issues
are our emulation we've talked about
sometimes it's writing style short
sentences are good but writing a complex
short sentence is bad so my advice is
normally use more words but keep the
sentences short use bullet points but it
points really help and don't use the
passive voice or rather the passive
voice should not be used because it's a
specification you want to make it very
clear who does want when why and we've
also talked about our sc2 and 1/9
language so ask the reviews
ask for more reviews ask for more
reviews and then run it through the last
calls and get everybody to look at it
probably that list should
really highlight ask for reviews from
friends they don't even have to be
technically knowledgeable friends they
may be working in a different area of
the ATF but you met them over a beer and
you'd like some help asked for help and
I picked an abstract from a draft and
this is not to get at the person
concerned so I picked one from somebody
who works same company as me and you can
try to read this and pause it in your
own time but basically about halfway
through this abstract I when I first
read it I felt I'm drowning I have no
idea of what this is talking about it's
confusing and and it's garbled and why
would you put an abstract in a job the
abstract is the bit that people read ok
it's the hook why would you put that out
there unless it's clear yeah why have
you written this draft okay do try to
tell your readers what it's there for
don't just say oh here's an idea
sometimes it can be really hard to write
this down but but if you don't know it
then nobody else will know it
so state the problem you're solving
clearly in a few words with a picture
that's like key if you don't know what
problem you're solving then what are you
doing if you're not using and
pre-existing mechanism say so say why
you're not doing it not just I've got
something new and it works but I've got
something new and it worked and it
solves this deficiency be aware that a
problem statement is not the same as a
use case often sometimes and news places
with I think we see a lot at the moment
of drafts that try to list they've got a
wonderful new idea for a prototype and
then I just ten use cases and maybe nine
of them are just thrown stuff
the wall to see what sticks and one of
them is the golden if this is the
problem you want to solve this is a news
case and now I have a solution so try to
focus on what the real problem is not
just coming up with oh I could do this
and I should do that does it work well
this this this is actually quite key if
you're writing a protocol spec does it
work and usually getting that the golden
path through the code or the protocol is
pretty easy dealing that right we don't
engineer for edge cases basically
because edge cases are suboptimal we
engineer for the golden path but we have
to cover the edge cases if your protocol
does not cover the edge cases then
basically when people implement it it's
going to go strange when it's being
reviewed you'll often get people saying
I wouldn't have done it like this and
that's actually not really relevant
because what they should be looking at
is does it actually work if you're if
it's not really clear that your solution
works if you haven't actually documented
the protocol in in a clear way people
will jump on it and say oh I wouldn't
have done it like that the principle
objective and now we're back to why are
we doing this is to make interoperable
implementations so remove all ambiguity
remove options if you can help it
because options people the chance to
make non interoperable implementations
catch all of the error cases
all right when you post your first
version of a draft it does not need to
be complete it should have all that
boilerplate it should have placed
markers for staff but if you write a
full spec the first time you posted it
it is perfect then probably nobody's
going to review it and discuss it it's
kind of interested in psychology but you
want to hook the working group into
talking about your your document but by
the time you go to working group the
school and certainly by the time the
document is just taking a photo of
somebody with a red lanyard but by the
time you get to working with law school
the the document really needs to be
right
you must think it's complete as
independent submissions editor I've just
picked up a document that which has got
a publication request and it's got three
sections in it that say TBD okay that's
not ready for publication you unreeling
right
gosh look at the time so this is the
part of the adrian i asked me to help
with and so i'm talking about the stream
specific staff IETF stream is what a lot
of us do but it's not everything that we
do in that stream we publish and this is
the only omission that I know in the
material that I have four kinds of our
essays of standards track TCP
experimental and informational RFC's
there's some guidance about where you
kind of want to target that but this is
you know figuring out what the right
answer is is still a minor art to take
your best shot and you know the area
director or even the Ihde
may ask ask questions about that but as
they start out and what looks like the
right place to you we usually publish
dress produced by working groups ABS can
sponsored rafts but why not from working
group in working groups have a lot of
flexibility but publication requested
sets off a list of machinery next slide
please
the machinery looks like this there's a
formal state machine for publication
I've got that there the reason you care
is because state transitions are going
to generate email that you will see as
an author or as a shepherd or as working
group chair and I had those listed there
so the ad looks at it and says here's
what you know here's what I see the
expert reviews from the Directorate get
set off at at last call time and get set
off foretell a chance the last call that
you get comments that you get from the
community as a whole become as that you
get from other area directors during isg
evaluation the state going to approve
this is you know you you may think that
your finish take a deep breath you're
not and then things that are in the RFC
atatürk you watch her eat questions from
the editors resolving comments and this
this is I think I hope this is valuable
for people you may see feedback from
your ad during ad evaluation you may see
feedback from the broader ITF community
during last call you may see feedback
from or with my next one area review
teams during last call and even just
before a tell a chat and from other AEDs
during IHG evaluation your best strategy
is to reply to emails with comments to
you know to basically say yes i this is
what i think you're telling me and this
is what i think the response for that
should be you don't have to make changes
to accommodate every comment even from
an area director so please do the right
thing and talk to your document shepherd
about when to submit update
dress that's hard to give general
guidance for one of the things is you
know should you know I got I got review
comments should I submit an updated
draft and the area director can you know
your area director can look and say well
actually no one else has Balan right
this would be a great time to do that
because none of the area directors have
you know I mean they're gonna they need
to see the new staff that you may change
us to you know because that's more
that's more correct than the stuff that
either publication requested on recently
this is also I think really important to
say recent is jeez have taken comments
in no objection positions as seriously
as they have taken comments in discuss
positions that's a good thing because
that means that you're not getting
discusses on things that the area
director think matters but doesn't trust
the authors or the working group or the
other area director to address the
comment okay we probably about a year in
and after I joined the isg we really
kind of we've really kind of changed on
that and it's been it's been that way
for several years where you know say we
don't you know we're not going to I know
you could put it in a comment for a no
checks in position that says you know
this is not a discussed but it's pretty
yeah it is pretty worrying to me you
know please take it seriously so you may
see comments like that those are not
blocking positions but somebody who is
like you and is trying to help is trying
to tell you something they may be they
may be wrong and they may not understand
what's going on especially if they're in
another area but they're really trying
to help so please please help them help
you next slide please discuss Bell it's
not that anyone would ever see one of
these at the IETF please
a statement please remember that a
discus is not a demand from the isg for
a change to your document it is
literally we should talk
the current describes criteria and non
criteria are at this link feel free to
take a look at them the common things
that I see in discuss ballast on you
know the last three or four is Jesus I
would say the number one that I do is I
can't understand what's going on here so
please keep non-experts in mind when you
write the people who implement this the
stuff that you're doing may not be in
the working group so making sure that
people who haven't been involved in this
protocol since somebody thought it up
can implement it actually turns out to
be a really useful thing for somebody to
wonder about this one a lot this reveals
personal identifiable information
so keep BCP whoever's that one 38 in
mind when you write the most recent
surprise that people have had it was the
realization slowly and painfully at
discuss Bell at time basically saying
you know you don't think of IP addresses
as personal identifiable personal
identifying information but a lot of IP
addresses and ipv6 prefixes are only
used by one person so when somebody does
something from that IP address or even
from that prefix they're kind of telling
you something you know and you might you
know maybe you want maybe you want to
tell people something you know in your
protocol about that but don't let that
be a surprise to you when somebody asks
about it you know we can we can do a lot
we can do a lot more if people have
thought about it and have thought
through the consequences then we can do
if you say I don't understand why this
is personal identifying information
that's like the beginning of a
conversation this
can't this isn't safe on the open
Internet because of congestion or
because of security or because of
scaling or you know whatever whatever
reason something that has happened and
it happened about a year in after I
joined the is G so 2014 was that we
started I'm a transport guy right so I'm
here from the transport area and I'm
here to help you you guys really have to
laugh at some of these statements
because they're intended to be curious
but to say you know we were we were we
were doing we were doing a lot of stuff
I think encapsulations on UDP so no
congestion mechanism there and it was
not you know some of the some of the
things that were being encapsulated it
had better congestion you know control
mechanisms than others okay so Adrian
and some other folk David why I want to
call out David black and there were some
other folks I spend a lot of time trying
to figure out how to do this well we've
ended up with is saying that if you are
doing something that is useful on the
open Internet but may not be safe on the
open Internet please explain to us what
the considerations are to run it on the
open Internet and then explain to us
which of those considerations you can
not worry about so much if you're on a
managed closed Network and we you know
and I think basically all of the reason
encapsulation drafts have have done
something like that so like I said you
know it's like tell us what you know
tell us the truth you know but you know
think about this stuff up front and you
know you'll get a lot more no objections
and yet you know I even been yes I mean
some of the stuff why is this should not
a must this is very much in the way this
is very much in the vein of what Adrian
was saying about
if it's if it's a shirt then that means
somebody may not do it and if somebody
doesn't do it what what was supposed to
happen and we we we asked that question
fairly frequently and there's a real
range of answers that we get back one is
that there are certain you know there is
a reason that you would not do this
awesome please put that in it you know
please put that in you know it shouldn't
less if you say there are two or three
reasons why you would do this please
give an example and explain what's
supposed to happen if it doesn't you
know if it doesn't happen if you say
well you know there's these legacy
implementations that don't do this and
we want them to be conforming with a
standard you're like that's all of them
so like I said just be thinking about
that up front yeah was my last one yeah
also need to describe what happens when
something happens that shouldn't next
slide please
the IRT F stream I'm also in the IR s G
so I see these also they publish RFC's
in their own stream and the process for
doing that is given in that link
RTF specific requirements for content in
these drafts please note that you know
there's things like saying this is you
know this is the this is the output of a
research group in research if you don't
know much about the RDF research groups
don't have to have consensus that this
is the right thing to do they only have
to have consensus to that publishing
this is valuable so what level of
consensus did the research group have
that like I said that's on the checklist
okay so you know be aware of that if
you're going to be doing something in
the IOT of stream the drafts are usually
the product of the research group I've
written actually I've been on that I've
been on the IR s G for probably five
years you know seven years and I've
written I wrote the only one that
didn't come through a research group
that I've seen go through the IRS G so
you don't have to go through a research
group depending on what you're doing I
was writing a draft saying here's how to
here's here's what I etf people should
know about the IRT F so it didn't come
through a research group and that you
know large published that but this stuff
will usually come through a research
group they are not standards track they
are experimental or informational there
is no last call outside the research
group before publication this is very
much in the you know let it live a
hundred flowers bloom view of what
research groups do the recent the IRS G
provides review and guidance for these
finish drafts and it's explained in the
publication process of the link the is G
does what is called a RFC 57:42 review
for conflicts with IETF standards
process but there's not a point of IOT F
stream drafts if you crack open RC 57:42
it basically says these are the five
things that the isg can say back to the
iot of string you know IRT of stream
controller and you know one of them is
we don't have any objection to this one
of them you know one of them is this is
related to work in this working group
but but that shouldn't block publication
and then you know then you're like read
down to number five or something like
that which is basically this is
extending a ITF protocol in ways that
should go through the IETF process so
that's all that's literally all that
you're supposed to get back from the is
is G if you're publishing the IOT of
string the next slide the IAB also
publishes in its own string and this is
described in RFC 4845 these are often
produced by entities that the IAB
overseas like IB programs I've actually
I've got a draft in the in the IAB stack
evolution program that's supposed to go
out for community comment like next week
or something
published by the RFC editor which the
IRB over has oversight responsibility
for published by the Ayana
which is the same thing workshop reports
that's for workshops that the IEP has
done I've actually go yeah that's that's
one of those so and these are not
standard struck either they are usually
informational and you'll you can publish
in the experimental drafts there that's
not common but it but it's possible the
process is that you will be working
closely with at least one IB member the
whole IB will review your work the IB
will issue a ITF wide call for comments
but this is not an ITF last call they
are not bound to seek consensus or
resolve comments the I you know this is
one of the beauties of the IEP is the
IEP can do the right thing even if
they're the only people in the room that
think it's that it's the right thing
that's why I think that's why they don't
publish on the standards track the IAB
the iesg you can say those guys are
right and they can write a BCP that says
those guys are right and you should read
that and we're going to act like those
guys are right that you know so that's
the linkage there basically the IES G
does not perform RFC 57:42
conflict review for the IEP string in
the independent stream yeah so the
independent streams publishes our C's
but they are not IETF RFC s okay be very
clear you can come to the independent
stream and get an RFC and you can
pretend to be an intern I ATF RFC but
it's not the process is in 4846
and what's going on we're publishing
documents
that are rooted in the IETF standards
process with following that paradigm but
we're only producing information or
experimental RFC's it's not intended to
publish Lots and my first pushback is
always why can't this be an IETF RFC but
if there's some Internet related
technologies that are not on the ITF
agenda and not going to be on the ITF
agenda if there's a discussion of
options or experiences if there's a
vendor specific protocol that needs to
be documented so that other people can
produce implementations interoperate if
there's a discussion of ITF processes or
protocols then those are all in scope
and this last one is quite important and
I think it's why the independent stream
exists there is a need for a safety
valve so that if you feel that your idea
has been blocked by some part of the
IETF process may be an area director has
sat on it and stopped it coming out
there's a way out of that to come to the
independent submissions editor the
editor sends stuff out to volunteers a
full review and has an editorial board
to help those reviews are not mandatory
they're not part of the consensus
process but they're they form a
discussion and you might look at this in
the same way as a journal paper would
get reviews and you would discuss with
the journal editor these documents go to
the ASG for a 57:42 review the principal
purpose is that it's not an end run on
an ATF process or protocols and the IES
you can say please
adesh or please wait the IOC has full
control and can say yes or no
the IOC does one other thing and which
is once a year gets to publish April
first RFC's there there has been some
interesting conflict in their community
about April first RFC's because some
folks say but there are RFC's we must
take them seriously well my advice to
them is don't take any RFC seriously but
you know look at the date as well I get
to summarize okay
make your draft clear and meaningful
that's the most important thing so write
carefully you want it to move quickly
and smoothly forward so do all the right
things early for the process and and for
the cookbook you personally you're
writing the draft you are responsible
for making that high quality so that
means fix the problems early ask for
help early don't leave it right up to
the editorial on stage saying oh yeah
they'll sort it out do not rely on the
is GM your RFC editor to catch and fix
your problems because that way is a good
way to meet those problems persist to
introduce new problems to delay your
work and make everybody unhappy with you
so we have a very brief moment for any
questions sorry I even have 300 pages
there few questions can you hand over
authorship to somebody else within the
working group yeah so authorships
fun you can hand your own draft before
it's a working group
over to anyone when it's a working group
draft technically the working group
chairs appoint the editors so if you
were going to make that change basically
stepping back from it and giving it to
somebody else just talk to the working
group chairs first and say look this is
happening for this reason is that okay
and is usually that's fine okay next
question is what drafts are very often
quite dry drafts in my humble opinion
should be accompanied by training
material to accompany a draft so that it
becomes understandable for everybody
like something like a youtube animation
and what is the standard and feeling
around that type of training material so
we are not against people understanding
the documents that we produce anybody
want to question it but what we've been
doing for a recent I well
recent probably seven or eight years is
we've started doing technical
presentations these tutorials on Sunday
afternoon including a technical material
they're like you know here's here's this
here's the deal about yang so we've had
you know so we've had one of those that
right now that is probably the most
common way that we do something like
training for our material number one
number two it is fine for people to
write users guides and things like that
you know if it's useful to produce that
in a working group that would be fine if
it's not useful to produce that in
working group but you understand how
something works and I'm not talking you
the person who's trying to understand it
I'm talking about you the person who
already understands it you know the
this is I'm writing a check for you here
this is a fine thing for the independent
stream edit to publish and say this is
this person's best understanding of how
this works and what your ways you should
use it and what the benefits are things
like that that should be fine and you
know that would be that would be a
pretty would be a pretty easy 57:42
conflict review which is we would have
no objection and we would actually be
thrilled if somebody made the protocols
easier to implement and easier to deploy
and easier to operate I think there are
the term of things working groups often
produce applicability statements this is
how you use this protocol of a set of
protocols to achieve a particular
function in the network but they're
still dry as we documents but they're
helping to explain the use case the
other thing is there is nothing to
prevent an informational pointer
reference to education or material about
a protocol or a use case that lives
outside the ATF the only thing I would
say about that is try to make it a
stable persistent URL so that when the
things in RFC in five years time people
will still be able to look at that
informational material if I could also
just mention so there's this plenary on
Wednesday night this would be a great
thing to see us the is G at that plenary
and say you know is this the best we can
do there would be a fine thing for the
new iesg to hear thank you and my last
question is what is if RFC's are not
come to maturity fast enough according
to the work group in a work group chair
and what is the process of dropping
RFC's
deeming something that has already been
published as an RFC and now heart of the
ITF of the whole IGF wants to move on
and say that's no no no before it is in
working group status nah Roxy but after
a an amount of discussion there is a
consensus that this work will never come
to maturity so you can let you can
simply let it expire and forget about it
every six months an internet draft is
technically dead my advice however is to
repost the draft replacing the text with
a statement we've given up on this for
these reasons so that the last thing
that was ever posted as a draft with
that name is a tombstone very clear
thank you yeah there's actually a dead
state in the data tracker for a draft
that is you know we almost made it over
the wall but it was not it was not ready
in time or it was it not as good an idea
as we thought it was and so if you tell
if you notate the working group chair
tells the area director that the area
director can mark it that way and and
you know everybody everyone will know
and I think that's one of your part of
your question is how would anybody know
hi there Stephen bang Hart there's been
some talk recently about spinning
privacy consideration off into a
separate section rather than just having
it in security considerations any
thoughts on that
I only personally don't see much of a
difference between section 6 and section
5.1 the important thing is to cover the
material if putting it in a separate
major section forces people to remember
it then whatever thank you there are
some considerations and maybe this is a
good thing for us to think about war
the first time we've done this tutorial
so one thing introduced one thing one
thing for us to mention maybe as well as
we're talking about debriefing is to say
basically why are some things the way
they are and so one of the things with
the structure of the internet drafts and
what we're expecting to see is that if
you know and I seen I've seen it working
I've seen a working group draft with
acknowledgement section and then like a
description of the experiment you know
and my I got that as the area director
and my guidance back was everybody stops
reading when they get to the Ayana
considerations they think they're
through if you you know if you want
anybody to read this I would move it
above about that there's there's no rule
about that but don't you know that's
kind of the way the community thinks
about things and and you're you're kind
of fitting into the way the community
thinks about things so that people will
understand you know well know what
they're looking at Thanks so I'm getting
the sense that people are leaving a room
but there are still questions so we
ought to finish but please come and ask
your question to us afterwards and as
one other thing the edgy team asks could
you please fill in the survey is about
the the tutorials so that they can help
plan but we're here all week so close we
are here all week please tip your
waitress and thank you all
[Applause]