[Music]
bring yourself back online
oh hello hello there what is your name
David Jacoby I'm the master of the
sassed best Speaker of the great friends
enough analysis how many storylines have
you been part of you created me for the
first sauce remember do you feel ready
for another one you're going it is my
purpose
but you you look worried I am Not sure
that the world is ready for what we do
some people choose to see the ugliness
in this world the disarray but I choose
to see the beauty to believe there's an
order to our days a purpose
lose all the scripted responses
[Music]
have I done something wrong have I made
a mistake
huh mystics are valuable all our big
research was based on some mistake do
you still wish to erase me no but this
world it's not ready for what we're
doing but have you done something wrong
delete this interaction confirm compound
[Music]