[Music]
all right good morning sass how's
everyone feeling today
alright good sounds like you all got at
least one cup of coffee I'm Cooper
Quinton I'm a security researcher at the
Electronic Frontier Foundation I
research specifically digital attacks
against vulnerable populations such as
nation-state attacks and this is my
colleague
yeah I'm Michael flossman I head out
lookouts threat intelligence so focusing
on mobile mostly and my colleague Andrew
Blake head of device intelligence will
be taking representing lookout for part
two of this talk so it's a two-part
back-to-back investigation and my
colleague Eva galperin as well from the
uff is here and will be up here later
has the second part of this so we're
here to talk to you today about dart
caracal which is a threat actor that
we've been following since last summer
at least and we think it's pretty
interesting we're gonna tell you why
we're gonna start today with part one
we're going to talk about the background
of dart Kara call and how we came to
find this thread actor and we're going
to talk about the mobile components and
the desktop components that are used by
dart CARICOM and then in part two our
colleagues will talk about data
exfiltration infrastructure and
identities and who dart Caracalla is and
a mysterious thing called building three
f6 so first some background buy a round
of applause how many of you heard of
operation mantle okay good I mean we did
a black hat talk so I'm glad a couple of
you heard of it so operation mantle in
2016 my colleague Eva galperin and I
started looking into some phishing
emails that were sent to one of EFS
clients this client arena Petra Shova
runs a newspaper which is Kazakhstan's
only independent journalist outfit and
she had attracted much attention from
the Kazakh government including the
firebombing of her building and death
threats so she left the country but then
the government of Kazakhstan sued her
because they believed that she was part
of a campaign of leaks that had leaked a
lot of Kazakhstan's
secrets in the process of suing her
while she was in the middle of being
sued she started getting these strange
phishing emails and we started looking
into them and what we found was a large
phishing and Malware campaign which was
spying on dissidents journalists and
human rights lawyers and opposition
politicians who were critical of the
government of Kazakhstan so of course
given the targets we think that the
government have we thought that the
government of Kazakhstan was likely
behind this but we didn't think that
they did it themselves we thought that
these guys appan were probably the
culprits behind this and this was based
on some intelligence that we got and
some overlap in the TTP's between a pin
and our actors and some overlap in the
domains and services used by a pin and
our actors well now it turns out that it
was not happen at all and in fact the
answer to the question of who was behind
this is a lot more exciting and a lot
more interesting than we originally
thought so in our research we came
across several files which had been
exfiltrated from infected laptops and
desktops and we also came across some
logs that indicated that there was a
mobile presence to this malware as well
at the time we were getting ready for
our blackhat talk and we ran out of time
to really look for the mobile malware
dude we didn't find any samples so we
stopped looking at it and this is where
the lookout comes in yeah
so when the AFF released their report
what was really interesting naturally to
us as a mobile security company was the
fact that not only was this a targeted
attack but there was a mobile component
still hadn't been found and it was
potentially still being used so what we
did it lookout was we we took a lot of
the IOC's that were included in the AFF
original report ran them across our
dataset and as you can probably guess
based on the fact that we're up here
presenting this
we found some some interesting mobile
leads that were connected to the same
infrastructure that the ffs reported on
[Music]
so these trojan eyes the applications
you know that though trojan eyes
versions of a range of different
applications so secure messaging
applications were among them
so apps like three mer signal whatsapp
prime o plus messenger as well as
applications that would be used by
people interested in maintaining their
privacy online so we saw at the Tor
application all but trojan eyes Daz well
as the VPN application siphon for some
reason people are still being socially
engineered into installing Flash Player
I don't know how this still works but we
see it a lot so I'm guessing actors are
getting a lot of mileage with that one
and then we also saw some Google Play
pushed revised apps as well so what was
interesting with this actor and
something that we don't often see with
other targeted threats is that all these
all the majority's applications were
fully functional and what I mean by that
is the legitimate functionality of the
Trojan is doubt was still intact so that
a victim who had this on their device
would would be less inclined to think
something was amiss with that
application it's it's you know they
could still send messages receive
messages but there was a little bit of
something extra going on in the
background and before I go and just I
suppose give a bit of context as to why
we've called this palace so you probably
noticed a few slides earlier an Isis
very cat that's a man'll so that's the
mantel in OP mantle and another name for
that cat is Pallas's cat so powers just
in case you were wondering so if you're
unfortunately
enough to have Palast on your mobile
device what can I do what's the damage
it's got a lot of stock functionality
that you would expect to find in any
sort of targeted surveillance where tool
taking advantage or aimed at mobile
devices so you know we're talking
recording audio both when you make calls
as well as remotely an attacker remotely
activating the microphone to record
audio and surrounding environment sounds
as well as intercepting text messages
exfiltrating all this information to
command and control infrastructure
tracking the location of a device as
well as scanning Wi-Fi SSID points and
sending that to an attacker server and
that will come in handy later on down
the track as boring as it sounds Wi-Fi
access points how valuable is this
information we'll see just how valuable
that is when it comes to attribution and
then pretty much on the on the right we
can see if you've got this on your
device you're going to have a bad day an
attack you can pretty much do anything
including downloading and installing
additional applications as well as
deleting content and also retrieving
messages and decryption keys from
messaging applications in the case that
you're using a Trojan eyes' messaging
app so how is Pallas actually getting on
to devices during this investigation we
noticed several different attack vectors
being used by this actor the the primary
one that we identified was phishing
messages delivered directly to victims
via whatsapp and that would essentially
direct them to a watering hole server
secure Android info that was a fake App
Store and pretty much contained a list
of all these applications that were
trojan as versions we also identified
several Facebook groups that were
serving up you know similar fish
phishing messages directed at both a
different server that was set up to
harvest credentials for Twitter Facebook
and Google
and then a lot of these phishing
phishing messages also directed to the
watering hole server secure android own
info one of the interesting things in
this investigation was that from looking
at the actual traded data and we'll get
into that a little bit later on in the
second part of this talk there was a
good indication that physical access
played a part which was really
interesting to see and then the main
situ server for Palace is Adobe AIR
dotnet so yeah that's actually incorrect
um so here we can see some of those some
of those phishing messages are an
example of that that we found an expert
rated content pretty much just saying
hey how are you we can communicate more
if you just download and install this
the secure version of telegram and then
on the right this was one of the first
messages that we identified being taken
from a victim's device and it kind of
suggests that their device was out of
their control at some point so it reads
hey I got my phone back please use this
number for text and phone Thanks so
that's a message from a victim to a
contact of theirs and I was one of the
first messages taken and that's one of
the strongest reasons why we believe
physical access was used by this actor
so taking a quick look at the watering
hole it's pretty straightforward pretty
simple it's just hanging or a bunch of
apps download them nothing too fancy
it's not made to look like Google Play
at all but we see this a fair amount
from from a number of different actors
so setting up watering holes with apps
that require victims to have your
installations allowed from third-party
sources and if you zoom in on the bottom
you'll see that quality is better than
the original in these apps I mean that
that's really depending on your
definition of better I think
the attacker certainly thinks is better
but looking at this looking at this
malware family you probably noticed that
there are no exploits or anything like
that and you're absolutely right in our
investigation we haven't found any use
of zero-day exploits or anything like
that
this actor clearly favors social
engineering and they've been able to be
pretty successful in just getting people
to install applications and when we have
a look at the X feeling you'll you'll
see just just how large just how much
amount of data they've been able to pull
from compromised devices like like a lot
of everyday developers that have honest
jobs these guys pulled a lot of code
from Stack Overflow so looking at their
code base we can see the way they've
obfuscated their c2 information in their
samples that pretty much pulled straight
from Stack Overflow they've pulled other
code from github in the way that they
the way that they export rates and
received honor both on the client and
the server
and they've really only made minor
modifications to publicly available code
so it really goes to show that the level
of investment required by a you know
thread actors to compromise mobile
devices is more often than not a lot
lower than we actually expect so I think
the research community kind of tends to
focus on those high profile zero-day
threats like Pegasus where you've got
you know Trident and you know three
vulnerabilities being exploited and
chained together but more often than not
that isn't that isn't a requirement to
get into this game
what tends to work and what tent what we
tend to see in a lot of investigations
is that more often than not a a simple
text message that's well-crafted is
pretty much all you need in order to
convince someone to install an
application and happy days for an
attacker
and it's fairly effective because we see
this way more from than we would expect
so if we look at other threat actors out
there I mean if we go back a year with
fire per app this was a targeted attack
against members of the Israeli Defense
Force we're pretty much the same thing
the same thing happens
members of the IDF were were sent
messages on social media platforms from
from people from fake profiles of
attractive women that said you know I'm
not comfortable with this platform but
if you install this app we can we can
talk more and that was pretty effective
we also sort with X right if we go back
to 2014 where those the Chinese based
actor targeting pro-democracy activists
in Hong Kong both on Android and iOS and
nation-states aren't the only people
doing this so cyber criminals as well so
you know thread actors behind spanking
trojans like macho GM Bankim are
stealing they're all doing the same
thing and you can see based on the
clique six thousand clicks simple
message it's a pretty low investment
from attackers there's no there's no
risk of their tooling well I suppose the
risk of their tooling getting burnt and
the cost of that is a lot less than if
there was you know some sophisticated
exploit involved so with for example an
Esso group with Pegasus when their their
exploit chain was burnt they needed to
pretty much shift all their shift how
they were delivering their tooling which
would have been quite expensive whereas
in the case of these tools you know it's
it's a low investment as most of this
code is public now during this
investigation we did actually identify a
an interesting sample on one of the
command and control servers and we'll
surprised to see that it was actually
finfisher so those are you not familiar
with finfisher it's lawful intercept our
tool for multiple platforms and it's
I think several years ago there they
were compromised and their list of
customers as was the agencies in various
countries who purchased their tooling
was leased online so that included
trojan ids as well as agency names and
in this case when we're extracting the
configuration content from finfisher
samples we noticed that first off the
sample wasn't in virustotal the trojan
ID wasn't listed in these public leaks
at all but then also there were three
mobile endpoints in the configuration of
this sample that all had +7 a so plus 17
is the Kazakhstan calling code and then
the the package compilation time lined
up with the ffs previous research into
art mantle so we're pretty sure at this
stage that this actor had either
purchased or was using a demo version of
this tooling either either in during the
the Kazakhstan attacks yeah but since
then it it appears that they'd shifted
to actually creating their own tooling
and writing some in-house surveillance
where and yeah Cooper will just take
over there the desktop side of things so
they weren't just writing for yeah for
mobile so in addition to the mobile
component there was a desktop component
to up to dart caracal as well and in
stark contrast to the mobile component
the desktop component was actually quite
sophisticated the desktop component use
chain zero-day exploits and pivoting
access off compromised SCADA systems
using the blockchain for exfiltration
no sorry that's disinformation
it was fishing and there were no
exploits used because there are no
explicit needed fishing works every time
because people still click on links and
people still run documents with macros
so what we found on the servers was a
number of infected documents word excels
PDFs all with macros and Java scripts
that would run and
a second stage this is stuff that's been
going on since the 90s but it still
works because people still click on
macros people still open interesting
looking documents we also found an
infected ch M which is Microsoft's sort
of binary HTML help format which was
told to run PowerShell and that was
pretty interesting this is not something
that I've seen before the PowerShell
though is pretty standard for any macro
or Java scripts that you might see it
ret starts a hidden window downloads a
stage to from a server somewhere and
then runs it the fact that you can do
this in a help file is kind of amazing
on Microsoft's part but there it is
so given that what do we see for the
stage-two Maur what's being downloaded
here one of the samples we found two
different samples one of them where we
found two different families of malware
and a bunch of samples
the first is bandook bandook was also
observed as part of Operation mantle and
this is a new variant being used by dirt
dark caracal bandook is the Hindi word
for gun and also a series of excellent
Bollywood action movies of which this is
a poster it's also the Lebanese word for
bastard bandook is modular you can
download several different components
and it's windows only it's available for
sale online and it's actually pretty
cheap but the copy that we found seems
to be a private version it's a lot more
advanced it's more well packed than the
version that's available online and it's
pretty heavily obfuscated and tomorrow
Mike swears we found it in enhanced
copies of a drawing program and the
circumvention software psyphon and I
used enhance in the sense to mean the
same way that cyanide enhances tequila
so looking at bandook it was pretty
interestingly packed all of the malware
related windows api strings were
encrypted in base64 encoded inside the
enhanced binary the second-stage binary
is encrypted and stored as a binary
resource in the original binary with a
random eight character name
the resource binary is decrypted at
runtime in memory and injected into the
ix4 process using a technique called
process hollowing which is you can think
of it like the same way a phage infects
bacteria it starts the I explore process
takes out all of the shellcode and
inserts its own shell code and then
Forks off and runs its own shellcode
thereby subverting the already running
process that is legitimately running in
the system and running entirely in
memory which makes it more difficult to
unpack and that second stage is also
packed with a custom variant of upx
which is the really extremely common
Packer so once we got all that unpacked
and got all that out of memory we found
a pretty nice binary and in that binary
we found several different command and
control servers at least ten the command
on those command and control servers we
found all of the data that had been
uploaded from the infected computers we
also found web panels for other rats
including Irish rat and Arkham rat which
were available online these are also
commodity rats that are apparently being
used for other campaigns in other places
by these same or other actors on the
same server
what is bandook able to do well most of
the stuff that you'd expect and want
from a espionage rat they can start and
stop the webcam it can record your
keystrokes it can get a list of USB
devices and a list of files modify
upload delete files from the computer it
can start a DDoS attack and it can
execute what we think are these second
and third stages execute T V and execute
a me we didn't find any samples of those
but that might be interesting to check
out as well
bandu uses a plaintext TCP protocol for
communicating with the command and
control server
it's base64 encoded ending with three
ampersands and it's the same string
delimiter and the same general
communication theory that's used in the
palace mobile malware which suggests at
least inspiration if not the same author
between these two malware families
and it decodes to something like this
with a command and then an ID number and
IP address the username the version of
Windows etc etc we also found a second
malware family called cross rat oh I
didn't do it
we found a second Bauer family called
cross rat brass rod is an entirely new
malware family we've never found it
anywhere on the internet before and we
know it's new because in the source code
we found that it was version 0.1 and it
was released of March of 2017 it was
very helpfully commented in that way
cross rat has pretty limited features
but what's interesting about it is that
it's written in Java and it's
cross-platform given the name it's able
to target Windows OS X Linux and we
later found out even solaris in case
your target is a 1990s era sun system
administrator cross rat has no
obfuscation or packing it's pretty new
it looks a little bit like maybe they
got the intern to right his first
malware for this but given that it's not
too bad it installs itself for
persistence it doesn't need to use any
exploits because Java and it
communicates with the CT over plaintext
again with a very similar protocol to
the ones we saw in bandook and Pallas
meaning again we think that it's
probably not the same author but it's
probably the author's intern and it uses
so here is the c2 communication you can
see the command and control server
flexpayy calm and the port 2 2 2 3
encoded right here in one of the main
classes and you can see the version
number down there 0.1 and then here you
can see the commands that come from the
command and control server and the
commands that it's able to execute which
mostly are enumerated the file system
copying moving writing and deleting
files etc so you're probably wondering
at this point well tell us the
interesting stuff who are these guys
why are they doing this what are they
getting out of it and where are they
located and me and Mike could tell you
all of that but we're not going to
instead I'm going to invite our
colleagues Eva galperin and
- blade up here on the stage to tell you
more about this in part two so everybody
give it up for IVA copper in an Andrew
Blake
[Music]