[Music]
I my name is Kurt I'm a principal
security researcher with Kaspersky as
global research and analysis team I'm
I've been with the team since 2010 and
I'm here to talk about apt 28 we call
them sofa see my angle on or my talk
will be about more recent activity I
want to focus on what they've been doing
in 2018 there have been some definitive
changes Mike just talked quite a bit
about their credential harvesting I
don't really talk about that in this
presentation I talk more about what has
been going on with their more
traditional malware set in particular
SPLM and how it's being replaced into
2018 and what's sort of interesting
targeting changes they've been having so
yeah that's lovely Masha so I I want to
describe it in terms of really apt
culture
what's going on with apt 28 in
particular this group is arguably not
always reckless not always destructive
they can be measured they can be agile
and now into 2018 we expect more changes
from the group they are becoming more
and more agile and innovative as time
goes on
they're targeting and there's some
interesting crossover going on this year
the ex-agent code is disappearing that
C++ code base is being replaced and then
again I'll go over some crypto and some
code comparisons so in addition to the
code we also see the infrastructure
itself changing so whereas the the
operators deploying XP or SPLM or the X
agent code has traditionally used
infrastructure that's domain centric
they use Bitcoin to set up at
registrar's that where they can maintain
their anonymity and that's slowly
changing and we're seeing more zebra
Cicco
zebra see what we call a zebra see
infrastructure which is really a subset
of the sofa see group they're using IP
addresses they're not using domains they
don't have to hide behind anonymity or
privacy services and they don't have to
pay in Bitcoin for those we also see
quite a bit of changing code and I will
go over that as well
so in my mind since I'm a little bit
SPLM focused or ex-agent focused I look
at different milestones in the code I
see delivered from this group from 2004
to 2009 it's interesting that they
maintain essentially the same code base
they keep delivering the same stuff for
years we see that in 2009 to 2015 and
then finally we start seeing changes
much more quickly to what they're
delivering and what they're replacing in
their code base over time and in 2018
SPLM has pretty much fallen off the map
except for one victim in particular so
at the beginning of 2017 we saw the the
common stuff that we always see from
surfacey they're targeting targeting
NATO their target targeting may be
tangential partners related to the to
the Ukraine but it's all very Western
focused and that's what you hear a lot
about in the media they're they're DNC
hack their Ukrainian focus their focus
on NATO and elections in the EU but we
see a different story
we see quite a bit of activity in
Central Asia and in 2018 now we see
movement completely further east so not
just the stands but we see them
throughout Mongolia Japan and China in
particular and while that is interesting
and trending and targeting profiles and
regions is interesting and I will say it
doesn't discount the fact that they will
continue to target organizations in the
US and Europe it's just from what we're
seeing there pretty intensely focused
there their focus is moving further east
in Asia so before I move on from the Far
East and they're targeting the Far East
really I'd like to talk about gray
Lambert and in well Koston mentioned
that for several years we had been
working to identify more Lambert
components this is a very high-level
sophisticated actor it's up there with
equation Dooku in terms of
sophistication and technical
capabilities coordination and who
they're hitting and Greene Lambert was
one of their passive sniffers so they'll
get on a server they have often they'll
replace white Lambert a kernel-mode
passive sniffer with grey Lambert
user-mode passive sniffer and it's a no
bus implant meaning it's nobody but us
can get on the server so you have to
send magic numbers or magic values in
your network stream to sort of enable
the capabilities of this implant and it
I mean this is a really complex graphic
but basically it fits in the Lambert
family's pretty comfortably it shares
some victims and some coding and it's
our 2016-2017 implant it's it's so I was
just mentioning it's a passive sniffer
it's functionally comparable to a very
advanced see door back door and it was
deployed very selectively in China and
Iran and here's just a few of the
commands that we were able to identify
within the components that we saw but
again it's very selective it's not a
huge back door it's not very large and
the interesting thing is we had found it
on a particular server in China which
takes me back to sofa C so in this sort
of pivot to Asia in 2018 now
see sofa see targeting targeting Chinese
organizations and in particular the
exact same server that they that great
Lambert had hit previously so this is an
aerospace and defense conglomerate it's
huge the the sofa see components that
were deployed to the system after we had
cleaned up gray Lambert are interesting
not because they're fairly different
from what we've previously seen
so throughout 2017 we had seen SPLM code
or this chopstick backdoor as a large
300 kilobyte backdoor it was full feet
fully featured it came usually with a
keylogger
remote shell and file of stealing
capabilities all the what they call
Colonel communications channels and it
was a fully featured backdoor well along
comes 2018 and everything's changed
those back doors are not showing up
anywhere except on the server there are
the modules not the backdoor but there
are the smaller modules that show up and
they're showing up as a remote shell in
memory and again this is shortly after
we had cleaned up grey Lambert and
kicked them off of the system so that
left us with some questions and really
all we can do is speculate about how
they're getting on these servers and
again this is interesting because
server-side exploitation is not
necessarily what they're doing in high
volume usually they're known for
spearfishing Mike Mike show to all the
all the credential harvesting they do on
the side as their spearfishing targets
but you don't see large numbers of
servers being exploited by these guys so
that leaves us with this speculation at
least some considerations one this is a
false flag planted there by the
Lambert's in order to create some
confusion to the Lambert's are actually
using the remote shell capabilities
of sofa C code that they've stolen that
kind of unlikely but possible three the
the sofa C guys had witnessed other and
recorded Network sessions with Lambert
implants elsewhere in the world and then
they're simply replaying those sessions
with the magic numbers in order to
deliver sofa C components to a server so
essentially they're exploiting Lambert
implants on this server in China or
finally and what is most likely going on
the sofa C guys are simply exploiting
the same vulnerable web app server
that's that's running on this host but
those are all interesting so that's
probably the the the Chinese server
itself is probably the newest and most
interesting because of that target
crossover and because it's a completely
new region that they're targeting one
thing that I mentioned is that SPLM
itself is not being delivered as you
know this fully featured backdoor it's
based on that what's known as the X
agent source code that's what the
developer called it and that's what they
used for years and for the most part the
source was divided into a set of modules
you can see that list and the module
list grew and shrank over time depending
on the target they were hitting and what
they needed at the time their multiple
channels so in 2016 and 2017 they were
communicating purely over HTTP which was
bundled into their HTTP channel but they
also maintained code for FTP and SMTP
capability that they were using you know
four or five years ago again almost all
of this has disappeared and really all
we're seeing is the keylogger or the
remote show and the process or the
filesystem module which is a file
stealer a file hunting tool and file
stealer but that seems to be
disappearing
which brings us to zebra see so zebra
see seems to be a subgroup of apt 28 or
sofa see more than a year ago we saw
them using the same infrastructure as
known sofa see malware and so we tied
the two together we believe that it's at
least a subgroup where it gets tricky
though
is that they're using a completely
different malware set so all of their
modules are dotnet they're PowerShell
here you see a function and sort of that
yellow box that's some of their dotnet
code from one of their file stealers
when you plug in USB sticks or removable
drives it provides a hook to identify
this event occurred and then it goes
ahead and steals files off of that file
system you can see their PowerShell here
is the replacing functionality that was
previously developed delivered in other
dotnet code and then over here is
something a little more interesting
here's the config file they have kind of
an any file that goes with their
PowerShell code which is odd
conceptually but in that powershell and
any file or in that config file there's
a little date stamp or at least in the
date field they maintain this field and
it's oh nine eight nine Oh J and I
thought about it I thought this is
strange I didn't know I've seen that
before
and if you look a little higher you'll
see build IDs there's 0 C 0 7 0 3 h ji
and for some of you who have been
following black energy in 2014 we posted
something on their custom plugins and we
would find build IDs in their custom
plugins in these any files so the format
that they're using is somewhat similar
and we don't I don't see it elsewhere I
find that kind of an interesting
similarity between the two groups
let's see so one thing I just like to
finish with about zebra sea is that
they're the code that and components
that they're delivering are very simple
and modular they're very different from
the C++
that's exhaustive and difficult to
maintain this stuff gets replaced and
pushed out frequently they they do not
sit on the same stuff for very long
which is again unusual for sofa see who
from 2004 to 2009 used the same stuff
from 2011 to 2017 was using the exact
same stuff for the most part the same
stuff so I'd like to go back to the the
stuff that we're seeing when it comes to
SPLM and kind of wrap up with
comparisons across sofa C and a little
bit of a comparison to what we see with
Turla to better understand sort of the
culture of apt 28 and what's going on so
these in process are these in-memory
plugins that we're seeing on the server
they maintain the same custom crypto
that was being used throughout 2017 and
basically it's a dynamic loop that
changes per victim they recompile the
code for each victim that they're
hitting so they're changing operators
and constraints there's 32 rounds it's
kind of a feedback feedback based cipher
and when I first looked at it really I
was kind of excited I'd be finding
something related to spec or based on
NSA's new spec algorithms but it's much
simpler and it's much it's much more of
a simple hack so it certainly isn't that
but I wasn't able to match this custom
algorithm to any standard standardized
or known algorithm so these guys are
very they are very practical and how
they recode things and
and custom custom fit their code so here
are some of the strings that they're
hiding away behind the encryption so
when they deploy a plug-in like the re
translator or the remote shell plug-in
you'll see these error messages and the
the English is really pretty good the
error messages are concise and it looks
pretty professional and measured I mean
it's it's what you need when you so when
you look at their 2017 code it's much
it's really pretty similar so they have
these this custom hack they encode
everything with this custom crypto and
that's essentially how they're trying to
maintain some level of obscurity within
their code in the 2016 code in the dnc
hack this is the crypto loop that they
were using there's simply 2x or two
sequential xor operations from
sequential bytes I should say it's a
really pretty simple crypto but again
it's a custom hack these are these guys
are very practical very custom and then
you compare it against the white bear
stuff so this is this is something in
2016 that we found related to Turla and
Turla is kind of the exact opposite it's
a flip image of what's going on with
sofa see you'll see elegant code you'll
see excellent like really well done
injection techniques and so they they
have a handle on professionally
implementing encryption schemes like RSA
and DES Triple DES it's very modular
it's really well done code but they are
crass and immature you can there their
code is littered with this kind of high
school amateurish stuff and it's been
that way for years so the really all I'm
trying to identify here compare is that
the develop that the teams behind Turla
are very different and the culture of
Turla is very different from what we see
with sofa capt 28 and that content
and then finally comparing it to zebra
see so the old SPLM stuff and even the
newer SPLM stuff that's being phased out
is very different from zebra see so
zebra see they they do some practical
custom hacks of crypto and ciphers but
it's it's simple to maintain they do it
in dotnet there isn't some unusually
difficult or dynamic algorithm they're
using they push this stuff out and then
little just replace it all together with
PowerShell or something completely
different but it's something that can be
cranked out fairly quickly so in 2018 we
expect to see more of this there's
they're going to continue their activity
they're very they're highly active group
we're gonna see more changed
infrastructure so I don't expect to see
the same infrastructure that sofa C has
been known to use in 2018 so you know
there have been all sorts of public
reports about identifying their
infrastructure and the registrar's and
the registration I think they they
understand they are going to change that
the malware itself is not the same
they're going to continue to move off of
C++ and into dotnet and PowerShell even
for existing tools they'll port those
over and we'll see continued open source
so a lot of the PowerShell that we've
been seeing for them from them has been
PowerShell empire or based on Empire or
other other orphan open source tools we
will see more of that and then of course
their focus has been shifting away from
parts of Central Asia towards the Far
East which I expect more of so that's
all I have for today thanks for your
attention
[Applause]
[Music]