[Music]
so hi there thank you for coming out
welcome to SAS as David mentioned last
year I came up here and I talked about a
new apt and this time I am up here to
talk to you about stalker wear and
spouse wear so this is going to be a
much less technical and sort of policy
influenced talk I always feel a little
bit guilty if I get up here and I don't
actually have a new apt for you so we
begin by traveling back to 2017 or as we
call it the beforetime so at the end of
I discovered that a security researcher
with whom I had been publishing research
for many years was a serial rapist and
at the beginning of 2018 an article was
published in which one of his victims
specifically said that one of the
reasons why she had not come out and
said anything about it was that he was a
security professional and that he had
threatened to compromise her devices and
so she felt really powerless and scared
well I was a little mad and I did what
any reasonable person would do when
their catastrophic ly angry which was I
tweeted and what I tweeted was if you're
a woman who has been sexually abused by
a hacker who threatened to compromise
your devices contact me and I will make
sure that they're properly examined and
I thought I thought that this was no big
deal I thought that maybe I would hear
from like one or two people maybe half a
dozen people I'd help like a couple of
people I would feel good about myself
I would sort of cover that nobody ever
has to feel that scared again feeling I
was wrong
so ninety four hundred retweets later
I appear to have accidentally started a
project and I'm spending all of my time
desperately fighting not starting a new
NGO which is the most popular pacify of
among people who work for the Electronic
Frontier Foundation we are activists
whose hobby is also activism so I heard
from a lot of people I got somewhere
between zero and twelve contacts a day
there were definitely some months where
things calm down a little bit and I was
able to do I don't know other work but
for the most part I heard from people
almost every day contacting me via email
and on Twitter and for some strange
reason on Instagram and via you know
facebook Messenger you know carrier
pigeon all the usual things and I heard
from mostly women and the abusers were
mostly men but I would like to make it
clear that there were cases of women
abusing men and also that there were
cases of abusive same-sex couples for
example one of the men who came into my
office and had me take a look at his
devices and review all of his all of his
accounts was a man whose abusive partner
had among other things outed him as gay
to his extremely conservative Korean
family so one of the biggest problems
that I encountered when people started
contacting me left and right is that it
turned out I was wrong about what people
needed this is not unusual it's really
common for people like me to come you
know barreling into a situation going
you need forensics it turns out how they
didn't need forensics most people
couldn't distinguish between a device
compromise and a compromise of their
account because that's just not one of
those things that comes up in ordinary
people's lives they also couldn't
distinguish between a real threat and a
scam there is extremely common scam
going around in the last year of people
receiving emails saying I have installed
a rat on your computer I have
pictures of you masturbating and I am
going to send these pictures of you and
your masturbation to everyone in your
contact list unless you send Bitcoin
this is
it never happens you can freely delete
that and boy was I happy that many of
the people who I was contacting they
were really easy to help in that way but
I also got a lot of people with account
compromised their accounts their email
accounts were compromised Google Drive
accounts were compromised Facebook
accounts Twitter accounts snapchat
accounts Instagram accounts whatsapp
Apple ID if it has a login it was
compromised I saw a whole lot of that
and the nice thing about sort of login
compromised and account compromised is
that I know what to tell people we have
solutions for that so what I did was I
wrote up a little a little email and I
explained that if you are worried about
account compromised what you do is you
go and you look to see what devices have
been logging into your account you use
strong unique passwords you use a
password manager you need to be careful
with your security questions especially
if you're worried about an attacker who
knows you very well and can guess the
answers to your security questions and
use the highest level of two-factor
authentication that is feasible for you
there are people in this room who will
quibble with this advice will say that
2fa is bad there will also be people who
say that unless you are using a token
why do you even bother and I advocate
for the harm reduction approach which is
use as much security as I could get you
to use if I gave the people who came to
me advice to do things that they then
did not do then all I'm doing is making
myself feel good for giving such good
advice and I'm not actually helping them
but sometimes sometimes it really is a
wrap and those were actually a lot of
the most heart wrenching experiences a
lot of the times the people who came to
me were terrified a lot of this tracking
went hand-in-hand with physical abuse
threats blackmail the abuser frequently
had physical access to their devices and
the abuser was able to guess or compel
the victim to give up their passwords
it was extremely common to talk to
people who had their accounts
compromised in the most straightforward
way I told him what my password was he
said that if I loved him he would that I
would share my email password and that I
would have nothing to hide from him and
now all of these bad things are
happening to me now I see only a small
fraction of the sort of infections that
we see in the wild and one of the
reasons for that is that I was using a
self-selecting sample I was using I was
talking only to people who were being
threatened and I discovered something
really interesting which is that the
kind of hackers who threaten their
victims with a rat are usually full of
they don't install a rat on
anyone's device because if they did
they'd stay quiet in order to maintain
their access usually the threat was just
a way of keeping their victim in line
keeping them cowed and unable to
understand the size and shape of the
surveillance that they were facing they
got what they wanted without ever having
to install a rat
hackers are lazy but there were also
situations in which I encountered
victims who had had rats installed on
their on their devices on their on their
iPads on their phones on their PCs and
they came to me pretty much every day
and I did sort of a combination of first
responder therapist hand holder threat
analyst thing and it was not
particularly great for my mental health
now we call this
in an activism we refer to this as the
hero model everything goes through me I
get to feel extremely heroic and smug
because I'm helping people
I get fancy profiles in Wired in which I
look off into the distance heroically
and it's
this doesn't scale this is not
sustainable and it will only drive you
crazy so I'm here to tell you kill your
heroes just kill them right now so in
addition to not being that technical I
am also extremely lazy so I didn't want
to continue doing this sort of frontline
tech support for people telling me the
worst thing that had ever happened to
them day after day after day and I
started to think about how I could get
more bang for the buck how I could make
a bigger difference without having to
individually help people one by one or
as we call it thought leadership so I
have a device for people with
compromised accounts but the worst
abuses that I was seeing were the result
of compromised devices mostly Android
phones running spouse wear and stalker
wear this sort of software is really
prevalent and it's tempting phones are
juicy targets for for abusers for
exactly the same reason that they're
juicy targets for a PT's your phone
gives away your location your emails
their text messages your whatsapp
messages your photos your snapchats your
Instagram messages your web browsing
your searches your phone is basically an
extension of your mind and that is
extremely useful for abusers in the same
way that is extremely useful for
nation-states so how do we know it's
spouse where this is actually way easier
than finding samples of you know of a
PT's you google it all you really need
to do is go Google how can I spy on my
husband's cell
how do I spy on my wife's cellphone and
see who's buying these ads who is
positioning themselves in this SEO I
this is a product it has to sell
somebody has to aim it at people so that
actually makes this job way way easier
than what I usually do this is a
screenshot from a product called cocoa
spy again they will tell you their
spouse where the website says access to
cocoa spy gives you the lead on how to
spy on your wife with ease you do not
have to worry about where she goes who
she talks to or the website she visits
this is particularly endearing this is a
archived screenshot from Hello spy I it
is an entire page on how useful Hello
Spy is for catching your your cheating
spouse and as you can see there is a
picture of a man holding a woman who is
looking away with a bruised and bloody
face and I want you to understand that
hello Spy is on the side of the abuser
in this picture that is the entire point
of the product you can be that blonde
dude catching your cheating wife giving
her a shiner good work and honestly the
hacker community has has played along
with this uh in 2012 this is jean
careless suru shut down his his rat
project called dark comet and the reason
that he shut it down was someone me and
also some other people wrote over a
dozen reports about it being used by
pro-assad hackers in Syria against the
opposition wired coverage was
hilariously as sympathetic the title
that they used for their article on him
was how the boy next door accidentally
built a syrian spy tool and what he said
was i never imagined that this product
would be used by governments and what he
didn't say
was I was totally fine with it being
used by abusive husbands and other other
actors with you know the blonde guy in
the previous shot so for a very long
time we thought that this sort of thing
was really okay again how can you tell
its spouse where deception is the key
there are lots of products that you can
use to keep an eye on your employees to
keep an eye on your on your children
even to keep an eye on your spouse but
what I'm particularly concerned about
our products that are designed to run on
a device covertly and yes I mean that
even if you have the phone's password or
their Apple ID credentials I would not
equate that to consent especially in
these abusive situations where people
are compelled to hand over their login
credentials and right now we're doing a
lousy job of detecting these products
it's not particularly hard to signature
spouse wear but as you can see here as I
revved up a copy of virustotal what we
have here is a detection of 7 out of 60
products I think this is cocoa spy
[Music]
slightly better 10 out of 61 recognizing
the truth spy dye apk so we're doing a
lousy job
so last week because Persky decided that
maybe they should do something about
this and they made an announcement
saying that they were going to make a
change to the way that they treat spouse
wear and not only are they going to
recognize spouse wear in their AV
product but they've decided to change
the way in which the alert comes up so
the new alert looks like this this is a
privacy alert it specifically calls out
the spouse where as malicious and that's
one of the things I would really like to
see other antivirus companies doing
one of the interesting things that the
Kaspersky announcement says quite
explicitly is that these products are
legal and in some cases they are legal
again it depends on where you are it
depends on what the what the law is and
how it is being used and how they're
being advertised but what there's no
question about in my mind is that these
products are unethical it is not up to
the AV industry to make calls about what
is legal or illegal and if it's if it's
legal we live it we leave it alone we
have an ethical obligation to mark these
products as malicious antivirus should
not automatically remove this product
because victims should have a choice
about whether or not they wish to alert
their abusers that they know they're
under surveillance the abuser may
escalate to violence and our first duty
I say having stolen this directly from
doctors is to first do no harm for
people who don't feel comfortable
installing Kaspersky's products and let
me tell you my twitter feed is full of
these people right now all I can say is
that other companies should catch the
hell up so that I can recommend some
alternatives so AV is not the only actor
in this area there are some things that
Google can do in my survey of spouse
where I know just that some of it still
shows up in the Google Playstore even
though products that that monitor
surreptitiously and that are designed to
to be covert on your phone are I think
against their Terms of Service so
they're supposed to remove them I have a
sort of crazy pie-in-the-sky vision for
something that Apple can do which is
that I I see that a lot of the spouse
where for iOS depends on jailbreaks
and it would be nice if Apple could find
a way to alert users when their phone
has been jailbroken so it cannot be done
covertly I understand that this is not a
small or trivial ask and that it may
turn out not to be possible this is you
know can God make a
rock so heavy he can't lift it kind of
problem but I do think that it is
something that Apple should look into
I've also seen the the Apple products
have really moved away from jailbreaks
since I think the last untethered
jailbreak was like I don't know
iOS 9 something since they've moved away
from that what they have moved towards
is picking up old old copies of iCloud
backups so encrypting those would be a
really great idea by default and that
was the question of what governments can
do so very frequently one of the things
that I hear when something goes wrong is
there ought to be a law and as a member
of a digital civil liberties
organization I'm often skeptical of this
I don't usually think that we need a lot
of you laws what we really need is to
start enforcing some of the laws that we
already have this next bit of analysis
is us-based and this is because EF f is
a t-shirt and sticker organization with
a law firm attached and when all you
have is a hammer all your problems start
to look like nails and all I have is a
floor of angry us attack lawyers and so
all of my answers look a lot like legal
analysis for the US market so there are
some laws that are being broken
including the federal wiretapping Act
the stored Communications Act and the
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act one thing
that I want to make clear because I'm
not sure that there would be time to
discuss these things in detail is that
yeah if F frequently fights the misuse
of these laws code is speech and EFS
fought to make sure that code is
recognized as speech in the United
States and we are no less committed to
that position now then we were last week
or the week before code is still speech
I continue to defend the rights of
security researchers
and the rights of hackers I continue to
defend the right of people to tinker
with the things that they bought that
they own but you're right ends at a
certain point and that point is the
creation of malicious software that you
then sell specifically for the purpose
of breaking the wall that's really where
my sympathy kind of fizzles out as you
can see here one of the other things
that we can do is you can actually go
after the companies themselves
I believe the s Bev did the FTC the FTC
what after stealthGenie the cellphone
spying and monitoring app which is why
when you go to their page now you can
see that stuff genie is no longer
available
some courts have also held that the
makers of spyware installed on a
computer used to intercept electronic
communications and send them to the
company's server is itself guilty of the
interception under the federal
wiretapping Act even though it was an
end-user not the company itself that
installed the software we've also seen a
lot of successful prosecutions against
companies selling voice recorders
transmitters hidden in pens light bulbs
wall plugs and calculators but
prosecutions against purveyors of
spyware are pretty rare one spyware
software developer was indicted in 2005
but fled the country in 2014 stealth
genius CEO was indicted and pled guilty
and was fined $500,000 which you know
will put a down payment on a house in
San Francisco prosecutors have also
prosecuted the sorry prosecution's have
occurred with respect to end users of
spyware and the end user of a number of
spyware programs was indicted and pled
guilty in 2014 both interception of
electronic communications and possession
of interception devices so do we involve
the FTC I at least in the case of this
2012 case in which the FTC
charged designer wear LLC a company that
provided spyware to rent to own computer
providers and entered into a consent
decree with the company agreeing not to
collect data from computers without
giving clear and prominent notice and
obtaining obtaining affirmative consent
similarly in 20 2008 the FTC sued cyber
spies software which sold a keylogger
program the company entered into a
consent decree with the FTC in 2010 in
which you agreed not to promote sell or
distribute software to be installed on
computers without the knowledge and
consent of the computers owner and
finally there are state laws various
states in the in the Union have
wiretapping statutes we have a we have
sorry two-party consent which means that
there are certain states in which if you
are having a conversation with someone
and you are recording it without their
consent it is a violation of their
rights and finally there's the in the
state of California there's the consumer
protection against computers spyware Act
so we get like extra extra super
specific there is also the matter of
whether or not it's okay to spy on your
children so a lot of these parental
tracking apps are extremely common as
spyware and a lot of the reason why
people say that they need this spyware
is because you know hey I I own this
phone and these are my kids and I should
be able to keep to keep track of them
but the right of a parent to spy on
their kid is not absolute it has limits
so a lot of states have this belief of
vicarious consent so parents can consent
on behalf of their children but this
this is a right that has limits for
example parents found that a parent in a
custody battle could serve to ously
record their child's phone conversations
with the other parent
where the parent was concerned about
abuse of a child so that's considered to
be okay but the parent has to
demonstrate a good faith objectively
reasonable basis for believing such
consent was necessary for the welfare of
the child so you can't just run around a
spying on your children willy-nilly and
having it be illegal
some states interpreting their own
wiretapping statutes have limited this
concept to situations where there is a
specific demonstration of a good faith
basis that is objectively reasonable for
believing that the minor child is being
abused so there are a lot of tools that
we could use there are plenty of tools
at our disposal there's a lot that the
ADA that the AV industry can do there's
a lot that individual security
researchers can do there is a lot that
governments can do we've seen that we
don't necessarily need new laws we just
need to use the ones that we already
have and the last point that I want to
make to you all is that I didn't invent
the terms stalker wear or spouse wear
the first reference that I was able to
find goes back to 2007 I people have
been doing this work for years and I
think it's extremely important to
acknowledge the contributions of people
like Harlow Holmes from the freedom of
press foundation who has been doing a
lot of this sort of on-the-ground work
for a very long time and also the
journalists at vices motherboard who do
a series called when spies come home
that's done a lot to bring attention not
only to the spouse we're in stalker wear
industry but to the fact that the people
who make this to make their stop this
software aren't very good and so
frequently they end up having very
serious data breaches it's one of those
things that's really weird to complain
about because it feels like going into a
restaurant and saying this food isn't
very good and such small portions but in
this particular case not only is stalker
we're bad but also it you
can end up with these sort of like Exxon
Valdez oil spills of data going on and
so I think it's really important that
that we acknowledge Lorenzo and Joe and
Harlow and Thomas Brewster at Forbes and
all of the other people who came before
me and hope that we can all work
together in order to make it so that I
never have to give another talk on
spouse wear or stalker wear again that's