[Music]
hello everyone huh Wow I have a few
words to start with we were doing so
many fantastic researches we did a lot
of exposures this years so many a PT's
discovered so many cyber criminals
financial gangs being exposed silence
carbonic a beer is everything we are
hunting for the really sophisticated
threats all the researchers hunting for
them they want something sophisticated
they want something to be published they
want to impress everyone but for the
last few years we forget about one old
pink that actually brings more direct
money than any apt any financial cyber
crime gang anything together the carding
I don't see any recent researches about
guarding actually see a big one that
everyone is speaking about it
unfortunately because the carding is not
dead more than this it leaves and shines
and for some researchers it's expected
to reach thirty two billion applauses by
the global cybercrime financial fraud
ATM skimmers carrying everything is in
there in these numbers and the carding
still has a huge part of this in the
next year by some researches it will
exceed 35 billion
40 percents in in USA it's not dead it
lives
I've been monitoring Guardian candor
quorum for the last 15 years and the
funny thing is it's all started on a few
small forums like Carter planet who
remember Skaar the planet right not so
many people remember scarred the planet
well probably that Carter plane is older
than some security researchers actually
and when I started to monitor it I was a
police officer it was 15 years ago I was
in the cybercrime investigation unit I
was looking into the bad guys I was
looking for the Carters I was interested
and the carding is a starting point for
many new cyber criminals dark korea
nowadays 15 years ago i was looking into
the dark forums and i was searching for
the threats and the stress was like how
i want to become a hacker how can i be
as a big guy sitting there for say hey
go to the carding forum learn how to
kick him stolen credit card information
alright and I'm monitoring dark forums
now I go to the dark market I go to the
dark forum and what's Red's I see hey
mommy how can I become a hacker go to
the carding forum and start to steal
credit card information the carding
today is not the carding it was 15 years
ago because in that time you only need a
credit card data information like a
number
maybe the expiry date and you go to the
shop into this information and boom you
will buy something then a laptop
whatever it is and then you can send it
to the drop location or something like
this but the thing is that protection
mechanism really developed for the last
15 years definitely and it's not so easy
right now if you have a credit card
information stolen it's not so easy just
to put it
inside the shop inside the payment
system and steal money from here but
beef beef is a Russian slang word to
enter stolen information is still exist
it's still there and a lot of new
carries are doing this bill but it's not
so easy because the thing is that for
the last 15 years we have something that
called anti-fraud systems and when I
started this research I started to learn
what is a normal typical anti-fraud
system how it works
what it do how it protect us how to
protect payment system how it protects
shops from heartless and when I started
to research at first I thought that the
anti-fraud system work like this this is
anti-fraud system it initiates its
protection protocols
it's the carters and finally a decision
to block the transaction right easy
should work like this should block the
transaction very simple few of these and
everything is blocked right but when I
start to research further when I go
deeper I actually started to think that
I'm different systems work like this
okay this is me Smith from Boulder
Colorado and her transaction was blocked
she's like what what happening well the
problem is that the anti-fraud systems
is really hard to configure properly I
mean if you overpower them they will
become and they will bring too many
false positives they will block many
legitimate transactions and it's much
harder to like to implement the system
all the technologies that being used in
there in a proper way to detect all the
carding transactions doesn't matter if
it's a credit cut if it's a payment
system fraud if it's a online banking
fraud doesn't matter there is an t4
system are a few words how their modern
anti-fraud system works and how it looks
like it looks like an imperial star
destroyer but unfortunately not on any
Star Destroyer there is a GA with a bomb
good and different system how it works
it works in different kind of ways it
works in different kind of modules by
the basic thing is that the anti-fraud
system first doing a device fingerprint
your browser when you enter online
banking site or online shop collects a
lot of information about your system it
collects various data like your screen
information device build operation
system version even the battery
information even the vendor of your
graphical card GPU or audio unit it's
all done by the web scripts this
information is being collected it could
be it's possible even like there is a
passive TCP IP fingerprint passive
different kind of checks so actually and
different system takes digital
fingerprint of your identity of you
sounds nice right really nice protective
technology actually the social networks
doing the same thing and themselves your
data into the advertisers do you think
this is bad but in this case this is
good the anti-fraud system started to
evolve and they studied not to only
collect this information they started to
collect advanced analytic using machine
learning algorithms it started to
collect to understand for example for
what time a cook here lives inside your
system what time you spent on the shop
inside what did you click what actually
your mouse or touchscreen behavior it
started even to analyze if you have a
social network account using the
third-party cookie because it's well it
sounds funny but if you don't have a
social network account you don't have
Facebook you don't have other social
networks if you try to buy something you
will be flagged as suspicious because
you are not real
everyone has social network account and
of course you have a cookie of this
I can't install ins your browser
this is how the fingerprint check
example looks so there are various sites
inside internet that you can simply go
and your fingerprint will be analyzed
and you will get exact data what it's
collecting sorry like I always told
about the device fingerprint phones give
opposition times on your browser headers
and so on and so on and so on and so on
and everything sounds really complicated
really nice more than 100 parameters to
be checked and finally when the
anti-fraud system collects all this data
it making a decision if you fingerprint
completely unique and was used already
to make a legitimate transaction using
your credit card or to make a legitimate
buy in the shop you are becoming a
legitimate a trusted user for the
anti-fraud system it puts you inside the
database and next time you come to do
the same to by Thomson you will be
legitimate and it will not ask you any
additional questions it will not ask you
for your credit card number it will not
ask you for some additional verification
not any of course it depends on region
heavily usually in the United States it
doesn't ask anything because Miss Smith
from Colorado she doesn't know this
information she don't want to provide
any additional verification two-factor
stuff or your fingerprint should be
completely unique it may be not in the
system at all but it should be unique it
shouldn't have any patterns for example
of the virtual machines or some known
anonymizing software or tor browser and
so on and so on
if antipode sees that the your digital
fingerprint looks like known it will
burn you
so actually final decision is blog the
transaction hold the transaction form
manual verification it will ask you to
input additional unlined information
like cv v expiry date and so on and so
on or it will understand that you are
legitimate and that will confirm the
transaction so final decision make you
should be known or unique but the best
thing that the cyber criminal is fully
aware of this and here's the
doppelganger scalp
they found waves how to use a special
malware to steal your fingerprint from
your PC and to bypass and ID fraud
system quite easily now imagine a
malware and imagine the things that you
anti fraud bypass the rule number one be
a trusted copy there is a malware who
infect the PC dumps your logins and
passwords steals your cookies system
information makes a full fingerprint
device in the print of your system and
send it to the cyber criminal if Samba
criminal somehow can take this
information put it inside his machine or
his browser take a proxy like by a
proximal special side that is proxy in
some state or the same city as a
legitimate user he can also emulate the
trusted activity and then he goes to
your account that he stole on the first
step eBay Amazon whatever it is doesn't
matter
he will log in and the system will not
ask any questions he will try to
initiate the transaction and buy
something and information about your
credit cut are already in the system he
didn't need to enter it the system
things that you are legitimate and it
will allow you to buy anything and sent
it to the drop in address
when I was researching this thing I
found this bad guy meet at Genesis
Genesis is a biggest market of the
stolen accounts stolen fingerprint
database stolen what that includes
global fingerprints a bad guy could come
to the genesis market and Hickey
searched for boots on sale more than
sixty thousand stolen fingerprints are
right now in there everything is there
all the accounts like like payment
system banking accounts social networks
email accounts everything is on sale at
the moment right there and I can see
that the bad guy can search for any
popular website he want to get access to
bank in a key again account on payment
system and so on and so on
there is a details when the bad guy buys
a boat he can after he bite he will get
in immediate information login and
password cookies and the fingerprint all
this data is very searchable the bad
guys could search for this information
he could buy a boat from a special
countries special cities everything or
resource name and so on and so on he can
look for the credit cards already
sniffed by the web inject and so on and
so on also he can only not buy stolen
fingerprint in the same market he can i
generate unique fingerprint just with
the three clicks he can choose the ratio
system he can choose browser and fully
unique fingerprint would be generated
and he can use it after then he bought
by a credit card information on some
other side and the anti-fraud system
will think okay
this profile is unique I never see it
before
probably it's a user first time
legitimately came to my site
he wants to buy phones
more than thirds the bed gas implemented
a special plugin for the chromium based
browsers and when the customer install
this plugin he can in one click from
this genesis market install just bought
stolen profile and in one click he
became a doppelganger a full copy of the
legitimate users with all the logins and
passwords cookies and the fingerprint
information that's how the anti-fraud
system could be bypassed this is the
example of this site there is a lot of
configurable a lot sorry example of the
plugin there are a lot of configurable
information everything could be changed
like user agent IP address WebRTC and so
on and so on you see how many cookies
are available for import from the stolen
board you can see there is a vendor of
the graphic card that anti-fraud system
checks everything could be easily
manipulated everything could be very
adjustable to make the needs of the
cyber criminal the rule number two like
I said be unique in case of Genesis we
just buy two about stolen information
and use it in our cases and actually
it's quite amazing because I didn't
think that it would be like sixty
thousand variants of this information to
be bought and there are many tools
actually on the carding forum that works
almost the same for example the sphere
browser tenebris company they position
themselves at companies that provide an
anonymity but actually they created a
browser used mostly 99% for cardiac it's
a non tool for the ten years it's known
in the cardi community everyone knows
about it it's not a plugin it's a fully
prepared browser that actually he is in
Russian the description on the official
website
it's paid you have to pay its owners
$100 per month to get full access to the
browser or $500 there are six months on
$1,900 per year it's it's a licensing
system and if you pay this money to the
bad guys you will get a fully
customizable browser that fingerprint
could be customized in any way you like
more than that it could be generated
more than that it's possible to import
stolen fingerprint into this browser you
can choose platform you can be anything
Linux Windows Android you can choose any
parameter in the digital fingerprint
that you can adjust and then use this
browser to access shop beef chicken
stolen credit card information and
anti-fraud system would be bypassed this
is the example of the test using the
sphere browser typical site that checks
for fingerprints you see your anonymity
100% your anonymity measures are safe or
you don't use them the system thinks
that this one guy is not using them it's
completely unique it has timezone
location and every other stuff that
looks completely legitimate
another example of the fingerprint check
even the installed plugins could be fake
even their phones could be fake screen
size HTTP headers everything would be
fake so you can ask how to mitigate this
stuff how to fight against this thing
first of all is to use two-factor
authentication on any transaction it's
not useful but it absolutely should be
implemented right now it doesn't matter
if you stay on the website shop for
weeks
any new transaction there should be
additional two-factor authentication
any new initiation of the money transfer
from payment system a two-factor a
sophistication should immediately
trigger it doesn't matter if SMS on the
phone or a token authentication device
that how Cardian lives know to F a money
is being lost another few points its new
methods for additional verification
I don't know biometric information heavy
usage of the neural networks new
additional verification and holistic
system of user behavior banking agents
installed on PC well it's against GDP
are the factor is everything and trust
me
Cardon lives for 20 years and it will
live for the next 20 - thank you
[Applause]