[Music]
here we go again a world has transformed
in unbelievable ways what was just a
crazy idea decade ago is now a reality
we are replacing everything we used to
know B corporations and data brokers use
algorithms to control our minds control
almost everything we want or new society
does not care anymore about what's real
and what's artificial it's all becoming
one but with every great opportunity
comes even greater risk a great risk to
lose yourself to disappear into the sea
of information and become a puppet of
something more powerful and evil this is
why we're here
the time has come to join us and to
elevate our consciousness to a higher
plane it is time to become a part of all
things