[Music]
great to see everyone Thank You Ryan my
name is Kurt Baumgartner I'm a principal
security researcher with Kaspersky Labs
global research and analysis team I've
been working out of Boulder Colorado in
the US since 2010 with the team
today I'd like to talk with you about a
particular group a kind of a curious
subgroup of sofa C activity that we've
been seeing since late 2015 and we've
been pouring out private reports and I
would like to put it sort of an
intelligent perspective on zebra sea its
activity resources malware they show up
in the news every now and then and you
know a lot of the what shows up in the
news is you know people pulling pulling
down samples from public sources and
drawing out implications and in saying
oh this piece of spear fish implies that
they're attacking a certain government
I'm I'm placing this perspective in
firmly in data that we've been pouring
out again and on zebra sea activity that
we've been seeing in the wild so I
wanted to come up with three simple
bullet points to describe these guys
five years of activity hundreds of
targets essentially it's a
russian-speaking abt that that are
specialists in profiling and gaining
access these guys steal credentials and
they maintain their access quietly once
they do that they they they are routed
they have a lineage in something we call
Delphi see that also was a part of a
sofa C project back in 2013 until about
2015 and they share malware artifacts
back then at least the Delphi C project
did with the black energy guys so if
you're familiar with or have heard the
term sandworm they share some
similarities with that group and ongoing
there continues to be overlap with sofa
C and black energy which is interesting
as well
so really what I want to dive into are
some claims and predictions that I made
a little bit of a review from SAS 2018
my my presentation Masha and the Bears
are these bears I want to give you a
timeline of what I see is zebra sea
activity and resources talk about recent
stuff just a week ago or two weeks ago
we saw another spearfishing wave so
these guys are a spear fishing machine
and it's interesting that they are now
using go which is a very portable
language designed by Rob Pike and he's
particularly proud of the machine
generated assembler that he's been
creating and the portability it provides
so that's an interesting note that
they're interested in machine generated
portability really and so and they're
also delivering second-stage implants
which is rarely touched on I don't think
people really understand what's going on
with this group partly because of that
so we'll cover some second-stage
implants we'll talk about the malware
that they've been delivering since 2013
and what to expect for the rest of 2019
so last year I had a presentation
Martian bears if you were fewer there I
love you thank you for coming back
I made some claims last year the
presentation it focused on the second
stage implant that the more traditional
sofa see group has been using SPLM or
ex-agent and really I I claimed that we
had a very interesting finding with sofa
C because they had been changing or
shifting their focused eastward and we
found overlap between gray Lambert
target system in China that was shared
with sofa C's SPLM later at the same
time sofa C's SPLM and ex-agent implant
was withering withering away its use is
totally on the doubt on the decline and
while zebra see activity and and malware
continued to beat on the increase
throughout the globe so some of the
predictions I came up with for 2018 were
pretty simple I I discussed well we're
probably going to see a lot more zebra
see they're effective what they do is
ever see it isn't replacing SPLM
ex-agent activity that's also known for
allegedly the DNC hack and all sorts of
other hacks at governments throughout
the world but SPLM is definitely
disappearing and and at the same time
while they're disappearing they're
they're shifting eastward and zebra sea
might shift eastward as well
and really what ended up happening the
data came in for 2018 2019 and we saw a
massive surge in global zebra sea
activity around September October of
2018 so that was that was accurate SPLM
fell off the map altogether the the last
two targets that I knew of in Malaysia
and Japan are no longer targeted with
SPLM so it's it's kind of a question of
if are they recoding are they are they
just leaving that tool behind or that
implant behind I don't know the answer
to that but we certainly saw them
disappearing so I want to give you a
timeline of zebra sea itself so in
October of 2013 there was this Delphi
thing sophist II was delivering Delphis
II and they were delivering it in
Eastern Europe there was a boot kit that
would install in part a Delphi Delphi
backdoor and this was very unusual to
see Delphi anything from an apt really
the only other actor at the time that I
had focused on was Mahdi an Iranian or a
Persian speaking APD and the back door
showed shared infrastructure
with sofa see so apt 28 infrastructure
and then code
so both hashing functions or hashed IP
api's and sort of this modified or
custom rc4 algorithm which was
specifically only used by Delphis e
kernel-mode loaders and black energy
kernel-mode loaders up until 2015 and
then eventually was resurrected in VPN
filters so there's an ongoing connection
there at in malware artifacts with with
black energy so along comes 2015
Delphis II and that Delphi project of
really whoever's behind it ends so
Delphis II is is done and along comes
zebra see the new zebra see Delphi
package and backdoor shows up in October
of 2015 and the rc4 and the carb air API
hashing that was being used in the
Delphi C packages and black energy as
well
now disappears as well so there's some
sort of split here it's kind of a little
Bang of russian-speaking apt subsets
sofa see goes off there way black energy
goes off there way and now zebra see is
kind of right in the middle there
development really doesn't make huge
leaps and bounds there's twiddling
around with different variants of Delphi
back doors throughout 2015 and 16 and
along in 20 July of 2017 they start
toying or not toying but they start Reed
redeveloping their code in dotnet we see
multiple dotnet deployments throughout
2017 and 2018 and then eventually we
start seeing them pushing things with go
multiple overlaps with black energy
infrastructure and spearfishing activity
and these massive new waves along with
activity we're seeing even in the past
couple weeks from these guys where
they're downloading a huge 5 Meg DLL
that's another read
right of their Commons ever see payload
code so um so again I want to I want to
say that the the implant the zebra see
implant as we know it really showed up
in December to or October of 2015 and
while it's rooted in sofa CE and shared
sofa scenes for infrastructure and we
considered a subset of sofa see it's
very different from previous sofa see
efforts so to date we've seen modules
developed in auto IT Delphi c-sharp
PowerShell going and I don't know what
we're gonna see this year but I would
assume we might see some rust some are
some Python and I look at Python and I
think most likely they'll look at Python
because it's the most discussed and
produced code on stack overflow one of
the things about this particular apt
that's very unusual when you come from a
lineage of sofas see and black energy -
very capable technically capable actors
is that they rip they rip off coding
projects every chance they get and it's
almost as though this is machine guided
they they will copy and paste portions
of their backdoor recompile it and send
it out to additional targets which I'll
come back to that's interesting but
that's something we didn't see with sofa
C and there's sort of elegant exhaustive
C code base in X agent and certainly not
we we saw with the black energy guys and
the code they deployed during their
wiping efforts in 2014 and they're
destructive efforts in Ukraine in 2015
so why don't I start with something very
recent in the past couple of weeks these
guys sent out another small wave of
Spearfish it's it's the usual stuff it's
the name of the game again for these
guys is profiling targets and then
gaining access
maintaining that access so they go about
that by identifying the volume serial
number of the system there they're
running on and they maintain that as a
unique ID for that system then they
identify system information they gather
everything they can about it a running
process list and a screen shot that kind
of anchors in time when they were first
on the machine the running process list
is going to be interesting later when it
comes to the second stage implants but
this is the this is their playbook
they do this in order to steal
credentials if the if the system is of
further interest to them and again
they're active and they're redeveloping
the the the go code and the the code
base is actually getting larger because
they're adding AES and other
cryptography modules and code to their
to their malware every now in the news
you might see that oh there are a couple
of variants of there are two variants of
zebra see and with the go code you can
see multiple project strings over the
past year functions are added and
removed from this module per target so
on almost on a case-by-case basis
they are recreating and recoating new
variants and this is just the goal
module let alone auto IT Delphi all the
other stuff so there are certainly more
than two variants of zebra see these
guys are very active and they continue
to be very active it also might suggest
to you that they're fairly effective at
what they're doing if there's so much
resource being put into maintaining this
code set so when you see them delivering
second stage implants things become a
little more interesting because it does
tell you what they're what they're
really focused on the second stage
implants are always in relation to the
the list of running processes that
they've pulled off a machine so if they
haven't delivered something in the first
stage
of code that they've spear fished a
target with they'll see the process list
coming back to them and in in some cases
there are these Asian custom builds of
chromium sent browsers seven-star they
go after Yandex but they send down these
second stage implants to gather up
credential stores from these additional
browsers and again that's what they're
after they're after credentials and
maintaining access quietly so later on
it's going to be very difficult to see
these guys because they're living off
the land or they're coming back with
credentials to monitor email accounts
communications that sort of thing they
they've delivered second stage implants
for common email clients like Outlook
and Thunderbird and others as well and
then finally in 2000 I think it was in
2017 they they started delivering sort
of this unexpected file content c-sharp
stealer
we called it Kofa C and essentially when
a network drive or USB stick would be
plugged in or added to the system it
would identify files less than 60 Meg
and certain types of content based on
file extensions and start copying across
that data it this is unusual for this
group they don't do a lot of file copies
the capable capability is there but for
the most part they're looking looking at
stealing credentials and then finally
the c-sharp logger they added four
generic credential stealing across all
these software packages so I mentioned
in December of 2000 5000 BER of 2015
again that's that was our first sighting
of zebra C and the zebra C payload auto
IT well an auto IT compiled executable
was what they first spear fished the
target with the the auto IT script and
its original sort of process flow or
control
flow is recoded again and again in
delphi and go and other modules and
essentially this type of functionality
is what they want to deliver to a system
every time so they capture that well
first they get the volume information a
serial number from the hard drive and
then they perform a screen capture they
gather up system system information
there's a process list call here that
gives them a list of processes so they
can identify whether or not they're
missing out on credentials from an
unexpected software package and and then
some other some other functionality as
well
I've been asked several times why we
don't call it Z kabab in April of 2016 I
believe is when this URL came about our
research had been ongoing and had
connected these guys with Delphis II
before then so we were calling it zebra
C by this point but that's really where
it this came from an individual was
spear fish who works in a fairly
bureaucratic organization related to
visa applications and other things and
and that the malware reached out to that
URL to pull down further Delphi
backdoors but we're sticking with zebra
see the Delphi backdoors that these guys
code up add and removes functionality
over time but usually it's over a dozen
maybe 16 different functions that they
maintain within these backdoors to again
maintain access sometimes do some level
of
file file theft but generally they're
going to pull down a second stage
implant or and run it with something
like this there's c-sharp
they made incremental changes to their
code but again it's kind of the same
stuff they're collecting system
information volume serial number the
task list and then a screen shot this is
c-sharp their c-sharp code for gathering
screenshots from a system and anchoring
sort of when they first get on that
system in time it has multiple variants
where they are
grabbing up the serial number
information for example it with a
different function so they are
constantly sort of tweaking and trying
to improve what their malware is doing
there c-sharp modules in 2017 included
network file stealers key loggers and
eventually the Canon backdoor which has
gotten quite a bit of public coverage
again this is very unusual and different
from previous sofa C activity that we've
seen they don't crank out modules like
this they don't modify make incremental
changes and have sort of this agile
style in multiple languages like like
these guys do so the Delphi I want to I
want to step back again to the Delphi
package so the Delphi has ever see that
we originally saw that Delphi payload
has its roots in Delphi C and late 2013
is when we initially saw this sofa C
boot kit and that boot kit in turn was
used to load a delphi backdoor Delphis e
and black energy shared a very unique
function for about two years and then
when zebra see at the in October of 2015
one's ever see itself took off when that
project took off then this at this
custom rc4 just disappeared I've
searched through multiple collections
looking for that function and there are
about 12 black energy modules and a few
Delphis e kernel modules that maintain
that unusual
rc4 code so again this this is kind of
circumstantial stuff but I really do
believe that got it that it ties
together the the the the groups and the
lineage and sort of this break in
October 2015
another thing that ties together is
embassy with sofa see early on this is
early 2016 this is 2015 was some Whois
data we were able to collect on one of
the only domains that they had used in
their lineup so they were spearfishing
people with an auto IT payload they
downloaded that pail they downloaded or
I should say they they were spear
fishing with an auto IT executable which
in turn downloaded a Delphi backdoor and
that called back to Rome Attica comm GDP
GDP our has redacted Whois information
but we know because of the Whois
information on the same day with the
same ailment email account the zebra see
guys created rheumatica and Ravis 10.com
and this this domain was hosted on an IP
address that maintained and hosted
multiple sofa see known sofa see domains
so this isn't exactly a loose connection
this is this is a fairly solid
connection we know that they were
sharing infrastructure in the early days
of the project so another unusual thing
that has come up out of this I wanted to
take a look at the the flashy new
decompiler and this is the the custom
rc4 implementation that the decompiler
spits out and what the code looks like
and again the two thousand two two
thousand 2013 to 2015
timing and the usage and the sort of end
of this code again ties together as ever
see with both black energy and sofa c as
ever see in practice so what we're
seeing what we're seeing ongoing are
multiple waves of Spearfish ongoing
innovation we see them bringing in
multiple languages and making tweaks
here and there they're innovative
they're not inventing something new but
they're very innovative they're
consistently they're OPSEC is very good
they hide behind VPNs cryptocurrency
when handling their infrastructure so
this is which is fairly common for these
types of groups but they are very
consistent very good at what they're
doing they have a stable and separate
infrastructure now from the actual sofa
see infrastructure and they continued to
you to move towards better encryption
strategies within their infrastructure
and communications so next up what do I
think we're going to see for the rest of
2019 well we're going to continue to see
spearfishing from from these guys that's
the name of the game they're a
spearfishing machine that gains access
compromises boxes maintains that access
in Steel's credentials I
I predict that they're going to move
possibly to Python Ruby are something
new another managed language or
scripting language that makes
incremental changes and rewriting
backdoors quick easy agile and I don't
think we'll see Mimi Katz but we because
we haven't been seeing Mimi Katz with
these guys which is really odd for a
group so interested in credential
stealing but we will continue to see
more credential stealing code rips from
these guys being implemented and
deployed a second stage implants and in
the spirit of sort of the ghost in the
shell' theme here I want to at least
bring up one possibility about what's
really going on because when you have a
group a subgroup like zebra sea that's
rooted in a technically advanced and
capable group like sofa sea and black
energy it makes me think something is
going on behind the scenes that's a lot
more interesting than these guys just
ripping code and sending it out
potentially we have some machine
learning going on here that is
maintaining some level of effectiveness
for these guys we know that the DoD
completed a grant where machines are
performing coding and programming for
themselves quite possibly these guys are
have some sort of machine learning
guided development process going on
and they're they're ripping code and
implementing re implementing things
based on that advice so that's that's
all I have for today and I'm gonna wrap
it up I thank you for your time good
[Applause]