uh we are once again here with the
serious seminar
uh held weekly
and uh
this week we have somebody that uh has
been involved in
cyber security uh for
well really 30 years
a long time
been
deeply involved in not only research but
in education
was uh
one of the people involved with one of
the very first centers of academic
excellence
where he continues to uh
be director and this is at the uh as you
can see the university of idaho
so jim elvis foss
um
has
just a long career you can read some of
his bio here you can find him online
he's worked in a number of areas um
including as you see here in
source code analysis he's worked in
quantum
he's worked in uh i think he did some
work in ids as well
um and so
he's got a lot of experience he's going
to share some of it with us today with
some insights into function boundary
detection in stripped binaries and so
uh please welcome professor jim elvis
foss
all right thank you staff and i've known
staff at least 25 years if not longer so
this has been really exciting um to do
this
i'll just jump right in i've got a lot
to share with you
so the problem we're facing here is
compilers translate source code into
binary images you know executable code
a strip binary does not have a symbol
table doesn't have information to help
the analyst
figure out what portions of the code
belong to which
so it's not obvious where a function
start
where functions end
the problem exasperated by if we use
different compilers uh different
architectures different compiler options
like optimization options uh the common
ones people look at are o0
which is no optimization o10203 which do
different levels of optimization
even your programming language choice so
you can find c c plus plus fortran
some other language
and so to have a general purpose tool
that can do this analysis is a tricky
thing
if we can do this analysis it will help
us when we do reverse engineering when
we do decompilation when we look at that
executable and
want to figure out what's going on
um
can we do unit level testing of the
binaries can we look at hey let's find a
function and now analyze it for
vulnerability well i have to find know
where the function is first before i do
that can i do binary patching so if you
look at the darpa cybergrain challenge
if you're not familiar with it i urge
you to look at it it was back 2014-16
was take a binary analyze it add
security features to it
without breaking functionality or
performance
all automated
well to do that you need to know where
the function starts are
so an example of one this is this is all
using att
syntax from obj dump
for the intel compiler uh this happens
to be 32-bit intel
compilers do weird things icc compiler
for optimization
in 32-bit
executables
normally
data is pushed on the stack passed on
the stack
however
in um
64-bit
executables the first several
parameters are actually passed in
registers
intel in their compiler the icc compiler
decided they liked internally within a
function or within a program to pass the
parameters
in registers
but to be compatible with
external functions that would call that
they would pass things on the stack so
the first two lines here things are
passed on the stack they copy them into
registers then they fall through to a
second part where they just deal use
those registers so internally within the
program it can call directly here
passing everything as registers if an
external program
called it
the external program would pass things
through stacks so we have two different
entry points for the same function
which one's the function start
um symbol tables icc actually here's an
example they did they took one function
which i'll show a little later broke it
up into five constituent parts
uh sometimes you'll have multiple uh
symbols pointing to the exact same
function
so we have to look at that
uh what happened here with the intel
compiler they found a function that
passed a parameter
as a constant the parameter was a radix
this was converting a string into an
integer
so is it a 16-bit string
you know 60 um base 16 format base 2
format base 4. so if a base 16 there was
a switch statement at the beginning of
the
code that said oh if it's base 16 do
this base 2 do this the compiler caught
that figured that out and said hey let's
create sub functions one for when it's
base 16 one for its base two and only
combine those together and optimize them
together and pass everything as a
constant and deal with it um so it
compiled different code and actually
notice the code here is a little
different because here it knew was
16-bit here news or base 16 here was
base two so it did things differently
but it took a single expression a single
function integer constant and
expression.c and broken up into five
functions so what's the function
um
here's another example from source code
we have a while loop here that keeps
repeating until there's an error then it
generates an error
well some to it'll generate code like
this
no there's a jump here in that while
loop
um and a bunch of no ops
and then the actual beginning of the
while loop that's a an optimization
option to allow
uh
to fit on an address boundary
well so the jumps actually here but
certain tools like idapro thinks oh this
is the end of the function because
there's a bunch of no ops after it
because this looked like a typical
pattern matching end of a function
and i've seen tools where they do
training with machine learning
and they say oh yeah a bunch of no ops
that's a pattern matching end of the
function in this case it's not
so we have to figure out how to fix that
here's another example
where we have a
star rax is a jump pointer so this
contains the address you dereference the
contents in this address and jump to
that commonly used and switch statements
so you have switch case statements
case 1 case 2 case 3
compilers generate a lookup table
calculate it
and use the jump pointer and that lookup
table figure out where to jump to
ida pro couldn't figure that out so it
must be the end of the function
so these are things that we have to look
at and figure out and there's a whole
lot of other things um there's
unreachable code there's other things so
how do we do this
well what we did
and i know i'm talking fast and you can
slow me down if you have to
um
we did what we call a static semantics
based approach and there's some other
approaches that have been done
what we did
is we used objdunk not the best way to
do this but
we started this as a tool and never
experimental never fixed it so we took
obj dump to generate actual source code
like this
in text and then we parse the text
fed it into what we call our jill data
structure for jim as our tool
i should mention
so i did this work with dr jia song her
first name j i a my first name jim jim
so we merged those two together to get
jima
um
so our jima intermediate language data
structure is where we maintain
everything when we do the disassembly
so we use obj dump to feed data into our
jill data structure we also read the raw
binary executable linking format file
the elf file
we track in the disassembled code all
the jumps all the calls
um all the returns to figure out hey
these are addresses we know about
we figured out where code was and where
data was in general sections
we found all instructions that
explicitly referenced code and data
addresses
we uh looked at the information about
dynamic libraries
we determined if functions are actually
aligned on specific byte boundaries like
every 16 bytes every four bytes or
they're just randomly through based on
the ones where we have hard-coded
addresses for because we can see if i
can go
here
you often have hard you have the
hard-coded addresses in a lot of code
and that's where we started
and then we said well there's exception
handlers and exception handlers list a
block of code that they have an
exception on so we'll grab that
information give us other
other analysis of where the code is and
we looked at also
where the exceptional handlers are
because they're part of the function
where they're handling the exception for
even though they're not directly
reachable
because if you did a uh
control flow analysis of a program
you're not going to find the exception
handling code that's at the bottom
so we looked for that
we looked for the jump pointers
uh and we did a
pseudo symbolic execution where we took
every jump pointer i'll go back here
like this one we said oh it's rax well
let's work backwards in the code to
figure out where our ax is populated oh
it was populated from the context of our
dx here
well rdx was populated from rax we work
our way back to figure out if we can
find out where in memory that
jump pointer is
where that table is calculate all those
table addresses and say those are all
part of the same function
this works about 90 of the time in what
we have
then we go through the code and say okay
we've got this we got this let's start
going start with something we know is
the start of functions target a call
and work through it
analyzing all the places where an
instruction is a target of a jump
or a call or something
or instructions where the control flow
leaves we call these inflection points
places where the code diverges from our
linear flow so calls jumps returns etc
walk through all these inflections where
we're leaving the code so we're stepping
through the code
uh beginning to end
let's see where's my
so we're going through the code
beginning to end
every instruction is executed when we
get to a point where we say oh
this could have been a jump or target
out
that's something to look at then we find
the next one where it was a jump out and
we look at and we decide
when our analysis is this part of the
same function or is this leaving the
function
that's ideally the goal so we're doing a
control flow analysis saying
are we in there or not now we got a lot
of problems
um
some code does what it calls
uh
tail jumps or tail optimization if the
very last instruction of a function is a
call to another function
there's no read to return no need to
return back to the original
because it's just going to return again
you have nested returns optimizing the
pilots throw that out so at the end of
the function we may see a jump instead
of a return or a jump instead of a call
we have to be able to detect that
sometimes we have uh a call to a
function but it's an it's a um terminal
function
it's like exit or a board
so the code after that's never gonna be
executed so should it be part of your
function so we went through and we did
all this type of analysis and
determination
let's see what else
can get to the next one
come on okay
my slides are not changing here we go
and then
we go through say we're at the end of a
function
now we look at
the next
several block
instructions and say are they part of a
function we already know about
are they not if they're not we put the
start address of that next block into a
table we'll come back and look at it and
we move forward so we go through find
all the targets of calls calculate them
as
functions
find any any code or instructions op
codes we didn't know about assembly
instruction we didn't know about we go
back analyze those
every time we find a function that's a
terminal function we say wait
you know i'm calling these non-returning
functions i call exit well if all my
program does is prints things out and
then calls exit
my my function is non-terminating
or is is so
um
it's jimmy terminal so if i call a
terminal function exit and that's all i
do
my calling functions terminal so we go
back and say oh who calls that
because since it's a terminal function
anything after a call to that doesn't
exist so we reapply this we apply this
it's fun it's a lot of code and i'm
going faster again i apologize
we've done all this type of analysis
how do we do the terminal function calls
well we know certain system calls in
the gcc standard library
are
terminal
so we hard code those in and then
everything else like i said if all
execution paths of a function call call
one of these terminals the calling
function is marked as terminal
we throw that whole function that we
analyzed back into the unknown space and
reanalyze it
to maybe see
if we had combined too much because
without doing this we would sometimes
combine multiple functions together into
a single one thinking it was a single
one
because we didn't realize the control
flow stopped
and then we clean this up
um
sometimes at the end of a function and
after your turn or a call to a terminal
there's a jump over a bunch of no-ops
and all it is is basically a noaa so we
clean that out we uh clean out some
padding
um
we look for other padding we uh look for
embedded data and mark it as embedded
data we do all this we clean it up we
say now we've got the functions
so
quick
that's kind of what we do now how does
it work
we've you know we're we're measuring
this executable we're going through this
code and we're trying to say oh this is
the start of a function this is the end
of the function
how well does it work this is kind of
what i kind of want to get to here
because i think this is the fun part
um so we measure our true positives
if if i said this byte or this
instructions to start a function i'm
right
it's a true positive if i'm wrong it's a
false positive if i completely missed a
function didn't say anything about it
it's a false negative
so if a function starts when did i get
the right location is this truly the
start of a function
and i have to deal with you know what if
the symbol table had aliases or other
things so we've dealt with that
and function boundaries did i get the
right length
is this the last instruction what if i'm
short
is that okay
one of the papers we looked at actually
said yes that was okay
why
because some compilers like the intel
compiler counts the padding bytes
between functions as part of the
preceding function other compilers like
gcc and client do not
so they said well it was a hack on the
student's report they said oh well
because compilers do things differently
we'll just say if it's short it's okay
and i don't like that hack
um what if the symbol table shows zero
length built-in functions
don't have a specified length
so we've never matched the length
um so we have to think all about that
when we're doing our analysis we have to
think what is the true ground truth
and for my point of view if we're really
good at this as long as you have the
function starts correct
everything after that function start
to the next function start could be part
of the same function and you're you're
good because all i really need to know
is the start of the function and assume
all the bytes afterwards until the next
function started part of the same
um
if you have
code that is dealing with obsousation
they try to mess up the binary make it
harder to reverse engineer
the code in a single function will not
be contiguous and things will break
we're assuming we're not dealing with
that problem
so prior work that people did in this
area
and i'll explain this in a minute
used terms precision recall and the f1
value to measure how good we are
precision basically says how correct are
answers we reported a bunch of things 2b
function starts
true positives were right false positive
where we're wrong so true positive the
percentage of things we reported so true
positive that are right true positive
divided by the sum of everything
reported
high precision means you have a low
false positive rate
recall how many of the functions did we
actually even talk about
so our true positive divided by sum of
true positive and false negatives
which is the total number this is the
total number of functions n
high recall means you have a low false
negative rate and we want low pres high
low false positive low false negatives
f1 is now a weighted average of
precision to recall
so two times p times r divided by p plus
r
accuracy and i'm going to come to this
in a minute
is what a lot of people say well how
accurate are you accuracy actually means
something mathematically different than
these and i'll come to like i said i'll
come to that minute
i'm also going to hint at this i'm going
to come to better
we're doing percentages we're talking
about and a lot of the tools do this
they say hey i've tested 5 000 binaries
here's my i got 98
f1
that misses the big picture and so i
want to talk about that
so let's first
how accurate is accuracy let's talk
about this so we have something we call
a confusion matrix
the if these the columns specify reality
so is something positive or negative
so if i'm trying to detect something
a vulnerability a an attack in network
traffic a function boundary
um
true positive means that's really what
that is that's one of these true
negative means it's not one of these
um so negatives here predictive positive
is where i'm saying yes i think this is
a function boundary i think this is an
attack if i get it right that's the true
positive i get it wrong it's a false
positive i said this is a function
boundary i was wrong type one error this
is an attack it's not this is a
vulnerability it's not you have covet if
i'm right true if i'm wrong and i said
judd covet false
predicted negative i said
no
and it could be i said nothing
in most of our detection tools you know
if i'm looking at network packets i'll
say here's the ones i think are attacks
i'll ignore the others
function boundary i list every address i
think as a function start i don't say
anything about the other ones so let's
assume those are negatives
if i'm right it's a true negative
if i'm wrong i missed one a missed a
function boundary it's false negative
okay
so consider this
let's assume there are rare instances of
what we're looking for function
boundaries right
i've got you know
100 000 assembly instructions and 100
functions
most of them are going to be
not function starts
so maybe in this case i have 10 things
i'm a thousand things i'm looking at so
a thousand instructions 10 function
starts and 999 starts so this is reality
all right
let's assume my tool
misses every single thing i'm looking
for it says there are no function
boundaries
so i say everything's at zero
i've got ten the ten real ones wrong
and i've got the 990 ones that weren't
function boundaries correct
accuracy says accuracy is basically
saying
how well did i do in
this diagonal
well in this diagonal
um
i did pretty well
i got 990 out of a thousand i was 99
active my tool that did absolutely
nothing right was 99 accurate and 100
useful useless
or zero percent useful
and this is i've seen on several papers
people talk about oh i'm accurate well
mathematically accuracy means
true positives plus true negatives
divided by totals and
if you have a low prevalence of what
you're searching for accuracy is the
wrong thing to report and you should
never have it in your papers
and i've seen it in some of these papers
function boundary by 98 actions well
what's that mean
let's look at another one
if this is precision
precision says how many of these are
right how many predicted positive right
well we predicted nothing positive so
we're zero
recall
says how many
of the actual function boundaries did we
find we found zero of them
so our f one the weighted average is
zero and zero is zero so we're hot
accurate but zero percent precision
recall in f1
here's a different one let's say hey we
split it up three different ways we
predicted some things we found some
things we predict some things that were
wrong and we missed some
precision
five out of the ten reported is fifty
percent
recall
we found five out of the ten real ones
that was fifty percent so f1 is fifty
percent but i'm still 99 accurate i got
990 out of a thousand right
so what i don't want to see in these
things is people reporting about the
negatives if the negatives overwhelm the
data set throw them out analyze the
other three parts those are the errors
that are relevant so when we look at
this research that and the data i'm
going to be showing you that's what i'm
talking about this relevant part
how much of these things i actually
found
and how much you know what i said i
found how much of that was
all right so how do we do this
sorry that was my
teacher aside there
following models of prior work
we took ben utils core utils and fine
utils there's 129 unique programs
we took spec cp oops this wasn't updated
but there's basically
60 so much unique programs
in each of these data sets
they include some fortran code include c
and c plus with some exception handling
um some require position independent
code so that was interesting
we compiled everything with the gcc or
g4 train compiler clang
and
the intel compiler we compiled them
using optimization options zero
oh zero one two and three
um we also compiled the chrome browser
because it's big
uh just using the default
how do we know if we're right we looked
at the symbol table of an unstripped
binary so i should say we compiled these
on strip we extracted out the symbol
table got all the right data then
we stripped all the data and ran our
tools on the strip data
are there some hidden symbols in the
text section that we had to look for
listed functions in text sections
removed all duplicates
we noticed some functions had multiple
entries for now we count those as
separate functions
then we ran our results
so
summarizing what we did
with jima
using this
with gcc we had an f1 value of 99.96
so basically we looked at 1
files
they contained 1.66 million different
functions across both 32 and 64-bit with
all the optimization options
out of the 1.66 million functions
we had no false negatives we found every
one and we reported 150 incorrect
so 150 false positives this actually
happened in some of the spec cpu
benchmarks where
in testing spec is for performance
testing they take standard tools and
modify them to do the test one thing
they do is they
jump out early out of functions or
comment out code or jump out early
inspect 2006 they jumped out early
before it did things like printouts and
other stuff that they didn't want to
actually do so there was technically
some unreachable code
our tool actually detected
and and said hey that function never
calls this it must be part of another
function when actually it was just
unreachable code the compiler optimizer
compiler didn't throw away
um
we also had uh
some functions that were too long
uh in several the compilations there was
extra code
uh after
um
the function actually terminated that we
couldn't to tell if it was a
it was just extraneous code but we
detected it
um but again half a percent so not too
bad with clang we did a little worse
um and with icc intel does such weird
stuff we did a little worse but not too
bad now these are the averages over the
one thousand five hundred some odd files
let's look at what other people did
so tiffany balon all did a machine
learning based approach shin it all did
a neural network approach undressy at
all did a graph theoretic approach with
the tool called nucleus we compared ours
to
um
ida pro well-known tool for doing this
we did this actually the versions i'm
showing today we didn't test with the
free version we did the commercial
version nsa's giger is a free tool that
does a lot of things idapro did we test
it with that
but what did we find well if we look at
things other people did like andressi or
bao they report things this way
they say oh here's the different tools
we looked at ida probe bap dinens
nuclear we looked at 32-bit or 64-bit
different compilers and we gave our
numbers
a precision recall
here precision recall
so they gave their results using these
raw numbers and this is what you
normally see in a paper i don't like
this yeah i can do this too and i can
say hey here's the f1 values
you know and 99.96 is better than 99.27
we win right 98.81 is better than all
these 70s we win okay that one we do win
on
but what does it really look like
you know we're talking about the mean
the average what does the mean mean i
use the same data set for all tools and
my numbers are bigger and better than
their numbers i win right
that's what i often see in a lot of
these publications and this is one thing
i'm
i'm railing on just a little here
because are you always better
if not where and why right let's let's
look at the average income
in idaho
compared to the average income in new
york city
or maybe let's pick universities average
income university idaho a faculty versus
average income of faculty at purdue
purdue's gonna have a higher number
but maybe we add as an adjunct to our
university elon musk
now when we look at the average suddenly
we win
because one person drives all the data
up
the average for all of us is much bigger
than the average for purdue because he
almost beats everybody
i want to see the results so i say this
when i'm talking to groups of students
you have to do better than just show me
these numbers you know are there a few
instances where i'm a lot better do they
skew the means
so i we actually
did a scatter plot of the data
we we dealt three columns of data one
for gcc one for icc one for el uh llvm
is clan compiler and we looked at ida
pro f1 for function starts and plotted
that
and they have a number right
there let's go back to their number for
gcc was
92.73
or here actually look at this icc 72.14
nucleus was close giger was close
but this is what the data looks like and
those just from zero to 100 percent so
they're all over the place
with gcc the blue being much little
higher
we look at nucleus
nucleus is struggling on icc
in clusters of this we'll come back to
that in a minute and doing pretty well
on others but again some places they're
having some issues
ghidra now let's look at this versus
this who's better
or who's better here versus this one the
data's all over the place and you can
give me a raw number
but i don't know who's really winning
now i know who's really winning it's us
because this is our uh
oops this wasn't zoomed in here's our
zoomed in one so this is um from zero to
100 percent our tool all three there is
blue underneath the green underneath the
red so yeah we obviously win because
we're not all scattered like this
if i even zoom in from 70 up i notice a
few places we have problems
this was a decompilation error by obj
dump
i don't remember what this one was so
some of these i can look at
we can also look at it a different way
i can say how well do we do overall so
here
this is a histogram i'm bending it
what percentage of binary where the
tool's f1 values for function starts
fits the x-axis so how many of the
f-1 values are zero to nine percent 10
to 19
up for each of the five 1 500 binaries
this one actually is for a data set
where we did it 97 000 different
binaries it's one i'm still working on
so 80 of our stuff is up in this hundred
percent range for jima
where ida pro has ten percent of their
stuff in the hundred percent range
guide nucleus have nothing
in the hundred percent range but they're
in the 90 to 99 range they're do that's
where they're doing pretty well
so if i zoom in on this a little
from 96 to 100 percent again we're up
here at 100
then things where we're 99
f1 value
giger 98.97
pretty well here and then drops down
nucleus uh is a little slower
um so it's another way of visualizing
the data looking at our results and say
hey
did we do well did we win
more results chrome
default option there's 353 000 functions
in chrome it's a 90 megabyte file
we had eight false negative function
starts one false positive function start
no false function n so we did pretty
well in that one
um
take this a little further
again
average we're talking average averages
are just a single value you can do
better than that i just showed you that
i want people to visualize the data
report in the graphs the visualization
in the report papers visualization data
again we normally see these tables
i want to see charts
you know here's histograms that combine
data sets where things fit in
or the scatter plots
now here's one i want to talk about for
a second because this
when we were doing our research was
really interesting
so right away we saw there's some
problems with the spec
benchmarks the unix benchmarks were good
except there was something weird here so
we decided let's dig in
these are interesting the places where
we're not successful are interesting so
we looked at those
what we did is we grouped it by
optimization level 0.10203 to see if
there was something there and sure
enough in the 01 optimization
is where we're seeing some issues
that is interesting and now notice this
is 80 to 100 i'm zooming in
so then i thought this was sorted by
name then my optimization level name is
not useful
i actually in excel when you plot that
you can click on this and it highlights
and tells you hey this is the
row that it is you can look at that and
find out which binary i started noticing
and looking at these some of these were
smaller binaries
so we sorted by size
and notice the the
loops here especially this one
well what happens here is there's
certain things we fail on
and if this one if i'm failing on 20
functions out of 100
or you know out of 110 i'm down here in
the 80 some odd percent
f1 values
if i'm failing on 20 out of 10 000 i'm
up here in the 90s
99s
we looked at this data and found out
all of this was from the unix utilities
data set
all of the utilities in that data set
were using the same file that they were
including
so even though we had 129 files compiled
16 different ways from sunday
they actually had the same base code
that was compiled the same way and in
the l1 optimization option our tool was
not recognizing that the function starts
correctly for the way this was compiled
and the fact that certain of these tools
were really small it drove the data
so we found out what the error was fixed
this and ran this to the top
but our numbers were still actually like
98 we thought we were winning we were
doing well until we visualized the date
and realized we were winning some places
and losing in others
so we went we fixed we did the analysis
we looked at it we visualized it we
fixed it and now we're at 99.8 percent
f1 values instead of 98
98 still sounded good but i like 99.9 or
eight better
um
so i'm just i i encourage my students
encourage people and and when you're
graphing this and showing them papers to
show this stuff
these are the interesting things
okay i went fast so questions
there's one there in the q a jim
yeah so have we been using any coverage
guided binary fuzzers not yet
uh we are looking at it
um jim is in python right now so um
it can be run on any platform but it's
currently only working on um linux
executables 32 and 64-bit linux we are
working on the uh i've got a student
right now working on the intel's things
uh originally gma was developed for the
cyber grant challenge so it was on a
specialized platform for just that we
ported it from that to the full 32 and
64-bit intel
um
and it was all written in java back then
with some c and we modified it moved it
all to python
probably a mistake it is definitely
slower in python but
it was easier for a lot of the students
to work with
so how did one result in lower accuracy
actually what happened
was just the way the optimizing compiler
worked it
set things up in a pattern
that our analysis tools did not
recognize and so we combined multiple uh
we were actually missing function by
entries we were merging multiple
functions together we were missing a
function end how did we find it
one figure out which binary it was
going through the raw data figuring out
where the errors occurred and then
looking at it and staring at it for a
while and then like huh
so one thing that we have here that's
really interesting like i said we're
still working on this to try and make it
better
we have these data sets and just have to
rerun things so my current data set uses
97 000
binaries but there are multiple
compilations of a lot of the same code
and so
an error in one thing may appear
multiple times
the current data set we're using from a
tool called bin kit
where they have like six versions of the
client compiler six versions of gcc
and they compile those using six
different optim uh command line
parameters so compile the same
executables into lots and lots of
different variants we're still having
some problems with link time
optimization as one of the options
because
it breaks um
obj dumps decompilation fails on some of
those it's misclassifying things as
instructions that aren't really
instructions
um
and they're we don't word sensory line
that we can't fix that
so
but a lot of this has been just looking
at it thinking about it visualizing it
playing with it
and
keeping track of the old versions of
code because too many times like oh this
is a problem i'll fix it i rerun it and
said yeah it fixed it for that one case
and broke thousand other cases so our
numbers actually went down so it's been
a lot of trial and error back and forth
for everybody working on this to make
sure that we're always making
incremental improvements
a lot of graphing a lot of spreadsheets
of the data a lot of version
control um and it's been you know we
started this like i said the java
version of this probably back in 2014
uh redid it into python probably in 2018
it sat for a couple years not being
touched and then this last year or two
we've been re-digging into it again
because we want to get it ready where we
can port to actually not only windows
but arm architecture and some other
architectures so we're trying to
modularize everything we were doing uh
to make sure that we can pull out and
say this is an intel specific module
replace it with an arm module
what else
well you got a comment thanking you for
the talk and another question just
posted
yeah how does symbolic execution stack
up against static analysis can they
evaluate functions 100 accuracy given
it's not vulnerable disassembly
inaccuracies for optimizations okay so
symbolic execution as you're going how
do you know you've entered a function
right so
some functions like i said if the last
instruction of your function is a call
to another function
the optimizing compiler could turn it
into a jump
you don't see the call
you don't know you're in the function
um second there
in a lot of programs that there are is
unreachable code
there are functions there that you'll
never execute
and if you're not executing with some
with any type of execution
um symbolic or otherwise because maybe
it's unreachable it's still part of the
binary it still exists it's still
something that an attacker can use in a
if they use any type of um
control flow attack
so the symbolic won't detect it
also we're faster than symbolic
execution would ever do
i can analyze most binaries in seconds
with this
of course i i haven't been paying
attention amount of time now because i
got a nice machine i'm running on so i
have a 60 processor course and i just
run it all you know 60 versions of this
simultaneously on my set of 97 000
binaries i go to lunch i come back get
the results
i should say 60 processing cores and 2
terabytes of ram so i don't have to
worry about swapping
what else
any other questions
so um
yeah you've gotten several very positive
uh yeah uh comments here
i wanted to uh ask you you sort of
alluded to this but
um
what are some further steps where are
you gonna
you had mentioned other architectures
pointing importing into something other
than windows
maybe taking it out of python
maybe including some uh
machine learning in it i mean what are
some what are some directions where
you're interested in taking this so so
one thing we're trying to do is beyond
just the function boundaries because
we're pretty close to being done with
that part what else can we analyze what
other properties about a function would
be useful for cyber security now
analysts so we're detecting um
you know is it
from the raw binary is it a variatic
function you know variable length
arguments
um once we can determine that then we
can look are there controls in place to
prevent you from overrunning
so maybe i can look at if it's a total
standalone binary
um and not a library can i look at the
maximum number of parameters that were
ever passed to that variatic function
and make sure there's a control in place
to make sure you don't overrun it
um
maybe we can do some type analysis and
say hey these are parameters or local
variables that are pointers i want to do
some extra controls on those
um because eventually what we want to be
able to do we did the cyber grant
challenge
partially we were able to use this
decompile the code add stack canaries
and some other features to the functions
recompile it and re-execute it we want
to
be able to do better on that because it
wasn't perfect when we did it with the
cybergram challenge we want to make it
so we don't break the code but we add
these features so those are some of the
things we're looking at right now
um our main focus has been in embedded
systems for some of the things we're
doing
so it is analyzing it for something
that's not a library but a standalone
piece full function but we do also want
to look what if we do this in a library
um
what if we do this when somebody's
calling dynamic library how does it how
do we deal with all that too
great one thing we want to be able to do
with this function analysis too is there
was a question about fuzzing we want to
deal with fuzzing can i can it help me
with uh
with fuzzing if i know more about what
these functions are
i heard a dog
that was at my end here
you have another question in the q and a
that was the same one
it was just a
typo
oh no that's different is there a way of
decompiling malware
from binaries well
depends how well it's hidden in the
binary
if they're using any officer station
techniques or stuff we're we're not i'm
assuming decompilation as an input to
what we're doing
so if the decompilation fails uh because
of observation techniques or other
things we're not going to do it
um
[Music]
and there's lots of different
opportunitation techniques out there in
terms of just you know changing the
binaries or uh encrypting
and have itself decrypting as it's going
um
we're not dealing with any of that
all right
well
we'll leave it open here for another
minute or two uh see if other questions
occur
i think this is a very interesting area
to be able to do this
there's there's a lot of application not
only in code analysis but in
re-engineering
one thing i'd like to in the long term
look at
is how do we protect the developers from
themselves
you know for years i have said
when you're looking it's dealing with
security you're dealing with the fact
that bad guys lie cheat and steal
so when i was doing crypto protocol
analysis for example people say oh just
assume somebody's sending the right
message i said no i'm gonna assume
they're sending me the wrong stuff
because bad guys like cheating steel
well i've been adding for the last
several years to that bad guys like
cheat and steal and good guys make
mistakes
so how do we help the good guys and stop
them from making mistakes when we're
looking at the code
how do we help the developer who's
downloaded a library from the internet
and doesn't know if it's secure or not
doesn't know this uh what the you know
security concerns if it has
vulnerabilities can we help them analyze
and fix that as they embed it into their
tools
because surprisingly a lot of people
download things from the internet and
put it into their commercial tools
i yeah that's
it's a surprising thing
we've actually i started saying that our
students nowadays program via google
yeah and stack overflow
uh and stack overflow yes exactly
nobody writes anything from scratch
and well you know it's the same thing as
a as a fellow academic
right we we have problems with students
trying to find ways to cheat and it's
always the case that they seem to copy
from the people who have the wrong
answers so they're easy to find
uh the people who reuse code who don't
know enough
to actually check it for boundary
conditions and failures that's a lot of
our problem right there
but um
yeah i can see a lot of interesting
applications for this yeah i know
somebody who has a um
a software vulnerability analysis tool
what he does is he goes through stack
overflow finds commonly used code with
vulnerabilities and it searches for
instances of that in other people's ex
uh
work
you know the commercial code he says oh
i know somebody's going to download this
embedded in their commercial code
it says i'm not going to look for you
know new things i'm going to look for
existing things so
well one of the things that i'll put you
before you get to this other question
that's in here
um
i i don't know if you've looked in
detail at what solar winds the hack and
the solar winds did
where they introduced something into the
compilation process
as it was being recompiled and then took
it out again so that the binary and the
source code didn't reflect each other at
all
um
it might be interesting to think about
how your work
could be used to find those kinds of
problems
um
dick clark who gave the talk last week
at our symposium actually mentioned this
as
i guess he
kind of called it a grand challenge i
don't think he used those words
is to be able to find things that are
introduced into the supply chain in a
way that doesn't really alter the source
code
so
you know i'll just leave that for you as
a thought
and
there's another question in the q a
so oops
i'm going to put in chat i put it in the
q a too a link
um
so an earlier version of this work uh
was in 2019 axac
um so there's a lot of citations and
references uh from that date related to
this area that are in that paper
um
i don't have a more recent version of
this paper yet
uh there have been if you do you know
some function boundary detection there's
been some more recent work that people
have looked at
um
but i don't have links to those right
away so
all right
well um
you've generated a lot of interesting uh
questions and thoughts here you've given
us some references to look at for future
work i would encourage people to look
you can also do searches on on
jim's name
currently
besides my wife having one paper
i'm the only als foss out there with
publications so that makes it easier yep
my son is a phd student now in english
so that's going to change but it should
be able
we should be able to differentiate our
publications at least yeah i would
expect they wouldn't overlap by much
but you might set that as a goal for
some day is to do a joint paper
uh but in the meantime um
thank you so much jim for
uh speaking it's it's been too long
since we've
seen you and um
continued uh good luck with what you're
doing
i hope see you in person before too long
yeah i'm just i'm going to my first
conference in a couple years i'm going
to ndss the end of this month oh
excellent excellent
um
so well as life as life resumes we'll
we'll see where it takes us all
uh for everybody who's listening in uh
please tune in next week we'll have
another seminar speaker
and
until then
everybody have a good week
you