well good morning
my name is don yan shu i'm the director
of sirius
on behalf of everyone here at sirius i
would like to open the 2022 and the 23rd
series annual symposium
we're so happy that you make it
and we would like to extend a warm
welcome and welcome back to all of you
so it's really a special privilege and
honor to welcome you to the very first
in-person symposium since the start of
the pandemic so in the past two years we
offer the online version of the
symposium and we always close the event
by saying hope to see you in person
someday soon so that day is today
so we have an exciting two-day program
waiting for you
with keynotes a fireside chat panels
tech talks and a in-person poster
session so by the way the poster session
will be in a different room in the same
building this afternoon
we would like to thank our honorable
keynote speakers panelists
tech talk speakers and poster presenters
for your time and your contribution and
we admire your technical vision
achievements and experiences
in cyber security
i would also like to express my special
thanks to our friends and colleagues
from sandia national labs who work hard
to bring two pre-symposium events to
campus
the first one is the tracer fire camp
cyber forensic and response training
camp that happened this past weekend and
the second one is the solas cyber cyber
physical test bed expo that happened
yesterday
so the turn cyber security has a ever
expanding scope today
it covers not only the traditional cyber
systems and infrastructure such as our
data centers our computers and laptops
and smartphones it is now expanding to
any real-world systems and
infrastructure with a cyber component in
it so correspondingly the cyber security
r d education workforce development has
never been so interdisciplinary and full
of new challenges and opportunities
so to adapt to this trend so we at
sirius envision the embedding of cyber
security in a wide range of discipline
we call our vision cyber security plus x
where x is equal to
you name it right ai 5g manufacturing
microelectronics supply chains
autonomous vehicles healthcare
transportation et cetera so this vision
is being reflected by our ongoing r d
and education efforts and initiatives
and by the topics of the panels and tech
talks and posters that you will see
later this week in the symposium so the
symposium wouldn't be possible and ready
to go without the dedicated hard work of
my fellow serious team members so i
would like to thank and give high five
to all of my team members here
first professor gene spafford uh serious
founder and director emeritus and and my
mentor
joe rasmus managing director
sean huddy
senior manager for strategic
partnerships
tracy edmonds student program
administrator
lori floyd administrative assistant and
our calendar controller and myfocosi
senior web administrator and winner of
the best cinematography
back there and adam hammer senior i.t
specialist and our project sprint leader
and amber marley and megan rector who
really control our wallet and checkbook
for serious very well so without further
ado i would like to uh hand it over to
uh joel
who will
talk a bit about the logistics of the
event
thank you dunyan uh i had with it
welcome everybody it's uh great to be
back in person
so uh you are on the third floor of uh
of the stewart center the as don young
mentioned the poster session this
afternoon this afternoon uh is one floor
below us the next building over is
stewart's center is the i'm sorry is the
union behind me here uh in the basement
of the union
is a number of restaurants so if you're
looking someplace to grab lunch that is
one option the other option is a lot of
us will be going to ford dining hall and
before you uh wrinkle your nose at that
purdue has some pretty amazing cafeteria
so
so that is an option we will have a bus
that will be taking
people to that cafeteria back and forth
so you can join us there
this is march in indiana so inclement
weather is certainly possible and
regardless of where you're from the joke
is if you don't like
the weather wait five minutes that
certainly applies here but in case of
that five minutes is truly bad weather
we'll head to the basement of this
building now when i first started at
sirius 16 years ago staff used to make
this announcement i thought
okay yeah it's probably good to share
but you know we can figure this out and
yes in 2018 if you saw some of these
slides we actually had the tornado
warning go off there was one in our
county and we did all move the entire
conference to the basement of the
building for over an hour
all but except about a handful of
students who devoured everything on the
appetizer table at the poster session we
came back from the uh from the tornado
warning and there was nothing but dirty
dishes and empty plates
but we were all safe so let's hope that
we don't have any weather today with
that
coffee
hot water
are all in the back of the room it will
be here this morning it will be in the
afternoon so
when you have to hear me any talk and
start your head starts to nod please
feel free to get up at any time grab
coffee bathrooms are right outside these
doors here uh as well as in the same
locations on each floor so if
there's a line one place we can can go
to the next one
um
this event
uh often i'm asked to describe it and i
try to say that it is not like
any other cyber security event i know
because the true mix of people from
academia that being both faculty staff
not both faculty staff and students as
well as people from industry and by
industrymeaning.com.milan.gov
all here there are international
visitors so at this time i want to
formally say hello to uh 13 participants
who are joining us this morning from the
western balkans over this last three
years
sirius has been working on a u.s state
department program that has been
providing cyber security training
cyber security curriculum development
and then uh
and then workshops to uh cyber security
professionals students and faculty in
the western balkans moldova and across
ukraine so with that at the mention of
ukraine uh please continue to think of
our peers
and those citizens and uh others who are
in ukraine and unfortunately are not
joining us today who had intent to be
here but are now uh either are in
refugee status or have taken up and are
defending their nation so
again formally welcome to all of our uh
balkans fellows who are joining us today
uh and our fingers are crossed that
you'll be able to join us in
in the coming years in this event and i
look forward to my visit to uh to your
region here in two months
don young anything else i should touch
on before we wrap this up
okay
already mentioned
yeah so with that it is my distinct
honor to be able to introduce you to the
founder of sirius professor eugene h
spafford uh spaff as is usually known as
is universally known within the industry
uh started sirius in 1998 but before
that he started the coast laboratory in
uh in 1992
30 years ago this year he started the
first security laboratory at purdue
university we have a number of our coast
alumni who are with us as well as
serious alumni who are with us today
so if you get it a chance because coast
predated me at purdue please make sure
that i have an opportunity to meet you
and hear some of the old stories that
you had but spaff started this with a
vision of making sure that cyber
security was looked at as an
interdisciplinary perspective it was not
just computer science
so the coast laboratory was computer
science and then sirius was started six
years later with the idea that this was
not going to be solved by just computer
scientists
and so if you look at the agenda today
those that we have brought from industry
as well as those from purdue who will be
speaking you'll see they come from five
different academic departments and
multiple focuses across
industry so i'm very pleased that we 23
years later
30 years later from coast are holding
true to that interdisciplinary nature
nature spath
thank you
actually
so um
let me also uh give credit uh sam
wagstaff
uh
what helped me in founding the uh the
coast laboratory
uh and uh he's now a professor emeritus
uh so those of you who remember sam
he is enjoying his retirement
exploring hiking trails throughout
the united states
so i get to introduce
our speaker and i'm going to give a
little bit of context uh for this
uh when i started
with sam the the coast laboratory back
in 92
there were a number of companies that
were involved that were supportive of
what we were doing
and in about 1995-96
one of the companies that we
enlisted in our efforts was
cisco uh cisco was a supporter first of
the coz lab and then when
syria started in may of 1998
they became one of our founding sponsors
so we have a long history with cisco and
we're we're delighted to have a speaker
from cisco here uh in in a little bit of
celebration of that
uh but in particular
we had a number of events over the first
few years well every year we have a
number of events but back then we had a
couple workshops
looking at the future of cyber security
to do some predictions and to do some
looking ahead
one of those was sponsored by accenture
and it was a workshop where we decided
we were going to invite visionaries
people with some idea of where we were
headed
and in particular we asked for some
visionaries from some of our partner
organizations
uh cisco provided
uh a visionary a cryptographer that had
recently joined the company from trusted
information systems as where you were
and
it turns out i have a picture from this
from 2001
which i realize is longer ago than some
in the audience may have been alive
or at least awake um
i'm not going to mention everybody in
this picture
uh but
uh we have some people here uh howard
schmidt and becky bass both who have
spoken here and both unfortunately have
passed on
but
whit diffy
is there marv shaffer
okay yeah i'll look here then uh
phil venables
great echo uh
and and several others but right there
in the center
at the front
is uh our speaker today
he has a history with sirius that goes
back
22 years
and a history in the field that goes
back much longer than that
he is a well-known cryptographer and
security expert
he's a fellow at cisco
he leads the
internet engineering task force forum on
cryptography he's written over a dozen
of the rfcs
he has nearly a hundred patents in the
field
one of the things he's best known for
is his
invention of the galwa counter mode for
stream encryption
and
numerous other items his biography in
the program
doesn't really do justice
to
all that he has done
and with that
i would like to introduce
our speaker
dr david mcgrew of cisco where he will
continue to enlighten us and share with
us his views on cyber security david
thank you so much thank you very much
[Applause]
can you hear me
great
i think they hear just you once
hear me just once all right perfect
so i'm going to be talking today about
network security in a zero trust world i
want to share my my thoughts on this
subject
you know when i when i was first invited
i i set some very high goals for myself
i wanted to connect with people i wanted
to inspire you i was hoping to challenge
your thinking but after hearing about
the academy awards event right i'm
thinking if nobody jumps up and hits me
i'm good
so
you staff thank you very much for the
kind introduction
uh i have a a varied background so just
to you know explain myself a little bit
i like to think of myself as you know
being in that sweet spot in between
theory and practice where i get to um i
am involved in research but i'm also um
you know even more deeply involved in
uh you know designing uh implementing
operating products engaging with
customers all the things in practice
on the practice side i've worked very
closely with some uh incident response
and security monitoring teams and i'm
very passionate about you know actually
empowering those people
um
and then on the on the personal side uh
i love linux and jazz and sports cars
so here's the thesis for my presentation
today
network
encryption is eroding
visibility into indicators of compromise
in a way that i think
you know should be
on everybody's mind
at the same time encryption is
absolutely essential
to zero trust architectures right when
you look at zero trust
you need encryption all over your
network
so you know these two trends are coming
together
and making network security evolve right
so that
network security functionality is
increasingly being distributed
um on endpoints as well as networks
right so endpoints and networks need to
work together to actually deliver the
you know outcomes we want from network
security
and
network-based security you know here i'm
making a distinction of you know you
know network devices or network
monitoring is actually delivering it not
a host-based thing needs to monitor and
protect
the implicit trust zone right so that's
a zta thing that i'll i'll talk about
right so
this is my thesis and
uh feel free to ask a question or you
know if it's short in the middle of the
talk
otherwise i'll hopefully save some time
for uh discussion at the end
so
let's start off with a discussion of
visibility and encryption
and i want to motivate this first
this is
a table showing
indicators of compromise
from cisa
for the basically the first couple of
weeks right it was a data set i had
available so i categorized these by
indicator types
and counted the fraction of the
different types
of iocs right so these are you know
iocs that people thought were worth
sharing through cisa
and if you count up the fraction of
network-based iocs ipwatchlist and
domain watchlist those are the ones i
really want to focus on
they constitute
about 77
of all indicators of compromise
and
so i'm going to be presenting some very
technical detailed slides showing like
how these iocs are going away are
becoming harder to get or less
trustworthy so i think that's uh
so this is the motivation for why we
should care about all those dry boring
technical slides that are about to come
up
so
this
slide shows
data features
that are used in indicators of
compromise right so there's several
protocols i'm listing here a domain name
system which is used to map
a domain name to an address
the tls and quick protocol right tls is
the
long-standing um
you know transport layer security
protocol which you know we all rely on
probably even when we don't realize it
it's uh it's nearly ubiquitous today and
then quick is
a protocol that is replacing it it's
kind of a
more modern take on
uh both tcp and tls and then ip of
course is the the underlying protocol
that actually moves packets from you
know your network to somebody else's
network
so
i've listed some of these features here
and tied them into the watch lists you
can see the
the little daggers indicate you know if
they're associated with an ip watch list
or domain watch list
and so for dns the host name
which is relied on for
visibility and control by
i think most enterprises
so that's something that goes away due
to dns over https or dns over quick
right so that's doh or doq
and
um
there really is doq out there
uh and there's plenty of dns over https
um today it's baked into uh several
applications from
uh apple
um
facebook and you know other companies
google has an implementation microsoft
does i think we've seen all the their uh
quick traffic
and quick is something that has been
adopted by many of the web scale
companies um but then again the rest of
the world seems to be sticking with tls
so far
but tls and
quick
encrypt the
client hello server name which is
basically a hostname it's the same as
the dns hostname except it appears in a
tls client hello
so that's actually present and you can
use that
when
doh is used
there is a standards proposal it's not
yet a standard it's a draft for
encrypted client hello which would make
the client hello server name go away
and tls certificates contain
similar information to the host names
in the
and so you know certificates are visible
in network traffic for tls version 1.2
and previous but tls 1.3 is encrypting
them
there is a way
you know to obtain that information i'll
talk about it in a little bit a way to
obtain the information for 1.3
and there's some other information that
actually doesn't show up in in
indicators of compromised lists the
application layer protocol
which is an indication of what client
wants to do over tls
and usually it's http
but very often it's not for example
they're smb right smb quick is now
something that
is real and you can
observe that if you're paying attention
to
the application there protocol field
which probably we should pay more
attention to it
and it would go away that field would be
encrypted and kind of removed from
visibility uh again by the ech
proposal encrypted client hello
one data feature that doesn't go away
due to encryption is a network protocol
fingerprint right it is possible to come
up with a detailed fingerprint
of a client hello and encryption doesn't
make that go away including encrypted
client hello doesn't make it go away
i'll talk a little bit more about
fingerprinting at the very end of the
talk
and and lastly you know if you're using
ip addresses in a
indicator of compromise you need to pay
attention to the fact that i watch lists
um that ipwatchlist information isn't
going to do any good if in your
environment the environment that you're
monitoring there are there's vpn traffic
or proxy traffic right so there's things
like tor
and all sorts of
uh commercial products that you know
claim to do something even better than
tor
and so they'll encrypt your traffic and
send it up to some place where you know
they can see it but
um
you the person trying to monitor the
network uh i can't see it
so
um
apologies for rushing rather quickly
through a different set of technologies
i will talk a little bit more in detail
about the like the visibility features
and how we can recover some visibility
but the really key thing for me here is
that the
the data
published as indicators of compromise
we're losing visibility into it or we
need to change the way we have to go get
that visibility
so
to to talk about the the protocols in a
little bit more detail
i wanted to start out with an example of
say we've got a factory floor and we've
got an industrial robot that needs to
upgrade its operating system or maybe it
needs to download a user manual to make
you know provide that to a worker on the
floor or something like that it needs to
make a connection out to an https server
on the internet
so
within the factory so this is the
conventional ladder diagram right if you
don't work with protocols right this is
you know the different entities are at
the top and then time progresses at the
bottom and the the the data being sent
from one device to the other is
illustrated with the boxes and arrows
and
so
our the first thing our robot does is it
sends out a dns request
for this the name of the server it wants
to talk to
and
you know conventionally the the
enterprise would provide dns services
and they would provide them to the they
would tell the robot you know what what
the ip address was and then the the
robot would send out a client hello
would initiate a tls connection
and you know with convention with tls
1.2
and
i guess even 1.3 all this stuff is is
not encrypted um but of course the
actual http communication between the
robot and the web server is going to be
encrypted right so this is kind of like
most of the
uh https on the internet it looks like
this
then
how does dns over https change things
right so
there are some real positive benefits to
running dns over https that
um they encrypt the the dns traffic and
they authenticate the the dns server
which are very positive things that that
we should want but then
the the
big
and to explain you know the on the
diagram here
so when our robot makes this dns request
it's going out to a doh service dns over
https service
and whatever it's requesting is whenever
the address is being requested is
the request is going to go to the doh
provider
and if that's
an enterprise run system or like a
third-party security service that's
actually monitoring and you know using
the dns information for visibility and
control you're golden right because
you've just improved the security the
overall system however
um
you know if you're just letting your
software use any doh provider out there
on the internet you've just lost
visibility and and you've lost a control
point
and
so
for this reason you know
doh is great as long as you you can
trust your provider
there's there's another thing called dns
domain fronting
or domain faking and
so here we're back to our regular dns
system
and the the interesting thing to note is
that
in the tls server name our client is
saying i want to go to example.com
but
in the actual http request is saying no
i want to go to bogus.com right so we
see we've got a separate http server
called bogus.com so
the
most
web providers will not
allow domain fronting
and it's due to you know network
defenders telling
the the the big cloud scale companies we
don't want you to do domain fronting
because that makes it impossible for us
to
uh because the loss of visibility here
would be unacceptable so you know
cloudflare you know used to support
domain funding they backed away from it
and
fastly i think is the biggest provider
that actually supports domain funding
nowadays some cloud providers support
domain funding and they don't realize it
right so this has happened where uh you
know like tor used uh
microsoft
as uh microsoft azure and they you know
my audio didn't realize they supported
domain fronting but the tour people
figured out how to make it work so
um
domain fronting is another example of
how loss of visibility can happen
so
let's talk a little bit about the
certificates right because certificates
are wonderful information right when
you're asking the question like
you know but on on the system i'm trying
to protect right there are all these
encrypted connections who are they
talking to the first thing you should
think about maybe is like what are the
certificates associated with those
endpoints right so with tls 1.2 and
previous versions you could just watch
the network and the entire certificate
would be there right in the server's
response in the handshake right so it
would look just like this right so here
i'm focusing on the subject adult name
you know there's other information in
the certificate that's useful
but it's essentially the same
information that you get from say you
know
passive dns monitoring or something like
that
so that's for tls 1.2 for 1.3
what happens is this information is
encrypted between the the server and the
client right so
you've lost your visibility into it
there is a way to recover visibility
which would be
uh having a triggered scan
right so you
we observed that
the client hello went out
going to this tls server
and there was no server name so
we'll send ourselves uh our own client
hello you know i've used a different
color to highlight the fact that it's a
different client hello an entirely
different session but we're mimicking
exactly the client hello that was being
sent
and we get the the response certificate
which is encrypted but you know it's in
our session so we know the data and then
we cache the data and so we essentially
build up a map of oh here are the
certificates associated with the servers
that the people i'm trying to defend are
talking to
right so um
you know at cisco we call this
server identity discovery i think is the
name for it right so
and and it works really well and
it's um
uh it's a good thing to do
because uh it goes a long way to
recovering uh lost visibility
so
um i don't have any pictures of quick
right because they would look just like
the tls picture so i didn't want to add
them
but let me speak a little bit too quick
the quick protocol really replaces both
tcp and tls and it includes some
components of tls but in a way that
um
you know doesn't actually it's hard to
get code reuse
between the tls implementation and a
quick implementation there's some but
not as much as you'd want
and
so quick has some performance benefits
it removes head of line blocking and and
it also you know quick is designed to
um get around network access controls
and traditional operating system
controls right because quick is
something you can implement in you know
in user space not in the kernel right so
the the the people designing quick
wanted to maximize their performance and
work around any existing uh
you know operating systems or networks
really interesting thing with kwik is
the initial handshake packets are
encrypted
using
uh a fixed key like if you can imagine
like putting a key in into an internet
rfc and everybody uses that key and
which means that we all have extra key
derivation and encryption steps to
perform um believe it or not they
actually derive two keys uh
and and then do this uh
decryption of the headers and they have
distinct keys for client direct you know
client send and server send directions
so there's there's a lot of key
derivation going on with quick and
um
it's something that's definitely an
impact on the the scale of
the clients and servers and also
in a monitoring situation you need to do
this one thing that really surprises me
about quick is
the keys are not registered with the
internet assigned numbers authority
right so in the traditional internet you
know people who wrote rfcs expect that
i'm writing an rfc so that anybody in
the world can interoperate with
something it's actually hard to track
down the quick keys if you actually want
to know the quick keys associated with
every distinct version of quick
that it takes a lot of uh you know a
little bit of reverse engineering and
some sleuthing to actually get them all
so
the the quick authors uh didn't make it
easy to monitor quick and it's pretty um
radical departure from
the the way the internet was 20 years
ago
um application layer protocols are also
not registered with the internet
assigned numbers authority
so
you know the you know like with tls
when a client talks to a server it can
say i want to do
um
speedy or i want to do http 2 or
something like that right that's what
the application there protocol is in
quick they've made it so that you don't
have to register those right so quick is
designed to be a framework for uh people
developing their own
uh
you know
encrypted transport protocols
essentially
and something interesting about quick
right if you're doing network traffic
analysis
there
some quick implementations randomize
the order in which extensions appear
appear right so the
there's a list of extensions and like
most protocols right the client can
propose a list of things it wants to do
and uh there's randomization that goes
on i think in an attempt to make
fingerprinting harder to do although
fingerprinting is still pretty effective
against quick
so
um quick is is very interesting
and
um at this point you know i'll tell you
how i feel is like i feel like i'm
playing visibility bingo right which is
like there's all these different data
features and you know my hope is like
each each indicator of compromise i have
at least one way to observe it right you
know so
um
but there are some i think sensible
mitigations and so i want to you know
make clear that
so these mitigations that i'm talking
about to regain visibility these are
would be appropriate when you're
defending an enterprise network right
i'm they absolutely would be
inappropriate like if you're an internet
service provider or if you're monitoring
the public internet or something like
that right so i'll talk a little bit
about privacy later but just to be clear
you know when you're when you're
defending a network
these mitigations would be good for
retaining visibility for a domain name
watch list right
you should use an enterprise
sanctioned doh provider right in other
words you know there's
use doh but make sure that it's all
connected to
a service that actually is doing you
know
visibility and control there
and then there's
another thing you have to do
unfortunately which is you need to block
unsanctioned doh
and uh dns over quick and and also
unsanctioned dns right because i think
in in some networks um you can run dns
over tcp
and and that's accepted or maybe even
they're they're not blocking dns to you
know like because quad 8 is really
popular right you know it's a good
backup to have
but you need to at least be paying
attention to unsanctioned use of
um
these other you know dns providers
and as far as tls rate i talked about
like a way to get a triggered scan to
get certificates
that's a good way to get visibility into
the
server names
and
you can block domain fronting right it's
actually there's a small number of
places on the internet that support
domain fronting there's domain faking
thing can go on in any cloud provider
where somebody can stand up
their own tls server
but
it is possible to detect and block
domain fronting
so for an ip watch list
to defend a network you're going to want
to block this unsanctioned lens like you
don't want tor running in your data
center or your secure environment right
which isn't to say that tor doesn't have
you know
let me say it positively right tor has
really good uses allowing people in
uh
in repressive regimes to you know access
the real internet which is a wonderful
incredible positive but that that
doesn't change like it doesn't make tor
all of a sudden good to run in your
secure enclave right you know that's uh
a different thing so you need to be able
to detect and block that sort of thing
and
and the last point is host based network
activity monitoring by which i mean you
can look for all of these iocs on an
endpoint in other words you sit on the
endpoint and and watch this network
activity there's a bunch of commercial
products that do that
and uh it's an obvious trend
that a positive trend
and
uh it's also hard there's a lot of
challenges right so the
if if there's a software application
that has embedded in it a hard-coded
address of a doh provider it's going to
reach out to that thing unless you block
it on your network or or on the host
right the host could detect oh wait a
minute this is the doh unsanctioned doh
that's being reached out to right but
the point is that even when you're doing
host-based network
monitoring
you're still going to have to pay
attention to these these evasions right
it's not like a slam dunk there
so that's a lot of information
i hope it came through and
if not you know please ask questions
so it's really important to state
um
people deserve privacy malware does not
right which is you know one of the this
is like a mantra for us inside cisco
right because we do a lot of network
security monitoring and you know i
sometimes get questions from you know
well-meaning but uninformed people who
don't understand the difference between
like uh
you know like a network switch and a
data center and an internet service
provider right but it's different
equipment different use cases
um
so
before i get on to talking about
zero trust architectures which is you
know like probably what you were hoping
i'd be talking about
let me just spend a little time on the
privacy issues right so
you know
i would say
that it's a false dichotomy to say that
you have to have privacy or you have to
have security to say they're exclusive
is a false dichotomy right so
privacy is a human right
and
um defending a data center and
defending a server that contains
somebody's personal information you're
defending privacy that way right so
that's how i view it
you know
to get real privacy in the scenario you
need real security
and
indicator of compromise visibility does
not require us to like you know run
everybody's tls connection to a proxy so
that we can scan all their their files
or something like that right all the
visibility i'm talking about here uh you
know requires some you know some
attention but you know we're not like
both decrypting somebody's traffic
and a really important point to lead
into the zero trust
part of the talk
privacy considerations do not apply to a
huge fraction of the encrypted
connections on the internet today right
they don't apply to machine to machine
communication or all sorts of automation
or all these cases where you know
somebody has a process that's reaching
out over a rest api over https and
they're oh we're going to download the
data every day right knowing that that's
part of your critical infrastructure
is
is really good and doesn't violate
anybody's privacy to like know what that
what's going on inside that encrypted
connection and the iot space is of
course really huge here right that
you know my thermostat doesn't deserve
privacy as far as i'm concerned
so
now i'm so i think i'm like halfway
through my talk and i finally got into
the zero trust part
so
i have uh
so here's my definition of zero trust
right and
i'm
heavily indebted to this nist zero trust
architecture special publication that
came out i guess two years ago now
and uh it's a good document i really
appreciate it for being you know vendor
neutral
so in a zero trust world
trust is never granted implicitly
and it has to be continuously evaluated
right so this is kind of like you know
when we were you know back in the 90s
like staff was talking about you know
the we're imagining wow we could use
cryptography we could actually secure
all these connections right this is just
what we wanted right was that we can
authenticate who we're talking to
um
most of this traffic in the zero trust
world is encrypted
and of course in the world we've got a
heterogeneous mix we've got enterprise
managed devices and then we also have to
deal with unmanaged devices and there's
going to be non-enterprise assets there
and
you know we've got a lot of
mission-critical connections right from
like our devices out to you know like a
partner's device or something like that
um
so the xero trust world is i mean it's
really cool if we can actually like
authenticate who we're talking to and
you know we should do that where we can
but
in in the zero trust architecture they
have something called the implicit trust
zone
right the implicit trust zone is all
those places where you can't actually
authenticate you know who you're talking
to and
so
um
you know it's basic basically in the
zero trust architecture the the implicit
trust zone is an admission that
there's going to be a lot of devices and
a lot of software and a bunch of users
and a bunch of providers right you know
i can't really verify that i trust them
right so this is what we call the
implicit trust zone and
sometimes it can be very large
especially as an organization
um you know moves to zero trust
architecture it's not gonna get there
overnight you know it might get there
over a decade
and
and so the implicit
um could include things like uh
unmanaged systems like your guest os or
containers which like
is it really feasible to deploy
um you know host monitoring in all your
docker containers you know that that
would be awesome if you could
um
you know same goes for
virtual machine guest os's
you know a lot of organizations have
development or test machines that are
run by some group other than its because
they have some you know requirements to
run whatever software and hardware
there's out of policy devices right you
have all these legacy devices that like
okay well you know we paid a lot of
money for it we're going to use it until
the warranty expires and then you have
like people install workarounds right
you know it's like well i just bought
this nat off of ebay and that's going to
really solve a problem in our lab
and
bring your own device the guest devices
are you know in the implicit trust zone
very often the physical infrastructure
iot
and ot
and and then network infrastructure
uh you know might be in this zone
so
you know zta is really cool i really
honestly think it's a good thing but i
want to focus on the implicit trust zone
which is kind of like okay this is the
part of our architecture that's not yet
up to speed
and the really key point here is at the
bottom right in a zero trust
architecture we do not trust the network
but at the same time
we need to do everything we can to deny
to the threat actors the ability to
operate an environment
and this is a really key point right
because a lot of people talking about
zta will focus on like all the cool
stuff we can do when we can authenticate
somebody so well okay that's super but
what about the implicit trust zone which
is like 70 of your devices
and
so
um so here's a graphic you know
you know it's kind of a word salad on on
the last slide right hopefully this
illustrates it a little bit
i'm trying to show here we've got a
factory we've got an office and we've
got a home network and like a mobile
network
and then we've got like enterprise cloud
we've got third-party clouds and then
we've got the the web
and we have you know some enterprise
devices some managed devices some
unmanaged devices and all these things
are going to be communicating right
there's going to be you know connections
all over it you know it's a nearly
complete graph
or or it's not a sparse graph if you
were to plot out the communication
between these things right and we're
going to rely on security
and we're going to need encryption
yet we're not going to actually be able
to rely on
um
you know the zero trust architecture so
we're going to have to worry about the
implicit trust zone here right so this
is
um
you know i was talking about visibility
because we're now going to need to use
it to secure our implicit trust zone
so as far as network security goes here
like i said before we want to use host
based software to monitor network
activity wherever we can right so if we
can install a software agent on an
endpoint and it's able to monitor the
activity and and get those those
indicators of compromise and do like
behavioral monitoring that's super we
should do that
um
but then there's gonna be a lot of
places where we can't
actually install
the that agent or we can't get the
telemetry off it the way we want you
know in the real world um you can try
even if you're you know it's even if
it's a priority to run host-based
monitoring network-based monitoring is
often the best you have
so
you know network-based visibility and
control is going to be everywhere else
and especially in this implicit trust
zone
so let me
move right on to that right so
here i am channeling again this special
publication
right because
it's really interesting how you can take
this like
network visibility ideas and map them
onto
the the xero trust architecture and how
it talks about
the need to manage the devices in the
implicit trust zone so we need to
identify all of the devices that are
actually in this trust zone and if you
work in a large enterprise actually
defending it you might
you probably know that like one of the
hardest things of your job is to
actually inventory every single bit of
device every device and every bit of
software and and every you know
communication interaction right i mean
that's
that's huge so we need to identify these
devices we need to track them over time
we need to use network visibility to
check for the indicators of compromise
in the implicit trust zone
we need to be able to detect devices in
this zone that are out of policy
and especially ones that are infected
right so that they can be contained
and
um we need to identify uh insecure
communication that's going on there
and uh devices with a poor security
posture i'm actually really excited
about this one
because
when you're doing network monitoring one
one of the things you can tell is like
you know somebody's using a self-signed
certificate somebody else is using rc4
md5
that that sort of thing is really easy
to spot with network visibility
and we need to
detect scans or attempted logins in in
the implicit trust zone the network
visibility is the best thing for that
and and the last point
we need to integrate with apis that
allow the enterprise to
um
understand
you know programmatically right we want
to programmatically integrate the
network visibility into
the zta right so this is a great point
and i can't speak to that so much but i
think it's a fantastic direction
so
most of what i've talked to you know up
to this point has been an explanation of
like why i'm working on what i'm working
on and the next few slides are going to
explain a little bit of what i am
working on
so
um we can our best way to get visibility
in into
the things we need is through
inferencing right identification of
operating systems or devices
client or server software and then
identifying malware communication these
are well studied problems in network
protocol fingerprinting
and you know very often when people say
fingerprinting they're being a little
bit um you know it's sometimes used in
two ways sometimes a fingerprint means
like
like a byte string and sometimes
fingerprinting is used to mean like i'm
actually analyzing some behavior and
applying some rules to it or maybe some
machine learning to it
and um
so
and
both senses are perfectly good
machine learning is very often the best
way to
uh frame these inferencing problems
right so
uh within the network security world
right you have like paxon and summer's
paper which is like 10 years old
that speaks to the difficulty of
applying machine learning in network
analysis and and and i certainly think
they have many valid points but in my
experience when you're when you're
actually analyzing something like you i
want to identify is somebody running
an unpatched you know windows 7 version
or whatever there are fingerprinting
techniques you can apply there that use
simple and interpretable machine
learning models right so
in our work we've used a lot of naive
bayes and we've used um a lot of
logistic regression right these these
are interpretable models and
you know we're not throwing it into a
neural net and and and then getting an
answer that we can't tell you you know
how the model got the answer but machine
learning i think has a lot of value here
and um
one last plug here
better data sharing would improve all of
these solutions right so
you know everybody trying to defend a
network has
to make decisions like you know
is this is this device doing something
that it shouldn't is this should this
device be on my network what kind of
device is that
and
so um you know big vendors can get
data pretty easily
and you know network defenders have a
view of their own devices
but the world would be such a better
place if we could come up with ways to
share data about um
devices and about threats right so the
um i
this is an area where i think
research could make a huge difference in
the world and specifically uh privacy
techniques that made that could solve
these problems
where
organizations would be willing to share
data because there was some mechanism
that was protecting their privacy
oh and i have a link down here to the
naive bayes uh fingerprinting with
destination contacts right so this is my
contribution to this
space
so
like kind of the foundation level when
you're analyzing stuff on the network
network protocol fingerprints right so
uh we have an open source
release that includes
uh i've got a url to the specification
here
um
the the open source project is called
mercury at cisco we do a lot of
different kinds of network traffic
analysis and we've published this thing
a fingerprinting system that can be
applied to different protocols
to explain network protocol
fingerprinting you look at a packet that
somebody sends
and probably you're going to sift
through it so like you're going to want
to find a tls client hello for example
and then you're going to select certain
substrings from that packet like the the
cipher suite offer and the extensions
and then you're going to normalize that
data the normalization step removes
things that are session specific so
what's left is just
client specific right so
here we have some examples
of what fingerprints look like
and uh there's tcp http tls and quick
and so this is uh
the interesting thing with the you know
quick looks a lot like the other ones
and
uh but you know despite the fact that
the this is i forget which fingerprint
this is but you know the there was
randomization that was used in uh by the
client to try to um
make fingerprinting harder
so this is kind of like the foundation
for all fingerprinting is this like
string analysis you need to do in order
to get the the data features and we have
an open source contribution we'd love to
have uh you know anyone interested in
this
um you know reach out to me or just uh
open an issue on the on github
but i think there's a
a good opportunity around network
protocol fingerprinting because
it can be used in indicators of
compromise and
you know some indicators of compromise
are shared
with fingerprints i think that's
a good direction to consider
and
so
from my colleague blake anderson here's
a confusion chart to show what accuracy
you can get
if you have an environment where you
have good labels you can get a really
good accuracy this is looking at a
single tls client hello and estimating
what client sent that client hello and
so there's
it's a confusion matrix right so if
there's a one on the diagonal
then
we're perfect to you know two
significant figures and if there's a
lower number on the diagonal that means
you know that we're mistaking something
on the row oh i should explain we have
the
the true label
is on the vertical
and then the predicted label is on the
horizontal right in other words
so
um an off-diagonal element means we
guessed that
we made an incorrect guess as to what
process it was
so you know this is a randomly chosen
example
to show that you can get really good
accuracy if you have good labels
so
so i've talked a lot i i hope i made
sense and i'm going to try to sum up
with some conclusions
so
it seems really clear network security
is evolving
and the the loss of visibility is
something we need to pay attention to
and we need to distribute network
security functionality so that it's
sometimes network devices but also you
know increasingly end host devices are
actually looking for the iocs for us or
they're doing the monitoring so network
security is moving more to end hosts
and we need the
host monitoring and network monitoring
to work together which you know some
industry analysts would say okay that's
xdr and i'm i'm perfectly good with that
i'm a big fan of xdr um xdr is extended
detection and response forester and
gartner have different definitions of
xdr range so
um
and frost and sullivan you know i'm not
sure where they lie but anyway extended
detection and response is a good way to
analyze network and host data together
um
so network-based security
we need it to monitor
that implicit trust zone right and we
need it to
to to make sure that we have an
integrated view that okay inside my xero
trust architecture i'm talk you know i
have this device that's talking to
something in the implicit trust zone you
know is that is it a good thing out
there or is it something that's on the
on the bad list because it's it's
behaving strangely or i'm not sure it
should actually be there
and uh network protocol fingerprints
could be a valuable addition to
indicators of compromise because you
know on the list of iocs right
the fingerprints aren't going away due
to any form of encryption
and
fingerprinting can be applied to
all encrypted connections including vpn
and including
dns over https or
dns over quick right so fingerprinting
uh seems to be a good tool
and and lastly i'd really love to see
research right so i'm talking uh to a
place with some brilliant researchers
and
uh people who can make an impact in the
real world with their research so
getting visibility
to actually defend the information
systems that we need to defend while at
the same time not like weakening
technologies that would in a way that
would hurt privacy right i think this is
a major challenge for our time
and i think there's all sorts of
different solutions that could be
brought to bear here right so
i you know i i hope i i motivate you to
think about the problem and i would you
know i hesitate to try to you know
suggest an approach because i think
there's many different approaches that
could possibly work
and
um and i think it's a problem that that
really deserves our some of our
attention
and
so speaking of attention i want to thank
you for your attention to my talk today
i
really appreciate the opportunity
[Applause]
yeah so
we have time for questions are we going
to use this microphone here
so so what do you think
does it make sense to you do you see uh
something i missed maybe you have a
different perspective on something
david from
david from your perspective
what are you seeing that most industry
who is trying to adopt zero trust
architectures are getting it wrong
what are the common mistakes that you
see over and over again
i'm not sure
i can really speak to that
because uh
you can see where my thoughts are my
thoughts are on the implicit trust zone
um
i
my sense is that
a lot of people adopting zero trust
architectures might say something like
well
you know here here's i've got this data
that's really important and it's on this
device and i'm going to install a
monitoring agent on that device
and and that's kind of where the focus
is like while i'm protecting the crown
jewels and that's where my focus is
and
that's
um
that's good
uh you know where it succeeds but
in my experience the
let's see
there it would be really good to have
some introspection i think introspection
like
like in the programming sense right
or
your monitoring system should be
tracking how good a job it's actually
doing is it actually monitoring the
connections and in my experience right
so if you actually do this like network
monitoring and host monitoring and
i work with some some customers
including cisco who actually do this
like try to monitor you know they have a
set of devices they're monitoring
and and then they're monitoring the
network and then they actually bring all
that data together and it's pretty
revealing it's like well there's all
these hosts that you know you thought
you had the host monitoring working on
but there's all this net your activity
you see on the network side that you
don't see on the host side
so
i think that's a
we could do a lot better there right we
should
we should be finding a way to
um
do you know get visibility where we need
it
chris clifton uh from here at sirius you
brought up something earlier about
people deserve privacy but you know
devices don't
and
i'm concerned that that's a very
slippery slope i mean
my thermostat may not deserve privacy
but
what about the data that my thermostat
has saying i'm going to be gone for the
next week
you know how do we figure out
when
you know
when information is
something we shouldn't be disclosing and
when it's some and and where's that line
that that's a that's a really great
point thank you chris
yeah you're totally right
that
um so so actually what the slide said
was like malware doesn't deserve privacy
right so it's always good to have a
statement there that you know nobody
could disagree with right
um
but but you're absolutely right about
the thermostat example and it's a
non-trip thing right so i would say like
if we're getting visibility into like so
i forget kind of thermostat
like a honeywell i think i have a
honeywell right so it goes to
honeywell.com or whatever right so i've
actually monitored this i've looked at
what it is going to and it's like okay i
can tell it's going to honeywell.com and
if honeywell were to implement like you
know all of those like encrypted client
hello
and with with quick and
um you know in in an attempt to like
prevent me from being able to tell the
server name that it was contacting right
i think that was a big mistake on
honeywell's part right i think honeywell
should make a commitment to like
yeah our thermostat goes to honeywell
and maybe a few other you know providers
that are associated with honeywell and
and you should be able to tell that like
because otherwise how are you supposed
to know that like
like uh
i forget what
there was a there was a brand of a
router that was involved in a recent
botnet right and it was like a home
router that was in a bond i'm sorry i
can't
uh it doesn't come to mind now right but
this is an example of like
um home networks are you know don't
necessarily have the security that
we would want and
um
monitoring for on you know communication
to
unusual places on the internet uh
you know
is often valuable
anyway it's a fantastic point chris and
good for discussion
hi sir my name is alex master i'm a
graduate researcher here at purdue what
i wanted to ask you specifically about
your thoughts on
tls so industry adoption of ech so
i've been watching the rfc draft pretty
closely we know that in 2018 cloudflare
tried to roll out esni only web one web
browser in the industry supported it
eventually that kind of eroded and they
stopped supporting esi
and disclaimer i come from the
countering censorship and consumer
privacy part of the research equation
and so i'm just interested in do you
think that you know ech once this
actually gets ratified if and when it
gets ratified will industry actually be
willing to embrace and adopt it because
of some of the
limited visibility that enterprises are
going to have do you see that as
something that they're eventually going
to be willing to embrace in the sake of
privacy or do you think it's going to be
a challenge to roll it out from what
we've seen with cloudflare and other
protocol proposals that's a great
question thank you um
so
i think you know the solution we we want
to get to is one where
um
it's one more
you know network defenders people
defending information systems need to
know that like you know when i pull down
a docker container from docker hub
and you know it doesn't contain software
that goes out to
some weird place right because somebody
managed to infect that you know this
particular container they put up a
container there that actually does
something nefarious and it's there and i
can tell if i can see the communication
but
you know if i can't see the
communication because it's using ech
right that would be a problem um
let me try to more directly answer right
so the solution we want would be one
where an enterprise that's actually
defending something
has some kind of visibility they have a
way to
um
to to know
what the software is connecting to
and i i think there's a very
serious case to be made that right there
there does need to be a solution that
permits visibility in some scenarios and
you know within the itf i i have opposed
several
of the proposals that have been made
that would weaken tls right and i think
that's really important too and
a couple of times i stood up at the itaf
microphone and said um
you know we need to not give the
dictators the easy button
right because that's the thing right you
need to be wary so like something like
the browser has like here you can
integrate with the doh provider and the
doh provider um
has you know this visibility and control
they can give to the enterprise so and
then there's there's got to be a way
that within the enterprise you can
actually direct people to hey here's the
doh you should be using if you're going
to be accessing this network right
so i think some of that's in motion
and and certainly ech could be part of
that solution
so
um
that
uh
you know they're i'm hoping that there's
there's some kind of
uh that it's possible to get to like a a
happy medium there
um
and you know i hate to say it but in in
a lot of ways i think the current
situation is like the
as bad as it gets right you know it's uh
um if you look at the possible solution
space right so it's like people using
toy
it's obvious that they're using tor
right so frankly you know if i lived in
iran or russia you know i wouldn't be
using
because i'm pretty sure that gets
a it it it's uh it's obvious to the
people in charge that you're using it
right so they're not getting that so
they are getting
uh a connection to tor
but it's not actually hidden and then
you know similarly with with things like
um
you know the the the server name
it's something that
uh
in the vast majority of cases i don't
think it's sensitive
and i'll grant you though sometimes it
is sensitive and those are the cases
that matter right so
um and again you know iran would be
another good example right because there
are probably places on the internet that
you know you could visit that would get
you instantly thrown in jail
for
uh
yeah
so
i don't know i'm rambling
we should connect after this right
because i'd love to talk to you more
thank you sir i appreciate it
uh don't you serious uh thank you for a
very technically motivating uh speech
so my question is regarding mpf so i
i agreed that the mpf is a very powerful
method and approach to ioc and also for
indicating especially early stage
attacks and all that
i also know that the mpf or the related
mp reverse engineering techniques they
could be you know in different contexts
you know a kind of a double-sided sword
um
would you be worrying about using mpf or
mp reverse engineering for actually
kind of violate the you know privacy of
user especially for example in a
wireless environment
the network protocol fingerprinting
technologies are so advanced right with
machine learning and all that now
uh at least based on my own experience
i'm actually able to infer not only the
specific network protocol that is being
used i can even infer what is the
specific stage or what is the specific
operation that is going on at the end
system so for example i have a uh
airline app i can actually differentiate
between your online checking and the
online purchase and for a online dating
app i can differentiate between browsing
your potential contacts and chatting
with a specific friend so that kind of
information can be
disclosed with high accuracy because of
mpf mp reverse engineering so what is
your insight on kind of balancing
because we're supposed to fight the
attack right to enhance ioc not to
compromise privacy
yeah
so if you actually look at what it's
possible to infer encrypted connections
it's it there's a tremendous amount of
things that could be inferred
um
my colleague blake anderson did a a
study of http 2 protocol machinery
it you could learn you could infer like
a huge amount of what was actually going
on inside of an http 2 connection which
is was really meaningful like
like
file sizes say right um
that are you know the size of the files
going up and down
um
i think
let's see i really tried to focus more
on visibility and then some of the basic
inferencing things right which is like
what operating system you're using or
maybe more importantly like i'm using an
operating system that's patched and up
to date i i'm not running you know
unpatched windows 8 or something like
that right i mean that's there's no
privacy issues there
um
definitely i think in theory there's
probably a lot of privacy invasive stuff
that could be done
i
i'm a little bit skeptical that it's
actually being done
and i might be wrong about that but in
my own you know in in my experience like
when you work on a big data project and
you're trying to you've got billions of
events a day
and uh
managing the scale of the data
especially
the sophisticated attacks need labeled
data right so trying to get labeled data
that's comprehensive at scale is
uh
is really really ugly right so
i don't know it's an it's another
interesting question right it deserves a
lot more thought than than i could give
it now
i hopefully on the last question so
people can get some break but um
zac tutor uh idaho national lab um so
when you're mentioning your example of
monitoring you talk about so that the
network you know sought certain data the
host uh was providing other data and
they didn't uh you know fully correlate
so i'm kind of on the other side so when
in this era of now ubiquitous sensing um
you have endpoints all over the place
you know flooding with data shouldn't
the host just be providing the data
that's important to it or that it thinks
is important to the network and let the
network
then develop those things and if we
collect everything we won't be able to
analyze anything in enough time to stop
an attack that might be coming that that
sounds like a great vision to me
so
what you're saying totally makes sense
and
i still think there's there's a lot of
challenges as far as like the visibility
example would be like the
the application software might not be
cooperating
with the operating system right so you
install something as a shim in the
operating system um like i don't know if
anybody who does like
monitoring on a host will know that
there's all sorts of ways that packets
can go from like an application onto the
network that somehow like well wait a
minute i inserted this shim that the
operating syst you know the os vendor
told me to do this shim here but somehow
a packet got out onto the network right
and and it's like okay there's another
path there oh there's a raw socket or
whatever like or like wait the
the virtual machine thing goes through a
tunnel and so there's this extra
encapsulation i wasn't recognizing any
of the packets um there's all sorts of
like challenges to visibility and that's
what i meant to allude to more than
uh i was you know i
anyway i hope that's clear anyway i
think we've hit all the questions and i
i think there's
a break now
[Applause]
you