welcome we have um
an interesting panel coming up for you
and uh
kind of
moving a little from
traditional views of computer security
and looking at some other other issues
fairness which actually has a lot in
common with data privacy
uh and trustworthiness in ai which
trust is something we think of a lot in
computer security
uh trustworthy ai
some relationships some differences
so
i'm gonna just go through a couple of
things uh
before i introduce the panel
uh
you know what's the problem here
well
there's a lot of concerns about fairness
trustworthiness of ai systems
uh
fairness ai systems
exhibit recognizable biases
amazon created a resume screener that
was showing gender bias
there's
software being used to predict
recidivism and that is being used in
setting bail for example
that
is showing
racial biases
uh
various various types of of biases here
and
trustworthiness
ai systems we know can get it wrong
and sometimes they get it wrong in ways
that you know humans would perfectly
succeed many of you see have seen the
example of taking a stop sign
putting a few stickers on it and all of
a sudden the ai system thinks it's a
speed limit sign
um
you know there's
you know some some problems here
contexts of this
well
trustworthiness has long been an issue
in cyber security particularly in safety
critical systems
fairness and privacy turn out to have a
lot in relation
this fairness
a lot of the work and the concern in ai
has largely been in
civil traditional civil rights spaces
and those types of issues
but are there other issues
trustworthiness
again has been primarily in safety
critical systems use of ai and safety
critical systems particularly autonomous
vehicles
the use of ai and autonomous vehicles
has
generated a lot of safety concerns
so yeah but there's a couple of things
to think about like you know are fair
and trusted ai
independent concepts do they really you
know they really together
we may get into some of that as we go
into this
uh
as we go into this panel but let me
start by introducing the panelists for
those who don't know me i'm chris
clifton i'm
on the faculty here at purdue
i've been part of sirius for
over 20 years now
and
and actually i think
my first interaction with sirius was in
the previous millennium
so uh it's been a while
uh also with us we have a distinguished
panel of people all of whom have
purdue
connections
tom grunwald who is a senior vice
president with blue waves ai got his phd
here at purdue in 1976
2007 was named an outstanding alum
uh has a long history including faculty
university of portland bell labs
tel labs spectrum control
westhall
i'll let you go into a little on kind of
your thoughts on these fairness
trustworthiness issues and why this
interests you okay thank you
you know the our company bluewave ai
labs
generates software make software that's
used in the nuclear industry as well as
defense we do support for darpa as well
and
trustworthiness
comes in a little different flavor
with respect to nuclear because the
folks who use our our software
are using it to plan how they're going
to operate
the reactor for the next two years so we
have to do a really thorough job
of showing them
that
the software the predictions are really
accurate and trustworthy
and sometimes it's good to step back and
ask yourself okay what is ai because ai
is one of those words that can mean a
lot of different things
um primarily it's a blanket term for a
lot of different techniques those of you
who are here for the
poster session
saw that
there there's an amazing set of talented
people who are using ai in a lot of
different ways and a lot of different ai
techniques
but basically
aai is always
supported or a reflection of the data
there are a lot of different techniques
but the data is really what determines
how well the quote unquote ai is going
to work and the data is primarily but
not always what introduces the bias in
our work we have to make sure that the
data act that reflects the real way the
reactors operate we take usually 20
years of historical data to train a
model
to then give predictions
so again we focus a lot on the data the
other thing we worry about a lot is
using the models in the regime that the
data describes it it would be as if you
were trying to
select
blue cars but you've never had a blue
car in your training set
there's also the difficulty sometimes
with the models because you don't know
exactly what the model is going to pick
up on in some of these models actually
the most complicated model in use right
now has one trillion
free parameters
that are determined by the training data
and there's a famous problem of uh
an ai that's that was trying to to
identify different animals
it had problems with horses and when
they looked into it they found out that
oh
the ai was training on the copyright
that appeared in the horse pictures
because the horse pictures that they
used to train the ai all had a copyright
on them but nobody else none of the
other pictures did
and so what that leads us to do in order
to engender trust with our customers is
we do a lot of work what are called
explainability analyses
trying to understand what features
actually made the result come true and
then that plus accuracy is what really
gives our customers trust in what we do
so it's a little different kind of trust
than when you're dealing with people and
i think most folks know
that you know the europeans are
significantly ahead of us
in the whole trust thing they've got the
gdpr which is about a hundred page set
of regulations about what you do
what you have to do when you use data
that pertains human beings so
that's sort of my introduction to how we
look at trust
okay also with us we have ashish kandu
who is
again purdue connections uh he's
currently head of cyber security
research at cisco
but his phd is from purdue computer
science in 2010
for those of you tomorrow morning
come to the awards and hear about uh
and here are some of our awards
ashish 10 years ago was
11 years ago was a recipient of the
serious diamond award
he's previously been at ibm research and
neuro
unfortunately unable to join us in
person today but is is with us so as she
i'll let you give a little idea of
fairness and trust and how that's of
interest to you
um thank you so much professor clifton
um for your kind introduction and
it is a pleasure and honor actually to
be to be part of the series again
um there's an alam series and cs alum
from purdue
and you know and i was a student of uh
professor clifton
uh it's a also a great honor to be part
of the panel where he
is moderating so uh thank you everyone
again and
the
i think when we look at
the important topic of fairness and
trustworthy
ness in ai
right let me focus on primarily machine
learning instead of going into the
general area of ai
you when you look at fairness right
they're more about uh um something uh
something relative like civil rights uh
that change from geopolitical region to
another region from time to time
and uh
whereas uh uh trustworthiness might
is a close cousin but they are more that
is more related to as
as professor clifton and
tom pointed out earlier right that
they're more more related to security in
some way in in trust can can we can you
compromise
a given
machine learning system a model
or it's uh
or it's a real-time
classification or prediction mechanism
in some way that it is going to
uh work uh in a
in an unintended manner
uh right so if you focus on little more
unfair ai right
it talks about essentially algorithmic
bias
uh with respect to
certain fairness policies maybe that is
the or regulatory requirement that is
developed by a government or or certain
certain civil rights body right you know
like
pay you know and gender equality
or your
[Music]
voting rights for example
or hiring decisions right
uh but
there is a general pro
from my point of view the general
problem there that
when you talk about fairness in
machine learning systems
are we trying to make it
fairer than what is in the world today
right
um
or are we trying to match the fairness
of of the fairness that we have in the
world today or we plan to have in next
few years and that is here comes the
problem of uh now are you developing
machine learning systems for this world
or
or another world
that is in the future
and
in that context
what does fairness in of ai means in
metaverse
okay
that's that's something i'm currently
working on to write a write a
paper about
what does it mean
uh in in
fairness uh and ethics of ai in in
metagross
of the avatars and other things
so
um
and under some work that has been
carried out there there are fairness
metrics very well studied in from from
the statistical
standpoint
there are
so from a trustworthy point of view
that the challenges are essentially can
can the model be compromised right
uh is it compromised what are the what
are the cyber physical safety issues
right how does what does adversarial
machine learning play a role how does it
play a role in in trustworthiness now
can adversarial machine learning uh
contribute to unfairness okay or
fairness in machine learning systems
that is you are they they they can
they overlap with each other to give an
example uh right
imagine a map service right
that you are you that one can use on
there well the drive and and that map
service is going to give directions to
improve sales of
an ev charging station electric
battery charging station of the car
right it's going to change it increase
your distance or whatever right will you
call it trusted
ml or untrusted ml or unfair
let me pause here
and then
we can come back to that later
thank you
thanks
thanks ashish and
the our other two panelists
are currently affiliated with purdue and
i've had the honor of working with both
of them on a
project funded by nsf and amazon on
fairness in ai
lindsey weinberg
is an assistant professor in the honors
college
and uh i think
has a history of kind of working
cross-disciplinary just like being in an
honors college which is
kind of deals with multiple disciplines
her phd from uc santa cruz
was in history of consciousness
uh she has
the director i think founding director
is the
correct word for this of the tech
justice lab here at purdue so let me
turn it over to lindsay yeah
can you folks hear me okay is this all
right for folks on the back is that good
okay awesome um thank you all so much
for inviting me to speak with you i
always love the opportunity to talk
across disciplines and i'm of course
honored to be up here with two of my
colleagues on the grant that i'm on
precisely on this idea of ai fairness um
so i guess i'll just try and be very
very quick about how i approach ai
fairness as a feminist researcher
and i think what my my training in
feminist studies has taught me to think
about is how do we center questions of
power um and how do we think about the
experiences of folks who are the most
marginalized oftentimes in these
conversations
both in terms of who gets to participate
in ai research who is most disparately
impacted by ai systems whose voices and
experiences tend to be left out of these
discussions and really kind of immersing
myself
in those community experiences so i
think there's a few ways we can start
asking questions about ai fairness you
know how do
assumptions about what it means for a
system to be fair get baked into these
kinds of conversations to what extent
are impacted communities at the table
and able to give their input into
exactly when we should decide an ai
system is actually the best solution to
a given problem um and i actually think
there's two dominant ways in which ai
fairness discourse actually perpetuates
harm you know oftentimes we think of
aspirations for ai fairness as achieving
greater equality or greater fairness in
society but i want to give you two
examples to think about that i think
help
maybe temper claims that algorithmic
fairness is something that we should
always aspire to
um so one example might be facial
recognition technology right this is a
technology with known racial and gender
bias and within kind of conventional ai
fairness thinking we might say okay
let's solve for that racial and gender
bias let's make sure that facial
recognition technology works equally
well across all race racial and gender
groups right
the problem with that type of approach
to ai fairness is that when something
like facial recognition technology is
used to optimize the existing criminal
legal system and that existing criminal
legal system tends to mass incarcerate
folks of color do we really want that
system to be able to more accurately
read folks of color spaces right when
you listen to communities on the ground
when you listen to communities of color
doing activism work around the the
prison industrial complex they don't
necessarily want to be more legible to
facial recognition technology and yet
within the discourse around aspirations
to algorithmic fairness we would assume
that making frt fairer would would be a
positive outcome right um just to give
you one other example for thinking about
this and this is a case study that uh dr
clifton had brought up you know compass
is an algorithm that's used to help
inform judges decisions about the
likelihood that a defendant will will
become a repeat offender right so it's
meant to guide judges in making these
really difficult decisions it's probably
a more accurate tool because it's based
on you know historical data patterns
right and yet we know that folks of
color are disproportionately targeted
within the prison industrial complex
right so we also see that these
decisions can optimize those existing
biases
if we were to fix compass right if we
were to make sure that compass is
equally predictably accurate for all
racial and ethnic groups would that be a
fairer tool and i think what folks on
the ground might say is you're still
optimizing a system that seeks to put
folks in jail right you're still
thinking about a problem formulation
space where justice is conceived of how
do we incarcerate people more fairly
right and there's other ways to imagine
a society
of thinking about justice thinking about
what do we do with people who commit
harms in society that aren't rooted in
mass incarceration right lots of folks
make other kinds of arguments for ways
we might solve these problems and yet
the problem formulation space within the
dominant discourse is how do we optimize
the status quo how do we optimize this
compass technology to be fair right so
my my discipline teaches me to kind of
um interrogate the kinds of
epistemological assumptions we make
about what ai fairness even means right
and to maybe take a step back from those
those discourses
thank you
and our final panelist is christopher
yeomans who is
professor and uh
and head of the department of philosophy
here at purdue uh
his phd in riverside you see riverside
so we have two people from uc two people
from purdue
and and the oddball here
and uh
uh so
uh
and christopher's also had the
experience of being a humble fellow
where he spent time at uh ludwig
maximilian university in munchin munich
that was in 2016.
so i'll let you go ahead and
give an idea of some of the things
you're doing in fairness yeah sure i
mean maybe i'll also speak a little to
the disciplinary background so
philosophers spend a lot of time
thinking about what you might call
natural intelligence right the kind of
intelligence that we all
seem to have or lack as the case may be
on any given day
and
spoiler alert the result is it's really
complicated
so part of my interest in ai generally
is wondering how any of this could be
built from the ground up
right and
trying to see
what insights might be derived from
trying to do it that way
the kinds of modeling that are involved
but with a
heavy dose of i think realism about
the complexity and context sensitivity
of all sorts of human judgments whether
epistemic or normative judgments that is
judgments about what is the case or
judgments about what ought to be the
case um and so
uh even within philosophy i think
i am on a continuum of people i'm on one
end thinking that in particular
our normative judgments our moral and
our political judgments are incredibly
complicated they're very context
sensitive i'm a value pluralist i don't
think that our moral or political values
are reducible to
freedom or equality or one single value
i think we always have values that are
trading off against each other and that
there's
no equation for what the right trade-off
is particularly in any given situation
um
to come to fairness in particular i
think it's notable
that of all of the sort of
terms for normative rightness that we
have like if you put fair up against
just good right moral i think fair at
least in english is the most
context-sensitive and the most local of
all of those terms and the most likely
to be tied to
particular decisions in particular
contexts and that raises particular
issues of complexity for any attempt to
automate this or to explain what an
automated system is done with it um
and
so anyway those are sort of my
expectations of what artificial
intelligence will look like from
thinking about what natural intelligence
will look like
i do think that there's an upside there
which is i do think sometimes people in
the ii community think
you won't have found fair ai until you
can eliminate disagreement
about the decisions that are being made
but uh let me tell you that's a fool's
errand right you're not going to
eliminate that kind of disagreement and
it's more important to understand the
quality of the disagreement and it's
more important to understand the
different groups and the different
perspectives and the different interests
that are involved in the disagreement
and getting those people talking to each
other about how as she put it to make it
fairer
right that's the goal right um and um
right so maybe i'll just stop there
well i'll tell you we've we've had some
discussions amongst ourselves email
discussions and came up with a few
questions and so i'm gonna pose those
and
to get things started but you know as we
go on if you've got
questions to add or or
you know things you want to post the
panelists things you want to add
please step up to the mic i'd like this
to be a discussion i'm going to start
off with the first
and this kind of builds on something
she's
talked about in trustworthiness which is
you know how much do we really need
what about fairness why should we care
that ai is fair even if humans aren't
fair and ashish i'm going to put you on
the spot to start this off
up we go there we go
can you hear me now
yes we're good okay
thank you project so
yeah so why do we why do we need uh ai
to be fair right so if you look at
um
if we look at uh
the the the
you know how how machine learning models
or machine learning systems work right
they are data driven primarily they are
not a
implementation of a deterministic
algorithm
that is
being used there and it's going to be
totally contact context independent um
you know so so machine learning models
are
highly context sensitive with an and
dependent on the data
uh they're number one the data that is
being used for training
number two
the
way the training is carried out you know
it's like
there are there are work on going on
determining even for the same type of
data are there any other other variables
that affect how the models here right
then there are hyper parameter tuning
you know uh
so the weights are our
important aspects of uh how the model
will we have later even after training
right
so so
those are different aspects and then
there are aspects of at the run time
when the model is let's say is is based
on tensorflow right
and you are going to run it on on
nvidia gpus for example right but if
there are
the model doesn't execute properly right
or there are certain other issues with
respect to the run time
maybe maybe
we are looking at that the
ai may not be may not be acting in a
fair manner maybe the run time is not
fair itself you know the model may be
trained so so there is a necessity for
looking at fairness of ai not just from
algorithm algorithmic point of view not
just from data bias which the industry
has been looking at or the academy has
been looking at they have to look at the
entire
life cycle of the model model governance
you know
our ai governance and try to see where
fairness can be crafted and that is
where
key threats
to fairness might come in you know
and and fairness could also lead to
privacy disclosures um
you know so so there is there is a
strong overlap between
as you know civil rights privacy and
everything similarly ai fairness and
then privacy is also there and then that
is why we need to have explainability
and as
tom pointed out
earlier
we need to determine what bias means
what are the latent bias what are the
explicit and implicit bias in the data
or in the systems
and and
perhaps perhaps
improve the fairness matrix that we have
from just statistical properties to to
properties with respect to
computing
or our
runtime related properties
so
uh
i think i think those are those are
different aspects uh that we need to
address and and governance is important
there and regulatory compliance last
point i'd like to bring out is that
perhaps this this is where the the
government and and the
the federal
uh machinery should come up with
regulatory requirements on what it means
by ai fairness that is for only u.s then
then state rate fairness would change
geopolitical fairness would change over
time and and if you there are the what
is going on right now right the ukraine
um invasion
what do you mean by fairness there you
know there are there are drones that is
being used
uh there are there could be um perhaps
robots on
are they uh are they being tally
operated remotely
okay
are they being operated uh
semi-autonomously or are there
autonomous weapons right
so all those things bring out the
question is are they going to target
civilians
um or are they going to target only
military
targets
so uh so let me let me pause here
and and uh you know
see if there are other questions or
thoughts
you also want to pick up on this of you
know why do we care that ai is fair
i guess i would say we care that ai is
fair for the same reasons we care
about people being treated unfairly you
know we we try not to tolerate that
um and i know in europe you know they've
got this
data in a sense bill of rights and if a
machine makes a decision about you in
europe you at least have the right to
know how that machine made that decision
and that that actually happened
and and so it's sort of
like you would in an ordinary situation
where you're just dealing with people
you have recourse if somebody denied you
for a loan you can pick up the phone and
say hey tell me why i got denied so i
can do something about it and i think at
the lowest level of fairness
ai ought to be constructed so that
there's at least a recourse and a reason
given
anybody just follow i was gonna say
apart the same thing um ai should be
fair because people should be treated
well yeah right because that um
there's an additional
reason i think which is
ai applications are
promising
when
uh at scale right when you've got
massive data sets and you're trying to
get a lot of information to make a lot
of decisions consistently
right that's i i think the the great
promise of ai really is in crunching
through that sort of thing and making
those sorts of decisions at scale um
decisions made at scale are precisely
the sort of thing in human institutions
that are hardest to explain that are
hardest to make transparent and that are
most likely to seem alienating to people
even if you explain it at length right i
mean so
you know even human reasoning at scale
can be very alienated thinking think
about a supreme court decision these are
the best reasoners in the world they'll
spend a couple hundred pages explaining
a decision
um
and it doesn't stop the disagreement
right it doesn't stop the sense of
alienation and so on but you can
mitigate in that some way and i think
the institutions that are going to be
using ai applications to make these
decisions at scale a lot of their
legitimacy rests
on at least having a commitment to
making things fairer right uh or more
transparent even though
you have this scale that is inevitably
going to lead to a kind of
sorts of doubts right and and alienation
i guess i can i can quickly quickly uh
add thinking about what you folks are
sharing is how often i see a gap between
transparency and accountability um so
it's one thing for an institution or an
ai designer to explain every decision
they made where the province of that
data set was from and walk you know a
person through exactly how that system
was constructed and how decisions were
made but transparency in and of itself
doesn't guarantee that that person is
then empowered to say hey i don't feel
like that decision about me was actually
fair i don't feel like that decision
about me was right or even if it is
right that i don't think that that
system is actually how we should go
about making judgments as a society um i
think the simplest example of this that
comes to mind is privacy policies right
like you can imagine a company that has
a really transparent really good privacy
policy but if you need access to that
platform if you need access to that
service in order to apply for a job i
mean do you really have a meaningful
option to opt out of that system so i
think it's always useful to link
transparency and accountability and if
you have one without the other it can
actually shore up power for institutions
as opposed to being a meaningful check
and balance
interesting um you know lindsay you
brought up this question or this state
i think term ai justice
uh as opposed to fairness
um
would you care to elaborate is there a
difference between ai justice and ai
fairness
yeah i'll try and be quick because i'm
so curious uh to hear what the other
folks to my right think um i i do think
there's a distinction um and i think
there's a distinction for a few reasons
so i think that the terms fairness and
justice have um different genealogies in
terms of the how i see them come up um
ai fairness i think when you historicize
this this aspiration for it within
institutions it comes from this earlier
earlier period of actuarial risk
and insurance institutions historically
trying to make decisions about who
should be entitled onto certain access
to goods and resources and opportunities
and then when we look at ai fairness
discourse today it oftentimes takes
these very
mathematical parity-based metrics coming
out of civil rights era legislation and
there's been a tremendous amount of
scholarship that has been critical of
ideas of fairness within civil rights
discourse and yet none of those
criticisms have really been incorporated
and attended to on to the ways ai
fairness is being treated today right so
i think that there's a there's a way in
which um ai fairness discussions are
relying on this very uh computational
quantitative based approach that's
grounded in statistical decision making
that's been criticized outside the field
and it hasn't really attended to those
criticisms i think ai justice has not um
has not received that type of treatment
i don't think it's been co-opted
institutionally in the same kinds of
ways and i think justice has a different
um genealogical lineage as well when we
talk about justice we have to talk about
racial justice or social justice or
environmental justice it connects to a
different set of intellectual traditions
that i think provide more critical
frameworks
and i think justice makes us ask
questions about power it makes us ask
questions about who's included it makes
us ask questions about uh resources and
advantages and disadvantages in a way
that i don't think ai fairness
necessarily provokes us to do
do you want to you look like you're
ready to keep on sure no no no
uh i got lots to say too i think in one
sense i agree with lindsey in one sense
i disagree so i also
want to divide the concepts of fairness
and justice um
i do that and in fact at first it really
puzzled me
why we used the term fair why that came
to be the term that we use to talk about
a.i it's not really a technical term in
philosophy and philosophy we read lots
of books about justice about equality
about freedom we don't really write a
lot of books about fairness actually
it's uh it tends to be treated as a kind
of low budget uh
parochial notion right
yeah i've come to think of that as
actually a
feature rather than a bug when we're
talking about ai because i think a lot
of ai decisions can be evaluated along
one one axis in precisely that way right
um but that does precisely leave aside
questions of justice which i do think of
as as somewhat different um
where i would disagree is i guess i want
to think about justice as bigger
questions about larger institutions in
which ai decisions are embedded
right so in a way
um i think ai fairness is a good
question i don't think ai justice is a
good question but i think the justice of
the penal system is a great question or
the justice of capitalism is a good
question or something like that but i
would want to use justice and those that
set of normative questions for the kind
of bigger framework issues in which ai
decisions are necessarily going to be
embedded right now that doesn't mean
that there isn't going to be an
interesting interaction between the two
i think
oh
did you want to speak up yeah i just one
one comment it's a very nice discussion
audio justice and uh
lindsay and
chris
right so if you look at autonomous
driving
you know uh that is your air justice
actually makes uh makes a lot of sense
uh that if there is a there is a
liability there is a crash
uh who who is liable for that is the is
our you know self-driving system on it
or is the passenger
or the or the driver on the wheel but is
not driving that
or the other person's right so i think
there's a lot of
questions and and can you can you really
uh
trust you know the trustworthiness come
can you trust the explanability of the
of the ai system say that hey this is
why i crashed it you know but what tesla
is telling and this is why my car
crashed
so i think ai justice is a good good
thing good concept to
follow up on
yeah yeah
so here's another um how is you know
fairness related to ai ethics and let me
get chris christopher up for our
philosopher up for that yeah um
uh so philosophers use ethics very
broadly right generally we tend to use
ethics as the giant grab bag in which
almost all sorts of normative questions
fall
maybe not aesthetic questions if you
think aesthetic questions or normative
questions but political questions of uh
political justice questions of
individual virtue uh questions of moral
responsibility
um
uh and so on uh
so i guess i think of
fairness as
one of the ethical dimensions
along which
we can
evaluate really anything at all but i
think particularly when we're talking
about fairness and maybe this would be
one additional thing that i'll say is um
i think generally speaking when we're
talking about fairness
we're not talking about an individual
decision at an individual time we're
talking about repeated decisions over
time
right when um for example in
families or in academic departments
people start to feel like things are
unfair
it's not generally because something
went against them one time it's they
feel like it always goes against them
right if people feel like well i lost
this one but i won the next one people
don't start to feel like the decisions
being made or unfair or people like feel
like they're being heard and then the
next time right um they they get some
influence or something like that so i
think fairness really points to these
iterated decision-making processes and
so within ethics if we're asking about
fairness i think that's really focusing
our concern
on the historical pattern of these
decision making
or the decisions that are being made
which is why for example in compass
right
if it had been a situation where um
african americans felt like uh they were
getting a great fair shake from the uh
uh criminal justice system before the ai
and then all of a sudden there was this
bug with the ai that would have been a
very different situation than feeling
like oh this is just a continuation of
the same problem
right so i think fairness unlike so i
think fairness
focuses our attention on these
historical decisions i think justice
focuses our attention on
structures and structural relationships
i think equality focuses our attention
on what you might call second personal
relationships right where i stand with
relation to you and so on so i think all
of these different
normative terms within ethics are like
different perspectives that you can pick
up to evaluate the phenomenon that
you're trying to um that you're
interested in and so that's why i think
there's a real value in distinguishing
fairness and justice because they get at
these different things and we should be
thinking about both
anybody else want to
chime in on this
you know i'll add a little wrinkle not
to that specific
discussion but when it came to um
you know fairness and justice with
respect to ai there there are generally
two types of
ai systems
some of them are autonomous and some
have human in the loop
and i think
the thing that scares most people are
the totally autonomous systems
where there's
no recourse
um
it's just going to do what it's going to
do
and
at least with human in the loop the ai
system
is
is advising a human who will make the
final decision
now i'm not sure where that goes with
respect to fairness and justice but um i
think there is a distinction there
that is pretty important because
if i have a biased ai system and there's
a human in the loop hopefully that
person might be able to recognize
the cases where it's bad but if it's too
completely autonomous
whether it's a weapon or it's just you
know institutional decisions
that's when things get a little worse i
think a little more scary
we almost want to
let me um since i see time's getting
shorter we've got a lot we still want to
discuss
oh we have a question here yeah so i
have a question about
how much of this is to do with the ai
versus our expectations of it
and i want to point to an example of a
paper that i wrote in 1999 remember that
uh it was called what's related
everything but your privacy and it was a
dissection of a button that showed up in
the netscape communicator version 4
browser no explanation but there was a
thing up there next to your url that
would have a butt said what's related
and if you clicked on it
then it would show you a
list of pages that
alexa decided were related
when you would click on
that button when looking at my paper
describing the what's related button and
the privacy implications and the
consequences of that technology it said
the number one related thing was the
unabomber manifesto
now of course i was outraged but at the
same time it's a no-brainer the
unabomber was warning about technology
run away so you could see how it would
be related but of course then somebody
looks at this and now here i show up i'm
i'm putting my hand up in court i'm i'm
being you know sworn in and all this and
now the other side is trying to destroy
me by saying that well aren't you
related to the unibomb so is this an
expectations problem and is it any
better today than it was
23 years ago
i want to read the papers
i
i'll maybe say one thing about this this
is a uh
may i uh
give me a minute um so uh historical
analogy right uh 18th century prussia
frederick the great pushes out the uh uh
the poison alga minus number the
depression general code right why does
he do this because he hates lawyers
and he thinks if you can just write the
law out clearly everybody will see what
it is and we won't need lawyers anymore
right they'll just they'll go into
something more productive right that's
sometimes i think the kind of
expectation we have about ai if we just
get the coding right the disagreements
would go away
right uh and then we can all be more
productive um but i don't think there's
any better chance that ai will make the
disagreements go away then a properly
written legal code will make lawyers go
away
i might want to just add one thing to
that when we were talking about ethics
and
fairness it's also culturally a little
different and i'll give you a quick
example
um
when i was working for tel labs i was in
charge of human resources and we had
this grand idea that we would have a tel
labs code of ethics
so i went to finland where we had eleven
hundred people working and i said we're
gonna give you this code of ethics and
you would think they'd all be okay with
it they said this was outrageous we
behave like this anyway why do you have
to write it down and tell us
and the other thing was that was you
know maybe a little more stark we
decided that every employee would get
stock options so we went to finland and
we said you're all going to get stock
options even the janitor and anybody is
going to get a stock option they said
you're already paying us we don't want
stock options
so it was pretty interesting just to see
their sense of fairness
was different than ours but it made it
made no sense at first to us until we
kind of got to know how their culture
operated
well i think uh
kind of on on fairness let me bring up
oh did you no i just saw that oh we have
yeah okay
just add one no no
i'd like to anybody can comment but i'd
like to direct the question to tom you
know your corporation the company that
that you're heading right now its core
technology is very ai based and used for
business
can you talk from the commercial side of
some of the challenges that you deal
with in making sure that
the services that you're providing to
other to your customers you know that
you're i'm making assumptions that
you're showing them how it can help them
with business
but obviously underlying is that
sometimes the customer is concerned
sometimes maybe they're not concerned
but your company obviously has to deal
with these fairness and trusted ai
implications of your product how do you
deal with this in the commercials
without getting into too much detail
there there's a whole process that
covers almost everything
that this conference covers it starts
with data privacy we have to ensure them
that we are storing their data
in a secure place
with hat which has encryption etc etc
that the data is encrypted in flight et
cetera et cetera and that only the folks
in our company that need to use that
data can see it
now
as an aside the data makes absolutely no
sense to anybody but they're concerned
okay so we do that
um
then we we we have a a pretty intense
discourse with them about
what the data means
what data might be corrupt et cetera et
cetera and then we go
to the modeling
portion where we have a pretty
rigorous i mean it takes five or six
months of
developing the models
testing them under every circumstance
finding out where the model doesn't work
and then doing um various types of
analyses that allow us to understand
what features
are driving the model and even to get
down to the level of
what features are driving the model in
certain parts of the reactor
because that allows them to take
remedial action if they have to so
it's a it's a process of
continued analysis
understanding
and then once we deploy the model to
them what they do
is there's a human in the loop their
engineers use our software to do
planning where they say okay how many
bundles of fuel do we need to buy what
kind will it be etc and then the system
tells them what that's going to do
within the reactor
and then once that happens we'll we'll
take any new data they give us and test
it against what the model predicted so
it's a it's a process of a lot of
testing
and a lot of deep analysis past the
point where we just give them a black
box model
does that answer your question i think
okay
things yeah things constantly
yeah
yeah things surprise us often because
sometimes they don't tell us everything
like for instance
we did this model that calculated how
much energy they would get out of their
fuel and they said oh by the way we
changed our measuring system 10 years
ago so half the data you have
is off by 20 well that explained why we
were concerned about our answer
and so it's a
it's a constant
kind of making sure things make sense
it's not specifically a fairness thing
it's more of a trust thing
where understanding and accuracy
leads to trust
just to continue with that
trustworthiness
you know
should we
you know why what does it mean to be
trustworthy why do we care is it is it
enough to be just better than what we
had before
or is that not good enough
well i i think that
trustworthiness has a different
level of or a slightly different meaning
when you're dealing with people than
when you're dealing with machines
because
you know if we make a mistake somebody's
gonna lose
a hundred thousand dollars
if a machine makes a mistake about a
person
they're gonna lose the opportunity to
buy a house or a car or maybe even
something worse is gonna happen to them
so i think um
trust in a in an industrial quote
setting is a little different than trust
in a you know where an ai is making
decisions about human beings
what about in your context so is that
you know if
did
if you go and say
you know our predictions are going to be
better than what you had before
is shouldn't that be good enough
well it's it's you know good enough is
never good enough and that's actually
you know what we do we are we constantly
try to improve the accuracy and
the certainty with which these
predictions are made
um
generally that depends on having more
data
i mean we we talk a lot about fancy ai
models and this and that but ultimately
you know 95 of the battle is do you have
the right data and if you interpret it
correctly
if i could chris i just wanna yeah i
just want i think this is such an
interesting example um and i wanted to
bring in back the question of power and
i think when you talk about ai
trustworthiness i think it's an
interesting question like whose trust
are you trying to earn um and who are
the stakeholders that you're trying to
appeal to and i think even thinking
about nuclear power right when you think
about uranium mining and you think about
other communities that are perhaps not
the folks you need to interact with on a
daily basis but thinking about ashish's
point about the entire life cycle of a
model the entire life cycle of the
system are there stakeholders or are
there folks who might feel like their
measure of a system's trustworthiness is
going to be very different than perhaps
the different stakeholders but who are
the people that we're actually asking
whether or not they find the system
trustworthy or not is a question that i
find myself returning to
and we're mainly asking
the people who
use the system and who manage the whole
energy process
and one of the outcomes
of the the things that we do
is they do get to use less fuel which
means there's less waste which means
there's less of a problem downstream in
storing that waste um but no we don't
interact with the uranium miners
although
um
we do interact a lot with the green
energy community who you know the whole
idea of reducing
co2 emissions and from that perspective
you know they they tend to
they're at least interested in what
we're doing if not
giving us their trust
i think to add to this discussion
um you know about the stakeholders and
links they pointed out
um there's a great point that is coming
for about use of decentralized trust
that we are actually ready to
adopt
uh the concept of decentralized trust in
an ai governance
for for trustworthiness of ai and there
are there are certain
startups are there of using blockchain
for
for aifrs and then
yeah trustworthiness
and and also
i'll connect that to something called
supply chain of fairness or supply chain
of trust
and ai uh ai aspect because when you
talk about this
the nuclear waste and related
stakeholders
right how does the supply chain look
like and what does the
related responsibilities lie there
and decision making as well as as well
as in making sure that it is sustainable
and it is and it is the right decision
to make
so
anyone else on that
what about um
you know we talked about these safety
critical systems for trust uh autonomous
vehicles uh nuclear power plants
where else i mean we have things that
really aren't kind of the safety
critical that you know something goes
wrong and people die
where we still need this trustworthiness
from our ai or are there areas where
ai trustworthiness maybe isn't a big
issue
any
ah so i'll just add quickly yeah
quickly there's a lot of work going on
in
healthcare
one is about
drug discovery
right so drug discovery is is an area
personalized treatment is an area where
ai trustworthiness is extremely
important because personalized treatment
where you want to make sure that
you know it is it is fair to everybody
you know it's not treating someone in an
unfair manner but it is also trusted
that it's not going to actually
recommend a drug to someone
or or a group of individuals because if
the system has been compromised through
through data poisoning attacks or
through uh through model poisoning or
something
right and and uh this is where
we need to be we need to see both
fairness and trustworthy how they can
how they can play together
anybody else's
thoughts on this
well i mean i'll just say um
i think in
any situation in which
an ai application is
making a decision
or substantially
influencing a decision trust and
fairness are going to be important
right because
any decision is going to involve a
distribution of costs and benefits
responsibilities and so on
and
even if there aren't strictly speaking
winners and losers for that kind of a
decision there's still going to be
people who wanted it to go a different
way and people who wanted it to go that
way
and as long as it's involved in those
sorts of decisions the
long-term legitimacy
of whatever institution is using the ai
application to make those decisions is
at stake
and the treatment of people within those
institutions is at stake i think
well i mean we're getting close to time
so i'm going to start off with kind of a
final question for each of the panelists
to
what what do you see as the greatest
threat or barrier to
fair
or trustworthiness or justice in
in a.i so let's start here with lindsay
sure uh so i guess i i'd name a few
things i think the first for me is a
lack of interdisciplinarity in general
and i think the way that uh folks who
are trained to build ai systems they're
not necessarily required to talk to
folks with domain expertise from outside
the field
ethics isn't rigorously incorporated
into the education of a lot of folks who
end up building ai systems i think
that's another uh reform that i could
imagine um i also think you know for me
personally i do believe that
diversifying who gets to participate in
the development of these systems and
also giving folks who are oftentimes the
most severely and desperately impacted
more agency more power more control at
all stages of the ai life cycle i think
that those type of changes would would
get us move the needle in significant
kinds of ways yeah
okay
yeah um
expectations right and it's connected to
some of the things lindsay just said um
thinking that ai the successful ai will
somehow be an end run around human
complexity and that's not going to
happen it's going to be a certain kind
of participation in
human complexity and it can be an
improvement of that kind of complexity
but it is not going to be an end run
around it nor should it attempt to do so
you know i i think um
you know the biggest threat i do think
it's also expectations i think there's a
a level of misconception about ai i mean
people they're i mean they're very
bright people who think that uh
the terminator is gonna come here from
the future
uh it's it's really not that capable i
mean at least now and for the
foreseeable future it's a really really
excellent calculator
and
and that's the way you know our team is
our team is all engineers who understand
the systems that they're working on who
use ai as a tool
but in in my realm the biggest threat to
ai is just data understanding data
and using it correctly and understanding
where
the data isn't really going to give you
a result
that is applicable in another regime
that you want it to be applicable in
um
so my experience is kind of in a sense
limited we don't deal with autonomous
systems etc
so i think one of the important
barrier is actually the data
to agree with
tom is that the the way data is
collected curated and
used
for
testing sorry training testing
validation what not right and that and
that also that that is also
um
is a complicated issue when we bring in
regulatory compliance like gdpr
hipaa uh also trying to play uh that
clears data islands you know so and when
we we build models in one data island
and then try to reuse it in another data
island and that that is going to cause
concern about fairness as well as
trustworthiness the second one is
actually bringing regulatory compliance
you know while we are talking regulatory
compliance
not helping
um
ai fairness and transparency but
regulative compliance should be there
under standardization should be there on
how such data is curated and and how
what what do you mean by fairness and
trustworthiness and the third one is a
decent decentralized
model of fairness and trust that is
essential that there are multiple
stakeholders
there should not be any centralized
authority
to to work on that and another work that
is ongoing with us is cisco research on
responsible ai uh we are we are looking
at some of the few of the things here
thank
you well
we're time here and need to move on to
the poster session so let me let's thank
our panelists i think this has been
wonderful
you