today's speaker is a Dr ning Zhang and
he leads the computer security and
privacy laboratory at Washington
University in San Luis and previously he
also work at Raytheon and today today's
talk is about security and privacy in
the Cyber physical world including iot
devices and embedded systems
all right Pennsylvania for the
introduction
um
so the the topic that I'm going to talk
about today is security and privacy in
the Cyber physical world
um my very biased vision of the future
is that we are embracing a brave new
Cyber physical work
uh where everything is interconnected
and the cyberware and physical war is
closely intertwined together
we already we're already witnessing a
whole bunch of life-changing cyber
physical systems from you know voice
assistant to uh AR goggles that can
translate uh you know languages in real
time to 3D printed organs that is has
been used to save lives
however we have also witnessed how uh
vulnerabilities in these systems can
undermine the Safety and Security of its
users
um so my best solution of security and
privacy in the Cyber physical world in
other words our division for our lab is
freefold from the system security fronts
uh which is my background uh we are more
concerned on the security and private
security and safety in the presence of
cyber attacks some of the research
topics that we work on are CPS
availability real-time system security
resilience
software protection in real-time CPS
medical device trust institution
environments
um moving up the step a little bit uh AI
I believe is uh changing many uh
sectors in the society nowadays and we
are also interested in AI security
because it's sitting on top of the
system uh looking at the software uh
algorithm aspects uh so in in this
domain we work on physical realizable
over zero example semantic preserving of
a zero example and malware
um
and on the Privacy fronts uh we are
interested in both the Cyber privacy and
physical privacy in the emerging new
settings uh so I'm going to talk about
our work on spy camera detection
um so I'm going to start a presentation
with the research frost on security and
safety in the presence of Cyber attack
so in this line of work we make the
assumption that attacker can actually
find one abilities and compromise our
system and we think about ways to you
know bring the Lines line of defense in
such that we can remain safe even in the
presence of cyber attacks
um so the first one I'm gonna talk about
uh so from all of the work that I would
talk about in this talk I only give the
brief introduction except the first word
I'll go into the detail
um
for the first work the research question
is how do we secure the emerging safety
critical cyber physical systems even
when the attacker can compromise the
kernel uh can we maintain minimum
control such as you know for example the
Jung taxi can land safely and people can
get out
uh you know play this introduction video
a defining characteristic of real-time
cyber physical systems is their
continuous interaction with the physical
world
for safety functions like pedestrian
detection computation resources have to
be available in a timely manner
sensing control and actuation forms a
control Loop
availability for CPS implies timely
access to computation for control and
timely access to i o for sensing and
actuation
in this paper we present the design of a
real-time trusted execution environment
to ensure system availability
in order to minimize the TCB we Leverage
The observation that control programs in
CPS are predictable by Design
our system trades off Rich
functionalities for minimally yet secure
implementation using hierarchical
scheduling and I O driver deploading
if you are interested in our work please
join us at Essence so that's the
introduction
um as a matter of fact please ask me
questions and make this interactive as
much as possible
or otherwise I will be reading through
my slides for 40 minutes and it's not
very fun so
one of the things that you when you
think about hey I got a normal World
compromise or I have a compromise OS the
first thing you probably think about to
defend against disabled attack is
trusted execution environment
particularly because we're working on
embedded device so it would be Ultra
zone
um
so amtrakzone provides a hybrid assisted
a strong isolation between uh normal
work and secure
however
in existing deployment of Tes most of
the time we shifts uh all the scheduling
and I O to normal work for Simplicity
insecure right we are making this
cautious trade of choice because most of
the scheduling aisle management Resource
Management are complex so we're shifting
shifting all of them to normal work
but for availability it's very important
that we have a trustworthy research
resource scheduling algorithm
um why is availability important in
cyber physical systems uh because it you
know
CPS uh particularly safe criticals
safety critical CPS they have continuous
interaction with the physical world
um in order for for them to function
correctly they need to perform
sentencing control and actuation in a
timely manner for example
if we don't stop the vehicle in time
when we detect a possession then it
might be too late by the time the car
stops
and lastly uh there are you know very
bad or severe physical work and any
consequences for missing computation
deadlines uh in cyber physical systems
um therefore that's why in this
particular world we choose to focus on
um ensuring availability in cyber
physical systems
to further motivate why real-time
availability is important
we develop an attack called
the time whopping attack where we
exploit the dynamic frequency voltage
scaling DVS features in CPU to you know
sort of slow down the processor but you
know still let it run
um the moment we launch the attack you
can see the trajectory on the bottom
left of the figure start going out of
the Baseline and on the right you can
see the absolute error in the post just
skyrocketed and and that would lead to
crashing of the vehicle
so real-time mobility in cyber physical
systems actually implies two types of
availability protections uh the first
one is real-time computation
availability that is for the control
algorithm to run once you sense
something you want to perform
computation on the sense physical stage
so that you know how to control the
actuator right the second part is
real-time i o availability for sensing
and actuation so basically we want to be
able to sense
correctly and actuate the controls uh
the physical control of the robotic
vehicle uh securely
and Tommy our threat model is we assume
arbitrary code execution in normal world
uh we aim to use denial service attacks
to destabilize the Cyber physical system
and um we assume the attacker can deny
access to a processor deny access to IO
in other words deny all the access to
sensor and actuators and disable
peripherals for example disable the
timer and power and a text that we do
not consider a hardware and sensor
attacks side Channel attacks
there are so from rtte system overview
there are three main parts uh Freeman
research questions that we have to
answer the first one is what is the
minimum set of Hardware primitive for
availability
um that is for bootstrapping
availability using resource isolation
and secure timer
the second research question is how do
we ensure CPU availability with small
TCB
um you know one of the easiest thing to
ensure real-time availability is you
know implement re-implement the entire
scheduling system inside the secure
domain but that's going to blow up the
TCB
and the last research question that we
have to answer is how do we ensure
real-time High availability with with a
small TCB because directly migrating the
driver into the secure would also
increase the TCB significantly
so to answer your first research
question uh we look at the basic
requirements of cyber physical system or
real-time cyber physical systems then we
find out that you know there are
basically two things that you need in
order to ensure that you have secure and
timely execution of State safety
critical workloads the first one is a
secure timer
using the secure timer you can trap the
execution from untrusted normal work
back to secure in other words you can
get back your execution rates
the second one is
um resource isolation because you want
to be able to insert yourself into all
the access control to to mitigate all
the access control through the io
reference monitor
that would allow you to perform
fine-grained resource management
so these are the two key requirements
so uh tap on to the secure timer you you
also need to have access to physical
passage of time the reason why we record
we require that is because
um
passage of time is interesting in
computer computer doesn't really have a
concept of physical work type right it
goes by corrupting so you also need the
physical passage of time
but that's part of the secure timer
so given those two primitive how do we
ensure real-time CPU availability
without significantly increasing the TCB
um
if you look at uh existing scheduling
Paradigm uh all the all the scheduling
is done by the normal world
naive implementation is to move the
complex Linux scheduler to the secure
however if you if we do that then secure
work would not only need to know
um its own scheduling contest but also
all the complex tasks structures inside
the normal work kernel and that would
significantly uh increase the complexity
of the secure
uh within this hierarchical scheduling
framework uh then we can
decouple
the real-time responsiveness from the
complexity of the scheduler design
so hierarchical scheduling is a common
way to perform a compositional
scheduling within real-time computing
and we are leveraging this real-time
Computing tool to enable this decoupling
uh there are two levels of uh CPU
scheduler
at the worst scheduler level you have it
the sole purpose of that scheduler is to
decide whether to run the non-secure or
to run the secure right
um and once you decide you hand the
execution right to either the secure
scheduler or the non-secure scheduler
um this way the the work scheduler only
needs to know very basic information
about which word to uh to direct the
control to and and that's it
however it's actually not that easy
there are if you look at it there are
many challenges in terms of
um not having multiple physical Hammer
uh interrupts uh we have a lot more
detail in terms of Designing this policy
based and event-based optimization in
the paper but from a very high level at
design time we need to fit the task
execution model such as
um you know is it periodic task is it
sporadic task the scheduling algorithm
is it Raymond and tonic into this
composition scheduling analysis uh using
the compositional scheduling analysis
you get the word policy which is to get
fed into the work scheduler and the
individuals
uh OS scheduler can can handle their own
OS time once they they got the piece of
the slice of computation uh CPU to x to
the execute
how do we ensure the real-time i o
availability without significantly
increasing TCB that's the first research
challenge
um
within that availability there are
actually multiple smaller challenges for
example uh like I said in the very
beginning if you just migrate all the
driver from normal world to secure then
you could potentially increase the TCP
significantly
um
if if you can um
the current isolation for Te is bus
level such as i2c bus so we don't really
have lower than bus level uh isolation
Hardware enforce isolation that's
provided by trust Zone
um
the real-time property on iO is
um hard to guarantee when you don't
consider the real-time performance and
and priority inversions
because we're limited to 40 minutes so I
will only go through how we solve the
first one and if brief highlight of
about how we solve the rest illness of
the first challenge we Leverage The
observation that if you look at the CPS
sensing and actuation it's actually very
predictable so a predictable means it
always sends the same thing over the
serial bus so we templatize that entire
interaction uh that way we can
significantly reduce the TCB
and um but when you want to tabletize
that that your training of the
expressiveness of the driver with a
smaller TCB but how do you maintain what
happens if we need compressed features
of driver so one of the ways that we did
that is through a splitted kernel driver
which which is a Sandbox to prevent it
from compromising the uh
the secure OS we also implemented the
spatial temporal reference monitor to
ensure uh that you know you cannot
damage the motor or you cannot do
property immersions
to evaluate we build our own drone using
Raspberry Pi 3 as the control processing
board and navigo toolbar is the daughter
board that would you know connect with
other controls
uh we also done this on cortex a use
cortex M using nxp lpc55s69
and we have both physical work
experiments and software in the loop
experiments
um so we we Benchmark them and look at
how they perform in the real world and
we find that rtt actually has has
minimum control impacts
we also look at all the real-time tasks
and we find out that the real-time tasks
have you know none of them exceed the
deadline either when they are protected
by rtte
oh um that that is the rtt end of rdt
you work so after finishing rtte work
because we did the um the time warping
attack so we have noticed that
um your trust zone is not you know
bulletproof once you are able to slow
down its processing things go you know
strange or or it will crush the system
so we ask ourselves like can we use time
as an attack vector
so we did a work where we look at what
happens if we try to mess up the timing
of your control systems
it turns out that we analyze many slam
algorithm slam is for localization we
analyze many of the slam algorithms uh
and we'll find out that you know using
timing attack is actually possible
to crush them and if you look at the
open loop testing on the top right
you'll find that you know when it's
under attack the path deviates
significantly from the Baseline and it
goes to uh you know of course things are
much worse because it's close to testing
therefore you see the impact uh after
each frame it accumulates
what exactly so I I got a question
what exactly are the secure and
non-secure world are they separate OS
um thanks for the question
um so in Armstrong let me go back quite
a bit
so in arm trust uh Armstrong the
terminology is that your regular OS is a
rich OS the OS with tons of
functionality runs on the non-secure
states and
um your secure OS which does just very
limited stuff such as fingerprinting
authentication runs on secure so you can
understand it as two OS running on the
same Hardware
hopefully that answers your questions
okay
um so the the next thing we look at is
you know can we use timing as an
attacker
and we analyze them and find out we can
um you know that's good news for
attacker but bad news for Defender
um but but in that attack we actually
need to do many uh manual tuning and
manual uh investigation and profiling of
the system in order to launch the attack
so we immediately trying to you know we
are computer scientists so can we
automate these attacks
um so in our RT recent rtss work we look
at is it possible to automate the
resource contention based timing attack
um there are three separate research
challenges the first one is
um you know what our complete set of
resource contention channels right
um in our CCS work we basically look at
um cash but there are file system based
there are network based
um and how do we automatically tune the
Primitive of each uh the parameters of
each primitive and the last one is how
do we adaptively select the combination
of different channels you know both
especially in other words in one time
slides which channel are going to use
and you know temporarily in other words
um
for each of the time slides how should
you vary a between the channels you
don't log into one channel right to
maximum maximize data impact so um by
description you can probably tell it's a
very large search space
um so we start tackling this challenge
by solving existing work to look at what
are the performance uh contention
channels right uh interestingly it's
actually very
um closely related to side channels so
we get quite a bit of inspiration from
there and then we develop a free Phase
template attack also inspired by cache
template attack
so the free Phase basically tackles each
of the challenge stage
in the first phase we use genetic
algorithm to automatically find the
right parameter for each of the
primitive and in the second phase we
basically look at our Target that we
want to close performance significance
on and as you know you know let's search
for which Primitives is most effective
and for the last one we use
reinforcement learning to learn the time
series of what primitive we should use
at each stage
and the yellow bar is our attack as you
can see it's significantly better than
just you know bluntly writing memory
um so on the left are our Benchmark
attacks uh so uh disparity MSR and svm
are you know cortex and testing Suites
and on the right we're actually the the
figure shows our attack on an actual
localization algorithm and you can see
our attack using i o model which is the
brown uh tilted slash we're able to
cause deadline misses uh and let me see
in iteration uh 2500.
now with the automatic attack uh we
which you under the previous work we
show that it's possible to do auto to
automate this attack then we ask the
question you know can we defend against
this no if we cannot defend against at
least we should be able to mitigate this
right
um and this work up here in Iris this
year my student was actually
um just presented this yesterday in
Kyoto
um
so on the picture you can see four
trajectories top left is without uh you
know no resource constraint uh there's
no timing anomaly
um top right and bottom left uh the
resource constraint performs in The
Yards there are uh resource contention
due to platform resource uh limited
performance resources and you can see
the structure is all out of whack and
using our mitigation on the bottom right
you can see all the trajectories remain
uh somewhat aligned with the Baseline
now in order to go into how we were able
to design this mitigation step uh we
need to understand that in Slam
algorithm there's a front end and back
end and uh through our analysis we find
out that most of the tech was able was
uh successful because it was
desynchronizing front-end and back end
so uh our mitigation on the timing
attack is uh we perform online
adaptation
where the online adaptation
basically made a specifically a pig
samples that are temporarily aligned
with each other
um but then how do you know how many to
pick so we use an AI model to predict
um
what is our coming budget and how much
we are delaying
and the outcome as you can see at the uh
1 000 millisecond tick or 100 minutes
can take 10 points we start launching
the attack uh you can see on the bottom
left the the purple one uh purple line
is the response time uh without our
mitigation and the green line is worth
and hours performed significantly better
and on the bottom right you can see the
diagram where it shows that using our
mitigation step we are able to mitigate
the timing attack or at least timing
anomaly
so with that uh I just went through our
research on system security of cyber
physical systems I'm going to pause here
and take any questions if there's any
nope okay
um so I have about 40 minutes left
um uh you know I would just talk about
one word in our emerging uh in our
privacy line of work
um this one is in this year's ccs and we
are developing a usable spy camera
detector
um so spy camera actually has been a
real world
uh physical privacy thread uh as you can
see from all the news uh and Airbnb was
uh you know equipped with many spy
cameras so we asked ourselves you know
what does my camera look like uh so we
went out and purchased every single spy
camera on Amazon and this is the
collection as you can see
um so some of the spy cameras they are
disguised as Electronics some of them
are disguised as photo frames
um
keep this in mind because it's important
to for our solution
existing approach generally use either
if so for many of the spy cameras
because they are Wi-Fi enabled spy
cameras so of course if you look at if
you move around
um Wi-Fi actually transmits packet
because you know it detected moving
stuff and the move uh and the video
stream compression changes right so that
would allow you to correlate the event
um but then you know this is great but
um what happens to some of the spy
cameras that doesn't transmit uh in our
Market survey where we purchase all the
spy cameras we find that many of them
you know actually doesn't transmit about
40 if I recall correctly
um
the other approach is using a red light
to flicker around and hopefully the the
camera lens will reflect back the light
to you so you can see a flashing Dot
um so this also works great
um but sometimes you need to know where
to look at because the reflection is
um you know works very well when you're
directly against it but when you're like
at a tilted angle it's a lot more
difficult to spot so you need to have
expertise
um then then we'll come up with the way
we say you know geez I mean um
a photo frame shouldn't be shouldn't
have hit on right uh what's going on so
so we said you know let's use thermal
emissions
um so as you can see from the picture
um not only does those photo frames that
are supposed to heat up uh heat up but
also if you look at things that is
supposed to heat up it's actually much
hotter because
um it's you know you need to process all
the video and save them in SD cards and
one of the interesting thing that we
teach the machine learning algorithm to
learn is that if you think about the
packaging of the product right
um in order to be stealthy you need to
keep the original external packages
right but you need to fit extra extra
Electronic Component inside that changes
the heat distribution of the case so if
you look at the case the heat
distribution pattern you'll find that
side cameras is quite unique
so um in order to you know because I
mean not everybody knows those Pat what
those pattern looks like so in order to
make this particular tool more usable by
the general public and we develop a
neural network to try to recognize those
patterns because you know AI is very
good at recognizing patterns
and we because it's a data driven
approach uh we actually collected large
amount of photos
um we are making this repository uh
available for the community so please
please contact us and make use of the
data sets
uh now so besides privacy we're also
interested in looking at you know the
algorithm level vulnerabilities of the
Cyber physical world
um so I'll highlight two work that we've
done here uh one is this we're
realizable of zero uh example audio
examples and then uh semantic preserving
audio examples
um in this uh in this paper called when
it will cost targeted advers0 what is
over IP
um we're asking the research question of
how does new connectivity in the
physical world impact the iot system
security
foreign
has reshaped our life forever uh like it
or not you know right now we are very
used to zoom and delivering a talk with
your Zoom I can you know
three years ago I wouldn't think this is
possible I wouldn't think this is wrong
um but now it is so
um you know every audio samples has been
around for quite a bit so you know our
group was asking oh geez is it possible
to deliver F0 audio through Zoom then
you sort of have this teleport system
that can deliver or have a zero audios
you know you don't need to be not right
next to it anymore
um it turns out that yes it's possible
because we were able to do it but on the
other hand it's actually much harder
um because
um
for all the voice over IP Solutions uh
you actually need to go through a whole
bunch of processings including encoding
decoding transmission sometimes package
job uh and and you know in order to
optimizing performance many of the voice
over IP Solutions actually decided to
filter out the frequencies that is not
important for human to hear
um but it's actually very important for
our zero examples because we inject in
places that can maximize the deviation
probability once it reached the decision
boundary right
um now we also find out there's a whole
bunch of noise uh that we weren't
expecting because it's supposed to be
completely digital uh turns out that
there are many noises in
um the uh encoding and decoding process
and also uh the entire pipeline so we
did a whole bunch of reverse engineering
to understand them and we designed a
query based system to come up with
adversary examples
um we've performed attack on four of the
popular voice assistants including you
know Amazon Echo uh over all types of
video conferencing software
um you know generally if over the Lions
have we only need uh only 100 and 500
queries so that's that's quite fast
um we are able to also demonstrate it's
possible to perform all the error attack
without getting highlighted because I
mean one of the things uh in Zoom is
that when you talk Zoom highlight you
but if I'm the attacker I really don't
want you to highlight me because I am
sending the attack right I don't want to
get attributed so we look at it's
possible to hide just below the speaker
volume and you know play baby crying or
play the car driving by or play the
sirens
um so uh the website is right there if
you're interested please go on to the
website you can hear some of our several
examples
um there's a baby crying that embeds a
malicious comment
now lastly you're probably going to be
asking a question of uh geez now you can
of course you can deliver a zero audios
but how about voice authentication
um you know and and also I mean car horn
is pretty obvious
um you know then we asked ourselves can
we do better in terms of making
ourselves more stealthy and the solution
we come up with is uh semantic
meaningful adversarial audio attack
um so in this particular work uh it it
just got accepted to using security uh
the 2023 and
um we aim to use semantic adversarial
audio to attack the ASR and Sr so the
transcription system and the speaker
recognition systems
uh so different and previous work a
little bit uh instead of traditional LP
base so you just inject voice into the
entire Spectrum uh we do semantic
perturbation so you'll probably asking
what is semantic propagate uh
perturbation right
um so in this particular case we look at
porosity and porosity is a semantic
feature so it's something like are you
angry how fast are you talking you have
accent and things like that I'm going to
have an audio sample that you can listen
to uh in a bit and I just want to show
this diagram because I want to show you
in order to change a tune tune to from
you know anger to happy you actually
need to change a whole bunch of things
across the temporal spec it's not just
one point or two points and that's what
makes it hard so we come up with
um a generative method to combine the
original audio and the processing
manipulation Vector to create this type
of
porosity natural
semantic meaningful adversarial examples
and I just want to show quickly what
does it look like so to human is
supposed to listen as uh wipe the floor
but machine it says it's open the door
we'll play again
and this is also wipe the floor but it
says what I want to share
bite the floor right so it shows like
two changes I mean to human it sounds
almost exactly the same it's exactly my
tongue is different my mood is different
but to machine is it's quite different
um
and lastly I just want to highlight our
ongoing work uh called opcps open
platform for cyber physical systems
security research uh within this
um so at what Shield we have a whole
bunch of cyber physical systems that we
built ourselves uh we work with
hospitals and
um we're trying to aggregate all the
stuff because one of the key challenge
of cyber physical system research
um this lack of system to the physical
thing and
um we want to be able to
allow remote access into this physical
system so that we can conduct system
research on top of it if you're
interested please talk to me uh I'm
trying to get this started but again it
doesn't have to be my thing it should be
a our thing
and lastly I I sincerely want to thank
all my students
um you know these are brilliant work
with my students without them none of
this would be possible and I also like
to thank all the funding agencies uh
including NSF DHS uh Ambitions office
and
doe and lastly washu for supporting me
um
thank you so much and I'm going to take
questions
um my question is in your first work so
you mentioned that you have the kind of
word scheduler right so I'm going to top
up the
the normal and a secure work right so
this scheduler I mean is supposed to be
protected
yes the work scheduler is in the secure
world so it's uh within the traffic base
it's a soon to be secure okay and if the
work schedule is broken then we're you
know there's no security guarantee okay
so it's insecure word yes okay yes
anything on the right is unsecure so
including the secure World OS schedule
yeah we have Implement our own secure OS
scheduler it's fairly simple but clearly
the more complex uh you go with the
scheduling algorithm in the secure yeah
the the more complex the TCB is yeah
another question that I'm just curious
so you mentioned this a spy camera right
so and also you show the picture that
there's the there's a lamp yep
and the looks like their camera is right
on the right in the middle yes right so
you're trying to detect the heat do you
think that's going to be difficult
because um yeah it's supposed to be heat
yeah yeah
um that's a very good question uh in
Everest environment where it was
originally it was generating a lot of
heat
um heat heat itself should not be the
only determination so that's why we use
the neural network to train to recognize
patterns so um but you know if you see a
light bulb that's not evenly heated and
you know on the side it's heated and
then in the middle there's a ring that
is cold and the center again there's
another heating spot then some you know
it's not a normal rifle okay so yeah and
then you're yeah
it's off it's a it's a it's easier to
detect all right yeah it's fairly easy
for the new one that could detected
I mean until people use those type of
weird levels all around then it's a
different story yeah that's a good idea
yeah
so I I guess I lost that but for the for
the
hidden camera detection yeah
so what's the equipment you need to use
to do the things so so we have uh uh
um the thermal camera plugin into the
phone uh the thermal camera plug-in is
about 200 dollars
and you can plug it in a normal phone
yeah yeah USBC
interesting they have both uh the
Android version and the iPhone version I
have both
really yeah yeah I I see a lot of these
things actually so they use that thermal
camera to check your you know the
temperature the the some leakage from
your windows your doors yeah yeah so so
you know because we were like
um you know thermal it's always there it
doesn't matter what angle you look at it
so we're like let's use thermal then you
know we really don't need to tune at the
right angle and when I say we're still
able to pick them up I mean there are
definitely limitations uh if you put
them right next to the stove and you
know probably not gonna happen
uh looks like we have a question here um
how were the malicious commands to The
Voice Assistant developed were they made
with machine learning
um yes yes so uh we have two work uh the
first one is curry base inquiry base we
basically
um use Kirby
uh using the query result we estimate
the gradient and we try to push the zero
sample across the boundary right
um in the second example we use a
generative neural net to gen to
synthesize the voice of different types
of you know tune and possibly
so yes we did use ml to create those
thank you
okay I don't see any other questions but
uh yeah uh Professor Shang thank you so
much really appreciate you coming here
and we're so happy to have you here to
visit us on campus um
thank you it's my pleasure great thanks
thanks