all right well let me let me welcome uh
all the attendees to our security
seminar uh this week
we once again are fortunate to have
a really distinguished speaker to uh
present to all of you
um i've known our speaker bob gurley for
over a decade
um and he has a long career
in the field
including serving for a while as the
chief technology officer
of the defense intelligence agency
which
you may or may not know about
but it is one of the major intelligence
agencies in the u.s government
and
chief technology officer is certainly an
important role there but he's done much
more than that he's run consultancies
he's uh a speaker on the
the circuit in very many many places yes
strategist and analyst uh that many seek
out for his opinion
uh he recently is part of starting up an
organization called uda
which is uh based on the ooda loop
concept and if you're not familiar with
that you can look it up on wikipedia
but it's basically for strategic
intelligence in cyber and security
generally
and it's uh i hope it's off to a very
successful start bob
but today he's going to be talking to us
about a big theme defending the
metaverse from the fearsome five threats
so he'll be telling us about both the
metaverse and what those fearsome five
threats are
uh when you have questions please post
them in the q a and you'll get to them
either during or after his talk
so without further ado
bob
please enlighten us
well thanks staff and i really
appreciate that a very kind introduction
i wanted to say um that i started my
cyber security career
uh well i started defending information
from 1982 when i became a navy
intelligence officer but i really
started my cyber security career when i
was helping the department of defense
defend their computers and networks at
jtf cnd joint task force computer
network defense
in late 1998
and so in doing that we had to learn
quick a lot of things by the experts
who'd come before us and that included
learning from staff
was critically helpful being able to
learn from staff and
learn the many things he was teaching
others also the things he was saying to
congress and others in the executive
branch including congressional testimony
where he defined what a secure computer
is and i hope that that is one thing
that everybody is taking away from your
education today the definition of a
secure computer uh in spas words because
it really resonated with me and ever
since then i have never talked about
computer security the same way i talk
about reducing risk and becoming
resilient
but in starting this off i wanted to say
something that spaff missed from my bio
that i'm most proud of
is i'm a continual learner i love to
learn
new technologies new approaches new
defensive methods
new ways of analyzing information and if
you're in the cyber security space
there's always something to learn
and i also wanted to say this i don't
want this to sound too gloomy i also
learned from my mistakes and there's
been a lot of mistakes
and some of my mistakes
were huge and some of them were
collective big large scale mistakes that
a whole generation of people made and if
i think if we can examine some of those
in this brief it may help us think
through how to better defend in the
future
so with that i want to start with a
quote
listen to this i think it's good context
for what we're going to talk about
it's a letter and the letter starts
i have the desire to do what is good but
i cannot carry it out
for i do not do the good i want to do
but the evil i do not want to do
uh that letter was uh from over 2 000
years ago
it's from saint paul in his uh letters
the romans but i mentioned that because
i feel similar things about the internet
we never wanted the internet to be evil
all of us in the early days were
thinking this is a true force for good
it's going to push back on the dictators
and push back on the communists and
information wants to be free and it's
going to help all of us be more free
and i think the internet is a good thing
i'm really an optimist and i love it but
it did far more evil than i want than we
wanted
and i want you to keep that in mind as
we talk about the future of the
metaverse so with that let me get into
it here and i'll tell you what i mean up
front um about the metaverse we think of
the metaverse as the next wave of
internet technologies there have been
three waves and i'll talk about those in
a little more detail on the next slide
but this coming wave
i wanted to underscore
there's no indication it's going to be
any more secure than the previous two
waves so keep that in mind
we need it to be secure and it's not
um there it can be more secure if we as
the cyber security community get more
involved i'm sure of that so part of the
purpose of this brief is to capture the
essence of the metaverse what it's going
to be and then we can start a dialogue
on how to secure it
now what are these three waves of the
internet
think of the first wave as that
beginning internet it's interoperable
computers an interoperable comms
protocol it's the the killer app was
email
but also web pages
web browsers where you can click and go
from one link to another
there was the establishment in the first
wave of e-commerce sites where you could
buy things and shop from home at least a
little bit
and then companies were building web
apps for the first time where you could
use the internet and then interact with
the business uh
in some ways this first wave was almost
100 percent
fixed line communications either
copper cable or a phone line or
sometimes fiber optic if you're lucky
but it's mostly it's fixed line
communications in that first wave
we still live with a lot of the first
wave today uh the pc's on your desk the
a lot of hardwired systems
all of the e-commerce didn't go away
it's been modernized but we're still
living with the first wave and of course
email
will probably always be with us but the
second wave was really a revolution and
the second wave of computing let's i
mean of the internet
from about 2010
until today
was the mobile revolution so
because there was uh cell data and
advanced wi-fi and other mobile coms
there could be high data rate to
smartphones and with the regular phones
but then smartphones also and tablets
and laptops and it really did make a
difference along with this second wave
came this
massive need to move a video and
pictures that everybody was taking with
their mobile devices
so streaming midi media was part of the
second wave as was the internet of
things
and the second wave as you can imagine
still
relied on interoperable communications
but increasingly this was via very smart
well-designed cell communications that
could deliver high bandwidth streaming
video to a mobile device
but also wi-fi
especially the
secure
wi-fi for enterprises
now we're starting to move into the
third wave all of the second wave is
also here with us but the third wave is
this thing that people are calling the
metaverse it's a shared
interoperable virtual world where
there's a trust layer for store of value
and there's persistence for your actions
so this user persistence will give you
new capabilities
online in these virtual worlds so it's
not just the
the first two waves of the internet it
is those but also now an ability to be
in the internet
that's what i think of as the context
for this metaverse
um another point now is um this is a
very dynamic area
and if someone asks you for a specific
definition of the metaverse uh don't pin
yourself down i think that's going to
evolve because this is a very dynamic
and chaotic a period
but we can't frame it and kind of say
what this thing seems to be
um
broadly
the metaverse is a massive
infinitely scalable
shared virtual world
where land and buildings bots avatars
and other property can be bought and
sold and persist
i think of it as a future computing
environment the metaverse is not here
today
but we're seeing hints of what the
metaverse will be if you and i have a
slide coming up in just a second that
shows some of what uh
current metaverse capabilities look like
um but you think of all of this uh
current stuff converged and
interoperable and interconnected
and all of that being easy to exchange
interoperable value across
if you want an example of what this
could be like you can turn to science
fiction the term metaverse came out of
science fiction um snow crash was a very
famous science fiction novel that
motivated a lot of us in the 90s because
it was very forward-looking and frankly
painted a dystopian picture of a future
world that we do not want
but it motivated us to build a better
idea of a metaverse
but the term metaverse did come from
this book snow crash
and you can also turn to science fiction
movies like uh the book
ready player one and the movie ready
player one gives a fantastic glimpse of
what could be coming um in the metaverse
now i mentioned
it's not here yet but it's clearly
coming and we have seen hints of what
this is already of course we all saw uh
in the summer of 2021
uh mark zuckerberg declared that
facebook is a metaverse company and he
changed the name of his company to meta
and that brings a lot of attention to
this and it says uh really that
something big is coming i don't mind
telling you however that a lot of us are
saying
we don't really want facebook defining
the future of the metaverse
for a lot of reasons that's my opinion
anyway but still it is coming
hints of what the metaverse is i list a
couple on this chart uh there's
incredible business collaboration tools
available today where you can get into a
3d environment with virtual avatars of
your peers and others that you want to
collaborate with in a business
environment and there's dozens of these
kind of tools that are really working
now what about zoom like this
this is a hint of the coming virtual
environment it's a virtual interaction
now very basic still and not the
advanced sci-fi stuff that
is coming but it's a hint of a
distributed system where we can all come
together and exchange information
and a lot of folks are getting exposed
to this because of the online
environment for schools today
and of course the pandemic just taught
everybody about zoom another place where
we have seen hints of what is coming is
the gaming environment
roblox being one of the most famous of
fortnite
there are many many many others but
fortnite is so special
because you can create an avatar
and interact with others now the reason
why i say that is not the metaverse is
it doesn't scale you can have
20 million people watching a concert but
you can't interact with all 20 million
of those other people uh you are still
in a limited domain of who you can
interact with but still it's a hint of
what is coming and it's pretty exciting
then there's the online virtual worlds
places where you can buy land and you
can buy property like a decentraland is
one of the most famous and uh sandbox is
another
for ten thousand dollars you can buy a
little plot of land uh maybe it's
fifteen thousand today i need to check
there's several others like this where
you can buy land you don't have to buy
land to interact in there uh you can go
and just be a virtual avatar and you can
buy things if you want to or interact
with other people play games
it is kind of like second life
but
uh interoperable and distributed
and you can own pieces of that
other
indications of what the metaverse is
going to be can be seen in things like
pokemon go where that's a blending of
the physical world and the virtual world
through artificial reality
definitely there's going to be a
component of that in the metaverse
on the business side again the
manufacturing world and in cities
there's this concept of digital twins
give me a complete digital replica of a
machine or a city or a ship and i can
operate that and see if i have a better
idea for a better design or detect when
a failure is coming this is definitely
going to be a key uh piece of the future
metaverse now the metaverse does not
have to be something you enter with
goggles on you can enter the metaverse
by watching a a website or watching
something on your mobile device but for
the best experience people are wearing
uh the the devices like the oculus rift
of course for the gaming devices some of
the best are the commercial solutions
like magic leap and hololens and these
are giving us hints of what the coming
metaverse is going to be
as for the exchange layer of value
there's the web 3 revolution still very
early in
its age still a lot of issues with web 3
a lot of fraud a lot of criminal
activity but the promise is huge i'm a
huge believer in the future of web 3 and
i believe this is going to be the
interoperable store of value connecting
all of these metaverses together
other use cases include things like
remote medicine where through metaverse
type technologies you can get better
healthcare through your medical
professionals virtually
and participate in all sorts of kind of
um
appointments throughout with the medical
community some things you have to go in
for you have to get poked and prodded
you have to get blood samples drawn uh
you have to have things like that done
in person but a lot can just be the um
the interview be a remote medicine so
these are some of the things that we see
coming
today that are already here today
they're giving us hints of what's in the
future
now uh let's talk about the future
i'm really excited about this and i
really think this is going to change a
lot of how humanity works and plays
together
we will live work and play an
environment where
all of these interoperable technologies
work on top of the existing internet and
it gives us an ability to have
persistent
interactions with each other like we can
be there leave and come back and um
things
our avatar is still there continues to
live we can have a second
entity where we live
we can do this
with billions of other people not today
this could be decades from now but
eventually a shared persistent
simulation accessible by everyone at the
same time and again i do think this is
decades from now
another point
every major company is going to have a
metaverse strategy most of them are
forming metaverse strategies already um
and this includes all the big it
companies but soon every company will
have a metaverse strategy what's the
size of this industry um estimates vary
um i think it's a trillion dollar
industry and i think it's sooner of ice
later
and one of the reasons i say that is of
course the facebook announcement but
all the major i.t companies are
investing in the metaverse
and money's being made there right now
so this will be a trillion dollar
economy let me show you how one um
financial firm and an individual
matthew ball describes this
matthew ball has been studying the
metaverse for quite a while and he
captures the following components shown
on this slide
as being the places where there will be
companies
serving in this space of course
companies will build the hardware and
they will offer the compute services
there will be the coms fabric the
virtual platforms are built by companies
like epic or unity 3d
um and the many developers on top of
those the uh tools to build these
capabilities of are also like
you know epic and unity 3d payment
services will be that interoperable
store of value that is going to really
be huge
there's a lot of services around the
metaverse
already i mean for a decade there have
been people making their livings in
virtual environments building tools or
building clothes
and selling those in virtual
environments and these kind of content
services will grow so all of these are
the kind of things that matthew baldwin
are saying
are part of the metaverse economy and
this is what gets us to a trillion
dollar economy so very exciting but this
is all just background
it's background to get to where us we
the cyber security community
can start talking about the threats and
how to mitigate some of these risks
because as i mentioned
a big regret regret being part of this
wave of
the first wave of internet technologies
is
we were a little naive
some of us were
to the fact that the internet uh had so
many faults
we knew there were security problems and
we kept trying to address them and we're
still trying to address them
and we thought it was going to push back
on these dictators and bad guys and evil
doers and it really hasn't they have
pushed back themselves and used the
internet for tools of bad
so it's time for us security folks now
to think about this next wave the
metaverse
i list here what i think the big five
threats are
um i don't have a full solution although
after this i want to talk about a
framework that might get us towards a
solution but first let me review what i
think these threats are one
new
privacy threats because of the metaverse
think of surveillance by corporations
and by criminal groups and hostile
nations as well as just common
fraudsters
imagine a time when your digital life is
online
it's already online there's already more
of you online than it should be
but now
imagine even more of you is online and
whether you realize it or not you're
being watched and your avatar is being
watched when you're not there it's being
watched 24 7 365 to see what it will
reveal and it's being watched in a way
to see what your desires are
so you can they can better market to you
or better flip you or turn you
uh or better deceive you
so this is a serious serious threat with
the coming metaverse here's another that
now this is not simply in the domain of
cyber security professionals or even i.t
professionals it's something that
humanity needs to think about and that's
mass langer
this uh
inner new wave of the internet the
metaverse is so fun
i love it already imagine when it's
almost like reality um and you get these
super realistic simulations
imagine the effect on your dopamine and
your indoor and oxycontin imagine the
triggers and how much you're going to
love being in the metaverse uh all of us
so this um
is a threat that is some of us will
never want to leave and we will
reject those that try to pull us out of
this
um and so there's a worry there will
this contribute to society's mental
weakness and downfall
we need to think about that the next one
the uh owner afrinia
this is a well-studied state of mind
when people lose the ability to
determine what is real and what is not
and this already happens a lot to people
because of the virtual worlds that we're
in and the massive continuous
bombardment of misinformation and
disinformation the fear is that the
metaverse is going to make
misinformation and information even more
impactful and so we cyber security
professionals need to think about this
and how we can mitigate that threat
fraud
will be with us for as long as they're
human beings i'm sad to say
and the metaverse is probably going to
inject a lot of new fraud vectors
uh companies and communities need to
build in
uh trust and the bad guys want to
violate that trust and the more they
violate it the worse it's going to be
for communities
and we the security folks need to
participate in finding ways to improve
trust and protect the digital value of
the metaverse and keep the fraudsters
from stealing money from individuals and
companies and communities
i mentioned the last one here because
this is something all of us need to be
thinking about just about everybody in
humanity needs to think about this
the internet has in many ways uh
unleashed demons that should not have
been unleashed um
bringing like more bad people together
in ways where they can secretly conspire
to do their bad stuff
the
worst of it the child pornography
criminals murderers
drug runners
slave traders they all use the internet
terrorists use the internet
imagine now
the metaverse
and imagine that unleashing even more
demons and then there's the other demons
that we work so hard
to train people on things like
the importance of fairness
and equality
and justice
and the rule of law and applying to
everybody equally and
pushing back on things like misogyny
well we've already seen cases where
in 3d virtual environments
people have done bad bad things that
they never i'm sure never would have
done
if they knew that
they they could be
they were being seen
but they get in the metaverse and it for
something triggers on them i don't know
what it is but there have been cases of
horrible misogyny in interactions in the
metaverse
there's actually been a case of a
groping in the metaverse where a woman
says she was felt because of the haptic
device she was wearing and
of many disgusting examples of things
like that
we security people i think should play a
role in figuring out how to mitigate
this although we're not the only ones
everybody has to play a role in this but
we security people might be able to play
a critically important role in
mitigating some of that
these are what i think the five big
threats are now what's the solutions i
don't know
but i do know this we security people
learned a lot of lessons over the last
25 years and we should contribute to
finding solutions
and i think a lot of the old lessons
apply
but we got to find some new
solutions also
so my
concept and suggestion and i would love
your thoughts and feedback questions on
this too
is that we need a feedback i mean a
framework we need a framework for us to
be able to lay all of our thoughts out
and think what is the right thing to do
let me show you um
one idea for a framework
i believe we can establish a framework
for metaverse security
that's based on entities
this
entity-based framework for metaverse
security will help us ensure that the
right things are being done at the right
level to mitigate some of these risks
and here's what i mean by entities
i think the entities that need solutions
are individuals we our friends
everyone in all of humanity as
individuals there are things we need to
do
communities
i hope most of the goodness in the
metaverse is going to be delivered by
communities coming together well there's
things communities should do to mitigate
some of these threats
companies that makes the world go around
they deliver a lot of value
companies should help mitigate some of
these threats
governments especially
open governments in good countries
should help mitigate threats
uh and there's things
that we can spell out for them in a
framework and of course academia where
there's so much brain power and talent
and future focused thinking
there are things that they can do to
help
secure the metaverse
i have a few ideas on each of these now
as i go through these ideas i wanted to
pause and take a breath and say as you
have questions
please type them into the q and a box
because we'll have time at the end of
this
to discuss and answer these questions
anything that you type into this
we will get into
all right
back to the framework
individuals there's a lot that we as
individuals can do to
reduce threats to ourselves
and to others here's a few of my
recommendations
i think that we as individuals need to
learn all of us
about the new cryptocurrencies and how
cryptocurrencies can be protected and
how cryptocurrencies can be stolen and
how fraudsters try to trick you out of
your cryptocurrencies
we need to learn about cryptocurrency
wallets and the different kinds of
wallets
there's online wallets
called hot storage because they're
connected to the internet
and then there's offline storage offline
wallets called cold wallets which are
not connected to the internet extremely
secure
but both have strengths and weaknesses
also we as individuals need to keep
learning our security fundamentals uh
you need to protect your home computer
and your home networks because um that's
just fundamental if you have an
adversary that gets into your home
computer and they steal your credentials
and steal your logins you know it's it's
you're the weak link in the chain
we as individuals also need to
continually learn privacy best practices
our privacy will always be under attack
and there's just new methods of attack
all the time so this needs to be a
continuous process i think we as
individuals need to think through
pseudonymous accounts for the meters
we might want
multiple different personas depending on
what we're doing now this is easier said
than done because what we need is not
just personas that are pseudonymous and
cannot be tracked back to us
but can never be revealed in the future
and that is tough why
if you have a different persona for your
gaming personality a different persona
for your um news reading personality a
different persona for your concert going
personality
and then your a real name for your
business work and
community volunteer work
those five are all linked to the same
geography and you know it is knowable
that all five of those are the same if a
government really wants to dig into that
um it can be discovered
and then you know all of that work
you've done to build different
pseudonymous accounts is all for not
because it's all connected so we need to
think about this i'm a huge believer in
pseudonymity
but we need to understand
that there's risk that that can just all
be rolled back
i think we as individuals need to
develop our expectations
for the communities we work with and
also our expectations for companies
we need to be informed users of the
metaverse and be able to tell
communities and companies what we want
and in open societies the way it's
supposed to work is we are supposed to
tell the government what we want them to
do so we need to think about our
requirements for the metaverse and what
we want the government to do in the
metaverse we also want to tell the
government what we don't want them to do
in the metaverse
and so we need to think about our
requirements there and expectations
there's a lot we need to learn about the
metaverse before we get into it so
that's why i mentioned here know before
you go
as individuals you really need to study
up on the platform you're joining in the
metaverse and know about it and i talk
about these other things like mass
langer
i think we as individuals are the ones
that have to stop that for ourselves and
you do that through exercising and
developing self-discipline
that's that's
thoughts on some of the things for
individuals but now let's talk about
communities as i mentioned
i hope that as communities that really
develop the metaverse and bring the
metaverse to reality
because communities are groups of people
coming together to to do things that
they want to do
and
there's a lot communities can do to help
secure the metaverse
i think it's at the community level
where we need to find more ways to limit
misogyny and limit bullying and cut down
on fraud and
manipulation of people
i think the community level is an
extremely important role because
communities can involve users and ensure
strong feedback loops
when
users deviate from expected norms
including sanctions or removing from the
community and keeping a good community
free of the worst evils of our nature
at the community level
this is also a place where we can
develop common interoperable standards
especially for things like store of
value i think it's going to be something
like ethereum but whatever it is the
communities need to agree upon that and
that should be
their role i think
communities do a lot of design work and
they do that in open collaborative ways
the best of them do
and these open collaborative communities
that's where security should be built in
at the very beginning
communities also have a role in auditing
and testing themselves
and that should occur at that level
and then
communities also need to i hope address
this issue of owner
owner afrinia um easy for me to say
owner frenia
because
here it's a tough one we want
communities to respect privacy we really
do
but
it would be great if communities had a
way of detecting if a person
has
mental issues
and is becoming something that they
shouldn't be in the real world
i don't have the answer to this i'm just
saying i'm hoping communities can play a
role in
that let's talk a little bit about
high-level recommendations for companies
hey companies exist to deliver value and
i really believe that this is
a key component of the metaverse
companies should be able to make profit
and that's great as long
as that's not at the expense of society
and not at the expense of our personal
privacy and not at the expense of
communities that we many people will be
volunteering time to build
so a high level recommendation for
companies
understand
that profit is great but do not
do that at the expense of communities or
personal privacy
companies should also of course build
security and privacy protections in at
the beginning well we've been saying
things like that for decades
and
i'm always the naive and hopeful one and
i think oh finally they're going to
start doing that but really for them to
do that we're going to have to keep an
eye on them and keep the pressure on
them to do it we being individuals
communities and governments
companies have a great opportunity to
test their solutions through red teaming
adversarial um
exploitation of their systems to see how
secure they really and truly are
a company should also work with users
and communities to reduce risk to
privacy
and reduce the ability of criminals to
operate in their part of the metaverse
just some ideas now let's talk about
high level requirements and
recommendations for government
i believe that we as individuals should
encourage the government
to take these kind of steps
if we really want to reduce security
we need governments to
help incentivize the companies and
communities to build that security in
early
we also need governments to help find
ways to track and mitigate hostile
intelligence services in the metaverse
they're already there by the way
there's already indications of hostile
espionage occurring in these early
metaverse worlds
there's also indications of hostile
governments
using the metaverse already
for propaganda purposes
um and this is a threat that really in
our society governments should be
tracking and informing us on because
it's hard for individuals and companies
and communities to detect and mitigate
that
well government has a role in mitigating
the hostile intelligence services
there's also a role for law enforcement
but it needs to be the right role of law
enforcement you know
we don't want
the metaverse to become a surveillance
tool for the fbi for example
but we don't want bad guys to be able to
run through what we're doing and use it
for their gain either so what's the
right role for law enforcement
in fighting crime especially
international crime in the metaverse
one thing in open societies in all
societies we really need to push for is
staying on the side of human rights and
privacy when it comes to the government
because
the first thought for many might be to
overreact and overreach and say because
there's threats i will surveil
everything and that's not what we want
we don't want the government to become a
bigger threat to privacy than they
already are and we also want governments
everywhere to understand and respect
human rights because we're the humans
governments can also share threat
information and i think that's a key
part of their framework
now um academia here's one where would
appreciate your thoughts would love your
thoughts on this
what is the right role for academia in
reducing the threats to the metaverse
well one is teaching requirements
also teaching common language
to express
security and privacy requirements
and teaching how
to build with privacy and security in
mind uh there must be so many other
things for academia and would love your
input on this as we go forward
now that was the framework piece
to kind of slow down and wrap up i
wanted to say
i think we really should start a
dialogue all of us
i would love it if everybody hearing
this would start writing your ideas
about security in the metaverse and
write via any source you have access to
your personal blog your personal twitter
feed your personal linkedin
facebook
ask questions and state your
requirements and say what you think
about the coming metaverse and the need
for security
also
in academia write and publish and push
about requirements for the metaverse
all of us as individuals should think
about our requirements for the metaverse
our requirements for what we want
companies
and communities and the government to be
doing in the future of the metaverse
and i also believe it's an extremely
important point that we in the security
community should teach our friends
and family
and co-workers and others
in academia how to better protect their
data today
and of course going forward into the
metaverse uh really this is something
that all people ought to be thinking
about how do you protect your personal
information now and how do you protect
it as we move into the metaverse
i have a few closing thoughts i want to
share with you uh just to keep the
thoughts going
uh as i do please think if you have any
questions
ask them in the q a section here
we'll get to them shortly
claude shannon very famous not just
academic but leader
of the revolution in communications
brought us into the digital world i
think
he's said it so well when it comes to
security and risk mitigation
we have to assume that the enemy knows
the system it's going to be the same
with the metaverse we really have to
assume
that our adversaries the criminals the
fraudsters the hostile governments are
really going to know the system well
we need to know the system and we
security professionals need to design in
mitigation measures
that understand that the enemy knows the
system
i thought great food for thought from
claude shannon on the metaverse
john boyd you know uh spaff mentioned
oda as the concept we named our company
as an homage to this mental model the
ooda loop
and i always think of john boyd when i
think of taking action
and when it comes to the metaverse
we should make a lot of decisions but we
also need to take action and you don't
just take action without thinking that's
reckless and i think that was very well
put by by boyd here i think the
framework is a good strategy uh but for
that i wanted to mention uh food for
thought from winston churchill on the
meadowverse and defending the metaverse
i think it's a beautiful strategy but
maybe it's not what results are we going
to get with this
what's the right thing if you have an
approach that works now it may not work
tomorrow and we don't even know if this
is the right approach yet i really need
your ideas to think through if this is
the right approach
and you i just like as we talk about
adversaries and what they're going to be
doing in our networks i love that
science fiction so frequently expresses
things about this dynamic world that are
worth thinking about so i have a couple
charts here on uh science fiction
one from ender's game
since when do you have to tell the enemy
when he has won
as we think about the metaverse and the
role of machines in our future
um
you know the the whole plot of doom was
set in a world
where people got fed up with their
machines there was no metaverse in uh
dune
because these machines
were not permitted to think and i
thought how awesome
that was good
some benefits of having adversaries um
also captured from dune
now i think this is a little too harsh i
don't believe this is the reality but
it's interesting to think about
enemies strengthen you allies weaken no
i think look allies strengthen you too
but um it's interesting food for thought
if when you are in security and you're
face to face with an adversary and
you're trying to push them out of your
network you really should be learning
you should learn as much as you can
and you should learn how to mitigate the
current threat you should also learn how
to mitigate
issues of
misinformation
and disinformation
and i thought
dune was pretty good about that too
now why prepare uh there's
no evidence yet that the metaverse is a
threat to society well um
i just wanted to share this with you
when it comes to risk management
professionals just because something
hasn't happened yet
doesn't mean it's not going to happen
we should exercise our ability to think
about future scenarios and mitigate the
risk of those future scenarios
this is to me something any risk
management professional should think
about
you know another thing that a lot of
risk management professionals should
think about is wisdom from guys like
staff
who has been doing this for so long and
is able to take a long view and say
here's what's changed here's what hasn't
changed through the decades
another
common friend
said this and i
just wanted to oops sorry i have to go
back here
went a little too fast
said this in 1991
when schwartel
pointing out that
government and commercial computer
systems are so poorly protected today
that they can essentially be considered
defenseless
1991 he says this
and man there's been a lot of
improvement over the decades there
really has been uh some systems are far
more secure and risk is mitigated but so
many new avenues of attack have come up
society has been threatened because of
computer security issues and i just like
mentioning this for context saying
there's been a lot of warnings for a lot
of years
and it's time for us to really really
work to improve protections of our
systems
please if you have questions add them to
the question and answer uh section here
i'm about to come off the uh slide
presentation but first i wanted to say
here's my contact info
please drop me a note uh connect to me
on social media
send me your thoughts what i love more
than anything if you want to do me a
personal favor is tell me where i went
wrong
tell me a better idea tell me how to
improve any piece of this and the next
iteration i give i'll give a better
brief so i would really really
appreciate your feedback
and with that
that was great um i wanted to ask if you
had had a chance
to um
uh
listen to the talk from last week from
chris stemcheck
no i haven't not yet
so i i think a very brief
excerpt from that
was the concept that
we have
major entities in this space
who are building from a different set of
values and goals
than some of the ones you outlined
and
if we
spend too much of our time trying to
argue what those are
the ones who are very single-mindedly
building out to support their goals
may become
dominant and that's a danger and i i
think you illustrated that as well
but um
for purposes of the people who are
listening in this is two speakers in a
row who are basically pointing that out
that
what we have now is not the end result
we're still building towards something
and if we are not careful in defining
what it is we want to build we may not
be overly pleased with the results of
what we get
uh so thank you that was great
uh we have three questions in the q a so
if you want to tackle those uh that
would be great okay cool
one uh kinguan yan says
from reality the virtual world is
growing rapidly and the impact on it is
going to be wide
will the progress of building the
framework handle the development of the
metaverse
how can the strategy be to ensure our
privacy simultaneously with the growth
of technology at the same time get rid
of the growing range of people who might
be involved
in influence in the virtual world i
think that what this is getting to is
how do we really articulate a strategy
that's going to work
in this new reality because this is
gonna be tough um and just like you said
spaff people are building this out um
and the only way to influence this i
think is if we get our ducks in a row
and we start articulating what we want
and what we expect and so we need to get
our requirements together and articulate
that say here's the world i want built
um and
i think we need to do that in a way that
involves government
but as i mentioned
don't bring too much government in we
don't want government surveillance of
what we're doing but we want to do this
in a legal framework that is smart and
well thought out
so i think we need to start pulling
folks in like cisa
jen easterly and start getting their
thoughts
um and
maybe there's things that need to be
done at the legal level
but really it all starts with us as
individuals getting our requirements
together i think
another question
thoughts on how we impose ethics in the
metaverse where the traditional minds of
societies may not apply see this is
another really good one because we want
communities to come together from
all over the world
different cultures and different
backgrounds and that's the way it's
working today in a lot of areas
and the ethics that one group grow up
with is not necessarily going to be the
ethics of another and that is even
within a single region uh people have
slightly different approaches and you
would say different ethics and uh this
is so hard and i
sometimes make flippant jokes and i
shouldn't i say things like uh the way
to handle that is just make sure
everybody follows my ethics
but that's not right everybody
should have their own ethical center and
be able to come together in ways where
we can dialogue and talk through that
and i think this needs to occur at the
community level
where people know what community they're
joining and what the code of conduct is
for that community and follow that code
of conduct and those ethics
that's all i can say for now
another thoughts on the effects of
highly immersive and customized
advertising
which will become prevalent in the
metaverse oh you're so right you know in
some communities there's a fear
like imagine if facebook decides that
they're going to use all the data
they're going to have on you to deliver
ads
you know they will have perhaps if
you're using a headset they'll have what
you're looking at
and what you're interacting with in ways
that are going to let them know what you
desire
for example if you use tick tock today
they got so many great algorithms that
are figuring out what you look at how
long you look at it what you swipe to
next and how long you look at that next
one
and what you hit the like button on but
also what you're dwelling on so over
just a little bit of time
they're starting to figure out
what your desires are and so now that
they know what your desires are they can
better market to you
so imagine a metaverse that knows what
your desires are and as you walk around
in the metaverse your desires are being
presented to you all over the place and
yes i'll buy that and i'll buy that so
it's should be highly effective
advertising
i the nightmare scenario for me would be
if there's a world built like that that
was shown in altered carbon which is a
great science fiction series
and in that world when you enter their
version of the metaverse you just get
bombarded with ads and it's really
overwhelming and sickening so that's the
kind of world we don't want
now if we don't want that kind of world
there has to be some other way that
communities get enough money to support
themselves or if you go the company
route the companies have money to
support themselves
so those are just some thoughts there
another question on concerns of the
social mediverse
uh uh
concerns of the social mediverse and
industrial metaverse may be very
different
digital twins for example and their
human interfaces for example does this
proliferation of cyber physical systems
require an entirely new paradigm it
definitely requires different paradigms
i think maybe there's some foundational
security that needs to be done on all of
them but the interactions of a digital
twin i think are going to be easier to
restrict to you know only 12 people need
access to this digital twin for a ship
design
or if it's a digital twin of an entire
city maybe 300 people need access to
this digital twin of the entire city and
if i need other people in i'll invite
them in so maybe it's easier to control
that piece of the
the metaverse the digital twins
another question
the promise of the internet the early
days was the free exchange of thought ah
that's so true
today we have fear perpetuated by
governments and corporations restricting
this exchange
yeah you're right
uh there's fear perpetuated by
governments and corporations
and groups nonprofit organizations
uh groups coming together and
promulgating fear
there's so many doing that and
also groups coming together and
spreading misinformation and
disinformation
and
it's
really the kind of threat that few of us
anticipated at least to this extreme
and i haven't heard the full answer yet
i have seen great people studying this
and fielding solutions to pieces of it
but nothing that scales
and i really really worry about it
because one thing about humans is
unfortunately it seems like we like to
deceive ourselves
a lot of us
like
to be deceived and it gives us an open
fertile ground for misinformation and
disinformation
how do we mitigate this it's got to be
some
educational approach i think i don't
know what it is but it needs to start
early k-12 education on critical
thinking
not every school is the same as the same
curriculum
many high schools today do teach some
pieces of critical thinking but it's
kind of an oh by the way maybe that
should be the center of the whole
educational experience
is how to think about analytical
methodologies
and how to think about your own human
biases and all the wonderful research
that's been done on that and um how to
spot
misinformation and disinformation
maybe that should be the centerpiece of
all k-12 education
and then a little bit of math and
science on the side
uh just a thought
well i would uh
i would react to that bob myself by
saying that
in my experience and i think if you
reflect on this
um
lots of organizations and individuals
don't want to promote critical thinking
and don't want to promote controls
because it would get in the way of them
putting out their possibly false
messages
yeah
uh
and
and you know we we've seen that a lot
recently whether it's in
politics whether it's on views about
what's happening with ukraine uh views
on
vaccines
we have
a number of different viewpoints and the
people who are holding out with ones
that may be
contrary to the public good
don't want their speech restricted
yeah
you know i think you're so right and way
before the age of the internet um we can
go back and see the ads for cigarettes
where uh nine out of ten doctors prefer
camels
and smoking is good for you and it's
good for the lungs
and it's just that was believed and it
was pushed by the advertisers even when
evidence was coming out that it was
cancerous they continued to push that
and that's just one example the next
really really big one in the time scale
was the sugar industry when i was
growing up and maybe this excuse why i
can't keep the weight off it was sugar
is just calories like any other calories
there's no problem have as much sugar as
you want as long as you're counting
calories a calorie's a calorie
um and that was all a bunch of bs sugar
is like poison and
it's just one after the advertisers are
bad of course the polarized politics we
can't get away from uh but there's an
example i think where um a large number
of people would not want
a lot of critical thinking taught and
you're right i think in fact some people
would push back and say if we propose
critical thinking as the core of
education everywhere uh oh there's
government mind control they're trying
to control us all yep yeah i just uh
so i hope this isn't a gloomy thought
but i i wish we had more critical
thinking i i i well as an educator i
agree
i i think we we have some some issues
there
and
uh we actually are seeing a backlash now
in a number of states where legislation
is being introduced that prevents
teaching anything that might
upset students parents
uh in any way
so whatever their preconceived notions
are
whether it's backed by history or
scientific fact they don't want to talk
hopefully that's just temporary
but
it goes to a lot of what you're talking
about
as to
being able to move forward we need an
educated uh workforce we need an
educated populist who can actually think
through some of these issues rather than
being told what's right and wrong
and uh
we're not at a point in our history
right now where that's necessarily the
uh
the universal uh certainly
and maybe not even the popular view
and i say i i hesitate to say that
because it sounds gloomy but
um
you know as a his as a
somebody who's looked at history i won't
call you a historian but
um we do have cycles
of what
people are willing to accept and uh what
people are going to demand to be able to
deal with challenges
right
so you've got an audience here and
possibly others who will listen to this
who i think
should take this to heart that to think
through there aren't simple answers
but we have to learn how to think
carefully about them
right
well thanks for the invite today i
really appreciate it span it was great
it's great to see you again and uh we'll
let you know when the recording's up for
everybody who's tuned in we will have
another of these next wednesday
afternoon
uh the website has the list of all the
upcoming talks
and uh have a great remainder of the
evening
goodbye all
bye
thank you
you