so actually good afternoon everyone so
welcome back to actually you know our
services seminar every wednesday
afternoon and this afternoon you know we
are so happy to have at the nd clan to
give us a great talk and andy has
rich experience actually you know in
company about actually all the security
he worked a lot of companies like
semantics checkpoint pgp in the post
and staff in the silicon valley and now
he's working in the black
uh back blaster which is a cloud storage
company this is actually no surprise for
us he's going to talk about actually
storage security and astrology issues
and we are going to know a lot of
secrets about the hard drives because
they are actually launching a lot of
data in the i'm
i'm sorry and i i try to keep our
introduction a little bit shorter
because i believe you are going to have
a lot of exciting things actually in
your talk
yeah so let's welcome andy yeah
hi thank you thank you very much let me
uh i want to start it with the story
because it was it was funny how you you
tripped over uh black blaze okay um
back blaze is the name of the company
and we do cloud storage and a lot of
other stuff that's great but
a lot of folks say black blaze okay it's
not a hard thing to do um so much so
that people were typing it into browsers
and stuff and looking for us and things
and we decided we needed to buy
that that url right that website um
except it was owned by a porn company
um that did porn and so we had to pay
them
and put a porn site out of business in
order to get that
blackblaze.com site to come over to us
so whatever we need to do to make sure
that people are finding us
all right so today we're going to talk
about hard drives and a bunch of other
things related to them
and i'm going to talk first about how
you know how uh why we need them
most people these days you have a laptop
or whatever it's got an ssd in it and
you don't care about hard drives well
you really should and we'll talk about
that
we'll talk about the data we collect
all about hard drives we'll talk about
failure rates and all kinds of other
things and then we'll start to dig into
some of the things you can find out
about hard drives at the end and then
we'll finish up with something about
predicting drive failure can you
actually do that um so a little
adventure as we go through the day um
and we go through there if you have
questions please type them in we'll try
to get to as many of them as we can at
the end if not you know i'll give you my
email address you can always send them
to me later or we'll pick them up
all right so
why do we care what do we care about
hard drives they're going away right uh
no no they're not um this is uh idc does
this little chart here and you can see
by 2025 about 2.5 zettabytes worth of
hard drive storage is going to be out
there right and it's increasing you can
see every year hard drives aren't going
away certainly ssds are becoming part of
the personality uh but they're still
here and we're relying on this
technology it's over 60 years old now
right and you probably don't know
anything about it you don't think about
it because you're looking at your laptop
right and or you're looking at your pc
or whatever the case may be
well all folks like us are storing this
okay there's us there's obviously these
other little tiny companies called
amazon and google and microsoft
all have cloud storage as well and
there's a many others who do the same
similar types of things
guess what we store stuff on hard drives
and that's what i'm going to talk to you
about today so you know a little bit
more about
what what we're using
now each year each quarter we actually
publish a little report and i'll show
you that a copy of that later on all
right and but as of the end of 2021
this is what we had and what we're
paying attention to so we had over 200
000 hard drives that we monitor on a
regular basis uh it's about 2.1 exabytes
of storage so you probably got a little
bit more than you do at home
and then the next three things i want to
get into because this is how we measure
failure in hard drives something called
drive days dry failures which is kind of
obvious and then something called an
annualized failure rate and it's
important to understand how we do what
those values are because then you can
get understand why things fail and how
things fail and how they fail over time
and all of that in order to measure that
so let's start with the data that we
collect
since 2013 we've been collecting uh what
we call
drive stats data okay and for each hard
drive that we have each day
we collect one row of data you can see
that right there and there's five or six
rows right and so we collect the serial
number model and so on uh we also
collect what are called the smart stats
smart stats are something each
manufacturer builds into their drive now
they there's 255 pairs of stats
they use various different ones to
record data in some are common like
smart stat 1 is a read error rate and so
on um smart stat 9 is power on hours and
things of that nature but we've been
collecting these for all of our drives
and the only thing we add to that is
that failure column right and if a drive
fails we put that we put a little one
there if it doesn't fail it's got a zero
it's pretty straightforward so that's
the data we collect and again we've been
collecting it for a long time but a
drive day which is the point that i want
to make on this one is one line so one
drive for one day
so a single drive that very first one
listed there the sea gate st 400 4 000
so on
that drive for one day okay is counts as
one drive day that drive for 365 days is
365 drive days and it gives us a way to
organize data and you'll see why that's
important later
now the data like i said we've been
collecting it since april of 2013 uh all
drives in operation we actually have a
csv file for every uh day uh since then
and you can kind of see how much data
that really is right we're up to about
80 gig of raw data uh out there by the
way you can actually if you're so
inclined this data is open source
um and you can download it you just come
to our website there's the site there
the location there you scroll down to
the bottom the files are broken up
either annually or quarterly you can
download them they're zipped up you have
to unzip them um and you can look at the
data and and quite frankly actually many
people have
um and you'll see some examples of that
a little bit later on so the data's
there uh for you to look at if you don't
believe what i'm going to tell you
oops let's go to the next one there we
go
now a drive failure right what do we
think of failure is and there's two
types there's something called a
reactive failure which you're probably
familiar with the drive stops working
it doesn't work it doesn't do what you
want it to do you're banging on the top
of it or whatever you really need that
thing to spin so you can get some data
off that's a reactive failure then
there's something called the proactive
failure which is
the idea that we can predict at some
point that that drive is going to fail
in the future
and based on some factors and the smart
stats in particular okay we can we can
say that drive needs to come out and if
you look to the right there you notice
in the red there's things called five
reallocated sector count of 82 and 197
pending sector count 276. these are all
indicators to us because these values
should be zero or very low
that something is going on with this
drive and it needs to come out of the
system right you'll see later when we
talk about predicting failure rates if
we can get a look at that if we can get
that information ahead of time
we do much better off keeping up what's
called durability about drives and all
kinds of cool stuff like that
all right so so we talked about drive
days we understand what drive failure is
we put it into a formula um and you can
see we're just using a cohort here in
this case of all of the models
of drives that we have and we have 23 24
different models of different hard
drives that we use
and then we said for the period of 2021
and we have the formula down at the
bottom right now notice that formula
doesn't include drive count
and and it's an important reason i did
the math down at the bottom with drive
count but the reason is is that our
environment is very fluid there are
constantly new systems coming on and old
systems being taken out in other words
more drives coming in the beginning of
the year for example
we didn't have 200 2 000 drives we had
about 160.
so we added 40 000 drives over the year
that weren't there for a year so that's
why we count drive days and do the math
like this and this gives us a failure
rate okay so that's really kind of nice
but what can we do with that i mean what
is that and how does that matter to us
right well it matters to us because we
can look at it in lots of different ways
again we can group the drives different
ways we can group them over different
periods
and we can do that annualized failure
rate
and that's um
and that's really cool so you saw the
annual one there right 1.01 percent
we've done it we can do it quarterly
uh and we can even do it over the
lifetime of the that group of drives
and that gives us an idea of what's
happening with that group of drives so
if we want to look at one particular
drive model and we can say hmm
interesting i think that the rate is
going up more interesting the rate is
going down okay and we'll talk about
that in just a bit when we talk about
something called the bathtub curve right
so and that we could also do things like
look at it by manufacturer
right
now this is quarter by quarter
so what we did is we said okay in q2 of
q1 of 2018 here's the data that happened
in that period q2 here's the data that
happened that period and q3 and so on
and so forth
this gives us the ability to see changes
that are happening not quite in real
time because they don't usually happen
that quickly but trends that are
happening all right and that's really
important to us
so you see the the green line there
that's the seagate tries right
and they started to they were doing fine
around one and a half percent which is
about their traditional number for us
um and then they started going up and we
started paying attention to them we said
what's going on so we started digging in
we work with seagate and we found a
particular drive model that was just not
doing well in our environment
and our environment is really nice a
data center is a nice place i mean it's
air conditioned it's there's no dust in
the place right everybody's really quiet
you know the machines kind of make a
little bit of noise but
you get plenty of electricity it's
filtered it's you got two or three
sources of it
it's really really nice for these drives
right so when they start misbehaving as
a group
we really need to start paying attention
to that something's going on it just
didn't fit right in our environment may
be perfectly fine in for example an
external hard drive for you but not good
for us
and so we looked at that we made some
adjustments and you can see the curve
comes down and that's great and the
curve then again wandering around one
and a half percent and then starts to go
up again and we had another little drive
issue we only had a few of them this
time we were able to correct that um and
some of those corrections are things
like tuning firmware
that you can do we can do you probably
can't do that at home okay so if you
have an external hard drive and it's got
a
hard drive in there and you want to tune
it you probably don't have the ability
to do that you might be able to get some
tools off the internet and do some fun
stuff but um yeah you know that's what's
going on so the other way we can look at
the same data and we'll look at the same
data again is cumulative in other words
starting from the beginning of time each
quarter and just adding on right you
know what the difference is and there
you see some the macro trends right and
so we noticed for example that seagate
one
is way back in 2018 was up at two and a
half percent now it's below two percent
and it's moving downward and that's a
good trend
right now at this point you're going to
ask you may ask the question and say
well okay why would you ever use seagate
drives right because i can see for
example the hgst drives or even the
toshiba drives are doing better
and the answer has to do very simply
with you know failure rates to us our
systems are built for failure
right at home you have a system you have
a drive and maybe a backup drive and
when something goes wrong you're now
down to one or the other okay when
something goes wrong when the drive
fails in our system we have it's
completely designed for failure
right we
have uh we use something called read
solomon erasure coding algorithms to
parse data out
in our case we have 20 different drives
when your data comes in it's actually
parsed across those 20 drives in either
17 data data bits of data in three
parity or 16 bits of data and four
parity depending on the size of the hard
drive
uh that we're putting the data out there
parity is the is the
uses some matrix math and all kinds of
fun stuff like that in the in the
encoding algorithm that does that takes
care of that so you can lose up to four
drives in that particular case and still
rebuild any file
in out of that that came into that that
what we call a tone into that 20
different things
so with that in mind
we are really as long as we stay within
a certain range we understand that range
and we understand the behavior of those
systems
we can pay less money
sea gates are traditionally cost less
than toshiba or hgst drives and so
that's great for us and we can save a
few dollars
right but when we go out and buy drives
we don't buy one or two we buy 5 000 or
10 000 or 20 000 and so you get various
different prices for them and all of
that so there's some interesting
economics that go on to play when in our
environment
now i mentioned earlier that we do a
report okay we actually do a quarterly
report once a quarter we do something
called the drive stats report some of
you may have even been familiar with
that
and
we publish it and it is as you can see
this this that's about all of the
different drive models that are current
so this is the one from the end of the
year uh and this is a cumulative one
over the lifetime of the drives and
that's really cool model number size
drive count average age
the two important ones of course drive
days drive failures and then the
annualized failure rate and then the
confidence interval
and that's because and we published that
because we want you to understand how
good that that number is so we give you
an annualized failure rate of 0.5 okay
like that very first one
what's the what's the range what's the
confidence interval and so 0.1 0.1.2 is
great okay if you're between that low
and high that's a great number that
means
that .5 apr okay afr excuse me is
really really solid okay and you can
expect that to continue uh for a while
wider ones of course um not so much
especially newer drives that haven't
been around a while we only have a few
of them that confidence interval is
really wide
and at that point you have to go well i
i see the number but i don't know if i
trust the number uh and a good example
of that might be way all the way down at
the bottom the wdc one which is a good
looking 16 terabyte drive yay and it's
got a ridiculously low rate annualized
failure rate of 0.14
but that confidence interval's kind of
wide it's 0.8 somewhat all right and so
you don't know if that number's still
got plenty of room to go up uh and rise
and so so those are we publish those on
a regular basis like i said
to give people insights into how
our environment works for drive failures
now what else can we do with knowing
this information about drives right well
if any of you are in engineering or any
of that kind of stuff i know you you
probably most of you are cyber students
but you've probably heard of something
called the bathtub curve right the idea
that components fail early on they
settle into a rate in the middle of low
failure rates and then the increase as
things wear out going along
and
we wanted to test and see
if that was the case with hard drives
right we had never seen that before so
way back in 2013 one of the first things
we did as we started collecting this
data was to do that this is by quarter
and then at the bottom you can see it's
year so one two three four we were able
to go back about four years before the
data started to get a little squirrely
and if you look at that you kind of get
that sense that it looks kind of like a
bathtub curve right it's it starts up
kind of high and it wanders down um it
hits that constant rate in the middle
which is really kind of nice look below
choose 2 1 or so there and then at the
end it drives back up so we had a
bathtub curve and it looked like hard
drives as a group followed
the bathtub curve
well this past year i decided to go back
and take a look and see if that was
still the case
and
what we found right was
it doesn't look like it
right and we also had six years worth of
data which stretched out the curve a
little bit
and you'll see that in a second how they
compare right but the front end of that
curve the decreasing part really doesn't
look like it decreases terribly much
right it kind of looks flat
and then it slowly drops down into that
constant area and then it starts to come
up and it takes a long time before it
really gets to be bad like in year six
or so five or so um where it starts to
get those rates really start to get high
again right and and it kind of it didn't
feel like
a bathtub curve anymore i it was i kind
of said well it's it's pretty shallow um
in the middle there and it kind of leaks
off to the left-hand side
so when we put both of those together
okay you can see the difference here
right you can see how one kind of looks
like a bathtub the other one almost
doesn't look like one at all
but as we all know
looks can be
deceiving right we always want to do a
little bit further analysis when you
start to look right and something may
look right and so we dug into the 2021
data again
and we plotted it out and we said okay
great and then we threw a trend curve on
there it's a second-order polynomial and
you can see how the curve kind of looks
if you follow the curve all the way from
the beginning all the way to the end
it
doesn't really look like a bathtub curve
but
the interesting thing about it is if you
stop on that curve at about year four
you suddenly get the bathtub curve back
so the first four years seem to fit
and what that's kind of telling us is
the data that we have in in years five
and and leading up to six right
are
probably too thin to make a good
judgment with
right and these are the kinds of things
we challenge ourselves with all of the
time so even though it doesn't quite
look like the bathtub car was working it
seems to be holding for the first four
or five years we still get that same
effect of
a higher rate of incident at the
beginning a nice settling at the middle
and then drives start to fail a little
longer
over time drives are lasting longer okay
they seem to be lasting five and six
years and in our case we have
there's a particular model is um a six
terabyte seagate model that we have
that's almost seven years old now and
it's still under one percent failure
rates which is just stunning we have
some of the four terabyte hgsts which
are uh six years old and they're under a
half percent failure rate um amazing but
at some point they're gonna start
failing um and so if you ever wanna know
how long drives last maybe uh that's
what the next one is
okay
life expectancy
because most people and
most people you'll run into don't care
about annualized failure rates um and or
anything they don't think that way when
they walk into a store and they say i
want to buy a hard drive
right
what they think about is how long is
something going to last you don't go and
buy a washing machine and say uh what's
the annualized failure rate of this
washing machine it's just not the way
human we're programmed to to think
consumers as that is scientists
different story um but um but we're
programmed to think about how long
something's going to last so we used uh
kaplan-meier projections in order to to
model the data out and and i'm not the
first to do this we've actually had a
couple of folks who downloaded all of
our data and did the same thing now god
bless them um and and got similar types
of numbers that we had and what we see
here
is
you buy something you buy a hard drive
today and at the end of four years
there's a 90 percent chance that drive's
still going to be working which is a
pretty good number okay all in all now
if you're that 10 it didn't
right
always have a backup that's you know
that's our motto so to speak right
but you can start to see that by the
time you get out into the year six and
close to year seven now you're dealing
with a 50 number and that starts to get
really scary that's just a coin flip
as to whether your drive is going to be
alive or not so
when you start to think about
whether you're going to buy a hard drive
like i said if it's an external unit
maybe you start to think about hey i
think it's going to last three or four
years and then i'm going to have to
replace it and just make that part of
the way you think
and that can be pretty helpful uh going
forward
now
i mentioned earlier the smart stats and
and here's just an exploded view of that
so you can see how we collect the data
in this smart one smart 2 smart 3 smart
4 going all the way across
and there's a raw value and a normalized
value for each of those and each of
those has a meaning to the particular
drive that it's in
not all smart stats are reported for
each drive as a matter of fact a given
drive might report only 30 or 40
different ones um but they all report
some common ones that we can go and look
at
so we started looking at the smart stats
and
again they all mean something and some
of them are things like um you know
media wear and so on uh more recently we
started looking at ssds which we're not
going to talk about much today
but uh to see if uh how they're doing
right
and um and and they also have smart
stats and we're beginning to dig into
those as well
so i wanted to point out some things
that we looked at over the coming of the
last several years as it relates to
using these smart stats and the kinds of
things that you can find and we found
that are in there
first one is can answer a question for
us about temperature
right so
is the temperature of your hard drive
going to affect its failure rate in
other words
uh you know do do i really need to keep
it cool now the first answer is is
keep it cool okay
you know the um you know try to keep it
a fan on it and all of those kinds of
things because at some point you're
gonna run out of luck with it right uh
the operating range of most hard drives
is between 0 and 60 degrees celsius all
right and you'll see that on there you
want to stay very comfortably staying
something in the 70 to 90 degree
fahrenheit range
which is you know you know 25 to 33 or
so in celsius most of us in the u.s
don't think that way so fahrenheit
we took all of our drives and we looked
at and we looked at the operational ones
one's still running and then the ones
that had failed and we compared them we
said okay so
you know what was the temperature at
approximately the time they failed and
not right at the time they failed you go
back a little bit
because as they fail they might heat up
or something or they might cool down
um so he took an average um but the
interesting thing is is when you plot
them out
okay those curves
kind of look the same right there's no
skewing like oh my goodness um all of
the failed drives are on fire um and
there's there's 60 70 80 degrees in
celsius out there we just didn't see
that um you just don't see it in the
data you see a little bit of warmth
there at like 39 41 and so on and so
forth where it's obvious there's
something going on there but it's just
not prolific
temperature doesn't seem to bother
drives too much and this goes all the
way back to 2007 our friends at google
did a study and they found this and we
retested it like i said i retested it
this last year and this is what we found
it kind of confirms that
but interestingly enough and we'll see
this in a little bit sometimes
temperature works its way into the
equation right but for the most part
keep your drive running keep it happy
keep it at a reasonable temperature in
your house or whatever you'll be fine
that's not going to be the problem now
if you have a
like a tower a pc tower or something
like that
and it's uh and you stuffed it into a
cabinet and it's got no ventilation and
there's a million dust bunnies behind it
and all of that all bets are off at that
point because you're probably punishing
those drives inside
this is by the way the internal drive
temperature so this is what the drives
think like or they are inside
um and so
you know
temperature is generally not a problem
but
don't tempt fate you know keep them and
keep them nice keep them in your house
like i said and you'll be fine
um power cycling right the age-old
question
do you turn it off at night or do you
leave it on
right and you know your grandma turns it
off because she's going to save a tenth
of a watt of electricity um and you know
you you probably don't uh you probably
slam the lid closed on your laptop and
call it a day now most drives when they
are not busy they turn themselves off
right they they put themselves in sleep
mode and then they wake themselves back
up uh these days all right but we wanted
to test the theory and we we at least
wanted to see what we could find out and
we looked at our drives right as of the
end of
12 yeah as the end of december
um and we said okay so what's the uh
average number of times a good drive
fails a good drive um you know has been
turned off and on and then
for the failed drives how often they
turned on and you can see the numbers
just aren't that different right you
certainly couldn't come to anything that
says there's a correlation between
failure and turning a drive off and on
it just just doesn't seem to be there
now the only downside is is we don't
turn off our drives a whole lot we don't
turn them off every day and every night
um because people like to store data
with us and it's 24 7 and so on so
maybe there's something that says hey
after i get to 50 or 60 or 70 or 100
times in a year maybe there's a problem
um but for our sites we couldn't see
anything that was that different right
and we even looked at it over time
we said hey is there any relationship
between power cycles and time so
something like you know if i start
turning it off and on and after it's
older uh that will cause it to fail more
and the answer doesn't seem to be any no
it just doesn't seem to be related
at all uh so it doesn't matter whether a
drive is one year old or five years old
okay it's it doesn't seem to have an
effect right now in turning a drive off
and on there's just no real correlation
to that
now one of the last things i'll talk
about and this will give us plenty of
time for questions which is great
um is the
is predicting hard drive failure all
right and we first saw the first paper i
saw was that from some folks in ibm
there
marella and company
and they used some what i would call
traditional methods uh to try to figure
it out and they were actually pretty
good at being able to predict failure
drive failure
especially like three or four days out
and but really really good they could
get 97 accuracy on a particular drive
model uh three days out but they needed
like three years worth of data to do
that um and three years is a long time
to wait to find out that in year four
it's gonna fail
um but over the years people have done
more and more papers on this and and
sometime in 2018 or 2019
people started applying machine learning
and and artificial intelligence
algorithms to
to this problem set and they take all of
our data in and they use it and in 2021
there was a paper here and i happen to
like this particular paper it's by the
folks at interpretable um and they did a
nice study and i want to just walk you
through uh the kinds of things you can
do
with the data to learn all about hard
drives right um so they took our
statistics remember all that data i said
before and they actually downloaded all
of it and then they took a subset of it
they were looking at one particular
drive model because we had like 30 some
odd thousand of them we had lots of data
on it
and they applied what's called optimal
decision trees technology to it and then
techniques and then survival curves to
it and i'll show you examples of both of
those in just a second
and they were able to come up with the
ability to predict
from a long-term
uh drive failure so in other words
more than 90 days
and then short term less than 90 days so
drive is going to fail in a certain
period of time they're even able to
squeeze the number of
records they needed down to as little as
50 000
which isn't a lot of data okay we were
giving them
they had something like a million
different records and they were able to
use 50 000 take that train their system
and then apply it out and test it
against the rest of them and it worked
uh which is pretty awesome uh when you
start to think about it so they're they
were really on top of that
um
let me let me see so so the optimal
decision trees right i don't know if any
of you guys are terribly familiar with
all of this kind of stuff but basically
they build this node and you can see at
each node there's a smart stat so in the
top one there it says five the raw value
of smart stat number five and down below
it's the normalized value of smart stat
number three and they were looking at
all these different values and they run
the drives through one at a time and the
drive this has how they train their
model okay to build the uh the trees out
and when they get all the way down to
the bottom you get a set of criteria
that says hey like node 15 and node 24
which we'll take a look at in a minute
says this is how you get to this node
and node 15 is 88.9 so there was an 89
88.9 percent
um
survivability at that point um and so on
so let's take a look
healthy drives right
uh they used uh kaplan-meier curves
again healthy right and if that smart
stats lined up with those values or in
the ranges of those values as they
predict right
they will they could say that drive has
an 88.8
chance of lasting 90 days
that's pretty good for us okay it's
particularly good because we're we can
fix a drive within a short period of
time right and we uh you know a couple
of days sometimes but you know so all we
really need to care about is is it going
to last a little while longer but start
to think about the applications of that
when you start moving your data centers
from big gigantic things in the middle
out to what they call the edge
and there are smaller groups of drives
out there and you can't get a technician
out there for a week and all of that
this becomes to be really really
interesting and important right on the
flip side
is unhealthy drives
so if you had a drive that met these
conditions
that was going to fail okay it had an 11
it was it was going to fail and you can
see how quickly it was going to fail if
i had a drive with these conditions i
had i should have a guy on a scooter
running for that drive to replace it
because it's going to fail almost
inevitably really soon and they were
able to do things like say
like i said predict
this kind of capability get that drive
out of here night now you have 24 hours
right and that's really important to
places like us it's in if it's important
to us then it's important to you by
proxy because you want to make sure that
we
can store your data um you know and
companies like us can store your data
and stay on top of it and keep the
what's called durability of our entire
system up and running so whenever you
ask for something you get it back and
you know it's there
so so that's
a little bit about hard drives and all
kinds of interesting things i hope i'm
guessing you didn't know
right um and you know we talked a little
bit about why we care and all those
kinds of things about the data we
collect and failures and all that kind
of stuff i really like the i really like
looking at the smart stats and trying to
dig out interesting little things like
temperature um and and other things that
apply
to the human condition the whole idea
i i've spent the last couple of years
looking at the can i turn a drive off or
leave it on and i it saddens me that i
can't come up with a good answer um and
the only answer seems to be it doesn't
seem to matter um so maybe your grandma
was right after all of these years um
but um but those are fun things to look
at and but the real exciting part is in
that whole predictive area right where i
can get
the ability to figure out if something's
going to happen ahead of time
in a perfect world
i would replace every drive before it
failed the reason is very simple
okay if i can take that drive out before
it fails i can do something called clone
it and put it back in put its clone back
in and have that system up and running
within a half a day if i have to remove
that drive when it fails i have to
rebuild the entire contents of that
drive when i put a new one in which is
empty and that can take a week two weeks
right you're not losing any data because
of all the redundancies we have built in
there but it just means that the
durability of the system
comes down a little bit so all kinds of
fun stuff to do um all kinds of things
there
let's take a look and see what kinds of
questions we we have out there
let's see
questions blah blah blah sorry late
murray all right well i'll give you guys
a chance to uh see if you had any
questions we talked all kinds of
different things um about um about
drives um how does this apply to you
guys as security folks okay it's a good
question um one of the things i saw
recently right was somebody had talked
about the fact that
ssds all right have have a data section
where you write data and then they have
another section where the system keeps
track of things like smart stats and all
of that
and somebody had put a virus
into a piece of malware into that
section of the code in the system so
even if you wiped the drive you didn't
wipe the malware
um so
and that was a tough one to find it was
actually something that happened in a
manufacturing facility right so start to
think about that and how you would
detect it and how you would get rid of
that and what you would do about it when
you can't even format that particular
part of the hard drive or in this case
an ssd and the same thing by the way
happens as well uh with um with hard
drives they have that protected area
and we uh we've we can now format it
because we get from the manufacturer a
formatting mechanism that formats the
whole drive so for example when a drive
does go bad for us one of the things we
want to do is make sure it's cleaned of
all of the data
that's out there and we run these these
particular applications and they make
sure that the entire drive is
reformatted and not just where the data
resides
that were out there
so
lots of good things going on um
as it relates to secured as it relates
to hard drives um
uh the the whole idea of course uh for
us is keeping things encrypted when we
store them um and uh you guys are
i'm pretty sure pretty familiar with the
concept of encryption
[Laughter]
and how it all works that's what you're
looking for um whenever uh whenever you
want to store data somewhere um you know
and you all know that you
i'm sure you all have your home systems
um or your even your school systems uh
have the data turned on have uh file
locker or whatever the particular
application is and so the drive is and
if you don't shame on you go home and do
it immediately
and and make sure that when you do
things like store data on external
drives that it's also encrypted because
if you put it on there in plain text
and you lose that external drive
so um you know little lessons to
remember as you go along
all right um i think uh well we didn't
have any questions which is fine
either i did an excellent job or
everybody is still asleep um but it is
uh it is later in the day we're not
we're we're not sleeping i just feel
actually we learn a lot of fracturing
with this data because this data is from
you actually you teach a lot of things
we do not know i'm sorry because i as
the penalties i cannot type the question
so the only the the attendees can have
actually i want to say we we are not
sleeping actually i feel this you show a
lot of action the great numbers and help
us to know oh oh this is healthy of the
hard drive
we didn't know that before
yeah
and i wanted to uh
so it's important the other little thing
to know
um and and and
is that again that data set's open it's
available for anybody to download and
one of the things we've seen
is um is a number of different
universities actually download the data
so they can use so they can practice
okay building
building models um and so on and so
forth which and even in security even in
the cyber spaces is certainly part of
what you're doing on a real-time basis
and you know because you can go through
and you have enough data to do a
training set and then you can test it
against the actual real data to see if
it works out
and that's what we've seen um the data's
actually been used cited about a hundred
times in the last three or four years
with various different studies and
papers and all kinds of things like that
and so you guys may find that useful to
do it is free i don't care
to go and download it have a great old
time if you do something interesting
tell me about it that's always cool um
because we like to talk about things
like that
and highlight those kinds of things uh
and um you know and uh but it's it's
there um and that's that's really cool
so you can see some of the things i do
with it on a regular basis and i'm not
nearly as good
at uh stats and statistics and so on as
many of you are so um always good uh
always good to take a look at that data
and see what's going on
let's see
there's your red back
[Laughter]
uh
we we do have a question can you say the
question is the q and a we have two
questions comes out can you say that or
do you need me to read that for you
uh why don't you read them for me please
oh yes so the first question from the
patrick you just ask
is there any correlation between the
driver failing and the file size or
warrior
so that's a that's a good question we um
uh it's not file size that we see a
correlation for um we do see a
correlation and and that's all we can do
at this point between uh failure rates
and drive size so the size of dry
weather it's a four six and eight or so
on and the drives we have go from four
up to 16 right now terabytes each right
um and
it does rise um over time so
the the failure rates seem to go up um
as as the drives get bigger
right and but you have to be really
careful about that because one of the
things you want to make sure of is you
got them in the same time
uh remember remember that the uh the
bathtub curve right you want to make
sure you're looking at all of the drives
in their first year of operation
and all their drives in the second year
of operation and so on not just that
just not on december 1st because then
you're going to they're going to be all
over the board
and so where most of our
larger drives the 14s and 16s are only
about a year a year and a half old and
so while they look they look a little
they don't look as good
right now it's it's really early to tell
but right now we're seeing a little bit
of a rise in the failure rates and and
it kind of makes some sense i mean the
complexity
a couple of years ago before before
coven and all of this stuff i got a
chance to go to the
the seagate
prototyping facility in longmont
colorado and they walked me through
how they built a hard drive and they had
all the machines and everything like
that
it is amazing okay for what you're
getting what you're getting for 49 when
you buy one terabyte hard drive much
less a 16 terabyte hard drive with eight
or nine platters
spinning at 7 200 or more rpms
revolutions per minute right with a
whole bunch of read write heads stuffed
in between all of these things flying
you know a couple of nanometers above
the surface
and still being able to pick out dots
that are the the pluses and the ones and
zeros in order to get your data off of
there it
it's an amazing amount of technology
that's in there it's amazing it doesn't
fail like every day right
um so the mere fact that it's lasting
five or six years and they're pushing
that out
out now like i said they're talking
about nine platters in in three and a
half inch platform um they're looking at
technologies that are using uh hammer
which is uh heat assisted uh read and
write and mammor which is uh m um
i can't think of the right word uh
anyway
that's a another technology which helps
put the dots in place and all of this
kind of stuff and creating something
called aerial density and all of that is
just amazing what's going on
um and again half the world's data is
going to be on these things in 2025
anyway ssds by the way are pretty cool
too so don't get me wrong but but
they're not electromechanical okay these
are this is all an electrical mechanical
system which is like i said divided
built in in 1956 by ibm and the same
basic principles that are
put in then are still working today and
we've been able to scale them and it's
it's just amazing
actually andy i really for me i already
wanted your comments about the ssd and
the hard drive but because we have two
more questions from qri so let me know
and the one more so we have still have
two more questions and the one question
is from chris he just asked you know you
know right now we can actually predict
her right the statics we can get action
but this practice shows actually you
know the correlation between
smart and the failure is kind of a
short-term prediction so he should
wonder
um how can we leverage this one it's
difficult for us to leverage this one to
extend our drive live so just ask her
can you say actually an unclear
correlation that would help us to get
that better drive
from yeah yeah so it all depends if
you're just you know a regular user okay
you're you're not going to be you're not
going to have the enough data available
to you to do it some of the newer
systems i've seen
computers and so on and so forth
actually monitor some of these smart
stats
and
and they will report to you hey i think
the hard drive is failing
and and that's kind of cool that they're
doing some of that
but you as a regular user who's not very
familiar with the utilities and stuff
now if you're familiar with something
called um smart ctl or whatever
application
you can run on your computer that
monitors all of these stats and you can
look at all of that and start to make
some judgments that's really cool um but
um but most people can't do that you
have to rely on the manufacturer telling
you the best thing to do
is have it you know has a backup i mean
we always preach something called 321
backup which is you need three copies of
something before it's real
one on your laptop one on an external
drive and one someplace else i don't
care if it's in the cloud or whatever
just someplace else right um three
copies and and then two is just on two
different media which is don't put them
both on the same hard drive kind of
thing and then one copy off site right
um and if you think that way
then it really then i don't wanna say it
really doesn't matter but you have less
worry about your particular hard drive
running inside your system but to your
point
there are some tools available they are
not terribly user friendly sometimes
they're built into the operating system
or some of the applications may come
with your system and it will tell you
that your hard drive or ssd is failing
um and uh and then try not to ignore
them like most people will um so
black plaza is the professional action
cloud storage company so you'd have to
look into this data and then
right make the hard drive work longer
and healthy and um combat with this kind
of experience class yeah yeah yeah you
are professional right wait wait wait
but not okay then
we have one more question actually i
think which is very useful because it's
really into our daily life so he just
asked you know so this is very
interesting question so we just asked
you know what's the failing rate over
time will apply to
the active hdd or this kind of
non-active sdd because usually we have
like i said we have a hard drive running
24 hours seven days but we also have
some big kind of storage and which just
uh with external hdd which is the power
of when the most time they are they do
not work
so just ask you know this failing rate
over time will make a difference for
this two different working mode because
he worry he has a hard disc maybe
thought some very important fact that
this is from us
it's still something may be impossible
for us actually for more than two years
we want to make sure it's still working
right
so yeah he's uh so
you know we we obviously keep them
running 24 7. that's absolutely right um
and and but what we see is um
and this is just
after years and years of talking with
folks a lot of folks take it like you
see they say create an external hard
drive and they put their data on there
and then after they're done storing
everything they stick they put it in the
closet
um and
what happens is is the drives are really
meant to spin
okay
and and
they just seem to fail a lot more often
after they sit for a long period of time
and we've seen this with individuals
we've seen this with many businesses
that used uh external hard drives to
store second copies of things and they
create this closet of you know a hundred
external hard drives with all of their
data on it and then
they would have a failure rate of 20
percent taking them out of there um and
that's a crazy number all right
because they're just they just sat for a
long period of time one two
sometimes the conditions in your closet
or whatever are not particularly nice it
really does get warm in there in the
summertime and it really does get cold
in there in the wintertime and even
though i said temperature doesn't have a
whole lot of effect it's that swings
back and forth that can be it and then
you know the components are meant to
work
and so if you suddenly turn it on and
and they're you know maybe maybe
they've been sitting too long so i i
always encourage folks who have external
hard drives to plug them in
every so often just to see if they're
used
they're ready they're they're still
working um and don't expect them to last
10 years although you know sometimes
they do
and good on you if they do
but um i i always you know maybe once a
year whatever the case may be bring them
out of the closet plug them in make sure
everything's still there do a disk check
you know file system check or whatever
the case may be
and um and see if that
that drive is still up to snuff
um and make sure it's not the only copy
of something if you take all your
family's photos and stick it on an
external drive and that's your only copy
please make another copy you know
right
yeah so
andy i said it's very useful so it's
more like you know we should check you
know the external storage you document
right like this once a year because the
frequency the the use frequency of
course we are affected the lifetime but
also you know the
the the total time is also affects the
lifetime right the heart disco is not oh
yeah even you do not use this for for 10
years it's just your life no we cannot
show our hard disk or how else how to
drive you know it's so reliable
right yeah and and we're we we tell
people like this is our environment
yours is your mileage varies right
depending on your environment but places
like that where people are putting
drives in closets or whatever for years
on end
always a good idea just to take them out
and check them um you know like i said
once a year once every few months
whatever schedule you want to put
yourself on um because it's the value of
the data that's on there is is well
worth it
so let me maybe i can just last question
from me okay so maybe you can comment
then what will be actually recommended
or you believe more permanent actually
in the way for us to do family or
personal storage it's a cloud
i always like i said we always say three
two one you have your pc um or your mac
or whatever um and then you probably
have an external drive because you wanna
have an external drive you wanna have
your data close to you
as a backup copy
i for example use a mac and then i have
a time machine external backup system
and then i use of course backblaze
which is a cloud storage system and
between those three okay over the last
10 years since i've worked at backlash
i've crashed three systems and i've
never lost a file
i've always been able to recover either
off of
time machine um or uh and or if of uh
backblaze and so
um you know so i it's it's been the case
that i've been able to do that that way
so three copies of everything in three
different places uh obviously i say
cloud storage for the third one but um i
know people who burn who make a second
external drive and send it to a relative
in a different state
whatever you need to do just get it away
from your current ones get it off site
it's a little easier to do cloud storage
but it's up to you as to what you want
to pay for and how you want to do it
yeah
of course you know i think you know the
personnel and the cloud and all this one
will be important for us to have backup
one you know for lifetime our data
becomes more and more and then
eventually you know you put them in my
mouth you can store kind of like some
one terabyte but more than this one and
a lot of things we have to have backup
so actually use the solution used by
nasa just external disk but i need to
check this once a year to check is still
working
or maybe i'll forget about this data you
know because this data i rarely use i
cannot use the very own thing
the the important thing you know and and
and if you do store it in the cloud um
you know then make sure it's it may or
may not be uh under a subscription you
make sure you have to make sure that
stays up to date you want to make sure
other people have access to your account
in case something happens to you you got
to start thinking about all of those
kinds of things i mean that's just the
world we're in right now um you know so
um and that's fine um you know but but
like i said multiple copies
get them in different places um and if
it's really really important to you and
then check it on a regular basis and
make sure you got what you expect
yeah
so andy thank you very much you know not
only to give this great talk but also
give us a lot of useful tips we need to
use because we need to deal with action
the storage
and i think that right now we are kind
of you know i think you know that's the
good time for actually you know the this
seminar and
we really really appreciate your action
coming us to give us this great talk
and also thank you for others coming for
today's action the serious seminar so we
hope everybody's safe and healthy oh by
the way the next week is spring break so
we are going to see you two weeks later
yeah
and enjoying your spring break i'm not
sure if you have spring break but you
know this spring is coming soon so
yeah have a good day have a good day
thank you again bye