welcome everybody thinks I'm and I'll be
talking about some RFID attacks if I can
see you guys got everybody or anybody
somebody alright so it goes through a
series of a refresher what's been going
in and what we're talking about here is
RFID as it relates to access control for
buildings so not your bus passes not
sure my fare cards not sure you know ski
resort passes things like that
specifically two types technology that
will dive into a bit one of them around
for a long time
lot of researchers have talked about him
which is a low frequency Arthus and
newer technologies encrypted format and
that's all we're gonna focus home in the
latter part of the talk and after that
we'll talk about some advanced attacks
you can do against those kinds of
systems as well as some medication
around this things a little bit about
company that I work for large consulting
we've been around now for eight years
a decent stuff in the industry I just
work related but also things related to
improving the community one of things we
put together that we're proud of what
they've actually copied us so we start
writing standards for how to conduct
security assessments specifically round
pen testing standards about it prior to
what this with this created so myself
along with about one of the people in
the community got together a standard
around along with that of other things
about the company itself and one of
things that you guys may have heard of a
little TV show they made about us
Tiger Team we presented a number of
conferences around the world I
personally have presented here at the
Kodokan few times as well as performed
on the red team Percy City senior lot
about myself obviously tell him not
serious I don't have the suit picture I
was actually a boat race we did last
year when his ass off
what are some of the services like I
specialize in is contesting risk
assessment social engineering physical
security and Linda threat types of
attacks so this obviously is is one type
of attack you can do when you're looking
at things like red team physical
security implicit threats so important
enough to be able to do what I like to
do if you're not somebody made a quote a
long time ago if you're getting up into
working every day you're not happy then
its work not a career so I personally
been lucky enough to get everything and
be happy with what I do and the company
that i've i've helped build a network
for and it's more of a hobby than a job
so again you know what we're talking
about here is one aspect of raging
testing that's obviously got a long
definition of what rating testing us it
originated in the military and you guys
can read that long definition you want
to but the analogy that we like to use
are already testing is it simulates a
fight if you put someone in the ring and
they are actually in the middle of
flight
gonna know how they can't rain all day
in the gym boxing and perform all these
different types of martial arts until
you're actually in a fight you don't
know how you gonna stand up and fight so
when I read team testing is to put an
organization into an actual fight to
defend against similar what we do for a
number of reasons to conduct it
obviously one is still simulate what
would happen in a real attack was the
impact of the brand was the impact the
bottom line the company but also it's
essentially a full Dr test for your
emphasis program how well your gonna
hold up to a number of different types
of attacks whether it's physical social
electronic or a blend of those testing
like that already is a collaboration of
those different aspects so you may use
an electronic attack to gain access to
an organization once you've gained
access then you might use that to get
physical access so there's some things
I'll talk about in this talk where we
can leverage things like penetration
testing from the outside gain access to
a bad system learned details about
what's in that bag system to create a
badge and the shop on site magic to a
building and all that started from
external threat so there's a number of
techniques when you speak of Redding
testing and gain access to a facility
conventional attacks everything from
jail getting into a building a social
agenda if you wanna call it that all the
way down to lock picking and shimmy and
lock bypassing and doing things around
with elevators and also the different
types of direct attacks we're
specifically talked about today is just
are fighting so there's two technologies
the run talk about today one and they
both look similar
the badges are you see people all the
time around lenders things like that you
guys may have campus for doing certain
things there's two types there is a low
frequency which runs at $125 and there's
also high frequency that runs at 13.5
six megahertz to read ranges on both of
them
vary slightly depending on what kind of
reader that the card numbers and it's so
we'll dive into a little about the the
length of those and how some of those
things work but specifically there's two
types were on talk about today
low-frequency be an unencrypted
high-frequency being high class
technology which is always so here's the
stink of it this is a quote
released the date on it and it's from
hid which is the number one vendor for
all these different asset types of cards
and technologies and the quote was the
low frequency on the cards are still
using about eighty percent of their
their customers space the other 20% is
using a mixture of of these types of
assets some of them that I play some of
them being a third party that's not hid
specific but eighty percent of the
companies out there that use access
controls related to RFID cards or using
the unencrypted form so that scary just
a statistic but then you put it into
perspective of who's actually using
those kinds of cards and and this ties
back to some of what Scott was just
alluding to is whenever you can put
physical harm someone or you can impact
someone's life that's usually much more
risk than a business losing data using
personal records losing something that's
going to cost them a financial amount of
money and sometimes it's it's it's
compared to how much they make right
there's a big debate going on right now
about how much is a breach actually
impact a company phone company survive a
breach of those companies can look it
you know companies like TJMaxx years ago
they're still around doing great work at
Target their stock drop it was minimal
so when you put things into perspective
like this and you start looking at
places that that have these types of
technologies you looking at kato plants
nuclear plants hospitals all these are
places that you could cause physical
harm physical destruction to not only
two people in that facility but around
the facility imagine getting into a
nuclear plant causing destruction there
and all these are using an integrated
technology that you'll see all
passengers so how does it work
got one here that it wasn't working
it's all broke from flying on the blame
it's been three trips now with me but
this is this is a bad system that I
purchased a company called midpoint
security and they assemble whatever
badge technology you want to put in here
so this is actually a new reg reader a
multi-class reader that or a controller
animal to class reader supports both the
low-frequency and high-frequency
an encrypted so it's a great way to
simulate what you guys have or what a
company has for their entire facility
they would have an axe a reader on the
outside the building would walk up there
they would then have a controller
somewhere buried in a wall a switch
closet where the controller may be that
controller than interfaces to a system
on the back end that is the badge
software that controls who has access to
what was a user might have access just
first wore a privileged user might have
access to a datacenter the bad system
itself holds all these different roles
and access levels so those interface of
the best system then you have things
like you might see when you walk out a
push for snacks so the simulation have
forced exit you also have a simulation
here that most stores have some kind of
magnetic alarm so if you break that they
are not going to do it is loud if I
break that being that will stimulate the
door was open without that bad actually
opening the door so great way to
demonstrate how a bad system works but
essentially you look at the diagram here
user walks up to add or bad as in
there's a field of ivory for the RFID
reader itself powers the card
information stored on the card sends it
back to the controller then converts
that to what's called weekend and on
that side of the reader everything's
unencrypted and then from there to the
bad system determines if you have access
to that particular reader that you're so
far so hid is again there is an HID and
in my opinion the way I like to put it
is there a Microsoft without Apple the
only market there's no other company out
there that you can compete with what
they do or small little occurred over
the years they have a small part of
market but it's a fraction hid house for
years they've been putting out more and
more technologies but predominately the
design of them if you open up a card is
there is an RFID chip inside of it and
there's internet usually goes around the
perimeter of the card if you were to
open up one of these cars you'd see one
of these types of formats they all kind
of all the same process changes are
typically about the same there anywhere
from one to two inches for these kinds
of cards are for these kinds of readers
and then you look at a few of the big
garage salary or so in the parking
garages airports things like that you'll
see a reader that's usually two feet 3
think something like that
square those have a much wider range so
the card directly up to the reader you
can be a foot or two away from it so
we'll talk about how you can leverage
some of those things well so on the back
in a reference to something called the
weekend protocol is is how the reader
communicates to the axis controller
there's essentially two wires Thursday
20 and 80 one day soon we're protocol
back to the controller and unencrypted
and you can decode those attacks on the
controller will talk about some of those
later in the talk so
everything from the reader to the
controller is an unencrypted protocol
call weekend so when you're thinking
about what is required for you to
authenticate and gain access to a
particular door entry system there's
three things that gets looked at when
you receive your card or your tag is
what they call them to a reader they
look at what's called a card I 3537 bit
whatever it might be
it also looks at what you were assigned
to that building and also looks at what
your access card number which is
typically printed on the card so really
city code and access card number
the only two pieces of data I need to
either for differential or present
notification token to the reader to try
and gain access to that doorway facility
code an access card the access card
number is typically printed on the badge
now think of using the password if
you're walking around with a you know a
tag on your chest name tag and had your
user name on it you would consider that
somewhat of a league right now I know
what your username is all that is forgot
your password code and access card
number or really just to user IDs or two
passwords so if I can learn one off of
walking up to someone is looking at
their badge someone post pictures of
them all the time online if I'm in a bad
system and I can pull out now have at
least one of the two pieces required to
authenticate there's multi-factor we can
talk about later that enforces
biometrics and things like that those
flaws in those two but the the basis of
an authentication when you attack your
reader is a facility code and a card
number so they should consider private
your passwords whether it's encrypted on
the back in its still weakened the data
those two pieces of information should
be considered private what we are
finding when we were doing some of our
research is like the postings online
course people also like to buy extra
cards from ebay when they run out of
course because they've hired more
employees it lost chords whatever you
look here and so when HIV cells extra
cards they sell them in a series
by a range of cards and it might be you
know 6000 6500 cards but then you know
cost cuts budget cuts whatever you don't
have as many employees you thought you
were going to you might want to sell
those carts people don't put those on
eBay so on ebay they list right on the
box what my company code facility code
is in the range of cards that are
selling so think of it in terms of us
announced until collection right if I
figure out what the company to access
card number and then I do some kind of
intelligence gathering on eBay seller
cancel reply to find out who he works
for you than enough time I figure that
out now I know the possibility coat and
possibly the range of access card
numbers and then walk up to his facility
route numbers either before the ones he
selling her after or just brute arranged
already know the facility code and gain
access to the building because someone
stole some pretty bad so then we found
another issue HIV results through
partners channels there's resellers out
there that you can call up and say hey
I've got badge I don't know what my
facility code is I don't know anything
about it because our admin that used to
run the batch system got fired
doesn't work anymore can you help me out
anymore courts will take the series
number off of your heart
look it up in a database interfaces hid
and they can tell you exactly which are
based on the order strain which is on
the card so think of that from an attack
perspective now if one channel partner
gets compromised and that access to that
customer databases now I can look up any
serial number of water or any order
number and access card numbers for that
particular company so another Intel leak
that I've never even had to touch
anything on your company never had
anything I've done all history until
Gathering online to find out information
about how to get into your facility
before even show up
of how the card numbers and and access
card numbers and agent goes all work
together to authenticate but how easy it
is to gain information about even
compromise so let's dig into a to how
you can attack RFID systems and an asset
tax
start out with a low frequency first
because it's it's been a horses and beat
for four years
everyone's talked about it as the new
technology new hardware that's come out
but it's still seventy eighty percent
still
unencrypted horrible can be closed can
be modified so a piece of hardware came
out a few years ago it's been a number
of years now and it's kind of the Swiss
army knife of RFID so if you want to
dive into the hardware is called a box
marked three so you can buy a legitimate
from the vendor that makes them or you
can buy from China $400 left's think
they're a list for four bucks and
China's gone for like two or three at
the nearby the engine is reported so far
less than 450 bucks need to go break
into eighty percent of the buildings out
there it's pretty bad so there's a
couple ways you can use it
there's a lot of different types of
attacks you can do with it not just a
lower frequency in which you can also do
things like my fair which your bus
passes your ski resort lift tickets your
meal cards actually so think about it
from you know from that aspect right it
is not just a frequency that you have to
put in some parts but is actually works
at a very high level were your
controller or and this runs a operating
system firmware and then you've got a
USB connection to interface with me see
whether its Windows Linux or if you want
to use and then you got any antenna and
there's different types of antennas
there's
high-frequency antennas to get longer
rearranges you can supply extra power to
arrange things like that so a lot of
different stuff you can do with
three so first I want to show you how
easy it is to clone one of these
unencrypted proxy port to which you're
eighty percent of the market again right
so let's do that first you're so smart
three is a wizard mode kind of a
standalone mode you can use it without a
minute there is also the ability to to
watch the output which is what I want
you here so you guys can see what we're
doing and to interface with it
frequency hid modulation and I'll take
the card and so there's there's a couple
of methods out there to acquire bad
information there's what the industry's
kinda called how the blood test method
which David expertise and you can you
can walk by and their badges and read it
that fast and essentially it works like
this you put your reader into so as fast
as I resent to a line
so as fast as I resent cards little read
and the crips information on those carts
35 the card number
good everything it reads one of those
prints obviously the standard also
stores that in its memory buffer so in a
standalone mode I'll say that next and
how you can work it you can set into a
stand-alone vote vote in the first card
interacts with its rights to a memory
buffer is stores in their simulated and
it replays what's in that mode so you
get the right one that were so
44 indicates to this building so now we
do what's called simulation and we just
paste information now its simulation
that tag so I gave the stalking through
into laptops that have 5 dumbest
so
formation simulate replay it and people
that use these in our industry usually
carry the products markets out of their
jacket when the cord on their sleeve to
have these in their hand and walk up to
a building there inside no one thinks
anything different
the sad part about this attack these
types of attacks is the beach is enough
for someone to trust that what you just
did was authorized and you can even get
by with some of the things that we do
and I'm sure Dave team does well as just
having a card that does it indicate what
makes the reader is usually enough to
tell you to a building because someone
heard it be behind them they hold the
door they don't realize that that
Bieber's bad
is no different than a successful be
it's just a big the reader may display a
reader rain if that's turned on but
that's enough for someone to not check
the guy behind them hold the door for
you let you in so we always have a
couple cars are pockets just trying to
indicate that he'll get into a building
but essentially that's how that attack
works you're within range of someone you
read that aggravation you then simulated
or go one step further in right that
information
clone command right that to a cartoon I
have a physical card and if that company
is you know enhanced and they put actual
pictures on the badges badges you can
put a picture on that edge so it looks
like you're an employee with someone
else's cock information and now you can
walk up to a gym with a legitimate
looking bad no one says anything so
pretty bad right now is that is anyone
can do it
push a button whatever so the rocks mark
becomes even more sexy when you can see
it because you can get regular power
bank USB battery bury all this inside of
a regular plastic keyboard transmits
RFID and now I'm walking around on
campus with a keyboard or a clipboard
and that transmit the RFID from the
internet so that I can walk up and
tapped the clipboard against the reader
that transmits and let me into the
building as well so now it's concealed
that it doesn't look
I don't look like Joe hacker walking
around with you know crazy looking
electronics hanging out of my tactical
jacket with forty pockets on it I'm
walking up with a clipboard and chances
are if you get a clipboard you mean
business and was gonna ask questions cuz
you look busy right so clipboards are
one the best tools for users when he
tried to get into the facility is
usually a collar shirt you're involved
with something no one's gonna question
you know you look like you're busy so
that's kind of just a quick demo of how
easy it is to again break into eighty
percent of the buildings out early that
use frequency so in perspective of we're
RFID has come from when it relates to
the low frequency products court Tues so
someone decided that found stone Brad
into its settings they pronounced it a
couple years ago took the firmware of
the products mark and customize it and
wrote something operatic route so now
think of this in a situation where I
still cats vag whether I take a picture
of it or I find in the bed method was to
get the facility Co the access card
number in the car type and then I have
this information but pat doesn't have
access to a char area where the
executive floor or wherever I want to go
there has elevated privileges data
center so code for that building still
gonna be the same most likely in most
cases it is but someone else's bad has
access to that reader to get into that
security area of the facility so it is a
different batch number right still seem
facility code still think are tight but
someone else has a different batch
number assigned to them and they have
extra rights so someone came up with a
method to brute through a series of
access card numbers so using a proxy for
custom firmware I don't have that
firmware on here you can read someone's
card
pools the facility code and it starts at
a series of bad ideas you give it
through one by one and you hold up to
the reader and it presents one every
half 2nd second wherever he said until
it finds one that opens the door so
literally rolling up so pretty simple
method because it's all an encrypted the
overhead or that transaction isn't very
intensive so it does take a lot of
computing power to brute force those
credentials so can all be done just you
know small little processors and so
something that you know obviously became
a big issue there was being able to
elevate privileges just put it in
perspective of a Windows environment I
have standard access user that has email
and SharePoint doesn't have access to
everything else but now I can brute
force a bunch of usernames essentially
until I find the right using to get into
domain controllers get into you you know
Linux environment whatever might be so
I've gone from standard user to
superuser just by breathing through a
series of just one property which is the
access card pretty bad right direction
so obviously became something big for
our industry but we decided that we want
to take it one step further and figure
out how to do what I've always referred
to as smart reporting I talked in the
past they've talked about it some too is
if an attacker I don't want to generate
so much in the way that you're gonna
find me want to be smart and intelligent
about how I tilt my logins brute forcing
things on the outside I'm not gonna run
dictionary of thirty thousand words but
chances are the one you're gonna see
that you're going to stop me with an IPS
something or 2 I'm gonna walk an account
now in batches counts but I'm generated
enough noise and traffic you're going to
see that at some point so I don't
necessarily want to walk up to a reader
in it for 10 minutes and looked like you
know look suspiciously I'm standing
there with my head at two o'clock in the
morning badge in waiting in a baby
smoking a cigarette or something to
consider myself but at some point
someone's going to catch me
maybe if there's a camera on that day or
whatever so let's be more intelligent
about how we try to indicate in an
attempt to negotiations so this is where
the Red Team threats of comes in right
if I can learn information either about
you as a target or I can learn
information from a bad system and
extracted data because I can look up and
see ok pat has access to first floor but
Scott has access to data center and
Scott badge numbers this now let's take
the information I know from Dave or
pattern whoever by example as it's now
and then showed that data in that I need
that associated a card number
make my asset tag in electronic format
then simulate that now I've done one
attempt but I use the information I've
learned from ocean from attack on bad
system from whatever and then I simulate
that so what i'm showing here is kinda
how the the binary stream appears and
then convert that to hexadecimal format
which is essentially what that tag ideas
so I showed you before was we did the
modulation demodulation gave us the tag
information after the heck string was
decoded and then what I did in the next
example was broken down one step further
so you can see what that binary string
looks like so 435 card format there's
always parody on both sides of the
string there's always a preamble based
on what kind of course format is always
remember that strength so I know where
my start stop is my code as well as
access card number which is what I'm
showing green and purple then I just
modify my access card number to match
the target in 2012 now I generate that
through anything online or you can write
a script where we wrote a script for
example appears I'm going from hexa
decimal to binary takes you know half
second right something's going to do it
for your script whatever you want to do
so I generates my strength from my badge
number that I want to become that back
into my stream
converted back the other way hexadecimal
and a similar that all encrypted again
I've taken a portion of the credentials
set modified it created the stream back
and I need for the hex tag reader all
again unencrypted very easy to do so
show there was was what I just did which
we were just generate that with the
script whatever a step back into
simulation command before that within
badge in much better shape than a shower
before so it's a good time of get on to
the next day off so we've gone from
nothing to clone and stimulate every
play and then also read or learn
information modify and elevate frivolous
so two solid attacks with with proxy
cards that are eighty percent of the
market again so now I can learn what I
need within inches of someone I can
learn from bad I can learn off buying
cards are looking up information about a
company or whatever I can you know
social and my way into something we do a
lot of work is maybe I come in
interview for a job or I get a tour of
your building something that is going to
give me a visitor patch chances are that
matches the same facility code but a
limited access card number to just get
me in first floor lobby to break room or
wherever they're gonna allow me to go as
a visitor so I the bathroom it's hard
right information then go back home
create a bunch of cards learn more
information take pictures somebody's
card whatever make the card I wanna make
to match an actual employee has access
come back in a later date just with what
I learned from a visitor badge that was
given to me during a tour or an
interview or whatever so they have a
perspective that way if I'm able to get
one read off a badge that can turn into
elevated privileges pretty easily so
to to extend our our attack range of
having to make it obvious and go up and
tap somebody to get the asset
information if they had a hangover waste
or lanyard or whatever let's increase
our or our distance for attack so from
standard reader on the side of a
building that usually has a read range
of ZnO couple years you know if you're
looking to what usually find a parking
garages because they don't you get a
liqueur your car gets the concrete
pylons there or it might be raining they
want to see vehicle whatever might be
moving out the window so now you have a
larger reader larger internal power is a
bit different and that now extends the
range 2 to 3 feet so that an attack
perspective to 3 feet is me walking up
and ask somebody for a lighter cigarette
or asking directions or just having a
conversation so now I've gone from being
suspicious attacker tapping someone to a
personal history of a conversation and
I've read what I need and the way that
we do that is we took a standard reader
stock off the shelf by one online for 34
bucks and we did the research that some
of this we took it a bit further later
on talk about and Audrina
assets on the other side of the reader
where the if it's encrypted where the
unencrypted data would occur the weekend
data and it reads the weekend data
echoes it extracts all the information
they need access card number and cards
and if it's encrypted data tells me that
as well so they somebody put some
clothes out a few years ago we use that
code along with some other researchers
have used it to modify it a bit and we
now have a hard reno that sits inside of
this reader and what's cool about this
reader is it can be deployed a number of
ways you can put it in your briefcase
and walk around and
you know if your European your satchel
call it and you walk around with your
purse and walk through a crowd of people
and as a crowd of people anyone who has
an expose RFID tag I'm reading of a min
within that range in its right into a
nasty court go back to my scary van in
the parking lot I look at all my
information I pull out which ones I want
I write my cards I walked back into the
building and I've done all that just by
walking through a crowd of people and
within two to three feet provided have
enough power for that reader I'm now
siphoning data off so now
couple that with what we've just talked
about hard and I've gone from walking to
a crowd of people to creating asset
credentials that I need or want to
create and encrypted in the reason that
it's so simple as because it's encrypted
so here's where it gets fun hid decided
all right let's solve this problem and
create an encrypted ass attack so
everything from card which looks like I
should get up close on it you look at
the details everything from car to
reader is encrypted so someone snoopy
that connection it's a group that I can
just Dakota like I did walking up
tapping the card is encrypted from
reader to controller is still unclear
that still week so we'll talk about a
tax on that side of the fence later but
everything from asset tag reader so that
means awesome so we decided let's take
the same attack and let's modify the
code a bit more and now it's be able to
do the same thing and get the
information I need all these encrypted
cards because we'll talk about a minute
is we can also do some of these same
attacks but now you're talking ten
percent of the market
whatever that statistic is not the
seventy to eighty thousand so this is
more of a specialized focused attack on
someone has a higher level of security
problem with that is the cost to replace
all of your unencrypted arrears
and then provision new cards for all
your employees and your that transition
phase you're rolling out its new cards
is pretty impactful to accompany him to
go in and just replace it all so chances
are usually those companies only do
things like this when they move into a
new building where they're building a
facility or even somewhere he has it
they don't go usually retrofit you know
new technology sometimes for these
things because you're talking about
pulling drywall pulling cables it's not
as easy as replacing the reader
sometimes replacing the controllers
giving everyone a new card so the the
architectural changes in the costs
obviously is is more of an impact
sometimes so this is obviously smaller
market but high-level security
facilities are probably going to have
these so we did the same thing same
concept use a large reader this time is
different models are ninety instead of a
maxi products and we took our ninety
connected on our geo to it
to wire state is your day 2012 read the
weekend data in the right to an sdcard
again same thing to 3 feet the rear ends
a little differently I class and I can
get that information I need to same
process right now as far as to what I
want to do so this kind of just give you
a high level we took it one step further
putting LCD on it
LCD prints out what it reads I don't
have to take it back to the van and
polyester information although the
Prince's lolz day there's an example of
a Reno now a cardinal and we did all
this in enforcing so you can actually go
preacher on board if you want to do and
then it gives you exact locations where
you need to sort everything go one step
further and pretty bored and connect the
Arjuna directly to the board so couple
ways you can go further with it we've
got a bit further sort of corporate into
some of our readers but concept is
pretty simple right
the Argentine assets on the unencrypted
side reads data 0221 wires that we can
information prints out the data you need
and we have a link that we have four
large consulting and hopefully we have
our code
so here's where it gets fun in 2010
someone couple of researchers milosz did
if that's how you pronounce his name up
there he did a paper that's become the
Bible of class acting is what's called
the heart of darkness are targets breaks
down everything start to finish and how
that I clasp cards work from the group
their routines to the ciphers to the
algorithms everything is in this paper
and what they discovered they were doing
their research is not this reader but
another record of you three hundred the
revision a reader's that came out had
the serial interface still enable
disable the interface given enough
research someone finally figured out how
to wire up and connect to the serial
interface and don't the firmware and saw
the firmware for the encryption keys
right class so now you could go by
revision a reader pull the firmware
encryption keys and essentially become
hid and do whatever I want to do with a
night class car because I can write my
class just like hid could so use the
data card same attacks we do with the
boss 429 now I class essentially became
a parts car to an unencrypted card if
you will because the key was stolen
right so you would think you obviously
will be changed the case your password
is compromised he has compromised
whatever it is
change the damn key right there was put
out new readers and disabled serial
nervous so it can't happen again
worst vacation ever
today they still use the same encryption
key so five years later thinking so that
he obviously isn't on paper but you go
out and you get a reader off ebay for 30
bucks all the processes outlined align
the firmware get key
so that obviously did you know a tidal
wave of things
cloning became possible which is
essentially what we do with the boxcar
to the mark as of last week just had
some functionality added to the firmware
do the same things with a class I can
close I can simulate a replay I can make
my own information generate my own tags
all those types of things all because I
have that theoretically if I had it have
the master key to do those things but
you can always call prison China and you
can buy a stock on the key reader 5321
is the model and you call China which
has been around for a long time there
were three so far from there and you buy
their eyeglass cleaner
corner really is is a key authentication
he the master key the decryption key on
USB Drive and a custom driver not unlike
the customer China thing so that's why I
have another laptop network so it's the
actual data but essentially they've
written a custom driver to interface
with this an actor's hid and give you
the ability to do the same thing we did
with aprox to take a class or do I get
my hands on one and the information
stored in the memory blocks I'll do a
quick demo at work so how easy is it to
clone that I class starts
Josh last RFID classes and they said no
so I figured this obviously would be
some dug into the research of it but at
a high level it's pretty simple to
understand right stuff is easy to
understand because it's all an assist a
vindication routine that a card is
presented to a reader
intercept that data is no difference
between the wire network like and sniff
and get a username and password you
don't have to be a genius to present
that somewhere you just figure out what
they used a password isn't how to
present it to whatever you're in this
case it's a reader not a website so
gods
here we've got a few minutes
perspective from Chi perspective you can
protect the data that's leaking off the
card if you will but really the right
way to protect these types of the tax is
protect the bag system itself more than
anything right if if i learn your
password I shouldn't be able to
compromise your entire organization and
that's essentially what happen here file
earn one piece of data off these badges
chances are good he'll be privileges to
super user and then get to where I need
to go right so this is standard security
i class when you talk about the IPSP
Starbucks cards you can do except limit
what could happen if if an attack were
to occur you can put two factors some of
the things that you actually all talk
about now so I classical want to show
that I'm not putting on this laptop has
its China the demo essentially dumps the
card information and list out the block
data stored on the card
broker now this work
security a custom key for your facility
so custom encryption key instead of the
leaky that came off of the reader so
that's where you're going with it right
and you set a custom p
there's some discoveries in that real
now with elite security high security
and the reader itself the technology
used the occasion process uses a weak
encryption which is similar to death so
many miners indifference when does this
does obviously can be brutal pretty
easily
the attack that can occur on a custom
security key applied which is high
security leak security is you can use
the products work now with new code and
present a number of indications hips
against a reader capture enough data go
back and brute force that encryption key
and then used a key versus the stolen
key and do the same thing again with a
class right so what I wanted to show
what it looks like when someone you
don't like last card
number of blocks that you are concerned
with lots 0 is the serial number
hardly any passes out there use the
serial number to indicate with you can
force as long as in the support a range
of what a night class you're supposed to
be like 12 where our data about the
court itself like six is usually card
type like seven is where the silicon the
access card number is stored block 89 is
typically wear to factor data elements
are stored by open things like that so
here's the stink about bio alluded to
earlier if in some situations if you
have to factor in place your second
factor authentication is stored on the
cart to see that again so the pin and
the bio is stored on the car so when I
walk up and resent my tagged the reader
the Reader goes card number is allowed
to authenticate facility goes live with
indicate what is your PIN or what is
your fingerprint you then enter that
data
validates that against what's on your
card lines so all I have to do is copy
Dave's card I don't care what his
fingerprint is I make an electronic
signature of my fingerprint whatever my
block a block 9 will look like or my pin
number and put that into block a block 9
in now a nice indicated that reader I
know what my pin is because I said it in
blocking blood flow to factor is that
way it doesn't exist
client-side validation everyone knows
that does web apps and things like that
his client side validation is the worst
you could have right there's nothing to
have any type of integrity about that
information is all forged so you can
overwrite information so what I want to
show was how easy it is just what the
army he to do all those blocks take a
blank card writers block back to the
heart and soul of a night class card
because I had that master encryption
stolen back in 2010 you can then
elevated privileges go one step further
and
and generate the information you need
for block seven which is your facility
code access card number and write that
down to now have gone from standard
security standard user to elevate user
because I modified my blocks of
information which is my access code for
the elevated views about 12 minutes so
again you know the class offers
encryption so someone can snoop the
connection but what good is a cryptic
easy compromise that's really what all
this boils down too so leave a minute or
two for questions is a couple of other
things that you can do it is about one
is what's called the Gecko attack attack
is essentially snapping in today 2021
wires on the backside of the reader is
unencrypted
intercept that we can data as a bad
indicates now have the information I
need to go make the badge because now of
fighting off the data that I need for
cards I so there's a tax of you can
physically get to the controller of the
wiring behind the reader which
essentially is pull the reader off all
your data one and sniffing to date all
those wires and it's what's called a
gecko attack so research and learning
more about that one
there's also the the blended threats we
talked about before right if I can gain
access to a bad system itself the
Badshah for the roses system I can
extract information off the system and
start doing what I need to do their
respective mitigation peace really is
the last talked about we're doing so I
can talk about after we're done we're
going to run out of time but there's a
there's some stuff that there were
starting to build now that will
basically simulate kind of a mesh
network of all the red team members so
maybe I have someone in the parking lot
is running the equipment and doing the
card builds and you know taking the date
of someone's feeding them out a an
operational person in the field and
using a mesh network to feed all that
data back and forth whether it's a
microcontroller that's buried
in a Micro PC with a signal connection
or 3G or 4G connection somewhere down
the field siphoning cards get the data
they need public back to the guy in the
van van's making cards in simulating tag
during those things back to the reader
in the field in the fields of walking so
creating a collaboration of team members
to expedite access into a building
essentially a one person taking the
chance of getting burned but three or
four people on it each person has a
different role within that attack and
feel that centrally to a place that we
need also being able to back door reader
itself so what if I get back to a reader
in this has been done already
back to a reader in every time someone
who hates I loaded it into something I
come back later twenty-four hours later
I take it out the reader home and I'll
get the data I need instead of taking
the chances of you know I am I gonna get
a good read a lot of people get the
right off the bat bags into the reader
for the days when sdcard ever want to
store or actual traded over 3G or maybe
the wireless on that campus and now have
gained the information I need to go back
to a reader mitigation there's there's
really not a lot you can do to protect
the tag on the cheap RFID sleeves they
do work they're decent some of them in
approving the network as well but really
what you want to do is implement a
system that has the right to technology
not something that's right to the court
there are systems out there that do
server-side validation air gap the
bestest I should be able to compromise
your Active Directory environment and an
RDP to your badges happens a lot we we
see a lot some companies now are getting
smart in their air gap in that just like
they would there be no RSA server
security service here got that thing off
the network so that I can pivot from
compromising user workstation to getting
domain admin to getting that system as I
get the bad system chances are can then
get your facility could get your access
card numbers I now who's in the building
at that time
find out what you know what access level
they have can they get there sooner or
even better what we like to do
compromises open the doors so I'm in a
bad system remotely Dave's on-site I say
goes right datacenter door open they
wanted so the blended threats up is
really where the beauty is for some of
these days and then the last thing is
something that we haven't seen as an
industry yet and that's kinda IPS
technology around that doesn't exist
today all batches of have their own
logging for good or bad whatever they
are no one's really centralizing those
logs like they do other systems in the
environments but there's really no IPS
system that would detect if someone
walked up to 50 immediate indication
tips on a reader that is exists the
chances are the only way someone
approximate
classroom or a smart route is if they
are physically see no camera someone
observes and staying there for a minute
trying to get into this reader so
there's not a lot of coverage around
some type of technology to still layer
in front of a bad system so will be and
then obviously training training
training your guard training your staff
training for what the lookout for looks
that crazy guy with a quick shout outs
number of people that get a lot of stuff
a lot of research that are way smarter
than I am about the stuff essentially
I've been able to put a lot of stuff
together and talk about how it impacts
the company but also be able to put it
into a a one hour talk versus a year so
a lot of people there that I definitely
give thanks to