michael collins i got talking to the
mike I tend to wander so I'm gonna have
to stand in front of the mic remind me
when I'm doing this I bought my robot
I'll explain him here in a second but
but yeah I'm here today to talk about
how hacking is dead which is a terrible
intro to a hacking conference but I
promise there's light at the end of the
tunnel and we'll kind of we'll kind of
talk through that so thanks to everybody
besides for putting on a really awesome
awesome conference seeing this thing bro
I think first year I came it was what 60
some-odd people
I heard it's 300 this year and that
there was approximately like an 80
person waitlist to be able to get into
this thing so I primarily to see the
keynote talk apparently I don't know so
thanks thanks Adrian Crenshaw for doing
all the video for this it's a it's a
really nice my my talk that I did at
Derby con two years ago is actually
taped and it's really nice what it's
taped sorry it's it's reported it's a
really nice way to you know be able to
kind of send people link and show kind
of you know your speaking skills kind of
stuff you worked on on things like that
so it's a nice it's a nice bonus to have
him here
big thanks to Chris Sanders for putting
on an awesome training yesterday the he
wrote practical packet analysis which is
basically the Bible on this stuff so
it's really cool to have him come into a
conference like this and do some
training thanks for letting me talk at
10 o'clock in the morning instead of 8
I'm a little a little spunkier after I
get some coffee and miso and I do I will
warn you I get a little chatty sometimes
so I've been told this time that Ben
will actually come tackle me to get me
off stage if if I talk too long so
speaking of it's 1007 ok and then you
may notice I just wanted to bring this
up I'm kind of in the middle of an
awkward breakup I've truly had a Matt I
I recently decided to get this really
nice Alienware a laptop because I could
do some gaming on it super powerful it's
way more powerful than my Mac
and as you can see I have my Mac with me
so I'm not really sure what I'm gonna do
in May I may go and get a Mac actually
again so I don't so if you were here two
years ago you might remember me I gave a
talk called drone delivered attack
platform which is basically using a
drone to deliver a wireless hacking drop
kit and I wrote the the talk from the
perspective of me attacking my
chicken-coop to kind of take the sting
out of it they'd actually propped up a
wireless network and we're doing some
stuff looking at a salacious pictures of
roosters it turned out on the internet
but but I bring that up because one of
the things I want to talk about is I've
continued to kind of evolve my kit so
I've managed to turn it into robot form
which is a completely useless it's
actually better for the drone because he
can like fly over fences at least this
guy's really slow but what's cool is
because I've coupled the kind of the
architecture of the driving with the
architecture of the hacking it uses the
trusted set tab like I did on my drone
project to call back out over Wi-Fi and
call home which means basically that I
can send this to LA have somebody power
it on it would call home and I could
drive it around as if I was standing
five feet away from it which is which is
pretty cool so now and the reason I
brought that up is because in my
original talk I had decoupled the
hacking kit from kind of the drive
mechanism of the drone now I'm kind of
back to it would be kind of cool to kind
of couple those again because you can do
the same thing with the drone again
right basically have the drone call back
out over the Internet
you know VPN into it and you could you
could literally drive the drone from you
know anywhere as long as you were within
within cellphone range so just just
brought that up is kind of a kind of a
cool aside this is actually kind of it's
it's my current kit - my software and I
just wanted to kind of bring that up for
one reason because one of the things
that we're gonna do today is this is
open to be able to hack into
so I'm gonna I'm gonna plug this in
because one of the things I'm gonna talk
about is kind of new kind of technology
and kind of looking at new technology to
hack in to things like that so I propped
my robot up if you can hack into him
before the end of the day and send me a
picture from the front of the camera of
yourself well we'll have some will have
some giveaways for you so I think I
think I heard a new car is what I heard
you're getting a literally a new car if
you if you break into the robot that's
what the besides people told me it's in
the budget so it's it's gonna be okay
yeah so there's a couple talks I decided
not to give I'm an avid I'm gonna have a
jiu-jitsu practitioner when I started I
wait around 235 pounds I've little down
a little bit since then but there's a
lot of kind of similarities between how
you learn jujitsu and how you learn
hacking it's very organic a lot of times
you feel like you're really not getting
anywhere you it's good to kind of pick
skills and kind of focus on them so that
was gonna be one of my talks that one's
on the cutting room floor I'm not giving
that one today obviously but I want to
bring that up your phone is listening to
you when I when I first saw this this is
one of those things where like your
sister-in-law sends you something and
she's like no Mike really you know
Facebook Messenger is listening to you
they listen to all your stuff and and
I'm thinking now there's there's really
no way and then you know over time
there's been some really weird things
that have happened I think everybody
here at this point has probably had
something happen where you're sitting
around at dinner you're talking about
some really obtuse subject that you
would never Google you probably never
have googled and next thing you know
it's in the the newsfeed on your on your
phone so so I thought that was
interesting the other interesting part
about it is you know how is nobody kind
of kind of figured that part out yet
well it turns out that the some of these
clients are pretty hard to get in the
middle of they're pretty hard to hack
and I I think you know some of it is
probably using code that is used for
other stuff so then I was at
at besides in Las Vegas and this guy
gave this talk about robot hacking you
see you see how I ended up here this is
this is a continuous story I promise and
one of the things he talked about it was
super interesting I was like who cares
if somebody can hack into your robot
right like I can drive your robot around
who really cares well he's talking about
all the stuff that your robot can do and
you know what it's got a GPS in it it's
got this other stuff and he's like and
it's got a gyroscope in it
and your your gyroscope can be used as a
microphone and so then I was like okay
so your your phone has a gyroscope in it
let's just pretend because all of the
all of the companies deny that they're
listening to you on your microphone to
inform ads right what if they're using
the gyroscope on your phone to process
vibrations and it knows if it sees a
certain pattern of vibrations that that
meant you talked about camping and then
all of a sudden you know it's popping up
camping ads and things like that
completely a theory I'm just you know
just just just bring that up so not what
we're talking about today feel free to
steal that talk idea by the way if you
want to do the research and stuff it
turns out it's very difficult to like
sit in a restaurant and just organically
like talk about camping and then it
never it just never does it does the one
you don't want it to do it so so what
we're here to talk about today is things
that kill our love it's not it's not my
needy nature it's I'm actually talking
about a love of hacking so we're gonna
we're gonna talk through a few things
and kind of the reason I got the idea
for this this talk is that and I go way
back so I I started literally hacking
when I was in sixth grade I'm 47 now so
it's it's been a while I've probably
been doing infoset and ethical hacking
stuff for probably about 25 years now so
I have a I have a long history in this
and the the thing that's happened you
know a number of times over the years is
people you know some new technology will
come up and people would be like well
this is gonna be the end of the need for
hacking skills right you know you know
it could be automation you know we'll
talk
endpoint protection I've heard a lot
where it's like oh you're not gonna be
able to get something running on you
know the actual device I'm not gonna
steal too much thunder on the endpoint
protection stuff because my buddy
Brandon is gonna be giving a really good
talk on that stuff but we will talk
about that a little bit but the these
are the things that have kind of come up
over the years so we'll talk about kind
of arms races and some examples of that
automation the decline in available
exploit code which i think is a really
interesting kind of topic talk a little
bit about firewalls endpoint protection
and then kind of improve programming
frameworks and how that's kind of
continually kind of killing whatever the
latest hacks are because they build they
basically build the mitigations into the
programming frameworks over time so so
kind of one of the first arms races that
occurred and this this takes your way
back to I believe the the 60s originally
but you used to be able to do something
called blue boxing so interestingly
enough the guy that's giving the last
talk mentions the same computer that I
started on back in the day which was a
TI 99 for a it had this was in fifth
grade it had no floppy drive no hard
drive it had a it was basically like a
big 20 like it was a cassette you know
thing and you saved your programs off to
cassette tape there's people here young
enough not to remember cassette tapes I
promise you but but what was interesting
about that that computer specifically is
that you could generate Hertz tones you
could generate to hurt stones on top of
each other and basically generate things
like dial tones generate a 2600 tone
which is what you needed to do to take
over you know take over a trunk line at
the time the problem here is that there
was kind of dual back back in these days
people didn't really even kind of think
about hacking right like you know just
there hadn't been hackers before so so
when they designed things they would
typically put all the documentation
house the bell labs literally would put
all the documentation out about their
signaling and kind of the the tones that
are used and things like that
it turns out that there was a few people
that discovered this independently
before the documents were published
there used to be a whistle you can hear
that that would
blow in a Captain Crunch that would blow
2,600 but but it was basically an
inbound signalling earn and banned
signaling problem right the the control
tones got sent over the same lines that
that you were talking on so you could
you can use it to get free phone calls
and things you know kind of kind of
control long-distance mechanism this was
back in the day when you had to pay for
a long-distance I know I know I know
people don't remember that anymore
either but that used to be a thing so
but what ended up happening is the phone
company had to respond to this and then
this is this is going to be the pattern
that we see continually here right so
somebody comes up with a hack they kind
of they kind of automate it so that
other people can use it in this instance
people were basically building kids for
other people to be able to do this this
is an example of kind of one of the
early kids over here Steve Jobs and
Wozniak were famous for kind of being in
this business way back in the day and
then the Hat gets widespread and then
companies have to kind of respond to it
so then then there's this arms race that
I'm talking about right you're there's
this development of the stuff that's
that's you're using the hack and then
they start developing countermeasures
and then this then you start getting
this race that goes out right so so what
happened is they basically had to
develop mechanisms to mitigate this and
not publish how that was going on which
was very unusual at the time because
Bell Labs basically published everything
that they came out with so they had to
do this in secret and they actually
modified the central offices to be able
to detect that tone so people started
getting in trouble when I say trouble I
don't know if anyone actually got got
arrested for any of this stuff for a
while because at first there was really
functionally no laws against against
hacking right so but then then
eventually this died off when they did
digital switching systems and the all
the signalling was kind of taken out of
and at that point so so for this example
this was an arms race that eventually
gets lost right we you know you can't
blue box anymore it's just not gonna
work so another another kind of arms
race that came up was was
dialing I'm gonna try and show a demo
here let's really keep our fingers
crossed that this works but this is kind
of kind of back at the start of my
career I never really did too much blue
boxing but I did a whole bunch of war
dialing the the war dialing term came
from the movie basically the only thing
that's true in the movie about hacking
is that people did war dial all the
other stuff doesn't work Ally Sheedy is
actually not going to show up at your
house and come watch you hack and think
you're cool so I was I was completely
misled I got into this business for all
the wrong reasons but but you know
basically what you would do and this is
in the days of landlines I know this is
way way back now you know nobody nobody
it doesn't have a landline seriously at
their house anymore no one no their oh
my gosh okay
holy cow okay so you know you had to be
home to answer the phone
there was no caller ID you had to
literally pick the phone up and not know
who was on the other hand there's crazy
who's crazy times you know but but what
you could do is your computer you could
literally sit it up um you know I'm
talking out of school here I was I was
under 18 at the time but you know you
would literally in the morning you'd set
your computer up to to dial just a bunch
of numbers and your exchange during the
day it would find you know you'd come
home you know find maybe you know twenty
to thirty modems that you could then go
follow up on you know they might be
bulletin board systems they might be fax
machines they might be legitimate kind
of computer systems the other thing that
was kind of happening at that time is
you know again people didn't really
think about computer hacking is a thing
and even until this movie came out and
then you know people kind of understood
that there was you know some stuff going
on but most people didn't change the
defaults for the computer systems that
they were setting up so if you dialed up
to some sort of system and you did some
research on and looked up what the
default username and password was
typically that would get you in so you
know hacking was kind of easy mode back
in this stage right you're literally
just kind of dialing around looking for
stuff
and you know that's kind of how that
worked what what ended up happening
again is the the phone company
implemented digital switching stuff they
started having to monitor for things
right so so then what you would do is
you had instead of having like like a
fixed dial rate you had to kind of
modify your timing which we're gonna see
what the port scanning thing kind of the
arms race they're very similar kind of
thing goes on and so they got they got
much better kind of detecting this so
they also had to pass some laws because
again there was it relating kind of laws
against this stuff at the time so that
you know it was it was basically you
know illegal to to try and dial a device
that that you weren't you know it had
had no intent to kind of you know
communicate with so one of the popular
war dialers at the time was called tone
log if if you go out in google tone lobe
you come up with this guy who's who's
the greatest rapper in the world
apparently but but actually he was
that's the that is the guy that they
kind of named the the program after it's
called tone locator right so we're gonna
see
I love that when demos work thank god
this was the only one I didn't think was
gonna work so so come back me come back
with me in the Wayback Machine for a
minute I need you to imagine a couple
things I need you to imagine me with a
full head of hair it was somewhat a
mullet ish kind of haircut if I could
describe it that way I'm probably
getting up getting ready for high school
or my late middle school I'm probably
playing playing Def Leppard on cassette
tape and if you don't know who Def
Leppard is it's the it's the greatest
seven-armed band on the planet so sorry
that was terrible and this could be on
video too good so so the way this one
works let me get it all typed out so you
guys can see
oh it's gotta work that's not beautiful
so um so this is kind of what it looked
like right this is this is exactly the
code that I was running back in high
school when I was doing my war dialing
it's running in a DOS emulator thanks to
emulators so actually when I first
looked up the image I'm like I bet I can
run this in an emulator that'd be really
cool and like five people here are gonna
thinks is really cool but I thought it
was cool so but you can you can see kind
of how it goes right like it just it
just you know is gonna keep dialing
numbers until it until it finds
computers and then it's gonna stack them
by you know well that was a busy one so
you know you could you could move back
around on it CDs would be carriers
detected which would be computers that
you found things like that and because
because this was written by nerds it's
got some funny features like if you hit
G it'll it'll mark it as a girl in case
a girl picked up the phone while you're
dialing I I assure you that there was
exactly zero relationships that started
this way zero exactly zero so so yeah so
that's kind of what that looked like
they eventually came out with there was
u.s. robotics modems after a while so
this got way more efficient because what
would happen is it can tell if a voice
picked up so if a voice picked up it
would hang up right away and start start
dialing other stuff but again this was
an arms race right like at first you
would do you know wait 30 seconds if you
didn't get it carrier you would move on
to the next and you could you could just
dial sequentially at first well then you
had to kind of randomize it because they
were getting savvy to it so if they saw
you you know dialing you know 1 2 3 4
they would shut you down pretty quick
then you would randomize it then you had
to randomize the timing again this is
gonna be super similar to the port
scanning stuff that we're gonna talk
about here in a second right the you
know a whole arms race where you know
the as the the attackers techniques get
better the defenders techniques kind of
rise at the same pace and kind of get
better along with them so oh yeah
it's that look okay yeah okay so yeah so
so foot scanning again back back in the
early days this is even before nmap I
know some people didn't remember a row
beforehand map but but there was there
was port scanners and it was kind of one
of the earliest kind of port scanners
was called strobe there were a few other
ones there I think the interesting thing
about this one that a lot of people
don't know is written by Julian Assange
who's the the WikiLeaks guy so he was he
was actually a super legit hacker back
in the day I don't want to say he's not
a legit hacker anymore but he did
apparently rub feces all over the walls
at his uh his that he kind of went crazy
a little bit so but but yeah so that was
his code again this was a super simple
port scanner there's no kind of ability
to do half-open scans or send scans or
any of that stuff there's no kind of
timing you know modifications to unless
you went into the code but what was nice
about this port scanner at the time
especially on high security networks is
it was basically a self-contained C file
and one of the one of the only ways you
would typically get caught on a high
security network back in the day was my
movement files back and forth right they
were there watching for that but what
you can do is you could take the C code
here you can basically get two terminals
up you could cut and paste it over to
the system and then compile it on the
other system and run it from there and
it ran fine and it was a really nice way
to kind of hop around whatever their
detection mechanisms were on things like
that that probably doesn't work that
well anymore but you know just just kind
of bring that up this again this is old
this this is exactly what inspired a few
doors who's the guy who wrote and mapped
a there was a group of
three of us at the time we had we had a
research group called basement research
but we had done some of the initial kind
of looks into kind of tcpi
fingerprinting which which which got
integrated later among a couple a couple
other things but but again you know so
nmap comes out you know you've got a
sophisticated scanner as in mapping and
you know port scanning became more
popular you know firewalls and stuff
started having better defenses so again
and map starts implementing all these
other features you know you can do you
know you can mess with your timing you
can mess with you know the type of scan
things like that to try and avoid
whatever defense mechanisms are out
there so again this was supposed to kill
hacking at the time right there they're
gonna be like no we're gonna come up
with a thing you can't poor it's key and
you really can't map as any of my sock
brethren will tell you that working a
sock currently people mostly don't care
if you port scan them anymore because
it's such a common thing so it's kind of
come back around now to where you know
you can pour it's gained just about
anything and yeah I promise you that
well I don't promise you don't go scan
the FBI they might come find you but you
know you can scan a lot of stuff and
they're not gonna they're not gonna
necessarily come come get you so DDoS
one of the first things I want to point
out is I do not consider DDoS hacking at
all it's the technical functional
equivalent of me calling a hundred pizza
guys and having them show up at your
door all at the same time but it's
somewhat effective right you know you
you get enough people who participate in
this and you can you know you can bring
down bring down networks some of the
some of the original companies the you
know got attacked kind of struggled with
this because there really wasn't any
kind of defenses in place at the time
now there's whole companies that
specialize in DDoS protection because
it's been become such a common kind of
thing I don't know if any of you were
around at the time this is going on
if you logged into the IRC Channel and
kind of read what was going on at this
time you would lose an IQ point
approximately every 30 minutes it was
some of the dumbest stuff you've ever
seen
I saw people like you know hey I found
their DNS server it's 127 dot zero dot
zero dot one and and there's literally
this whole crowd of people like yeah you
know you guys you're terrible hackers
but you know but you know they kind of
feel like they're part of something you
know so so again it's this pattern right
this pattern we keep talking about you
know hardly any defenses at first the
attackers get more sophisticated and
then every you know everything kind of
Rises at the at the same pace how am i
doing on top I'm doing pretty good
actually
so automation is one of the big ones I
want to talk about one of the big things
where I continually heard kind of about
the depth of hacking so at this time I
was probably working a lot of
professional services stuff so I used to
work for a couple of big accounting
firms for like a lot of my early career
and I would basically go around and hack
in probably every big company that you
could think of you know just that had
been hired by these accounting firms to
kind of come to pen testing and stuff
and I literally remember remember
sitting with someone one time and
they're showing the Internet security
scanner which is one of the first kind
of commercial you know braid
vulnerability scanners at the time and
he's like look Mike it's hacking and I'm
like it's kind of hacking I mean it's
you know so so the thing the thing one
of the things I want to talk about is
don't ever confuse automation with kind
of the end of what you're doing because
what's gonna happen is automation and
this is true with any hack that comes
out right like there's any exploit that
somebody comes up with if first is very
difficult to implement and then
somebody's gonna write some sort of
Metasploit module for it or something
like that and then it's become automated
then it becomes very easy to do right
you literally just go plug in a couple
of parameters kick it off and then that
exploit has been been
made it at that point but what I want us
to do is embrace automation because what
automation is automation is not killing
hacking or it's not killing things that
we do what it's doing is it's taking
pieces of what we do
automating those so that we can do it at
a wide scale so that we can move on and
do cooler things right because there's a
lot of cool things that we want to work
on as hackers there's lots of new
technology that comes out so so don't
ever think that you know automation
automation is kind of the killer of
things but but you know the war dialer
was kind of an early example of
automation you could even kind of look
at that then and be like okay this is
kind of automating functions
the thing I didn't mention when I was
talking about war dialers was again not
only could you dial during the day for
for other computers but again this was
back at the time when you had to pay for
a long distance so people had long
distance calling carts right so what you
can do is basically dial up the number
for you know for the longest where you
would put in your long-distance calling
card enter a random number if it got a
carrier on the other end it would know
you got a legit kind of long-distance
calling card number and they barely had
any monitoring for this stuff back in
the day so if you allegedly did
something like that during the day you
would come home and maybe have 20 or 30
other people's long-distance calling
card numbers that you could use to make
long-distance calls but again same type
of thing you know the the phone
companies eventually kind of got wise to
that and kind of shut that down ISS and
Expos and scanners of that you know that
same thing like it's automating the
process of mapping networks which is
something that hackers do it's
automating the process of looking for
vulnerabilities but what it what it's
it's not really killing what you need to
be doing is a hacker what it's doing is
automating some of the pieces that used
to be really painful and making those
simple so that you can spend more of
your time doing kind of the manual
techniques and things like that
same thing with web application security
scanners you know back in the day I
don't know if people
remember like the days before sequel map
trying to do like a sequel injection on
a website was super super painful oh my
god
you know it's you know you know now
we've got things like verbs that
automate a lot of that stuff we've got
programs like sequel map that automate a
lot of that stuff this makes our life
better this doesn't make this isn't like
taking something and being like oh well
that's that's not a thing anymore
again this is taking things and you know
make it making it easier so that we can
focus on cooler stuff so source code
scanning the same thing is been kind of
killing a lot of the typical exploits
that we would find were to talk about
exploits here in a second and kind of
what happened with those but again you
know it's it's it's allowing us to focus
on other things you know if the if the
source code is good and we were putting
out good programs then let's go out and
look at look at other places in the
organization where there might be
problems and kind of focus on those
right this this one really hurts my
heart you're gonna have to give me a
minute here so I I don't remember if
people remember way back in the day I'm
gonna say like in the 90s especially
there was there was really mailing lists
and things out there and so if somebody
came up with an exploit for something
you know typically they would even even
before responsible disclosure was a
thing you know they a lot of people
would typically be like look I had this
bug and this particular vendors product
I let the vendor know 30 days later they
would drop the exploit code and the the
thought at the time and I've I've
changed my thinking on this a little bit
since then and I'll explain why but the
thought at the time was it really levels
the playing field right the the bad guys
have the exploit code but the good guys
have the exploit code also so that you
can use that code to test your own
systems and find out if you're
vulnerable to this specific thing or not
right what ended up happening is people
would would automate this and they would
militarize it on a large scale so what
ended up happening is shortly after
someone would publish an exploit
someone would write some sort of scanner
that would look for it on a wide scale
and then they basically just bang across
the whole internet looking for whatever
this specific bug is and you getting
hacked at that point is not any
different than being a victim and like a
drive-by right you're literally just
happened to be on the internet with the
specific piece of software that has the
specific bug but what was nice at that
time especially if you're a protester is
you had access to a lot of good quality
exploit code without having to buy a
commercial tool or anything like that it
just tended to be freely available so
that was I don't want to say that was
the good old days of hacking I'm gonna
I'm gonna age myself again here a bit
but but it was you know it was nice
because you had you had access to really
good quality exploit code can anyone
here remember the last time that new
vulnerability came out and you had an
exploit within 90 days even I mean for
some simple stuff probably but but
what's kind of happened is there became
a market for exploit code and and
there's a couple reasons for that
the the companies founded valuable to
kind of know about this stuff before it
came out right so this is where some of
this bug bounty stuff comes and things
like that where you know people are
getting paid to develop exploits so they
don't want to give it away for free
right if you can if you can sell it the
other thing that happened is and this
this is still true if you were if you
have a zero-day X say I find a zero day
exploit and my iPhone if I did I would
be rich I wouldn't be here right now
let's be honest I mean those things go
for an incredible amount of money now
but you know if I have something like
that and I don't tell anyone about it I
basically have a skeleton key to get
into everybody's iPhone that nobody
knows about and nobody's got any kind of
protection mechanisms to protect against
right so this would be similar with any
kind of zero day that comes out right
like you get a zero day exploit that
comes out let's say it's Apache you
don't tell anyone about it well that
that's the skeleton key to get into that
Apache server
no one knows enough about it to develop
any protection mechanisms you know
there's no IDs there's no laughs in the
world that's gonna see what you're doing
because no one
all snows about it so then what happened
is these things got attractive to
government agencies and intelligence
agencies and things because you know we
you know I we there's you know the NSA
has huge groups of people
I think it's called tailored access
operations I think is what they call it
but you know people that literally their
job is to go break into other computers
you know from you know from an
intelligence standpoint and try and get
access to things so they find things
like that super valuable so what's kind
of happened is we've gotten into this
age now where when exploits come out
they may most likely be being developed
by by some sort of government agency not
only us you know the US has used
capabilities here but you know China has
incredible capabilities in this area you
know Russia's got really incredible
capabilities in this area and they have
just huge teams of people that are super
smart that can get paid a lot they have
you know kind of unlimited research
budgets to go do this stuff so a lot of
zero-days now kind of sit with people
that you probably wouldn't want to have
them you know unless unless you're a
terrorist or something I you know I
don't think you're probably a target I
don't I don't think they really care
about my you know my pub pictures or
anything like that probably but you know
it's it's kind of it's kind of where
things have gone is you know there's
just not this kind of availability of
exploit code anymore now interestingly
enough if you talk to red teamers this
day and you ask them like well in the
course of you know because then when I
define red teamer I'm saying you know
typically you know maybe like a Mandy
Anderson or a company like that where
they come in and they basically do two
things they they start off with an
assumed breach so they they basically
you know give us a workstation we're
gonna have access to we're gonna see how
much damage we can do in your
environment
and and I asked someone I'm like well
how much exploit code do you typically
use in the course of a day or a year and
he's like zero you're basically living
off the land anymore right on that stuff
so as kind of the availability of
exploit code went down they've kind of
ship
two different techniques yeah and
they're kind of assuming kind of an
internal kind of you know they've
already got access access to stuff so
[Music]
firewalls were another technology that
came out again it was supposed to kill
basically everything that we do as
hackers you know first it was just basic
Network firewalls quickly we learned
that you know you have to open the
firewall for some stuff and the some
stuff tends to be vulnerable so if you
can get into the some stuff you're
behind the firewall and then you can
kind of kind of weave your way around
and do damage there's next-gen firewalls
now like palos and things and then
there's web application firewalls that's
down a lot of some you know especially
sequel injection and things like that
the thing we'll talk about here in a
minute is you know you have to do your
testing sometimes assuming that controls
will fail you know there's there's all
the times where you know you have a Web
Application Firewall and you think it's
doing what it should be doing and
somebody comes out with some sort of
bypass or something or maybe the the
laughs is down you know something like
that
I really want to kind of encourage
people to start thinking about things
from kind of a deconstructed perspective
you know don't don't assume that if
you're hacking something and you didn't
get in that day that that should be the
end of kind of your exploits because you
know what you should really be thinking
of is here's kind of here's kind of my
application here's all the layers of
stuff that protect it and maybe I want
to go pick on the Web Application
Firewall specifically for awhile right
because because again you know controls
will fail and some especially like
network pentesting anymore has become
very situational right like if there
happens to be an exploit out that day
that works on a particular system that
you find and you catch them between when
the exploit came out and when they put
the patch down you know you're gonna
have a successful you know engagement
there unless you know you're somebody
like you know a trader sore someone
who's sitting on like this whole army of
people who reverse engineer in their
sleep and right
you know right zero days you know
constantly it's just not within a normal
pen testers capability typically to be
writing zero days on the fly so what I'm
saying is the fact that you know it's
kind of time-based so you need to be
able to kind of test like all of the
controls and an account for the fact
that maybe you know maybe there isn't an
exploit and an Apache that comes out you
know next month and then what happens to
you when that when that happens right an
end point protection this one kind of
cracked me up for a while I'm gonna I'm
gonna let Brandon talk about this one a
lot
this is again where I heard a lot that
this is gonna be the death of hacking
right you know we've got stuff on our
end point now you can't land malware on
there that's gonna work anymore you know
whitelisting was a big thing you know
we're basically you have a list of
allowed programs and because of that
your your malware is just absolutely not
gonna run on the end point we all know
especially uh people that work in
security operations centers that
typically nowadays you know people don't
come hack through the front door right
the the days of you know people haven't
really week perimeter defenses are kind
of gone for the most part there are some
examples but you know typically you know
it lands on your workstation somewhere
you know you've got you've got some
button clicker in your organization you
know you send them an email I actually
decided that the security education and
this front is completely useless
I've seen it's true it's true
I uh it has to be technical controls I
don't care how many times you send
people fake spam messages or you know
you can do talks you can do all this
other stuff my experience has been that
no matter how much education you do with
your users the the numbers stay roughly
the same you know you can make them a
little more savvy and I've seen some
cool stuff we're like you know it'll
alert you know on things in your you
know in Outlook to kind of you know help
you make some better decisions but but
you never you're never going to get that
number down to zero and you have to get
that number down to zero because it just
takes one person right you just need one
person to click on a link and all of a
sudden somebody's landed on your and
network and they're running they're
running all over the place any of my big
any of my big sock operations will tell
you that this is still a constant battle
right no matter how good their and we're
talking about really really big
companies that have all the money in the
world to spend on protection
capabilities and they still it still
ends up landing on the workstation and
and you've got problems so similar to
obeying you know and this is what I tell
people all the time you can't have
perfect security ever right you can have
pretty good security that's going to
keep out most people and then what you
need is really good monitoring
capabilities to kind of detect when
things go wrong so that would be the the
bank alarm that goes off and hopefully
what happens is the police show up in
time to catch the robber which is what
we want out of our out of our security
operations right so man I'm gonna hit
this right on time on that on that front
just to talk talk a little bit this was
kind of the arms race again right so you
know originally it was really easy to
kind of land malware on a workstation as
endpoint protection improved there was
kind of these things that came up to
basically like obfuscate your malware
code I will tell you that running Python
through veil is still like magic pretty
much for the most part it gets by a lot
of stuff but you know there's you know
there's a you know ms/ms a venom there's
a you know veil and then lo P a lot a
lot of people know lo P here he was he's
a local guy that's out in Denver now
when one of my favorite people but he
wrote he wrote Great Scott which is
basically a tool to kind of help you get
around whitelisting it'll kind of buzz
through stuff until it finds things that
works and things like that and then
Metasploit actually just come out with a
new evasion module so you know these
these things again it's an arms race but
this is this has been an imperfect
science you know no matter no matter how
did this this stuff is that this that
comes out no matter how good kind of
obfuscation techniques are people still
find a way to make things work and and
they do this in mass it's it's pretty
crazy you know
they have this all all kind of
militarized and make it make it work at
scale so a lot of a lot of these botnets
and things and things that exist now it
exists because of this kind of
deficiency and this ability to kind of
detect things like this improve
programming frameworks so this this is
kind of the other thing that goes on is
as time goes on programming frameworks
are making it harder to be a bad
developer at least a bad developer from
a security perspective I've always been
really surprised because you look at
things from a hackers perspective for so
long and then when you talk to
developers they have very different
considerations and I think that's one of
the things we all need to think about
sometimes right is they need to get
things working they need the users to be
happy with the code but a lot of times
security is kind of a secondary
consideration to what they have going on
right so traditionally you know it was
it was not uncommon for me like to test
a web application and find a cross-site
scripting and then go talk to the
developer and they hadn't ever heard of
cross-site scripting you know so they
they just they don't a lot of times I
just don't think you know like a hacker
does so but what's happened is let you
know languages have improved
you know Python is you know super
popular kind of you know scripting type
language now but you know it kills a lot
of stuff like you know buffer overflows
and things like that that used to were
to work on something like a C language
or something like that and then you know
programming frameworks have gotten a lot
smarter and kind of force you down the
right path right so it's much it's
becoming much harder if you implement
you know programming frameworks properly
you know to do the wrong thing in your
code so so again you know this is this
is improve things the yeah so why why
can't you kill hacking which is kind of
where we're trying to get to here right
why why why all this stuff that keeps
coming up and hacking is still super
prevalent and we still seem to be able
to do what we want from the
most part on systems and things well the
first thing is is it the people problem
right people people are button clickers
you know again you know talking about
the fishing thing you know you can't you
cannot do enough education to where
you're gonna have someone that doesn't
get some email and and they're going to
click on it and they're in the work
station is gonna be owned
so social engineering just in general is
tends to be a really big problem I would
say over the course of my career
probably have broken into about half as
many systems through social engineering
as I have through technical means and I
think that lines up with a lot of other
people who have worked in this space I
know I know kevin Mitnick was real
famous for you know for kind of being a
really good social engineer but you know
I looked like I'm a nice guy you know I
stroll up you know I kind of chitchat
with the you know the person guard in
the lobby and next thing you know I'm
kind of in the building
you know plugged in in a conference room
and the defense is looking much
different from that perspective than
they do when you're trying to hit them
from the internet I always tell people I
think that's a super unlikely attack I
said you know the reason that I'm good
at it is because I have a letter in my
pocket that says you're not going to
take me to jail if you catch me because
I'm they're supposed to be doing it on
purpose and it's really hard to put a
nerd in a suit sometimes and make them
look like like they're supposed to be
there so I got complete a suit on and
look look reasonably like I'm supposed
to be there so but but yes social
engineering is not going away you know
calling people up talking talking them
out of stuff over the phone you know
fishing all these types of things are
not going away so and have always been a
problem again developers don't think
like hackers right
so so kind of forcing them down a path
to you know to do better stuff you know
source code review having these
frameworks that kind of continually
review source code as they're doing
development and things help help kind of
that problem a lot but I especially
noticed this in newer thing so one of
the things I noticed about my robot when
I first propped him up is I started
digging in on the code it was
terrible it's literally terrible and I'm
like but again this is new technology so
you know old problems resurfacing right
you know you you get established
technology they work the kinks out for a
while you know the problems tend to go
away and then they implement some new
feature and all of a sudden some 20 year
old bug is back in the product or you
know maybe it's just new technology you
know you know Internet of Things or you
know your Smart TV you know all of these
types of things again are a lot of times
developed without really thinking about
the security implications of them so one
of the things I would encourage you to
do is to always really really be
thinking about kind of what the next
thing is right so don't don't don't kind
of if you become a really good network
pen tester don't know it's it and think
I've developed a really good network pen
testing skills you should be thinking
about you know developing you know some
some web application hacking skills or
some highly encourage people to develop
some reversing skills these days because
a lot of a lot of hardware hacking kind
of requires some of that but you know
don't don't don't kind of don't kind of
sit around you know continually be kind
of thinking about the next thing to
study I have always just kind of gone
out and studied what I think is
interesting and that's never really
failed me it's actually always been kind
of kind of interesting to see like I'll
be studying some particular technology
and like a week later comes up on some
hack that I'm doing or something like
that so you know I really encourage you
just to kind of you know you know let's
just study what you find interesting you
know we all do this because we love it
and that that's part of that's part of
why we're good at this stuff right is
because you know we don't we don't see
this as pain but there there are people
out there who literally like kind of
kind of find things and just kind of sit
on them and then they're like okay I'm
good at this and you can't you can't do
that in this field because things are
moving too quickly the targets are
moving they keep moving our cheese so to
speak right you know they move the
cheese from one side of the maze to the
other and if you're sitting over here
waiting on them to drop cheese again
you're not going to find it you know you
got it you got to be be be kind of agile
new technologies are coming out quicker
than then defenses right and traditional
things so as much as sometimes it seems
like things that I used to hack that
were fun to hack or not hackable anymore
and I say that with reservation because
everything's hackable from some you know
from some standpoint but you know
there's all this new stuff that's
continually coming out so the growth the
growth of things you know they're new is
for sure outpacing the the pace of
things that are getting buttoned up
properly so and then defenses are always
imperfect right so so again think of
think of think of things from a controls
perspective you know don't don't go out
and maybe bang on the front door of your
internet connection and think things are
okay kind of deconstruct that internet
connection and be like well I'm gonna go
pick on the web server for a little
while in the absence of the laughs you
know and see how that looks so I'm gonna
go pick on the firewall or I'm gonna
pick on the intrusion detection system I
think you'll be amazed if you kind of
take that approach to things sometimes
how much how many controls that you
thought were operating properly or not
operating like you would expect you know
you're gonna find gaps there I guarantee
you and it's just because there's kind
of this tendency to you know you put a
firewall up and you're like okay the
firewall is good and then you never
really loop back around and retest it so
and then you know kind of kind of
expanding your influence this would this
would be for a lot of people you know
well and and first of all before I get
there you know III don't want people to
think that you know to be a good hacker
to be a good insecurity you know you
have to have started in in sixth grade
you know and have been doing this a long
time some of some of the people that I'm
most most proud of you know started kind
of later in life Sean who's who's one of
my favorite people on the planet you
know was it a talk of mine and decided
he wanted to get into this he just got a
black badge at derbycon you know super
super proud of that guy
Aaron Miller which is one of the guys
that I originally started with when we
did the basement research stuff was a
was a lawyer or an accountant by trade
and just like a Linux hobbyist and just
decided pick security up so it literally
anyone can pick I don't say anyone can
pick this up up you know but you know if
you're interested in it you have the
drive there's there's a ton of you know
need in this space right now there's a
ton of jobs out there and you can kind
of take your pick of things that that
you want to work on I definitely want to
encourage you to I'm gonna hits us right
on time this is great
embrace embrace automation so don't
don't think of automation is as evil
think of automation is the thing that's
kind of helping helping your job helping
automate the detection of things in a
quicker manner to enable you to move on
to cooler stuff I want you to think of
that think of it like that don't ever
think of automation as oh my god this I
came up with this really cool hack
someone wrote a Metasploit model for it
now everybody can do it you shouldn't
think of it like that this is what
enables you to move on to cooler things
I think think of hacking as a skill that
can be broadly applied maybe maybe your
job is not necessarily a a hacker but I
think thinking about things from a
hackers perspective it can be valuable
to just about anyone's job
I recently transitioned to I'm not
working specifically in InfoSec I'm
working on some internal cloud things
and software-defined networking things
and what I found is my hacking
backgrounds super valuable in that space
because you know again it's it's Linux
containers again what's old is new we're
back we're back to Linux again you know
you know understanding firewalling and
things like that all super important in
that space so so think think of hacking
as a skill that you can kind of broadly
apply to your job and and other things
attack emulation is kind of something
cool that's kind of been coming up
lately but a lot of people is they're
developing these controls frameworks
especially like like miter attack and
things like that having the ability to
automate attacks and be able to do them
at scale and repetitively so again so
that you can go test individual controls
and things is super valuable so again
kind of having an attacker mindset and
that spaces is really valuable because
you can basically take things that you
do on a day to day basis use them in an
applied framework and then use that to
kind of broadly test lots of things it
really kind of gives you the ability
instead of like I'm gonna go look at
this today you can you know hit it all
all over the place and kind of you know
kind of apply that on a lot of things an
incident response is somewhere where you
can plug in in your organization if
you're like on the pen test team I I'm
always shocked when I see C socks that
don't rope in the hackers when something
big happens because I find that the
hackers especially your internal hackers
that have kind of been engaged to be
continually testing your defenses have
some really good ideas when a real hat
goes down as far as like oh well I think
maybe they're trying to do this because
I know this is over here or they're
trying this technique or you know it's
really good to kind of plug those guys
in there so if you're an internal pen
tester and you're not involved with your
sock I would encourage you to to get
involved with your sock if you can as a
way to kind of expand your influence and
kind of kind of functions at your at
your company their vulnerability
validation is a really interesting one
too I'm getting the the Aaron's gonna
come tackle me here in one minute so
yeah but he's got a long way to run so
yeah I have a vulnerability validation
as part of you know vulnerability
management is a good one to plug in to
kind of kind of doing proof of concept
things on vulnerabilities to show if
they work or not secure design physical
security and social engineering like we
talked about already and then again you
know focus on new technologies as they
come out because those are gonna kind of
be the new thing Charlie Miller's a
famous local guy he's the guy that's the
the jeep hacker but everybody's heard
about he was famous for kind of you know
he was originally like famous for
breaking in a max and then he would go
out to this pond on come
in every year and they and him and his
buddy wouldn't run over the max and then
then he was the iPhone hacker you know
so he's been really good about doing
what I'm talking about which is you know
don't don't sit in one spot you know he
kind of figured out what the next thing
was and so now he's you know he's kind
of the famous car hacker guy so so yeah
you know just kind of move on to things
you know move on to new technologies and
kind of kind of study what uh what
you're passionate about so and that is
the end according to the sign right at
the back thing thank you everyone