one our next talk is by Eric Lee he's
traveled away from Kansas City to be
with us today he's gonna be talking
about IT burnout
so here's Eric thank you
okay so Oh pictures crazy this is gonna
be a different talk than you've probably
seen in most conferences this is not
gonna be a technical talk in any way
shape or form so just be aware that it's
non-technical number one and number two
this is going to be my story about me
you may be able to take things from it
but that'll vary depending on who you
are and where you're at in life okay
so about me again my name is Eric Lee
I've been an IT for a little over 25
years my friends always call me the
weird person in IT because I'm not into
sci-fi Lord of the Rings any of that
stuff like that so when they start
talking about Star Trek I just kind of
like tone-deaf and in glazed-over look I
do a lot of got a lot of dirt track
races and build things and and do other
things like that so that's what I'm into
all right what we're here for
IT burnout how many people have heard
about IT burnout much over the last
couple years yeah there you go
so I've written this presentation a
couple years ago I submitted it to about
six conferences I got turned down for
all of them and I was like this sucks
so I said after about four or five beers
one night I said screw it I banged out a
blog post on it send it over to a friend
and I was like what do you think about
this and they were like this needs to be
in the community so I hit submit with my
finger shaking two posts and closed my
laptop went to bed next day I had a ton
of responses and everybody saying we
should be talking about this stuff and
I'm like well that's funny because none
of the conference's want me to so I
don't know what to do so I went through
right I would through burnout a couple
times but I never really thought about
it when it happened because burn
was never talked about in the community
for about the first 15 years that I was
in IT I'd heard about it twice couple
people in the community committed
suicide we talked about it for two or
three weeks and then it just disappeared
right like a lot of other topics that we
deal with so when I was going through
burnout I had no idea at first that's
what it was
right it was not around we didn't talk
about it so I had no idea but after
going through it twice I think about it
every day right it's something I have to
stay on top of so I don't go through it
again I would like to say I was normally
say right now we don't talk about it
enough in the community but we're
getting better at it I if you haven't
noticed the mental health village over
here has phenomenal information about
burnout and mental health over there too
so please stop by look at their
literature talk to somebody if you need
to even though we're doing this we still
need to do a better job mental health
soft skills stuff like this is no
different than the technical skills that
we're learning at this conference we
need to be helping out each other make
sure everybody is aware of what's going
on look out for each other
and help them through it so this is my
journey through IT burnout starting when
I was little so a little background
information I grew up in a busy family
had two brothers a ton of cousins know
most all boys my parents got married
were in there 18 had an older brother in
there 19 myself when they're 21 I spent
most of my time hanging around family
and friends riding bikes skateboarding
you know playing kick-the-can anybody
kick the can
yeah miss that game and BB gun wars lots
of BB gun wars huh we were they called
free range kids anybody else yeah just
be home before the lights come on or
else you get your your your butt beat
right my parents were working all the
time so we just we were just kind of
running around doing whatever we could
kill time as I got older my things
changed that I did best friend I helped
build that race car and the top left
your left from the ground up we borrow
his dad's flatbed truck went and bought
it at the junkyard and we did everything
but put the roll cage in it you know I
played baseball I played golf I played
on a competitive traveling soccer team
we went all over the Midwest my parents
as I said worked a bunch of hours they
tried to make it to our events what they
could but they couldn't make it to all
of them we weren't poor by any means but
we didn't have a lot of money either I
vividly remember going the grocery
stores a couple times with my mom you
know my brothers in tow and we couldn't
check out because her check wouldn't
clear so we we got by but we didn't have
the money to always go to the doctor and
go do all these other things after high
school I moved to Kansas City to play
college soccer I'm completely on my own
now you know physically mentally and
financially my dad gave me 20 bucks for
gas and said good luck son
two years playing soccer my parents saw
one of my college soccer games but not
only I go to school full time in order
to pay for this I had to work full time
one year I even had eleven w-2s
that's how busy I was on top of playing
soccer I also held executive positions
in the fraternity I was in I was busy
all the time sometimes I don't remember
when I slept but I was busy had to do
what I had to do to survive and get done
in the jobs I was working most of them
were in the IT field so to me just being
busy isn't IT burnout after college I
spent four years doing a back-end
systems integration for the company I
worked at our company was bought out by
another one in Finland so I was in
charge of all the Americas so I did
across five companies back in systems
integration for Active Directory and
some other things and then after those
first two years I actually got to do it
globally so someone for the Midwest who
vacation was going to your grandparents
house in the next town over going to
Finland going to Sweden go into
Australia Sal Paulo all these other
places was awesome
I traveled over 80% of the time those
four years some weeks when we were doing
cut overs I worked 90 hours that we even
more okay lots of long hours I felt the
stress of getting the job done that week
but nothing that didn't go away you know
once we were done with that we got that
site done you could breathe you'd come
back you'd have a few days to get caught
up before you would go to the next one
or what have you he was a lot of work
and there was some stress but I still
enjoyed other activities that I did with
my other friends when I actually had
time so to me just working long hours by
itself isn't IT burnout
the only thing that is constant is
change this has been around for quite a
while and this is kind of where things
started taking a shift during the last
year of that long project I was on and
then the following two years there was a
hugely noticeable change in the company
I worked at specifically in our team
none of our internal customers were
happy with us anymore
none of our projects were getting fully
funded we were losing good teammates
that were leaving to go somewhere else
and in general our overall morale was
just down people weren't happy I wasn't
happy because because projects weren't
getting funded in the manufacturing
company I worked at the manufacturing
side of the company were hiring their
own IT staff to make up for it
and on top of that they put in their own
switches their own servers and
everything else right next stars it was
ridiculous by this time I'd worked there
11 years and my boss at the time had
been my boss for about six years he just
really didn't care he hid like well
that's great less work we have to do
this is awesome right I implemented a
ton of the improvements over the years
that were there I really felt like I was
a part of the company but I was pissed
off at my boss I really hated him okay I
wanted to do even more for the company
but my boss was an idiot but to me not
liking my boss or that job or that
company by itself is not IT burnout I
didn't know how much like stress and
everything else that was going on with
this and my boss and some of the other
things during this time until I was
watching TV with my wife one day and I
can still remember this vividly it was
in the basement downstairs to the left
sitting on the couch watching TV I can't
tell you what's on the TV because I had
no idea I was so engulfed in what I was
doing like thinking about work and
everything else I don't remember it was
on the TV but my wife I can still
picture it she asked me what are you
thinking about and I'm like why she said
look at your hand and my left hand
just shaking like tremors like I've had
Parkinson's for 15 years or something
like that I was like oh crap there it is
something's going on right we started
talking about how I felt you know what I
was thinking about you know how I
physically felt stuff like that and it
became obvious that I couldn't even
watch TV without fixating on what was
going on at work as we talked over the
next few days there was other symptoms
that came about I speak sarcasm as a
primary language anybody else yep there
you go
sarcasm usually like you're right on
that line of being snarky right that can
go bad versus the sarcasm well I didn't
tiptoe that line I like jumped in with
both feet when I was in that well and I
didn't realize it until my wife brought
it up I was extremely snarky to the
point where I was just being mean about
stuff that didn't matter at all like
leaving a jacket out or something like
that
I was never physically being or or
anything like that to her but just these
snide little comments all the time other
things I hated going to the movies
anymore I hated paying money to go to a
movie that when it was over I could
remember anything that actually happened
because I'm thinking about work right
the other thing is I would play freecell
like for hours and have no idea how many
games I won or lost you're just clicking
right have you ever seen that men like
Oh was at Homer he found the end of the
Internet I would just be like searching
through the internet at times and have
no idea what I was looking for what I
looked at so in essence I was wrapped up
so much into my work that I wasn't
looking out for my own mental and
physical health
my wife had seen a lot of these signs
but we never really talked about him and
part of that is is back to how I was
brought up as a free-range kid with
mostly boys doing mostly stupid stuff we
never talked about our feelings ever
my wife on the other hand is from almost
all females and they still to this day
talk at least once a day about what's
going on about everything in life so
it's really hard to get somebody who
wants to talk about everything and
somebody who wants to talk about
absolutely nothing to actually talk
about feelings together it's kind of
like getting people that like vm's to
talk to people who likes kubernetes
right it's the same thing so I didn't
know what else did you I know I didn't
want to be at the company anymore but I
also didn't want to leave because I'd
been there for so long and done all that
but I was burned out on the job the
situation the tech that was there the
amount hours I was putting in all of it
so what did I do
well not much actually or could be a lot
depending on who you are and how you
feel about things I just changed jobs
that fixes everything right after
spending some time reflecting I was like
you know I just gotta go luckily didn't
take long for me to find a new job and
within two weeks of starting my new job
the shaking went completely away when I
was at home my wife is like hey there
you are again I know this person right
but what did I actually change
nothing nothing at all
well actually you know not nothing but
very very close right so start a new job
was there about three and a half years
had a lot of the same things I had at my
previous job we merged with another
company more integrations long hours I
had to get rid of Lotus Notes puke very
stressful projects the company I worked
at was in marketing advertising area it
was 2008 recession budget cuts again you
know but through all of this I didn't
have any of the shaking I didn't have
the excessive snarkiness I didn't have
any of that stuff so I had absolutely no
symptoms of IT burnout and then one day
I'm out shoveling the driveway and the
guy cross streets like hey I'm looking
for somebody that knows all this stuff
I'm like okay cool like I'm interested
it's like yeah we're trying to do a CI
CD journey I need to automate all this
stuff we don't know how to do it I'm
like sweetie that's right up my alley
let's go do it so I took this other job
and it was awesome
free rein to do whatever we wanted to
take a manual process of building and
testing code and completely automated it
so they would do five builds a week and
test it for a full stack and report on
it within about four or five months we
got it down to automated no touch
testing every 12 hours of about a
hundred and fifty tests and from that
point on it just grew and grew and grew
the it was the best job I ever had
because I 50 percent of my job was to go
to conferences look at software look at
processes do whatever we can to make
this process better and faster the VP of
our company was full-on like he he
understood that this was gonna make our
software better you know customers
happier everything like that it was
awesome the most challenging part of the
job was every year we had a client
conference and I was in charge of the
lab infrastructure for them to run stuff
on I didn't have to do the content of
the labs but I had to have the lab front
end and the back end stuff as well too
and it usually took about three to four
months to get that all set up and
working one year we're having problems
with the cloud vendor getting their
stuff working right and it was Thursday
and the conference starts on Monday
and we're doing the conference in
Orlando and my coworker he looked over
at me and he was like hey dude er you're
all right I'm like why and he goes look
at your hand
and I started shaking again so I looked
down at it and it was probably about a
fifth as bad as it was previously before
luckily I kinda remembered most of the
symptoms I've had the last time so took
a step back looked at all the other
symptoms I wasn't being snarky I enjoyed
hanging out with friends I enjoyed going
the movies Jay enjoyed a lot of that
stuff so I didn't think I was in burnout
this time after we arrived in Orlando a
few days later I called the vendor we
ran another test everything worked
successfully right 30 minutes later look
down my hands not shaking anymore so I
just wrapped that up to stress should
have probably gone to a doctor yeah but
let's go back and think about you know
where I came from we didn't talk about
her feelings we didn't go to the doctor
we didn't talk to doctors about her
feelings yeah you know people like this
right yeah same kind of deal so even
though I had some physical stuff I
related it to mental stuff and in our
realm you don't go to the doctors for
mental stuff or physical stuff unless it
can't be cured with duct tape in paper
towels superglue all right so so during
this time I was been recruited by a
reseller that I'd known for a while I
never really wanted to go over there
because I didn't like some of the
management at this time there was about
five people that I'd worked with at a
previous company that were there and
they're like it's different come on over
it's great you know we've changed
so I was trying to decide if I should
stay at the best job I ever had or
should I go to this other place pros and
cons I could go help some other
companies you know would be great I can
learn new things about how other places
do it it was I thought it would be
awesome so um and it worked last time
right to change jobs like let's just do
this again so I changed jobs and the
first nine months it was awesome met a
lot of people loved my customers most of
them it was awesome
and then all of a sudden after nine
months some practices came back or
showed up that I didn't like some weird
things that I didn't think were I don't
know how to put it like I just didn't
agree with them like sharing data that
shouldn't be shared to the sales staff
or what have you and then I got blasted
by the the the CEO of the company to the
whole entire sales team for two things
that I had nothing to do with and when
it was finally shown to him that I had
nothing to do with it he just kind of
blew me off like oh no big deal you know
he's just a peon it shouldn't matter and
there was no retractions than now
it was awful like the the crappy part of
the company he'd come back and and I
just you know had to go but before they
could even get out of there I lost half
my account managers as they hired
somebody else in another area that part
of the company or that those account
managers accounted for roughly 60% of my
quota if anybody in sales in sales if
you don't know your salary is really
small and most your money comes from
your bonuses from getting your quota so
now I've lost the potential to even make
quota because they didn't really Jeff
tur losing them so there is no way I
could even remotely provide for my
family
like I would able to before yeah on top
of all this I left the best job I ever
had in my life and now I have a wife and
two kids so
not only am I not being able to provide
for myself but my wife and two kids the
way it was before every time I needed
work on TAS you know before I left I
would catch myself repeatedly thinking
about that last job I had and I just
couldn't let it go I faded into some
depression previous symptoms all came
back the good news this time as I was
able to recognize the symptoms I took a
different job with another company in an
area where I wasn't excited to be but I
had to get out of where I was at just to
get away from there's terrible people
the problem is is that a couple of my
good friends when I talk to them about
taking this job they told me not to do
it don't go there so one of the things I
had sitting in the back of my head this
whole time is the I told you so
right that's one of the worst things
ever and I didn't want to hear it
because of that I closed off myself I
didn't go to social activities with them
I stayed out of the community I did a
lot of things I quit doing a lot of
things I used to do before
so changing this changing jobs again
didn't make me happy and honestly like I
alluded to earlier earlier it never did
now I was still depressed every day I
would see somebody from the old
organization where I was at before cuz
we were in the same area of town and it
would just remind me that I left the
best job I ever had for the worst job I
ever had my window where I said looked
right at the old building where I was at
so it was damn near impossible to get
anything done I was in burnout again
false depression full everything else
and I couldn't get myself out so let's
talk about a couple things real quick
I've stated some things that you've
heard in the past that working long
hours is burped out just don't work long
hours and you won't be burnt out okay
that's not it
so that and some of the others what does
IT burnout to me
to me it's any combination of these
areas that are being far enough
quote-unquote out of whack that leaves
you exhausted day after day to the point
that you stop doing the things that you
normally do so make sense so for some
people it might be one or two of these
for other people it's all of these it's
gonna be different for everybody but for
me it was pretty much all of them and
what's different about burnout and IT
versus just depression right cuz some
people have asked me hey Eric
your just depression why is this IT
burnout well I think IT can be different
in some areas right we're always
connected and have been before the rest
of the world was really always connected
we're always trying to keep up with new
technologies new methods new stuff like
that there's always more and more and
more a lot of times now we don't even
get breaks between projects right when I
was an IT years ago like you'd have a
project and then when you're done you
would at least have a couple weeks or if
not for two like before you started
working on next big project you'd have
some smaller stuff but now it seems like
you're not even halfway done with wine
and you're starting the next one and
then the first one never gets done
because you don't have enough time to
finish it and you're just in this
constant cycle of chasing your tail
right
sometimes it's the repetitive work you
know the monotonous clicking the same
thing over and over and over again right
having no real buy into what you're
doing the concept firefighting in some
places right you never can get ahead
because you like I said earlier constant
firefighting and then sometimes it's
just supporting those crappy old legacy
systems can just they just suck right
all right one more thing to talk about
right now let's talk about the suicide
because I'm guessing at least one person
here is thinking you know he hasn't said
anything about suicide you know he
there's no way he went through IT
burnout well let's talk about that not
everyone who has burnout or depression
automatically goes to suicide I'll be
candidly honest I
thought about suicide I thought about it
multiple times the number of hours I
thought about it could fill up a couple
months set my car in parking lots
thinking about it staring up at the sky
you know not going home to my wife and
kids thinking about it be better off for
me to not be here the reality is for me
the way I thought about it is sometimes
when we think about taking one of those
exotic trips to some island that you can
only see by zooming all the way into it
right on on Google Earth I thought about
it a lot about not being around but I
never thought about exactly how I would
do it and where I would do it or
anything like that I never thought about
what airplane I would have to take to
get there
what boat I'd have to then take or any
of that other stuff so not specifically
thinking about all that I mean doesn't
mean that you have not been in Burnout
or in severe enough depression of state
depressive state that you need to look
at help all right time to move forward
right why am I here now talking about
this how did I get there so I have some
friends that I meet with regularly and
they noticed I was in a bad state and
they would try to talk to me in all this
stuff right but as I said before we
never talked about our feelings yeah
heck by this time in my life my dad has
only told me he was proud of me twice
ever you know and this is only six years
ago so and I'm not young that's kind of
how I was brought up so we never talked
about feelings but talking to my friends
my peers felt easier because I felt that
you guys work in an IT can relate versus
talking to my wife who doesn't work in I
see she would have no idea right so it
was getting easier to talk to them but
talking didn't automatically you know
make me stop obsessing about leaving the
best job I ever had
right how like I just couldn't stop
obsessing about it so one day I'm out
with a friend who
doesn't work in IT and we're at the bar
just sitting there having a couple
drinks up to work and I'm staring
directly through the TV again and he's
chirping on about something I probably
golf or something stupid and finally he
was like hey dude like what's going on
I'm like wait what and he's like what
are you thinking about like what's going
on you're you're you're not being a good
friend here like what's happening so
after a while I finally gave in I told
him told him how I ruined my life by
leaving the best job I ever had for the
worst job I ever had and now I can't get
the best job ever head back and I'm
never gonna find another one and I'm a
loser and I'm dumb yada yada yada yada
and you know what this is what he said
sometimes you need to that friend to
just give you that little kick in the
rear end you know what I mean
like sometimes the touchy-feely stuff is
great for certain areas and sometimes
you need somebody to just kick you where
you need to be kicked so how did I get
out of this
I needed a strategy I started with one
and I worked my way up to six but I I
needed to figure out ways to combat this
to where it didn't happen again no
matter where I worked and what kind of
environment I worked in so let's go
through these six support system first
off I had to get rid of the idiots I
hung around with that all they did was
complain all the time about how bad
their life is in every single way shape
or form now I was doing that myself so
this was hard because I had to look at
some of them and decide you're just an
idiot and I don't need to be around you
anymore because you're negative all the
time
and you're going through the or the
other hand is you're going through the
same stuff I'm going through we need to
help each other out and move forward and
that one was really hard um
these people I had to make sure that
they had my back as much as I'm willing
to have their back and if they're not
willing to be there for me when I really
need them then I probably don't need
that in my life
the other thing I had to do with this is
talk to my boss and this is extremely
extremely extremely difficult luckily
I had a pretty good boss at the time my
late my current boss well he just left
yesterday so it sucks but he's awesome
both of those we talked about what
triggers my depression you know I like
to fix everything on my own and
sometimes I'll get stuck fixating on the
problem for days and days and days and
days and days and days and days anybody
else yeah yeah and then you got to get
that tunnel vision and then you find
yourself slipping into that like spot
and my boss I'm like listen if you see
me doing that like just kick me like
let's figure out how to get this solved
or something like that the other thing
is is I had to talk to him about how I
liked criticism right and in how I like
to be rewarded everybody likes to have
rewarded the recognition in different
ways so I really had to talk about how I
liked that versus the other the next
thing I had to do was get organized I've
been complaining to my wife for a while
about shared calendars she's a teacher
she likes her paper calendar and I'm
like this does not work I don't know
when the kids activities are I don't
know what's going on so I got her on
board and now she loves it the other
thing I do is inbox zero it's called as
an archaic I can't pronounce it effect
I've got a link to a great blog post
about it later and it's about how you're
constantly thinking about things that
you don't have done and you can't focus
on the things that you need to work on
so if your inbox has like a thousand
things in it you're constantly reviewing
is you're spinning through the other
stuff and it makes your mind wander
versus what you need to be working on
and getting it done and going to the
next thing
right so I so I organized my email
through a deal called inbox zero and I
have a link at the end for that as well
too and then I used to duyst
on my phone and I keep track of work
items in home items so my honey to-do
list is on there and my work list is on
there great thing about it is you can
see how many tasks you've completed and
you can say yay me right and it emails
you every day or you can set up your
notifications on on how have stuff to
you alright I have some links that stuff
at the end the third thing this is hard
especially with wife and kids you have
make time for yourself you have to talk
to your partner and make them understand
that I need some time for myself right
now I like to go the races Chili Bowl
actually two weeks ago got to drive a
sprint car it was awesome
ten laps I like building things I turned
that golden tea into a Raspberry Pi
arcade so hooked into the hop switch and
all that stuff it was pretty fun a part
of making time for yourself is also
making time for you and your spouse and
taking my vacation days we went with a
two other three other couples and spent
a week down in Mexico and enjoyed
ourselves and I came back and went to
work the very next day and it was
awesome like I didn't need a vacation
from the vacation
all right fourth this one's awesome
positive reflection a lot of us will get
into that drive about how we're terrible
right and if you take a step take ten
minutes 20 minutes and you look at where
you came from and where you're at now
there's a lot of things that we've
achieved that just get tucked back in
there and then you never think about him
again for me I think about like I talked
about earlier I'm the first person in my
family to go to four-year college that's
something I should be proud of I
shouldn't like forget about that stuff
right
think about certifications project stuff
like that it kind of seems a little
shallow too but sometimes I'll look
through my followers and and there's
some like very nice yeah there's there's
some very like popular like people with
a lot of followers that will actually
talk to me at times I'm like holy shit
you know I must be like I must be doing
something right but seems a little
shallow but it makes me feel good that
you know somebody who like they actually
care what I think
and then I read I keep a folder and I
put things in there screenshots copies
of emails stuff like that
where I've received things from other
people I have stuff from last jobs that
I've worked out where I finished a
project and somebody has said hey Eric
thanks for this you did a great job we
couldn't got this done without you
yes I'm saving that into my folder for
review later right v I
volunteer I volunteered multiple
different places but I had to pick one
place that I really wanted to do one of
my one of my friends in college he
co-founded Team Rubicon so I go and help
after disaster release through Team
Rubicon I spent eight days down in
Houston two years ago after the
hurricane I just did a tornado work in
Lawrence Kansas a few months ago we do
service projects do stuff like that it's
great I've got a blog post from 2017
about what that experience looks like
because if you think you have it bad and
then you go see people living in a tent
city that have lost everything your
perspective on life changes pretty darn
fast and it'll stick with you alright
the last thing I do is what I'm doing
right now I reach out to others okay
share my story if I see people that I
think need help I talked to them I don't
take no for an answer if I really
believe they need help I get to know
them stuff like that some people are
gonna just tell you to go jump off a
cliff you'll be able to tell by their
responses and stuff like that on if they
really need help or not it's something
that is very hard to do it takes time to
work on you really gotta try to get to
know people and techniques on how to
communicate with them why is this
important because you'll get some things
back out of it - I was having a horrible
day one day I just been talking to a
company and I was having a really
actually bad week one of the projects I
was on wasn't going well my manager was
being a pain in the rear and stuff like
that and then all of a sudden I got a
direct message on Twitter from somebody
that had said hey I heard you talked
with our company you know my exec said
you were awesome you know hands down if
I could put you on my team yada yada
yada
you know I'd love to down the road it's
like wow you know like they actually
like me you know and then later that
year a friend in the community I'd
talked to off and on we talked to you
about challenges we've been through
personally I just texted him a picture
of my family's Christmas card so it is
like hey Steve you know I hope you have
a good Christmas you know here's a
picture of our
family he no good and all of a sudden I
get a tweet back to me like that
and I was actually having a horrible day
that day I got that just lifted up my
day lifted up the rest of my weekend
made me feel good to take the time to do
the little things take its a time to
recognize people for doing what they're
supposed to be doing right don't be
afraid it's worth the little amount of
time the first time I gave this
presentation last year I was nervous as
all could be I barely made it through it
I got home that night and this was in my
email if you don't think it's worth it
it's extremely worth it you could help
that one person that then can help the
one person that could then help the one
person so I get stuff like this quite
often given this presentation this is my
18th time giving this presentation and I
haven't scheduled two more times next
month
one last thing that I've learned over
time giving this is what can managers do
if you're a manager here's some things
you can do how many people know what
resources your company have for you if
you need to go talk to somebody one yes
- so I didn't know that both as times I
was going through this my actually
benefits included therapy sessions for
free yours may - if you're a manager or
not check into things like that but
especially if you're a manager know in
case one of your employees comes up to
you know the reporting policy again some
of the things I talked about before the
praised communication look at tasks and
workload distribution don't give
somebody the same task over and over and
over again especially if it's a crappy
one spread that out all right
in conclusion your company isn't gonna
solve this for you you are going to be
responsible for your own well-being in
this area so look for symptoms in
yourself and others figure out
strategies that work for you I've taken
some things away like working out
it's terrible I try to add it back
sometimes but it sucks but don't give up
like I said I've worked in and out of
multiple strategies those six that are
over there now the ones I do now
and lastly pay it forward you never know
who needs it or who you might help from
from reaching out
lastly the World Health Organization if
you hadn't noticed earlier this year
they're actually recognizing burnout
it's being added into their list of
diagnosis it'll be published in January
2022 so if you see the characterized by
three dimensions at the bottom energy
depletion exhaustion oh yeah you know
mental disease from one's jobs the
negative Oh cynicism yeah it's a peer of
sarcasm and reduce professional efficacy
all right last but not least put a QR
code up here so if you want to download
the slide deck you can get it from that
QR code
there's some good resources up here if
you don't want to talk to me that's fine
if you want to talk to me I'm on Twitter
I'm not hard to find check with your
insurance provider if you prefer talking
to somebody in person there's a phone
number if you prefer texting there's a
phone number if you prefer reading
there's a website or two the OS mental
illness that Twitter account has books
digital books for you for managers for
stuff like that technically you can get
it for free or you can donate a little
money so they can keep doing it they're
very very good I have all three of them
if you want to see more sessions like
this
Sanja cuff put together a big old list
on that top one right there of other
presentations both in video and in text
form
there's cy i can't pronounce that does
anybody know how to pronounce that zig
and our candy geek effect that's the one
where you have a problem focusing if you
have too much stuff and then how to fix
that inbox zero it's great and then
there's three other my friends that have
posted similar sessions since I started
giving this if you want to read other
people's journeys as well too and with
that I'm here for y'all and I'm done so
thank you for having me
[Music]
good no no all right if you want to talk
you have or anything just hit me up
outside or out over here or wherever
[Music]