Good afternoon. My real name is
whatever that says. Thank you
for coming. It is awesome to be
here. Everyone who is affiliated
with DEF CON this is phenomenal.
The goons and this is
overwhelming and once you get
the letter that says you have
been accepted, you think, oh, my
God, I have been accepted. Thank
you for you guys that are coming
and standing in the room. I'm
going to keep going. [ LAUGHTER
] What I'm here to talk about
today is the "Beyond the Scan:
The Value Proposition of
Vulnerability Assessment." >>
Your talk has been cancelled. We
have a tradition here at DEF
CON. Wait, I got that mixed up.
All right. I do this all day.
DEF CON, our brand-new speaker!
>> DEF CON 23. Thank you very
much. [ APPLAUSE ] Water chaser.
So, a lot of us already do
vulnerability assessment and we
are involved in scanning
activity and we already know how
that works and we are doing it
in our organization. There are a
lot of aspects of performing and
scanning that are not
understood. Maybe not by us, but
our organizations. I was the
client that knew they needed to
do this, but they were not
necessarily all together knowing
what they would do with that
information once they got it.
And working with the clients and
going through the narrative and
performing the scans and I
realized there is an opportunity
for us, as performing this
activity to really make more
meaningful changes in our OS and
you are going to hear me say
this a couple of times, where
the later (Indiscernible)
happens and we were trying to
impact the business. There is
contact info on the CD, as well.
So, stay in touch. You do
vulnerability assessments and
say, I'm your tool guy and a lot
of people think that you set-up
a scanner and click scan and
that's it. It is regarded as one
of the least sexy things in info
sector. Vulnerability tends to
get glossed over and in my
opinion, it is a key component
of the accessibility program and
if it gets overlooked, you are
doing a disservice to your
organization. Hopefully, this is
going to be useful to you when
you go back to your
organizations that you are
supporting. We are going to talk
about "beyond the scan" and
provide support. Whether you are
a blue team or a red team, we
are doing the heavy lifting
blue-collar security work.
That's what we are talking
about. The next slide and we are
talking about the human tester
and the tools-based scanning.
The data by itself is very, very
useful and it tells you a lot
about your environment and what
you are doing. Without the human
testers, you are just gathering
data and making a bunch of
noise. I feel strongly when you
apply the human testers, that's
all of us, to the data that you
gather, that's when the magic
happens. Just to reiterate, this
is not a tool-based talk, we are
using tools in a smarter way and
having people know when to use
these tools. Does that make any
sense? We need to go a scan and
we are going to give it to some
new guy and let him scan the
network. I don't respond
positively to that. Please,
don't do that. You need to have
the talented humans and in
addition to having the humans
and applying it to the data, a
question that comes up a lot and
perhaps you have heard this
question, as well. What should
we scan? I like the longitudinal
scans. Scan everything. Clicking
and scanning is easy, but making
sense of the data is the hard
part. When I get later on in the
case studies, you have to do
longitudinal studies over time.
If there is an IP stack, you
should scan it. Maybe, you are
scanning very specific things
that you are interested in. To
understand your network
environment, you need to see
everything that is on there and
not just the known quantities
that you have. There are some
interesting stories coming up
and talking about that. Humans
that are looking at the data
also scan all of the things.
Another point and obviously, we
can't avoid talking about
(Indiscernible) because we are
using this data. I'm going to
try and be as vendor specific as
possible. There are some names
up. They are all very, very good
in their own way. In your future
engagements, you may need to
pick one tool. There is one tool
that I'm using currently that is
doing very fine. All will work,
and you have to work with your
organization and decide which
one is the best for you. I'm
going to make you sit through a
history lesson. The security
administrator tool for analyzing
networks or SATAN was released
in 1995. They were not
interested in marketing,
obviously. Anyone around in
1995? Thank goodness. That was a
big deal. I remember reading in
the trade magazines and this is
the worst idea ever. Why would
you make a tool to make it
easier to find vulnerabilities
and the other half of the people
thought; thank God, now I have a
way to find the vulnerabilities.
The conversation that we had a
year ago and firewalls were an
expensive way to slow down your
network and fire routers were
fine. We know that's not true.
To give you a state-of-the-art
work back then, it was a long
time ago and things were a lot
different back then. PC Magazine
-- to show you know and for
today and when we do scans all
of the time. There are millions
of people scanning the Internet.
20 years ago, this would get you
landed in jail. Two decades ago
and it is crazy to think this is
a dramatic thing. And one of the
tools that came out after SATAN
can scan 100 known
vulnerabilities. Think about
that. I have 100 in my pocket
right now that many of you are
trying to find, by the way. The
last time I checked, it was
vulnerabilities. 20, going from
100 known things on Linux and
now, almost a couple hundred
thousand on many different
platforms. You can learn about
these folks that created SATAN.
They wisely choose saint. Now,
it is like a Dan Brown novel.
Thank you, I wrote that myself.
It became a commercial product
in 1998. SATAN came out in '95
and all hell broke loose. And if
you remember from my slide,
there are a lot of commercial
products that exist. From that
humble beginning and now, an
entirely different capability
with the info sect. Now, we are
doing vulnerability assessment
and looking across multiple
platforms across a large number
of hosts and that leads to
vulnerability management. I'm
going to pause for a moment; it
is not just performing the scan.
Vulnerability management means
that now, that we have the
information and know it, what
are we going to do about it? You
mitigate, transfer it, but you
have to do something. And now,
we know about it and how to
document it in an audible way.
Now, we have this thing and we
know it is working and how do we
know that the decision that we
make today is going to be
ongoing in the future. The
landscape could be very, very
tiny and that could change. Now,
I care all of a sudden.
Vulnerability management
includes all of those things.
So, a couple of decades ago,
scanners came out and yesterday
yet, I still feel like in our
industry, particularly when we
start touching the business, we
are still misunderstood. I love
that cartoon. No one else likes
it? We are still misunderstood
and working with several clients
over the last several years and
one question that always comes
up, all right, I have human
testing. And I have tool-based
scanning. If I get this new
scanner, can I get
(Indiscernible). That's a
conversation that I started to
have. I started to talk about
the scanning activity relative
to the OSI model and this is
going to show certain tools that
we might use and how they work
relative to other tools. Are we
all familiar with the OSI model?
Love it? Hate it? Down at the
bottom we have electrons and
protons and going through fiber.
If you are interested in TTP
ports and if we are interested
in client applications that are
talking to a server somewhere.
And now, we are higher up in the
model and the host layers and it
is giving us visibility into
there. And maybe, we use web
inspect or Burke or in the host
layers or in the network and
wanting to sniff traffic and it
goes on. You can see already,
when I drop the scanner in
there, it is giving us a wider
view than the other tools. If
the question comes up, we bought
this great, expensive scanner,
and what can we get rid of? It
is not replacing something. It
gives us information that is
useful and the only thing, which
is capable of scanning the
entire stack, is the humans, us.
They are actually doing the work
and whether it is manually
penetration testing on an app
trying to break in or looking at
the tools that it is trying to
gather, the people are the most
important. I have gotten a lot
of really good feedback and I
would be interested to hear from
you folks if this OSI slide is
useful. Starting to talk to the
business, it helps them to see
that we have a lot to deal with
and securing the applications
and the systems and there are
lots of different ways to gather
that information. To kind of
illustrate that in a different
way. We can see our tools are
very, very useful for the
longitudinal scans and doing
scans over a long period of
time. And comparing results and
seeing what is our security
posture today and as that
changes, it moves on. The
people, don't let anyone
(Indiscernible) decide to start
use tools and ideas and going to
replace other tools and it is
also not going to replace your
people. You still have to have
people who know what that data
is and you can read through a
list of things that are on
there. There is a short list of
the things that we're good at
that the tools are not. It is
limited without the security
professionals. All right. This
is an interesting example of
that. I told the story earlier
and it worked out. We did an
assessment for a client and came
back with a lot of http
vulnerabilities and Apache
things. We asked them to come
back and update the Apache and
they came back and said,
obviously, they are S servers. I
can see the banner and assure
you there is a demon running.
Here is a false/positive and
here is why. And when you are
sharing with operations and
business units and other people.
I found a really interesting
thing and when you use words,
the same word might mean
something completely different
depending on who you are talking
to. If I say interface it is
going to mean three different
things and if you have this
experience, as well. And if you
are talking to a programmer and
you think API and it is an API,
that is allowing things and if
you talk to routing and
switching guys, they are talking
about a web-based guitar that is
attaching to a network. It is
important whom you are talking
to and language can be a
confusing thing. You have to
know what you are talking about.
You need to know your
environment, as well. On a
client engagement and how to
scan a very large network that
had a global presence. We had
distributed scan engines that
were in various networks around
the world. There is one in
Argentina. Intuitively and
backhauled through Houston. If I
wanted to scan Argentina or
Brazil, it went by way of
Houston first. Architecturally
the smart decision to scan North
America to South America. If you
have a sufficiently large
(Indiscernible) you really need
to know how those packets are
getting to where they are
getting to. Understand the
architecture of your network.
Now, we know which language to
use and our environment and now,
we need to know our
organization. Don't panic, I'm
going to walk you through this
whole slide. I know there are a
lot of boxes going on. There are
a lot of ways that the scanner
allows us to slice and dice data
and we can look at specific
vulnerabilities and hosts and
group them in many
(Indiscernible) and get in the
actual day that we are giving to
the organization, we have to
make very conscious decisions on
how to organize the data and how
to ultimately fix the problems
that we are going to identify.
You need to capitalize in your
organization and focus solely on
what is wrong with your box.
Let's get into the case study
part of it. Identifying the
potential vulnerabilities. What
we are trying to figure out here
and it might be a little
obvious, but (Indiscernible) and
we want to figure out what are
our attempted targets and what
hatches are missing from those
targets and what is our
environment is configured
properly. We found that SIDS was
exposed to the open environment.
Many of us panicked. Many of
them were on the Xbox's and in
2013. We asked the question, why
is it set-up that way? Why would
you put them on the Internet
that way? It is never a good
Windows and of course, there are
VPN's and a million way to do
those things and instead of
saying close those ports and
have a nice day. To realize
there is a gap in the
understanding and how they would
be supported in the first place.
There is a related issue where
the boxes need access to require
IP-based authentication and
that's how they let them in. Not
only were the ports exposed, but
they had static NATS set-up.
When they set-up the NATing and
they put an inbound firewall
rule and anything and everything
was coming into the inboxes. We
identified some technical
problems and also, a business
problem that was broken. They
should have never allowed that
firewall to be put in place as
it was, right? There were
multiple decisions that were
left in and they were unchecked
and we were afraid to change it
because something might stop
working, so we are going to
leave it alone. So, we resulted
-- we found not only those
vulnerabilities, but there was
poor documentation and we
couldn't figure out why it was
set-up the way it was and the
broken process that allowed the
firewall get in the first place
and lack of understanding of
what the specific requirements
were. At this same organization,
we found there is an obsolete
version of Java. Obsolete Java
shouldn't be a surprise and
having it result in hundreds of
vulnerabilities shouldn't be a
surprise either. But when we
asked, why is it set-up the way
that it is? Well, we have a
specific application that
requires that version of Java.
We called the vendor, which no
one had done. Do you require
this specific version of Java?
No, we require at least, that
version of Java. A very subtle
detail was left out at the
client's site. If I were a
cynical person and for those of
you that know me, I kind of am.
I think they were using that as
an excuse of not updating Java
in a large enter prize and there
was broken process and all of
these things were benefits that
the organization got long after
the scan was over. It happened
when we started working with the
business units and the support
organizations to clear these
things up. So, it is going to
provide a scheming tool and I it
will provide information. This
is another thing that maybe
obvious. I worked with another
client that were surprised to
find out; not only will it tell
me (Indiscernible) and a good
product will also fix it. This
client only saw the result of
the scan in a spreadsheet and
the IP address name and what
went wrong with it. When we
provided the information, it
became hugely valuable to this
organization. No, they knew not
only what was wrong and how to
fix it. It is impossible for any
of us to know everything. They
may not know. Make sure you take
advantage of the information
that is in the tool that you are
using. I have a pretty good idea
of what is on my home network
and what is on everywhere across
the whole organization and that
might not be true. Here is where
you have to make a decision. Are
you going to scan a specific set
of hosts or everything that is
out there? Those are two
different activities and
problems, but I think that we
should do them both. A client
that I worked with scanned all
of the cyber blocks that we knew
about. And at the end of the
engagement, we decided, let's
scan the stuff that doesn't
exist and the networks that are
completely undocumented.
Obviously, the switches didn't
turn themselves on and the hosts
didn't turn themselves on. And
someone did it in the
organization. Maybe, we can find
parts of the network that we
didn't know was there. And the
range of IP addresses that work
on your networks and try and
figure out what is there. One
client that I'm working with,
when you do that, scan these
huge blocks, you end up creating
a very, very nice inventory of
what exists on your network and
the information management, it
is helpful to share that
information with them. Now,
there is a check for the
day-to-day data that have. At
that point, it is not a security
related issue as it is asset
management. Still very important
if you don't know what is on
your network and how can you
possibly secure it? A large
number of IP cameras were not on
anybody's list and it was a
little embedded system and not a
computer so much that anyone
cared about. Many of them were
configured incorrectly with
default credentials and just
because IP didn't care; it was a
huge win for the client because
they fixed what could have been
a very big problem. The same
client and again, it wasn't a
security-related issue, but we
found some Nintendo machines on
the network. It was a children's
hospital, so it was okay. It
illustrated the point if IT
didn't know they were there and
then, you have to ask the
question, I have gaming consoles
that are on the same network as
my production equipment. And
that drives the question, how is
our network configured and are
we doing it the appropriate way?
And the best way that we can.
The next company, they had a lot
of oilrigs in Mexico. Every
platform has exactly four hosts
on it and that's exactly what
you are going to find. And we
did the scan and most of the
platforms did have exactly four
hosts and that's fine. There
were a couple that had more than
that. We went back to the client
and said there are hot IP
addresses coming off of this
rig. They were interested in
what those feeds were. Finding
out what is on our network in
the first place. And an asset
management is very much network
and if you don't find out what
is on it, you are screwed at
what you are doing. I think
that's very, very true and why
we should spend our time making
sure that we get to every corner
of our network that we can.
Speaking with software
management. Do you know each
machine that is in your
enterprise that you are
scanning? And doing the
credential scans and do we scan
with or without credentials and
obviously, you are going to get
a lot of information and the
scanning tool is going to allow
us to enumerate everything that
is on the box and once we do the
scan, we can go back and run the
reports and find out if there is
anything there and maybe if you
standardize on Internet explorer
and what about BitTorrent and
Kazaa. Compliance and on some
level we are flinging things and
scanning the packets and you can
learn about what the
organization is and what the
activities that are needed to
make them more secure. Is
compliance an issue for you?
Compliance an issue for anyone?
A few hands. If it is HIPPA or
GOBA, your scanner should be
able to tell you (Indiscernible)
relative to something else. That
could be important if you do
work with the folks or the
client's folks and make sure
that you are taking advantage of
the fact that you can gather
that information and make sure
that you are compliant of what
your health status is.
Strategically, the information
that we are gathering should be
important to our networks as
well. I will use the word again
because I like it; I'm talking
about these longitudinal scans
over time. It is not a scan at
the point in time
(Indiscernible) the trends that
are developing and you need to
do these scans. That can be very
important in an unexpected way.
If you are looking and
continuing to see that, you find
vulnerabilities and it is fixed
and maybe, you have a resourcing
problem. If something happens
and all of a sudden, bash is
vulnerable. Strategically, it
can be very, very important and
tactically, it can be very, very
important, as well. Anyone work
in health care or work in
environments that have
industrial control systems?
Yeah, more hands. So, this is --
this conversation is going on a
lot in our industry now and it
is going to continue because
these systems in particular are
not the same as the other
computers on our networks. The
biomedical devices and control
systems and the things that help
run plants and refineries and
whatnot are highly, highly
specialized and they are used to
getting (Indiscernible)
specific. As you are throwing
traffic at them -- the hot
button for me. Even though the
FDA is getting stronger in
forcing equipment manufacturers,
a lot of time you find that the
equipment manufacturers hide
behind the FDA. Does anyone know
specifically what the FDA fight
is and have to deal with it now?
Okay, the food and drug
administration says before you
sell a medical device, you have
to go through the FDA and once
the FDA says this is fine, you
can't make any changes to it.
That becomes a problem when I
say that you need to patch your
x-ray machine, the -- the
problem with health care and
sometimes, it can lead to poor
design decisions and with
radiology divisions and that's a
problem in this hospital. The
vendor supported it with FTP and
all of these stations had FTP
running on it. And setting it up
and the logons that are enabled
and they enabled the FTP route
and who this the world would
ever do that? Buy me a beer and
I will tell you who did that.
Everyone on this network had FTP
access to the file system and it
is the worst thing possibly
ever. Normally, if you scan and
see FTP and maybe the return
valves at the refineries and the
technology and they are not the
same as information technology
at all. Shutting down a plant to
do maintenance in computers and
their patch cycles maybe in
months or years. If you find
yourself working on these types
(Indiscernible) you need to make
sure that the OTP people
understand that once you find
the vulnerability, the OTP
patches are not going to be that
simple. They are purpose built
and very, very specific and if
you get unusual traffic,
(Indiscernible) at all. Be very,
very cautious. I know that I'm
running out of time and
basically, the story I'm trying
to tell you is that scanning has
been around for a long time and
it has matured to be a lot more
useful and becoming shared
appropriately and look for the
opportunities to share this data
with your organization and if
you come up with a data
manageability program that
shares all of these processes,
it will help you. Thank you very
much for sitting through all of
that and enjoy DEF CON 23. Thank
you. [ APPLAUSE ]