>> So today, I will introduce
you guys that how to hack video
device and it seems you guys are
tired so I make this quick,
yeah. >>And, uh, yeah in the
speaker room, somebody invited
me to drink beer, so Im a
little bit high. 	Yeah.
(Applause). 	So I'm from the
UNICORN team, 3 topics in this
DEF CON, so. 	And okay. 	So,
Unicorn Team, and focus hardware
and success of security and
research. 	We contain a lot of
Peruvian peoples, we focus on
anything that uses radio,
technologies and from any small
things like tablets, something
like that. GPS, use the
research, we hack it, we let
them land in the you know page,
such as audio ware in
America, the White House. We do
our research and we make a lot
of products and, [indiscernible]
and actually -- [indiscernible]
maybe you can buy it as well.
And I have this speck. 	And what
is this, why this is talk
relevant relevant to you.
Maybe you guys are hackers and,
might be able to, control these
devices and without
authorization and this talk,
will teach you how to package
it. Such as your your smoke
sensor, your HIV test system,
well if you can choose them, not
yours, well you can do
everything. 	What is Zigbee?
Zigbee is the only global
wireless standard that provides
the foundation of Internet of
Things. 	By, embedding a simple
and smart object to work
together, maybe you, prove the
comfort and efficiency of the
test. Maybe you guys use some
IOT devices and if you dissemble
it and you find oh, this is
[indiscernible]. 	So its just
a word is language I read that
device used to connect one from
another. And they connect the
person will be able to work from
you home right now. So maybe
someone buy a smoker alert, well
it if disassembles it, you might
buy another one. 	Blah, blah,
blah. 	[Laughter] 	I was told
that maybe you guys, that
somebody don't know Zigbee
design so I introduce it. Zigbee
is already using Internet of
Things, and adapted
[indiscernible], and it requires
low power computer consuming
machine. It will flex fold and
typology. 	And, so this is,
Zigbees networker. You can
stray, you can mash, you can
[indiscernible]. 	It's very
different. [Indiscernible] to
each letter. 	So, the most
important thing in Zigbee is
this talk. What is this? Its
the specification of the
implement of Zigbee. Start from
the Texas instructamentor.
2530, yeah. 	Point 15 and point
4 in baggage chip. Well in other
words Zigbee standard is right
-- this stack is writing code.
So here is chip and you can buy
it on the Texas instructament.
Well you can actually get it
free online. 	So, actually, a
lot of people research security
program in Zigbee have done a
lot of things. Zigbee is
[indiscernible]. 	Thank you,
Zigbee security, is best on
smash security, [indiscernible]
and the recipient of
[indiscernible] through a stem
key.. a stem pool key, its
changing so, if you're want to
know more details, download the
documents and do research on it.
So, the key distribution thing.
You can pre install it,
transport it, you can
establishment. 	There are 3 key
types. The Master Key, The
Linder Key, and The Literal Key.
So, hacking Zigbee
step-by-step, here is what I
want to say. What I want to
teach you guys. 	And, you know
here is the map that how Zigbee
transfer the information from
one to one. I think they so,
share with them the think
process, the polling it
background, yeah. A smart system
that that's one of better
qualities. [Indiscernible] 	We
bought it from the Internet.
Here is step 3. No more
[indiscernible] flows. 	Phone
connect with IOT get away. And
the connector will flow. Or your
phone will connect with the
wireless router and the router
will connect with the IOT away.
And connecter both. 	And,
phone, 4 G, 3 G or 2 G, the
Internet, connects to server
and, connects wireless router
and connects to IOG away. 	So,
what do we want, is directly
choose our own Zigbee note,
Zigbee note and choose the
phone. 	That's how we hack it
(losing sound). 	So, the whole
translation is encrypted. 	What
do we do to try to find
encryption key from the phone.
If you want to find it. 	The
first thing you do is download
the firmware the key are stored
in every node in the network.
The firm is harder to assemble,
so we chose to straggler key
from the get away. 	So, the I
try to disassemble, actually, I
find out -- well, so I use a
hand to smash it, WOW, this is
shit, it doesn't work, its
broken. 	Before I smash it,
yeah, I tried to disassemble the
get away. 	So we dissemble the
get away, and try to find, we
try to dump the firmware. Okay.
[Indiscernible] the debugging
test is right there, so you
know, [indiscernible] were
connecting our debugger, and we
use a GI smart I, a fresh
program to do the dump of the
firmware. 	So if you guys want
to dump some firmware from your
device. 	Well, this is
necessary. 	Okay, here is screen
shot of it. 	And programmer
software. 	Well, we got it from
here, it's a lot of minutes to
stand, so what should we do
so, if you just trying to find
encrypted key, what you do is
just trying to find wedding ring
from the garbage. 	So, here is
the way I try to find the
inquiry key. 	First, we set the
keys to the distinguished
structure [indiscernible] We
can see if we discover something
interesting. So as the keys used
to encrypt the packaging. 	So
why do we not find the
instruction that the key so
lets try to reverse. So we
find that the instructions
reserve key that has
relunctanctly has a fixed part.
And showing you the next slide,
the whole concept with more
instruction could be used as
[indiscernible] or second nature
to hold the address of the key.
So here is most important
instruction that.. I dont
know if you guys can see. If you
you can't see, maybe you can
download if you can't see
clearly. 	Okay. 	Yeah. 	So, in
this right, yeah. 	You see it.
So, you can see the structures
and values that's the flow of
how I tried to find out the key.
And actually there are 2 keys.
Yes. The stored and the
exchange key. 	So if you guys
want to hack it, you guys need
to find the 2 keys to decrypt
the package. 	So, we do this to,
second enter, and in the upper
right corner the instructions to
magnify the Nano key. The OX 31,
on the OX 80. Its the memory
adjust that stores the keys. So
in the lower left corner. 	So,
on upper right corner is
instructions that magnify the
nano key, so it should oh
because it's really messy.
Something going wrong with my
laptop. 	I'm sorry. thats
embarrassing, yeah. Just junked
up, yeah. 	So, then use the
code, [indiscernible] there are
more instructions, corresponding
motion and motion code and
[indiscernible] For numbers, as
its harder to search through
the memory through the premiere
or [indiscernible]. 	So you guys
can know where the keys are used
and how to find it and how to
encrypt it. 	So that's the
screen shot of this. 	Address of
the keys. 	So, we were verify
this keys, is that what we want?
Verify this, we title it you
know, messaging integrated,
check, contents in package, and
if the desired package pass
through MIC, yeah, so we can be
sure that we find the right key.
So let's, you can just just
write simple script to verify
it, and put all keys to where
you can find, password,
password, bingo, that's it. 	So
that's our snipper used to
capture the package. 	Yeah so we
just, yeah we buy time so we
change a little -- so the
following screen shot shows
process that a new code joins a
network. 	As the speaker, its
quite self explanatory. The
network key is extending from
coding nature to join the device
and [indiscernible]. 	After
receiving the keys, the
communication is immediate
immediately encrypted. So if it
is encrypted we can use the key
that we find to decrypt it.
Here is screen shot. 	So, I
want to say is that after we
find the key we could do some
data-mining, to find the habit
of it because there are going
to be a little but of factors
but the foreign are some very
particular attacks that we can
perform. 	We can manifest the
starter data, we can repair and
spoof, we can intercept it,
yeah, we can just
[indiscernible] attack. 	So,
what matters of data where
we after we decipher the
data, we will take control over
the target device. We have the
nemesis the applied data. And
the result is following. 	You
can see, the, if you want to
control this, you know how to,
you know, the device you can
turn a different color. 	Here is
the things that you can, you can
know how to control it yet, this
is a bit, so the penalty
[indiscernible]. 	The last pace
being SOR stand of the
[indiscernible] bytes, byte one
and byte two of the
[indiscernible] of the target
device. [Indiscernible] 	Okay,
so, we can control this,
[indiscernible] While this is
the device that we use, it's
actually about our own, we just,
you know, use the echo
[indiscernible] and we to just
print it out. 	So, we can
reprint this both. 	If you know
the piece that we use, to
incorporate that we can just
generate, the stem package to
join the network and we can send
to the exactly send instructions
to control this device. 	Yes,
[indiscernible] well, you guys
are the get away, so now you
control me. 	So, this is the
text flow. This distance is
really hard, so yeah. So we know
that, the double k to send
instructions to the make and
product returns, yeah, so you
can now just, you know the
question so generate exactly
same questions to control it.
So, how do we protect or just
you know, prevent our device is
hacked by this way. 	So, you
can, know, just know, if, so you
can adjust, [indiscernible]
encryption keys in your
firmware, its not safe. So
you can just store a
[indiscernible] of the
encryption key instead of the
[indiscernible] and you know,
dont joke [indiscernible]
And use pre install of key,
look to attach instead. 	Blow
the fuse, to prevent from being
dumped. Such as use some
security water, use special
protection to, basically you
guys don't have to leave
[indiscernible] on either. so
every hacker seems to think well
I can hack it. 	So the employee
of the, [ indiscernible]
employee of the, some light
weight encryption on the
application type just to
manifest the [indiscernible]
its harder of the key
comprise 	Actually, I would like
to say something. Actually this
presentation is not mine, it's
my colleague. 	But
unfortunately, his visa got
rejected so he could not make
it, so I just, I am familiar
with his work, always says, take
laptop and do something.
Actually I dont know, what
are you guys doing? 	He says, no
you can replace me, you can
speak for me. I don't know what
you do, so how do I do it for
you, so I'm really sorry for
that. >> Youre doing fine.
(Applause) 	[Laughter] >>yeah,
I did my, already done my
presentation yesterday, so yeah.
I actually, Im familiar with
my work, not his. 	So, actually,
here is the, you know, here is
the work that my colleague,
former colleague help him a lot,
and actually, this, is, you
know, you guys want to know more
details, you can contact with
tweet or e-mail. 	I'm sorry
about him. 	Last thing, I should
ask him, you want me to do
lunch? No. 	I did a lot. 	I'm
really nervous. 	Because this
isn't my work. 	Yeah. 	I'm
sorry. 	So, thank you, if you
guys have questions, I think I
can't answer you, I'm sorry,
(Laughter). 	(Applause) Thank
you. 	I appreciate it.