All right, guys, we'll get
started. Welcome. Good
afternoon, thanks for coming.
Thanks to DEF CON for having me.
My name is Jeremy Dorrough on
two different variance of attack
I made for the USB rubber ducky
what we got here. Or is that
just their screen? Are these
screens screwed up, too, just
that one? USB two different
payloads for the USB rubber
ducky that will decrypt theWi-Fi
communications. Yeah, so, before
we get started. Quick
disclaimer. I'm here on my own
behalf. It's my own opinions.
Not my employer, no one else we
get the legal jargon out of the
way. Yeah. Okay. What are we
doing here? Sorry. Alternates
more than decade of experience
in national security industry
those ten years I've worked for
a couple of different sectors.
Started out with the Department
of Defense, working for the Army
at a datacenter hosting both
class and unclass material. Left
out of there to go to work in
the energy sector, defending a
nuclear power facility. Then
currently I'm working in
financial sector as network
security engineer for Genworth
financial. Just a side note, fun
fact. As a hobby I enjoyed
building, driving and detroying
demolition derby cars, if there
is any gear heads we'll talk
cars. What we'll talk about.
From a high level we're going to
first talk about what is a USB
rubber ducky those not familiar
then talk about how the attack
actually works. Then get into
the details of each of the
different payloads. First talk
about the keyboard payload then
we'll talk about the one
involves both keyboard and USB
mass storage. I'll demo the
second variant of the attack,
any time for questions, maybe
we'll take some questions but
it's probably going to take the
full time. All right, so, again,
those are not familiar with
rubber ducky in simple
description of what it is, think
about if you were able to take a
keyboard and apply some type of
logic or some type of memory,
what to send to a machine when
you plug it in ultimately have
the USB rubber ducky. They are
sold by hack 5. Run by and
support them. Really good group
of guys. Like 40 bucks or a
little better than 40 bucks,
pretty cheap. Here is what the
rubber ducky looks like. You'll
notice that it is a very common
form factor. Notice there on the
far right for you guys, if you
been to any of the trade shows
like any of the I.T. security
stuff, typically as vendors hand
out swag a lot of times it wilt
be actual form factor. If you go
to some of those you look you
probably have one that looks
very similar to. That inside the
enclosure you'll see it has
micro SD card storage area. As
well as a little micro
processor, a little 32 bit chip.
And again that's what kind of
drives the memory part of the
brain from that previous slide.
And to kind of talk about the
different ways that the ducky
behaves it comes shipped -- the
duck firmware which is that
first bullet there. And again
that is just keyboard input. But
there's also the detour duck,
but make note that have last
variant of the firmware as well.
That involves having both USB
mass storage at your disposal
when you plug the device in as
well as programmable decord. Lot
of powerful things can be done
once you start adding mass
storage, we'll see that in a
demo later. For those that are
like, thank you, he's trying to
pedal their products. You don't
have to go with the hack 5
rubber ducky, there are other
options out there. Sammy Cam car
he's got presentation later
today. I recommend you guys
support him. Really smart guy.
He developed the USB drive by he
does the same kind of mentality
with the device. So check his
stuff out if you don't want to
spring for the 40-some odd for
the rubber ducky. As women as
last year at Black Hat, Carson
and Jacob did the bad USB, those
that are familiar with that
term. Then later at derby
conadam called on Brandon Wilson
released code to take off the
shelf variant of a flash drive,
flash their firmware to it and
more or less it will run the
same scripting language that the
rubber ducky run. That is more
or less free if you have those
flash drive laying around. So,
how does attack works? This
slide just depicts the victim
having a wireless connection to
a little radio there you see the
lock. Any SSL connection they
have are working as they should.
Everything is encrypted.
Anything that this they are
supposed to be encrypted is
encrypted just standard
connection before the attack.
Then comes the rubber ducky, if
the rubber ducky was USB flash
drive was plugged in, first
thing going to happen there's
going to be a trust of
certificate that's loaded on
that victim's machine. After the
trusted cert is loaded will move
wireless connect over to a man
in the middle machine which I
will be running. If you kind of
think about this in your head
what just happened, not only are
we now man in the middle, but
since we provided that key
there's nothing I cannot
encrypt, right? It's kind of a
bad situation for that victim.
All right, so, first question I
had when I bought it was, is
this a novelty device? Yeah,
it's great to roll your buddies
with it, cool. Does this thing
really have a place in the
corporate environment for an
actual pentest or is this a real
useful tool for Black Hat for
that matter. I was kind of
astounded to see these numbers.
You may have heard these before,
but DHS obviously had the same
thought they paid a third party
to perform a study where they
dropped flash drives around
public areas, whether it be
smoking areas, walkways, what
have you. They found that an
astounding 60% of people plugged
them in once they picked them
up. Well, that's scary enough.
Then look at last bullet, if
they add official logo that
number jumped to 90%. The moral
of the story is that you really
don't need any clever social
engineering for this attack to
work. If someone really wanted
to be bad and do this attack for
$400 you got ten of them.
Someone is going to plug it in
your odds are pretty good.
Speaking of official logo. If
you recall the form factor of
what the rubber ducky ships this
is just a quick Google search of
marketing USB drive, Ta-da the
exact same form factor that the
rubber ducky ships in for couple
of bucks you can put whatever
logo you want here because it's
just a shield there that
connects to it. You're up to
your 90% mark according to the
DHS study. Pretty useful stuff.
I kind of want to talk about now
why I actually made this
payload. There's plenty much
good ones already out there,
rubber ducky is nothing new,
product has been out there for
awhile now. And Darren, the guy
that runs hack 5 has his get hub
is full of really good payloads
that people have written. What I
found is that most of those if
not all of them would be stopped
by the modern defenses that are
deployed in most enterprise
organizations. I'm not talking
about your -- trying to attack
random victim at Starbucks, I'm
more focused on corporations and
more secure area. The person
I'll touch on is anti-virus. Lot
of payloads that are out there
will pull down tools of some
type. Whether it be net cat or
try to do some interpreter
reverse shell, what have you.
That's cool and all but if you
pull those down on company asset
your anti-virus is going to
light up like a Christmas tree
and stop in its tracks, it's too
well-known at this point. The
next bullet there, web filters
and proxies. Some of the other
attacks what they will do try to
make you go out to some open
storage place, Dropbox or box or
something like that, well, most
organizations, at least if
they're more on the secure side
of things are going to block
those style of sites. Not let
you go to any open storage pull
down any random file you want.
That's going to be stopped. Same
kind of mentality below with the
FTP wait list, trying to pull
down through FTP, again, most
companies if their level of any
security knowledge at all
they're not going to just allow
to you FTP anywhere from any
asset in the organization. Then
the last bullet has nothing to
do with corporate security, I'm
sure most of you are familiar
with HSTS those that are not.
It's kind of tool that was
designed just to stop this style
of attack. So, the old school
way of doing man in the middle
attacks, once you got in the
middle of the communication
path, you would tell the victim
just go ahead talk to me in
clear text. Trust me. Talk clear
text to me. Even though you want
to talk encrypted so your
banking site, I'll telling you
to go ahead HTP so I can harvest
the credentials. On the side
talking to the real banking
website you talk encrypted. It
worked well for awhile until
things like HSTS came along
which is an actual browser-based
security mechanism that says, if
you're on this list of HSTS
enabled sites no matter what the
man in the middle machine tells
you, you must always use
encrypted traffic. That comes a
problem because it thwarts the
way old school way of attacking.
Again, all your big sites are
doing that, like a paid sites
like you see, PayPal and your
social media sites even DEF CON
implemented this year, I guess
DEF CON has some super speaker
information in it. Let's talk
attack. Enough pretalk. The
first step is to actually set
the man in the middle machine
up. Because you have to have
something for the victim to
connect to. This is not the
focus the attack I'm going to
breeze through this stuff. Just
to give you an idea of what I
use when I set up the demo
you're going to see in a minute.
I use host APD. For wireless
radio, I use DNS mask for the
NDS server as well at DHPT
server, I.P. tables to direct
traffic over to a proxy, I
mention the toolkit. Those guys
actually have developed some
really cool scripts that I use
to kind of just adjust their
stuff to work the way I wanted
it. I mentioned proxies. The
I.P. tables mover stuff over to
proxy, you got to think about
once you get the connections
coming in to your man in the
middle machine, and you've got
the radio, it's listening,
people connecting to you, you
have to have some way to
manipulate the traffic or view
the traffic, what's the point of
sending it through if you can't
do anything with it. You have to
set up some type of proxy, and
my example I use burp suite
doesn't mean you have to have
burp suite it's easiest in my
opinion. You can use SSL, quid,
whatever. I do make note here
that whatever proxy you want to
use for this style of attack
make sure you know how to pull
the certificate out. Because
we're going to have to convert
that certificate to a base 64
encoding. I'll get into that in
a little bit. For those not
familiar with burp suite, I'm
sure most of you have seen it,
configuration I'm using today
very, very simple, I got it
listening on all interfaces,
just pick the 880 port you'll
see that invisible box as they
call it is checked but, industry
that's a transparent load proxy.
I mentioned you have to export
your certificate, well that's
what the little button below
that, you click there. Go
through dialogue boxes to export
the certificate. When do you
that it's going to come out in a
-- formatting, but at least I
want to touch on this. The
certificate if it's in Der
formatting notice that top
window there, that is text that
I can't enter by keyboard,
right? I want to make sure I
convert that certificate to
something that my ducky can type
in easily. Using open SSL
convert that Der formatting to
the base 64 encoding and if it's
done right you should look
something like that bottom
window. It's readable, all
letters and numbers. Now we have
the man in the middle machine
set up let's talk about the
payload itself that will be sent
to the victim. What it's going
to first bypass Windows UAC open
command prompt window. If the
user is logged in with admin
credentials it's going to get
admin credentials. If they are
user, they get user credentials.
The test that I'm going to do I
have admin Creds I'll make note
that this will work with user
credentials. Without admin
credits. Just going to have a
few extra pop up boxes along the
way. Second step it's going to
do create that certificate from
keyboard input the same thing we
exported. Then it's going to add
that certificate to the trusted
route store using built in tool
Cert Util. Then the profile then
connect to that wireless profile
then lastly it's going to clean
up its tracks. Going to delete
the files that it made in the
process. So, before we actually
look at the code I wanted to let
everyone at least understand how
simple this thing is to really
write. DEF CON gave me a lot of
credit by making me talk to you
buys gut really it's pretty
simple stuff. Again, very
straight forward. Delay, delay
in milliseconds. What you're
actually typing to the machine,
what you activate the payload
then all your command keys like
enter, Gui is the Windows
command, remark, any question on
that, get hub that Darren keeps
up has pretty much all the
documentation needed to any of
the commands here that it
supports. So here actually is
the first step in the payload.
Kind of broken it out here a
little bit. You'll see how the
code kind of works. Delays
milliseconds, that's ten
seconds. The idea behind that
when you plug the device into a
machine the first time you're
going to see Windows spinning
there with the drivers, load
drivers, load drivers, hopefully
done in ten seconds. Then going
to enter the issue of Gui R
command those are not familiar
with Gui railroad that will open
run dialogue box going to delay
200 milliseconds to allow time
for that box to top up and going
to type a little Powershell
command, start process command,
all that does is open the dial
up box, admin credentials if
possible. A little side note
here you'll see I put side note
that Windows ten, as well as 8
don't have to do that Powershell
command, for those that got
Windows 10 thing if you just do
Gui X then type A. It opens up
admin command prompt. A little
side note. Next step we'll have
to create that certificate on
victim's machine with keyboard
input. The way we're going to do
that we're going to use a built
in tool Windows called copycon
is those are not familiar with
copycon it's copycon, file name,
anything below, you break out of
it now you have a certificate. I
had to put obligatory picture of
the hacker in the presentation I
noticed earlier on my slides
this poor guy having hard time
typing he's got like big thick
winter gloves on. I don't know.
That's Google search for hacker.
We're going to use, in my
opinion the climax of the
attack, this is the part that
it's doing bad things. Cert
Util, enterprise, that's added
to the machine root store adding
that certificate we just
created. This command succeeds,
game over. Lastly we're going to
create XML file those are not
familiar, Windows handles
wireless profiles just a little
XML file, create that, then
after we create it we then
connect to it with net SH
command. Again pretty straight
forward stuff. Lastly just
delete those XML file and
certify that we created. All
right. Here is what it looks
like from the attacker's
machine. This is again burp
suite, we're looking at the
proxy a view there I've
highlighted there, people
interested in post commands.
I've kind of looked at post
command to Wells Fargo. I'm not
picking on Wells Fargo hopefully
don't sue me. Any bank would
work. You'll see at the bottom
the details you've got user I.D.
and password, clear text. That
poor person's bank was just
compromised. Alternatively this
is what it looks like from the
victim's point of view. There
have been no pop-ups no
warnings, no errors, no issues,
no indications there was
anything wrong, I've even opened
up the certificate details to
show that this -- probably can't
read that it's issued by port
swigger. Those are not familiar
with port swigger company that
writes burp suite they put their
name in the certificate. Really
bad day, Internet explorer, got
the best of them. I'm sure some
of you in the crowd are like, I
don't ever use Internet
exploder, I'm cool, I use
chrome. There's no way you get
me. Here's chrome. Same deal.
Look at the credentials, look at
the certificate details, you
also see signed by port swigger,
same story, no pop ups, no
warnings, no errors, no issues,
fully transparent to the user no
way by at least certificate
you'd ever know that somebody
bad had happened. So again, they
have no more money in their bank
account. Firefox, though. How
about Firefox. Yeah, yeah, clap.
Bad day for me I'm glad y'all
think it's funny. Firefox I'm
sure inform you -- some of you
know why this is the case.
Firefox decided they're not
going to trust Windows key store
and trust store that they're
going to implement their own key
store and trust store. Those
commands that I issued earlier
with the Cert Util that's all
for the Windows certificates.
NSS labs has the tool you can
download to actually manipulate
Firefox Certs they have their
own store. It's not installed on
typical distribution, there for
be very hard to use on victim's
machine. I kind of banged my
head against the wall for
awhile. My face looked like that
for quite a bit trying to figure
out how in the world to get this
to work. I just couldn't come up
with anything clever. That
brings me up to the next variant
of the attack. The twin duck
that I referred to earlier. So,
twin duck firmware again just to
recap, it mounts both a USB mass
storage device as well as that
same programmable keyboard
mentality we just had before.
So, to use the twin buck
firmware, obviously have to
reflash the device, not a big
deal. Instructions are out there
how to do that, very straight
forward. And I will make one
little side note if you're
planning on making some attacks
using the twin duck firmware
it's not really designed for
really fast IO, don't be trying
to load some massive application
up on your micro SD card and
pull from it through command,
it's probably going to behave a
little differently what you
expected. That's a cool quick
side note there. Let's start
this attack, what is different
this time we have to set it up.
First up, the steps are to
create a new Firefox key store
trust store. The easiest way to
do that go ahead infect your own
browser. So, go ahead open your
own Firefox up and take that
certificate that you just
exported from your proxy, load
it into your own browser. I've
kind of listed here how to do
that I'm sure you all know. Go
ahead and click trust the
certificate identity and
website, yes, that way port
swigger can sign anything
through Firefox, okay. After do
you that then you're going to
pull your key store and trust
store and copy it over to your
micro SD card, it's located in
the path there listed on the
screen. That variable works for
pretty much any basic install
you see it uses variables. As
well as wild card.default going
to give it some crazy number
stream.default that path right
there if you just enter that
into your machine it would go to
your Firefox profile. Going to
get those two files there listed
in the bottom. Get the Cert ADD
your key store and trust store
for Firefox profile. So, again
from, high level how this attack
is going to work now done the
prework set it all up. Same as
before going to open a command
prompt with admin CDs if it can
get them. Then this time a
little bit different going to
create a script to identify
where that mass storage was
mapped. Again, got to think
about this going to it blind we
don't know what is on the
machine once it's plugged in it
could be mapped to E drive, F
drive, who knows. A little
script trying to find where the
ducky mass storage is located.
Then it will create another
script, BSD script that will run
batch file invisibly. Just run
can in the background. And the
idea behind that it's quicker to
write a script on the screen
because it's all done with
keyboard input than it is to run
-- write the whole batch file
out. Just gives you a little
less time to scroll across the
screen. But what that batch file
is going to do is going to first
add just like before, going to
add the Windows, trusted root
certificate, it's then over
write user's Firefox Cert and
key store then create new
wireless profile, connect to it,
clean up. Here is what that
batch file looks like. Just for
those that are looking for the
code part of the talk. You'll
see here we obviously killed
Firefox don't want to do
anything while it's running.
Same commands added to the
Windows enterprise store of the
machine store. Then you'll see
over writes the Firefox
profiles. A quick view, sheer
what the micro SD card looks
like on my device, I'm getting
ready. You'll see the XML file,
the wireless profile, you'll see
the Cert file which we load the
Windows, you'll see the Cert and
key files for Firefox as well as
batch file we just looked at. So
there's the files that are
needed to run in the twin duck
mode. So, again, we'll go back
to looking what it looks like
from the user's point ever view
or victim's point much view.
Internet exploder, yeah, got
'em. Chrome, same story, no more
money in their bank account.
Firefox, yeah, Firefox. Sneaky
bastards, got you. You'll see
also been signed by port
swigger, we got 'em. Again,
because we loaded those trusted
certificates into their own key
store and trust store, this
point I'm more or less consider
the attack successful. We've got
all three modern browsers and,
yeah, they have all been -- with
that being said. Thank you.
[Applause] We'll dive into the
demonstration now and I kind of
want to set this up it makes
somewhat of sense, I obviously
don't have environment here to
have someone over there getting
attacked and want to show you
guys. What is going to happen is
hopefully, please no one in the
crowd be that guy that tries to
mess up my SSID, please. If you
do, whatever, I've got a video.
But I'd rather do it live.
Please don't screw with it.
There's going to be -- Windows
machine which I'm presenting
from that's going to be the
victim. You'll see, Windows
machines where I'll actually
apply the rubber ducky payload.
But there's going to be a Linux
box to represent which is which,
a Dabian background I have bunch
of like USB connections up here
I can't really show you. I have
USB connection to hard wired out
to the Internet as well as a
wireless radio that is going to
be hosting the SSID. From the
VM. And when the payload is
deployed hopefully the built in
wireless on the Windows machine
will connect to that wireless
radio. It's all kind of in one
but should depict what the
attack would look like. Let's do
that now without further adue.
That's what the Windows machine
is going to look like. I'm going
to change it to clone the
machine again. Should be able to
see my desktop now. All right,
so, here is going to be the
victim. Let's go ahead pull up
super secret password. Before I
actually get started, my
resolution is all whacked out
now. This is the script that I
was talking about, the toolkit
script that I kind of modified.
Again, for anyone that wants to
take note using host APD again,
using DNS mass and I.P. tables
to redirect traffic. Let's
actually do that. Actually
before I kick it off, let me
show you again, here is the --
I've got burp suite up and
running it's just listening on
any interface on port 8080 in
transparent mode that's where
again you go to export those
certificates. Let's go ahead run
that script. Hit enter to kill
me that's a little brutal. Okay.
At this point what I should see
if I were to look. There's SSID
being broadcast. It's actually
trying to connect. I'm
disconnect from it once to prove
that this does work. Now again
what I'm going to do I'm going
to restart the payload. This
would be indicative of me
plugging in, I'm dumb user that
picked it up and I decided I
found a nice flash drive let me
see what I can do with it. Ten
seconds. This is where drivers
will be loading but I already
had the drivers on the machine.
And payload has now started. And
it's now done. That's how long
it takes to do its magic.
[Applause] It's connectings like
it's supposed to be doing. Takes
a little bit. You guys are being
nice to me not kicking me off
there. Appreciate that. Now
we're going to -- you guys
already probably know damage
that can be done now that I've
got this connection in this
shape. But just for grins, we're
going to a Facebook account
created just for this
presentation here please don't
-- my Facebook account. Then
we'll also go again, poor Wells
Fargo, I could use another bank,
they're not my bank that's why I
chose them. All right. Let's go
for DEF CON user. Some super
secret password. Let's log in.
Hope to God this is no one's
password that would be awful.
Obviously, didn't work. Okay,
perfect. Just demonstrate, here
we go. We got some data. The
attack is working as we expect.
Let's first look at Wells Fargo.
You'll see like I had in the
slides there's the
authentication packet you'll see
the post, the off log on. Just
go here to parameters, I scroll
a little bit. You guys hope you
can see that -- DEF CON user,
password DEFCON3d. Let's
transfer all the money out of
that account. Got 'em.
[Applause] Scratch your head,
dude, you forgot to put a
password in Facebook. Good luck
getting that password now. You
messed the presentation up it
was in one of those leave me
always logged in which we know
what that means use
authentication cookies. That
actually may be even worse
because any of the Facebooks,
anyone who is Facebook how they
do their authentication cookies,
drag it up to see it better.
Every packet that you ever send
to Facebook you'll see this DATR
cookie that's authentication
cookie. Every time you do
anything in Facebook it sends it
over and over so I can click on
pretty much any of those posts
you'll see, there it is again.
And there it is again. What
we'll do we'll go ahead say, let
me just have those cookies for a
minute. Then I'll go over here
to this account, just prove
there's no shenanigans going on
I'm not logged in, I just
refreshed, no one logged in
here, with the help of a little
tool foes that are familiar with
grease monkey is crypting tool,
I got the cookie inject for
script loaded if I go in here to
-- let's take those cookies I
just stole and paste them in.
Thank you, all right. Now we
have hijacked the session.
Gotcha. [Applause] Thank you.
Again, the point being there not
that Facebook is your end goal
but so many sites that are using
authentication cookies I think
Facebook drives the point home
anyone that use the cookies or
passwords doesn't matter once
you're encrypted in traffic the
data is yours. Let's go back to
presentation. Wait for it. Got
it. So now since like I told you
guys at the beginning I'm not a
pentester I'm not a security
researcher, I am a security
engineer. So I am paid to defend
against these attacks not create
them. It's only fair that in a
responsible thing that I talk
about how to stop this kind of
attack. First bullet is wireless
intrution prevention system,
Wips, they're very powerful. But
this style attack would not work
because as soon as I spin up
that rogue AP start flooding me
with packets just wouldn't work.
If your organization employs a
Wips environment you have to
find some other mechanism to get
into traffic to you other than
through wireless. WIPS disable
mass storage. This is more
common there's lots of style of
attacks, not to mention DLP,
saying mass storage, that's also
kind of a bummer if you're
trying to do that second variant
because you don't have mass
storage available, you can't get
all through browsers the way I
did the payload. If you take
that mentality step further a
little more extreme, some
companies even disabled USB
ports entirely that would
certainly limit the attack
because none of the style of
attacks would work if you won't
turn on. Then this slide, this
bullet, frankly that bullet
could be in any DEF CON talk
given this weekend in user
training can always be
encouraged to be more
responsible with X. Just today
it's USB usage because that's
what I'm talking about. Yeah,
you can always use more user
training. To encourage
responsible use of technology.
Multi-factor authentication. If
I was able to pull this attack
off on you and you are using
one-time use password or some
token-based password it's going
to be very difficult for me to
reuse that credential. So,
that's another check in a box
for why you should use
multi-factor authentication.
Last one here may not be quite
obvious but those familiar with
cloud proxy agents, a lot of
organizations are now starting
to deploy them. On all the
corporate assets, what that does
it requires the company asset to
talk directly out to a cloud
resource for their proxy
exceptions. And typically
happens to both mechanism built
in if I got that communication
probably just break. It just
wouldn't allow you to go
anywhere I wouldn't be able to
encrypt anything because it
would have broken your
connection. Couple of other
things here, to consider. I use
wireless as mechanism of getting
the data to me. But that
certainly doesn't have to be
what you use. You can set up
proxy that listens out in the
cloud, right, instead of
changing wireless settings you
could go in let's monkey with
some of the proxy settings to
have it no matter if it's hard
wired, wireless, whatever, you
always connect out to say AWS
proxy listener you can have the
same kind of attack take place.
And benefits there is, one,
again, hard wire or wireless,
but you also don't have to be in
physical proximity. So you could
deploy this thing no matter
where they went it would be
taken out to like a cloud
listener. You could also
increase the authenticity. What
I mean by that is, again, I made
this as just a proof of concept,
the files are labeled what they
are, you could certainly label
them more suspicious things that
people would be trying to click
in, like if I was trying to make
it more authentic probably put
in file that says like salaries
or something. And I'd corrupt it
so they keep trying to open it,
just buy me more time of that
screen before they thought
something was fishy, as well as
talked about putting label on
the device, company X put that
label on it. Another note here
that the syntax will need to be
adjusted slightly for whatever
your victim base will be. And
the reason I say that certain
OSs will have different dialogue
boxes pop up at different times
with warnings, pop up at
different times as well as
timers. If your timers are on
like -- try to get very
aggressive on your timers, you
put into really slow old machine
timers may not work out right it
will break the whole attack. Go
to the play with the timer, play
with the syntax, the attack
should work pretty much
regardless of any version of
Windows. Just a quick little
shout out for the guys at hack
5. They have a form out there
for people to share,
collaborate, new payloads,
pretty active community. If
you're thinking about doing this
style of attack or you're
looking at new ways to get into
this kind of thing I recommend
you check them out. That's where
I got a lot of the ideas, some
of the code that I use for my
attack. With that, I'll finish
here with please, any questions
you have, e-mail me. I'm not
going to try to do the question
thing in this forum, too many
people. Find me out in the
public areas and with, that
thank you guys all for your
attention, I appreciate it. [
Applause ]