>> Hello, everyone. Thank you
for coming. My name is Fernando
Arnaboldi and I work as a
security consultant for
IOActive. I would like to show
you today how XML applications
are vulnerable to multiple
practical attacks. And for that
matter, the very first question
that I would like to have
addressed if I was sitting over
there is why are we talking
about XSLT? This is a
programming language that is not
so common. It has been created
when XML was created and it was
a way to parse XML data. So, a
couple years ago I came across--
Ariel Sanchez, a coworker, found
an external entity expansion
that allowed him to retrieve
some passwords. And I thought,
this is pretty cool. I want to
learn more about XML, schemas,
and XSLT. Those are all the
technologies related to XML. And
I was doing that, I noticed that
there were no things talking
about how to explore XML
implementations. When you are
reviewing a language, you may
want to know that. So what we
will be doing here is to analyze
what are those weaknesses and we
will present five different
issues in here and how you can
practically explore them. So
whether you are reviewing code,
if you are a penetration tester,
or if you are developing
technology related to XSLT,
these will come in handy, or
just trying to abuse an
implementation, hopefully this
will help. One of the things is
that even today no one of the
weaknesses have been fixed, so
everything will work. And you
may be able to affect the
confidentiality and the
integrity of multiple
implementations. And that means
that you may get even some
profit in certain areas. So, the
good thing is that you are not
exploiting flaws in a way that a
malicious virus or Malware
would. You will see no assembly
code. You will see just XSLT and
how that can be used to get some
fun things. So, we will briefly
talk today about how you can
identify your target, how
numbers will let you affect the
integrity, how random numbers
may be predictable sometimes.
I'll show you how to bypass the
same margin policy in a web
browser using XSLT and finally
some information disclosure
through (Inaudible) So,
basically the idea here is to
tell you what XSLT does, briefly
and how XSLT can be attacked.
And finally, if you didn't
know-- >> How's it going? >>
Hello. I was actually expecting
this. >> I know. That's why I'm
here. So, where's the mic? This
is your first time at DEF CON,
huh? >> This is my first time at
DEF CON, yes. >> How's it going?
>> A little bit anxious. >> You
seem a little nervous. Do you
want me to rub your shoulders?
>> I would be a little bit
uncomfortable. >> We have a
medicine for that. >> It comes
in a bottle, right? >> Yes, it
does. I gave him the right one,
right? >> Why am I getting the
water? I don't want the water.
>>Moron. >>Welcome to DEF CON.
>> Thank you very much. >> Yes.
>> [Clapping]. >> That was
interesting. >> You feel much
better, don't you? >> I feel
like a madman. Thank you very
much. >> You want to talk
directly into the mic...very
close to it. (Laughing) I'll
show you later. >> I would
expect that...and as I was
saying, you can identify your
target right here. Thank you. >>
So basically, XSLT is a language
that's being used to modify an
XML. So what it does is receive
as an input an XML document, it
creates a text document or an
HTML document or a new XML
document for that matter. So,
there are different versions
when it comes to XSLT. There are
three, V1, V2, V3. The different
versions doesn't mean that they
are improvement... well, they
are, or should be, but they have
more functionality. Each version
has more functionality. And V1
is the more implemented version
here because it has been
supported by web browsers and
because it is supported by
previous versions. So an XSLT
processor supporting V2 will be
supporting V1. So, I tested two
types of software. Server side
processors and client side
processors. Server side
processors means those are
standalone things that you can
run and come online or they
could be libraries hooked up to
different languages (Inaudible)
Java, whatever. When it comes to
client process servers,
basically I believe you have two
types, you will have web
browsers or eventually XML or
XSLT editors, and I believe that
that is a very narrow set of
people that are using those. So,
the processors in the libraries
are mostly three. These are the
most important ones, developed
by (Inaudible) Apache. Linux is
the most widely deployed one.
It's not only implemented by
server side processors, but also
by client side process servers,
web browsers. And you also have
(Inaudible), developed by the
Apache people which comes in two
flavors, SQL plus and Java. And
the similar thing with
(Inaudible) And the client
process servers, here we have
browsers, all the things that I
tested was in the latest
versions available of all the
servers, libraries, and the web
browsers. So, we have three ways
to do this. The first one
involves an XSLT processor
receiving XML and XSLT. This
only happens when you are
calling a common line processor.
And eventually you will get a
new document. You'll do this if
you need to parse an XML. So
people will be using this if
they need to parse something
server side. Another possibility
which is more common from a
client perspective is when the
XSLT processor is grabbing the
XSLT document. There is a small
portion in the XML that says you
will find here XSLT document. Go
get it for me, and create a new
document. And finally you can
embed the XSLT document along
with the XML and by doing that
you are just supplying one file
to the processor to get the new
result. So you might want to
know if you don't know already
who is your target, and which
kind of properties do the target
has. By getting which type of
version and vendor they have you
may know what type of
vulnerabilities you could
exploit in this target. Since
clients may also support Java
script, and that would be the
case for a typical web browser,
you may retrieve some Java
script information. All these
codes that you see here, and you
will be seeing here, it is only
white paper and you can do a
copy and paste and try on your
target of choice to see what
happens. At the end of each
section I will show you a brief
summary of the server sites.
Here we have all of them.
(Inaudible) all related to XLT
in this example. Then you have
the clients, which would be the
web browsers. You will see the
first column for the version,
the vendor, over there, and if
support Java script or not and
basically all web browsers
support Java script. And there
is one final thing. Normally,
XLT is more widely deployed than
other things, so you will notice
that it is sometimes when it
reaches (Inaudible) it may also
effect the client one. So let's
talk about the issues. So this
is something present in client
side and service side. And it
doesn't matter if you are
talking about floating point
numbers or integers, all numbers
will introduce errors in here.
So as I was testing this, it
felt a little bit weird that
sometimes that relation was not
working as I would expect it to
be. Certain additions,
subtractions were not doing what
I expecting. So, the very first
thing that I did was define a
simple calculation. What I was
trying to do is just to add a
few numbers. So for that matter,
I have (Inaudible) specific
output here, says text output.
In the middle, you will have
this simple thing, 0.2 + 0.1 -
0.3. That should be 0, right?
Pretty simple. May not be that
simple for processors. Only two
said that that was 0. That was
the case for (?) and Chrome. The
rest said, well, close to that.
Why is this happening? This is
weird. The weird thing is that
you'll see this across all
implementations. Ok. This is
cool. But it would be better if
it would do something with this.
I mean this shows numbers that
were not properly rounded by the
programming language. So this is
the things that is present in
all programming languages. I
realize that you have these in
Java script, Python, whatever.
This is a common thing. Floating
point numbers will have certain
decimals that are over there
hanging around that you may
take. So I created a simple Java
script application simulating a
bank. This is not my real bank.
I wouldn't try this on my real
bank. Hopefully my real bank
would limit the amount of
transaction. I wouldn't allow a
very small decimal to be
transferred from one account to
another. So the very first thing
that I tried was to see-- this
application I deposit a million
dollars in first account and the
second account has 0 balance at
the moment. This is where I will
deposit profit. So I notice that
if I remove a very small number
from million dollar account, it
will not get subtracted, but it
will be added to the secondary
account, because it has a lower
number than a million, it has a
0, and that decimal means more
for a 0 than it gets for the
million. So this program will
try to do the first portion of
the problem, will try to see how
big of a number it can retrieve.
It is a small number. And then
it will do millions of
transactions to move it to the
secondary account. So you will
see here that we will be using
V8, and that is the Chrome, Java
script processor, (Inaudible)
and we'll try to see what's the
best process to getting here.
How much money can I steal from
a million dollars that would not
be noticed? And I will try
moving that money from the
account number 0 to the account
number 1. And hopefully that
will gain me a daily profit of
around $1,300. It's moving
right? Yeah. So, this was good.
But it would be better if it
were a higher number. So let's
talk about integers. (Inaudible)
This should be fairly easy to
understand even if you are not
developing. You'll see that you
have five exponential numbers in
here, and the same five
exponential numbers written with
the number one with a bunch of
0s. The things is that
programming languages do not
handle it well when you have 16
digits because of precision. But
what I tried to do was print in
here the same number that I was
having on the XML document and
then format it with commas and
periods and such so it would be
more legible. In here you will
see that Saxon is doing great.
This is what you want to see.
You will see number one,
followed by a bunch of zeros.
This is pretty clear. This is
awesome. You will have the same
for non-exponential
exploitation. Internet Explorer
and Firefox are good. They
weren't able to show the
exponential notation. But that's
ok. The problem comes when you
are introducing errors. Because
there is nothing worse than
believing you have the right
number when in fact you do not.
In fact, I was noting today that
how they are finishing is
different depending on whether
you using exploitation notation
or not. We will try to use this
number in a couple of minutes.
Same for Java, almost there. For
C, they just don't care about
what's going on over there, so
anything can happen there. First
thing, this is something related
to an error in this download, so
I want to read this download
(Inaudible) But the problem is
not with the error. All
implementations have problems.
It's what you do with floating
point numbers and integers that
matters. You should be saying,
Ok, a number should be between
this value, and not allowing a
value to be so big if you are
not able to handle it. Either
way, this shouldn't be working
like this. So I reported all of
the issues, including this one,
the floating point numbers, to
the vendors. And the first thing
that I heard was that I should
be reading Wikipedia to
understand how floating point
numbers work. That was
interesting, but probably you
wouldn't find the answers there.
Then, I heard that I should be
reading the (Inaudible) that
this was effecting purely V1,
that was nice as well, but
clearly was not solving the
problem that was in here. And
the very same person also said
this is something that you'll
see in Java script as well.
That's fine, I know that you can
find this in Java script, but I
don't want to have this in my
programming language, or any
programming language because
these numbers are everywhere.
So, we stole some decimals
before, and now we are trying to
do a similar thing but with
integers. The thing is that if
you put a number zero, a number
one, followed by 17 zeros and
subtract the number one,
programming language will not
notice that the one is missing.
So perhaps, I created in here a
fake cryptic currency which I
have named fake coin. That the
value is very small, very, very,
small. So I bought a number one
followed by 17 zeros of this
coin. So I have a lot of coins
with a total net value of
transfer one coin at a time to a
secondary account, which will be
my profit account. And hopefully
by the end of the day I will
have a better profit than moving
decimals. The profit would be
better if I use more coins. I
would be able to transfer more
coins at the same time. Here,
just going for the minimum
amount possible just to show
you. The minimum amount here
gave me a profit of $2,300. If
you add a 0 to the coins, you
should add a 0 to the daily
profit as well. So that was
nice. That was nice. So the very
next thing that I did was to see
how random numbers work. If you
ever develop, if you have ever
developed, you need random
numbers. This is something that
you should normally see on
server side processors. And you
should also know that of course
not any random number generator
should be used (Inaudible)
Random number, you have to be
careful with them. In XSLT, this
is a function that comes from
the extended XSLT, which is an
extension of XSLT. It is defined
as a function that returns a
value between 0 and 1, as any
random function should be.
Supposedly any random number
should be a number that doesn't
have any pattern. You shouldn't
know what will be the number
before calling this map. That
would be fairly logical from a
random point of view. So, we
normally have two types of
random functions. If you have
ever developed you may know that
you have functions that are less
secure like random-random in
Python and you have more
cryptographically secure
mechanisms like system-random in
Python. You may want to use that
if you are moving cryptographic
things. And some of the software
that I tested, the service line
processors, the, you are able to
see the code, you are able to
see how that was developed.
(Inaudible) and Saxon, you will
see that in all those areas they
are using a random generator.
Which is fine. The thing comes,
the problem may come on the
implementation. If people are
using random numbers for any
cryptograph proposer, that may
be a problem because you may
know with a certain random
number generator what is going
on. This was a point that we
would see in C and C++ and Java.
And a good definition comes from
(Inaudible). These are chosen by
a random number generator. You
have to take that into
consideration and shouldn't use
them for cryptograph proposers.
But there is one more thing when
it comes to random numbers that
you normally pay attention to,
or you should at least, what
happens if there is no
initialization vector. This is
something basic for many random
number. And that's that you need
to have some sort of-- something
that's changing when you getting
a random number, otherwise you
may get always the very same
volume. And that's not very
useful if you're expecting a
random number. And that's
because you may know in advance
which numbers you will be
getting. So once you have a
proper IV in place, you will
have different volumes every
time that you are calling the
random functions. But let's see
again how the functions that we
saw before are working with the
(Inaudible) association vector.
And here there is only one that
doesn't have the IV. Again,
leave it XLT. This is not
something new to Linux XSLT.
They knew about these things in
2006, but this is how it works.
So, if you try to create an XSLT
that will produce a random
function, or you see anyone who
is trying to produce a random
value out of Linux XSLT, you
will see something like this.
And you will see these kinds of
results if you are executing
that on common line. I executed
twice on the same terminal and I
got twice the same number. You
can see that the 7.82, you
always get that first number
every time that you are
executing the random function
from Linux XSLT. So, the next
thing that I do is try to
understand how this can be used
in cipher modes when they are
doing blog ciphers. That is not
a way to cipher things if you
are using random. So I created
two executions of the very first
time to understand how these
numbers look like. So first I
printed the Python version of
random-random. And you get two
different numbers. Of course,
these are from the random number
generator. They may not be the
best, but they are not
predictable, and they are not
the same every time that I
execute that function. But Linux
XSLT can recognize again the
very same number that we saw on
the previous line, that 7.82
thing. That is the very same
number. If you are calling
Python again with a print
random-random function, we will
see that we have again two
different numbers. So, so far,
four for Python and one for
Linux XSLT. If we are calling
Linus XSLT again, you will
notice in second position we'll
always have these new values,
the 0.13 and it will be repeated
every second time they are
calling this. So, without having
an external (Inaudible) you may
know in advance which will be
the sequence of numbers that
will be generated by Linux XSLT.
Which is pretty cool, because
you may know in advance what's
being encrypted if they are
using this to encrypt something,
which would be pretty
ridiculous. So again, you may
predict values when you see
random numbers. The same origin
point is something present in
client side processors, this
means web browsers. Basically
this says that if you are on a
website, you shouldn't be
reading information from other
websites, but again that may not
be the case for (Inaudible) So
this is important, the origin is
always defined from the scheme,
the host, on the port of a URL.
What would be an example of
this? The http at the very
beginning or https would be the
scheme. The host should be
example.com and the ports should
be either port 80 or port 443 or
something like that. Generally
speaking, when we are retrieving
documents from different
origins, the web browsers will
not share the information. I
mean when we are taking the same
origin over and over, we may
have-- we'll be sending the same
cookie over and over to the same
website and that would be ok.
Normally, Java script is used to
try to deter this, but you don't
necessarily need to use it to
effect the same origin policy.
You should not be expecting that
when you are connecting to
Google.com your browser will be
saving the very same cookie to
this website because it have the
very same origin. If you are
connecting to Microsoft.com you
should be seeing a different
cookie. This will be a very
(Inaudible) You just connected
to the website and you are on
the main webpage and you are
trying to access a second
webpage that's being stored over
there. That will be fine. That's
ok, you are allowed to see that.
In fact, you are even allowed to
see other webpages on the very
same domain. But, if you are
changing the scheme, if you are
changing the host name, or if
you are changing the port, you
shouldn't be allowed to see any
of the information that is
present on that other website. I
mean you are not sharing the
private information between
websites. That's what you would
expect at least. So, there is
only one function that reads
documents, and that's document.
Ok, so you may try to use that
to read another XML document. In
fact, since we're speaking about
websites, we could also see here
xhtml, which is a fairly common
way to represent a webpage by
certain web servers. Once we
retrieve the html documents, we
could see what's inside using
either of these two functions
(Inaudible) It will show either
an XML representation or
(Inaudible) representation. So,
the very first thing that you
want to do if you want to use
this, you need to find a server
that uses xhtml. Ok. Bing.com
uses xhtml. I'm logging in here.
What can you do with this? So in
the upper right corner you will
see that my name is in a red box
and that is also reflected in
the code. Since it is xhtml this
is some sort of XML and my name
is in an element named ID
underscore M. So you may be able
to target your web browser to
retrieve that value. So let's
see how using that document, how
using many of the other
functions, we can retrieve that
information. In here, we can see
that the document function is
accessing the URL, WWW being dot
com. Then right in the middle we
are retrieving the information
that we just grabbed from the
document. And finally, because
I'm lazy, on Java script, I will
be subtracting the ID_ dot
element, which has my name.
Let's see a demo of this. First
I will open Safari and I will
show you that I'm using Bing.com
as my home page. And then I will
open the document that is on the
desktop that it is not sharing
the same origin because one,
Bing.com is being hosted on
https, Bing.com, and the other
one it is a file, it is a local
file. Let's see what happens.
Notice again my number in the
upper right corner. And when I
open that file, I'm reading the
document that is being stored by
Bing.com and I'm able to
retrieve my name from using
XSLT. Even though it is not
hosted on Bing.com, Safari
doesn't care, and we'll show you
that information. So, basically
Safari will all you to read
this. Internet Explorer may show
you a warning message, it will
retrieve the information, but
you won't be sharing anything
related to this. And other
browsers didn't show anything.
Another cool thing would be that
you may use some of these sites
to scan internal networks in
case you wanted to. There are
multiple ways to try to scan
internal networks when you are
executing something locally and
this could be another way as
well. So another vulnerability
that I found and I found would
be very interesting to discuss
would be an information
disclosure and I'm probably
reading through errors. This is
something that's present in
server side and client side
processors. The focus here is of
course on server side processors
because we wouldn't care what
would happen on a web browser.
So the cool thing about this is
that it is not possible to read
text files in XSLT1. It's only
possible to read XML documents,
or as we saw, xhtml documents.
And since it's not possible to
read plain text files, it
doesn't matter what function you
are trying to use in here
because all functions wouldn't
be capable of doing this. Let's
see what happens even though
when the W3C consortium says
it's not possible. We saw before
that there was one function to
read XML documents and that is
the document function. This
document will allow access to
other XML documents other than
the main document. We have that.
We can try to use that. There
are also other functions used
for accessing XML documents. And
that would be the functions
"include" and "import". These
functions do just retrieve and
(Inaudible) and I'll try to use
it combined with other
(Inaudible) We don't care what
the manual says about this
because either way we're not
trying to read a stylesheet in
here. I created a text file that
contains three lines, very
simple. If you see the contents
on my test file you will see a
line one, line two, and a line
three. Pretty simple. If you
read the documentations, you see
that when you are reading a
file-- this comes from XML
documentation-- if you are
reading a file, there are a
couple possibilities. The first
one is that you may show that
XSLT processor found an error.
And this is what some of the
processor do. They say this is
not allowed in (Inaudible) Okay.
That would be-- that's okay. The
other possibility would be to
return an empty XML document.
That's what Ruby does. Ruby will
show you that there is nothing
to see in here and this is
something that is also expected
as well. But again, this doesn't
solve the problem that-- we
wanted to read something that
was in the test file. Linus XSLT
comes again to help us with
this. So when using document,
XSLT prompt, PHP, and Pearl,
will show you first line of our
test file. Remember line one of
test file? That's not too much.
But it's cool. Perhaps we could
do something with that. We also
try to use other functions to
try to access these files later.
But having this unexpected
behavior in place may allow us
to do something with it. So you
may know in advance where I'm
going with this. We've saw
before as it may have an
interesting first line that
would be valuable for us. There
are certain specific files that
store the most valuable
information of a computer on the
very first line. So what if we
won't be able to read, for
example, a password file. Where
could we find those passwords?
The most common answer for any
Linux system would be in its
inner password. The next one if
you go off a bit (Inaudible)
through a shadow. The
possibilities are in your
imagination in here. Depending
what you are trying to read, you
may be able to retrieve certain
information that might be
valuable for you or someone
else. You also have the Apache
password and you may also have
database passwords. There are a
number of possibilities down
there. The thing is that this is
what you'll see when using, for
example, one of the processors
when trying to read it into your
password. You will see an error,
and also something else: the
password. Which is cool. I mean
you could also now use XSLT to
retrieve this information.
Another example you seen PHP
could be to try to use to read
HD password of an Apache. And
again, since this is something
that you store on the very first
line, you may see a bunch of
errors and right in the middle,
what you were planning to see,
the password for Joe, in this
case. And as I was saying
before, just in case they do not
care about what they are doing,
you could also have someone
using the shadow, leaving that
available if they are running
this as root, and this will
happen if you are using Ruby to
try to retrieve that file.
Again, expect all the errors,
but also expect the password for
the root over there. So, this is
pretty neat because I believe
this opens the possibility for
XSLT to be as interesting
perhaps as (Inaudible) expansion
as a way to retrieve some
information even if a hacker is
able to compromise an XSLT
because the application is
allowing-their application is
allowing XSLT to be uploaded, or
XML that are relying on document
importing include that may be
trying to read files. So,
either, if you are able to
control an XML and you have an
XLT processor in the back end
parsing this, or you are able to
control the XLT, you may
compromise the security of an
application. As we also saw, we
don't always need to do that in
place to have the
confidentiality and integrity
effected because sometimes when
using random function or
integers, they may be doing that
to our profit without doing
anything on our side. So, I
would recommend, as a very last
thing, that you should check
your code, or someone else, in
case they want to see what's
going on to use these things.
So, that's what I have for
today. If anyone has any
questions, I would be happy to
answer them. [Clapping] >> Thank
you very much. And thank you to
all these people who helped me
with the presentation.