So my name is Ken Westin, so
today I'm going to be talking
about being a professional cyber
stalker. I found a company
called Gadget Track, kind of
fell into it. I was sort of a
reluctant hacker and CEO, and I
actually learned quite a bit
along the way. My basic -- I
basically started developing
step recovery tools to help
recover stolen devices. Kind of
got into also the investigation
side because law enforcement
needed a lot of help, and I'll
kind of talk about some of those
challenges and things I learned
along the way. So I've actually
assisted law enforcement with a
number of investigations, not
just with the tools I developed.
A lot of times, they would come
to me for other debt recovery
tools, and -- or other data they
may have, and I'll kind of talk
about that too, how to harvest
information from social media on
other sources as well. I'm not
with -- currently senior
security analyst at Tripwire.
Catching a different type of
criminal, dealing with different
types of data, but I still --
still get to keep involved in
some of this stuff with some of
the investigations. So for those
of you, hard core justice porn,
this is my wall of shame. These
are actual cases I've been
involved with. You'll see a lot
of photos taken by web cameras.
I blur their faces out to
protect the guilty. And some of
these folks actually recovered
devices for -- we didn't have
photos of them from the web
camera. So it's interesting,
more than half the time, when I
we want to go recover a device
the people would go in and they
would -- the police would go in.
They would find other crimes. A
lot of times fencing operations,
drugs, people had warrants for
other crimes. Even got involved
with a very violent carjacking,
laptop sort of served as trojan
to help us identify and find the
people involved. And also, you
know, by basically trojanizing
devices, it becomes a trojan
providing visibility into these
larger criminal enterprises.
I'll go into detail throughout
the presentation. That being
said, you can probably imagine
some of the work I do. It
doesn't have its critics. It's
-- folks who don't quite
understand the intention or
background of the tools. The
fact, incredibly -- tools that
are much more invasive that are
available, nefarious things,
rats, malware out there, that
people can use if they want to
spy on someone. During the
process of developing the tools,
I was very concerned how the
tools might be used, and also
concerned about privacy.
Actually, investigating some of
the other -- recovery tools that
were out there, a lot of them
had back doors into the systems.
They would actually gather more
data than they really needed.
And so I tried to develop a tool
that was both useful for law
enforcement investigations but
also balance the privacy
implications as well. So I also
found mobile devices in
particular that applications
gather a lot more information
than what I did, and I'll talk a
little bit about that. A lot of
things that marketing
applications do more scary than
some of the information I would
gather for theft recovery
purposes. I got started with
this when I -- when I was
working for a company.
Specializing in blocking USB
devices, a long time ago, 2008,
2008. Exposure security, server
administrator, trying to secure
ebb with servers -- web servers
and managing websites and I got
really interested in how these
USB-based tools were being used
to compromise networks. You
know, hacking is hard. Trying to
access a network from outside is
very difficult. But being a lazy
hacker, you know, using USB
devices to compromise a system
or steal data a lot easier so I
started working with these tools
and created a website called
USBhacks. Some of the cools the
community was developing.
Started working with some of
these myself and it was really
interesting. I started getting
some interesting inquiries from
both sides of the law, first
time the FBI gave me a little
call. But I think once they
understood my intentions, that
this was more about raising
awareness, but at that time
nobody was actually talking
about this or providing these
tools, and now you know, they --
at least they had those tools to
play with, so other
administrators can actually test
their networks to see how it
would react to these particular
tools. A lot of researchers
actually still ask for those
tools, so actually put the URL
there just below the title, so
if you want to download those,
just be careful. Those should be
picked up by antivirus, but you
can still modify some of the
scripts and it will still work.
So you know, after I brought it
down, I thought about, what if I
was able to utilize these tools
and actually make them more
friendly, right? So instead of
taking a trojan and -- damage,
what if we turn that into a
happy trojan? Right? So you
know, the idea, very similar, is
that, you know, you plug in a
flash drive, utilize auto run
capability, you run a binary,
and you're able to gather a lot
of information. And you know,
you can do a lot where you can
grab -- you can grab all the
stuff but for theft recovery
purposes, I figure, IP address,
internal network address. We can
do some geolocation, just off
the IP, so we know what city
they're in. But the more useful
information was the computer
name and then the username of
the person that actually is --
is using that system. And
through that, I launch this as a
free tool. It was actually part
of my master's degree, the
system I built, and I put it out
there for free. I just kind of
curious if people would be
interested in this. I got on the
home page of dig and it got dug
registered over the course of
two to three days and as you can
imagine, this was all coming to
a central server, so it actually
-- you can actually activate
tracking, remotely. And then
when the device gets connected,
it will then send data to the
owner. So I was able to harvest
a lot of information about the
devices that this was working
with, and far beyond USB
devices. I found it was working
with external hard drives, GPS
devices, because that's how you
update the maps at the time. It
worked with -- also the iPods,
so didn't have the right
software all the time and you
plug in, one of these iPods and
you access it, it would get
triggered as well, which was
pretty interesting. I've gone
ahead, and put the actual USB
client source code, at least one
version of it, up here, so you
guys get the slides or you want
to download it, it's in C++. But
then here's the auto run
capability, right? A massive
vulnerability that Microsoft put
out there and it's still present
today. You know, you'll even see
a systems that are vulnerable in
industrial environments on
health care, still going to be
running Windows XP and still
vulnerable to these types of
attacks and I'll kind of show
examples of that too. You think
-- we would have learned by now
that USB devices are -- are bad,
but even Black Hat this year, a
lot of people they scattered a
bunch of flash drives out,
hacked into it and had data
stolen from systems. I'm not
sure innocent bystanders,
hopefully it wasn't any of you
guys. If it was one of you, get
the hell out. The trouble with
getting the IP address, we talk
about attribution, this attack
came from China. Well, you know,
IP address, you know, it's very,
very difficult to -- to use for
attribution. One thing I found,
law enforcement don't like
paperwork, don't like doing a
lot of work. So when you're
dealing with IP addresses, they
have to do a lot of filing, they
have to go through to get a
court order, to get that
information from an ISP. Some of
this process can take anywhere
from two weeks to three months,
it depends on who you're dealing
with. It also doesn't -- it's
not identity. It doesn't put the
person in front of the computer.
So you can go and you can
recover that, and it's, like,
yeah, that wasn't me. I don't
know what you're talking about.
Also, you know, it can help with
probable cause, but it's
increasingly becoming a
challenge to use IP address for
probable cause. Not accurate as
well. Nowadays, mobile hot
spots. People at Starbucks,
things like that. IP address
really isn't working very well
and in general takes a really
long time. When you're trying to
recover a stolen device, it's a
major hassle because time is of
the essence, especially when
these devices are getting
fenced. So with this, though, I
had the first -- first that I
know, the first iPod recovery,
it wasn't from IP address. I was
getting a lot of these things
where a lot of kids were
installing on iPods and it was
easy because a lot of times
these kids would still it and
they would go home and they
would plug it in, and then it
would be the -- like the family,
only one kid that had that last
name. So the school was able to
actually get the iPod back for
those kids, so -- it was kind of
fun. And I think it was cool
too, this time we did this, is
this the idea you steal
something it can be tracked. So
I like to think maybe that had a
little bit of an impact on
people's wanting to steal these
devices. And also through this
process, when I learned, all the
devices working with, I found it
was working with these high end
thermal imaging cameras.
Approached by a company to
develop a custom agent for them
where we actually would use this
to protect these devices around
imaging devices. So it was a
very similar process. The one
thing with this was, they
actually wrote the images to an
SD card, so, what if someone
takes out the SD card? We wrote
some custom code in the
firmware, puts in a new SD card
it will actually write a new
agent backed to the SD card, so
even if you put a new one in,
it's going to block it. What's
really interesting too is that
they weren't just concerned
about theft recovery but also
these devices, controlled, and
they were finding some of these
devices in countries where they
shouldn't be. That was another
sort of additional measures that
they wanted to take. So if one
of these cameras ended up
somewhere, was connected to a
computer in Iran, for example,
they would be able to map that
back to the resaler who sold it.
I -- who sold it. I disguised as
a thermal image of a cat. Meow.
So this is actually some stuff I
was working. Never actually
released it. I was looking how
to do similar things with --
with OSX. You don't have the
auto run capability but you can
still trick people. One of the
big vulnerabilities I like to
exploit is greed and stupidity.
But I found some things that
were really interesting, is that
you know using Apple script, why
Apple script? Why not objective
C in first I'm a shitty
programmer and two, Apple script
is trusted. It has a lot of
interfaces with a lot of other
applications, so if you're
targeting an Apple system, you
know it's going to have iTunes
and interface with this, so I
can -- and that's -- leverage.
So one thing I found too was
that, you know, Apple is a
little tricky. It's kind of
tiny, you guys can't see that. I
disguise the trojan as MP3 file.
What's interesting with OSX, if
you try to put like a .MP3 on an
app, it will throw a .app at the
end of it. So they know it's an
application. The first rule was
to try to trick that, and use
what's called a homo glip, looks
like a period and Turkish
character, if you put that in
there instead, it won't throw on
the end and looks like a .MP3. I
have a demo with this too, I'll
try to do at the end if I have
time. Further, you can disguise
the icon, pretty simple. And
I've actually put some of this
code up. I'm going to go through
some bits of it. There's an
object where you can get system
nervous. There's also another
one you can get where you can
get all the applications that
are currently running, which is
cool. You can then write
scripts. They will then
interface with those
applications and try to steal
data. The biggest one was, I was
trying to exfiltrate data. Sure
you can do things with shell
scripts and what not, but
sometimes that will throw errors
or alerts. So what I did, I just
-- I found a way to actually
exfiltrate data through iTunes.
So I will grab all that data I
want and coding I do. Included
in the URL here, GitHub page.
Full script. And then I'll pass
it out through iTunes. So -- and
then, iTunes, actually will
stream MP3. So you think you're
listening to some music while in
the background, we're doing some
bad stuff. What's neat too, you
can actually do shell scripts
from Apple script, which is
great. I'm not sure if you saw
the new -- vulnerability, I
threw that in there. Be careful
if you run on your system. It's
not on the one on GitHub but
still review the code, please. I
don't want to get in trouble. So
-- so you know, USB is still --
it's still an attack vector.
Still a threat. You know, we saw
that with Stuxnet. We've seen
with USB malware. International
Space Station. UP power plants
actually had -- were infiltrated
with employee, accidentally
bringing USB sticks. A lot of
those systems are still running
vulnerable versions of Window,
pretty much all now. We saw this
again here a Black Hat. Still is
a threat. So kind of moving on.
You know, IP address. You know,
that's a one piece of
information, but a lot of times
you're going to need a lot of
other data. This is a crazy
wall, you've seen this in all
the CSI shows, trying to track a
murder. They have all the
evidence and they put these
lines, right? And that's kind of
the thought process that I
follow as well. Tools that make
this a lot easier nowadays are
Maltego, automates a lot of that
process. I'm not sure if you've
used it, a pretty great tool and
you can actually write all the
custom transforms to do all of
this work. But basically, I had
a case where I was -- flash
drive, give you an example. We
were able to get the initial IP
address, and it was a weird
username too. It wasn't
something that would actually
identify a person, and we mapped
the -- and AT & T subscriber. AT
& T is going to take three
months to track it down and the
flash drive, from a professor,
and he had some research data on
it. But it was still hard to
convince law enforcement to use
their resources to track the
down. But we did start getting
connections from a university,
and specific computer lab. So
that was useful. Because we also
get the internal network
information, which is useful, so
we went to the university IT
Department, their campus
security and we found that,
yeah, so we got a time stamp. We
have an internal address, but
these are guest computers, so
not a student ID when log in, so
still not able to get the
specific person but I started
asking questions, what other
data sources do we have here,
and come to find out, you have
to swipe your student ID card to
get in, and so they have logs
there, right? So we're able to
access those logs. We -- time
stamp. Now we have a list of who
is in the actual room. Also, a
year before, systems actually
stolen out of that lab, and so
they actually had cameras as
well. What's really cool a lot
of people don't realize, a lot
of these cameras, when actually
store the data, also a log file
that gets generated so able to
correlate that time stamp as
well to identify who
specifically was in that room
and they were able to use this
information, found out who it
was. You know, had professor, as
well as the campus security
outside of the guy's classroom
the next and he got his device
back. All of his information was
still there. Yay. So after
working with USB devices, I
wanted to find ways of, you
know, looking how to recover
more expensive devices like
laptops. I looked at a lot of
existing tools and relied
heavily on the IP address. As I
mentioned before, it takes a lot
of time. Some of them --
actually they'll utilize more
invasive techniques as well,
open up back door to the system,
recovery teams that can deploy
that. They can install key --
and other things like that,
which I found not to be overly
intrusive and makes the system
more vulnerable. Stuff in the
firmware and muck with that, a
lot of risks. We don't need to
go to that extreme. I think
there's other ways of going
about it, recovering devices. So
I combined utilizing the web
camera, and with Wi-Fi-based
location. A company already
doing the web camera on the MAC,
but no one was utilizing Wi-Fi
location, this is where I --
when the first iPhone came out,
was using. I worked with
Skyhook, got that deployed for
this. So able to get
geolocation, able to get camera
information, so this was sort of
a game changer, especially for
law enforcement. Some challenges
with it. The way it worked, you
would activate tracking on a
remote server, the device would
check in to see if it's been
stolen, if it's been flagged,
supposed to start on gathering
evidence and a lot of things to
trigger. Moved to new network,
IP address changed, log in
event. Pretty smart. Would know
if it changed location, that it
would also check in. And so it
would then send information, and
at the time I didn't want to
manage a server, especially with
photos and things like that, so
we just had a -- had it go
director into Flickr. You
register your Flickr account,
that way you have control of all
your data. You don't have to
worry about a third party
accessing your information. Or
activating your camera and
spying on you. I don't trust
myself. So laptop would connect,
it would get location from
Wi-Fi, it would capture photos,
and it would do this every 30
minutes and it would do it very
quickly, so the green light, it
would be just like a blip. You
wouldn't even notice it was on.
So for location, use Skyhook
wireless, a great service. But
now geolocation is embedded in
all the operating systems, APIs
for it, and pretty much every
major -- laptop as well as
mobile operating systems. You
can also get location from the
Google map API, here's kind of
-- how to go about doing that.
So if you want to write your own
scripts to track your devices,
that's a good way to go. So the
first recovery I had was
actually with this tool was in
New York. A -- I had to work
with a New York police officer
who was kind of an A hole. He --
he was basically saying -- he
was really frustrated, he had to
deal with these types of tools
before and all pissed off
because he's going to have to
deal with paperwork. I'm, like,
no, you're fine. The location is
within ten to 20 meters. He
goes, okay, what's that mean?
Print out a photo of the guy, go
to that location, ask around.
He's, like, don't tell me how to
do my job, right? [ Laughter ]
But then -- and then he did.
Right. And they go in, and it
was this owner of a tattoo
parlor, and if you look at the
photo in the background, you're
going to see a lot of cool toys.
So there's a nice big-screened
TV, there's all sorts of cool
synthesizers, all kinds of audio
equipment and when the police
finally went in there, they
found the customers, it was an
iMac, and they also found three
laptops from different cases,
and a lot of other stolen
property. So this is one of
those examples where you
trojanize an app and then the
trojan app is sort of -- sort of
unveils all these different
crimes being committed. That one
I said we had a 300% recovery
rate because the other laptops
were recovered. So another case
we had was in Portland, Oregon,
where I live, there was a group
that was repeatedly breaking
into schools. So they were
targeting a bunch of Portland
schools, they would go in and
kept stealing laptops. What was
really frustrating, they would
do this continuously. They would
go in, they would steal the
laptops. District go and replace
laptops, a week later they would
come back this and steal again.
It was really -- it was, like --
it was like four or five
different schools this kept
happening to. I approached them,
I said, hey, I got an idea. So
we deployed this software to a
bunch of date laptops and left
them out. We didn't put in
locked cabinets, let them out
there. A week later, got ripped
off. So we got the network
information, and this was a bit
of a challenge. We're getting
some photos, and we actually got
it to a house that was in
Vancouver, Washington, so that's
the next state over, right next
to Portland. And we got the
location to this one -- one
particular neighborhood. And
again, the location is within
ten to 20 meters, so I told them
about this, and gave the
information, and the detective
working on it, he goes there and
he thinks it's an exact
location. He goes to this one --
it's a duplex and he goes to one
side of it and the guy that
answers the door, he knows him.
It's the guy that works on his
roof. He's all pissed off at me,
you guys don't know what the
hell you're doing. So I was
pissed off so I drove out there,
and I started actually looking
at the wireless. A little street
there, I pulled in. And pulled
out my laptop and I started
looking at the wireless networks
in area, make sure accurate.
Wireless network, Russia, and I
look over and right next to --
on the other side of the duplex
there's a car and there's this
big, like, Russian pride bumper
sticker on the car. And then
look in there, girl comes out,
starts watching the car. The guy
we have a photo of walks out.
Oh, shit. He looks at me -- on
my laptop, right, like I'm lost.
I called the detective and they
came out and then finally they
-- they were able to continue
the investigation. What's
interesting with this, they
never actually told software was
involved in their case. I was an
anonymous source, and they ended
up arresting six to seven people
that were in this case. It was
an organized group. They were
stealing a lot of other property
as well. Some of them were
pretty bad dudes, and they got
them to think that they'd all
ratted on each other. So it was
kind of cool. So for some
reason, there's a lot of sort of
-- these Russian guys that are
involved in stealing property in
Oregon. I was involved in
another case where the laptop
was stolen and we didn't get
anything for like, two weeks.
I'm, like, oh, man, they
reformatted the hard drive or
something, right? I tracked --
starting getting -- in Missouri,
of all places. I'm, like, how
the hell did that happen, right?
We're getting this, and a guy
named Victor, and he -- who was
nice enough to change the
username on the computer to his
full name. Nice of him to do.
Really trying to help us out.
But I had photos from
everywhere. The first one we
had, McDonald's. And then at one
point he was in a hotel. That
was really shady, a girl behind
him. Something going on there.
But I was able to find -- yeah,
I found his Myspace profile, and
I was really -- noticed he's
into Scion. Car nut. He has a
bunch of posts on a lot of
different forums on Scion
showing off car. He gave me his
license plate number. He was
also a big eBay seller, he was
selling -- he had a store,
selling all kinds of car parts.
Kind of tell what kind of
business he was involved in. And
then he was nice too -- not so
nice, he sold stolen laptop to
his friend, O'Mar, as well as
stolen bike. What happened when
police went in, the first time
we worked with district
attorney, he said you guys have
given us enough evidence, even
if he doesn't have the laptop,
we can bust him for possession
of stolen property. That was
kind of interesting, start
making case law. But they --
what was happening is that
there's a Russian group that was
here in Portland. They would
steal a bunch of property. Load
it into this big white van and
another Russian group in
Missouri, and they would swap
stolen property. Where's the
first place you're going to look
when your laptop gets stolen?
Craigslist, right. So they're
kind of smart there. Not that
smart. We got them. Oh, yeah,
and Victor too. It was actually
his dad who was involved -- it
was a birthday present. So his
dad, nice guy, gave him a stolen
laptop for his birthday. Now he
has a criminal record. Thanks,
Dad. There was another case
where we had -- I was in Brazil,
not just the U.S. A little bit
of a challenge, working with the
Brazilian police, but there was
a -- a couple guys that were in
their car. And these guys came
out with guns, and you know,
said, get out of the car, and
then the driver, they punched
him in the face, knocked him to
the ground and kicked him. He
had like broken ribs and a
broken nose, and then guy who
actually installed my software,
he left his laptop, was still in
the back. So we started getting
pings, and then the police were
actually really excited about
this, but they were -- I guess
they did -- quite a bit, right?
So they were assaulting a lot of
other people as well, stole a
lot of vehicles. But just a good
example of how this can work
internationally as well. It
doesn't have to be the U.S.
Sometimes it depends on law
enforcement, how willing they
are to help out. There's ways of
convincing them. And here's the
customer with his laptop bag.
Veterinary student too. Just
finished dissertation and didn't
have it backed up. So he was
really happy to get it back. So
then I also moved on to mobile.
So mobile is a little
challenging, geolocation is
easier, I'm in the device
itself. But IP addresses becomes
much more problematic. We also
want to -- we found people
really don't care so much about
the device as the data. So we
built a system for backing up
photo and contact information.
And I was really concerned about
actually doing that, like
storing people's photos on a
server, you know, first of all,
get hacked and someone accesses
all of customer's photos, really
bad. Contact information as
well. We saw this with -- that
the risks that are associated
with that. And so we built a
system so that when you actually
install the app, you enter a
key, a privacy key, so it will
-- it actually encrypts images
and contact information before
it sends it to the server. I
like this too because if we do
get hacked, we're -- data is
still protected. Also if law
enforcement comes to us and they
want information, yeah, here you
go. Big encrypted blob and they
have to go to the customer to
get that key. So, umm -- and
then you can also do the data
wipe and things like that. So I
-- I built this tool, and -- and
I have a little bit of a video
to walk through one of the
cases. So I'll -- hopefully the
video works. >> Helping track
them down. News channel eight,
spent last two days with police
and investigators on the trail
of swiped cell phones. He's live
outside the Washington square
mall where the theft look place.
>> The managers of the Sprint
store here say they're very
confident tracking software
developed only miles away from
here and put on their demo
phones will lead to an arrest.
>> This is a $500 phone. Ended
up being a $450 phone. >> Two
empty display cradles all
remains, after one -- stole,
Washington Square Mall. Thought
theft on tape, initiated
tracking software installed on
the stolen phones. >> Able not
to only find the GPS location
but also we've been able to
monitor any activity that
happens in the phone. >> That
activity turned out to be
pictures. Someone took shortly
after the phones were stolen.
Admit it's a brave new world
when pictures taken on cell
phones can be told to send back
pictures once stolen. >> That
has not only peaked the interest
of our investigators but in
essence appears at this point
could be very credible
information for us to follow up
on. >> The Portland creator of
the software tracking, police
are on the right track. >>
Definitely know who stole it. >>
If you look over the head of
this man, you'll see in the
window an Oregon temporary
permit. >> This is it. >> A
gadget track investigator on the
phone, we tracked to Vancouver
apartment complex. There found
the permit and -- >> Hi. >>
Young woman told us off camera,
man called Peter, sent photo
this Saturday evening, knew
nothing about the phones.
Tracked the second cell phone
signal to this duplex about
eight blocks away. >> Don't have
a Samsung epic phone at this
location. >> Police were here
yesterday looking for it. >>
We're back live now outside the
Washington Square Mall, obtained
within the lawyer, temporary
permit. Hope the men in the
pictures will contact them soon,
so they can explain how their
faces ended up on a stolen cell
phone. Back to you. >> Thank
you, Ed. Teach out. The
contractors -- [ Applause ] >>
Thank you. So you know, helpful
-- we had the footage, again,
kind of like I was talking about
with the video camera footage
that's helpful. Actually see
where you caught it. We have
some challenges with some of
these devices because the -- the
-- for some reason, the GPS
coordinates with software --
luckily the photos they were
taking of themselves, embedded
in it. Time stamp as well.
Stupidity one of the
vulnerabilities that helps us
out. Location as well. The trip
permit, that's just ridiculous.
But they ended up getting these
guys, and they -- again, they
ended up -- five guys that were
involved in this, and actually
stealing other property. One of
these guys actually had a
warrant out for his arrest
already. And they also, in the
process of investigating this,
they also recovered a stolen
car, so -- and so what I learned
from this too, I started looking
at the data that's actually
embedded in the images where
it's really helpful, so there's
a lot of metadata actually
embedded in it. You're probably
familiar with it. GPS
coordinates, time stamp. High
digital cameras, embed model and
serial number and really good
tool here, URL called -- if you
want to mess with data and write
scripts to do this kind of work
you think do that. I also have a
tool called -- scan.com, where
you can upload an image and you
can see what -- if there's GPS
coordinates or serial numbers
embedded in it. You can do that.
And one thing I found is that
there's several camera brands
that actually will embed that
serial number, and many of them
are high end cameras, so I
wanted to go out and see if I
could, you know, use this for
tracking stolen cameras, and one
thing I found too, I had a
reporter that actually asked me,
a thing about a celebrities
getting nude photos hacked. And
the -- the media kept saying,
yeah, the phones were hacked,
but in actuality, the data
revealed actually multiple
phones over the course of
several years, so the odds of it
being one device hacked was very
slim. The point of compromise
was actually e-mail. Guy named
Chris Cheney, just guessing
passwords, now serving ten years
in jail. So I looked at, like,
how can I use this information?
There wasn't a way to actually
search for it. You can search
for a serial number. Sometimes
you'll see something on Flickr,
but I was, like, I want a
database of this data where I
can actually go through. And
identify that, so I worked an
experiment -- and experimented
with something. I was actually
helping another startup friend
of mine. They were doing a thing
called CP usage, where you can
-- you give up your idle
computer time, and they'll give
you money for utilizing that, so
a punch of computer labs,
universities were using this.
Sort of like -- but for other
projects, right? And then you as
researcher could harness the
power of thousands. I wanted to
go through and mine Flickr. The
way it works, wrote scripts that
go out and hit the Flickr API.
It was very restrictive how many
calls you can make. Trying to do
that from one system and trying
to do it quickly, they're going
to block you. Actually talked
with a friend of mine who -- who
they had some issues, they saw
the data and they saw the
reports coming through, Yahoo
and trying to figure out who
this was. And it was me. But we
-- so we -- we basically were
allowed -- we had about 200
computers at our disposal and
went through and mined all of
Flickr. It took about three
weeks to a month, and it was
like 4 billion images, so we had
this huge database. And then I
put it out there in the media
that this was available, and the
way that it works, you know, I
also mined 500 -- I found other
ones, Twitter, some other sites
as well. Harvesting some data
from there. So the way it was
working, we would harvest this
information and you can actually
put in the serial number of your
camera, and then it will show
back results all the images that
we found. So the idea is that if
your camera was stolen and three
months later you see a photo get
upload to Flickr, you can go
recover your camera and a proof
of concept, but it worked. We
actually -- John Heller, he saw
this service. He actually had a
camera that was stolen when he
was on assignment for Getty
gear gone. A contractor, not
going to get that back. It's
pretty hurtful here. But he did
a search. And then he found an
image on Flickr, uploaded, well
after it was stolen, and that
mapped to Facebook, to another
professional photographer, and
he was -- had a photo of all of
his gear, and there, sure
enough, was his camera. The LA
PD got involved and what
happened was, the thief he stole
the camera from him, sold it on
Craigslist, and then the guy
that bought it from him on
Craigslist, sold it on eBay. The
person actually had it actually
had no idea it was stolen. The
police went in, were able to
recover it. The guy that got it
on eBay, he went to the seller
and was able to get his money
back, yay, not the other guy --
the other guy, not so much. The
year after it was stolen to the
apartment, the guy bought on
Craigslist, the guy was still
there, all kinds of other stolen
property. The first recovery of
its kind I have ever seen about
that. Here's the report there.
But, yeah, he got arrested. So
had another case where a guy,
Craigslist, I'm going to start
calling it crime list or
something, because that seems to
be where all this stuff
happening. A bunch of camera
gear before he moved, and a guy
came with cash in his hand. He
wanted to take a look at this
camera he was selling. Takes him
out to the garage, shows him the
box. The guy just pops him one,
knocks to the ground and runs
off. So -- he actually found
images that were mapped to it.
Help with this. We got a lot of
information about this guy. And
all the other photos he was
uploading to other social media
websites as well, and he was
doing some pretty interesting
things, you know, taking photos
of themselves, speaking weed,
driving down the freeway, photo
of himself with a gun, showing
how hard core he is. And also
took a photo of his speedometer,
going 110 miles an hour down the
freeway while smoking dope and
we had the time stamp
geolocation and everything, so
law enforcement really liked
that. [ Laughter ] >>
Vulnerability stupidity. And
tool was actually used by ICE,
really interested in using this
in trial exploitation
investigations unit. So at the
do some really cool work where a
lot of these guys that are
actually victimizing children,
there's some sick forums out
there, actually be giving each
other advice. Actually upload
photos, young girl, I have in my
car, and they can actually look
at some of the images, the ICE
guys, road sign or something
like that, to look for some
indicators they can go and try
to stop this before anything
happens. And so they were
actually utilizing this tool as
well, so the idea is that, you
know, Joe Pervert, he's
uploading child porn, and maybe
he's using the same camera when
he goes to Disneyland, photos
with family. Image, and you map
that and correlate that with a
camera on Flickr, for example,
that can help them ID a suspect.
I'm not sure if it was ever
used, caught anybody, they
couldn't tell me. I thought it
was kind of a cool application
of it. So basically what I
learned a lot, there's a lot of
pieces of information out there
that can be used to identify a
suspect. This is -- he's the
grandfather of forensic science
and he has this thing called
Locard's exchange principle,
every contact leads a trace.
Physical crimes. I believe that
actually carries over into the
digital world as well, from my
experience. We have all these
pieces of data, IP addresses, I
get really worried about all
these different breaches that
are happening. We have all these
data points, and we start to
correlate them, we can actually
start to create a rich profile
of an individual and then we
talk about -- all the different
places where we can find those
indicators from device IDs,
things that we may not even
think about right now they can
identify. Technology can exist a
year from now that will allow us
to mine that and identify us.
And I talk about interaction of
things. There's data that's
created by us that we're aware
of. There's data created for us,
that we may not be aware of.
There's also data created about
us, that correlates all of this
information. So I really worry
about the marketing groups in
particular. And then what I call
boogie data. So a lot of people
don't realize when you send an
SNS message for example, the
other person deletes it, there's
20 log files that get generated
at least through the carrier. So
there's always a trace
somewhere, talk about Ashley
Madison, things like that, our
privacy being protected when in
actuality it's not. So I call
this boogie data because it's
information that's out there,
and it's -- it can come back and
haunt us later. It -- it's going
to hit us really hard. I've been
working with a group, privacy
century, application, called
spyware.b and looking at
applications accessing your
location and sending that
information. We've been doing
some really interesting research
here, identifying some very
popular applications that are
actually gathering location,
your IMEI -- sending to servers
in China, for example. And
that's it for my talk here. If
you guys have questions, feel
free to reach out to me on
Twitter or on my e-mail. Do we
have more time? Five minutes.
Okay. I'm going to do a quick
demo. See if this works. Demo
gods. Here's the Trojan. Dot
app. Another one, MP3. Double
click on this, network
connection works, we should see
it in action. [ Music playing ]
Thanks a lot, guys. [ Inaudible
]