[Music]
thank you
better yes
all right then all right so I think I've
got my work cut out for me because some
people knew at least 30 less but nobody
thought it was insecure so let's see how
you think about this at the end of this
talk
uh Reds all right let's start by taking
a quick look at the email ecosystem so
let's assume we have a sender Alice that
wants to send an email
to Bob
both of them use the so-called mail user
agent orange or what you would normally
call a male client like for example
Thunderbird
both also have a so-called main service
provider for example Gmail or Android
and MSP
now Alice wants to get their email to
Bob
first they will have to talk to the mail
submission agent or the MSA so
just an SMTP server for example in this
case they will have to configure
this work not really all right whatever
they have to configure a host a port and
an encryption mechanism in this case
start killers
then that will get the mail to the SMTP
server and Bob on the other side will
have to do the same for the mail
delivery agent so just an IMAP or POP3
server in this case
then the maid reaches Bob and that is
basically the connections we will be
focusing on during this talk
but I don't want to leave you hanging so
how does the mail get from there to
there
we have the mail transfer agents or
short ntas of both msps talking to each
other some way over the internet via
sntp
and this is generally considered to be a
pretty hazardous field so certificate
validation is hard DNS is hard so that's
why we are not talking about this
because it's generally assumed to be at
least somewhat insecure so we'll be
talking about the first and the last hop
so submission SMTP and IMAP and POP3
however at least in our opinion the
first and the last hops are the most
critical ones because in this steps user
credentials are transmitted so just a
single insecure connection gives full
access to the victim's mailbox with all
catastrophic consequences you might
imagine from that
we therefore Define our attacker model
as follows we assume an active metal in
the middle that can manipulate TCP
packets in plain text but not break TLS
in any way
so no actual TLS attacks here
so let me now give you an introduction
to starting less starting with a little
history lesson
demon protocols SMTP POP3 and IMAP we're
all defined before as Valentine's very
little thing therefore they were of
course plain text only
and there were plain text Parts defined
for these protocols in the first place
note here that the standards distinguish
between transmitting layer from NTA to
MTA and submitting a mail to the MSA
so there are two parts defined for that
with the Advent of S7 TLS
parts were defined for implicitly less
so just speaking the protocol over TLS
so what you would normally see for https
just for part 3 IMAP and sntp
and there were new parts for that
however it was considered to be wasteful
to have two parts for the same protocol
so in 1998 and 1989 the start TLS
mechanism was defined to allow for what
is called opportunistic encryption
so basically the mail server and the
mail client will negotiate tell us if
they both support it
to this day Wikipedia's starting this
article redirects to the opportunistic
TLs article so that kind of gives India
how people think about starting less
nowadays still
and we on the other hand think that
there's absolutely no reason for start
here let's to be opportunistic in May
clients nowadays because your mail
server should really support you less by
now
so when adding status Simplicity less
port for sntp was revoked by Diana since
I realized the mail ecosystem and
especially MX records do not allow for
specifying ports sadly they also removed
the port for submission for no apparent
reason
but since 2018 it's all good there was a
RC 8314 which is aptly titled key text
considered obsolete the implicit area
supports are back and there are now the
parts you should be used for you should
be using for email and we even got an
implicit TLS port for submission back
snpp MTA 20a is still a mess though but
it's being worked on by people
so let's look at status at the example
of sntp
upon connecting the server Center
greeting telling that they are
sntp.example.org
Alice is more will respond with an ELO
command to which the server responds
with their capabilities in this case
just start TLS
the client sends a star TLS command
to which the server responds that I will
do this now everything up until this
point was basically in plain text
now client and server will perform the
actual TLS handshake and everything
after it will be encrypted the client
will again Ask for capabilities to which
the server responds that they now
support Authentication
will authenticate and send the actual
email
but next let's talk about what started
as dripping is a means
assume again that we have this active
metal in the middle that can manipulate
TCP packets therefore they can simply
strip the starting as capability from
the ELO response without the server or
the client realizing because nothing is
okay authenticated here
assuming that the client is really
opportunistic they will first not send
the start TLS command second not perform
the handshake and third send everything
in plain text
this is of course pretty problematic
because LSS user credentials and their
email will now be transmitted in plain
text with the attacker still listening
of course the server could potentially
block any commands except the start TLS
command but nothing would prevent the
metal element from hijacking the whole
now unauthenticated and unencrypted
connection and poses a legit mail server
to the mail client
but it of course does not stop here what
if the attacker changes something over
here
like pretending the star TS command
failed
or over here like adding an insecure
extension to the either response that
Ellis might use later on
or
here like adding some data after the
star Taylor's response before the
handshake that might be interpreted like
anywhere
it turns out that when you start digging
into the details you will find that
exceptionally many issues in real world
applications access to start Healers
and of course it does not stop with SMTP
this is an iMac trace the concept is
basically the same it starts with a
greeting they negotiate starting less
they perform the handshake
but what happens if an attacker changes
something here or here or here or here
or here or really anywhere
all right let's slow down a bit and take
a look at the research during our talk
we will consider four questions
regarding startiness
first we wanted to find out out if
modern clients are still opportunistic
in their use of star TLS and we'll fall
back to plain text if it's not available
if that would be the case an attacker
could simply use one of the well-known
Star Theater stooping attacks like the
one I've shown you before
to force a client to send sensitive data
in plain text
in that case there were really not much
to be learned here so let's assume for
now that that is not the case
so second we analyze what potentially
sensitive data is exchanged in plain
text and how clients might requested by
exposing additional sensitive data in
plain text
third we looked at what data is retained
from the plain text phase after the
transition to TLS so nothing is
authenticated before the TLs handshake
and really no data should spill into the
encrypted phase of course
as well
so finally we looked at what happens in
error cases so all protocols have some
kind of error mechanism and we wanted to
know what happens if these errors happen
before the TLs handshakes so an active
metal in the middle code first errors to
happen or just inject errors
and we wanted to know what clients do
with these
all of this accumulated in using
security 2021 paper called ytls is
better without starting Less on which
Damian will now give you the details
okay thanks Fabian
so s Fabian has motivated start LS
leaves really a lot of room for mistakes
but let's step back for a moment and
explain our methodology
what we wanted to do is to obtain a very
Broad View on the start TLS ecosystem
meaning that we wanted to test as many
clients and as many servers as possible
possibly coming from different platforms
such as Linux Windows and Mac but also
from mobile platforms such as Android
and iOS
and especially in the mobile space we
have a very interesting platform that is
called Cloud mail and in Cloud mail what
an application what a mobile application
is doing is that it does not talk with
the email server directly but instead in
it it instructs a third party to do the
email communication for it for example
via http
so for example if any one of you is
using Outlook or my mail on Android your
password is basically first transmitted
to this third-party backend which is
will then do the email communication for
you
however this means that we cannot really
observe what the system under test is
doing which is why we have right from
the beginning restricted our tests to
network only black box testing which
means that we need to have a test set or
a set of test cases
what's also interesting here is that
generally is it is a lot easier to test
email servers than it is to test clients
because typically an email server will
constantly listen for new incoming
connections in clients we had here to
get a little bit more creative by using
pre-configured snapshots and virtual
machines such that we could basically
request connections so to say
and now how do we create a good start
TLS test Corpus
what we did was in the first place we
conducted a literature review in this
view in this review We queried cve
databases bug trackers and search
engines for keywords such as stls and
star TLS
and what's interesting here is that
already at this stage
we could create a small test Corpus and
we will as we will see that two of the
most devastating attacks were already
present at this time and basically we
just had to apply a well-known issue to
a new set of email applications
and the second thing that we did was to
conduct a protocol analysis by taking
the protocols uh the protocol
specifications into account and thinking
about how we can generalize the found
problems
as a result we ended up with a test
Corpus containing more than more than
100 starting specific test cases that we
classified into five distinct attack
classes and for the remain remainder of
my part of this talk I will go with you
through each of these class and and
explain the most interesting findings
that we found
so let's start with the negotiation
class
in this class the aim of the attacker is
always to derail the star TLS connection
such that TLS is not made in the first
place
and the two most prominent or the the
most prominent example of that of this
is starting less stripping as Fabian
shot in the introduction
so an Attica can hear a script the star
TLS or remove the start DLS capability
from the server response make the client
think that start till as a start LS is
not supported which which means that the
client will not do the or not
participate in a TLS handshake and
besides changing the message flow a bit
the result is that the edge can obtain
the password in clear text
there is a second variant of start LS
which consists of changing the Response
Code of the of the start DLS command but
basically the result is the same as for
this first variant
and now I think there is an even more
interesting case
um and this is called the pre-off
greeting or the pre pre-off attack and
here we already changed the greeting
type Itself by exchanging the OK
response with a pre-op response
and now it is not clear what happens in
this case and to understand it we need
to look at the IMAP State machine
and if you look here you will note that
IMAP has that IMAP defines multiple
types of greetings that transition the
client to different states so for
example the OK the OK greeting will
transition the client into the not
authenticated state
however when you lose use the three of
greeting the client is inspected is um
is expected to directly transition into
the authenticated State this can make
sense for example if you're using IMAP
via an already authenticated connection
for example SSH
but now something interesting happens
IMAP is pretty specific about which
commands are allowed in which stage or
in which a state and the started S
command is not allowed in the
authenticated state
this means that the client would
basically violate the specification
should it do the start LS command but
the alternative is clearly to do
something similar as to start a less
stripping by not doing the start LS
transition transition at all
but here there's something more we have
to consider because as I explained to
you the client is now in the in the
authenticated state so you could you can
ask yourself why should it log in again
and in fact if you have a standard
conforming client it will not do the
login but maybe proceed with the select
command and stack instead to select the
inbox
and now the question is what does it
give gives us as an attacker what we
could do here is um to for example mimic
a valid IMAP server and for example
present an inbox that is almost empty
but only contains a single message
asking for ransom for example
but we can do better if the client
supports the mailbox referrals extension
we as an attacker can instruct the
client to select the inbox on another
server for example then this should
remind you a bit about the HTTP about
HTTP redirects
and because the Attica can choose the
domain name freely they can use a name
that they have full control to or where
they can obtain a valid TLS certificate
too
so this means that at this point the
attacker can just do the full hand check
including the transition to TLs but
still obtain the credentials from the
login or from the network traces
so in total we found that 15 of the
tested applications were vulnerable to
certain forms of negotiation attacks but
we have to be a little bit careful here
not in all cases we could obtain valid
user credentials but at least in every
one of these cases we could obtain
sensitive data such as send emails or
drafted emails
which brings us to session fixation
attacks
as I as I have explained the start DLS
command is not allowed in the
authenticated State and it turns out
that there is a very good reason for
that
consider our user Alice who wants to
communicate with your implicit TLS
meaning no start Killers involved at all
with an IMAP server
so this means that both parties are in a
state where the next thing that is
expected is the TLs handshake
and now also consider our attacker what
they can do is in the first step to
first get a hold on the connection
and then instead of proxying Ls
connection directly to the IMAP server
the attacker would connect to the server
receive the greeting
log in with his or with with their own
account and then initially initiate the
start TLS command afterwards
and now it should be evident that what
the attacker could do is they can just
exchange the port number of Ls
connection and start to proxy the TLs
data directly to the IMAP server and
vice versa
and this means that when Ellis tries to
log into the server with valid
credentials she will unexpectedly
receive a login that tells tells her
that she is already locked in as the
attacker
which is unsettling at least I think
um we found that we can uh we can
exploit two email clients with session
fixations to obtain user credentials but
in nine additional cases we saw at least
fragments of session fixations with not
so clear impact for security or at least
where we did not could come up with a
working exploit
and the next class is tampering
the the aim of tampering attacks is
always to try to make persistent changes
to the mailbox of our victim for example
by already telling before starters
before the starter started as command
was already sent that there is a new
email in the inbox or for example by
telling that a new folder was created
and in fact if you do this in
Thunderbird for example you will see
that now there is an Attica controlled
folder in your email client which will
not go away
um in total five of the of the 28 tested
email applications
um do accept
um IMAP responses even before start DLS
um was conducted also with varying
consequences but we know of at least one
client where we could for example delete
the whole mailbox
by doing things like that
which brings us to your ice spoofing
which is similar to tampering but in UI
spoofing we are not interested on the
permanent part but instead we want to
show dialogues to our user for example
for Effective social engineering attacks
and here I may perhaps as a bit because
in IMAP there is a dedicated dedicated
response um that should be showed to the
user it is called the alert response and
when you do this when you execute this
trace for example in Outlook you will
receive something like that which looks
um pretty much like a benign email but
with the addition additional information
that this message was sent with higher
importance and a large um or or a data
controlled field that you can for
example use for social engineering
attacks
and in total
um considering the alert Response Code
and also different error mechanisms
mechanisms we were able to present a
user Attica controlled dialogues in 11
of the 28 tested clients
and now let's come to the buffering
class which is in I think in our opinion
the most interesting class of a text of
in Star TLS
and here we have to get into a little
bit more detail about protocol handling
itself or in other words where is the
buffer where is the data buffered to
where is it passed and so on
so let's consider now that we are a
server and as a server our first task is
to send a positive greeting which means
basically that we are able to or that we
are willing to accept new commands from
a client and then the client will send
us something
this something is first read into an
internal buffer and then the next step
is that this buffer is parsed enter
enter server detects that it's indeed
the start LS command and removes it from
the buffer
then it responds with the OK command
now both both parties are in a state
where TLS should be made and the TLs
handshake is executed
then LS sends again something that is
buffat parsed the server detects that
it's indeed the login command maybe even
with valid credentials and it responds
with a positive response meaning that
Alice is now authenticated
but let's consider buffering in our the
command injection case
again let's assume that we first sent a
greeting and then a client sends the
start TLS command but now instead of
just hold a whole um just um stopping at
this point the client will also
additionally in the same TCP segment add
additional data for example this one
here
so in fact this data is again buffered
first and then the server tries to pass
what it received so it will detect the
start LS command remove it from the
buffer
and respond with an OK command which
means the start LS is now uh is this
data list should be executed then both
parties execute the TLs handshake
and Alice can send her new command
but what should be now I think pretty
evident is that this data is appended to
the internal buffer which means that
when the server parses this buffer it
will not detect the recent command but
in fact the command that was sent even
before TLS was made meaning that it will
get an invalid command
and now the effect is that even though
Alice has the right credentials she will
she will receive a command telling her
that she sent for some reason an invalid
command
so I think um how you should think about
this about this problem is that the
command we send up at the bottom the
invalid command is interpreted as if
would have been sent in Via an encrypted
encrypted Channel
and basically both parties do not align
on the meaning of the session which
leads to pretty interesting ETA classes
and besides that at credential stealing
is almost always possible in the
protocols I think the most adventurous
attack we have can we could come up with
is by hosting a valid https content
through an IMAP server
so let's consider that case again we
assume that there is that there is a
user Alice
um and she will do implicit TLS no
started as involved at all to
communicate with an https server now
and we also assume that inside of this
structure there is also an IMAP server
that shares the same TLS certificate
with the IMAP server or with the https
server
and now we also have our attacker which
first gets a hold of the connection
and then instead of um directly proxying
Alice connection to the IMAP server the
attacker will first Prime the IMAP
server towards a certain state by using
the command injection it will receive
the greeting then send to start TLS
command and then send a very
specifically crafted set of valid IMAP
commands that somehow resemble artifacts
of http
so the server will respond with a with
an OK and expect the TLs handshake and
now at this place the attacker can just
proxy Alice's connection to the IMAP
server
and now what what happens in so this is
an instant of cross protocol attacks and
what happens normally in Cross protocol
protocol attacks is that you get somehow
a result but the impact is often not so
clear so in this case what would happen
is that Alice sends an HTTP get command
to an IMAP server which is obviously
something you should not do and leads to
likely some error cases
but because we have primed the server
towards a certain State we can control
the output of the server meaning that
the output it will generate reassemble
something that looks very very close to
valid http
and although I know that some of you
might note that there are some syntax
elements missing at least recent
browsers such as Firefox and chrome will
accept this response and show a valid
https website without any certificate
problems at all
in total we found that we found eight
new instances of command injections in
our test but what's even more
interesting about this case is that it
was already described more than 10 years
before by Vice vinema the author of
postfix in 2011.
and when we take all these issues into
account so the historic issues we know
that servers were vulnerable to the
command injection we see that in total
16 of 23 email email servers were
vulnerable to command injections and I
think this should point you to the fact
that it that these are not merely
implementation issues but really an
issue with the specification itself
we can generalize this attack also to a
response injection which mimics the same
kind of buffering injections as on the
server side to the client side and also
what we see here is that 16 of the 28
applications are vulnerable to command
injections
okay so let's continue with internet
scanning
right yes this works again
all right Damian gave you an overview of
all the issues in mail servers and mail
clients however we found it especially
interesting that we still found servers
vulnerable to the command injection 10
years after it was first published
therefore we took to internet scanning
to learn how widespread these issues are
still in practice
of course scanning always comes a lot of
things you should consider of course we
Applied Standard best practices we used
a block list to prevent scanning people
who do not want to be scanned we handed
a lot of abuse males asking for us to
put people on the block list we
identified ourselves during our scans
for example using the ELO command or
using comments where possible so people
could actually contact us contact us and
know who we are and finally we published
a website setting what we are doing on
the scanner IP address so people could
look at people could look it up and
again get the abuse contact
however we realized that this just does
not cut it for email scanning
so due to spam problems male transfer
agents especially will not talk to
everyone
there are many specific block lists that
are hard to get off
therefore we need an untainted IP for
scanning so it's another so our normal
IP address we use for scanning was
basically on all those learning on all
the email block lists that you could
imagine and there really was nobody that
was
who wanted to get us off that so we
decided to take a new IP address first
then we realized NDS still won't talk to
us because well they expect you to be an
MTA as well so you have to run an SMTP
server on your scanning IP address
then you need to publish appropriate DNS
records like an MX record and a pointer
record an SPF and decom Records help if
you are new to email sending which
scanner server usually is because we
will not be sending any emails over the
server
so people would want you to have these
records as well and finally we were made
a way of an email specific allow list
that might have helped in getting the
mail server over the threshold of being
accepted by other servers as well but
that is pretty hard to measure really
all right our main question while
scanning was how many servers are still
vulnerable to the command injection that
was first published in 2011.
surprisingly out of the 60 million
servers we could scan two percent were
still vulnerable to this pack
interestingly this percentage is higher
for IMAP and POP3
from our disclosure we know that most
server developers were aware of this
back in SMTP but not really in IMAP and
POP3 possibly because the original bug
came to be known as the star TLS SMTP
bug but not for the other protocols
so we've talked about a lot about issues
now let's talk about fixing them
the most straightforward thing to do as
a mail user is to switch to implicit TLS
so that's a pretty easy fix for the
issues in male clients
server providers on the other hand
should also evaluate if they can cut
study less support in the future for
example by migrating existing users that
still use star TLS to TLS in some way
however recognize if you have a large
user base this might not be a workable
solution for everyone therefore if you
really really really really really must
use star trailers you should isolate the
plain text phase completely from the TLs
phase by cleaning any remaining state
after it this includes playing any
application buffers hopefully you're
also fixing the buffering issues in the
process
and finally as the both as both a
implementation and the standardization
measure we recommend streamlining the
star TLS negotiation only sending and
accepting the bare minimum of messages
before transitioning to actual TLS
so no complex negotiation or actual
other extensions just a start TLS
command and then check
finally I want to tell you about
interesting things we learned from our
disclosure include this part in our talk
because reviewers and readers kept
asking about this and we think there's
something to be learned here
just to remind you there were a lot of
issues uncovered in clients servers and
on the internet
of course this means a lot of disclosure
and disclosure is never easy so this
issue Damian posted on GitHub on a
GitHub repository of an open source mail
library is pretty representative for
disclosure I'd like to report a security
vulnerability but I don't know how
let's start with some lessons we learned
during our disclosure first to answer
one of the questions we asked ourselves
in the beginning
clients are not meant to be
opportunistic most of the developers we
talk to recognize the issues as
vulnerabilities and fix them so starting
less at least the male clients is not
opportunistic
I said before server developers knew the
command injection smdp but not in IMAP
and POP3 which kind of surprised us and
the last lesson ties back to ties back
to the issue Damian posted contacting
the contacting developers in admins is
still hard nowadays if you could just
just all agree to use the security txt
or have some way of letting researchers
know where to contact people that would
be really great
all right this ties back to the last
point and let's talk about disclosure of
scan results communicating scan results
can be especially hard because it's hard
to get a hold of the affected admins you
usually just have a have an IP address
and no real mail address to contact and
even if you can contact the admins what
do you tell them
you cannot always tell which cell they
are actually using we tried identifying
servers but that doesn't work that well
and patches are not always available so
what do you tell them and this is where
the German BSI third came into play they
handled all the communications with the
server admins in Germany and helped us
contact National search so that they
could contact survey admins in their
countries so special thank you there
while scanning and reporting to the
bigger made service providers we had
some interesting experiences one of them
paid a bounty but never fixed the issue
one silently fixed all issues and
stopped answering to our emails
one argued that star TLS is really meant
to be opportunistic and there was
nothing to be done even though we
presented a real vulnerability to them
that could be kind of bad
and some never responded or had really
no way to contact them that would have
that would get us past the normal
customer support so that ties back to
adding a security txt please
all right of course we're scanning
people contact you as well which is a
nice change of pace from the normal
disclosure asking what you are doing
asking you to stop and so on and so on
turns out that people seem to be
monitoring their mail servers especially
well
most of these emails are automated of
course and this is just an excerpt of
the emails we got but we had some
interesting conversations to say the
least with real people
however this is not where the fun email
stopped we reported an issue to an open
source mail client that commonly appears
on top 10 lists of most used email
clients
yeah turns out their bug tracker is
overrun by Bots trying to sell us
watches like lots of bots selling lots
of watches and we never got a hold of
the actual developers and we think this
client might be unmaintained
we also had an interesting experience
experience while disclosing all to an
open source client we found an older
issue requesting TLS to be enabled by
default which seemed quite sensible to
us however the dev responded that they
tried this in a previous release but it
resulted in an issue about the
configuration being broken by a user
therefore this change was inverted in a
later version
we decided to take a closer look at this
broken configuration issue and we
realized that this was a male user that
was in fact a checked with star tiller
stripping
so in this case we started as command
never reaches the server because it is
exed out somewhere in between the
statutes command and it reaching the
server so of course this would cause
breakage when the client enforces TLS
but let's end these details on a more
positive note of course we had lots of
positive experiences so this is
non-exhaustive for example most open
source developers were pleasure to deal
with also one of the big msps Einstein's
male media game behind known for Game X
and webpage in Germany we stood out
answering fast and detailing what
they're doing throughout the whole
process so that was a nice change of
pace as well in contrast to the other
msps I've told you before
but the open source projects are really
where it's at it took the mud developer
all of 55 minutes to release a patch
boss to test
took a day and explained to us why the
issue happened in their code in the
first place and requested the cve
themselves
and the Santa Barbara developers were
especially helpful doing a lot of
research themselves and giving us now
new ideas to improve upon our own
research and improve the paper
so let's tie this all up
in conclusion we found that compared to
implicit T less star TLS adds the tech
surface to image perfect email protocols
without adding anything of value really
furthermore we found that started as
implementation in both servers and
clients have widespread issues handing
at systemic problems with star tailors
as we have shown the effect of this
vulnerability is not limited to Star TLs
but also allows for cross protocol
attacks for example against https and
implicit TLS versions of these protocols
we conclude that TLS is better without
status and start less should be avoided
where possible
and for all of you we recommend looking
into your own email client to check if
you're still using statist for some old
mail account and if you find to do
consider changing that and talk to us
about it at the social event tonight
and now we're happy to take your
questions
[Applause]
[Music]