I think this is the inside Jason first I
want to thank for letting me actually
come into line as I was late because we
all we just finished our statement this
is the culture statement from the cross
community working group on enhancing
icons accountability for a double in
meeting guy cam 24 and members and
participants of the cross community
working group on enhancing eigen
accountability met in Dublin Ireland
from the sixteen to twenty second of the
October 2015 at I am 54 over the past
seven days the CC WG accountability has
held more than 25 hours of formal
meetings with additional discussions
taking place in various SOA see led
sessions in the hallways and oftentimes
over meals and drinks after some voiced
concerns with the speed of progress
leading into Dublin we the cultures call
on the community for full mobilization
and reinvigorated dedication to making
measurable progress over the weekend
Dublin we are extremely pleased to
announce that the community tackle this
challenge head-on and succeeded in what
the group has coined an environment of
collaboration cwg accountability members
participants ICANN board directors
external advisors legal counsel and
interested observers came together to
identify outstanding issues in the
second draft report and move towards
consensus on solutions a summary of key
decisions and agreed upon next steps are
outlined below on the salt designator as
reference model for enforcement the
group reached broad agreement to move
forward with the sole designator as the
new reference enforcement model for the
next draft proposal the group will next
attempt to finalise patching the model
to alleviate any outstanding concerns on
their next draft proposal decision
making model the group begun defining a
consensus based decision making model
which includes a community consultation
period discussions on the topic were
informed by concerns raised in the
public comment on the second draft
report about unintended concentration of
power on the independent
you process the group confirmed support
for the proposed IRP enhancements and is
now moving into the implementation phase
to spearhead this face a drafting
subgroup with expert support will be
constructed to develop and draft by
lowes and detail operating procedures on
the committee power that refers to
review and reject of the budget and
operating plan the group has identified
a balanced process and approach for the
one year operating plan and budget which
was an outstanding item coming into
Dublin on the creative power of
recalling individual board directors the
brig confirmed a decision method for
removal of a director appointed by the
nominating committee and a separate
decision method for removal of a
director appointed by an advisory
committee or supporting organization in
the mission in corvallis the group
confirmed its support for a
clarification of the mission statement
and articulation of the commitments and
core values an example of operation of a
clarification includes icons ability to
enforce agreements with contracted
parties subject to reasonable checks and
balances on Human Rights the group
reached consensus to include a general
human rights commitment into the bios
however further work is needed on
language and has been tasked to the
human rights working party on the
incorporation of affirmation of
commitments into the bios the group
finalized outstanding details of the
incorporation of the AOC review into the
bios there is high confidence that these
values are nearly ready for
consideration in terms of implementation
as we got to welcome to the group had
opted a focus list of works room two
items with an emphasis on transparency
requirements there was also broad
agreement to bring some of these
transparency requirements into work
swimming one in consideration of the
discussions around the sole designator
enforcement model you got the timeline
the next steps the cwg accountability
has had intensive discussion discussions
on the group's work plan anticipated
progress and next steps towards
finalization as such the group has
adjusted its timeline in a manner that
attempts to balance the various timeline
constraints
both inside and outside of the community
while details are still being solidified
the timeline is rigorous and will likely
keep the cwg accountability bc through
the winter season however the cultures
members and participants of the cwg
accountability understand the importance
of and will execute an inclusive open
and bottom-up process the current
timeline proposes posting a high-level
overview of recommendations and a
summary of changes from the second draft
proposal for a 35-day public comment
period on 15 November 2015 alongside the
35 day public comment the cwg
accountability will submit these
resources to the charger and
organizations for initial feedback the
CCW g accountability plans to issue a
full detailed report including an access
and in-depth documentation midway into
the public comment period for roughly 20
days of consultation after today this of
the comments received and assuming no
major changes the group currently
projects submission of works from one
recommendations to the ICANN board in
late January 2016 we sincerely thank the
community for the dedication to our
unprecedented go we'd like to give
special recognition to the GAC a lack
ASO and SS ack for their comments and on
our proposal while in Dublin in addition
we are grateful to the volunteers
support staff advisers and independent
counsel who put in a tremendous effort
this past week they deserve and have
earned the community's greatest respect
and the deepest recognition the cwg
accountability cultures thomas richard
leong sanchez and matthew bait