hi I'm Luna Maddie head of
communications for europe middle east
and africa we've just wrapped up i can
54 here in Dublin and had the chance to
sit with both Steve Crocker and fetish
hider let's have a look so thank you
very much both for being here this
morning Steve let's start with you last
night we see two three new members on
the board can you tell us a little bit
about them this is the time of year
which we do have members departing and
members arriving and so it's always
interesting and with a certain amount of
anticipation who's going to come and how
they're going to fit in we have three
spectacular new board members each very
different from the other we have Lido
avarra from Salvador who has one of the
irreplaceable credentials of having
received at the top level domain from El
Salvador directly from jon postel so
there's a piece of history there that he
brings a very nice guy deeply
knowledgeable and we have Ron de Silva
who's a part of one of the major ISPs in
the u.s. deep technical background and a
lot of managerial experience and Louise
van der laan with enormous political
skills enormous energy and just making a
strong impression on everybody the
people that have left have also made
their marks and sour bitter sweet sense
of loss there but the new people are
incredible good so with this new board
what are your hopes for them well the
hopes for the board really are very much
entwined with hopes for I can and for
the Internet community as a whole all of
us have been involved rather intensively
with the transition process and most
particularly with the development of the
accountability mechanisms that are
coming out of the sea cwg and the board
is as a meshed and involved in that
as every other part of the community
from my perspective I have two hopes one
is of course that that process goes
through and continues and it's looking
pretty good actually and that we have a
lot to do to execute and put those piece
together and then we have the regular
business of what I can is all about and
the board is focused on how to
continually improve I can how to get our
regular order of business taken care of
and to move things to the next level
Thank You fati so this week has been
busy but how do you characterize the
progress that has been made on the iono
stewardship transition during I can 54
in Dublin I think this week exceeded all
expectations we have come together we
have built consensus we have removed
many of the misunderstandings and the
community has come together we cannot
ask for more Dublin has been good to us
and I think as we leave Dublin from this
week we still have work to do to
complete this transition but I think a
clear path is drawn now and everyone is
in sync as to what we still need to do
to get it done and that in itself is a
great triumph for Dublin so yes the
community has worked tirelessly on this
and what would you advise the community
moving forward to keep this momentum
going I think the spirit of Dublin needs
to continue the spirit of working
together of understanding each other of
listening to each other endless hours
were spent here in Dublin either in
meeting rooms or in the hallways or
sometimes in the pubs that enabled
people to listen and to understand each
other I think we have narrowed the
remaining questions to very few that I
believe are very much addressable with
the continued commitment to the core
values that brought us together from the
very beginning and they were evident
this week frankly remarkably so what
binds us together the principles that
bind us together got us great success
this week still have worked too
and we cannot lose this great momentum
but i think the weeks ahead will be
important and we are all committed to
get the job done in fact many teams
already starting meetings today in the
hours ahead of me excellent and Steve
today is the second anniversary for the
new generic top-level domains program
and which happens also to have been the
first with the four domains being
internationalized domain names how do
you think the program has progressed so
far and where are we with that the
internationalized domain names are a
very big deal and it's I'm glad that
you've mentioned that and that's a key
to opening up the Internet beyond its
western and American roots to embrace
the entire globe so I think we're all
proud of that and we're all very very
pleased to see that that aspect has been
successful on the generic names of
generika new TT entities in general that
has been progressing it is almost
exactly a case of let a thousand flowers
bloom and with the implication that
there will be some that will do well and
some less well the full results are not
in but I am seeing considerable pressure
for let's get more and let's open up the
next round as rapidly as possible I'm
personally of the mindset that we want
to be careful like to take the lessons
that we are there to be learned from
that from the current experience but I
understand and fully appreciate that we
should move forward with all due speed
and on the ID ins by the way here in a
Dublin one of the many things we got
done is we signed with the Catholic
Church the dot Catholic top-level domain
in Chinese in Arabic in Cyrillic and of
course in Latin characters that was a
great
frankly use of the internationalized
domain name system for an institution
that's in many ways universal so we're
delighted that this happened here in
Dublin and Steve in 2016 well 2016
brings a new meeting strategy into
effect how will that impact the meetings
moving forwards and the community as
well quite a lot of work went into
making the decision to adjust the way we
have the meetings so in in some sense
the broad scope of having three meetings
a year remains in place but we've
adjusted what to do during those
meetings and the biggest change I'll
have an a meaning early in the year a be
meeting in the middle of the year which
is somewhat shorter and more focused
with less of the formalities and more
working sessions and then AC meeting at
the end of the year that is got all of
this stuff that we usually do plus some
outreach and attempt to communicate with
the with the rest of the world that does
not normally pay attention to I can so
much as with any new program a lot of
thought goes into it and a lot of
organization and there's also a certain
amount of hope and waiting to see how it
works out so next year will be the test
and expect that we'll we'll find out
expecto so it'll work well and expect
we'll find some things that will want to
learn out of that it will cause some
adjustments down at the second and third
levels of things I just came out of a
meeting in which saying okay how do we
fit one of our programs into this and
where does it fit smoothly in but change
like this always brings a certain sense
of renewed energy and thoughtfulness
about how we operate and some very much
looking forward to that and finding that
brings us to maracas which will be the
first time this is an effect next year
in in March how do you feel about the
meeting and how important is it to take
place in Africa I am really looking
forward to Marrakech for three reasons
one Marrakech will be a meeting in
Africa that will celebrate this great
continent a continent that is dear to me
but also dear to many of us at ICANN who
believe that I cans place in Africa is
important and bringing together this
fast growing community into the fold in
every way we can is important Marrakech
will be a chance to do that to deepen
our roots in Africa and to connect with
the African people at all levels we plan
to bring high-level ministers we plan to
bring businesses business
representatives from Africa we have
plans to also bring students from
various universities in Africa to the
meeting so that this becomes a meeting
not just in Africa but about Africa the
second reason Marrakech will be great is
because Marrakech maybe when we could
celebrate the multi-stakeholder models
delivery of a proposal to the US
government and that in itself is a huge
celebration it's a triumph of our model
a model that says that a public-private
partnerships between governments and
businesses and users and civil society
work and they produce results and so all
the work we've done to prepare for this
transition will culminate in delivering
a multi-stakeholder bottom-up consensus
proposal to the US government to
complete our independence and I hope
that by Marrakech we can all be
celebrating very much the delivery of
that proposal and of course finally
maracas will be my last meeting as
president and CEO of I can and for me it
will be a chance to make sure that my
successor can be handed and I can that
he or she can continue growing in the
same spirit and a spirit that is rooted
in our principles of openness of
inclusivity in our spirit of
Independence that will hopefully be then
closer
certainly the integrity of the system
end of the internet layer that we are
responsible for so I'm looking forward
to introduce him or her to our community
and to work with him to transfer all of
the good will and capital we've built so
that he or she can continue in this
great endeavor a lot of work so just to
wrap up any final words either one of
you would like to say where we're
sitting here in the conventions that are
overlooking the river on a very calm and
peaceful morning with the Sun coming up
and it is it resonates with exactly the
spirit coming out of this meeting that
I'm just here informally ready to go to
work on the substance never mind all of
the posturing and and it's a just a
delightful day and a perfect setting and
it couldn't be better indeed I would
second Steve's comment about the
difference in the tone of how we enter
Dublin and how we're exiting Dublin we
entered with a lot of questions and
tribulations and concerns but we are
exiting Dublin calm confident and clear
on the path forward to complete the
transition from the USD stewardship
leading I can to a very good place a
place where the global community feels
that we have a partnership to maintain
our work so I'm delighted this has been
a very good meeting and thank you Steve
thank you and thank you very much for
this interview today I think we've
covered a lot of points and good luck
and safe travels thank you thank you
you