hi I'm last Hoffman I'm he had I can 54
we are wrapping up and meeting Stefania
Milan from the non-commercial
stakeholder group like I'm Stefania
Tyler's and Stephanie you've just been
elected to genus or Council and can you
tell us a little bit about what the
entity G does and who represents yeah so
I'm a representative of the NCS G which
is the non-commercial stakeholder group
on the genus or council the
non-commercial stakeholder group is
composed by two constituencies one is
the NC you see the non-commercial user
constituency and the other is the n park
the non-profit organization concern
constituency they might seem similar I
to some extent we do share a lot of
concerns but we represent slightly
different social groups if you want in
that NC you see is open to both
organizations like for example NGOs and
the individuals whereas the end park
represents only organizations more
specifically the end park represents the
interest of organization that might want
of have registered domain name whereas
MC you see that I that's let's say my
first family in the end CSG as a
slightly broader agenda and that we care
also about a number of other issues I
can tell you what the issues are broadly
speaking will look for example privacy
without the implication of names and
numbers for individuals and groups
privacy then we look we care about
development human rights but also the
diversity and consumer choice ok very
good thank you and you talk about
individuals who are engaged with the NC
UCM the nchs as well how do they how can
they get in best involved with icon in
the genus oh oh it's actually quite easy
as we all know I can is pretty open
everything is recorded and it can also
be followed remotely so the best way to
get involved is to you know jump in a
working group for example there's plenty
this always shortage of individual
especially and from the non commercial
site because we usually have also other
daily jobs and so we're always happy to
welcome other volunteers to help us to
fight for the issues that i just
described it's not easy at the beginning
let's say because indeed the issues are
relatively complex especially for a
newcomer there's plenty of help both
from the icon stuff and from other
individual organizational members to get
you by if you just want to dive into
icon is that how you joined to did you
did you just jump in or did you have a
slightly different path to get involved
I actually was was jumped in in that
well I used to work for a government at
some point and I came to I can actually
through guck although I only lasted for
a meeting but in this meeting I met some
and see you see members and that sort of
prompt me through getting boat and as
the first move they proposed to nominate
me for one of the position in the
executive committee on an cuc which is
some actually something that i recommend
because it gives you a role and give you
some tasks which are allowed over mostly
administrative and the possibility of
being forced to learn let's say so doing
your forthcoming term here on the
council what do you think are the hot
topics going to be for the NCS G and you
personally as well well i'm interested
in privacy and now to protect users
privacy and therefore i'm going to
follow closely the work of the peat on
the policy development process on the
next generation registration directory
service which is the updated boo hiss ok
there's very interesting thank you so
much too funny for your time and i'll
see you Marrakech and good luck thank
you