hi I'm Las Hoffman he had I can 54 with
Valerie tan who has just been elected to
gina's her cancer Valerie how did you
actually get involved with I can so
thank you lass for having me here to
talk a bit about my appointment to the
gns or counsel from nominating committee
so my first acquaintance with ICANN was
as a law student and then during that
time the I can you dr peon who is very
quickly became a fascination for most of
us and at a time i can to a lot of us
was this great institution that churned
out rules you know that allowed the
internet to work perfectly when I join a
private sector later on I had the
opportunity to work with I can on
various aspects and being in the
telecoms and Internet technology sectors
that quickly became a you know great
piece of you know the work that I did
and when I can expend it and globalized
around the world setting up its
Singapore hop I then had more of an
opportunity to become engaged as a
business stakeholder and one fine day
somebody suggested that you know I
should apply for a non composition and I
wasn't quite sure what it meant but I
was guaranteed that you know it would
not be boring and so I did and so I'm
here and I'm very glad to be here it's
really an eye-opener for me these couple
of days some you know being in various
workshops of the genus or council and
you know I do realize I really have a
lot of what to do to you know get up to
speed with the various working groups
with the various transition projects and
there's so much important work ahead
well we're very glad to have you here
thank you and you mentioned briefly that
you are from Singapore do you think
you're obviously bring a certain aspect
diversity to the two I can end the tuna
so do you think that it's important and
if so
mine yes I think one of the challenges I
guess facing the organization going
forward is really diversity or you know
divergent or diverse views I mean given
various projects that ongoing like the
you know new GTL gTLD rounds and a iana
stewardship transition I guess we're
looking at space in the internet that is
going to be a lot larger where they're
going to be more stakeholders more
communities that have not yet in you
know present now taking part in the
multi-stakeholder model process so I
think it's important because especially
coming from Asia and the region where
we're seeing almost I've just received
some new statistics that more than about
fifty percent of you know users on the
internet now come from the asia-pacific
region so from a policy and building
perspective I think that part of the
work is has has a lot of scope for
representation in the in the future
years ahead this is the first time I
read that you are on the genus or
Council as a noncom appointee and what
do you expect for you to your term what
do you think is in license tool for you
so one thing that I have come to take
away from the couple of days having been
you know involved really ingenious or
council discussions is that I'm assured
of myself that it will not be a boring
appointment I mean there's just so much
intellectual stimulation I mean it's
just the topics and the fact that there
can be varying perspectives and also the
possibility i think you know for
discussions where at some point in time
you know people agree to disagree and
then come to a consensus and i think
that's really important because the the
work of the gns or council is
to manage the policy development process
and the community looks to counsel for
that leadership role okay all right
thank you very much for your time and
I'm looking forward to seeing you over
the next two years with the genus Owen
here I can thank you laugh
you