I'm gonna get started thanks for your
time and hopefully everybody a good
lunch hopefully out too many cars going
to given him a lot of sleep into the
cargo hi so how do you guys enjoyed the
morning so far and of course open
everybody learned something excellent
well thanks again to Josh a man and
would also drop a clock for anybody was
not already attending last time the next
two dates to this this event is
sponsored by the last time which with
our conference there's discount code
rather than me saying it watch on the
whiteboard programmatic door so if you'd
like to get a discounted still come to
the conference the next two days here
are the same venue
having attention to me even more talks
like this with your cap and a variety of
different topics and fun events
including a mimosa event to the morning
and a lockpick village and lots of other
cool activities capture the flag bash
challenge else we have look at the pole
mechanical bull happy hour free drinks
it's kind of a hard combo beat so
without with that knowledge on semantics
over it now we have a great afternoon
thank you so much for joining us and we
hope you'll come back the last pot if
not tomorrow definitely next year and
join us for yo ass Boston events
throughout the year thank you alright so
Kevin bull danken was talking about last
comment it kind of reminded me of Hawaii
games tonight out of that comp first
place you know we had another security
conference here in Austin and you know
both of us who kind of gone there we
spoke at the conference whatnot and got
a number of other conferences all over
the place and it was right after I had
attended my first piece on Las Vegas
black hat back in 2010 and for me what I
came to realize was that this is more
information security access gloss is
more than just a show up learn something
after dusting of your day job for me
this was really about establishing
community and so when I when I became
president the old Austin chapter one of
my key areas i focused on is how do i
strengthen relationships between these
two developers between the information
security people between otters and how
do i vs all together and start talking
the same language and start learning
from each other and so last con really
was founded on on that goal and it gets
a way to get the community all together
in one place we can talk a common
language we can learn from each other so
I really hope that if you don't have
plans on thursday and friday to do
joanna's good conference i can pretty
much promise you it's going to be the
most fun security conference you can
never attend that that was another one
of our goals we wanted to be something
that people went and like a good time
it's too bad over you know so tomorrow
for example before the happy hour we're
going to do our last con speed debates
and the speed debate is like you know
some of your favorite speakers up on
stage arguing for things that they have
no business are waiting for and against
it's amazing so we're trying to keep the
phone we try and keep it light-hearted
in trying to keep an educational as well
so I hope you all will definitely join
us for Alaska alright so with that we'll
go ahead and continue through our
journey continue with our journey
through the OWASP top ten the next one
up is more in strict object reference so
what is this Easter direct object
reference
developer exposes the reference to an
internal inhuman tation object like I
love the directory or deadly scheme and
then without a tour access control
channels to make sure that the user
accessing it is actually supposed to be
able to get at that or some other form
of protection the attackers can then
manipulate those references to access
things they're not supposed assets
unauthorized attagirl so the attackers
water this is not going to be as
significant as like the sequel objection
were two straight up old data database
but he's kind of lost and compromise the
data that's records by that brand new so
it's a little bit more scope but it's
still pretty serious unless the object
references are unpredictable that it's
easy for attacker taxes all the
available data of that time and this is
really where things like the ORM tools
kind of come handy because they're
basically creating a situation where
those those preferences are highly
unpredictable or they're strongly tied
to it it's fun for difficult for
attacker to to make complications like
that so in order to really determine the
impact here we have to consider the
business value to expose data as both
the business impact of the public
exposure is vulnerability and that will
be kind of a theme for most of these
because after all data is king and our
our impact is really good depend on the
type of data that gets exposed so here's
an example I like to think of this as
like a banking application everything
baking is just so cool right if all this
money and all this information from PII
account information that that's just
staying there is ripe for the picking
lesson sort of attack I like to think of
this as something like that where you've
got these statements right and the
statements are lined up nor from
mortgage well excuse rs.12 statements
under there
and so in the normal use of this
application we would have something like
I want to view statement in my safety is
number 40 right what happens now if as a
malicious person I say come on 17
instead of three but the users only
supposed to have access 1 for 12 so now
they're asking for 17 wolf 17 exists and
we don't have a check in place that says
this user can only access 1 for 12 now
that users game number 17 right and they
could access 418 number 0 whatever the
case may be um as long as we don't come
any sort of restrictions provisions
remaining the masses in that that's
where we have this problem so testing
applications for this can be difficult
to automate again and again this has to
do with the context that are scaling
tools running they don't know what data
the user should have access to and
because they don't know what the users
have access to and they can go through
they can say i equals 4 on to entry for
all we have 200 whatever the case may be
but unless there's some way saying yes
that's something they should have access
to know that something they should this
is just a logic issue alright so that's
why this is really really hard for us
automated but it's very important for us
to test and the way that we do this is
we inspect the parameters that we passed
the application we then manipulate those
parameters to see if we can get it to
display something other than what we
expect a display and then we look at the
pages whose only purpose is to display
information dosing lot so doc Mimms
account statements no I guess give you
guys a little bit of a story that I like
to use
training class what I'm talking with
developers start from way back when
there was a website and this company
their job was to put information on this
website having to do with Peleus
earnings announcements from the company
and new stocks that I or things like
that and what would happen is the
company before the official time that
the press release was supposed to go out
they basically q these documents up and
so you know they go and write their
little heart of emphasis and then they
publish that publish atmosphere sake
well when they send publish what the
system would do is it would basically
create a preference for that IV it maybe
it's a date that is referencing
something like that but once I
references in the system then you could
actually go even if they did publish li
an actual link to that somebody thank
you where to go could basically get like
that page and see all the news
information for that day and what I am
happening is there were some of who
called entrepreneurs who decided that
figure this the scheme out right and
they figure out that on any day they
could basically plug in that date and I
can see the news even if it's not
published in the day was there and so
will they figure this out they actually
start to do stop training based on that
information and so they were able to say
hey this entry's announcement is down
the shore that stopped for this company
is earning is an announcement give way
way over what they had projecting let's
buy a lot of this right because the
process can go up and I believe that
those guys actually got charged with
problem as a result of this because they
were trading with the insider knowledge
so bless you here we want to protect
that information
something that somebody should have
access to we need to make sure that
we're treating me as sensitive and that
we're up for restricting permissions to
access to that so let's say well
automate some sort of exploitation here
in let's say it's like that statement
thing where the vulnerable parameter is
incrementing enter 1234 release right I
just say hey here's your ice starts at
zero and I won't move for forever and I
want you to get this page this is the
parameter that I want to put in so in
this case the answer value and then I
want you to test page and see what value
you get back and then receive and so
will stand up happening is this test
page is going to run over and over and
over you should the different values
that come in in this case is kill Duke
to infinity and then three more days
can't capture whatever that is it is
Erica we want to see if that's a
200-page meaning that the pages there it
was a success or 400 air being the valve
maybe I want to capture the size because
the sizes of the size of the paper turn
is addictive of the amount of data
that's coming back to me my name is I
can use this to kind of go through in
one off go for all values a kind of
funny story around this matt to star was
doing walker other three classes here
he's down an employee of the ool
foundation and back in Los a was Tony me
11 I was in Washington DC with him for
the O's conference and that was staying
at the hotel and the hotel basically
used to things south and in case their
wives well their wireless is a game
feature so you had to basically paid in
order to give
the hotel it require two things require
your room number and your last night and
Matt knew that there were a number of
other boss board members that were
staying at this hotel so we knew their
last names it's a good place to start
and the hotel only had so many girls
right so we can basically go and we can
say our let's try the wireless with last
name Cruz dinners cruises one of the
four different of the time or chat
Williams or whatever and then let's loop
I presume zero cruising more in prison
to be all the way up to over the biggest
room numbers well it didn't take long
and overweight field 964 member seven
board members so it didn't take a long
time for Matt to look through those and
find a combination with this blasting
plus this room number equals now I have
a year in taxes so these are the kind of
things that we want to protect me most
people that some agents for this the
person is doing suppose control keys or
identifiers so if we have things that
are kind of intervals the application
you know some account ideas or things
like that we should try not to expose
those to be used so we need to create
random identifies and things like that
and by using the random identifiers that
means that an attacker you know they're
they're not gonna be able to guess what
the value should be you're only going to
be able get this value this value or
this value because
prideth present the other thing that we
can do here is we can use object
references they're challenging to get so
like a GU ID for example is a randomizer
entire it's something that you couldn't
guess what that value is and we can use
that to track whatever it is over
contract and then the last I'll interior
is performing server-side authorization
chefs project access this is really
probably the most important thing which
is yeah we can try and do this kind of
security through obscurity thing by
randomizing the values of their getting
use to access it and you hope that
nobody guess is a tour don't waste able
to enforce those values but really the
way handle this is to say your long game
with this account you have access to you
say is only these things and if you
request anything other than that we're
going to night that's really the way
that we want games so to recap Instagram
object references occurred when
application exposes internal references
to objects view parameters that are past
the application in the guard against if
we notice those intro music identifiers
who the use object references that
challenging guest rating values and we
performed servers on authorization
checks during taxes questions about that
now alright so there's some references
and I'll turn it over to mr. Cornell
preserve
alright
so to talk a little bit about security
miss configuration and this is something
that we've touched on a lot of things
we've touched on this in a couple of
areas we talked about these privileged
to talk but that's in depth and those
are topics that have come up along the
way and other vulnerabilities we'll be
covering some familiar ground and a
little bit more specific structure way
and this is also something that I think
we are seeing become more important as
organizations move toward DevOps how
many people here doing DevOps how people
are doing get off right now right so if
anybody'd appoint go to brush your head
up that's it allows this is all get out
but it's long been a problem that we've
seen in organizations where they deploy
applications into environments that have
for security configurations and in just
for security practices in general and
what we've seen in a lot of
organizations that are moving toward a
lost is that's a great chance to get
something right there may be getting
wrong before but it's also a great
opportunity to get stuff really really
wrong I was talking with our director
technology and he was lamenting that
with the wide adoption of object
relational mapping systems every
developer not next ferry deviate right
and thinks the traditional dda's we do
like make sure your cables are properly
normalized and next things and whatnot a
lot of those get ignored until you have
got formal problems until they could do
late that's also we're seeing now that
the infrastructure that applications
gets deployed on is now controlled by
developers or developers now a junior
sis has been with their doctors and
their software-defined networking
like that so especially in organizations
where you're looking to make transitions
to a Doppler that lost type of all types
of approaches that's a great opportunity
to get some of these good practices in
place so what we do is our about
security miss configuration so the
security is not just that the security
the system is not just controlled by the
application good security means that you
have your application well written from
a security standpoint but it also means
they have your frame horse configured in
a secure manner that you have your
application server your web server
database server configured in a secure
manner as an attacker I don't have I
don't have a need to take over the world
via sequel injection or I have a need
for your data if I get that data made a
sequel injection that's great if I get
that data by using metasploit off the
database server box and I just pulled a
bit over there that's totally fine too
and so it's important to understand that
these applications you're writing get
deployed on to an infrastructure that
potentially has or that lightly has
vulnerabilities and that at the end of
the day it's the least secure link or
orderly or any secure link in the chain
is going to be acceptable to attacker as
an attack vector for them to get into
and so when you look at deploying your
code you need to look at the security
settings and how those are implemented
when you first have the system and but
also how they're maintained as the
system matures and evolves over time now
and also we'll talk specifically over
phone a little bit more as well but you
know this is software it needs to be
kept up to date that's the the cool
thing about security is that it is
always changing right here you're
fighting a human adversary and you
adversaries are going to adapt get
better over time as a security
consultant that means I will always have
a job as a software developer it means
that unfortunately or is it person who's
appealing systems and also unfortunately
mean that there's always going to be
stuff to do alright they're never going
to undiscovered vulnerabilities in the
linux version you're running they're
going to discover more vulnerabilities
in the version of Linux that you're up
and so you need to keep things up to
date so the impact here again is because
modern these could be you can have
really really bad problems that lead to
serious I stayed up you could also have
an impact where it's more of information
leakage in things of that but this is
something that again need to pay
attention to because doing this wrong
can allow their completed two pretty
serious compromised and recovery costs
can be really expensive remember the
story I told my buddy in California
where they basically had to take their
infrastructure pull the data off slick
it and start over again because they had
compromised they couldn't figure out the
extent that compromises the only real
solution was burn it all down and start
over again so are you mull neural with
your sister to you vulnerable to
security this configuration and this
causes you or should put in a position
to ask a number of different questions
all right is that your soft Friday so
you've got operating systems that are
running all of these various servers
you've got your web and or application
server you've got your database plus you
have the applications that you've
written as well as all the code
libraries that are used to make that
application do the stuff that it is
supposed to do and so a question is how
are you planning to keep track of
whether or not these systems are out of
date mailing list you have patching and
other things of that nature what what
are you doing so that when inevitably
one more of these components and systems
you're go to buy that you can make a
determination of power if you're going
to ask them are there any unnecessary
features enable are installed ports
services pages and an application
accounts for an application privileges
for an application again this is
something where the big vendors have
gotten a lot better anybody remember
like the good old days with the windows
NT are you like installed Windows NT and
like internet printing turned on by
default because why not right don't need
a good various worms and things like
that but now that was their philosophy
you looking at ok we're trying to get
additional systems administrators fuel
stand up windows or what it'd be easy we
just we just want stuff to work versus
all is up from the UX bowls full just
turn everything on all the time with the
expectation or the statement or the care
but we statement if we should go ahead
and turn off the stuff that you don't
want I would contrast that with the
approach that people would be a fee
boats head which was we're going to turn
nothin on you have to explicitly enable
anything that you want to run this
system and so you know as we see over
time the big vendors have shifted from a
turn everything on it good luck two more
of a we want to be secure in our default
configuration and if people are going to
reduce the security system we want them
to make explicit explicit decisions to
do that not everybody is doing mr.
that's certainly the direction that we
have gone is this an industry I don't
think we're there yet but I think that's
great progress because the end you if
you really want to turn on in an
imprinting on your Windows Server that's
probably a decision that you should
adapt innate and you should probably
have to stand up in front of your peers
and tell them they are making that
decision so you can suffer the
appropriate division and potentially
change your behavior you keep all
accounts their passwords still unable to
not change
the denial of service attack just a last
week with the IOT devices with the
default passwords so that's a that's an
important question is how we do
provision the servers are you setting
accounts and things and that's something
that's a challenging problem if you are
employing me an image of docker images
and things like that there's a lot of
value of being able to lock down
configurations going in and have that be
done repeatedly flip side of that is how
you manage access to those so that you
don't have a kind of a monoculture where
everything has the exact name effort
we've talked a little bit about this you
know but from a configuration standpoint
as well as from a logic standpoint when
your application encounters errors how
do you make sure that you're not leaking
too much information out to the users of
the system if some of that is done via
configuration if there's an error don't
show the page of the stack trace and all
that other stuff but there are also
decisions that you make is developers
that also can impact this so what do you
report on a fill volume you say hey
that's a good user name password is
wrong or you say I can find a username
or do you say that username and password
combination is incorrect alright in
those first two cases you're leaking
information because of the way you're
communicating the failure you're leaking
information to an attacker that says
that's a valid account or it's not about
account or that's a valid account about
the right password versus in the second
case you're saying you gave us a bad and
username or password where I'm going to
tell you which try logging also look at
the security settings of your
development frameworks are those instead
to secure value he's one of the cool
things about the dotnet framework it man
two built-in cross-site scripting
protection where they would look through
in scan again this is a negative type of
input validation that they had a couple
of things that they would check for just
very lightly to look for potential
cross-site scripting attacks and they
show those requests
I evil I looked at it one of the systems
we were looking at had that turn off
Fred they are supposedly gone in and
turned this off and equipped with a
whitey to do that this is a nice little
bit of protection you get it certainly
those giving my sister a lot of
processor thing but this is at least
some production you get in place and
their answer was well you know like
sometimes we need to send ex-mla on
request that was breaking sweet is
instead of being very focused in the way
that we worked around that protection
where needed we just turn it off so we
don't have striven be more so looking at
the way you have configured these
frameworks in the detectors they have in
place is your application set up such
that they can take advantage of those
and but the problem about this is that
its work and its work than a lot of
cases spans you know people's knowledge
areas or spans rules because what you're
asking across the board with this
configuration is staying at the highest
level of the application level hey when
you communicate about errors are you
revealing too much right but that's the
stuff you can automate the answer to
that or have like a lockdown tool that
says that that's asking a question of
what are you communicating information
that may be valuable to a user talking
about the business state the system
you're in all the way looking at the
configuration of application servers the
configuration of operating systems of
configuration database servers all of
these things so this can be a
challenging thing for organizations to
get right because it crosses so many
live it's not like you can go to your
configuration like you're the secure
configuration expert and let's just go
spend an hour security configuration
expert in there so every sort all this
whole thing that's important to
understand is that these concerns
typically cut across roles within or
is a to get it right you going to do
this bolt or via so let's look at that
example snare here when you install an
application server is the administrative
console automatically installed right on
a developer's workstation that's
probably cool because a lot of our
developers do they have you can access a
lot of cases under workspaces they
install stuff you things and whatnot
similarly if they're installing local
version of the application server they
probably need that administrative access
to go turn things on earth dissolved
whatever yeah but when you go to install
two production systems that's not
appropriate that you've got your jboss
admin console exposed out for for
everybody to accident you know simply
your default account you know when you
put things into production or do you
have default credentials that are
exposed out there not change these a lot
of application servers these
administrative consoles have signatures
that are pretty easy to figure out right
you know there are well known urls that
you go and test to say oh yeah well this
is a JBoss server running this version
and this is the administrative console
start on and here's the default username
and password so that's something you
need to pay attention to is as you
deploy your systems the way that you
build these images and deploy these
servers when you are looking rough
systems are you only deploying the stuff
that you need and when you're deploying
this up do you have some sort of
procedure or control in place that
forces you change these your change
these default passwords okay second
scenario you know you've got your web
server you're deploying code out your
web server and you've got the web server
configured such that it allows for a
directory listing so if you if you go to
a grifter that has a
index HTML page back in destination
locations going to render if you go to a
directory where it doesn't have that
page the behavior of the web server is
to listen say here's although here's
only your pages yet that you can access
underneath this directory we see this in
a lot of situations as well and it's
something that is pretty easy for an
attacker to go and look forward to get a
10 minute backers an oddity and so from
a configuration standpoint when you
deploy new web servers how do you know
that you've got the right web server
configuration set up to not expose these
vulnerable behaviors another great
example is your stack traces if you're a
developer write code it's pretty
important valuable to be able to see
verbose information about yours if
you're writing code you got a problem
the system it's great to see like oh the
eye of the problem is I didn't check for
null and that was the code that I was
just working right really handy if you
were looking at a production systems is
absolutely the type of stuff you do not
want to expose you know because if you
can see a stack trace again you know
language frameworks well not you know
versions you know in case in a lot of
cases you'll get error messages that may
have stupids of sequel queries and
things of that nature and so when you
deploy production servers you want to
make sure that those are configured in
such a way that if you have an error you
display a generic error page not woman
has a lot of information about the
internal state of the system and the
internal construction of the application
go again there's no reason to give
attackers help they've already go
there's probably plenty of
vulnerabilities out there you don't need
to help them along and figuring out
where the
abilities are how to get out in floyd
another great example sample
applications that come with your tomcat
or whatever other server it might be you
know those are probably not things easy
Floyd either right there's no reason for
those to exist on a production system
why would you have to come there because
if there are vulnerabilities in those
example applications and the answer
example applications I'm sure they've
been subject to a lot support by
scanning and taping and things of that
nature price the Java pet store whatever
whatever stuff might be included with
your app server you know if you sample
applications have security flaws that
attackers who potentially use those to
compromise the server as well so you can
do you can do a great job ray secure
code but if you have a bunch of other
apps with security problems hang off of
your hanging off your deployments again
that's so that maybe only attack need to
accomplish whatever they love to attack
and so you want to make sure when you
have production systems deployed you
have only the code that you want
deployed in those systems you don't
necessarily want administrative console
and default application you want the
latest version of your application and
only the latest version of your
application running on that application
server so how do you prevent security
this configuration and the big
recommendation here is that you need to
establish a hardening process that makes
it easy to deploy another environment is
proper lockdown and 22 degree possible
you want your development QA a
production environments you're
configuring idea identically so that
testing on bone is representative of
test
another you know that said there are
situations where you need did you may
need additional tools in a development
environment essentially to a promise to
do the appropriate Diagnostics as you
look at muvico dough through to
production and the process again to the
degree that you can automate this to
minimize the effort that is going to
help you we've done a lot of work doing
remediation of application level
vulnerabilities and an interesting thing
that we noticed is we saw applications
or systems where you can under one touch
like redeploy the whole thing they can
do environment Amazon because somebody
had just that's the patch script at that
out with your puppet chip dr. all the
cool whiz-bang stuff you know on the
other side of the system there's a on
the other side of the spectrum their
systems where it's like yeah nobody
touches the production server because
we're not sure how we'd be builded if we
had like nobody knows what version msxml
required about this application so like
nobody goes near this server of truth
because they're afraid that we will
break everything where field1 case found
at a regional bank there is a devil
workstation under someone's desk like
collecting dust that someone had kept
their feet on that was required for them
to provision new employees or a
provisional employees there are some
weird function running on this machine
and get that machine where to go down
they would no longer be able to hire new
people scary and so you know so we think
we see things small across the spectrum
and in addition to this being important
for harming automation allow you to do
things the same every time to do those
things much more quickly and they also
help you do things like fix
vulnerabilities
environment to go in make changes verify
those changes that one up and so to the
degree you can push and there are a lot
of great technologies these days public
chef ansible again the shift to DevOps
which is for business driven looking for
that agility look for that heightened
speed those tools can also be harnessed
to accomplish tremendous security good
things for your organization that's the
tension that we see with a lot of kind
of older school security holes is like
the idea of DevOps abuddin it quickly
drives a little crazy but we've also
seen environment where people have taken
advantage of the shift to use these
tools to make sure that things get
locked down the same every day all the
time every time is done so and that's
what you need is repeatable hardening
process to say how do we go from nothing
to having a new version of the system
how do we make sure that all of the
configuration Harvey that we wanted to
do along the way got done gotten up
repeatedly you also need to have a
process in place to keep track of the
changes that have been made available
for the components of the system and to
be able to get those deployed into a
production environment and this is also
something very important for code
libraries again that's something that
were to spend some time looking at me
and death but what do you have in play
what I patch management do you have to
place for your environment so that you
know when patches when critical patches
are available for servers and that you
have a process to say yes we know we can
we can take this online upgraded
verified right back up then roll it back
into the rotation same thing with code
libraries again new motor abilities
might be the count of security
vulnerabilities that are known in the
world is only increasing monocoque way
over
we're never going to get rid of
vulnerabilities you're ever going to
undiscovered motor abilities we're only
going to find new one so over time you
need to understand that the code
libraries are using obviously the
operating system database servers and so
long those are going to have new
vulnerabilities identified and you've
got to have a way to get these things up
to date you know also looking at the
architecture of the application in the
system as a whole to provide separation
between components where we talked a lot
about defensive depth and that's exactly
what we're talking about here is how do
we build the system as a whole so the
compromise of one part of the system
doesn't have a catastrophic impact on
other Carson systems you can do that
again an infrastructure level shaping
network traffic figure a two level and
also you know this is the type of thing
in your production in products you need
to be able to run scans and do periodic
audits to make sure that what you think
is deployed in the security state of
what is deployed is in line with your
expectation so to recap again attackers
going to use whatever is available to
them default accounts on these pages
pages unpatched applause the operating
system files under boy who shouldn't be
directories that recording off of
whatever facilities are available to the
attacker they're going to take advantage
of that because at the end of the day if
I ojala steal your data it doesn't
matter if I got your data from sequel
injection or if I got your data from by
pulling up under grouped it back up and
tape off of the back of the truck stock
quote me or whatever it gets me into the
data that I
is fair game so it's probably for
criminals that there's no like laser
focus on home video technique so you
need to understand that application
security and the security the system the
application code you're writing those
get to put into system so you need to
understand that from an operating system
platform the web server / Napster the
framework in a custom code all of those
have an impact on the security of what
result employed the floor though I mean
honestly for me one of the cool things
about working in application security is
that as a discipline expand a number of
different areas so that's fun for me
what's dangerous or the flip side of
that we're a thing can be it is to do
this right requires input from folks and
a variety of person organization and
across a number of different technology
stacks in areas experience so which one
is a repeatable hardening process
perfectly as automated as possible which
these days should be very achievable
given the great tool sets they're not
available to support a lot of DevOps and
agile stuff if you want to an agreement
off like that identical configurations
between QA and prod so that you can do
testing on want and expect that to be
indicative of the security state of
others automated secure to build a
process that says something like I'm
looking at the security building process
is something a lot of organizations even
if they're looking at security under
areas sometimes this gets ignored your
security of the servers are using all
the way to build these artifacts before
they employed you know process for doing
passionate tracking software updates
process for keeping track of the
security state of the verses library
view of
with your application you want to strong
systems and application architecture to
provide at that type of safe occasion
isolation where possible and over time
you want to do scans and audits to
detect misconfigurations missing patches
other things that they creep in any
questions on any of them yes
this is a great way can you harm Deb
systems so there are there's a number of
aspects of this a challenger or
something that we see go wrong
frequently if you have very open systems
in dev and a intention of very hard
systems of production is a lot of times
if you're developing on an open system
you may be relying on features or
capabilities you may be relying on
something to work in a circle way that
when it's pushed into production all the
sudden you if you broken that assumption
and the only answer is well we have to
turn that fort up tonight we can't
figure this problem out we need to get
this deployed turn on that production
crypto calm that protection and
production I will start it out later
which means never right and so that's
the kind of challenge we see if you've
got front of the specific configuration
things you know looking at application
frameworks and things like that so you
don't know you want to like a train like
a good fight to the degree possible that
said in development environments you are
going to need you are often going to
need access to additional tools for
Diagnostics you are going to probably
want more verbose error messages in
development versus being in production
another area where we see a lot of
trouble at a sudden pay attention to is
handling things like muscle cell
certificates I don't know a lot of
organizations that are lying from each
each developer gets like an actual ssl
cert for their workstation and so we see
them a lot like mobile applications
where in development they'll have the
baby talking to self-signed certificates
and so you see the configuration will be
except the our ssl handshake is not
going to be your shield potentially
not gonna work properly a bit of
production USA yes I actually want this
only to connect to HBS I pencom right
and so that's the situation where you
need to be able to certainly we talked
about automation have a process to know
these are the differences that we had to
have between development and production
you know let's make sure when our
production build our mobile app goes out
that it has this compiled these flags is
compiled XYZ you know that the law
except I know and TLS certificate
something of that nature so that's kind
of be like ideally you would want that
as much possible so that you could go in
and do your most invasive testing like a
QA environment and you assume I hey the
ribosome that this is roughly equivalent
to the production environment the
reality of it is for like certain things
there are you're going to run into
situations where you have those
differences and that's why it's
important again to degree we have a
document and process preferably an
automated process where you say seven
new production build is going to flip
all the flags it's a TLS handshake has
to work and XYZ whatever still gonna be
pushing any other question fantastic
he remove it long you guys still dunno
kept very quiet all right okay so let's
move on number six of our top ten
sensitive data is oh sure what is this
well many web applications don't
prominently protect sensitive data
things like credit cards tax identifier
account information the count IDs health
information authentication credentials
and if they don't properly protect that
then the attackers can steal a lot I
those the weekly protected data and
using that data they can do things like
credit card fraud identity theft and
other crimes and as a result of this our
sense of data deserves extra protection
right and so this is where we start
talking about things like encryption the
person can happen both at rest meaning
when the data is sitting in datastore
whether it's a pile pile system whether
it's a entry in a database as well as in
prison so as we're clicking submit the
data is flying over the wire our client
to our server Oh things like that and we
need to take special precautions over
exchanging data between the browse
server now even half tier is going to be
severe because failure in this case is
going to compromise all the data that we
intended to protect so once we lose the
data once it's out the door it's game
over if you start looking at uh like the
Lockheed Martin cyber kill chain the
last step is data exfiltration right
once the day is gone is people so
typically this information food
sensitive data like health records like
credentials personal data Craig heart
sinks of that I don't remember if it's
in this step or not but it's really
important for you guys
as a security company as do any secure
development to make sure that you are
properly classified the data that you
guys have so when you look at what data
is in your applications you can very
quickly look at and say oh this
application call subscriber data that
credit card data is listed as high
business impact there for something that
we say we happen and oh by the way
because that's high desisting tag it
means them for knocking put that day on
SAS provider or something like that so
having those kind of pastas those kind
of policies in place are really good
good way when we start looking at the
data that your applications are bossy to
be able to determine what they adopt is
obviously the value of that data and the
impact our reputation or lose it are
going to be the biggest factors in terms
of determining the actual impact here
that said there's also legal liability
if the data is exposed so in the case of
health records we have HIPAA that
basically says you can't share health
information unless it's authorized by
the user this is the reason why when you
go a doctor's office and you know doctor
tells you everything about you but they
can't share you even the information
about your spouse your computers until
they actually sign that HIPAA release
for that my daughter had does some
tonsil surgery about yours so ago and
the doctor actually new practices he
start his little practice and he had to
send us a release so that you could give
the records from his old practice
transfer to his new practice that's how
strip the
pharma and then we talked earlier about
California's 236 where you it doesn't
air where the world is if you lose data
in Toulouse gii relating to assist
instead of California you are legally
required to report that information to
the citizen and say hey we screwed up
you lost your faith and then peace guy
has to deal with credit cards in this
case if you have a breach of your credit
card data pci basically says that they
can take away their ability to process
credit cards they can find you a pretty
significant amount of money if you're
not PCI compliant so these are things
where we have to consider all these
different ramifications of not properly
protecting the data so am I vulnerable
to a sense of data exposure well the
first thing we have to do here is
determine if the data is sensitive
enough to require that protection and so
this is where I come back to that data
classification pulse you look at the
data that we're going to be keeping in
this application we look at the
classification where it sits in our
environment and it would look at what we
need to do to protect that so I was on
call last night actually with our
arbitration to pay and they're working
with a vendor of China to procure
certain application and the very first
question I have is what data are we sort
a SAS application what data is going in
there because for me my entire security
conversation how proud men treat this
application and how you know far been
digging to what this vendor is doing is
entirely dependent
of the data that feels for them now they
tell me you're in the information that
we're going to store is just give us
some information about how many clicks
people do on a webpage and that's
probably not really sensitive
information but they tell me you know
we're going to take prep our orders from
all the people were buying this widget
and then we're going to send them the
products whatever the case may be okay
credit card information I know I made a
classification sense of us I business
impact and therefore I need to protect
that buy-in for people make so the type
of data is really going to change the
conversation about having an email after
that point you to figuring out what
security and hats off so we have things
like passwords very hard workers health
records p III and all those things so to
figure out if we're if we're vulnerable
the first question we ask is because any
of this data stored in clear text long
term including a backup of the stand
right because if that data is being
stored for example in database but that
means that there is a point of exposure
there were so many good access that
database sequel injection clogging you
one possible way to get at that data
likewise with backhoes there are having
situations remember specific University
one offhand or they basically have a cup
cakes when pissing and when the question
was asked you was were those gates
encrypted the answer was dead so they
lost remember only a hundred thousand
student records as a result of that tape
box just going this and they all know
that somebody actually used that
information right all they know is that
there was a tape boxing when gone you
know maybe so late when code and overall
all those tapes use it but there's notes
people do silly things the next question
or ask ourselves is any of this data
transmitting clear tax and that could be
internal or external e because if that
data is being trained
your tax then that data is being exposed
and we don't have a really good way
other living HTTPS to say did somebody
listen to this connection between here
here and if you think about how far our
information travels right if I go to a
website right now for my phone or my
computer it's not like that's going from
my wire to know the closet over there
right that's literally going across the
country if not across the world in order
to get there and you know every single
compliment that touches do you know
every cop that's been take you'll run
out of the phrase phone sometime when
you are hitting a website and see how
many routers that that that packet is
gonna promise right we can't trust
everybody there so we have to use things
like transport layer security like our
HTTPS to ensure that that data is safe
and secure and we still have to do this
internally i got my soapbox earlier
talking about house just as important to
do https on that you know stupid for
layer using to do whatever internally
it's because you know these credentials
the username or password that we have
for our organization this is sensitive
information and if anybody you know have
an attacker on my network and i always
assumed another attack ground my temper
if they're able to capture my
information my username and password
regardless of the method scheme over
right they now have access to a
privileged account of multiple systems
and they can use that to take the data
and pestle training so we need to make
sure that we're using strong transport
layer security we also want to look at
encryption algorithms cryptographic
algorithms because there's a number of
algorithms now have been obsoleted
meaning that has computing resources
Valens it becomes easier and easier for
attacker to basically have the number of
resources available that they can break
those things so good example is me my
passion every hot ashes at one point in
time we're considered to be a
cryptographically secure a hash is
basically when you take one value
whether through a functioning you get
back a different value any time you run
your function you're always going to get
that value back right but there's no way
to kind of reverse so one point I'm and
we pile which is a way of doing that
what's considered to be a triple
graphically secure way to do that well
now human resources are such that that's
not really the case in fact there's a
number of different places that you can
go on online where you can just plug in
it's like a search you can be plugin
ashing to the database and it goes it's
like there's your answer right because
it always keeps one way it's all you
have to do is just keep the dictionary
in calculate the hash for all these
different coming just meet up with all
the rain move it basically look up all
the sins so we want to make sure that
all these old week / graphic algorithms
they're not in our code I saw a really
interesting graphic the other day I wish
I put the deficit is pretty awesome
those basically starts with TLS middle
and it was like he cures all the
difference transport layer of mechanisms
that you can use it was like yo Jerry
tomorrow say here's 80s all these
different things and then from there and
has spun off its like 85 passion do a
shot 256 in childhood basically kind of
spiraled out and then they even use some
cool color coding where it was like
reading for all the illegal actives
you're like oh that's a good way to kind
of visualize what the space looks like
it's a good way see okay well if I need
this and I use the green
you just kind of all the paths I thought
that was pretty cool crypto keys so we
want to make sure their keys are strong
that were using property management
being that our keys are being stored in
a secure location that we're using you
know that they're being encrypted it's
like that that our keys are being
rotated on regular basis again talked
about some of the country the session
from forcing earlier just as easily you
can group horse a square of the keys so
we wanna make sure that those are being
rotated on river basis and then the last
one here is browser security directives
or headaches so there's lots of
different headers that you can who
hasn't helped her in your application to
make it more secure one problem that i
was thinking of earlier so just lost it
Jeremiah Grossman are spanked talked
about it in for a really cold clip
Jackie I mean look jacking was this kind
of thing where you basically put like a
think of it as like an I crave my top of
the age that you're trying to discern if
I clean this microwave layer on top of
the page they were basically able to
capture the clicks like they're making
and so while they were able to do is
have like anal web page that tells you
you know make sure do this whatever and
on the background you're actually
putting out something else so for
example it might be like a deactivate
account functionality or might be a
password change functionality and so
what do you think you're playing at a
clicky clicky game you'll put the bowls
or whatever in the background
at least you're clicking the right
buttons to make this other application
that you don't you can see this is a
transparent layer two things that you
don't want to do well there's actually a
browser a browser I had basically the
directive that you tu the web browser
says don't vibrate my patient right it's
an anti clicking cook jacking header
that specifically says when you move my
page to not be in a knacker now that
might break something if you're trying
to create some weird proxy portal you
want that page to show up in that portal
it's going to break that because it's
going to break out pray but it's also
good prevents in life been doing
something like that good jack so these
are things that we need to kind of be
conscious of it and actually take action
on based on our situation so here's an
example scenario we have an application
in groups credit card numbers in
database using on Mac database
encryption but this also means that
decrypt the data when's retreat so think
in terms of like the guys who I was
talking to last night they were like
yeah we use Microsoft Azure and bike
shop if you're automatically does the
incur fee and deeper okay but honestly
does the encryption decryption that
means that every time their application
basically calls into the database is
going to do the incorrect or the deep
roots well the sequel injection is just
another way of calling into the database
right so if there are encryption layers
based on that then my sequel injection
is going past that as well so in the
case of encrypting the day of the
database I probably want to do an
application level encryption and then
shove it through my steep or whatever
into the day because I want to make sure
the my application is
virgin decription that way a sequel
injection was 50 cent here's another
scenario this was a great tool maybe
five years ago or so is called fireship
ir she was basically it is this firefox
plugin that you could use and if you
went to like a starbucks or some coffee
shop fire up the parachute and what i
would do is if the network for anybody
using certain applications
twitterfacebook of stuff like that and
when it saw that information go across
the network we would actually capture
the cookie capture with prudential that
they're using or taxes that side and it
was like it basically was like do you or
logon esta season and all you have to do
is like yes and now I was under login as
I use your surfing facebook like manner
and posted where like you're done right
and so firesheep would was really good
in terms of the fruit concept of showing
the importance of SSL encryption it
basically told us that if we're not
encrypting that data and we're sitting
in a coffee shop and he knew a certain
Facebook or whatever then anybody can
steal that cookie if I can be us they
can do that broken authentication
session management that we talked about
earlier and now they're logged in and as
I reviews so unfortunately parachute
kind of shown the light on this big big
problem and since that point Twitter
Facebook and Notre of other companies
have now gone to a celebration yes by
default so they are you go to an HP game
twitter com you're immediately
redirected a Shinto PS we're calm and
this is the recent line a little graphic
here just kind of showing what we're
talking about so you've got this user
and whatever their trans
with an application on the other end and
we're not using HTTPS in order your act
with this application that somewhere
along the line that is hacker may be
able to see that information that might
be that they've compromised another
server on the way it may be that they
they're staying in that coffee shop and
they're able see the traffic is imposed
water was network maybe that they've
compromised a router or something but
regardless of where they sit at work
path variable C macaques flying over the
temper and it's not encrypted that
they're able to accomplish the data a
third scenario here we have a password
database that uses unsalted hashes to
store passwords so talk a little bit of
a hash earlier and Dan mentioned yoga we
don't want to store the actual password
of the database will escort for the hash
value following if all you're doing is
writing that that password room will say
an md5 hash which we said is not
cryptograph to secure and we're scouring
the information in the database then we
can do what a great low tables and we
can basically run through all the
different password combinations and now
all we have to do is if we get that that
password hash we just plug it into their
get back the information about what the
password is and now we can log into the
web web site and so this camel actually
shows you those md5 rainbow tables it's
a about four thousand gigabytes or so
across all of these different tables and
so for example if you're
have the Alpha space and 109 characters
they besides that regular tables at the
front of four games relatively small and
you'll have basically open percent
success rate at gain that information
right 139 here most of her password
policy somewhere on a to false and like
that yo a kind of goes up from there you
can see if we added your numeric spaces
special characters things like that the
size of those databases but with
computing power today's really really
easy for us to just say cheers all the
possible inputs let's throw all those
into business growth through this a
solution and put all the other comes
data now we have that matter this is
without something I was just yep again I
was going to get to that well I don't
know about most people I can't speak to
that basically when saying is that what
we do to prevent this as we do is call
salting insulting is basically for every
user entry in addition to their password
which we use to make this hash we added
a random down and that rate of values
most all the songs and so for each user
that we're trying to do this with we
basically create another entry that's
our salt and then when the first time
this user you uses this password the
first time they set this bathroom we
take the password we combine with the
salt roadmap for the hashing function
and now we have our hatch that's the
value that we stored our database and
because we're store data our database we
don't have the actual cops word which
means that our system gets compromised
or something like that and I won't do
that because we've add the self value it
means that they can't even do this
rainbow table thing we
we have basically entirely random value
plus their password in or do you even
try and do this rainbow table think it
becomes way way more complicated to to
do a rainbow table with that so that's
the reason why we use salted passive oh
yeah yeah so most of the hashing
algorithms that you see the ones that
haven't been obsoleted of the md5 the
reason why is because of the number of
rotations that they do so what you'll
see is I'll be curved as an example they
don't just do this hashing thing once
right if I take it through this function
I take this and put it here that's
really really easy for me to do and it
doesn't take a computer long time to do
that so you can whip through those
combinations very quickly the whole idea
behind these more is bigger alber that
was the shop I probably would not is it
takes more time to construe de and so
what they do to do that is they run
through that function and then they
write it again and they run again
sometimes in some words other times you
know going through that that process of
writing for that hashing function in
ordering in that fight back yep exactly
yeah I'm going to when it comes to the
hashing you want hashing functions that
are going to be slower because it makes
it much more difficult for somebody to
do rainbow tangler or to traffic report
yep all right yes the truth the salt the
salt is stored in the database it's
stored alongside to use
bass the idea is that the salt is just a
random value that you're able to
impending so you're you're not counting
on the user a lot of times users make
poor choices but it comes to the
passwords and things like that right a
lot of times those choices are based on
things like dictionary borders and stuff
like that which are easy to look up a
lot of times those choices are very
short words and things like that and so
the salt is basically adding in some
randomization and we're not entirely
found on the user to to give us proper
balance it also means that when the
attackers trying to create these rainbow
tables and automate that here this hash
calculates to this value and we're
basically making it so that they can't
do that we've added this random chunk
onto it so they can't just go through
the dictionary here's all the stuff so
usually get salt okay
right they would not have the salt and
the password can they happen they
basically have to go through that
exercise all over again regenerating the
rainbow table with that particular salt
and email can do that they only have one
user it's pretty slow puncture yeah it's
definitely possible the goal of this
exercises is more disclosing talent than
anything else because long as you're
doing your security right in front they
shouldn't be able to assess fault but
you have to absolutely they're able to
get away to get the salt out of the
database now they have that piece they
still have to do they still have to go
through the entire dictionary create
that 4,000 Gate rainbow table of all the
different passwords plus the salt and I
hope that they come up with the right
answer
yeah I all depends on the vendor that's
doing it and the developers that work
which is the whole reason why we're here
today right so Amazon may be hiring okay
you can fix that or or sharp or samsung
or
I mean idea if they were smart right
they put like a TPM module onto the
board and what they use the TV on we're
doing things like that but you can do
hardware-based encryption but yeah i'm
guessing that when you can buy this is a
huge classroom TV for four hundred
dollars that they're not really worried
about bridge those having virtual ships
and things like that is good
yes yep well I mean these devices don't
have a ton of computing power there it's
like a raspberry pi base is nothing to
it
fire
I
yeah interesting related note so I at
one point I was like hey order I can get
my suit horse application for my
raspberry pi the answer is yes FK the
challenge that I ran into was actually
with the hashing function the raspberry
pi didn't have enough power and didn't
have enough memory to really approach
during the hashing this book is possible
so long in to savour it was something
that probably took it because it had to
go through through all that function
once you're in there pending works just
fine because now you're just using that
session credential but getting asked
that initial watery screams in forever
because they can create the bicycles of
college enough to do all that yeah other
questions however keep going the last
scenario here is really just showing
another pictorial in this case it's of
the balance right so we have this
scenario where some bass in a pinch
application they're sensitive different
patients being stored into the database
and then that information gets both out
of the database including to some sort
of Ibaka if those backups are decrypted
and they fall off the truck or they get
stolen or whatever the case may be now
we have a scenario where some a has
access to that data so this really
importance to why it's really important
if you're doing that dose of sensitive
data that those backups on purpose as
well the good news is that most of the
modern backup utilities and we're using
have the ability to use ease to do
encourage enter that data and then it
becomes a
exercise the team and how control back
you rotate that uses all right so how
about the vent sense of day exposure
first of all crawl sense data you want
to consider those for us that we plan to
protect the damper right so we have to
know what what is the the cat was the
scenario under which we need to be
concerned and so you contemplate part is
this a the inside uses somebody who has
access to our network vast access that
system that is this next to a loser
because its own hear that and then based
on that will make sure that we improve
all the sense of day of rest and transit
in America the feds against those
attacks so we will all make sure that
we're addressing those specific
steering's the second one is we don't
wanna source sense of data unnecessarily
right this goes for things like credit
cards it is a great example if all I do
every time somebody places in order on
my site is take that current artists for
real daya's take the course or database
eventually that Davis is really really
big right if somebody were to compromise
that system so we were able not a sequel
injection bar whatever and get get
access to that data now they've got huge
history of all the credit cards that
were used on that site and some of these
credit cards are valid for unity real
all series from so the the moral of this
story is if it stated that we don't need
right if it is one time to charge the
car and then we're good sku read that
data right maybe maybe we have a policy
where sometimes we have to charge back
at cards we have to sort that reason
okay oh I get it so let's do that for
two months let's keep the car
information every month and then we
delete the data the idea here of you
that we have some sort of policy sort of
a process in place that when we no
longer need that D to make the data
based on whatever qualification that
that is that we get rid the third ampere
is ensuring that we're using strong
standard algorithms and strong key
property management place and the way
that we do our children what's true and
what's not is there's a standard pump
it's 140 he's our models have basically
been validated by the government as
strong cryptography and Rizzo mr. snake
in this fits 140 I think one for us too
as long as we're staying in that
category we should be a pretty good
shape when it comes to cryptographic
algorithms if we start drinking outside
that especially of dripping outside that
means that we're using homemade
cryptography we are entering a very very
bad place tonight I hope don't you guys
in the fourth one here in true that
passwords are stored with an algorithm
to specifically designed password
protection gentlemen up your invention
feat krebs there's a TV gaiety of to
theirs Esper things like that but
basically we're using common standard
algorithms to do the protection of those
those pieces of data and then the last
one here autocomplete if we have forms
that are plucking sensitive data I have
those forums do this ugly thing which
basically means that are saving that it
the browser and there are exploits that
can allow an attacker to pull that data
out of the browser dan talk about
cross-site scripting earlier there's a
fragrant called beef the browser
exploitation print work and using e you
can actually pull this current data out
of the browser just through cross-site
scripting so it becomes very very easy
for an attacker to love to leverage
these from taps and young they have said
hey is this prospect string is very
focused on that browser well think about
how easy it is once you have to pull the
browser to now take over the users cute
once you have control over their
computer now you can control their
network and so on so these things that
are seemingly pretty small from the
beginning actually grown important too
much bigger issues than they are there
come do all the browsers are the disable
auto complete I believe so Oh modern
browser should you go back to like next
gamers a barren landscape are cool
tournament the window oh is it windows
three more or something like that yeah
back back in the day still right alright
cool that's awesome I remember when my
dad got his first nap classic there's a
game I love playing other dark room it
was basically just move the mouse and
throw rocks at like baths thereby making
good old games right all right high
level safe bones here and talk about
this river and good i do to my next
I actually have the example data
classification polls right if you don't
already have one it's a great place to
start this gives us kind of the basis
for a whole policy here and then when we
start talking with developed or sort of
business or whatever we can use this day
consultation policy we've been very
easily point2 okay this is the day this
is the type of data that you're talking
about storing this is the impact that we
conserve it here's the policy that says
that we have to encrypt your that we
can't a trip there we do whatever here's
the piece that says where we can store
this data right it's no longer just a
conversational way I think we should do
this whenever it's yours impulsive this
is what we feel I should be in place if
you like except you can talk about that
but this is the standard company balls
we want to review the information store
near an application against that policy
and Inter and what needs to be printed
and then we want to build a Rotarian
application to improve those fields
impressed so here's a sample policy very
very simple it just says we create three
different classifications we've got high
medium low for high business impact to
determine that govern identification
like driver's license social security
half work things like that that balls in
their personal financial information
becomes record numbers health
information we're concerned all that
high business impact and then Eric a
consultation policy would then go on to
say anything hi business impact should
be encrypted and with our medium which
is sensitive information
Gracie religion stuff like that personal
contact information name email address
things like that and then maybe we've
heard that maybe we know that's up to
our company or urban policy and the last
one with the slow business impact which
is only accessible web pages whitepapers
things like that that's probably stuff
you don't care about that is meant to be
public information so we don't really
eat you improve that day the at the end
of the day we're making this very
conscious decision about what data is is
not gave me high impact and whether it
should or should not be pretty in terms
of implementation level safeguards who
are you strong encryption algorithms
fifth says that Triple DES is still ok
however AES is the preferred mechanism
for Charlotte approach so for doing on
the encroaching aes-256 is probably the
way to go likewise md5 obsolete shower
from game obsolete shocking 56 is
recommended by this as the hashing
algorithm will I use top will provide
implementations of the algorithms so
this is the the scattered don't roll
your own thing if the if the plaque
holder wat some sort encryption of
implementation we should take advantage
of that primarily because if there's an
issue a name is going to get fixed alas
good private the report and
complications can give updated
they have the latest and greatest
available to us in some cases that might
not be and in those cases we should look
to reliable source libraries things have
been around for a while tested found
true be in those situations we can run
into those situations words like healthy
or ability that was sickening openssl
generally concerned to be very secure
there was an in there for a decade right
and then the last piece is key
management or make sure their keys are
stored in a secure manner like a
keystore other secured facility in terms
of java there's java cryptography
extensions which basically is the key
information the keystore pieces it's got
the the encryption algorithms what gods
of JC key store yeah so to recap this
occurs when applications don't properly
protect sensitive data can be prevented
by encrypting sensitive data at rest and
transit we don't want sources of data
necessarily get rid of it and don't eat
it and then using strong encryption
algorithms keys questions
ok
what's up
pagers there was a really interesting
presentation of black hat was the year
before last and what these guys did is
they used a standard kind of like a TV
card yeah and they basically start doing
spectrum analyzation of it was like
restaurant patrons have a really cool
presentation they basically looked at it
the rainbow figure out based on this
wave pattern or whatever here's the bits
they're actually being broadcasted and
they reversed engineered that back to
this bit identifies this particular
device and therefore if I flip this I
can access this device and if I do this
and actually all the devices to off at
once so these guys basically sat outside
the restaurant they're really all right
let's make that we go and those two
things are exposing your new person fix
it up like okay let's make that one that
one starts going off in the leg strength
let's make them all go off that's what I
was going crazy bald of the things are
going off this is great soft really
interesting stuff
yeah yeah
yet the self side thing is another for
my soap box out it again the salt sign
is another really interesting thing
because any time the cordless all
signing certificates out there they have
mentioned it you know there's a lot of
Deb environments where we use
self-signed certificates we're
effectively training those users to
click OK what's meant to be a security
work the whole purpose of that self
signed certificate is to say that the
certificate is either inspired or it's a
different domain than what we're trying
to access here and we get that such as
good morning begins to danger will
robinson there's a problem here right
and the user should really think about I
think okay why is it convenient probable
that thing's expired oh they probably
got rotate it or oh that I mean those
match hey that's a big problem but ain't
who you see that that means that
attacker two of them right there in the
middle they go change the ssl
certificate and because the person is
trained to just put yes both yes the
attacker can be looking at that
conversation you've seen all that date
of it so any time you give one of those
ssl certificate worries i urge you not
to just click yes but the take a moment
pause right it doesn't have to be click
away and think about why that message
popped up and think about is this
typical should i click this is this an
outpatient I trust if I going over the
Internet or is this just your my home
server over the kids maybe because that
could be indicative of a much bigger
step off my soap box a other motions
poop all right so I'm going to let Dan
talk you guys about missing function
global access control oh yeah great idea
oh so it is 217 I will take 10 minute
breaks and people's own