[Music]
this year had a data protection failed
personally raised your hands any data
protection fails in the audience I can
see as interpreter I can see 10 hands
maybe two honest who knows someone who
has had a personal data fail yeah many
more hands raised and for whom of you
did were the were close relatives
affected I know your pain I'm completely
happy that I can introduce overflow
tentative and linked to you with the
gdpr fails show about GDP are but also
in Freedom of Information and hopefully
a very entertaining 19 minutes show an
applause for these two please crying we
can't see much from here yeah a very
nice evening to you will simply start
with something to loosen up and we'll
see if our technology works at the same
time GDP our privacy by design privacy
by design data protection impact
assessment tech technical and
organizational measures
I hate paper red tape data oh dear
data I hate data so much and ordering I
hate that even more filing in order
it's about personal data name email
account number perhaps where they live
but also age size and weight and the tax
number are under protection obligations
data air data we have to protect the
data data is not a little thing
it should first take the effort then
reap the rewards reap the rewards these
in gun protecting data from all these
hackers and spies and all that nonsense
this happens if you use the same
password for several services and leave
your laptop open lying around or lose
that paper with all the passwords on it
data earlier data indeed we must protect
the data that all the data we have to
maintain them and order them fire them
fire them fire them data
yeah data I love data so much we have to
maintain them and and that's easy
look after them then they are much more
useful all right now to the Foundation's
the fundamentals of the GDP are and the
German Data Protection Act you have to
know what you have and why and prove
that they are safe
that's where why the EU had seven
principles that they came up with
according to which you record and
transmit and establish your protection
measures and these are fairness purpose
minimization correctness limitation of
storage integrity and accountability
and that's what you need for your
privacy statement data or year data you
have to protect the data
yeah the data we have to maintain it and
file it have to file it file it file it
data
oh yeah data I love data so much we have
to maintain it and look after it they're
much more useful in case we don't
understand something you have a hard
time interpreting the law data Tech
Protection commissioners will help us
it's free of costs data or year data we
have to protect the data so what does
that mean
were you in life I promise that I'll
take as much care as I can solving then
I can finally go back to my work data oh
yeah data I love data so much we have to
maintain it and look after it they're
much more useful and finally sight isn't
another - exactly
remember your processing manual and your
privacy statement and then we can start
[Music]
[Applause]
okay okay right and then we start so
we'll start how do we start over
well GDP our or fails we'll just get
some victims from the audience
which will help us get the most
difficult rules in the GDP are and I get
to grips with them somehow right okay
good idea
we have four chairs louder fire okay I
see lots of volunteers I'm looking for
four of them right
wow I still don't see a lot
one person showing up someone shouted
out in the back there that's the second
one get on to the stage we need two more
okay the third one there so right the
last one last candidate okay that looks
good okay you choose a color
there's Andreas sit down please welcome
Stephanie hi given us Holly great so do
sit down
of course I didn't remember all the
names Andrea's Jonas Jonas Katrin and
Ollie without Ollie Ollie ollie ollie
okay I don't have to remember this well
but these are all personal data and
these people have all invented
pseudonyms obviously and each of you
will get a sheet yeah you can talk kinda
get me an awesome prize this is the
beautiful satsang and Azir good for us
itself that's that's very good each make
a shaft up woman Vendela mind session ID
yes for us
and detent title feared yeah it says of
us yeah okay Oscar that we've come up
with some very interesting questions for
all of you and you all have the same
chance to win you we've taken through
two rounds and the best two will then
get into the final and that was it
basically the rest will explain itself
so shall we start
we still need four other candidates for
more volunteers please but you stay on
stage but you should be able to do some
limited amount of maths because we need
people that can calculate from the first
row because these people need to tally
up the points because I didn't manage to
get this kind of elaborate tasks
programmed which is tallying up the
points we'll just get some people on the
first where they can all calculate mmm
I'm quite sure of that they look that
way so who would like to count points
for Andreas yeah yes like that Saddam
you two belong together
you're not biased you know related 200s
or anything okay so you'll count his
points that's not an easy feat but
though because there have been many
points but you ain't managed and
sometimes candidates will fall back to
zero but they can catch up again to be a
Jonas another pseudonym who will count
Jonas's points you can call me musi as
well do we have someone ok please speak
into the microphone second volunteer for
counting
Jonas's points you just have to count
come on great so you count muesli
whatever well please do not travel the
points triple the points but who will
count for Katrina or fairly cleanly and
observantly and doubly no someone over
there perhaps they all look they're all
looking away now
let's site BRV and we'll just point to
someone well that would be mean though
well if the advantage these people have
to stay until the end so we'll have four
people in the audience at least okay you
two belong together
I'm going to tell you what you have to
count up and you remember that in points
and who will do this for do this for
Wally looking and that way we'll get the
90 minutes field as well keine no one
over there you two belong together
you'll count for Olie
don't cheat just and you'll all start
with zero you can all remember that and
then we will start with round one we'll
start with the very easy tasks there's
always going to be four options for
choices and you have papers sheets that
you will hold up with the letters A to D
but the others should not see which
letter you will choose just the
secretive okay we'll start easy
who what does data protection protect
what do you think a data is a data
that's protected or be security of data
gigan one see what is particularly see a
data these security of data see the
offenders or D self determination about
personal information could you repeat a
question
please forgive them how what we forgot
to say each of these four has a an
audience Joker well no it didn't figure
that that's only in round two so thank
mr. cookie if you ask about fishing
against is it protecting
of what so what does data protection
protect data security of data offenders
or self-determination of post about this
information dude deep beautiful these
sheets are maximally transparent and the
correct answer of course is D which
means 23 points for Andreas muesli will
go without Catherine 23 and only 23 you
all remember that so three times 23 okay
second question since when do we have
data protection laws maybe since May
2018 maybe since 1995 relied maybe since
May 1949 maybe since 1970 so a may 2018
be 1995 C may 1949 and D 1970 since when
do we have data protection laws decide
now ah this is sliced Nessie spread
great I don't have to count it down at
all it's very simple
we'll start simple so further back may
213 yes there was a data protection or
the GD P R but of course that was not
the first one by far in 1985 there was
the Data Protection Directive at the EU
level quite opened not old enough May
1949 was the basic law the German
constitutions in 1970 that was in fact
fact when the first date election law
was passed in the German federal state
of Hesse er so zero for muesli didn't he
have Dino yet see Katrin 23 to you I
don't know if it's 23 plus 23 Coe if you
can calculate that but try and over
there no points
next round over come on next round yeah
who is the father of the gdpr
that's going to be very difficult their
staff who is the father of the GDP our
first is that yun philip i believe
someone problem over fee
oh we have a problem now is it yun
Philip blushed slightly different
spelling there I see is it
Yun Philip or D is it host Z over the
current interior minister in Germany
okay they're all looking at the spelling
varieties of young Philip Ivan its name
you're completely correct to take a look
there you can all decipher this can you
you see the difference don't you between
a and B there's a another P coming
between B and C there's a - added or D
of course if if you choose D it's very
it's going to be very simple for you
right now try your luck see Connie come
on wonderful you've finished andreas
zero points for andreas a wrong zero
points Catherine wrong zero points and
only got it right B is correctly Yun
Phillip MIT does not have a hyphen in it
his name but two peas at the end of the
Phillip only how long have you been
training secretly not long at all next
question great why does the number 23
come from where does the number 23 come
from good question who can explain
Vietnam at 23 question to the audience
who got that idea and where from before
we own C oblem you know before we just
embarrass ourselves completely and and
try to tell the story ourselves who
wants to tell the story he would like to
I didn't want to tell so what why should
they tell the tale I have no idea at all
come on please tell we'll just we just
insert John Google Tron and 23 and
before we say something that's wrong
okay next question which important
principle has ever learned when I
started when he started working at the
data protection office from the lawyers
a the principal lawyers legal people are
always right be it depends CC well
surely it's in the law just look it up
or D we are God okay the question which
important principle has ever learned
from the legal people a the legal people
are always right
B it depends see what it's there in the
law or D we are God and from now on I
will follow a strategy ah tactic so we
have one B andreas 23 points to you
maybe you should fold it up so that it
cannot be seen through the sheets
doesn't muesli zero points Kathleen 23
points right it's correctly and Ollie
again correct again what is the correct
solution can you see I won this thought
okay I have a next round
ah it's the truth yes which of the
following ciphers huge should you select
should you choose and also come to us
and yes they are
where's that coming from on that screen
they're seeing the last question the
previous question which of the following
ciphers suits should you select TLS it
is each ADCs a with
RLC for 128 as a
it let us a or be TLS DHE RSA export
with TS forty cbc sha TLS DHE RSA with
aes 128 cbc che 256 or TTLs acdhh
RSA with aes 256 cbc 384 so flight
sorted here normal course cooking on
money you know that copter you see
Fukuda by so all the monitor has nice
time on without monitor its bill easier
okay yet you have you made your choice
let's see your letters cool holy I can
see show it to me please
you've got seen that's correct
30 23 points for Kerry in they start no
points for loosely and andreas please
resolve why ok you just kissed why the
rest is just bollocks the rest doesn't
just make sense
exactly I could just remember the lasts
digits and that would be nice these are
all existing surfaces not in my world
however claims that they're all real
name 9 buuck knocked libyan no it's been
broken hours for the
- a conduct was released our people in
volleyball reached B we don't want as
well C and D don't look that bad dear
countrymen saga is not funnyman d you
could use in an emergency if you don't
if you can't use perfect so forward
secrecy and if you lock the data and
years later you get to the key that's
kind of I'd seen it it's going to be
broken
C encryption is a tiny bit weaker but it
has perfect forward secrecy so that's
better
HT month good nobody objects ok wrong
direction again wrong direction this is
the correct education who is drastically
responsible legally responsible the
manufacturer a setoka a the manufacturer
the organization see their admin see the
administrator the meditator protection
official essence that's here
I neighborhood we have a story we can
[Music]
this is off there is stuff you become to
us see an office wants to use a software
which has data leaks to somewhere
some call it telemetry somebody says
that's not allowed
and who's responsible it is after a
garnish the responsible oversight agency
says that is not allowed now where does
the agency turn to whom does the agency
turn to who's responsible
I was cleared
Plato's minor static in your art Sofia
knows I'm stopping my strategy to select
only a answer B is correct site whoever
decides what to use is responsible the
organization for example it company
chooses or when yeah as admin the ions
at soonest most mysterious all the
starfish dishes often if you as a data
controller use software you are
responsible
let's see you what is the points 92
points for andreas worth and applause
[Applause]
not much less 23 points from his leave
who is counted for Katrine 125 points
for Kathleen
holy how much savage yes of course
oh you get the fifty euro later
insecurities in communication how many
points well the audience members said
125 but that's not a multiple of 23 so
it was corrected 215 and the 50 euro fee
will be handed over later okay so now
there's going to be a jeopardy style
panel to choose lectures question from
data fails fake news hacker information
free to free vibration and question mark
other categories and there are different
values of course to choose from and if
you lose your category then you'll be
you're having a hard time so if there
are certain risk feels hidden here and
where you have to gamble a certain
amount of points and there are a few
jokers in there and a few surprises that
we will just not mention at this point
cutting there is risk hidden that means
that the number that's shown here does
not apply you select which how many of
your points you want to gamble now those
that get it wrong will be taken down but
due to the great counting method of your
calculator you're in front so you choose
so is the audience Joker now active yes
one time you can ask the audience if you
don't know and those those whose turn it
is can also pass on the turn to whoever
shows up first okay I see so you can
always pass without losing points but if
you show up and get the wrong answer
when the question is passed
then you will lose points and what do we
do have no one's showing up okay we'll
see cutting you go
data fails 64 okay let's see if your
conversation works yes this is a
question that you will read out okay
niobium on an hashing person really
personal relation let's imagine an
enterprise is building some telephony
app and and because email addresses and
phone numbers and says these are not
personal data because we've hashed them
with sha-256 it's come too far now the
question then is that are these data
anonymous or personal and why you get
arrows hashed data for whom for the
authority that is sending the data or
the organization that receives them for
the processor of those data so the
company that has calculated the hash all
that's left is the hash I don't know if
this is gonna be a hint first you'll
have to say do you accept the question
are you going to pass I'm going to
accept the question there
Turner's there is is this an exclusive
or an inclusive or that can be important
well you always have to remember he
plays against you yeah yeah so now would
be the moment for you to answer the
question well we just talked about the
SSA 255 6 hashes and said that that's
it's actually in a one-way route there's
no way back vanished so in that regard
you can't get back from to the phone
numbers from the hash that's what you
said when we went with other questions
did I say that that hashes cannot be
reversed so you say it's anonymous no
way that's why I'm asking for whom and
not for whom is it
because the number that cutlass did the
company that calculates us has just may
still have the key for that lying around
and could reverse it there are other
keys with hashes there are no keys my
dying I I was thinking of cryptography
they're not salted and not peppered
either definitely I have been debating
with many people whether hash is still
personal or anonymous and my belief is
that it's anonymous but there's always
two different opinions so you decide it
depends yeah the answer is it depends
and we will exclude the Interior
Minister Jose Hoffa okay so question is
this data enormous a person and why and
that irritates me this and why because I
would say anonymous but the and why
would only make sense if personal would
be the right answer
no is it a trap well personally I
believe that hashes of this quality are
anonymous data how quickly will you
calculate 10 million hashes back into a
phone number I understood endure one
hour was the case with sha-256 how many
phone numbers do we have in German it's
not so many I don't know a hundred
million a billion maybe so a few seconds
you will need so sadly no that's wrong
just simply by brute force you can try
out the hash for all the phone numbers
and once you have it you hit it you have
the right number it's a bit more
difficult with passwords but a simple
example and that has been subject to a
court decision maybe you've heard of a
facebook custom audience where you can
transfer hashes of email addresses to
Facebook and the colleagues in Bavaria
prohibited local companies to supply
Facebook customers audiences with
emailed lists and transmitted at the
Facebook of what is it used for
it's used by Facebook
then these um match which people are
registered with the same images so in
effect the company will give the
information to Facebook that this person
is our customer whether it's by hash or
by direct email address is doesn't
really matter at all because Facebook
can always use the interests of the
customers they know about and calculate
the same hash and that's why these
companies were prohibited from from
transferring the data and the yeah vary
in Administrative Court the has
administered court in Bavaria in Munich
did confirm this decision so hashes of
email addresses and phone numbers are
personal data okay let's go a bit slow
ever so 64 points down that's the
difference between plus and minus do you
know about it from the 125 right well
let's move on the next round right what
is left
I think it's andreas turn now you choose
okay I'll use information freedom 23 if
you know information 23 anonymous
application so we're in the area of
freedom of information so it's going to
be the reverse game it's not about what
the state one's knows about it registers
of our data but what we want to know
from the state so we ask about data and
ask the authorities to hand out data the
question is can I hand submit such an
application anonymously can I submit it
in a way that the authorities does not
know who is applying and does they do
this they'll have to process the
application andreas what do you think is
that a question for you or will you pass
well I'll just consider how I will do
this how I would get the read a reply
because with fuckton start that might be
nice idea if I could still then as an
applicant be identifiable I would just
guess and I think that on a beautiful
it's a good question
because well the legal system in Germany
there's always feature an applicant I'll
just pass the question on ah he passes
it on who wants to answer it 50/50 50/50
chance
Holly do you say something Ryan smoking
83 okay I'll take it
and what's your answer answer that the
question is no the application doesn't
cannot be processed further if the
applicant is anonymous I don't know if I
should do it it need to give a reason no
no you don't have to because it's
actually wrong so 23 points deducted
negative you know mandamus phone you can
submit few information requests
anonymously many authorities do not know
this many authorities will then ask who
are you and you can respond no you
cannot ask that anonymous applications
work but the state laws are improved in
quotes because anonymous applications
are being forbidden in certain German
federal states that is quite mean but
that's the exception to the rule the
rule is that applications can be handed
in and honestly if you use a fact in
start the website the one on website
they are offering that service of
handing in your request anonymously back
to the fun you can now choose okay I'll
choose the 128th common data leaks start
and panin cremated yeah we often hear
about data leaks and we often very often
hear about this who which were lost or
CC BCC errors and emails or hacker
attacks
but the most common thing is missing
here what's the most common things ended
the email it's often this is clear CC
BCC is clear because the recipients see
all the other recipients and check
attacks are hard to explain but you know
these are the most common except for the
really most common one that's still
missing so everyone thinks about where
is the most common Dayton link facility
email I guess the first thing would be
not encrypted emails and encrypted
emails I shouldn't ask questions how how
they're reported or how they actually
happen so by the GDP our data leaks have
to be registered reported and also the
[Music]
things that the company did so that it
won't happen in the future couple of
other things
Oh delicious for example if we say that
doesn't suffice this passive is on the
sofa so which so which is the most
common way for data leaks to happen I
would guess loss of personal data but
that's a data leak okay how how did this
happen
what activity led to this I guess hacker
attack is also undefined the right
solution isn't on the part yeah no I
guess it's companies that
accidentally leaked email or hazard data
to github account networks if caught
some thug enough that's who as I still
have a question you say data leaks also
and under median Dean DeHoff well then I
guess it's just business card exchanging
a business card it's just business dates
and business cards that are exchanged
and that happens there so the real
answer is I'm looking for it but
everyone knows it right it's it's the
the sending of personal data to the
wrong recipients it might be wrongly
addressed mail email or a fax all of
these happen very often hundreds of
thousands of times we wanted to send the
prescription to the pharmacy but we sent
it to the wrong person it wasn't in
there in all your answers so I guess we
won't deduct points from anyone so maybe
as background that's just the most
simple thing thing that can happen for
example doctors that send the reports to
the wrong often recipient cheeks
it doesn't really matter I mean how many
possible recipients are there that's
they say it isn't really high-risk move
on by add up so yeah use you still have
to and from the actual victims of the
data leak but most people don't do that
can I tell you an anecdote I'm I have
contacts with some of the people who are
involved with this and then I talked
about exactly this example and then what
happens if the doctor what happens if
the if you sent the wrong report the
reports of the wrong person and two of
the people who were there just happens
to them so when in conclusion this
really happens way too often
so andreas asked what happens with these
data leaks so people have to report them
the data leaks to us so that's article
34 35 of the GD P R if it happens to
bigger groups it depends on how the the
report is delivered to the effect that
people sometimes you have to think about
fine if it if the data leak was really
severe that reminds me
it's 34 and 33 and that 35 in the radio
here but email encryption that's that's
something I really like because that's a
data leak that probably happens a lot
but yeah okay okay
1024 also but if I actually wanted data
face but we'd never had the question
mark so I picked that so what's behind
that question mark 1024 oh right risk
risk
so I'll just fix this do I have to look
at this whole stuff now no that won't
help you at all right sorry I don't know
the question myself I haven't got I
hadn't didn't
memorize it okay whether it was template
I have to expand it fastest is not hot
okay now I can reload I just have to be
fog away it's tough I thought that was
the question
all right can you just tell a story or
something so we had question mark 1024
oh yeah that's a little movie that you
are about that you should show now show
us a movie by mr. K from be risk
instructions in which areas can the
federal data protection commissioner
instruct the data Commission the federal
states data protection commissioner's in
determine federal states in which areas
okay a question like it maybe one or
other will recognize this guy no that's
not bad I just have to search that video
that wasn't the plan to show it now and
what is risk risk yeah what does it mean
risk means that you have to choose how
many points of your 1,024 you want to
gamble all of them you could gamble 1000
only four points if you had do- points
exist both ask mueslix my expansive
still 23 do you want to gamble all of
them
he'll end at zero and that will be it
but if you get out of it
so for 23 points we'll just listen
closely that's the German Data
Protection Commissioner all this cover
my name is Alec ever I am the German
data protection commissioner I turned it
down Thomas let's restart no right
my name is Alice Kober I'm the German
Data Protection Commissioner for theft
protection and freedom information now
my question about gdpr and the Data
Protection Act in which areas can the
German data protection commissioner
instructs the federal states data
protection Commission's not that I heard
this but it was in the slide earlier
maybe we should add that these 1024
point questions were all rather
difficult now the question of course is
you have 10 seconds ok I can't know that
long the question mr. Keval was in which
areas can the federal data protection
commissioner instruct the German federal
state data protection commissioners what
areas actually exist by which illegal
air is legal issues you could say which
issues the instruction be made maybe we
can give a hint about the number of
areas of the binary numbers there are
many options there No
no forget that hint nope yes so today
not what corner now you you should reach
your answer audience Joker great do you
still have this okay how should we do it
does anyone know let's look through the
audience the angel with the microphone
will now look for someone who knows and
otherwise we'll just vote because
obviously who wants to step into the
breach for muesli he will have to of
course decide whether he will accept the
answer someone is showing up in the very
back office did okay where was that
raised hand let's hope that we found
someone who knows it's a clearly
answerable question well since I haven't
got so many points to lose I will say
zero yes correct answer so 1024 points
for muesli no no no no 23 23 he only had
23 points to gamble yes it was the risk
question you had to gamble a certain
number of points because that question
was far too simple for 1,024 he was it
was because someone knew the answer so
now let's explain the federal data
Protection Commissioner has no relation
to the federal state datum additional
commissioners they're different errors
the federal identification Commissioner
is many tasks with federal authorities
and the 30 prediction there and the
federal state debt petitioners are
involved with debt reduction at the
federal state organizations authorities
and also have supervision about private
enterprises so they deal with everything
that takes place in terms of private
data processing the federal date of a
detection Commissioner has a small area
where he will deal with
telecommunication law but mainly the
areas of supervision are completely
separate so he has nothing to tell us
and we
have nothing to tell him so the answer
zero is completely right and it was
there's no area which instructions can
be made okay great miss you can now
choose the next question we'll have to
speed things up a bit
okay hacker which number how much you
again
okay I'll choose 24 yeah you're really
on a roll here risk again how much do
you wanna bet all 64 points or I really
didn't come up with a hacker question
that I was sure that no one could answer
[Music]
wait wait okay I have to tell you
something this is a risk question how
many questions how many points do you
wanna bet 64 okay I first have to tell
the story
HRM member of the company has a suit
case in a car it was a locked case in a
locked car the suitcase was lost or
rather stolen including the laptop ten
days later the company receives
blackmail please send us X number of
bitcoins for in the hundreds of
thousands at the address below and the
blackmailer was sending personal data
that was on that laptop so hit our
payroll information and 24 hours later
the company reports the data breach data
leak
can the governance organization the
supervising authority impose its calm
cough a pin penalty so the question is
what's the reasoning who do they have to
inform do you want to solve it can the
supervising body impose a penalty do I
have to have to solve all of them
okay I'm passing what's your name
yeah the name is e Catholic I'll take it
but then you you only get six four
points right because he bent 64 what why
am I getting his points half moon so
good okay I'm gonna go back to zero okay
okay I only got some fifty something so
can the supervisory authority impose a
penalty yes because usually after 24
hours the breach has to be reported and
either there was a bad cryptography on
it even if they got the laptop obviously
they could read it so that's a problem
in itself the company has to a minimum
inform the the body because there is a
HR or rather personally identifiable
information on it for example
health-related information so I would
assume that the relevant people had the
data on their laptop so all of them have
to be informed yeah I'm glad I didn't
take that question yeah I really think
we can avoid all 64 points to her okay
next question next round what do we
learn from this yes encrypt your load
books otherwise this could be very
expensive it happens all the time it's
not just laptops also stationery desktop
computers
so it's really not that hard anymore to
encrypt it
yeah please also encrypt all of the USB
sticks and if you find a USB stick on
the parking lot and please don't just
put it into the slot you can choose
[Music]
from Freedom of Information 64 in full
flight linda information freedom of
information for on a state level so i
have to improvise a little bit to find
the right video here hello my name is
Isabel Krause I'm a referent in the Data
Protection Agency and in has its data
protection is important but not given
how many country how many states have
not passed a law regarding data comments
and data security how many how many
states in Germany do not have an
information of Freedom Act yet I want to
pass okay so there are sixteen states
during let's census at least which one
of those doesn't have a Freedom of
Information Act yet its proper for 64
points well we yes 60 points yep
assessment mindful is also a little what
about my points now so you passed
nothing happens so you get the same
statement damage to do is who wants to
solve it okay special offer who can at
least name one state that doesn't have a
freedom of information I get yes come on
someone who's the first one to name one
oh yeah Barry I'm Tavares right okay
what else is there
Bavaria Lower Saxony yeah they're
working on a draft sex on you know yes
right it doesn't have it and obviously
sex on it doesn't have one either
that sounds fair that's 64 points for
Katherine they thought that next round
still your turn choose fake news name
let's take fake news 42 Thank You
Seinfeld sesh oh the kindergarten we're
looking for the kindergarten this looks
good hello my name is Susan Mayer and we
have I D for the unfuck I sell I got the
following question area of my shell
child was photographed in the
kindergarten and now it's in the
Internet is that allowed just to lose
Catherine do you wanna self no they're
not allowed to do that it's okay if you
do photograph and kindergarten it's fine
but if you upload it somewhere in the
internet on social media or somewhere
I've totally lost so that's not allowed
perfect capturing that's 42 points for
you
supa dupa dupa so still your turn
jeez can you still keep count
let's take question mark 42 that looks
interesting
Joker for your on the roll
oh you just get 64 points 42 points
I didn't go on posh party because I kind
of said and somewhere this is a social
booth here in for my tunes five thousand
teens wanted Oh freedom of information
1,024 no you wouldn't
that's a really difficult question in
which country which country has passed
the first law for freedom of information
in the world audience Joker and in which
year was it passed so audience Joker who
knows it you can you can tell Katherine
yeah that's it
all the way back there good now I'm very
becomes Joker interested yeah so the
first freedom of information act right
so is this worldwide ninety nine bases
yeah
zips in Texas it's seven 1966 probably
no food that was 1024 points for
Katherine what was the country Sweden
okay okay
many greetings to start E EDF a
platform in Germany right many thanks
whoever it was I didn't see
thank you I'll donate somebody okay now
let's take something I surely don't know
a hacker 42 changing passwords - a
Zoltan after which period of time admins
should make users change their passwords
how often how often should passwords be
changed so actually in - oh there we go
the standard term was three months but
since for shortly it's just regarding
any issues any incidents or so maybe
there is no time period at all because
short timers will lead to people of
writing passwords down and fitting them
to the screen either correct and if your
admin in your company somewhere tells
you to change your passwords every 30 or
90 days or something then point them to
our password guidelines which you can
get from our website where it says no
you shouldn't enforce password changes
only if there is a reason an occasion so
that was as many as how many was that 42
points right yes
42 points you'll keep the tally you can
do sums above a thousand surely cutting
just continue well maybe someone else
you can pass on the question okay
mmm informations finite reading with
evasion 128 in freedom of information
and human rights or basic rights a lie
still in question is their basic rights
to freedom of information in Germany
we've all learned that the right to
informational self-determination is a
basic right as determined by the German
Federal Constitutional Court but the
right to get information from
authorities
Kathleen's good that there you are a
legal expert is that a basic right I
pass that's a clever decision and I
guess I'll take that question and I'll
say no because it's not in the basic law
in the Constitution but it's in the
Freedom of Information Law which is a
federal law but not a basic law nice try
but sadly wrong in freedom of
information is a basic right it's an
article 5 of the Constitution where it
says that people can inform themselves
from public sources what you said about
the interplay between state laws which
are the FOI laws and German basic rights
at the time a state passes a freedom
information law that the the data
becomes a public source and you then
have a constitutional right to access
that source so sadly we have to deduct
points from you 128 you still have any
no so 0 points we have 2 people forget 0
you are out and only how's he doing
92 so everything's still open and in the
running there because you gave such a
nice answer you can choose the next
question what do you want out what do
you choose done name
I'll take hacker 64
so he hack a 64 job well and we have a
hacker attack an attacker took the email
address of a customer of an online shop
and copied it fellas
three important measures that the shop
owner has to take now you wanna solved
and yes so the first two I would
probably come up with but the third I'll
just pass so who wants this off now ok
I'll take it off Lincoln in for me yeah
they have to inform the customers they
have to inform the authorities and they
have to invalidate the login credentials
well I was actually waiting for a
different one but yeah that's ok that's
alright given the points this estêvão
Emma so the first one would have been
yeah well obviously mitigate the problem
ie
solved the leak or the the the threat
vector so how many points was that von
glowers check off yes TJ was 64 right
yeah 64 or so you can also choose the
next category now well we still have to
do fake news can we look at no I'll take
the 128 it's time Joe okay it's a joker
nice
yet Kassadin Alicia didn't tidy ageles
so snake eaters powers
okay I'll try Jacques I don't know that
data leaks 23 ha that's a stable scale
twist so the first fine imposed on a
company in Germany so since the latest
change in the law and the fines were
raised massively so there was a first
fine imposed by the the state
Commissioner for data protection and
button looking back so what was that
about
what was the first fine done for it was
on Heiser obviously no one wants to have
its own
it was the platform called snoodles what
they did was they had unencrypted
passwords on a database and it was 80
thousand euro zone 20 it was twenty
thousand years as a fine for having
clear text passwords saved in their
database that were copied today is it
possible for me to know that website
with my age well it depends it could be
difficult
it depends can we ask you for your age
[Music]
Corsi offer knows about it so 23 points
happened okay you're calculating
right
theta fails 42 plus symbol this is a
class book class and ball translator
doesn't know the register the
translation of it's a book where the
behavior of pupils is registered by the
teacher at school section agency the
class book has been lost
do I have to report they'll fail what is
a very good question I have to ask the
colleagues come here can somebody help
me
register lose Katrien you wanna solve
Amanda countertop truly intertube fingon
this is a clarity - in the elementary
school in the topping and
some Barbie registers who's there and
who was missing I'd say very difficult
normally I'd say okay there's no
automated data processing it's just in a
book but it's systematic its class books
the epitome of systematic order that's
right and that's full marks for Katrina
[Applause]
as additional out of Matty's year
forever I did that zone and also gdpr
does not just protect automatically
register data but all kinds of data that
are systematically collected and
completely rightly is it that the the
systematic order of information in a
class register is something you can
imagine so that is a breach that has to
be reported and if that would be a
repeated problem at the primary and
secondary school of hinter tipping and
we would have to look into that and see
if maybe we need to do something more my
fagot okay let's take the question marks
again 128 question mark hundred and
twenty-eight now that is an urn has been
washed ashore
I registered either do you like to tell
the story at a beach an urn washes
ashore and the number of the of the
cremation can be found read on the urn
is that personal data the cremation
number may be registered in some kind of
list somewhere and that might lead to
the to the name of the deceased now
captain would you like to solve this
you're conferring that is quite
perfidious videos yes I just wanted to
see if I should pass on the question to
someone who would stand a few points
with it but in some cemetery register
that is not very unique well but the
person in this urn is dead mostly that
is the case yes sir and and gdpr would
only protect living people great cutting
marks
120 points to cut him add that to the
tally that is the fact and they the gdpr
does not apply to deceased people that
is the lesson to learn from this
question next question okay let's finish
off it information so if your
information 42
it's a guesstimation question for
everybody on swab so everybody has to do
a guesstimate and the question is how
many countries in the world have Freedom
of Information Act so there is free
information I'm gonna give you there are
roughly 193 countries in the world so
the question is how many of those have
passed a feat of an Information Act
bein a strap is what one who's closest
gets the full marks shitless you might
find my octant from sake I'm gonna
choose 58 I'm gonna say Bree okay 42
what happens if I also say 42 no well
then we do a tie breaker
so for tactical reasons maybe choose 41
or 43 so he chooses 43 clear victory for
Andreas it is a hundred and thirty
you've done a boat so with your 58 you
were actually pretty bad but you're
still closest so four points for Andreas
is a category also and you may choose
the next category poke ring and using
data failed 1024 it's Castillo's maximum
fine what about if Archdiocese the
question is how I exactly is a maximum
fine for an non reported data fail beats
to lose
each named alpha you wanna solve a bully
and it a happen virtually to escape I
have an idea but I'm still gonna use my
audience Joker
I'm pretty sure that some people that
several people know the exact number
this always thought that so who can help
andreas andreas you choose million four
percent of revenue yearly revenue for
twenty million whatever is higher I'm
sorry I didn't get the number let me buy
this fresh it's both wrong my poor
sensitive it's two percent of your
yearly revenue he's laughing
Andrea's the rules are if they are you
just lost thousands and twenty four
points your own folds the maximum fine
is the so-called small fine
real bad arrows costs four percent
formal errors costs two percent of
revenue yearly revenue ten million is
the I would say this vid five yards at
swell lower limit maximally boo scared
that's one thing that's very good but
lost all points you may choose okay go
high and take 1024 again GDP are so that
is my favorite question I'm not gonna
spill it I spoil it just ask the
question when did the GDP are
come into force we would like the exact
date please the guy owns 1/6 on my 23rd
of May 2018 this is that it's quite a
good answer I would have said 25th of
May made 2018 big sounds very good but
unfortunately it's wrong 24th of May
2016 but I would have said oh oh is it
25th of May 2016 is May correct well
decide anyway it's about 2016 we are not
happy with just a year we want the exact
date one will give us the months the
other the date and the earth person the
year 21st of May would anyone else like
to lose all their points would you like
to solve this so are you going to chat
it will be in force as it is published
in the European register right and that
was in 2016 that was when the date of
the gdpr was finalized the negotiations
and it was then published in the
register of laws and that's when it came
into force it wasn't a 25th of May 2018
that was the moment when it became
effective it was in force it was out
there but it became effective at on the
25th of May 2018 we asked about the
coming into force and that in fact will
see yes now wasn't it something strange
like the 5th 45th day after publication
so that's that's nineteen nine right now
you only need to know what the fifth
45th day after application was oh come
on the 1,024 questions are extremely
hard so I would suggest that you would
not want to pass answer question yes all
right about which day in May was it it
was the 24th 24th on the 20th day after
publication in the register it was
published on the 4th of May
16th 16th or 17th of May it was passed
it comes even I say 24th of May 2000 yes
you did but you then decided not to
answer the question oh you are evil we
are the supervisors of your authority at
least you get to choose the next
question ok I'm gonna choose hackers 128
ok hacker 128 another Joker oh wow ok
are you still keeping track getting
close ok ok let's choose question marks
64 so this is about scoring and your
residential address is it allowed to use
the information that the person lives in
a high-rise building when calculating
the score value and if it's detrimental
to the score that the person gets so
these kind of scoring systems they try
to determine if you're solvent if you
can pay for your bills so there are
companies like safar that's the most
important one that creates a score and
the question now is if they calculate
the score are they allowed to take into
account the effect that they're living
in a high-rise building so for example
if someone lives in a detached house or
in a semi-detached house that's probably
a better value this location do you want
to answer I'm passing so please choose
someone who actually has asked already I
probably already have a free bed score
but I'd say in principle yes it's
probably disallowed
to choose the residential address but in
this particular case is not about your
dress itself but rather about some
property of that so in this case I'd say
yes this is something we can count yeah
it is allowed to count that information
there is another problem it's not
allowed to choose to calculate this
score with just this information if
someone thinks this is unfair please
write to the sofa so I just want to say
that I've asked the shoe for before how
they calculate the score and I'm still
waiting for the answer there is actually
very interesting they're just very
interesting ruling by the Constitutional
Court and they say that this is a trade
secret of the shoe feh and they don't
have to tell you we actually have the
open shoe portfolio and they should
actually have to they could force them
to come up with the secret and yeah this
is another one of those things where we
use fact in stat and we want to
encourage you to participate in this to
give them some some more questions that
I can ask to the state where they can
try to figure out a method for creating
this score by the sofa so andreas your
turn well there's not much left
choosing fake news 64 true or false and
why
this site adapters good for a parameter
de Clichy de new landlords have to screw
off the doorbell shields
since the gdpr has gone into effect want
Vince can landlords have to remove
Dobel shields skipped spider too much
the housing hood I can find about dr.
Burke he hung out us once we gave de
Vargas Tim does father is this correct
for not good afforded adapters conferred
with us dish obvious that's first and
finished as airship andreas says no they
don't have to be removed 64 points for
Andrea's correct other marks book minute
his double shield is still there if it
sounds silly it's not data protection
it's your turn ok I'll just take the
three question marks 23 actually there's
a exclamation mark in there to question
mark or exclamation mark 23 photos
okay we're dealing with photos again is
the audience allowed to take photos from
us of us on the stage here well
according to camp regulations come on
held on and rest would you like to
answer question I would answer yes
because we are part of a public event
with respective consent is that your
final answer
well it's only 23 points so yes I'll
stick with it I will accept that yeah
I just wanted to raise the tension a bit
yes would have been enough even if the
introduction meeting said that if you
have to ask before taking questions yes
but that is House law or House Rules
organizers can say that you can only
take a photos after you've called out
the German interior minister wholesale
help us name three times they are
allowed to do that but what is legally
permissible is another question and
legally yes of course it is allowed to
take photos of anyone you want the
question the problem only arises when
you want to distribute those photos and
that's where data protection comes in
but beforehand taking photos is fully
allowed difficult question because many
out of fear or ignorance starts to
prohibit taking photos in schools for
example and so scoot over to save you're
not allowed to take photos anymore
completely superfluous that's nothing to
do with data protection at all you can
take photos of your own children and
other people's children as long as you
don't publish them online what is
prohibited is publishing those photos
without consent by the parents for
example but the actual taking of photos
is always allowed very little too small
restriction if you somewhere photograph
of your neighbors in secret through
their bedroom window that is probably a
breach of first knowledge right but in
terms of data protection you can take
photos much you want take keep them to
yourselves you can look at them as often
as you want but as soon as you want to
publish them online you have to obtain
consent or have to have to have a
contractual basis or something like that
so we have a public event here well so
public for an entrance fee of two
hundred ninety five years I think that
is everyone well public doesn't mean it
has to be free of charge it just has to
be that people can participate on a
general basis even in a public bath
where there's an entrance fee this is a
part of a place we're talking about the
data protection law of though not about
the rights to your own
image or something that's because I'm
just giving it gaining here and
credulous glances that is the difference
between data protection law and
personality law yes we'll get to almost
the end we have two questions left is
your turn to choose no matter how much I
get right now you're still ahead of me
so I'll choose hacker 23 so that's hot
meerschaum oh we had that one okay how
is that possible must be a bug so I
guess I'll choose fake news genifique
news transition how much room is inside
each part okay so we save ten now just
to get the point okay true or false and
why so close the thing of data is only
valid with the consent of the person
affected so is this statement correct if
I am using the data from some third
party do I need their consent do you
want to solve andreas so I wish it was
but obviously it's not right because Xu
Fei wouldn't exist otherwise so yes
answer correct 23 points one is score so
consent is an important basis but not
always there is a legitimate reason for
example if you waive your rights in a
contractual form so consent is one but
it's not a the central or even the most
important one so that was the second
round and this is the moment where we
have to say goodbye to two people so
let's look at the scoreboard so andreas
has how many points now
yes 164 please applaud some fun so how
many does muesli have what that's so
important 110 that's less but still
worthy of an applause so how many does
catch a nap over 9000 over 9000 632 yeah
it looks like you can stay here and how
many does Holly have 92 I'm sorry that's
not enough so that's why we have to say
goodbye to muesli and Ollie with the
warm applause you getting a consolation
prize stay there you're gonna come come
back on stage later now to the final of
the two first contestants top
contestants of the first of the second
row of the second round the pumped idiot
points that you're going to get in the
last round are going to be multiplicator
multiplicator pooja OD black
multiplicator boom that has been to kind
of poke the mast but the MFE have no
points which thousands extra panel is
typically and here's one
he gets his result so the first points
to win the first point isn't very
interesting and then it's going
to be interesting item oh okay you're
gonna turn off both so completes yet see
it's not so complicated
okay you go both going to be asked my
especially about what kind of video
surveillance are there most complaints
so video which of these draws the most
complaints it a pools be of employees
see in private houses the on cemeteries
enjoy us your choice you choose be
employees catherine chooses see in
private houses see is correct
cotton is one point because most of us
vanish beard Yuba it's really like that
most complaints about video surveillance
that we get is that I surveyed my
neighbor and either they survey back or
they go to the police complain
absolute LSD reforms country is very
difficult for us as well it's vital
August read a second question and that
again is a video question
[Music]
my god
hello mr. Maya say when I was still in a
patrol car
I can only tell you the bends great and
now do you know what I do now now I'll
ask I'm now going to ask about number
plates and this woman I am NOT going to
let this great woman pass me by one or
two time only chance so I'm now going to
query that number plate in my database
okay now this fake police person here
this fake policeman wasn't ignored
father what is the exact question right
we are dealing with a policeman who has
seen a fantastic woman on in his patrol
and she was in a car with a lamb plate
and he memorized the number plate and
now he has access to the police database
and he goes ahead and looks up the
number plate to find out the name of
that lady the residence maybe contact
details such as mobile phone number and
goes ahead and the question in that
context is is that police person
policeman allowed to do this and what
happens to them to him if he goes ahead
and does it now it's Kathleen's turn to
start first is he allowed no no no well
he's a policeman police databases are
made for police men yes they're made for
police people if they have a task a case
to process and if they are authorized to
look at that data I'm sure that he's not
investigating this woman
and the interest does not count but
maybe she went around the bend in
illegal booze but he didn't say that
true what would happen to him well
trouble with the authorities protection
commissioner and the federal state data
protection commissioner and a fine laugh
at us oh and Jace what do you think is
he loud and what would happen of course
not that was in the press recently and
he will receive a fine
nice good you're both correct a point to
both of you applause by the way
according to the GDP our regulation that
was actually a point of contest that
anyone in public service for example for
at least people if it's allowed to give
them a fine or not a lot of people were
of the opinion that this is impossible
but some others also said yeah it is and
offered in this case the police person
received a fine of 1500 years because he
had interest in the person that was not
within the course of the duty and as a
police person they're always allowed to
use their respective databases but as a
private person they're not so two points
one for each of you
it was a question yeah who actually
supervises this so yeah partly us the
question is how do we get notice of this
or how would we suspect this in this
particular case for example if the woman
notices that the person that the police
guy is watching here what how is he able
to call me on my private number they
shouldn't be able to know it and by now
we can talk about this quite openly so
by now the police
databases are now watched with a sort of
a honeypot every access is logged and we
do superficial checks on all of the
requests that are being done maybe every
hundred or so request is looked at
they're supervised by an internal data
protection officer at the police and
they try to determine if it was an
official case that they were working on
or if they had private reasons to do so
and this actually works quite well those
areas there are no accesses on these
databases anymore that are not being
logged which is great because in this
particular context this is very
important and very sensible to do so to
the one for Katherine maybe Dan what's
this is a bug very hot that one today
this but vary over time anyway so we're
gonna just pass on to the next question
yeah no SOC fault is the wrong question
we had that that's the right one
mr. Kalba I'm the federal Commissioner
for data protection and information
protection my question what is the
maximum fine that a federal agency can
be fined
does anyone remember Mr ba-ba-ba-ba it's
schnell mr. Schwaab you was after all so
in the previous game show again what's
the maximum fine
that the federal agency it can has to
pay o0 kathleen answers none Reyes says
the same no I've some ideas personnel
fund what it would make more sense to
act against the personally responsible
person to correct answers three to two
for Katrina a bit of background for the
last question Alex hop in George offices
just as I mean agencies just as
corporations can be fined but several
states have decreed that agencies cannot
defined in other nations in Europe
there's different agencies can be fine
in Germany no way to find a federal
agency okay and now we're back with our
actor okay yeah of course I know I
cannot
but a little much mr. mayor you have
this website there's a legal problem
second problem the mayor wants to
evaluate the website statistics how many
men access our website how many women
you can do all kinds of analytics I
don't quite know so can I use an
analysis tool on my website asks the
mayor I think there's a large search
engine there us-based isn't do we need a
consent for this or can we just run this
please ask your husband who knows all
the technical details what is the legal
status
I just don't know maybe your husband
knows something that will be nice if you
could ask him right now you are the
husband of the colleague of this guy
could someone translate that was
Southwest German dialect and yes that
was hard for the interpreters to
understand - I have it in better audio
quality but I didn't manage to get it
worked into the video and then cut
edited okay three questions it's about
whether google analytics can be used and
in this case can Google Analytics be
used by a an authority the one that this
guy works for that is the first question
shall we go through all three yes the
second question is is an enterprise
allowed to use Google Analytics and
thirdly even what if it is allowed would
these organizations have to adhere to
SEO turn first question is a Authority
and author allowed to use Google index
I'll say no really and also to the
second question enterprises used allow
to use Google Analytics now again
all right and third question that's what
they have to adhere to what they have to
look out for well if they would do you
use this they would have to remove the
IP address the last two bytes of it at
least that's what I know from pivec but
it's google antics it's clear that
Google will not do this that's why I'm
saying no so to knows and response from
cuddling
authorities are completely agree no it's
just not on and enterprises yes they can
use Google Analytics but they should
take care to use these anonymizing
variants where the last two bytes are
made anonymous or pseudo and of course
they have to include this into in their
privacy statement and they have to state
a legal foundation which they do this
but in my opinion this does not require
consent it will be legitimate interest
would be enough good either how would we
score this zero points both cases I'll
be quick so what is correct authorities
are not allowed you can explain that
better than I can authorities would need
a legal foundation what would be
possible would be consent by the
visitors of a Authority website all
those that are affected by the
measurement of the website reach but
consent is excluded because according to
the legal foundation and a consent will
not give me any further legitimate
interest 6 111 is not a grounds for
processing so that's the end of that so
that's what you two said that's correct
so far our Enterprise is allowed yes
well it's always possible to obtain
consent but that would have to be
informed consent would have to be
voluntary that's not often the case of
third question other isn't it first
allowed yes but and thirdly what has to
be taken care of and we have a great FAQ
on our website regarding this which you
will find if you use this large search
engine to lose
look for tracking in websites only six
items just a few pages and that tells
you what companies have to take care of
if they use Google Analytics and its
simplest answer is just don't bother use
something where you don't need all this
stuff such as Matt homo or Mitama is the
successors of paraffin P week right yes
exactly so how's the data yourselves the
statistical data that you want to
collect and don't pass it on to the
third party if you use Google Analytics
in the Google ethics standard settings
you need informed voluntary active
previous and retractable consent by the
users it's not it will not suffice what
you see on many websites if you continue
using this website you will consent to
the use of cookies I have never seen a
cookie banner that will keep those five
conditions first informed team you'd
have to be told
are you do you agree that all the
everything you do on this website is
going to be transformed to transfer to
Google or whoever operates this service
I've never seen saving like that active
no tracking is not before you've said
yes voluntary it must be possible to
answer yes and no retractable you have
to be able to rescind your consent to
take back your consent previous
voluntary active what did I forget one
thing I forgot so these are the
obstacles it's all in the FAQ on our
website and that is the position of the
Supervisory authorities so none of you
and answered all three questions
correctly it's still a three to two
school and that gives us a winner for
tonight and that's cut in
you know sleep Millau yes do stand-up
will now go to the awarding ceremony I'd
like to ask the two colleagues muesli
and Ollie back to the stage because
they'll be actually there were prizes
Kathleen first of all there's this
fantastic certificate now that's why
number two you can enter your own names
there Ollie would you pass it on and
number four and then cut in you will win
the original south-southwest Germans
maybe in Malton soup whatever multitude
are and there is no ventilator to you
and Reza and lots of materials from the
lead from from the Data Protection
Commissioner and and then that same
speciality in chocolate form and gift
from the Porsche company which you can
exchange I would say yes thanks a lot to
all people that participated left we
overrun drastically but now it's over
short remark for me I would like to make
we have this wonderful protection
principle of transparency in the GD P R
and you will it wouldn't will not have
escaped you that I know some stuff I
don't know that much about a crypto I do
data protection
professionally as a lawyer yes sorry
it's not excluded but I have tried to be
as fair as possible and passed a few
questions on and I didn't answer
everything correctly so even lawyers can
be wrong so lawyers are always right or
legal people always read that wasn't
true anyway it was the wrong answer so
but the questions were extremely good I
would really like to thank you this was
great Kathleen now you'll have to live
with that victory thanks to all of you
to all that took part however and I will
thank you to everyone that you have
staked with us a song and have fun in
the next few years
with all these beautiful failures gdpr
wise and will keep reporting about them
have a great time
[Music]
you