[Music]
we're gonna talk about how to produce
hydrogen by using this fusion reactor
that is always hovering above us and how
that works
stoma will show us please applaud him
[Applause]
yeah good model yeah good morning oh all
right
that's a communist Oliver sighs sorry
welcome thanks good that you're all
awake I'm a chemist I have worked with
organic chemistry with biochemistry and
lately with physical and
electrochemistry I wrote a master's
thesis at the Hamilton home in Berlin
Ramsey and there I dealt with this
subject how to find materials to produce
to solve the energy problems of the
future so short agenda
how many agenda do we need per year I'm
going to go over some basics I'm not
going to dive deep some chemistry and
physics from school will be useful some
of you may remember the basics then
we'll look the well-known silicon
photovoltaic cells that are spread over
this over this cam then you need to
store the energy somehow I'm going to
talk about that shortly and then how to
couple this way with a new class of
materials so a bra neck 9 so
um doesn't spire doesn't slide these are
two diagrams from rocket egg
it is a council group for academia and
technology architect that is this pie
chart on the left looks like we have
only two percent solar energy some part
of renewable energy but most of it's
still from fossil fuels and on the right
side we see a diagram from the BP annual
reports BP you know them refueling
station the oil producer they write a
report on energy consumption every year
and you see this spike downwards pretty
well 2008 2009 when the world financial
crisis was and the changed went up back
again and now we have an increase in
energy consumption of 3 percent per year
which is a a three-year high and on the
right we see that the carbon dioxide
emissions have also increased so this
climate change thing is everywhere
everybody's talking about it and it's
time that even more people talk about it
here's the change over the years
consumption of primary energy the
composition is on the top coal then in
orange the renewable energies then we
have hydroelectricity the the bright
orange is nuclear energy then gas and in
green oil megatron calculation is in
megatons oil equivalent mt OE do you
believe that is the usual unit
and these are 166 petawatt hours - as a
recall pata is the one unit after Tara
so thousand terawatt-hours or 19 Tara
what years per year so you could you
could cross it out
the earth has a rated power of 19
terawatt Hong Kong has one our embassy
meow thankfully a lot more comes from
the energy from the Sun 179 petawatt so
more or less in fact 10,000 more
that's a graphic from NASA originally
the incoming radiation ninja in yellow
and the different ways how this
radiation is reflected going back to the
universe or staying on the ground 89
petawatt arrive at the ground that's
more than enough to cover all the demand
here's a repetition the more orange you
see on the map the more intense the Sun
radiation is that is average over the
year and the black dots are some spaces
with high radiation for example North
America the Great Basin Nevada desert or
South America atacama desert Sahara
Desert and these black dots alone would
cover those with solar panels would
cover the whole energy demand of the
world what is actually reaching us
that's the spectral intensity of
sunlight remember from school this
theory with black body radiation that is
the yellow curve and the orange curve is
the actually measured radiation outside
of the atmosphere inside the atmosphere
it's a little bit different that is the
lower curve
but you see the the the rainbow it's the
visible spectrum is it not just desert
and these notches that you can see are
actually filled filtered by water gas in
the atmosphere water has several
absorption bands and the right side of
the graphic they absorb radiation from a
price that has already been considered
in the diagram we just saw before which
also means that the more arid your
region is the less clouds you have the
harder it will be in the oceans on the
land and this whole story will run even
faster young standardize all of this the
atmospheric mass model has been
developed we place we have different
details different level of details so
the first approximation is the earth I'm
tell of the other I'll put a plate on
the earth you see where does it go back
in the atmosphere in the right angle and
the angle between the Sun and this
reflection is the presented angle
divided and then the atmosphere will be
passed only once if you go a bit more to
the north or to the south then even at
12 o'clock at summer solstice the Sun
will enter in an angle that is the a.m.
1.5 that's the usual radiation force in
Europe and northern America the in the
Stila now and because that's the
industry industrial countries that has
been used as a standard for measurements
but more to the north that would be 60
degrees Scandinavia for example that's a
m2 this equivalent for means that the
equivalent of 2 atmosphere thicknesses
are being traversed by the vital
radiation and if you see the Sun just
above the horizon at 90 degrees
in the more detailed models that is in
38 fold atmosphere penetration and of
course in the in space that is Ames ero
because there's no atmosphere at all so
you cannot wait until summer solstice to
make your measurements when there's
absolutely no clouds so that means in
the lab you mean you need a Sun
simulator that is the device
I made my measurements with you see in
the left side the control PC that's
where all the electronics is put in in
the middle is the measurement cell and
on the right this black L is the light
source here let's see it in detail the
white thing is the electrochemical cell
wires go to the mass electronics
measurement electronics and on the right
we have an aperture in order to go from
dark to clear quickly and on the right
we have X in on light that you also have
in cars these super clear bright bluish
lights arc Sanon lights why do we take
them well we need to model the Sun
spectrum pretty efficiently if you take
incandescent lamps then you reach 3000
3500 Kelvin you know the light
temperature that is exactly that data
and that orange thing is the Sun
spectrum and there you see that the blue
parts are just not well represented and
therefore you need that bluish light and
it is modulated with filters in order to
reach this equivalent of the intensity
in the cell about solar cells we've all
seen them before the shadow widths and
arrive at silicon and this is split into
their flat wafers I have sustained
you reach these glittering
polycrystalline solar cells at the mono
crystal like in the chip industry vain
hyperbole but in solar cells you luckily
don't need this high purity like you
need on ships in industry you usually
need about 99.999 degrees of purity and
solar industry you 99.5 are enough so
you can work with very simple processes
so how does the current come out of this
moody on the left hand side you see a
model a silicon semiconductor and the
solar cell the bluish part is the one
irradiated by Sun and the red one is the
actual material which you don't see you
and in between the electrical current
runs silicon solar cells this is 0.6 to
0.7 volts and the radiation intensity
determines how much current you get out
of the solar cell so if there's a cloud
above it gets darker and of course
eventually the current and voltage drop
down on the right hand side we see what
this cell actually absorbs the dark one
is the Sun spectrum that comes into the
cell the yellowish curve is the actually
used part of the spectrum in between you
see the bandgap at a temperature of 300
Kelvin yeah
which corresponds to the base state of
the valence band it's going up to the
state of the conducting band and the gap
in between is the actual band gap which
you can deduct as a voltage so the
energy is calculated by H times nu which
is a blank column times the irradiation
frequency which is also corresponding to
the color of the incoming light
so here the orange region is the visible
light up till infrared spectrum and then
there's a shot
nice nails guys on in school but we just
due to the energy of the incoming
photons not being sufficient anymore to
actually bridge the gap into the
conduction band so this light simply
isn't absorbed oh it's going to be
interesting later in the talk because
this is actually the upper limit
regarding efficiency that we can get out
of our solar cells because otherwise the
material simply can't catch the photons
anymore so here we have the bore at a
model which explains the atom as divided
into the core and the shell so here's an
excitation from a second to the third
shell sending out a quantum of light and
this is exactly what we want regarding
solar cells so there's a photon coming
in and there's an energy excitation
sending out and generating a voltage
difference which is what we can use in
our solar cells simple path models in
this case magnesia wouldn't the the
electron tire diseases and see that all
atoms in my compound share the electrons
the so-called covalent binding which
forms the valence band
that's highest of the conduction band is
only slightly above this valence band so
with only a little push in energy to the
electrons which they can already assume
at room temperature the electrons can
freely move and electronic conductivity
is established however which is silicon
which is the semiconductor
exactas lightning sponge quasi detect on
valence band runner in a matter that
again the valence and conduction bands
are very close to each other and the
band gap is sufficient however in a
nonconductor the conduction band is too
far away so no light and no electrical
energy is sufficient to get the
electrons into the conduction band
they're stuck with their atom cores and
the materials not kind
would diesel and the average of these
two is the semiconductor where the
bandgap is in the region below
approximately four electron volts which
roughly corresponds to ultraviolet light
and a bit lower corresponding to a
yellowish shade so silicon has a band
gap of about 1.2 electron volts which
corresponds to the infrared spectrum of
light is a in a given a little electron
void as all this energy is usually
expressed in electron volts which is
that elementary charge times the voltage
that was obtained by this charge
absolutely now everybody should have
heard about this concept tags is known
however what happens if we get
semiconductor into direct contact with
water
is these electron demons so photo
electrochemical cells can detect
actually conduct wouldn't electrons
directly into water so not by an outer
circuit but rather directly into water
splitting the water into hydrogen oxygen
by that omitting an outer circuit which
would of course cause losses in
efficiencies on besar so the one point
two or three electron volts we see is
the Braddock's potential of water which
is a minimum potential it has to be
surmounted in order to start this
process those red arrows are the so
called over potentials the false so in
the band gap we ideally need to split
water into hydrogen oxygen would be
approximately higher than 1.8 electron
volts
considering the over potentials as well
as does detect heat and we saw so far
that we obtained no material that was
actually able to perform this right away
so we had to introduce some tricks
mustard seller to do this schematic of a
photo electrochemical
14 comprising two half-cells so the
light enters the blue layer on the right
hand side these are very thin layers in
the region of 10 to 20 nanometers in the
minimal case or up to 100 nanometers in
a thicker case but then we have
stability issues in Elektra lutein
warszawa and the Rays transcend a
membrane which in this case is
water-based and arrive on the other side
on the red photocathode with the light
that still reaches the other the red
side can start the process of splitting
the water so the electrodes kind of
share the work and only the one
electrode has to surmount the work to
provide the electrons for these
processes the Undong button lighter also
Moomba lighted electrons are conducted
via an outer conductor coming back to
the photo a note in for exact is a
photovoltaic cell oh I'm sorry they come
back to the photo cathode via this
other's outer circuit bus is Okazaki
Vulcan who the energy but then we also
said we need higher energies than 1.2
electron volt much they are hot good we
have higher energies and a larger band
gap in a material understand only
high-energy radiation is absorbed
everything below it gets lost so it's
only used for example ultraviolet or
green light so what do we do with the
remaining radiation we just send it into
the next cell so from the left-hand side
the full spectrum light would reach a
yellowish photocatalytic material then
performs the first part of the active
reaction and the remaining irradiation
reaches the material behind the
yellowish part which is maybe then in
the reddish yellow spectrum and on the
back side it just reaches a
photovoltaic cells how it is highest
dusters on the right-hand side the image
is mirrored but the general it shows the
same processes the full-spectrum light
excites as many electrons as it can
everything else that doesn't manage to
do that shines through end of silicon
material reaches the silicon solar cell
and does its normal work so it's a kind
of tandem solar cell working together as
a compound Menken about sang-man tight
isn't functional bye-bye in spite time
so we're actually parting this orange
region into two parts the higher energy
part on the left hand side is absorbed
by photochemical material and the rest
the remains for the silicon solar cell
it was even if it's by water by
starvation a simple cost yeah this
material on the right hand side is
marked by fe2o3
which is simply in the breast it's just
corroded I usually use metal oxides
because they're very practical they're
stable they're widely available
MIPS but the problem is of course in the
periodic table of elements there's like
50 60 metals and then we're running out
of possibilities for materials you know
lots of work that's in fire so what are
the materials could we use below the
yellowish part this one is marked as
smooth vanadium and oxygen coming out so
on the script it's my country and if we
calculate how many actual combinations
of metal oxides we could have we end up
in the four digit region so we have a
lot of experimental grounds on which to
try which materials and which
combination of elements could be
suitable for these processes because of
course they all have different band gaps
they all absorb different energies and
could be more or less suitable for the
aim of
bring water Jordan in a steamer Medeiros
by Hume going back to energy storage
this is an excerpt from Agora and a
given tour energy transition report
marking the German wide energy
consumption over one and a half months
is the purple curve in the middle is the
most interesting one over so it's
actually the pink one which is the
demand for energy come on Ashley Indian
bhai does the energy in again on the
first of May we actually entered the
region that regenerative energies would
have been able to actually cover the
whole demand fact once worked I realize
that that can be put down to different
factors so of course we had a different
very high Sunday radiation it was a
public holiday in Germany so with a
quite lower energy demand and for the
first time we found this inversions that
could have actually just been able to
shut down conventional power plants and
use the renewables instead enjoyment of
inertial limousine one of the
applications would be simple
electrolysis everyone might probably
have seen this in their chemical essence
so we put in electricity in the water
and split it into its components
hydrogen oxygen which works quite well
in principle unfortunately the most
effective alert codes in this context
are platinum electrodes so platinum is
the material that very much is most
efficient in spreading water perform a
electrolysis so me tired of the Olivia
motors also not as rare as metals like
iridium for instance both divers in ones
are modern electronic which for instance
also components of our modern electronic
devices these are an order of magnitude
rarer
the man gets dim process in ainít
sailors on board however if we all three
concepts that I mentioned within one
photo active cell type like I said which
means generating a stack of three
different semiconducting materials which
absorb different colors marked by blue
green and red here in this case in
viagra Deanna Givaudan conducting in
series are setting up a series on and
immersed in water then we actually have
a cell which can split water into
hydrogen and oxygen by only being
irradiated by light ensign yet does
video by me raw fish
so on my screen the video doesn't work
as bluebirds have for one can out a
smashed exciting there's bubbles this is
actually or what I want to show in this
video there are class of the Lincoln
site is the site of our stuff so the
circle on the left hand side is where
hydrogen is developing I'm still Asakusa
you know that stock geometrically the
bubbles have to be larger one of the
anxiety is this is covered with platinum
and on the other side on the right hand
side we have Racine iam
oxide on the electrode which is also
quite rare metal and one of the only
oxides that are actually able to
catalyze the oxygen reduction reaction
or oxidation reaction in this case in a
very good way and sort of two systems in
Viera decisis in general about oxygen
needs a kind of conviction how to via
participate in this reaction which of
course we want to reduce because the
over potential time supplied current is
an electrical power output which we lose
in this case in the reaction
I guess this everybody has seen in
school as well that's a kind of
biological cell the chlorophyll in the
nature the same principle first call for
absorbs light of a first wavelength
it's excited then over this step that
you see in the next it D deactivates a
little bit then on the second
photosystem it is really excited I think
it gets a harder push and the energy of
the second photo system is strong enough
to push the following reaction and carry
out the photosynthesis in the plant so
that's also that would be the global the
big picture I hope that you have more
questions than before that from foolish
Danna and I would like to answer some of
those
[Applause]
so you can't ask a you know you know the
drill there's two microphone angels one
on the left one on the right if least go
see them if you have questions if you're
in the stream you have lost because
there's no signal angel I'm very sorry
oh hi how is it with efficiencies and
the wear and tear of the materials that
are being used now that's a good point
silicon solar cells while the
theoretical limit is 30 to 33 percent
from thermodynamics in practice the best
cells have a bit more than 20% the
super-expensive for military and space
applications have 25% the electrolysis
behind depending on how good inexpensive
the catalysts are 70 80 maybe 90 percent
and that means in the sum we have 15 20
% stop in this stack cell where we saw
the video there was the efficiency
written next it 9.5% that is pretty good
but I mean these materials deliver
efficiencies we're talking about the
solar to hydrogen efficiency as th my
since that is usually be below 1%
sometimes maybe 1 points or 2 point
something percent there's a lot to do
and the stability also good point is
generally I mean in the process the
materials being corroded in general we
bring on passivation layers to enhance
the lifetime so in the lab we reach
lifetimes of a week or something like
that and usually that is already good
but sometimes within minutes they get
decomposed so we need to look at these
thousands of combinations of which
material works has good efficiency and
isn't Ditka posts within minutes another
question from that side I saw in the
media that apparently a come
has developed a prisoner to use the non
- to shift the unusable part of the
light spectrum into the usable part well
for me that sounds like frequent
doubling there are nonlinear optics of
you has already seen a green laser
pointer I'm or less everybody that's
actually an infrared laser that is being
sent through this nonlinear optics which
sends out everything that is green but
it only works very selectively for
narrow spectrum so I don't know if that
is actually what you mean but otherwise
the convert the color yeah I don't know
a process that can do that and I don't
know how efficient that would be in
these green laser pointers have a
terrible efficiency from electrical
power to light hey let's move on a small
question is a big question small
question is how necessarily Clee how
clean does the water need to be I guess
that if you take just tap water in large
quantities that after some time the
catalysts will be dirty or something
like this botanic you generally don't
want to clean the water with a lot of
energy I guess and the other question
once can we imagine molecules that are
specially engineered named one to absorb
light and split water into hydrogen and
oxygen
I mean if we had that molecule we could
maybe create a DNA strand that we can
put into bacteria and then engineer
bacterias in order to conceive carry out
for that electrolysis or that
photosynthesis that splits water widely
open versions wide enough we're so far
in the technology question and regarding
water purity well
I've only dealt with lab setups so we
have ultra pure water which is called
milli poor has super low conductivity
almost none impurities inside because
the problem is we're talking about redox
chemistry so if other redox active
materials are implied salt metals lead
copper they are also being reduced and
oxidized electro chemically Syngenta you
will be dropping copper or lead you can
poison your material with that yeah
inside that's fine man and in doubt you
drop your efficiency talking about
filters and partake particles yeah you
don't want them so you need to filter
your stuff I can't tell you more detail
about that unfortunately regarding the
second question yeah there is such
things that's called Gretl cell somebody
worked on it and received the Nobel
Prize there was organic colorants on a
conductive support which was then
excited and the electrons were lad
offered there was a big hit for us
sometime I don't know how that has
developed for today it's a very special
man service you can do that at home to
make that work it's pretty simple
I mean organic colorant something like
can do that with with fruit he actually
is long off that doesn't live for a long
time also here this the incoming light
excites the molecules but they wear out
and don't work after sometimes when I
don't know how the practical
applications look like okay 10 minutes
left
who wants to ask a question maybe from
the left mic da you want you know
there's somebody standing up I might as
microphone unbidden yeah this is true
not exact it skipped there is this
combination of solar cells and fuel
cells seems only to be working in the
lab there's a lot of talk about I mean
you can just take solar cells and then
own the branch of the hint solar fuel
cell behind it to produce just just a
break you mean fuel cell or electrolysis
I mean electrolysis fuel cell comes
afterwards to use the hydrogen yeah
exactly that's a whole other chapter but
yeah my question is you see how it's the
Tigra from bow that is state-of-the-art
isn't it is that much more inefficient
or why do you want to go to this direct
coupling is the citation on that and how
far are we still in the future that's a
very good question probably a couple of
years ahead you know that solar power or
renewable power to electrolysis is being
done today the problem is on the one
hand it's half of course before of curve
off and I put up this slide sand to
silicon to solar cell it seems easy but
needs a lot of energy Ziya good thoughts
a very well researched process mostly
because the chip industry that had big
interest in to that but the production
from solar cells needs a lot of energy
and the amortization times are somewhere
in the domain of two three four or five
years until the solar cell has
compensated harvested the amount of
energy it has cost to produce being
produced on yachts in the lifetimes are
in the domain of decades 20 25 30 years
easily and that means
that afterlife time they still perform
80 85 percent of their energy so one
argument would be you can save the
energy to produce silicon from silicon
silicon dioxide the metal oxides are
already energy low materials how you
know that iron is resting because Ross
is a lower energy level than metallic
iron so the idea would be you get the
raw materials more easily
well silicon is one of the most frequent
materials we have in most abundant
materials we have the crust of the earth
the idea is we want to produce all of
that with less energy the next point is
that electrolysis is only working
efficiently and well if you have these
expensive valuable material catalysts
noble material catalysts so you can
lower the system costs instead of
building a solar farm and then an
electrolyzer and you have to maintain
them so that would be a possibility to
save money but how well that will be in
the end we will see next you know him
and does anyone else want to ask a
question of lighting this insights we
were working on a frog referral maybe to
bridge some time I have a question for
Diamond active and as Ohana kismet does
anyone do active research on these
materials so is there any working groups
you know that maybe simulate or just try
these kinds of materials out yes for its
for instance my working group so indeed
this very contemporary topic and it's
one that has been done by very excellent
research groups Diwali under a
stationary mission there's also the
variant of quantum chemically simulating
Mankins similar to these materials on
very big cluster one done upset since
okay to calculate the band gaps of these
materials and determine whether they
actually exhibit the properties that
we're looking for but actually I don't
know what the state of the art in this
respect is but in order to do this sighs
Lee we have to invest a lot of
calculations power and energy and it
could still be that theory doesn't
really match reality in this respect or
that the material works and has the
property that we desire but then
degrades and doesn't exhibit the
lifetime that we wish for so it's really
the literal search for the needle in the
haystack it's about the human taken
strong wish for a body detecting so
that's okay we talked about directly you
direct electrolysis and changing the
electricity into water electrolysis many
of you have Merton mingwan masam as a de
Conti fashionista gansan talked about
the amorous cancer camp long as of us
so I could talk about this for the whole
camp but are there any alternative
processes to actually perform this yes
for instance bioenergy mice so for
instance Lansing sushi indeed on in BO
disease for instance corn crops and
changing them into by ethanol and by
reactors which is also the refueling
station discussion this is actually
being done but I don't have the total
efficiency in mind I think however that
it's not very big just a few percent in
Manaus
and also of course we then compete
against our own nutrition generation the
planet I emitted this topic on therapist
for instance some spike and some neem -
mind it's from nuts importance is
hydroelectric storages this I omitted
and purpose because it's another very
big topic shadows fresh that's for the
electrode Lucinda here
vas Alchemist what is the zonin energy
but what for instance is also done is to
directly to focus in on damage translate
solar energy under water just evaporate
water and then drive turbines whither
which is for insistent in Spain or in
Sahara Desert honey time but otherwise I
don't have any spontaneous idea about
other couple processes
I'm pehangi know so we have room for a
couple more questions okay is it get
done good Dunn's another good douche
cook-off ok so everyone is heated up and
let's thank our speaker again you have
listened to the talk
[Music]
you