[Music]
introduce you in the next talk it's
gonna be by Eunice Geisler he's going to
talk about power 2x and dive a little
bit into carbon capturing and
utilization so I'm especially interested
in this since you know our planet is
burning and we're trying really hard to
save it so I hope
Yanis can give us some hints about how
that might be possible so please give a
warm welcome to Jonas thank you yeah hi
a warm welcome from my side as well to
my talk and yeah as already announced I
will talk about how to make things from
electricity or power tricks and the
outline of my talk is first what is the
idea behind power 2x and what does this
mysterious X might stand for then I want
to talk about carbon capture and
utilization like a group of techniques
which fall under this large word of
power tweaks then I want to talk about
the energy sector a little and the
chemistry sector so where this could be
applied and and why this might make
sense to do this so in the hopefully
very near future
so yeah the phrase power to eeks
basically the idea is when we're
generating renewable energy we produce
at certain times sufficient electricity
at certain times not sufficient
electricity and at other times surplus
electricity and this surplus electricity
the idea was what to do with it like we
have it we have it as a resource do
something with it and there is where the
first word you will find when you're
searching for word power to X terms
comes into the game which is the trivial
solution which is sorry power - well you
so make something valuable and we will
see later on that
the idea of using surplus energy won't
be enough but that's basically the idea
by the way power in that case usually is
electricity so not that you're confused
power refers always to to to electricity
then when we got this idea like power -
well you we can ask us the question like
what do we need and there comes the next
group of terms we can use into play and
the first one I want to present you is
power - power so now you might think
that's stupid
we have power why should we do something
to make power but that's basically
referring to all the energy storage
things like storing to make the grid
stable 4 times where we don't have
sufficient electricity supply and use it
then the next is heat heat is one of the
main fields besides electricity where we
put energy in so why not make heat with
that power third one mobility same thing
we have a certain field where we need a
lot of energy let's bring electricity to
that field
the next thing chemicals that will be
something I will talk a lot about
because carbon capture and utilization
is mainly about chemicals
yeah can we use that electricity to
produce chemicals in a efficient way and
in a renewable way and the last term one
might find is food in that field one
might find more terms but this is
basically what is the most common so
maybe we can also use it to produce some
food yeah now we have our needs in the
basics the question is now what products
can we actually make and they would come
to a very often hurt term power to gas
this mainly refers to methane and
hydrogen where we have another terms
power to maintain power to hydrogen
so let's produce gases which are storing
energy for us and we can apply them for
certain
very similar power to fuel or power to
liquid which is essentially the same
like when referring to fuels by that
term we very often think of liquid fuels
and when referring of liquids we very
often think of a fuel application so
that's that's rather similar and the
next one would be soon gas soon gas is
the mixture of carbon monoxide and
hydrogen which is very often used in
chemical industry so I will talk about
that later power to sin gas
yeah is what's meant with that you can
find power to ammonia ammonia is one of
the chemicals we are producing in very
large scale and which is very energy
demanding we're burning a lot of fossil
fuels to fuels to make ammonia and the
last one I want to show you is protein
which is a rather interesting idea as
well to make proteins directly using
that energy by some some chemistry now
how they are interconnected so all these
three energy applications refer mainly
to gas and fuel a little too soon gas
the chemicals of course like when we're
speaking of chemical products that's all
chemistry and food as many ammonia do to
virtualize a production and protein but
I won't talk too much about food ammonia
and and proteins I will mention ammonia
at some certain point but that's not the
focus of the talk now is that new and I
would say no that's just like modern bus
wording cause power to power we have
since a long time this is a hydro pump
station from the 30s power to heed you
might know such devices from your
grandparents power to mobility you this
is a bus from the 40s and power to
chemicals this is a chloral karlie
electrolyzers of producing chlorine gas
and sodium hydroxide solution from the
1920s so we have power to whatever
already the thing is just in times of
climate change and an increasing amount
of renewable energy it becomes more
interest
and new technologies could be
implemented but the general power to
something terms are nothing really new
now coming more to carbon capture and
utilization what we are doing in our
energy sector usually is we take fossil
carbon then we make some fuels out of it
we make one of those fields of energy we
are using and in the end we end up with
a co2 and water if we think of the
chemical sector we're doing the same
we're making commodity chemicals so like
the large-scale chemicals produced in in
really Megaton scale worldwide and from
those we producing all the fancy
products we have around us and at the
end of the light hopefully we burn them
or we degrade them to see you two in
water because if we don't do that we end
up with waste which is even more
problematic usually so this is very
linear we're coming from fossil fuels
and we commit going to see you two in
water and I guess that's not very new to
you but carbon capture and utilization
now means that I'd capture this co2 and
water again and I utilize it and make
exactly that fuels and commodity
chemicals to have a circle like no more
co2 should be produced but we're just
driving it in a circle very important
from the beginning we are not reducing
co2 as long as we're not producing way
more products as the products are
already there and we're just bringing
new products we're just lowering the
amount of new co2 emitted to make that
clear a lot of startups say something
like negative co2 emissions by carbon
capture and utilization you need to
really look into the detail if they
store somewhere the carbon or if they
really do yeah calm capture and
utilization and then they usually have
no negative emissions but I come to that
later again as well now this looks nice
but till now it's a perpetual mobile air
so of course we need to put in the
renewable energy
and we could either do that directly by
putting it into the energy sectors and
using this energy there or we could just
drive that cycle around by putting it
into capturing co2 from point sources we
can't avoid or from the dye from the air
around us which is a little more
complicated because the concentration is
very low but still possible and also
possible on a large scale and in the end
hopefully we get rid of this fossil
carbon but just having this cycle
ongoing when we look at exactly the same
thing from another point of view we come
to for example this energy scale and we
see different carbon products and the
and oxygen combined have a certain
energy level stored within the chemical
bonds and what we usually do when we
when we burn them which happens at a
certain point well as I said we kicked
them over the activation barrier and
then we throw them all the way down the
hill till we end up with co2 and water
which is really what for chemists to
tune water's quite stable so we're
really down at the bottom of the energy
somehow which is good because we wanted
to get this energy out of the reaction
but which also is a problem because now
we need to bring that back up again and
the question is how could we do that how
does that work
can we just heat up co2 and water and
all our nice products fall out again
that's sadly not that easy and at first
I want to talk about techniques which
are already like have a technology
readiness level very high so which are
could be implemented in in large-scale
reactions kind of already like minor
optimizations still needed but but we
could do that today and therefore we
take apart the the water and the co2
part
the first step we make water
electrolysis just to remind you like
water electrolysis you put two
electrodes into a salt solution you
apply electricity and from the anode you
will have oxygen Evolvin and from the
cathode you will have hydrogen involving
so far so easy like for chemists we know
that optimizing that is not that easy
but it's known technology we can still
make it better but it's out there so now
we have hydrogen and oxygen like we
already produce the oxygen we put in in
the beginning now we want to have our
product and therefore we combine this
hydrogen and co2 and then we go over
certain reactions which are downhill in
energy so we are getting energy out of
that again but why because the products
are uphill that is because we put in
more hydrogen from the beginning to
produce again water so we're splitting
water and using that water to reduce the
co2 to our products and we perform water
at the same time now you might have seen
such pictures in school at a certain
time when people were talking about
catalysts and catalysts from what I hear
from people who tell me what they heard
in school is this strange things which
makes erection fast or some some people
or still remember the thing that lowers
the activation barrier but what does
actually happen there and I want to make
the experiment to get your better
glimpse of what a catalyzed reaction
looks like by visualizing it and
therefore we take this picture we have
that very nice catalyst surface which is
very ordered and which is not the
reality for the experts this is also not
the outcome of some simulation or
whatever it's just a visualization how
such a reaction could look like in the
micro scale on the server
phase four for single molecules and
atoms and now this co2 is linear
molecule somewhere in the gas phase or
in a liquid phase which makes it more
complex but we're just looking at the
co2 here above this catalyst surface and
if we have the right math material what
could happen is that the co2 adsorbed to
the to one surface a term or to a group
of surface atoms and you already see
that I drawn this u2 molecule AB and so
it's not linear anymore and that might
be already one step where the activation
barrier is reduced because it's now
accessible for reactions from some
angles which were not there before and
the Elat or e electron density is
different and all that so that might be
even more reactive than before just by
absorbing it to that surface now we want
to react it this with hydrogen now we
saw we put in a hydrogen molecule and
some catalysts for example are capable
of splitting that hydrogen molecule
where it would never happen in normal
cases and this might look like this so
we form something we call surface
hydride so we have single hydrogen atoms
sitting on the surface and they are
splitted up at a rather low temperatures
and now we have that in very close
proximity on the surface and what could
happen is that one of the hydrogen atoms
just jumps to one of the oxygen atoms
and we formed a surface carbonyl group
this carbonyl group already is our first
reaction we have reduced carbon dioxide
to something not really useful yet but
we already did it next step the the
other hydrogen could jump to the very
same oxygen so this is not stable this
oxygen has three bonds in that case this
should in most of the cases break apart
and this is exactly what happens and we
form water which is in the gas phase and
we have carbon monoxide
still bound to the surface and now we
could do all kinds of things so if the
surface keeps that co absorbed we can
react it further and make one carbon
containing small molecules like methane
methanol all that stuff or we can have
another carbon monoxide at the same
surface very close and then something
similar could happen like where the
hydrogen atom reacted with the oxygen
but the two carbon atoms in a close
proximity now react and that's where we
form like longer carbon chains and there
we make complex more complex molecules
so not really complex still like two
carbon atoms three carbon atoms ten
carbon atoms in a chain or something but
yeah we form form a product and the last
thing which could happen this catalyst
is just not capable to keep that carbon
monoxide on the surface and it desorbs
and we produce carbon monoxide which
could also be fine so I hopefully could
explain you now a little more how this
catalysts thing might work and now the
question is what are their reactions
which we can use and the first thing you
already seen water electrolysis is in
that case the first step
you've also already seen the so-called
reverse water gas shift reaction where
we produce carbon monoxide from co2 and
hydrogen even if it in reality on the
real catalyst this might look a little
different but similar to what I've shown
you this could happen now I said carbon
monoxide can be a useful product and
they come back to the synthesis gas or
syngas I already mentioned and with this
in different mixtures we can do a lot of
things like mixture one or two two one
produces LPG so liquid petroleum gas
this is what you have in your camping
cooker butter bottles NAFTA is a certain
fraction you usually get when you
distill crude oil which is very useful
in chemical industry diesel which is
also something like that if you put in
like two to one you get for example
methanol ethanol demacia liter or
gasoline and with a mixture of three to
one you end up with methane or so called
SN G which is synthetic natural gas so
we which means exactly the same
basically because natural gas contains
mainly methane synthetic natural natural
gas usually is methane so here we are
already very happy we have a three-step
process and we produce all kinds of
things we can use
and the problem is by having a lot of
steps in a reaction we multiply the
efficiency and thereby the efficiency
goes down so we are always very happy if
we can produce things in few steps so
there's for example the reaction of co2
and hydrogen to methanol directly on one
catalyst in one step so we only have the
efficiency loss of one step instead of
two steps the reverse water gas shift
and the corresponding sin gas reaction
so we might have an increase in
efficiency by doing that if that
reaction is more efficient than the two
steps combined same principle with the
sabaki reaction there would takes you
two and hydrogen and might directly
methane without going two steps and one
reaction I want to to mention here even
if it's not carbon capture and
utilization is the harbor Bosch reaction
because we in principle it works the
same we could make the hydrogen from
from water electrolysis and react that
was nitrogen and there's exactly where
the reduction in producing ammonia in a
way that is more sustainable comes in
because usually the hydrogen and
chemical industry today is produced by a
lot of fossil fuels so you burn fossil
fuels with a too little oxygen to fully
fully burn it and you get a lot of
hydrogen out of there so if we would
just use
hydrogen from water electrolysis which
is more expensive today but would be way
more sustainable just to give you one
further example is I want to point out
on this direct methanol synthesis for a
second and we form methanol and the
picture you see is the George olá plant
in Iceland and it's named after a very
interesting person who made the concept
of methanol economy so like basically
like our today's economy is a oil
economy where we produce nearly
everything we have around us from oil he
proposes a economy that uses methanol as
the central resource and that's why they
called this plant after him because they
are producing four kilo tons a year of
methanol or at least they have the
capacity to do so this might seem not
too much when looking at a hundred
Megaton a year worldwide methanol
consumption but keep in mind that's just
one plant and we also don't have just
one plant producing methanol today and
it's one of the first plants who does
exactly that producing soot from co2 and
water by the use of a quasi renewable
energy in form of give thermal energy
producing methanol for the people who
are interested typical catalysts which
you could use for this process would be
a combination of copper and zinc oxide
I'm not sure if they are using it
because they for sure don't tell which
catalysts they're using but this would
be would be something typical one could
use let's go back to this picture where
you said away I showed you all these
steps we're going through in the
processes I've shown you till now these
are the processes like I said which are
on a technology ready a readiness level
that we could do that today basically
but you've seen it's a lot of steps and
I told you that a lot of steps sometimes
it's not good so let's look a little
more into the future and could we go
like one step and there's something
promising and this is actually the field
where I'm working in in a more detailed
way in my PhD and this is electric
catalytic co2 reduction so you've seen
the same picture as in the slide before
where I explained water electrolysis so
what do we change we put into YouTube
and then for sure we need to change the
catalyst material I don't know if you
really seen that but the color of the
one electrode changed and what will
happen then when we have the right
catalyst we get directly our renewable
carbon product or like yeah hydrocarbon
product and what could be those products
the first one formic acid formic acid is
a chemical which has a certain role in
chemical industries several kilotons a
year it's not too large but we can
produce it that way and already kind of
efficiently it is not like industrial
level yet but but that that works and we
can do the carbon monoxide which I also
said before that is useful and there I
know that some German companies are
right now bill trying to build a
commercial plant to do exactly that and
that step I won't mention companies
because I don't want to make stupid
advertisements but there is something
going on other products we could do a
could make is methane and ethylene
methane again synthetic natural gas and
ethyle on it would be the real thing
because ethylene is I think the chemical
made from from oil with like the largest
chemical made from oil because we are
producing a lot of polyethylene as
plastics and we can use it also for all
other kinds of things we also we has a
very large variety to make things out of
ethylene but methane and ethylene to be
honest are more on a scale where it
works in a lab and it's still not really
sure if we can bring that to industrial
scale but it might work and yeah like I
said that's what I'm trying to work on
or being part of large community working
on that so now I've talked a lot about
the processes and the chemistry behind
it let's see can we use that and like I
said to you I want to talk about the
energy sector and just to give you an
estimation the primary energy
consumption of the world is something
like 600 exajoules a year which equals
something like 167 petawatt hours that's
what we are using in form of gas and oil
and coal and renewables like all the
things we put into the energy sector in
the beginning and the three different
things I told you before electricity
transport or mobility and Heat are
roughly a third of each like in Germany
we need a little more heat because of
cold winters and in in other parts of
the world we have a little more
electricity so rough estimation
one-third each so now the question is if
we can mainly produce renewable energies
in the form of electricity how do we
bring that into that fields and we can
start with something which is very well
known mechanical storage and pumping up
water hill and we can calculate roughly
one kilogram of water we're pumping
uphill for a hundred meters and we
roughly come out at something like 0.3
watt hours which are contained within
the water
yeah more uphill that's something and
that's useful we've seen that people are
doing that with hydro pump storage but
we might put in more energy and then we
can go to terminal
energy storage and now we take the same
kilogram of water and heat it up from 25
degrees roughly room temperature to
boiling and we see we come to something
like 87 kilowatt hours in the same exact
same kilogram of water this is rough a
hundred a factor of two orders of
magnitude so now we can go to chemical
storage which is the thing and talking
to you since roughly half an hour and
then we can put in 3.7 kilowatt hours by
splitting the water into hydrogen and
oxygen this is again something like two
orders of magnitude higher that's the
reason basically why you don't see cars
driving around with hydro pump storage
because we couldn't just bring in enough
water and height into the into the into
the car to make that but we you only
have chemicals or electrochemical
driving a car now when we go to a
electrochemical storage I want to show
you this so-called Dragoon II plot which
draws the energy density by weight so
how much energy in one kilogram over the
energy density by volume how much energy
in one liter and if you are not too
familiar with the joules up there there
is one mega Joule is something like a
quarter kilowatt hour now let's take the
absolute standard which is lad acid like
car batteries which is down there it's
also as it
applications and weight-wise it's still
the largest energy market just cause
ladders heavy but we're still producing
mainly lad acid concerning weight some
of you might remember nickel-cadmium
which is prohibited due to the toxic
cadmium the better thing is a nickel
metal hydride that's what you know from
like normal the cylindrical battery
shaped rechargeable batteries that's
nickel metal hydride and then of course
lithium ion technology we can bring in a
lot of energy into these batteries and
you all have that in a whole lot of
devices but if that's still not enough
we need to go to a different scale and
we put all the batteries down there
and now we come to hydrogen hydrogen is
somewhere in that region and why is it
in such a broad region it's cause we
have hydrogen storage in materials which
is essentially a sponge sucking up
hydrogen but we have that additional
material in the storage so it becomes
heavier and is low in the energy density
by weight we have the gauges and the at
700 bar compressed and the liquefied so
that's what makes up this this square
but we see now we are very good in
energy density by white hydrogen is very
light but by density we there still
place above there and there is where the
C based materials come in and for to
give you some examples there we have
methanol down there we have gasoline up
there and that's also why electric
vehicle doesn't drive that far but it's
like three times as heavy as a normal
car that's exactly the thing why
gasoline is so good and from my personal
perspective I can't imagine a jet flying
with batteries because they would be too
heavy we need some some fuel that drives
them which is lighter and denser
so yeah that's why the the carbon
products are very interesting and
another thing why carbon products are
very interesting is because we know how
to handle them we have a large
infrastructure all around the globe to
transport them to store them to supply
them to to the applications we know what
to do
we just need to install capacities to
produce them from a renewable way but
where are the downsides if we're looking
at the downsides we come to that graph
and I really want to emphasize the work
of the group of angry body which do a
really great work in making these life
cycle assessments of these technologies
and what we see is the global warming
impact a measured in kilogram co2
equivalence so like greenhouse gases in
general or coming from certain products
we are producing by a carbon capture and
utilization technique so we have this
orange dotted lines of methane we have
this violet line is jet fuel and
different kinds of things and it's drawn
over the global warming impact of the
electricity we use to drive that process
and the vertical line is fossil diesel
so if we are above that line by driving
that carbon capture and utilization
cycle we're producing more glow
greenhouse gases then just using fossil
diesel and then we have this no the
other did I said a horizontal line I
think I said vertical line the
horizontal line is the the the fossil
diesel the the vertical lines are
the grid mixes of certain countries the
the intermediate grid makes us for
example the one right out there at
something like 370 grams co2 equivalent
per kilowatt-hour there is the you great
mix proposed for 2020 then we have the
you grid mix for 2050 which is still not
sufficient to produce anything
we have switched to a Switzerland with
this which is on the border of there
could be something useful we have France
which are very low in global warming
impact of their electricity because
they're using a lot of nuclear power
which is a total different discussion if
that is by any means helpful but but
they could do something on that field
and as at the best we have Iceland which
has really high amount of green
electricity in their grid and we have
the wind benchmark which is the
technology which is also not zero
because we are producing for example a
lot of concrete to be to build the
windmill and that produces a lot of co2
but it's still the best technology we
have global global warming impact wise
so yeah it makes only sense if we have a
lot of very green electricity going to
the chemical sector we have a graph that
it's slightly more complicated but it
essentially says shows the mass flows
from fossil fuels to the 20 largest
chemicals produced from fossil fuels
usually which have 75 percent of the
greenhouse gas emissions of the chemical
industry so that's like a model which
can refer to basically the whole
chemical industry and they modeled it
for these 20 chemicals and we see this
fossil fuels are over different
processes split up in what I said before
ethylene methanol poly olefins so
plastics
aromatics that didn't speak a lot about
them but or essentially not an ammonium
which is not a carbon-based but as I
said we put in a lot of fossil fuels to
to produce it now what is the
alternative of this thing which is the
proposal proposed mass flows so like
this size of the line refers to a mass
flow to this mass flows which are
proposed for 2034 by just using fossil
fuels on I said when I showed you
methanol I said something like methanol
economy and they made a model it's again
worked from from the group of an robado
where they basically use methanol as a
central chemic chemistry because they
say this is high in the technology
readiness level so we can could do that
right away but if you see that right the
outcome should be the same like we're
producing a certain amount of chemicals
in 2030 maybe and not it should not
depend on the way we produce it how much
we need of it
so actually we can scale that down here
so if we make that and capture the
carbon dioxide and use hydrogen by the
way here the hydrogen you see the
hydrogen mass flow going in this comes
from water this is why a lot of water
comes out of this reaction which is the
gray part on the top right part of the
this methanol pathway and we would need
to put in even more water and split it
at the beginning because some of the
water for sure ends up in our product
that's why we are doing that so we would
need to put in a whole lot of water to
make that and we would have massive mass
flow so we would have a by many factors
or by a huge factor larger chemical
industry if we would do that because we
would also need
plans to capture the carbon dioxide and
so on and so on and now the exact same
question does that make sense and here
is two models so I showed you the high
TRL model which is again technology
readiness level so can we do it today or
is it something we could do maybe in
future and the orange area is the we can
we can maybe do that today area and it's
the same graph plus as I shown you in
the in the electricity part or in the
sorry in the energy part just the other
way around like zero that x on the on
the right side and we see like again we
would need to have a whole lot of
renewable electricity which is really
clean not not a grid mix from today yeah
now we can come to another graphics like
how much electricity would we need to do
that and this graph shows like the
different lines the colored lines are
different global warming impacts of the
electricity are put in so 0 would be the
best thinkable so I have zero emission
electricity I put in so I go down that
line and it's drawn of the additional
electricity we need so how much do we
need to install extra to what we have
today and on the sides the scales is
cradle to grave greenhouse emissions
which is from my side the meaningful
thing because that says like how much
greenhouse gases do I emit from
producing the the chemical till
degrading or burning it at the end of
their life so how much extra co2 comes
out and the other side is craddle to
gate which is more interesting for a
company like i takes you to and make
something with it
how much do i produce from starting to
my factory gate where i ship the product
and that's also why
crowd - gate emissions can be negative
so we can store co2 there and they
cannot be negative when we're looking at
cradle-to-grave
at least not if we're burning the
product in the end of the lifetime and
we see we need a lot of electricity the
the scale down there is in petawatt
hours and just to give you a number the
today's generation of electricity in
total so a lot renewable electricity
electricity in total is something like
24 petawatt hours so we would
essentially need the same amount of
electricity as we are producing today to
produce the chemicals in future in a
renewable way keeping in mind that we
also need the renewable electricity to
make to make heat and mobility and there
is the point where I say like there is
this is nice technology and we can do a
lot with that but the question is so
from my point of view we cannot reach
that so we need definitely to reduce so
we need to reduce in all the ways we
need to reduce chemicals we need to
reduce all kinds of energy usage and
that on a severe level because we just
don't have enough energy to make that or
we are not from my perspective not able
to produce in a sufficient time scale
enough electricity to do so but we could
still do something and keep our like
luxury level at least at some level for
the next time and the next generations
and at the end I would just want to show
you very briefly where I think this
energy might come from and I want to
show you that map and this map is
basically the sun shining on the earth
like the in in what per square meter is
that that colored scale and there's a
reason there's two reasons why a
put that map the way you see at first
because it's anyway useful to change
perspective from time to time and not be
in the center of the world
and the other thing is that today it's
very often that the southern hemisphere
depends on the northern hemisphere for a
lot of reasons but in that case we
depend on the southern hemisphere and we
want to make that in a social and fair
way and not in a new colonial way we
essentially need to go to them and ask
them would you please generate energy
carrying products for us because we need
them other ways wise our society will
break apart cause this drop in luxury we
can't just can't afford for our saya tee
a society and what I would do in in in
large scale is putting their down their
concentrated solar power plants which
are really able to produce very high
amounts of electricity in a fairly easy
way on small small scale and we can
produce like all day and night if you
because you can store the heat in in the
in the liquid salt and you could place
like plants there which produce for
example methanol and ship it to us like
yeah in in that way and yeah with that I
think I have some few minutes left but
I'm already at the end of the talk and I
thank you for your kind attention but
for the questions I want to just start
something you see the source here
climate clock clock dotnet to just show
you how severe the discussion is yeah
and with that again thank you for your
attention and I'm happy to try to answer
your questions
all right since there's a longer break
after this talk we can take a couple of
questions so if you have a question for
Jonas please come to one of the two
microphones in the room and ask a brief
and concise question so we can be quick
about it but maybe there are actually no
questions or maybe one yeah all right
great talk how are we gonna capture all
the co2 because that's infrastructure
isn't there yet there is infrastructure
is not there but the technology is there
especially when concerning point sources
like going to some factory which
produces YouTube that we need to keep in
mind that deal between renewable
electricity like what is the footprint
of our electricity and what are we
producing but we have some processes
like for example concrete production
where inherently in the process we are
producing co2 that could be one option
and there are some startups around the
world who are making direct air capture
and who are quite efficiently especially
if they have a heat source or wait here
a waste heat source around they can very
efficiently capture already today very
pure co2 from from ambient air around us
so the technology is there the
infrastructure is not all right then
we're just gonna take that last question
please you mentioned that we need about
the same amount of electrical energy
that we have today for this power to X
so what amount of power of electricity
do we have renewable installed today I
actually have no idea about the
worldwide installed electricity I know
that we are in Germany where we always
say we were very good but we actually
are not like our footprint something
around 450 if you remember the scale
before that's on the far outside and of
these graphs in like the intermediate
value over the year
yeah I think there there is one page I
can recommend to you
electricity map where they collect data
like this and you can see like how green
is the electricity in different
countries but yeah basically I don't
know I know that the Chinese are
producing a whole lot of renewable
energies even if they are still building
coal plants but they are really going on
on with that so it's getting better but
it's still way too slow now alright
thank you so much for taking the
questions thanks for the great talk and
that concludes our Q&A session takes
Jonas
[Applause]
[Music]
you