see see camel 2019 I'm very happy to
introduce our next speaker and his name
is Harry Halpern he's the founder of
NIMH and the project coordinator of the
next leap and he's talking about
fighting a big back against library
decentralizing Facebook Connect name
anonymous authentication credentials and
I'm happy he's here please give a big
applause for Harry Hopman so it's always
good to be back at Kaos computer camp a
few years ago when I first came to Chaos
Computer Congress I was working on
JavaScript cryptography was really
thrilled that the community here came
back for camp where I talked about my
own rather personal experiences in terms
of surveillance and over the last few
years what I've been up to with a lot of
other people who will congratulate at
the end and who really have done a huge
amount of work is we've been trying to
build something which I think Chaos
Computer Congress inspired me to work on
decentralized privacy enhancing
technologies and in particular we're
gonna look at the case of Facebook as a
whole but in particularly what we
believe is the most dangerous part of
not only Facebook but all of the
centralization inside of Silicon Valley
which is their identity systems in
particular Facebook Connect and then
we're going to see how privacy enhanced
decentralized alternatives work so
fighting gets back against Libre and I
think you know the issue with Libre
originally called global coin is
incredibly politically and
philosophically interesting it saw its
signals that the nation-state order that
arised in Germany the Treaty of
Westphalia is collapsing
and that now private companies are now
taking over parts of infrastructure and
parts of services that were
traditionally provided by governments
currency is obviously one case and
identity is another and they're
intimately connected a global coin shows
that the ambition of Mark Zuckerberg and
the ambition of I think any of these
companies is to build a global system of
identity which is a necessity for a
global system of currency and that I
believe is extremely dangerous dangerous
insofar as if it is ran an authoritarian
manner in all for-profit companies are
ran in an authoritarian manner this is
actually considerably worse the
nation-state identity and incredibly
dangerous in compared to for example you
know decentralized key base identity or
federated email based identity so Libra
is announced as a global cryptocurrency
it actually makes quite a lot of sense
as a design of them a technical
perspective I'm not gonna go too far
into it I think Morgan Beller the
designer is somewhere here at camp so
you can talk to her about it but
effectively it is a blockchain
there are validators there are blocks
transactions are collected and written
two blocks on that level not actually
particularly interesting uses a fast
consensus algorithm which has the rather
hilarious name hot crap and is
essentially the validators confirm
transactions and this is where it gets
interesting because the validators are
the exact same companies and to some
extent investors and startups that
really power surveillance capitalism so
it's not just Facebook although Facebook
has built the technology and initiate
the effort they've created what's called
a Swiss
verne which is a equivalent to a mutual
Association and in this mutual
Association there are different
companies including some traditional
blockchain companies such as coinbase
large investment firms Anderson Horowitz
but also startups uber lyft and both
huge Silicon Valley companies such as
eBay telco providers such as Vodafone
and the current sort of payment
providers MasterCard Visa PayPal I mean
this is an incredibly powerful group of
companies and the primary design bet of
the Facebook Cali Libre Association is
that each of these companies has paid
ten million upfront to be a validator
for these transactions so that you know
even though the blockchain itself will
be public there will be an API against
it you'll probably be able to write apps
against it and it is interesting and I
think very to some extent cypherpunk to
try to put open-source in the middle of
such a titanically huge company which
really controls like the identity of a
third of sentient life in terms of
humanity nonetheless these are the
companies that we're trusting to
validate the transactions so on that
level it's not exactly decentralized but
that's not the real problem there's been
lots of complaints is that the
blockchain system is the real blockchain
system is it decentralized the real
problem and from an economic perspective
which I think we should actually
congratulate Facebook on is that they're
saying it's completely absurd that the
US government is the reserve currency of
the world I mean come on Trump's empower
they're doing a trade war with China
they are printing tons of money just
sustain unsustainable American consumer
debt so they took a basket of
uncorrelated assets yen dollars Swiss
franc combine them with percentages and
they've created a new currency and this
actually does threaten the US dollar as
a reserve
currency and that's where the actions
been you can see the US Congress is
called the kind of media head and the
director of Libre inside of Facebook to
testify at Congress but I think weirdly
enough I mean probably Facebook screwed
it up probably the regulator's will not
allow private companies to rant create a
new global payment and transaction
system based on essentially a basket of
currencies which will disrupt the dollar
and you know the III would be dubious if
the kind of six billion that got put in
the Libre associations Swiss bank
account
the US government can't poke through and
get all the way to the sixty bill you
know however much it is inside of
Facebook's bank account nonetheless if
it does happen and we already know these
things will eventually work even a
Facebook does it do it you know people
will have phone numbers and be able to
send payments and in their phones and
this will lead to tons of payment and
and the vision that Facebook is pushing
with a Libra alt is that this will allow
us to Bank the unbanked this will allow
us that the you know the large portion
of humanity in countries like India
sub-saharan Africa that do not have
access to bank accounts as an American
in Europe it's actually really hard to
get a European bank account this will
allow people to have bank accounts
however what even though Facebook has
said we will not use your personal data
in the Liebherr Association we will not
share your personal data with say PayPal
or whoever the people running the
validators there is this giant loophole
and that is that the wallet the caliber
wallet will have to do what's called kyc
AML know your customer anti money
laundering
they will essentially have to identify
every person using the Calibra wallet
and they will be able to as they have
stated in their response to the
regulator's able to leverage the
tremendous amount of personal data
that they control at least they easily
can in order to take these pseudonymous
keys which are on the libra blockchain
which has validators which is replicable
and etc etc and they will be able to
attach identities to those keys and how
they do that is a software which no one
has talked about which is the most
important part of Facebook's current
empire and to be honest I believe
Calibra and Libra are just another way
to leverage this kind of technology to
create even more personal data because
right now Facebook obviously has your
friends and your name and all that but
they really would like your bank account
and this is done via what's called
Facebook Connect everyone who uses the
app typically science and with Facebook
Connect and there are probably as many
Facebook connector on the same magnitude
at least Facebook Connect transactions
are as there are visa transactions this
is the identity system of the Internet
currently for the vast majority of users
whether we like it or not and it as
hackers as programmers as people who
want to change the system we should
understand this incredibly vital
technology and build alternatives so the
technology is built on a very innocent
standard called IETF oo auth which
stands for web authorization and what o
is it was invented good friend of mine
another great anarchist protocol Blaine
cook was working at Twitter and at the
time in 2003 four or five you know
people wanted to sign onto Twitter but
they wanted some you know profile data
from them a photo easy access not having
to repeat passwords so you know at the
time they said well just give us your
gmail password I'll give you access to
Twitter but that's very dangerous
because then Twitter has access to your
entire Gmail so olaf was invented not as
a mass personal data collection scheme
but as a way to essentially help people
log in for single sign-on login and then
authorize the transfer of data and the
transfer data takes place through
following players the identity provider
the who is for example Facebook who has
a lot of your personal data and you
would like to hand that data to a
service provider also called a relying
party that needs his personal data and
you have the user who gave the person's
they did identity provider to begin with
it needs to authorize the service
provider so they've already
authenticated using a password
two-factor authentication whatever
- they didn't provider they've
approached a new service for example say
Twitter and they want to use their
Facebook ID to log in a Twitter and so
you want to transfer data without
sharing any authentication credentials
you might want to transfer all sorts of
data cities age whatever you want to
authorize that
and how OAuth does is very simple
because at the time JavaScript
cryptography and web cryptography in
general is very immature so they
couldn't use digital signatures people
couldn't interoperate with digital
signatures instead all security boils
down to TLS this is the kind of flow I'm
just gonna step through the flow really
quickly but you've all done this a
million times so you kind of know how it
works in the first step you go up to
Twitter and you say hi I would like to
use my Twitter account Twitter says do
you want to log in with Facebook you
click that log in with Facebook button
and you are effectively shipped over to
the IDP which in this case would be
Facebook now you're on
you got ship that step 2 step 3 you say
yeah facebook says do you want to
authorize Twitter to have my data you
click yes that's step 3
you move you when you click step 4 you
go back to Twitter Twitter you have a
token which is called a bearer token
that toke it is basically a time-stamped
kind of hash is when we think about it
essentially capability if you're in the
sort of that kind of way of thinking
about things you hand that token which
functions as a capability to Twitter
Twitter then shows that the Facebook and
step 6 and then step 7 all that precious
personal data flows from Facebook to
Twitter and what's really dangerous is
that you will have to
do that when you use Calibra when you
use a wallet which is compliant and
they'll use the regulation that
compliance regulations is the kind of
excuse there are privacy ways to be
compliant but of course I would be
highly dubious that people would not
leverage in our public data they can
that they already have to to use here
that they will be able to control your
financial data and send that data back
and forth using this kind of centralized
I did any scheme they've already set up
with Facebook connect to both verify who
you are and what you're purchasing
because in the current scheme as you may
have noticed the identity provider which
is Facebook in this case has a hundred
percent transparency to which services
you're using and when you're using them
and what calibra they would have a
hundred percent transparency into what
purchases you're making and who you're
making them less of when you're making
with them and that of course is a
tremendous amount of very valuable data
currently spread in a heterogeneous
manner among various banks seems to be a
great business ploy to push that all
together inside of Facebook and you know
we have to do something here I think to
prevent what will be effectively a
totalitarian identity system on a scale
that we have never seen before it will
destroy people making think however they
want about the blockchain space but
essentially attaching
Facebook identities via Facebook Connect
to pseudonymous keys will kill
innovation and the block chain space of
divine the blockchain and essentially a
mass-market
identified blockchain and it will be to
be honest total nonsense in terms of the
people they're trying to serve obviously
people who are in countries such as you
know which took India China may not have
all the identity papers may not be able
to pass normal banking compliance will
also not be able to pass very easily
banking compliance for the Calibra
wallet and maybe Facebook can help do
that via leveraging all this data but it
still seems to be a very flimsy excuse
to engage
this truly tremendous amount of data
collection so what we want is we want a
alternative and luckily cypherpunks have
been working on this along with academic
photographers for more than 20 years so
the quote I'd like to repeat is that
privacy is the power to selectively
reveal oneself to the world which means
under your control when you want it and
with whatever data you believe is
sufficient for the operations and
whatever service you choose to use and
that really is freedom otherwise you
will be tracked and B services can be
censored and it's exceedingly dangerous
sorry so these are the sort of two
fundamental problems we have to tackle
one is how do we create how do we not
create the kinds of activities that
people want to do logging into things
paying for things without a centralized
I didn't provider like Facebook in the
middle and I hope some will talk about
this briefly but there was a great talk
about yesterday by David Stanton even
with that massive powerful adversaries
it's just the NSA can just kind of watch
the traffic and use that to violate
privacy so we do need some traffic tcpi
UDP level protection as well so the
centralized entity providers just to
repeat their own kind of attacks they
can use on date on ordinary people they
capture ID any data they know exactly
which services a user uses when they use
them they can transfer personal data
ideally with consent but they don't have
to ask for consent technically and they
can even impersonate you to other
service providers and they can censor
service providers they can prevent
people from logging in to service
providers they may not agree with
luckily there is technology and this is
the main technology I'm going to explain
it was created by an obscure London
startup I recommend looking at the wired
article called chain space that came out
of University College London and was
acquired by Facebook but luckily for us
that software was left open source and
the papers are all published
in the without patents and all that
stuff and it's it's a very ironic this
happened because the researchers that
were working on this were funded by you
know the European Commission mostly to
create privacy enhanced decentralized
technologies and cities such as
Barcelona and Amsterdam to enable
citizens to own their own data so that's
kind of the background of where this
technology came from and the particulars
technology some of it also came from
another project called next leap which I
coordinated which is sensors trying to
say after the Snowden revelations how
can we build better decentralized
privacy enhanced identity systems so
this is going to be a quick overview I'm
just gonna give the intuitions behind
the cryptography but I think you'll
probably get a get get something from it
the solutions on a very broad scale is
in order to in metadata collection as
mentioned earlier you need something
like tor or ideally some even better
such as a mixed net we're gonna focus on
authentication you want privacy enhance
transfer of any data under absolute user
control that's why we're gonna use
anonymous left indication credentials
and you want tokens which can basically
subsidize the whole system make sure
that's sustainable and people can do
transfer in a privacy way privacy dance
manner and we also want a few other
properties we want possibly these
transfers of data to be
cryptographically unlink able actually
anonymize we want users to be able not
only show data such as I'm 18 but also
private attributes proof that they know
something without revealing it such as
proof that I own a secret or proof that
I'm a member of a country citizen in
Europe but without revealing which
country and we also may want you know a
lot of anonymous technologies makes it
very hard to produce some very useful
applications such as for example long
term messaging we want a profile which
can receive and send messages over long
periods of time so we want pseudonym an
integration not just complete anonymity
so anonymous left indication credentials
have been around for a very long time
the initial work was of course done by
David CIAM who's one of the you know
fathers
of the modern cypherpunk movement and
and most the interesting work racine
cryptography including mixed nuts that
we're now finally getting to market and
it but what they do is a very simple
blinded signature scheme where you
basically have some credentials you
verify that these credentials are true
these attributes such as age name
citizenship and the blinding basically
prevents the issuer to kind of know
exactly what the credentials are they
can just show that there they have been
issued correctly that they are indeed
correct and that other service providers
can't verify them but the problem is
every time you reshow that credential
you allow yourself to be linked again
you know blind signatures you see the
same even if you see the same ciphertext
more than once you can look at the bite
pattern and the cipher text and link it
so luckily there's been some really
amazing work that's been a more research
papers I can possibly go into primarily
by yon common ish and many other people
talk about blinded showing which allows
multiple shows of the same credential
and that's really I think a wonderful
work but it's very complicated and we're
going to talk about some new work that
uses algebraic max which is we think
much more efficient but not
decentralized and then we're going to
discuss how we can make it decentralized
okay so the big picture is you have the
user wants to prove that they have some
attributes they get a certified
credential from what we call the issuer
so this is sort of a standard but we
would call Sigma protocol game if you're
familiar with cryptography you show
these assertions to a verifier could be
the third-party service providers such
as Twitter and then the verifier can for
example like check that these are
correct and the general intuition is
that the very unlike when I go to for
example a bar in the United States or I
go to vote I show you my ID card but you
know all you really want to know is the
age you instead you get my name and my
date of birth and my where it was born
we allow you just to show just the age
and they learn nothing else so we can
use max which are essentially a
symmetric crypto graphic authentication
mechanism which can guarantee integrity
authentication and symmetric crypto to
sort of make this work and a privacy
enhanced fashion but we need a little
bit extra so we want to be able to
effectively we have an issuer and they
want to be able to verify these
credentials are indeed correct that
they've issued them correctly there's
the user the prover they get the surf
eye credential we've seen this before
and they can make some assertions which
can be proven but we essentially there's
a secret mat key which is then used to
essentially Mack the credential and we
use a new cryptographic formulation
which we'll discuss right now called
algebraic max to basically make it
private because if you just use a normal
Mac it's a normal signature and you can
sort of you don't have any privacy over
the credential self algebraic max allow
a number of basically the way think
about is it's a normal Mac but you can
basically make them unlink able and
they're very efficient
just like max typically are very
efficient so you have efficient proofs
of Mac creation and efficient proofs of
possession and you use the possession of
the Mac as showing an attribute and the
issuer basically uses max is the source
signature over the attribute and you can
do these protocols and the clear for
parameters and key generation if you
want the whole paper that's a Sarah
Michael John and Melissa chase algebraic
max and key Vera Kate very keyed
verification anonymous credentials and
what we did is we took algebraic max and
we said let's make a privacy enhanced
version of Facebook Connect and we made
it system called unlimited ID which
embeds the tributes into the mac
messages but we want not only to
mitigate we don't want people to be able
to stay
yes you know my name is my ages but we
also want private attributes possession
of keys for example possession of keys
which could access a bank account which
could access a financial transaction and
so we take this construction embed it in
the previous setup we saw and then using
the issuing authority you kind of run it
like you wouldn't run it with a normal
Mac based credential so you you know you
you ask or prove er yeah make sure sign
off the fact I'm of age x5 a European
citizen whatever you get that credential
the algebraic Matt can't sort of with
over non zero zero knowledge
non-negative zero knowledge proof scan
hide the private attributes the Mac
prevents you from just forging it from
just making it up so if something third
party has signed off on it but you could
use an anonymous channel to basically
have these algebric max verified and
that's kind of one way to create a
centralized version of OAuth which has
privacy that's the unlimited ID
technique and you can do all sorts of
great things you can rate limit you can
check for duplication a lot of these
things you can do is by simply embedding
various hashes strings proof of
knowledge of strings and keys into the
credential itself and so for example
this prevents reuse so you can sort of
say hey I can't just keep showing you
the credential multiple time family show
it to you once which sounds were silly
but it actually could be very useful
that credential was for example sending
money because then you don't want to you
want to say hey yes I got a bank account
the spank account has let's say 30 euros
in it and then I send the anonymous
credential to a verifier and I ship them
the money they don't know no one who's
watching can figure it out your bank has
verified that you have 30 euros your
account that 30 euros then trans first a
service provider
but the service provider can then check
with the bank to make sure that 30 euros
is still there but you can still
maintain your privacy so this very good
neat tricks is algebraic max which
unfortunately do not have time to go
into but we're interested not just in a
privacy enhanced alternative to Facebook
Connect but a decentralized and privacy
enhance a version of Facebook Connect so
we want something that's a little bit
more complicated what we want to have we
don't want to have trusted a single
third party even if they don't know
anything about us to be able to hold all
hold our keys so we have a issuing
authority multiples you see multiple
sort of Bob's multiple bananas this is
in the screen we get a threshold
signature with multiple signing keys and
then we kind of get that credential we
merge the credential and then we can
show that credential to third parties
service providers so I'm going to show a
little bit of code about how that works
so we have this code for this and I'm
gonna explain it on github but let me
just show you a little video while we
have a second so this is what's called a
NIM wallet you can it in bed even
currency which we call NIMS
into this wallet and then you basically
this is why this step takes a while you
can ask different validators to validate
that you have that money in your wallet
so this is like three of five validators
or 60 of 100 or we even get kind of
pretty good performance when you have up
to 10,000 validators when that validator
confirms that transaction so it confirms
it on a essentially a blockchain you get
you can type in how much how much you
want you get that in a credential you
can embed other stuff such as name and
age or whatever else you want and then
you send it and this is the real trick
you make it privacy enhanced by
unlinking it so you can see there's a
rear an demise button you can click on
that button and the cipher text itself
re randomized this by simply taking the
existing cipher text and taking
to another exponent and boom you've just
created a unlink able decentralized
privacy enhanced transaction and you can
send the money to whatever service
provider you want so they go back to the
slides
so the codes a GPL free software online
would love to have people play with it
but just to give your intuition for the
tricks that we use it's very similar to
algebraic case but there's a few
different things going on and you should
read the coconut paper talk to Mustafa
al Bassam if he's here if you can see
him around in the audience you embed the
attribute says commitments sort of
standard Peterson style commits like I
said earlier you can use non directive
zero knowledge proof if you want private
attributes and then you have pairing
based elliptic curve cryptography which
helps allow the signature itself to be
reran demise
so you package up your commits into an
encrypted package using el-gamal
encryption because you can then re
randomize it ship it up the validators
they validate it let's say three or five
validate it you ship it back and you
have some new functions so while you can
get partial credentials from an issuer a
validator so to speak the user merges
these credentials together they don't
have the any third party do it for them
and that creates a full credential that
embeds all the information for identity
they need which can be shipped to verify
on a service and as I showed in a demo
they can then the user is under control
re randomization so at any time they
want the unlinking transaction they want
no one to connect their validation and
they're issuing they just basically hit
the realization button simple
explanation and they can reran demise
the signature itself and the two other
tricks the tricks well-known tricks
which essentially allow this to work as
you use threshold cryptography to
achieve decentralization and order to
achieve verifiability because you have
to the people who get these credentials
they have to verify that they're really
the the really valid that they actually
you know the someone actually saw
something that said you're eighteen or
you actually do have this amount money
in your bank account you can basically
use the hashing trick over the secrets
similar to identity based encryption so
make a hash which in anyone can check
which can be publicly published so we
built this whole giant system which I
actually just demoed to you
- the mix net component already taking
essentially some sort of nem some sort
of token shipping it around
embedding all sorts of attributes and
anonymous authentication provider
credential you take you can have third
party sign off of them you can create
these attributes yourself and make them
self sovereign so you can sign them ship
them up through from - validator the
validator doesn't know what credentials
you're you you're getting a signed off
on they don't know where you're going
with them they just said yep looks valid
someone signed that I don't really care
we trust a user here they ship it back
depends on the kind of attribute you
want you can then ship it through
something like a mixed net or a tour and
anonymous communication channel bring
the link ability on the timing aspects
and for various other metadata the
service provider can then check the
credential go back to the blockchain
make sure that there's been no double
spending and then you can both do
one-time attribute shows for essentially
financial transactions or other kinds of
one-time sort of things and also multi
shows for things like age date whatever
your name or you we really want to tell
multiple people you can just do it an
unlimited amount of time and you know
because we're not using full ZK snarks
we're using these kind of very
specialized not interactive zero
knowledge proof we get pretty linear
scaling things operate on link ability
can take place in two milliseconds and
verification you know tends to be around
50 it's a bit more expensive a procedure
because you have to check all the
secrets and you can see the more and
more people you add to the system it of
course gets slower because there's more
more things to check but it's it's
slower in a linear fashion so we think
that's pretty cool and I think we won't
really go into this but we're really
thinking really hard about rewards and
how that works how we can actually make
sure that to make privacy enhances
services really sustain a sustainable
surveillance capitalism is obviously not
sustainable and neither are US
government grants to tour and other
projects we really need to be able for
privacy enhancing technologies to be
able to plug into something that looks
like Facebook Connect
that's decentralized that defit
user privacy and then lets them get paid
in a way where they don't have to
essentially hold user data for example
if I'm whole if I run a VPN service I
don't want to have anyone's credit card
information I don't want anymore
personal data
ideally 0 I just want to provide a VPN
service and get paid it into the month
and no there's real users coming through
and there's tons of other use cases
outside of VPNs one which I think and
you know the European Commission worked
on attribute-based credentials and fun
tool all this for Identity Management to
make an alternative to Facebook Connect
but there's also I think there's a very
powerful use case around secure
messaging you know when you're used for
example signal you have a phone number
you have contacts all this stuff should
be embeddable within a privacy enhanced
credential and we're we have some
software i've recommend taking a look at
status which actually is decentralized
which tries to provide some of the same
capability a signal that this software
should be embeddable and some of the
newer standards coming out to try to
make open standards that have better
scalability than the signal protocol in
terms of large group messaging and to be
an actual IETF open standard and these
kind of standards because they're built
to support things like Facebook Connect
is the fundamental identity system we
want to make sure we can slot in sort of
decentralized privacy enhancing
credentials into these kinds of
next-generation messaging protocols so
I'd recommend anyone interested in
messaging check out the IETF message
layer security work I won't go into mix
nets because running out of time but
again there was a great talking
yesterday just check that talk out
essentially it is possible to obfuscate
metadata and hook that to a credential
this is all the wonderful people who've
been working on the on the project
Claudia Diaz Anya Dave who actually left
Libre and is now joined us
Jared Andrew who's done a lot of the
hard work on the code and I would really
recommend you know if you want to get
involved
everything is on github I want to review
some of the papers that you may want to
take a look at if you're interested in
deep diving so again the keywords or
chain space a lot of the code is on
their website lots of good links
even though they were purchased by
Facebook there's still website and the
code still there for early work on
Thomas authentication credentials the
really classic paper that goes over
Schnoor signatures all the way from 1991
efficient signature generation by smart
cards and then the kind of use of this
and well ended up being Microsoft
passport by stefan braun and the real
core paper for cocoanut credentials is
called coconut that gives you the
decentralization of privacy but you're
interested in the algebraic Mac work
which allows to have centralized privacy
enhanced identity it could be useful for
some use cases like government someplace
where you really need to really a lot of
speed a lot of transactions you can look
it up my work on unlimited ID and that's
it I do want to there was a lot of
information at once by just wanted I'm
just gonna reiterate the fundamental
points and the fundamental points are
this that everyone's very concerned
about currency but identity is the real
currency and any plays for new global
cryptocurrencies schemes are effectively
plays to make global ID na systems we
already have the world's largest IT
system operational right now bigger than
any nation-state ran by Facebook but
luckily did 20 years of research we have
the technology to build alternate if we
even have working code we just have more
people be aware of the problem build
this into their own apps and work with
us to make more efficient more private
into more decent choice alternative
because to be honest I don't think
anyone wants live in a society where
single Authority can watch all your
transactions and have the control over
both your financial transactions and the
most intimate details of your life we
need to have privacy enhanced decent
choice alternatives and I welcome you to
just join us and help make this true
make this reality fight back against
Libre so any questions
thank you
that was emotional but I think that's
really really well furred we need
engagement we need to fight okay do we
have questions
Danlos that I mean biases leashed just
Minds acknowledging a question about the
Libra basically when everybody puts
money there they pile up a lot of cash
so it's kind of a like a debit card
I couldn't found any information about
what happens with the money while after
you give it to Facebook and before you
spend it for something yeah so this is
something which there hasn't been too
much work on and the public because
Facebook is published very little about
this that being said it would likely
work as a fractional reserve banking
system so that when you give control
over sort of you know let's say you get
a I give Facebook $50 50 euros they can
then you know have that under their
control on or at least the Libra
Association control and then real end it
out there so that it will effectively
lead to mass capital accumulation by
liberal Libre Association if you add
that by one third of humanity being
stuck under Facebook Connect that's a
whole lot of cash that's essentially a
parallel corporate payment and banking
infrastructure which can rival
traditional banking structures and
that's on some level very cyberpunk
another level very terrifying okay we
have one more question we just have one
more question I'm here afterwards yeah
so I have any thoughts on decentralized
identity providers so would they verify
government credentials or anything or
are there different ideas about that to
do that decentralized yeah so what we
tried to do if I can get back to the
picture is we tried to build a system
where we disintermediate centralized
providers from validation and
verification so oh there it is
so you can see on in this diagram
instead
- okay the you your identity party it
could be the German government which is
big centralized entity they might sign
off on just your age or just your
passport and you can make up some other
stuff and you can work these together
and have them be validated in a
decentralized way so we don't think
they're incompatible okay thank you so
much you will be here for questions and
thank you for watching please wash your
hands take your stuff with you and don't
leave any garbage and a big applause for
Harry hubba
[Applause]
[Music]
you