[Music]
put your money where your mouth is
Tobias is gonna tell us what happened
when he did just that let's welcome him
with a heartfelt round of applause thank
you very much for the kind introduction
so today or tonight I want to tell you a
little story I was part of a project in
2016 and today I want to show you some
takes on vulnerability disclosure and
also how to do security research for
medical device products um some of you
might have seen this kind of news
articles they were out in 2017 you might
be thinking why is this guy talking
about stuff happened in 2017 there are
such things called
in das and mine was for three years so
it started to 16 now we've 219 that's
why I'm talking today about this stuff
stories there were some pacemakers out
there with a lot of vulnerabilities and
it led to a recall of more than half a
million pacemakers and also a new way
for vulnerability disclosure was taken
so why do I tell you about the stuff so
let me first introduce me briefly to you
my name is Tobias
I work as security researcher and mainly
I do
IOT embedded systems security and one of
my main area of interest is reversing
wireless communication and back in 215 I
did a talk at blackhat focusing on 6b
security and some guy from some guys
from a company called medic where they
were watching this talk and said ok hmm
we also have a interesting project
concerning reverse engineering reverse
engineering wireless communication maybe
hire this guy
so this company was called mezack yeah
they are interested in medical device
security and they had a project with the
goal to find zero day vulnerabilities in
pacemaker communication and they
assessed for vendors and I was part of
the team doing reverse engineering for
the same truth
project so quick introduction yeah how
does the ecosystem of modern pacemakers
look like so you have a pacemaker that's
implanted now medical term is implanted
cardiac device and ICD that's connected
to either a program that's usually at
the hospital or at the doctor so you can
do calibrations reading the health data
out of the system and send it back to
the cloud
the Merlin net in this case because
there is always a cloud also in medical
nowadays they also have a home monitor
that's used for I think some comfort for
the customers because usually they had
to go to the doctor's office regularly
to just to have the stuff inspected if
it works what a rate of what are the
data and just to have it double-checked
but a better doctor nowadays the stuff
is collected automatically using
wireless communication so you just have
it in your home usually in the bedroom
and as soon as you're within the range
of the system your data is collected and
sent back to the cloud that's kind of a
predictive maintaining and maintenance
for for humans and it's quite a big step
for patients but it's also a first
attack vector because in the past this
was done by a new field communication so
you had to be really really close by to
get a connection to the pacemaker but
they switched it up it's now a different
frequency band it's called the mix band
for medical devices it's 401 to 406
megahertz and we chose this is a first
attack vector and said okay would be
cool
to shock a pacemaker using wireless so
that's easy nowadays because hardware
made a huge progress the last years
yesterday there was a very interesting
talk about the limitations of
software-defined radio yeah I can highly
recommend to watch this talk because a
lot of this stuff I have experienced by
myself especially the limitation side so
have a look at it ok so we used
software-defined radio to inspect the
mix band to find first attack vector so
how do you do this because you don't
have any information where to start so
first we do wireless reverse engineering
and I all wanted just to give you a
short introduction what we are my best
practice for doing this not for the
pacemaker but in general I would
strongly recommend to check something
called the FCC Eddy every product sold
in the US has to be checked by the FCC
and you get a label with a number and
you can connect this number to wrong
direction to some information because
there is online a database where you
find some stuff from the testing
procedure and if you're lucky sometimes
you just have one device and you don't
want to open it because you maybe you
damage it but you want to get to know of
the internals and if you're lucky you
will find on this website also stuff
like internal what moment internal
photos oh the block diagram user manual
so that's a very good first start to
investigate a wireless device also I can
recommend check patents google has a
patent search online you won't find the
most detailed information but sometimes
you find specific URLs of protocols so
how does this communication work in
general also a nice point to check and
of course product documentation our F
chip
specs firmware software whatever you get
look at it take this information it will
speed up your process of reverse
engineering drastically if everything
doesn't work fall back - busy signal
inspection yeah but it's a very hard
task and you have to be kind of
experienced to do it and I would not
recommend to start with this with this
okay
also frequency bands for leaky issues
radio spectrum is very wide so where to
start from medical devices obviously
have a start at the mix band because
it's just reserved for this as a start
and what we also this did was interviews
interviews is always good ask people
they have experience with this tooling
what are the problems sometimes they
can't tell you how it works but they
have experience in troubleshooting maybe
to say okay if we have a lot of Wi-Fi
networks for example our stuff didn't
work so you can think maybe there is a
problem with some interference from
Wi-Fi and it doesn't work we also used
an additional service the company bought
the service that hooks you up with
former employees of companies so we got
access to former developers the work
there we talked with them facing the
problems are on a security perspective
where to start
sometimes they gave us good hints where
do you have a look at but I will touch
it later on ok
could be patent as a toll that's an
example from SiC P but you see there is
a description how the basic networking
works also RF chip documentation
what would I check by the way that's not
the transceiver chip from the pacemaker
but that's a good example for example
it's listed what kind of my relations
are supported and what frequency ranges
are supported and also what data rates
leave you issues so the the radio
spectrum is highly regulated if you have
a look for something the
this thing is not at the eyes and bands
have a look here maybe it has also
dedicated some some dedicated space we
did the stuff get at some information
did some basic testing we started with a
simple replay attack so we just record a
communication and played it back to the
a CD and what happened was we nearly
instantly found first vulnerabilities
what kind of warn abilities first we
call it crash attack it was no attack
they just crashed
if you replayed a communication for some
time the Pacemakers they just crashed
and they did they didn't recover so
where you were not able to use them
again
there was no failsafe no no safety no
security mode they were just broken yeah
so we brick devices just by simple
replaying stuff it was at now is still
my most the major concern I have because
that's no real yeah advanced the tech
it's just this might happen by by by
accident and we also found a way to
deplete the energy very very fast that's
a problem because you have limited
energy so you can't reload the battery
so if your battery's out you need to
have a surgery and you have it replaced
so this means also very very bad we
released some videos or we the company
called Matic released videos online
about this they are still on there I put
some the references on there if you want
to see it the proofs how this works
funny side story there is one comment on
there because the videos are not there
have a very great production quality and
I like the comment and I think it's kind
of funny and yeah so replay attacks
first and I warn abilities identified
but then we did talk a little bit deeper
and did some real reverse engineering so
we get our hands on the basic PEC
structure we found out okay where does
it start where's the synchronization
which CSE they're using what will it do
for error correction but we still
struggled with the data blocks yeah
in RF there are a lot of ways to cover
up your stuff where you can do data
whitening you can do encryption it was
not possible for us to find it easily so
we kind of got stuck because reverse
engineering is often a very
time-consuming task and since they had
nearly every only external researchers
it's also very expensive task if you buy
like 10 guys looking at pacemakers we
are not the cheapest I think it costs
you a lot of money and also even if it's
weak crypto cryptography you won't be
able to break it with your eyes just
looking at it won't solve the problem so
we had a decision decision to make get
somebody who is good at crypto analysis
or look at a different attack vector we
got got for the second because there is
a lot of other things to attack there is
also a complex IOT ecosystem and you
don't need to attack the hardest target
because every one is speaking the same
protocol this means we switch the up and
said ok the pacemaker and the wireless
communication directly might yeah be too
hard for us to break it in time let's
have a look at the home monitor why a
home monitor because it also
communicates wirelessly with the
pacemaker and it's a very cheap device
so you can just buy it on eBay for
eighteen dollars you can get it at home
I brought one today with me just to show
you how good that they are made and we
said okay maybe there is some stuff on
there that helps us understand the
protocol so we took it apart
and check what our f chips are or in
there how they're working and this took
us yeah a little further than further
down the road but a big big breakthrough
was we found some debug ports they are
not protected
so it's UART just hook up and you're
connected to the system and the
bootloader is not very good protected
yeah you see maybe on the screenshot if
you are capable of some basic stuff it's
easy to get root access there and let me
show you yeah
pray to the demo gods that everything
works so I hooked up a buzz pirate
that's connected to my system and it's
also connected to the pacemaker monitor
I have you see now I'm stuck at the
login so there was the traditional boot
sequence what I now do is I just press
the reset button let me and you see some
stuff is happening happening and I just
need to press one button to escape to
the bootloader during the screen you
just see it's blob is used and yeah we
just have to wait for the reboot I press
the button so now we jump directly into
the bootloader
and you will see there is written out to
put in progress press any key to stop so
that's easy help
what should we do just type in help you
see what commands you have there is one
called boot boot is very promising boot
Linux in RAM with optional kernel
options yeah sounds promising
because maybe our goal is to directly
put into the into the shell but how how
to do it is just type in status you see
your kernel command-line arguments there
you just copied them
let me honest that's very hard task boot
just insert it again and add just one
additional argument and now we should
put up directly into the yeah we don't
have a login prompt anymore so we have
root access now in the system and there
is some interesting information also
there typing is always the hardest part
for example you see a non host where is
it communicating to you you see the
addresses from the Merlin net from the
cloud listed there what else do you need
in a cloud you need a password how to
log in
let me check and there is for example
one exam if the P password listed here
and it's not a very good one I think
there is some room for improvement and
this password is the same for every
monitor just some examples you you find
very easily so that's not very
sophisticated hacking but it did the job
so we were able to extract some
components from the fembra and go
further down the road of reverse
engineering the protocol and what else
do we now have we also have now control
of a system the rest the proper RF chip
for communicating directly with the
pacemaker
so the problem also mentioned yesterday
is when you do software fine radio you
have some timing constraints because the
there is some net like in every protocol
you have some time slots you need to
reply in a specific time and when you do
this with a software fine radio you have
them attached by USB USB has a very high
latency so sometimes you're just too
slow to answer them in the right time to
get accepted by the receiver so we just
then switch to
at the Merlion at home as a tech device
okay what else do a tech ya programmer
we also bought this you can buy it on
eBay we bought one recently from a
German secondhand medical device
reseller for 160 euros with valid
medical data still on there so I think
the whole industry need to step up their
game when it comes to privacy and
cybersecurity just as an example so if
you tear down this system there's a
removable hard drive no encryption yeah
like Austin Powers says they'd like to
live dangerously yeah one of my favorite
movie quotes so this was our final piece
in the puzzle why because they were Java
files so you just decompile them have a
look and there is the the whole protocol
was just written there for us just to
implement and not only the protocol also
some codes they're using for kind of a
vector access to circumvent encryption
that's not only to blame them because
for pacemakers you have also like other
requirements if you go to Australia and
have an have a heart attack you I think
you want the doctors in Australia are
also able to connect to your pacemaker
and read some data so they have kind of
a vector Universal key for making this
possible okay so we use now the
Millennium as an attack device so we
were able to deliver emergency sharks
reconfigured as the device make it
vibrate test shocks the demo videos are
still on there on Vimeo
yeah the link is in there I have a look
I think they are better than the ones
before so they had a proper speaker I
think they're really good to just get
what we are doing there okay let's play
a simple game blaming the vendor which
method match
such authentication code is used a b c d
or e so who is for a a b c close race d
no T no e e no trust in the vendor it's
actually C so they're doing a little bit
of authentication but 24 bit RSA what
else did they do did to do the
home-brewed crypto you know I told you
about the universal key
you served up with RSA public keys or
truncate keys because memory see ya
they did all of this and because you
would be able to guess because when they
use 24 bit encryption and then they have
32 bit keys so it just the truncated
because they didn't have the memory I
it's like a first project to do in at
university or at school how to do
cryptography and do it the bad way and
that's a sad part in it because we have
some IP camps some Chinese IP camps in
our office just to get to get to get
trained in the stuff they have the same
security level as medical devices so I
think that's kind of a sad part so let's
give you a short technical summary so we
were able to find in two months a lot of
critical vulnerabilities with potential
lethal impact
so everybody analyst authorized users
could remotely just disabled your
pacemaker make them vibrate deliver you
a shock we found a lot of security mmm
nightmares
in there ya know best practice was
followed and no I think that's very bad
but one might think what about security
certifications because medical is for
certain highly regulated area and you
see there is a logo
it's ISO 27001 certified and they're
very proud of it because they're the the
first medical network that is properly
certified for information systems
management system formation security
management systems and they express it
openly they're very good at it and
that's a very stringent worldwide
information security standard but it's
not yeah it has nothing to do with
product security and that's maybe how
they run their mail server maybe but not
how they do pacemakers just keep this in
mind this certification it's not for
product security okay but what was
special yeah because it's just a project
with a lot of security vulnerabilities
that's no magic done you've seen it's
not the best hacking you need for the
stuff vulnerability disclosure and
that's actually I think why I'm here
today and the next days to talk to you
about what's a good way of an ability
disclosure okay what was special the
guys they have me and I thought we do
the traditional way yeah we do some
research go to big conferences talk to a
big crowd and everybody will come to us
and buy the services we sell they did it
differently this day licensed the
research to an investment company and
the investment company took a short
position insane truth medically and
purchase from competitors this means
they published a report with all the
findings in there not the technical
details but with the findings in there
and explained how these kind of findings
will affect the stock market price from
offs and shoot so vulnerability disclose
approach the process no there was no
notification notification to the vendor
previously because there is a history
attached to this vendor yeah
this vendor was accused the same
vulnerabilities by a by a guy core
called Barnaby check a couple of years
ago but they were never made public
because Barnaby check died so the
research in this area kind of cut stock
and so they said now since youth mmm
they keep denying this stuff and yeah
which would be just some litigation
let's just public let's just partner
with muddy waters because they are good
at making these bad Bender's pay for the
harm that they do it's like a kind of a
Robin Hood story they want to sell you
and as mentioned the set a very big
impact because on the day the
information was released the stock
market dropped 12% which means two
billion dollars yeah
it's five million it's a very big number
and I think it's the first time this was
done for vulnerability disclosure and
from monetizing vulnerabilities and I
think a quite big one and then it all
started yeah because st. Jude started to
deny the stuff they said okay this
reached researchers they just want to
make money out of us it's there delete
the results of Falls they're made up
that everything not true let's sue them
and they sued a lot of the persons
involved like Mary waters the CEO the
doctors that were involved in this
project and in October because assume
the report was published in August and
in October we had a third-party
independent third party to just recheck
what the work we did and it was an
expert team from Bishop Fox and us-based
cybersecurity compre company and they
verified every claim we made so we were
ready to go and said okay we didn't made
it up
somebody has to take actions and a
couple months later the ics-cert
released vulnerability note and also the
FDA released vulnerability note together
with a first update for cybersecurity
and sent Ruth to say they are very proud
of our security we are leading the way
but it's not true because the update was
just for communication between the
Merlin and the cloud because this was
done unencrypted in the past and they
just put certificates on there so that's
not the update we want it to happen
because the PageMaker communication the
wireless communication was still
unpatched also fun stuff because there
is a German a nice phrasing for to de
shocks yeah you see up gabay una mezcla
stimulations in pull Z it's the proper
word the medical term for I will kill
you with this shock yeah so everything
is a kind of phrasing yeah a little bit
later down the road the FDA also took
reboot the information and they made an
official statement so ok he said ah
that's true what they are what they are
claiming that's possible st. Jude you
need to do a second update yeah and they
did nearly one year later the final
update came out with which also targeted
the insecure communication I never
retested the stuff but I think there
were a lot of knowledgeable people
involved so this might be good and we
are back at the beginning it ended in a
big recall with more than 500,000
pacemakers so I think that's kind of a
interesting way
but vulnerability disclosure yeah we
have now the way we just push it out and
make the vendor pay but
funny stuff is that nearly at the same
time two other researchers from America
Billy Reyes and Jonathan Patz from white
cop they're also into medical device
security and they reviewed pacemakers
from a form another vendor called
Medtronic so they did a security
assessment and they also found a lot of
packs and vulnerabilities in there
especially in the ecosystem so they were
able to deploy their own firmware I
think on the pacemakers using the
software delivery system of Medtronic
they disclosed it to the vendor and try
to work with the vendor to fix it and
you have a new mental response so they
also they reviewed it because they have
an internal vulnerability disclosure
process but they found this is no new
potential safety risk so it's no problem
if you are able to deployed a firmware
on a large scale to the pacemakers
that's no problem for them has nothing
to do with safety and that's what very
often in in this position when you a
security researcher talk to vendors then
they are not used to talk to security
researchers and they try to downplay the
findings they don't talk to you they
will come up with a lot of stories just
to don't fix the vulnerabilities and one
of the guys I think Jonathan bat said
for the time they just talked about the
box with Medtronic they could easily
just fixed it yeah it's just a question
of they won't admit they made a failure
because this would affect maybe the new
regulations the maybe that the payment
from the CEO I don't know but it's very
very frustrating also for them because
two years later the vulnerabilities were
still in there and there was no patch
out so they were in the situation
or still discussing with the vendor so
this leads me to the point what is the
better way because that's the
traditional way and I think the more
yeah ethically way in the broad
perception when you get go to the the
first approach you have one year later
you have an update sounds not the
traditional ethical way but a very
effective way to do it so what is the
better better way I don't know first in
this project I was pretty pissed because
I wasn't expecting this way if we
believe the disclosure and yeah then
lawsuit started so it was not the best
time but now I think more open about the
way they took maybe this was a good
approach I'm not sure and I'm open to
discuss afterwards give me give me your
thoughts on this in the Q&A let's sum it
up key takeaways so first point in
medical or in general is safety in
security if it's not secure it's not
safe keep this in mind there is no
safety without security and security is
not ISO 27001 certified yeah that's not
equal I am secure especially not if it
comes to product security there are some
new regulations out there you need to do
now cyber security risk assessments if
you build a new security product we're
working with vendors doing this stuff
but I think there is a lot of room for
improvement still problems they have
lots of potential new attack vectors
yeah it's like you've seen you have a
pacemaker a programmer a cloud maybe
there are some apps in the future maybe
there is a lot of interconnected stuff
so it's getting getting more complex
also for medical devices so you need to
cover every potential attack vector yeah
also the the cheap end-user devices
maybe there are the
his point and they went into the
ecosystem also this way was a new way of
monetizing vulnerabilities it was the
first time and with a big hit especially
on the media in the American media and
it started a huge discussion about
ethics and would ability disclosure
again it's great I think in enforcing
every couple of years there's a
discussion about how to do proper
vulnerability disclosure and I think
there is no one way it depends yeah the
answer from our consultant okay then one
last thing why this picture because it's
my favorite picture in information
security let me explain this picture
symbolizes my experience in the project
because first you start you have a look
at it upfront you think okay
seems properly secured there might be a
way to climb above and do some stuff but
it's a hard way and yeah maybe they have
done a good job but if you switch your
perspectives and take a different angle
one step by the to the to the side at to
stay with this picture it gets much much
easier easier so you have to really
cover every angle of your product don't
go down the rabbit holes in security
research try to take a step back get a
new look on your problem and maybe there
is an easier way just right next to the
way you're in so I don't think because
you just you invested twenty days of
research on this protocol maybe there's
a second protocol also built in that's
much easier to do okay so that's my
journey that's the story I wanted to
share with you I hope you enjoyed it if
you have some questions please ask them
now and I will be also around afterwards
and the next days to talk about this
thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you so much to be us so we have
microphone angels over there maybe yes
he's waving his hand we have a
microphone angel over there and we have
questions from the internet perhaps no
it questions from the internet internet
step up your game so over here just
about a legal situation the first
question they just sued for defamation
libel something like this like you were
lying but isn't there also an aspect of
manipulating the stock market that
that's the point yeah they claimed
because due to this false information
they manipulated the stock market yeah
I'm no expert in the law stuff
especially not in the American ones but
long story short that's not insider
trading yeah that's what everybody
usually asks because there is no inside
information taking it's a proper way to
just have a look at the books of a
company to do your own research and to
an evolution and say okay we think this
company has no outlook on the market
we'd bet against the desktop okay
another question from the sign thank you
you didn't discuss the role of the FDA
and in my experience also in cardiology
we had a lot of outdated amplifiers
because they were they had to
certification and they will still be
used even though we could build better
ones and I think this is one of the
places where it is also close place is
that the they had the system that was
allowed on the market and it is an
enormous investment to read certify it
at the FDA and I think that's the reason
why they took a shortcut and I think
it's unless this whole system with the
FDA changes its it's unavoidable that
this kind of part of keep on the market
all right so the impact of the
certification process yes that's a very
very good point and I'm completely with
you but I think there is
movement yeah they acknowledged that's a
problem and they will need to do a
different kind of different process how
to get updates out or to get security
updates out yet you need to do some kind
of separation between safety related
systems and other systems but they're on
it yeah but I think now it's still very
like the old system but they're at least
thinking about it and I know from some
very well-known and popular security
experts they are talking to them giving
them input how to come up with a better
solution right great story I don't know
if my question is too easy or too hard
because I'm not really in the sector and
sim but I was wondering when the zero
day exploit was disclosed publicly if
somebody would have maybe in the next
week used it to cause real harm to a
patient how is it likely that the
company would have tried to sue you okay
good question but I think that's an easy
one to answer because that's maybe my
fault we didn't release proof of concept
code we just said okay there is a
vulnerability have a look at this video
this video proves that there is a that
there is a vulnerability in there we
never put out the real code to make it
happen but to elaborate on this what is
the potential the worst impact you can
generate to kill someone but there are
other ways to kill people and you don't
need to do pacemaker hacking you just
shoot them or strangle them or run them
over by a car if you're not politically
exposed person I think that's maybe not
your most the the major concern of
getting killed by a random hacker yeah
if you have other problems but for
especially exposed persons this might be
a way yeah do we have any questions from
the internet now
still internet come on
I see a question over here okay you sets
they had to cut 36 bit eres a down to 24
because of the low power hardware so how
do you think they were able to fix it
with this hardware the proper algorithm
yeah that's why I always mention it I
don't didn't retest retest it and I had
a look at a lot of the code and I'm
curious by myself but I think they
needed I think there is still a way in
there how to get the kind of a backup
access I think they just change codes
and protected them a little bit better
but if you have the same hardware you
have the same hardware yeah you you
can't just do a different register size
and switch from two different key
lengths I think that's not possible but
I think maybe they did some compensative
measures in there yeah yeah our very
popular microphone angel over here has
yet another customer yes you were
talking about the US legal system I
assume I just want to add that if you
were working in Europe or especially in
Germany you would have problems with the
OHIP arrest which is like copyright law
when reverse engineering
there was a great talk on the last
Congress about two research groups from
Berlin and Munich running into
difficulties and they are being sued on
the basis of copyright so be careful
around there I have to follow up on this
the law changed this year so it's better
now for researchers but what I what I
wanted to ask yeah great thanks to the
you what I want to ask that you look
it's the CPU so what hardware is inside
these things this is very so low-power
or what is it
they have custom chips so but it's I
can't remember the the specific
processor but I can look it up if you
want yeah but but they did a custom
solution for the stuff could it be that
our lonely microphone angel has found
yes a question just a very short
question so how much money did Muddy
Waters make out of this I was I'm still
curious by myself there are no numbers
out I just know that I didn't get paid
for all of my work yeah because as soon
as they get got suit
they froze all accounts and they set it
up long term because the company was
founded in Saint Kitts and Nevis that's
an island in the Caribbean Sea not even
in the US and they once explained me by
beer they had every lawyer on this
island so they can't be sued by an
lawyer from this island so they had a
plan in mind already but I don't know
how much money they made I think their
plan didn't work out as they wanted it
because the the stock mark the stock
price recovered as well but I think it
was a huge outburst of curiosity at the
beginning because dropping by to me to
billions and there were there was a
merger ongoing st. Ruth was bought by
Abbott so I think that was not the best
time frame and to get hit by such a
market drop I see all right we have time
for one more is it gonna come from the
internet oh all right any one else no
then please
another great warm heartfelt
round of applause for Tobias thank you
very much
[Music]
you