[Music]
testing for software developers who
don't know security at all so this is a
very interesting topic that has been
wildly popular the last couple of months
and I'm personally very interested in
this topic too so I'm curious to see
what he's going to tell us today and how
all of you can make your projects more
secure
so please welcome sigh thanks ok
it's I can't really see you guys but it
looks like it filled up pretty good for
like 2 p.m. talk buy some Java stuff I
will just give you a quick introduction
to me or myself and we can show you why
and what and how we can do all this
fancy automated security testing stuff
it's not necessary this order if you
have questions maybe you can raise your
hands and maybe I will see them but
probably not or you can scream at me and
let's give it a go
I'm Chris I'm a system developer I do a
Java back-end stuff mostly I do
kubernetes and cloud stuff and I'm
trying to get into security I am also a
co-organizer of the cards were DevOps
Meetup
[Music]
I work for cynics just a quick shout out
we do mostly Java development for our
customers with therefore this special
needs and stuff our slogan is code with
attitude so we try not to work for arms
dealers or people who do nuclear energy
stuff yeah
you also can be also do consulting and
we have glitter shirts and they paid for
our camp tickets so just a quick shout
out if you ever in southern
and you're looking for a job so thank
you for listening any questions no I got
questions is any of you directly
involved with a software product
developing it running it maintaining it
surprised who of you uses Java okay
the talk will our first part will run
mainly with maven context so I hope it's
not too far-fetched for people who
haven't seen this I think it's quite
self-explanatory who've you use a
stalker or kubernetes or something
container in production okay
who view scans your software regularly
for security problems or known
vulnerabilities who of you runs software
in production where they know they have
known security vulnerabilities okay I
think we get back to this later on ok so
what's the problem with software
security issues what could go wrong with
software that has not only technical
issues but also security stuff where
people could break in and do bad stuff
well you could use your lose your
business data or your customers business
data you could also use your actual end
customer data which is like very hard
topic I think it has been quite
interesting in Germany in like forever
but since 2018 the GDP are kicked in in
Europe and apparently a lot of companies
have never thought about securing their
users or customers personal later I have
an example about this later on security
issues could cause service interruptions
like somebody is trying to attack your
web server if your web server goes down
your business is you can serve
the customers
make money yeah well anyone can think
about what happens you could use so you
could have industry malfunction we have
the prettiest infrastructure in Germany
where we it's or its infrastructure
that's used for your daily life and
that's absolutely necessary like sewage
cleaning stuff and the electricity and
stuff like that and maybe you've heard
about deaths that actually happened
because automated cars drove over
someone because they thought it was like
some kind of paper bag flying over the
street that's a technical error but this
could also possibly be used by a hacker
if you have a security issue in your
automated car that or people have shown
that they could remote these stop cars
start the ignition brakes and whatever
okay does anyone know about Equifax it's
like the German Ruffa they do credit
monitoring for their consumers so if you
apply for credit if you have trouble
paying your bills
it will could happen that if you live in
the u.s. you show up in their databases
in 2017 they were hacked they hackers
some hackers breached their web server
through a vulnerability in Apache struts
it's an open source project where you
can build web views turns out that
stretch was or had been patched there
was an official patch for struts for
like four weeks and apparently Equifax
didn't know about this or nobody cared
and people were able to infiltrate their
servers and take out a lot of personal
data like I think 134 43 million social
security numbers
and if you know about the US Social
Security system it's a number that you
get assigned by birth and you can never
change that and there's a lot of
services where you can like change your
passwords you call them on the phone and
you have to give them the last four
digits of your social security number
and that's their authentication for you
so this is pretty bad there was also a
lot of credit card numbers involved and
well you can think about what happens
next
vulnerabilities can also happen in the
platform that you use your to run your
servers Germans might know this under
the name Panama papers or maybe everyone
I don't think we have time for this but
they had a bad drupal version they did
not upgrade this for their web servers
and well that turned out not so good for
them so why would you not patch your
software
well there's negligence so you just like
you don't care you don't have the time
it's priority problem your product
managers like no we need to feature
maybe you might be preoccupied by doing
performance tests or something that you
purge has higher it could happen you
might not have the training like when I
started interesting myself in this whole
security thing I had no idea what to do
I'm not even I've been doing this for
like two years now and I'm far from
being an expert in software security
I've more like the average basic
knowledge so you might like the inside
or you could just say security it's not
my department
I've seen people at customers that claim
that they are software developers and
the company has a security team a pen
testing team they have a test
engineering team and yeah people that
change your diapers in the morning I
don't know okay and there's the to
tackle all these problems there's the
open web applications
your project it's a I think it's a
nonprofit organization and they give out
the top ten list of application security
risks and sometimes they renew it so I
think the last one was from 2017 and
what we are trying to tackle today is
the top nine it's about using components
with known vulnerabilities so this is
like somebody has found a vulnerability
and like struts and they report it to
someone at sea patchy or at the struts
project and they would the report is
publicly available so everyone can see
it and everyone can also write a scanner
for this you might ask the question why
do we start with a nine and not with the
top one problems well you can have all
the top eight problems and many many
more inside third-party libraries that
you use and so we try to get the easiest
way to tackle this problem and it's also
you can learn a lot by this okay so what
can we do to address the problem we can
search for known vulnerabilities there's
public databases where we can everyone
also the bad guys but also the good guys
can look for vulnerabilities and fix
them and see what what they have to do
what versions they have to patch to
that's pretty easy technically because
there's two linked for this we have to
implement a process to fix it you know
like you find a vulnerability but you
need the time to fix it desperate he is
there's features to do there's other
stuff to to address and you have to find
a way who is going to fix or to patch or
to delete vulnerable software and I
think that's the hardest part for a
company and I personally will also treat
security issues like technical debt
like the longer it takes you to patch
this the harder it is to upgrade or to
patch because there will be new
vulnerabilities there will be new
features every one of you knows this
like if you if you wait for weeks
to patch software technical issues
vulnerabilities whatever and the
software progresses it's much harder to
fix it and to update it so and also well
I think the best thing is also always to
automate everything so I don't I don't
want to know like it's Monday morning
10:00 a.m. I have to run a vulnerability
test no it should be automatically you
know like I don't know it's it's the
same as with unit tests integration
tests performance tests this software it
changes so it should be automatically
built it should be automatically test it
and it should be automatically scanned
for security issues okay so let's check
this out how we can find dependency in
third-party libraries I've chosen to
make a quick maven project I hope if you
haven't used maven or Java before you
still get the message we will scan for
components in docker images because like
stuff like Drupal could be packaged into
a darker image where you put your actual
web server or website web software or
website in and if you've got time we can
also scan or API later on because we are
doing a Web API or web app okay and well
I said we want to automate it so I try
to show you something that could be in a
continuous delivery pipeline right now
so this is from the Jenkins blue ocean
plugin it's an open source tool every
Java developer probably has used it
before and these are steps that I think
are in some respect necessary for modern
software development like you you want
to unit test your stuff you need to
package your new software so you can use
it you need to upload this RFA
so it's safe for later you run a docker
build if you use docker and push the
docker image to the docker registry so
it can be deployed to some servers and
this is just a demo project obviously
usually you would add more tests and
maybe it would be deployed to production
or to test systems automatically in this
pipeline so we could add additional
steps to this pipeline and increase the
steps and improve our software security
scanning part I have added three demo
steps one is running a dependency check
one is running a container security scan
and one would be running an API security
test it could also look like this yellow
usually means in Jenkins that the build
has been unstable so it has been built
and there's no major breaking point but
something's fishy so you have to look
into the build I'll show you this later
on
I think the build should always build
there's people who say if you have a
vulnerability or if you have bad tests
well test should break the build in my
in my opinion but vulnerabilities are a
little tricky because it might you might
have to fix two vulnerabilities at once
but you don't you can do both at a time
sometimes like maybe there's one of them
is missing a patch but you still want to
fix the other one so your build has to
run so in my opinion you should have
some visual or some alert that the built
has not fully or the pipeline has not
fully run like by setting it on to
unstable and at the teams I usually work
at we have big dashboards for our
development processing and we usually
show like traffic lights so dashboards
that will show by color if the builds on
the most most needed branches like NASA
branch or any stage systems were fully
built and so it would you would directly
get a visual feedback if something has
happened by the automatic build process
so you don't have to necessarily check
every build but rather you you get a
visual alert if something went wrong and
then you have to like implement this
process how to actually fix this problem
or address the problem okay so what's a
vulnerability vulnerability Wikipedia's
has the quality or state of being
exposed to the possibility of being
attacked or harmed either physically or
emotionally so something might happen to
your software and it's in third-party
libraries the problem is that it might
be publicly known because you haven't
touched the software and well how would
you know this there's a public reference
database our multiple ones that lists
common vulnerabilities and exposures or
well a CVE common vulnerabilities and
exposures is actually a description for
a vulnerability so I've taken the
Equifax example with Apache struts so
you see there is the one of this or this
is the vulnerability description for the
Apache struts problem in this particular
version you see there's on the left
lower left side there's a base score
that says something critical something
and you don't have to be a security
expert to know that you should probably
address this problem and it has some
information and you get infos about
what's the actual problem in this struts
version like there's something content
crafted package you could send to this
thing to run code on somebody else's web
server
and there's also some scoring and some
exploitability z-scores and this much
information that you don't actually need
at the first place when you get started
it's more like an in-depth information
thing later on okay I'll jump into the
Maven and dependency part and this is
just an example how many dependencies in
a modern java application what you look
like I have written or actually I have
just are generated a maven project and I
have added some some dependencies and
third-party libraries that I think are
the minimum that I would use in every
new Java
Springwood application that also runs
something web service so we have the I'm
sorry we have this spring boot starter
spring boot is a framework on top of
Java that actually does a lot for you so
you don't have to program everything and
just can focus on your business case and
don't have to do the Java basics and
it's the most common Java framework
right now so you can add these starters
to this that's third-party libraries
that bring certain functionality like
obviously we make an API so we have to
secure it so we need a starter for
security that does authorization and
authentication stuff out of the box so
you can just add little snippets into
your code and Springwood will actually
have this all programmed out we want to
do an API so we need a web starter to
run a web server actuator can give you
runtime metrics and information about
the health of your application I think
this one is absolutely necessary if you
want to monitor your
application later on and then we have a
test scope so this will not actually run
in the production compilation of the
software where we can test the actual
spring boot framework and also this
spring security that comes with spring
boot security starter and it's not you
don't have to necessarily understand all
the parts of this and and and become a
Java developer to actually use this I
think every language has that has a
dependency management framework can do
stuff like this
oh and obviously we added the vulnerable
Apache stratts version so we can find
something that we actually want to fix
or whitelist
maybe okay and the problem is right now
that these six or seven dependencies
bloat the stuff you see them on the left
side and they block the software and
they download like 80 more dependencies
themselves and they're called transient
dependencies so every dependency brings
more libraries and they bring more
libraries and so on so it's a big
bloated library and well I wanted to say
up but it's depending on what
you're actually using Springwood is very
very well maintained and they are have a
quite quick reaction time if they find
something okay after set this six maven
dependencies you can find this on github
and I will tell you something more about
it later on and almost 80 transitive or
70 transitive dependencies so it's like
80 overall and they can all have
vulnerabilities and you want to at least
patch the ones that are publicly known
for having security issues so it's like
low-hanging fruit and everyone can find
this and you should too so what can we
do to find vulnerable dependencies or
third-party libraries there's tooling
for this and this is a really big hype
right now in the software industry
this quite a lot of vendors who add
products for this github I'm not big on
advertising for paid services but github
does this for open source public
software so if you have created github
repository as the owner you will see
when github finds a vulnerability in
your dependency system if you use one of
the big programming frameworks and they
will show you an order and alert for
this and if you set the correct
notification settings you would also get
an email for this this is pretty nice
and a couple months ago they added a
system that can also patch your
vulnerabilities or patch your
third-party libraries and well you might
think if the owner sees one of the
problems that's ok because it's still
hidden nobody else sees it but if
someone Fox your repository they are the
owner of the fork so they will get a
notification if github finds the same
vulnerability in their repo for the demo
and for this whole talk I'm using
dependency check because it's an open
source tool it's in in the open web
application security project so if you
contribute or if you donate money to the
OS project some of it will allow the
maintainer of dependency check to make
the software better and it's really well
maintained
they have quick they react quickly if
you ask them something or if you setup a
full request or something like that
ok how does it work this this database
is run by a an American government
organization publicly where you can get
the CVE data so that's the database with
the actual vulnerabilities and their
descriptions and scoring our health and
dependency check downloads this into a
local database and then you can run a
dependency check in maven you can also
use docker if you are not using maven
you can use a command line client to
check your
fair I think for maven or Gradle that's
the same for Java suffer it's really
easy to use it this way but it's up to
you in the end you should check this in
anyway it's not necessarily necessarily
the best one okay let's just see how
this works out okay so I have for the
guys who know Java and maven I have
programmed a maven goal for this oops
and let's just run this check and see
what it tells us and it takes a couple
seconds and the demo repo I have
disabled the automatic update so if you
run this for if you check this out and
if you haven't never used dependency
check before you will be told to update
your database beforehand so some
vulnerabilities were found so our build
broke so this will end in a exit code
one
so anything different from zero is bad
and here you can see the vulnerabilities
that were actually found so we have
Jackson data bind this is the can you
read this in the back thumbs up okay
it's it's a jsonparser that you can use
to for for your application it's pretty
well known and this is one of the
transient dependencies I have not
actually chosen to use this but it comes
with one of the spring boot dependencies
then their spring security and actually
this is an actual vulnerability and
there is a patch for this in two nine
nine one hotfix but the spring boot
version that actually brings this
dependency has not yet been upgraded for
this so this is a if you if you have a
process for fixing this you could
manually upgrade this to two nine nine
one for example and then this should
work out if we have time later on or if
you join my workshop
tomorrow you we can we can play around
with this the spring security core this
is actually a false positive
so spring security core has a or has had
a problem in five zero something and
they have fixed it but somehow this is
still in the vulnerability database so
the vulnerability database will still
have the information that this is
actually problematic and this is for
authentication stuff and authorization
so if this was still an issue and you're
using authorization annotations in Java
you should probably upgrade this and
then there's our good struts
vulnerability which has like ten
vulnerabilities and it's really old it's
from 2017 and the comments file upload
is just another one that comes with
strats so we won't care about this
what's the cool thing about dependency
check I forgot
the app itself does nothing it doesn't
even have a world it's just this is the
basic what you get if you use these
dependencies use you get a web a web
server you get a login screen because we
use security and you could never login
because you have nowhere to find any
user data okay
dependency check not also gives you the
command line references but also
generates an HTML report that you can
use for other stuff and if you like
search for the struts problem whoops
there you go you find a description
what's the actual problem here this is
this one is passed from this CV about
struts and there's some more information
about what happens here and then they
have a list of all the vulnerabilities
found and there's a very good
description what's up actually happening
here and some scoring and this is the
point where you can actually learn just
by by using this dependency check and
checking out the the HTML report
you will find these vulnerable
third-party libraries and the report
will also tell you what what could
potentially happen here and sometimes
there is also a link to exploit DB so
exploit this is the big the big one the
critical 10 zero password thing that I
mentioned earlier and you can also find
working exploits that you can use to
test please only your own servers nobody
else's and usually this is a very good
way to learn about vulnerabilities if
you find them if you have no idea how to
actually what the problem is you look
for in the report for exploit the
Billings or check some of the other
descriptions and some of them are very
very helpful in understanding this stuff
want one more thing
the report also lets you has a prepared
xml statement that you can use to
whitelist false positives string
security there you go so we can we want
to watch your spring security core
because we have read reports that this
is actually false positive so we go to
the suppression button and if the CSS is
working which ayah that is we get some
XML data that we can use for a
configuration file and we can just copy
this and add this to the I think I've
opened it before to a suppressions file
that we have configured in our Java file
and now this CVE
that I have suppressed here so this one
will no longer show up because the
dependency check will now whitelist it
because I've configured this
xml file - before whitelisting or
something how I miss something that okay
I did an upgrade of the dependency check
plugin earlier to prepare for the talk
and apparently something in the XML
description changed so you just have to
trust me that this will would actually
have whitelist of the false positive
okay let's go on with some more fun
stuff okay you can also use the report
to run some report and other reporting
oddity to use it in other reporting
tools like this is sonar a code quality
plug code quality tool that shows you
trends and stuff and we don't have time
for this so docker
who in here has actually scanned their
docker containers for problems three
people very good docker is well you use
you stock review so you know how it
works you pull some container is like
that someone on the internet has built
for you and this is like the euro style
of running software and there's also a
scanner it's called Claire it's has been
written by core OS now owned by Red Hat
now owned by IBM I think they do
container stuff in kubernetes stuff and
so apparently they needed some
containers scanning utilities and it
works similarly they also query the NIST
database but they host the vulnerable
one durability data in a another
database on your local servers and they
run a Claire server and you can run a
client that actually feeds your daughter
to the server and the server will scan
all the doctor layers and tell you
what's happening okay
so I have started a class server and a
database on my on my machine usually you
would have to run these servers in your
infrastructure somewhere and I have
packaged this app that we wrote earlier
into a container and I have used there
you go I've used a basic java image for
Java eight it's one of the official
images from open JDK and let's see what
happens to this so this takes a couple
of seconds so the and we're pretty late
so we'll just go to the you see a lot of
red and earlier I ran this test and it
found that these are the image content
ninety-six vulnerabilities and they are
all already in the base image so this
has no none of the vulnerabilities that
we found in the java application
this is everything you get when you
download a new open JDK package and this
is the slim one so it's not loaded
and there's fun stuff like gee lip see
obviously and util-linux and you can
actually also whitelist false positives
or you can also whitelist stuff that you
know that are not not applying to your
software like if you have a problem with
the SSH daemon you someone could
probably break into your server but in
darker you usually don't open the port
so it should not be so hard to just not
scan for it anymore and then you can you
can also set thresholds I will not show
the examples now because
little behind so you could choose only
to see a high or critical or medium
vulnerabilities and upwards and
everything else is Auto approved and to
run this in continuous integration you
might have to add some more fun stuff
typically if you run stuff in modern
build tools like git lab CI github
automated tools you won't necessarily
have the power or the the time to set up
infrastructure and you don't need it so
you maybe don't want to run a class
server that you have to care for all the
time you don't want to manage another
Postgres database so what you can do is
inside continuous integration just
before the scan the actual scan happens
you can start a database container and a
clear scanner container and this guy our
mean C is something I can indeed as a
French sounding name and I can pronounce
it you can find his repos on github he
actually came up with this solution so
just before you run the scan you start
those docker containers and after the
scan you just stop them again and I've
obviously just started them on my
machine so after the scan I would just
stop them the demo repo contains a
Jenkins file so if you used Jenkins you
can also run all these tests you might
have to play around with little
injections with the credentials of the
Jenkins user and the permissions that
they have there's also public
repositories that do the scan for you
like clay is an alternative to docker
hub so you can choose to host your
repositories with Quay and they will do
a scan for you
github or get lab offers a a method to
scan your container for you and give you
a hint about broken stuff
okay and I think we have some more time
to do a quick quick API scan as I
mentioned earlier I've started the
application on my local machine and I
could now run a zap I'm so sorry
okay so let's start over
sorry we can use another almost tool
it's called that attack proxy to
actually attack our API and dynamically
scan it to find actual vulnerabilities
that it's serving like stuff like that
offers SQL injection or cross-site
scripting and what we is not important
what we do here is just use docker again
because we've great docker and container
fans so we can download a docker
container that they provide that
actually has the scanner built in and
then you can just run it against your
website and I will just show you the
report that is actually coming out of
this and I've taken the liberty a couple
of weeks ago just scanned this annex
website so please don't hack us and the
scanner shows and this is very very cool
about this tool also a great description
about the actual vulnerabilities because
like I have no idea of what the X frame
method option header is does any of you
another two people very good but it
actually it's is I think in this
solution there is always a description
what the actual problem here is and what
you can do to fix it and there's also
references where this is where there's
the description for this and where you
can find are you okay good where you can
find more options what you can do I will
run one more
attack I think yeah this also takes some
time so I've already done this before
for you and if you run the the this
against the cynic side
nowadays we run WordPress so you will
find a lot of warnings that might or
might not be critical we have a company
that does the page for us so maybe we
should address them with this and then
again this is just a spider so this one
this attack will go to I think I
configured Zune XD somewhere there and
this will start at a landing page that
you configure at a target and we it will
just spider all the links inside this
page and just Traverse into deeper into
the into the page you give it you can
also run this and feed it an open API
spec so if you develop an your own
application you usually know which API
endpoints you are serving you might
generate this using tools like swagger
if you know this but let's say you have
like three endpoints like login or I
don't know shop and web page something
like that you might tell the tool which
which API endpoints or which URLs to
look for so you save the time that it
would use to spider all these links and
the longer it runs obviously the more
it's able to find okay I'm a little
sorry that I had to rush to the end if
you want to try this more in-depth
Daniel and I are hosting a two hour
workshop about this where we will show
you more the usage of the tools and you
can ask questions and might just get
your hands dirty and try this yourself
tomorrow I think it's 3:15 p.m. it has
been rescheduled for a couple times so
you may 3 headed monkeys are scheduled I
guess if you don't heck if you can make
it you can also stop by our village
vacant business world and ask your
questions and well usually I would
discuss this in the end this is like
this is about the process what can you
do maybe one sentence about this in my
current team if if a vulnerability is
found the creator of the current pull
request is also responsible to fix this
as soon as possible we have a zero
vulnerabilities policy so anything that
is found has to be fixed immediately if
we found something on our production
code we will also have a job that's
against this nightly and the first one
to be in the office or the one on call
also is a responsibility to responsible
to at least look into the issue so they
could find out rights it's a false
positive
they might just suppress it they could
find out that it's a horrible horrible
bad possibility to bring your own your
own enterprise down so they might want
to patch it immediately but this is
mainly up to you and I think as I
mentioned earlier this is like the most
interesting part for a company and a
development team thank you
all right we have a couple of minutes
left for questions so if you want to ask
a question please come to one of the
microphones in the front or in the back
and ask your question
all right I don't see any questions at
the moment so if you well there is one
please go well I thank you for the talk
my question is about handling false
positives again you already showed an
example and especially dealing with
something like zap you get a lot of
false positive
but sometimes doors are pretty hard like
stuff in libraries which you actually
don't use right so if you use AP is that
are not vulnerable and I mean talking to
development teams I know that they spend
most of their time handling exceptions
do you have some general recommendation
or could you share some experience
regarding that especially in dynamic
scanning with URLs or api's or web
servers this is like really
time-consuming I can maybe share example
that I've seen in a team of a friend of
mine
they run API tests every night and when
they started this they just sat down for
a couple of days actually and because
they have a very big application that
has grown over the years with a big big
API and they scanned this and with with
the open eyes open API specification
that they had generated earlier they
scanned their app and then they actually
sat down and checked every vulnerability
that zaps bad out so and and I think
that's the only way to do it you have to
take the time and and get all of those
and sorry if you're at a point where you
have zero new vulnerabilities or zero
vulnerabilities found that you think are
worth fixing then you can do for example
a weekly task or a nightly build that
checks your API and if something new is
found you have to fix it according to
your policy but I don't think there's a
good way to do this differently
well you can you can always if you have
like libraries that are vulnerable in
and that you don't really need I'm a
biggest the biggest fan of deleting your
code if you don't need it or deleting or
black holing api's that you don't need
so I think it's it's not if you are if
you're new to this you should always
maybe talk to your security team or if
you're not sure to the networking team
or if you're the networking team
yourself you should probably think about
your firewall rules and stuff like that
but I think you have to address every
vulnerability that is found that's
painful
alright then maybe let's do one last
question from the back okay thank you
for your talk do you have any we have
any experience with growl VM or Krakow's
because if you have all this bloat in
your containers it's easy to get
confused and to run the bare necessities
it could be interesting to have XY
experiences with Maul as bare metal I
will bear coat containers without any
operating system or I think it's it's a
general rule to use as as little
suffered to run your code on as as you
do itself away one of the darker best
practices I think in Dockery you can use
the official like in Java you can use
the open JDK official Alpine images and
they come if you download them right now
they won't come with any vulnerabilities
the a little problem with the with the
scanners that I have used is that stuff
like growl DM doesn't have a container
or its stuff that Google provides if you
use gyp if you know this one it will
dynamically create containers and they
are not really containers in the darker
sense so the scanner can actually scan
them I think these are projects that you
have to rely on the maintainer to find
vulnerabilities and fix it but it's also
it's also more easily
to handle it because you can just
upgrade your running systems like
nightly or something like that or every
week every hour alright we're out of
time so thanks so much Sai for the talk
[Applause]
[Music]
you