[Music]
internet scanning or how to become your
isp please give a big round of applause
to Joanna streak can you Kenny audience
it's perfect
yeah welcome to the talk first Internet
scanning challenges and new approaches
or how to become your own RSP my name is
Johannes click I'm concentrating on
internet scanning and my second favorite
topic is industrial control system ot
hacking have discovered in the past
several her abilities industrial control
systems and fire vaults are protected
exam and also have given some talks to
pH days that's Russia and in blackhat us
USA about how to find industrial
controls on the internet and then to
compromise them and also I did some
publications on academic conferences
like the ACM internet measurement
conference so what is the motivation
first to talk how to set up an
infrastructure for scanning the Internet
repeatedly so my problem was that showed
an IO is does not provide raw data for
free and as a researcher you are very
interested in raw data because you
cannot be sure that maybe comprehend
stated or manipulated data you will get
and the next problem is children IO had
does not provide clean snapshots of the
Internet this means they're scanning the
internet but they are not deleting old
results they are putting every time
newer results into it and it means that
if you have and you think on dynamic IP
addresses you will have the same server
twice or whatever however multiple times
in the database this means you have no
real clean data census is very good also
academic projects or in the past now
they got startup but they also since
they're in our startups they are not
providing the raw data for free and they
also have some inconsistencies in the
database I will show later and the next
point is you need to think about that
people or the persons that are running
these platforms they know what are you
looking for and the question is what are
doing what are they doing with the
stator and the next question is who
might be interested in this data right
so that's why I better to to scan on
your own the Internet
here a good example from show down here
you can see for talat the children says
you have appropriate five million telnet
hosts you're looking on sensors they say
our it's a properly Laurens
approximately 3.1 million and also our
own scans show that we have 3.1 million
tenant house from the internet if you
there you can see that children has much
more systems in the database course by
the dynamic IPS and not providing clean
snapshots can source ain't in it that's
why if you're clicking on children on
some host you see very often that they
are not reachable and so on you may be
know it when you're working with show
down on a next point here you can see
inconsistencies on sanz's on the left
side you can see I look for please give
me the number of all HTTP host that has
reported and responded on port 443 on
the right side I did this similar
request
I said please provide me all holes that
had given you on via HTTP 54 for 3 a
status code status code is that 200 ok
or 400 for 315 and it's and you need to
get a status code for a full handshake
on HTTP so both requests should result
with the same number but they are
different you see on the left side you
have 41 million on quite the equal
request you have 35 million and there's
a big difference it shows there's some
inconsistencies and that's why I cannot
use these data for my research and I
have not enough know the raw data access
and that was my final motivation there
was the first quarter of this year there
was a new project called packet L packet
on are some researchers said yeah
there's no raw data we were scanning the
internet just using masking it's getting
the internet from one single source IP
and doing it in a time span of two hours
and then we are providing the easy data
for all for free and then they got some
problems with spam hoes because spam
house is rarely crazy they have a lot of
black hole IPS on the internet and then
if you say receive one or two sincere
say oh you're a really really bad
partner you're you're malicious whatever
and then you're putting it on understand
list and the block list and so on and
their problem run packet tongue because
there is there is a there is preset on
our here your butcher private we will
cut your virtual private server because
you're going to get you have you cannot
scan anymore and there were also some
first of stories about packet tell and
then they try to make spam house angry
and in the end Brian
traps talks them and then they stop
their service very funny story okay so
this talk is about how to set a so how
to set up an infrastructure for long
term repeatedly scans I'm very
interested in the distribution of
vulnerable or exotic network services
for instance like industrial control
systems or building management systems
in the internet or was the time of
different autonomous systems or BGP
prefixes and this talk will explain how
to set up this framework in the first
50% we will talk about the setup itself
and the next 50% we will talk about the
results of our scans so what is history
first tribe was like every other body
has this year probably in the room just
taking a fast gunner and running and
running it on the internet from a single
source IP but that's a really bad idea
you will get blocked very first and we
receive a lot of abuse messages and a
virtual private service provider will
kill your service and you are not lucky
in see at second try just rent like 20
virtual private servers for 4 to 10
years Mark's per month maybe globally
distributed the results might be getting
better because you're using more source
IP addresses but nevertheless you have a
lot of big problems of abuse messages
because 0 so your service provider will
receive abuse messages they say all your
malicious you're infected we have to
kill yourselves please clean
please clean your virtual private server
or you will get kicked out like see
pecker tell guys the third try was to
rent at slash twenty nine from an isp to
get your own who is DB entry with your
own abuse mail contact then we thought
okay we are lucky not everything will be
fine but the problem was that these
automated IDs intrusion systems they are
not only reporting to the abuse mail
dead standing the u.s. entry they are
also sending messages to the maintainer
of the IP address block this means your
direct RSP and then we got the same
problem that said he that our I speak or
the forms that we are malicious we have
a botnet and whatever and then we got a
lot of trouble yeah well in the end we
we managed a lot of abused messages on
our own but in the end it was too
complicated to get in some discussions
with the RSP sir the final solution is
we got our own ISP
so we become a rhyme Bama a rap member
and get our own autonomous system a
complete slash twenty two networks this
means 1024 IP addresses signup fee is
approximately two thousand euros
membership membership fee is like about
1400 bucks and then we went to different
colocation spaces got a first slash
twenty nine from another RSP and then we
bought a server for thirty thousand
euros for see all the big data
management and yes and then we used
outer replies for our abuse emails this
means if somebody feels annoyed by our
scans he sends abuse message and get an
automatic reply which explains what we
are doing why we are doing the research
and how he can and what is the way to
get excluded from our scans by putting
them on our blacklist
the result is that the abuse messages
messages reduced by approximately 90
percent and that also the IDS message
messages that told us that we are get
blocked and so on also massively reduced
and we are can now do complete with you
complete abuse message messages of our
own and this shows that using a slash 24
sir like 1000 IP addresses for source
addresses for scan
works really good so what is the
infrastructure sir first we have a front
end then you can click okay I want to
scan this IP address space very often
just saying zero zero zero slash zero
this means incomplete internet then this
goes to the scan Marsters the scan
master looks what scan algorithm we have
choosen then he will take the IP for
address base cut it into small pieces
randomize the IP addresses in this into
small pieces and then it sends to the
search node cluster search node cluster
scans internet and sends the data to the
aggregator
first of all it is very important that
if the search node fails that the work
package the search node has to work on
to source the number of IP addresses
will get reassigned by a scan master
through another search node this is a
kind of failsafe because very often
maybe people using jet map or a
distributed map scanners they know it
then it's a servant node cut pro and
then you have to do some manual work and
then you have to choose to look or what
was the last IP number where and how was
lost prime number and how to in the end
go on with your own skin and that's very
important if you want to set up a global
scale infrastructure you need a kind of
scan master that is managing the scans
looking that everything is working and
if not then he needs to kind have like a
kind of recovery procedure so the search
node cluster itself consists of
different search nodes into two
differents colocation centers at first
we have person scanner just sending the
masses of sins out on the internet that
self-written ago and for and then we
have an app scanner it's a customized
death-grip version because that group is
very good tool that surprised a lot of
protocols and we added some some frozen
protocols and and use this kind of
application scanner and then all the
data goes to the aggregator the task of
the aggregator is that if a search not
failed and another search node has has
has has taken over in the NZ burg then
you have maybe multiple results and the
aggregator aggregates all data and
pays attention that you will not have
multiple results in the database then we
have data enrichment that's very
important just scanning the Internet is
not sufficient so maybe you have know
all the ports and then you have the
application data like TLS certificates
information and so on but we have two
enrichment with further data we have
access to G Whois database so the inert
objects this means if you're doing who
is 8.8.8.8 as the companies that own see
who is blog and then maybe stand some
information for what is see who is blog
used then we have also reverse dns 0ip
let's say where our CIP approximately
located and we using a BGP prefix
information so we're saying ok - which
announced BGP prove prefix dustless IP
belong and also we put the information
together and which autonomous systems
belongs which autonomous system belongs
to the IP address asteroid solution we
have choosen elasticsearch because it's
one of the best databases I have ever
seen recently since the new version 7.3
it's very good and here you can see that
as a protocols we are currently support
we are concentrating very very strongly
on industrial protocols but we also
support normal protocol most of the
protocols are from z-trip itself but we
have also some special protocols like
the phoenix protocol and some other so
now thinking about some numbers and
settings so if you know you're really
not IP addresses we have approximately
4.3 billion IP addresses and very often
people are sending all the IP addresses
out but the problem is that only 2.8
billion of these IP addresses are routed
in the Internet this means you can only
reach at a maximum of 2.8 billion IP
addresses on the internet so if you get
some kind of BGP feed like if you have
your own bgp router or have a fee to the
bgp router or use cairo data you can
reduce the number of TCP syn packets by
35 percent because when you're only
sends the TCP IP packets in the routed
IP space then you can save a lot of a
lot of TC
soon packets you don't need to scan the
private IP addresses and so on right so
first thing you have to reconsider set a
TCP syn packet is approximately 30 pi
it's big this means 70 pius x 2.8
billion IP addresses means that you're
just sending data with a single tcp/ip
scan 200 gigabyte of data you will us
send it to the internet but the
interesting point is that that you will
at the maximum get only reply from 2% of
all appear packets you will send out
it's very easy calculation the most used
protocol on the Internet is HTTP and so
you can see that we have 55 56 million
HTTP hosts divided by 2.8 billion routed
IP addresses as 2% this means we have
just a hit rate of 2% 98 percent of all
TCP syn packets from the 2.8 billion IP
addresses are overhead in the end so
next question is using one son or two
soon every time it's a discussion we
have tested it sending doubled since
makes no sense because results get not
doubled right you see it's negligible in
my perspective you maybe receive some
better results but we can also see an
ssa ssh you can you are able to receive
worse results at the same time kind and
it's permeating the standard aeration so
and also compared to sensors you can see
that the results our results are really
comparable to chances that this kind of
setup works very interesting census uses
slash 23 we are losing it / 21st which
means we have s twice and source IP
addresses and our results are also some
minor better but you have to keep in
mind census is running much more long as
a service you're getting much more
internet and they have maybe a bigger
black lists so what about skete very
often people say mass gain maximum speed
I can't don't recommend that if you use
the packet they tell data they provide
that you can
look it up then you can see that we have
your scanning with scan speed a la
approximately 70 am but taking six to
seven hours and then you can see that if
your scan from a single source of pee
like everybody can do in a time period
of two hours your data will be decorated
by ten to thirty percent
this means you will see in a worst case
only 2/3 of the whole internet so
scanning strategies very interesting
point you see that the imagine a new
zero day remote explored a Brazil day
arrives on earth right and then you may
be interested to scan the internet very
repeatedly not not like every week but
like every day or every 10 hours or 20
hours whatever then it's a very good
idea to scan the complete internet once
and then to Riskin only see bgp prefixes
was at least one host in it and this
will save you additional 25 to 50
percent of the routed ipv4 address space
and scan time and I call those bgp
prefix hitler's ever in a paper out
about it and published on the internet
measurement conference if you're
interested please have a look into very
interesting so next problem was we are
our own ISP
and suddenly the police arrived said mmm
you're doing malicious attempts not they
do not ask the sort of doing malicious I
said who is the owner of this IP address
who has used this IP address and then I
because we are our own Internet service
provider and then we receive it and then
we talked with them and said now it's we
are as the owner of the IP address and
we have used that for the Internet's
against and they got some kind of afraid
because normally you are not allowed to
get informed that there are some police
investigations about you but then we
explained that we are a chief security
researcher that we are doing good stuff
that we are providing the information
that we informing people and so on and
then for them at worst okay and we have
never heard about it but in the first
moment I have read susima
I got well was really amazing
hardware setup very important if you
want to do a lot of internet scans all
of this protocol application data in
Richmond runs on the size of C protocol
it's quite different and you can see
it's all really big numbers a single
HTTP again is about like seven hundred
gigabyte HTTP we hundred gigabyte and
tell others only like two gigabyte of
data so therefore we have bought a big a
big server consisting of MDF XE seven
five five one so we bought two of these
CPUs we have one terabyte RAM and we use
fifty percent of C of the memory for the
elasticsearch people itself
and they use 50 percent just for caching
then we have 40 terabyte of SSD data
because the is the stuff that it cannot
sit in the RAM needs to be stored on the
SSD because we need a lot of high i/o
interaction and then we are running it
on a right now for just performance in
treatments and for long term storage and
also copying copying see data from the
index that are running on the right now
as a steve we have about seventy two
terabyte HDD running in a right v so our
first problem was when we have get at
our server we started an h top and we
are not able to see our processes
because we got so much cpus and they got
hyper-threaded is like 120 128 is abuse
and first we need to investigate how to
configure h top to see our processes
okay next interesting point
elasticsearch also some tweaking points
most people do a really really big
mistake there have may be a lot of
memory and they're doing just only one
elasticsearch node but the problem is if
you have you note has
allocates more than 26 gigabyte of ram
then the approval machine they use
64-bit pointers
instead of special compressed 32-bit
pointers Java does some pointers special
magic and the problem is when they use
64-bit pointers then each load of a
pointer uses as as much as twice
officer of the Benton earth because 2062
bit are much bigger than a 32-bit
pointer right so it this gave autism so
we are have divided elasticsearch into
different search nodes and each and each
in each node has a maximum of 20 60 or
byte per node and this has given us an
in treatment of approximately 30 to 40
percent unbelievable by just splitting
the database into several several
processes in the end if you're
interested how Java is doing memory
management and so on using elasticsearch
there's a very good article about it
just have a look into it so now let's go
into the results so what we see here
it's a key banner it's the front end of
this of elasticsearch and here we have
an interactive possibility to get a
rough overview about the autonomous
systems and the structure of the
Internet at first you can see so it's
the most HTTP HTTP host here hosted by
Amazon and then we have we can go see
what is the next biggest autonomous
system okay we sees a common Akamai's
once the biggest content delivery
networks we have ones on the earth and
then in the second ring we can see the
BGP prefixes there can see that amazon
has here 12/12 and announces this area
also no slash 12 there we have slash 13
and so on so and next step on the third
ring we can see ok there is Amazon we
can see there is a specific announced
BGP prefix is 3 208 / 12 and we can see
how a service distribution inside of
this prefix and that is the way how how
I understand the internet the internet
is not about nations and countries it's
only about autonomous systems their
prefixes and the internal structure of
the previous which kind of services -
they use and here you can very good see
that it uses Apache engines and also
some some other servers and you can see
there's a big difference between Amazon
and Akamai because he on Akamai you can
see every server and the prefix has the
same server banner
every time it's Akamai jiho's you would
got any information about which kind of
web servers are they using is your own
web server is it Apache or nginx
whatever they have just changed the
banner and here you can see the
difference between two autonomous system
echo Mars content delivery provider
Amazon a small kind of a holster right
and that's why they have a much more
hetero green structure what I have not
done is we clicked on Amazon and said
okay let's look into Amazon how is
Amazon structured and Tito and here can
see the different prefixes and again the
service distribution you can get a rough
overview it's just about it's a top 10
or top 12 prefixes and now we are adding
the Whois information and now it's
getting very interesting so we have from
inner circles the autonomous system then
we have the prefix now we have the huge
description and see who is prefix and we
can see that Amazon is structuring their
previous there is a network they have a
slash 12 and then they have inside a
slash 26 standing in his database and we
can also see the customer here it's
actor in cooperation right and then you
can go around and can see about the
different Amazon customers and see how
Amazon structuring their internet and
then you can look okay that's BGP prefix
that custom X was it that is prefix who
is prefix XY that and then you can look
how is the service distribution inside
officer who is prefix you're occurring
the network in more slices and getting a
good understanding about the about the
structure of the complete autonomous
system here we can have found zoom zoom
was a very well known video conference
communication system and here you can
see which kind of services they use we
will click on it just say okay I'm
interesting how house zooms that is
hosted on Amazon how is it structured
they are using a lot of services just
called zoom but they also use some 1.13
7 service from M Jakes and also some
engines without any kind of version
information in the end sir and using
autonomous system information BGP
prefixes
and also Whois information gives you a
very good overview about the structure
of autonomous system and about the
internet itself so going next here
another servlets that was bagged up now
here a look into OVH over ages one of
the third or one of the biggest european
hoster we have and here can also see the
BGP prefix oh and let me go to the
presentation mode better so here we can
see they use this slash 16 who has said
it's for dedicated servers and then you
can see they use the slash 18 from the
slash 16 for dedicated service somewhere
else we can see they use the slash 24
from this another slash 16 for fail over
IPS this means we get infrastructure
information how are organizing themself
that may be interesting for an aunt a
carer or for somebody else right so and
then we can also see which kind of
services do they use and we can see that
all fail over IPS have the same web
server in the end and what we can also
do is which kind of web services does
OVH at all use and you can see mostly
they use Apache or nginx Apache and so
on so we can see here is a separate list
sorted from top down by their major
numbers very interesting but then we
have to complete another all-tournament
system here we have SSH a complete
another protocol and and we can seize it
GoDaddy does not reveal any kind of
information about the internal structure
all who is blocks are the same and and
they also have the same name like the
autonomic system itself and very
interesting they are using everywhere
like on 90% of all the servers yeah
using the same open SSH version so you
can see that GoDaddy is a holster right
so there's as there's a web holster so
they are completely matching different
on a different way than OVH or Amazon is
doing or Akamai so using this we have
looked for different customers and if
you look and we
description here you can see you can
enumerate a lot of customers from
Amazon's very interesting you can see we
have Cisco you have Samsung we have zoom
and so on
next we can all look how is Amazon
structuring the ec2 infrastructure
there's all the cloud stuff and so on we
can see we have a lot of house in AVH
asia-pacific because they have a very
big slash 16 there and we can see says
they use airport abbreviations for the
locations of the ec2 clusters you can
see it's Dublin then we can see they
using CD which CD G which stands for
child to go
it's France then we CFRA it's Frankfurt
is the Germany and so on and that's very
interesting use these also use
information you're getting a lot of
infrastructure information about the
autonomous systems and of companies how
are the instructions the network and for
what parts and you know what they what
they are doing with their reserved
subnets then you can also do some other
first further interesting analyzation x'
i have said please provide me all
microsoft i as 5.0 servers who knows
what is the operating system of of it
it's Windows 2000 and then I tell then I
tell my database please provide me all
these subject common names so we have a
list of the sexual content and we have
now a lot of domains that are that are
running on a Microsoft I as a Windows
2000 server a very very also selects 20
years old and then we have cannot mostly
people say alkanes maybe some old
service they have forgotten to shut it
down whatever but then we can see here
on the right side it's the start date to
start validity date of the certificate
in there you can see there are servers
they are running for some stuff because
old all dated forgotten servers get not
new as a SSL Certificates right people
are running Windows 2000 server 2000
fears not supported since 15 or 10 years
whatever and providing them as new
certificates and that is unbelievable
for me to see that people are doing an
ant it's also awesome that these Windows
systems are still running right it's
okay now having looked at the dark side
what we also can do is that we can we
also doing some happily analyzes and as
taught my database please provide me an
an overview about all governance
agencies whatever in Austria and the
Whois database and that contains a TLS
certificate from forty net in the end so
we are looking for forty net 49
firewalls that are hard bit vulnerable
in Austria on governance agencies in the
end and we can see here that we have
find a lot of certs German and inst and
some like a bureau of district 1
district 2 and whatever and then we can
see that the issuer organization keyword
is 40 nets or the issue of the
certificate is 40 net and on the right
side you can see very good the different
versions of see firewalls that was can
date from 2017 then ask and again at the
Internet in one real later and now you
can see they have replaced the 14th
firewalls were so force appliance right
very interesting what you can see using
time differential analysis in the end so
then if you're scanning for industrial
control systems you can also see that
it's scan for a self a common Modbus you
can see a very big distribution and you
can see there's a hard collation for the
economic point so if you look to former
GDR region here you have not that much
industrial control systems we have more
in south and the West you have an North
Italy a lot of industrial control system
Hart big economic area in Italy and
thous Adelie you have not that much
industrial control system seems to
Scotland compared to England it's very
interesting that you can can can derive
the economic power from the internet
against very interesting when we can see
it's a very big problem that always
evolve people putting industrial control
systems on the Internet here are some
numbers so makes sense as sevakram
stands for Siemens and we can see
Germany has the most number of Siemens
industrial control systems also fully
reasonable so now next analysis here we
can see I said I want to see for
heartbeat vulnerable servers in April
17 in Afghanistan and here we can see on
the autonomous system the autonomous
system is the Afghan telecom government
communication network and see who is
description is in debt I have never seen
an so detailed whose information it's a
government communication network
district communication whatever for the
communication of 34 provinces into 357
districts in Kabul Afghanistan and now
you're looking who is the issue of the
certificate you can see it's a pfSense
firewall so you can if doing these kind
of analyzers and putting data together
with other data you are very first
finding very interesting results and I'm
sure that the CIA is going on the since
in some years right okay now we are
getting to the real bad point people are
putting in the Whois information a lot
of stuffs you also to say this is power
plant XYZ I can't believe it people are
doing that and here we can see it it's a
bigger power bigger power plant is a
coal-fired power plant and here we have
VPN endpoint by our HTTP and since power
plant has a capacity of approximately
500 megawatts supplying like 1.5 million
people it's not a small power plant
right so and now we are looking the scan
date is from 2018 right so in August
2000 18 and we can see the certificate
got eight invalid on July ok it's one
month it's ok but in the end it's a
critical infrastructure with an invalid
VPN endpoint certificate then I did the
risk in and inform Tinelli mode them I
contacted them I got never a reply and
then I risk and November and still again
sees certificate as out of dead and now
I did some neural scans and I found that
they have updated certificate in April
2000 19 and it's a critical
infrastructure people should not care
about it in the end
so for me I'm living in Germany I'm not
funny but that so now I will provide you
another further very interesting
analysis
another power plant where is it
perfectly so what we have here in the
first as we are looking for craft work
that stands for power plant in German
and we can see we have only here south
on am assistant names the BGP prefix
name and the server banners that is
information you can see on senses or
showdown because they do not use Whois
information now we are say please enable
Whois information and then we can see
some very more interesting result in the
end
so let's enable the Whois information
and then we can see we have our ve it's
a very big German energy company and
the power plant called neither
awesome-looking on Wikipedia what is
neither awesome oh it's just a second
largest coal power plant in Germany this
time we have about like 4 mega watt of
energy of energy capacity in the end so
now that's very interesting but what is
for service oh very interesting
it's a Lancome seven one one one VPN
gateway Lancome for a critical
infrastructure ok let's look ah there is
a list of ant
oil and of the services devices right
maybe is it the end of service device
maybe it's like one of your old I don't
know let's have a look how old is this
unsupported system or since when is it
not unsupported and here you can see
it's Lancome seven one one device is
unsupported since May 2010 it's a nine
year old unsupported VPN a gateway and
that is the scan from the mid of August
it's like one week old right so it's
recent we can see it on the internet
life so very interesting thanks
so now it's getting better right
let's look which kind of cipher suite is
it supporting so now let's go back again
to the lancome device and we can see how
it's a secure cipher we have on the
world is the T errors errors our C for
cipher right Oh unbelievable because
it's so old system it's not surprising
but in the end hell we have a Curtis law
here in Germany energy company is
spending a lot of money how could it
possible there is a very very 10 year
old VPN gateway with the rc4 site on a
critical infrastructure I cannot get it
right so I have a lot of data I could
talk like 2030 you further minutes
whatever but it's my wife sense I have
to stop spending so much time time as
this dater yeah so now we are going to
the summary and then I'm very I want to
discuss with you about the results ok so
summing it up using raw data or internet
scans is very important and you have to
enrich with this bgp who is in protocol
for specific information this only gives
you the power for complete
infrastructure analyzers of the internet
there are a lot of sir it's very
important for you to understand the
topology the structure the structure
itself and you can you know very easy
for you then in the end if you do your
own scans in the data enrichment to
identify all websites or vulnerabilities
that may be belong to a company to a
critical infrastructure of maybe to
government agencies in the end
furthermore how to do this here is my
small cheat sheet get here ona s vs / 22
this means like 1024 IP addresses
skin.not forrester than 70 m bit use
ones and twos and makes most makes no
sense because you take like twice for
your skin and you will send too much
data and you will get more engaged with
industrial with IDs systems
scanning the internet in two hours from
a single source RP you will only see 10
you will only see like 70 to 90% of the
Internet
sir it's not a good idea or you need you
can do it but then you know that it idea
is not very reliable you can use only
your should only scan bgp prefixes that
are rooted and that way you will save
about 35 office efficient traffic and
time and if you want to do very fast
repeatedly scans in a case of a short
remote executable were a bit ideas may
be released you should beat use BGP
prefix Hitler's meaning scanning the
internet once and then only scanning the
BGP prefixes and this will save you
further 25 to 50 percent of C routed
ipv4 address space thank you very much
if you want to email me or whatever just
email me and I'm living here on the camp
it's a Garofalo and a big green tent and
if you're interested in scanning please
contact me because a lot of people i
know what scanning on ourselves and
you're not talking to each other and
that why I'm sitting here I want to
explain you how to scan and I really
would like to set up a kind of scan
community in the USA 1/2 a scanning
community and here in Germany rebound so
please help me come around with a beer
and then we can talk about how to scan
and I have also some further interesting
informations yeah thank you very much
so thank you Johannes for a super
interesting talk we have some time for
questions so if you have any questions
please we will have a microphone shortly
but in the meantime we'll take a
question from the internet
yes the that wants to know whether it's
possible to access the scan data or you
publish your scan result or your
research resides yeah sir in the end I'm
not publishing the results results
because and this talk was aimed to
explain you how you can set up your own
infrastructure sir you don't need that
much money like 30000 euros for the
service you can I just need it because I
want to scan a load a huge load of
different protocols and so let's talk
the aim was to show you how to do it on
your own but I want to share the
information with penetration testers
because they need this kind of
information to detect complete attack
surfaces or companies they are dealing
with in the end and it's for me to to in
the end I do not know what people would
do with all these data and I don't want
to be the people as the guy who was
publishing it to maybe to the bad guys
and that that's why I only want to
provide it to some penetration testers
ok question from the audience
hello I even from Italy so I'm doing a
project focused on Italy in doing
massive scanning and I come up with an
interesting problem that you may already
figured out basically those kind of scan
are not aggressive vulnerability
analysis are basically creating a
software inventory from the service you
can connect to a speak to I came up to
the problem of out of a scan I would
like to detect the surface of
vulnerabilities so get out some kind of
indicators that this service is
vulnerable or not and the very simplest
easiest approach is to make a matching
with the CVE database or
conversion fingerprinting but I've been
told by multiple person that the amount
of a false positive is pretty high
yeah do you have any insight on that
yeah so you just need to look on
especially Debian dip and distribution
is it very doing very often if there is
some kind for a vulnerability version 1
1 1 of a certain web server they will
provide a patch but they will not
increase the minor number of the service
so it's only a potential vulnerability
right in the end that's that's a big
problem and how to just the only way
would be try to exploit it but you
cannot do it as a researcher and there's
bad guys are more in a better position
and so we can only say what is the
potential what are the potential
vulnerability or capacity and the end
yeah I'm totally agree with you that's a
big problem and for this I have no
solution in the end right now next
question thanks for the talk and have
you thought about scanning ipv6 prefixes
yeah we have we have some currently also
a research project not maybe next year
thank you any more questions from the
audience or from the internet ok looks
like we're done so again a big round of
applause to Jonas
[Applause]
[Music]
you