[Music]
so our next speaker is Moe who works for
the Sybok foundation and see where she
will be presenting this foundation now
which was founded I think in 2017 in
Barcelona and we will now learn much
more about it so please give a warm
round of applause okay hello do you hear
me well yes okay thank you
so as they said my name is 'more
Accomack net and I work in cyber
foundation labs and it's what I'm gonna
present today it's been a long time
since I don't give a talk
so please and I didn't leave asleep very
much so please be Vanna valent with me
okay I'll talk about CFL and its story
first first of all I'll be a little bit
fast in the story and then I will
explain what we are up to right now so
the beginnings of the cyber foundation
was created by these two artists nail
Harbison and moon rebus that you might
know they are both considered by media
this is the two first female and male
cyborg artists and well as you can see
the CF what it does it's an organization
that encourages humans to become cyborgs
and promote cyber cyber Gizem as an art
movement so first of all I'll talk about
nearly Harvison inhibition is a person
that has its colour blind he only sees
in grey scale so then in 2004 he decided
to get an implant in his skull of an
antenna
it's called Nyborg and what it does is
that it the text it detects colors as
frequencies so he has the sound
connected to his skull and the vibration
the vibrations of the of the colors he
can read them so whenever he hears our
an F alpha its color red for example no
later on nowadays he's he decided he
wanted to get a crown a sense of time a
solar crown which is a sensor that it's
a sense that we are developing right now
in cyber foundation labs these time
sense is very interesting because well
here on the on the Left I think on the
right on your left you can see the
circuit that we did so this this time
sense it's a crown that reproduces the
movement of the earth towards the Sun so
well not the white Sun towards itself
and the thing is that it gives different
points of hot with some resistors
depending on where the Sun is so if he
feels here the heat this means that it's
12:00 in London I hope you understand me
a little bit but yes and so this was a
problem to elaborate because with
different with Arduino you don't have
you have too much pins and you have too
much power too much current so you have
like a lot of current and it's
impossible to power it up so then we
decided to work with that a tiny 85 and
the idea that we had is to use this
microcontroller called W as 2811 which
is a shift register and that is used for
RGB LEDs okay and we are generating 12
inputs of hot with those resistors using
only their tiny 85 and and what is very
interesting about this is that Neil
Harrison his idea is that you know that
Einstein he says if we have eyes as we
have eyes we can we have time illusions
no not time illusion sorry optical
illusions okay so if he's if his brain
is able to
connect to feel time instead of the 24
hours/day we have filling time through
the through his skull he will be able to
have time illusions I don't know if you
understood that because maybe I'm not
explaining myself very good but the
thing is that when he you know that our
brain is very plastic so it can get used
to the new sensors that we are
introducing it to our body so the thing
is that when he feels all this heat
going around his head he has this
perception of time and if he has lows
down this this rotatory time passing he
thinks that he's gonna be able to slow
his perception of time so to age slower
okay so now you have to sink this then
I'm gonna talk about moon Reba's she's a
choreographer and dancer and she like at
2007 she got these seismic sensors on
her feet that were connected to
bluetooth to a mobile phone to some
servers that reproduced the different
seismic movements that are around the
world and she does these performances
with a big thumb ball okay we have big
drum and she reproduces all the
earthquakes that have happened for
example in Mexico from 1880 till
nowadays but two months ago she decided
to take off these seismic sensors and
what it's very interesting as I said
before our brain is very plastic so for
more than 10 years she had these sensors
so when she took them off her brain was
repeating these movements even so that's
what it's called ghost cyborg because
she doesn't have anymore these sensors
but she feels the vibrations another
circuit that we elaborated is the
transcendental communication system it's
a Bluetooth tools both near Harbison and
moon' Reba's they included a Bluetooth
enabled buton button
I mean vibrate vibrator so they could
talk via Morse code by pressing their
teeth right now they took it off so
they're not wearing it anymore but they
used it for some years then later on
after 2017 some more people got inside
the project and we changed the name and
we call it transmission Society well
it's just it's the same but just another
name so I'm just gonna pass fast here in
your right you can see man Elmo knows
which is another cyber artist man Elmo
knows he has a parametric sense that it
sends pressure temperature and humidity
first of all this circuit used to make
vibrations in his skull so the thing is
you have this circuit knob which sensors
humidity pressure and temperature and
depending on the levels of these three
parameters he would feel some vibrations
stronger or slow our our software
vibrations but nowadays we changed this
circuit and the input that he is
receiving is is a bone conduction sun
wave so here has this flash memory
inside the circuit which reproduces
bubble sounds and depending on if it's
more pressure or if it's more humid he
will feel more more bubbles a different
type of bubble and so nowadays this year
2019 we created the cyber foundation
labs which is like a new emerging for us
and we are centered we are based in
Barcelona and we give voice to non human
and identities we are a group of
technicians philosophers designers and
artists as I already said that we
explore the relationship between species
and also how we can involve humans as
you see we base our experimentation or
natural unnatural because humans we have
five
senses not but depending on how you
check it we have five six seven it
depends but the idea is that we looked
through nature through all the beings
because they have some senses that we
don't and this helps us a lot to
innovate this till now I've only talked
about artists I don't consider myself an
artist I consider myself a technician
and I I am from the crowd of technicians
no well technicians are the core of the
Association and we are the ones to
create all these ideas that artists have
or that we by ourselves have then we
have philosophers who are the ones that
generate the cybox theory and some
designers that are the ones that take
care of the materials here I am I just
wrote some because I don't want to only
talk about artists so I just put
technicians here Phoenix Bernardo he's
the main technician and he's a great
developer and he is the one to generate
all these new circuits that we have to
generate because all these new circuits
are not created yet they we invent them
using the materials and the circuits
that we have on in a commercial view we
apply it to our domain and we build them
and improve them well we also have Judy
Perez who is a designer but she's also a
technician and myself and I don't have a
website so I didn't put my website the
philosopher touch enough another Lopez
and a designer or a Alva there are many
many more people collaborating with us
but I didn't have time to put them all
they they are they didn't connect me so
nevermind okay now I'm gonna talk about
cosmic rays organ this organ is a an
organ that helps you to detect the
cosmic rays that travel around the
atmosphere cosmic rays are these
particles they crash onto the atmosphere
and
they and also two Mons and the thing is
that we used a project from the MIT that
they designed which I don't know if
there's someone here from the MIT but
there were a lot of errors in the
circuit but we are using this circuit
from the MIT where they detect these the
cosmic rays the thing is that you have
cell with some oxy oxy oxides I don't
know how you say it inside a dark
chamber with a scintillator
okay which is a type of polymer and this
helps you to it it bounces these
particles bounce and they reduce the
speed of the muons so that we can detect
them
so we detect these moans and we give an
input to to the person that has this
sense and in this case we did the same
as the pressure as the bottom as the
pressure sense where this person is
gonna hear frequencies and sounds and
right now we are as I said before
presenting myself here we are developing
a new way because one of the most
problems that we have with our sensors
with our senses sorry is that it's
battery power problems because these new
organs are supposed to to be with you
all your life at least one year now so
what do you do is power it's a big
problem so right now we are just
developing I wanted to bring a prototype
here but some materials that we bought
didn't arrive so I was not able to bring
it but we are right now developing this
Seebeck effect it's the first prototype
development ever and I don't know if you
know what Seebeck effect is but it's a
thermoelectric effect and this
thermoelectric effect what it does is
that it it converts temperature
difference to voltage and it also and
also vice versa so as you can see here
we have
prototype designed and well the back
view is just the aluminum it's just
about years or whatever then we can see
the dissipator the head sink
heat sink and the chip basically what
you have is two plates of two different
materials like copper and constantan I
don't know how to say it in English but
whatever and the thing is that when they
enter in contact with with with your
skin between it there is if there is a
difference of temperature it is gonna
generate voltage so to generate voltage
the temperature must be at least from
nine to eleven Celsius and if the
temperature is the difference of
temperature is lower it will set to even
eight that's why if the temperature is
higher we will have a battery so that we
can help you can store it and use it
when necessary it's still a prototype so
we are still working on it and figuring
out the charge and discharge systems and
which I see we can use here you can see
in the top view you can see these are
the the plates that will be in contact
with the skin and I'm well so laughs to
finish I would like to say that our
future expectations is to generate a bit
directional connection because as I
explain you right now we have the the
medium I mean the world so the world
generates some inputs now and these
senses that we have they read these
inputs and they throw some output that
us as human will read as an input but
these are only only directional
connection as you can see there is no
back and forth between the sensor and
our self so our expectations are from
this for the future are to to generate
this be directional connection where you
are able to communicate with your organ
and the organ is able to
communicate with yourself and I'm I'm
actually done I don't know if I've been
super fast but the thing is that we are
calling for engineers to come work with
us in Barcelona
we can work also on these stunts and but
we are very interested to collaborate
with people with with anyway anyone but
with technicians it would be better so
as you can see you are more than welcome
to our lab and our team to experimental
built together and thank you thank you
it's been we have plenty of time okay so
please prepare extremely long questions
we have a lot of time as you know we
have this time we only have one
microphone angel so if you have a
question or something to discuss just go
to this gentleman over there and go
speak into the microphone does anyone
have a question yet we are also open to
receive people that want to get some new
census and yeah we can talk later then
all right we have a question does anyone
hug thank you
hello I'm over here we're okay thank you
for the talk I was really interested in
your Seebeck effect prototype so one of
the problems I've been having is
generating power or having a battery
inside the body
so for implantable devices how have you
done any research into powering those
yes actually we have some implanted
devices inside and for now the battery
stays outside we have an implanted yet
in this case all right
any more questions from anyone okay
maybe one question from me for to do the
Seebeck effect stuff how large do you
need a temperature gradient to be that
from 9 to 11 degrees okay so not for
camp use ah so it's not usable at camp
where it's super it depends on your body
temperature it depends on the difference
of the of the body temperature and the
temperature of the any of the outside
okay but the idea is to generate a
system that as a house now when you have
the solar with your solar panels you
generate a system where when there is no
Sun you still have your batteries
working on because you're stored it so
that that would be the idea yes how
large was the device that you showed
actually I don't know because we my
friend was the one who designed these um
the match the prototype so I'm not sure
actually I don't think I'm not sure I
cannot tell you anything
can let you know all right we have a
question from the audience yeah could
you speak more to how the current
cyborgs who use powered devices are
dealing with batteries and dealing with
charging to make it as seamless a part
of their lives as possible without these
devices that you're currently developing
so right now we are working with a tiny
so what tiny has a really really low
current consumption so I I don't have
any sense installed in me so I'm not
able to speak for them I would need to
ask them what how they work how do they
do it but actually we only take off our
the battery and put it back again and
that's what I'm saying that we are like
looking for very low consumption icees
microcontrollers so right now with your
tiny we are working fine okay just one
second if we if someone in the room
wants to be a signal angel for this talk
please just maybe talk to the stage
manager in the back and then we can also
receive questions from the internet
which would be very cool thank you now
please hey thanks again for this great
note um I was curious about two aspects
that are a bit boring one is how do you
fund your work oh yes yeah that's the
part I didn't that I didn't add so right
now we are trying to to see a way to
finance ourselves right now none of us
are receiving any money it's all because
we love it as I said we have a little
bit of problems between artists and
technicians actually I wanted to bring
some devices here but all the artists
were like no no no I'm sorry no I'm
keeping it it's too risky and I'm like
what we developed it for you and you
don't let me bring it here no but the
thing is that so right now we are
starting to on September because the
laboratory emerged this year I mean I
explained some years ago they were
working but they were more artistic and
more their selves they go to talks by
themselves
because they are known but right now
there is emerging
we are emerging as collective as
technician designers and philosophers
and we are looking ways of renunciation
some some ways of financiación would be
the no return financiación no so we are
developing these documents to send to
different enterprises that would be
interested in our project and then they
would give us some finance situation
with no return but we are also planning
to do some workshops and some open some
parties in our bunker we call it so that
we can finance she ate all this because
we have a kind of problem between the
Seibert the artists that the people that
wants to get some new sensors because we
don't make them pay at all at all so we
are like working like crazy and giving
the work to other people and we are not
getting anything in our laboratory I
don't know if you are getting me sorry
my English but the thing is that that's
what I the last thing I talked with my
colleagues was ok no more sense for
anyone we will build senses for us just
some prototypes to have them here if
they want them in a commercial way
they're gonna have to pay for it for it
now ok so in this case we are totally
open distribution schematics everything
it's totally open but if you're gonna
use it in a commercial way then yes
you're gonna have to pay for the rights
I don't know if I know so that leads to
my second question which is somehow
related I started working on an
electronic implant a few years ago with
body modification artists called Samba
van cyborgs you might know anyway and my
approach was to go through academia so
we started trying to get some ethical
approval from the academic world which
is almost impossible are you do you have
any constraints on certification and
this kind of ok so I think this is my my
and weak point because I'm not sure
about it but what I do know is that as I
said I don't like to consider myself an
artist but what happens with art is that
everything fits there so that's why all
my colleagues that are with some senses
and they consider themselves artists IRA
side works they call themselves artists
because everything fits in art so people
will not question yourself if you say
it's art what I do know is that Neil
Harrison had some trouble with police
they were he wanted to cross the
passport Airport and they well he had
two problems one was in the airport with
his antenna they were saying that he
could not cross it because in his
picture was without antenna and he had
the antenna and finally and he started a
bureaucratic situation where they
finally recognized him as the first
cyborg so he could pass and cross the
the the 101 and then he also had some
problems with police where they broke
his he had some troubles in Barcelona I
don't know if he was drinking on the
street or whatever and they started they
hit him and they broke his antenna and
but about bureaucratic stuff I think we
should have here my colleagues to talk
about it I mean because I'm I'm not into
that I'm into electronics thank you ok I
think we found a signal angel so if you
under stream you might be able to okay
no the answer's no all right first of
all thank you for your soul kiss was
super clear I'm wondering usually we
when we want to sleep well at night we
should the light we have no sound
pretty not too warm the tickled
remittitur
so you know if these people all cyborgs
are ever like you quiet smooth for the
sensors or just turn dinner for
something because you cannot really
control like cosmic rays for example
that's a good question I think each
person would do whatever they feel like
but what I'd know that they don't do is
take it off because they are too
concentrated I mean they are to focus on
on that but for example near Harrison he
has his antenna is connected to he
connect it he gave permission to three
friends of them around the world to send
him colors so that whenever he sleeps he
dreams with those colors with these
frequencies you have to think of these
devices as your own organ so whenever
you are sleeping and suddenly you open
your eyes um you're still sleeping some
people would I don't know maybe some
people would sleep with with all the
whites our but your ears you're not able
to close them either whether you put
some plugs so these organ works the same
I mean is part of your body so whether
you are sleeping whether you are awake
the organ is functioning so and yes as I
said the brain is very plastic the brain
is like a sculpture
you can modulate and do whatever you
want so um after some months maybe six
months maybe one year your brain gaze
gets super used to it to this to these
new sense that you have and you don't
even feel it anymore you don't even feel
it
not yours you it's totally yours
actually if they take it off you're
totally like up no and yeah when
as I said when you sleep your ears are
still on you're not able to turn them
off so that would be the same with the
organ alright any other questions
if anything else you want to show well I
would want to say well there is a video
but it is stupid video so no so but
thank you very much for listening and
you are more than welcome to come to our
laboratory or thought we are wherever
you want and yeah thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
you