yep so uh just a quick about so I work
for NCC group in a team of three people
just called the exploit Development
Group and we basically just mostly focus
on end days until recently we started
doing some pone to own stuff
um so we
um joined the poem to own Austin uh 2021
which is more like iot and embedded
stuff and we exploited uh Nas and
Lexmark printer and
um released some blogs talking about the
the bugs we exploited in methodology and
stuff
um if you're interested
so yeah basically we um we ended up
wanting to or tried to
um compete in pone to own desktop 2022
or yeah 2022 but
um it didn't quite go as planned so
basically at first we found uh a bug and
exploited it and we were happy and we
were all ready to go and then it was
patched
um before the competition so we had to
start from scratch which was kind of too
bad so we founded or we founded a second
vulnerability and we were pretty well on
our way to exploiting it it definitely
was exploitable and then that was also
publicly patched before we were finished
so we had to start from scratch again
but it was getting kind of late
um and unfortunately we didn't finish
exploiting the third bug in time but it
was still interesting experience and we
decided to disclose it rather than sit
on it for a year just because probably
it would get found anyways
um and yeah so basically this talk is
just about the third bug because in the
end there was no like collisions for
this bug at ponton or anything so it's
kind of interesting and yeah so at the
time of the competition uh the the
target was Ubuntu
22.04 and it was
um kernel 5.15
um so yeah I guess I'm kind of fortunate
to follow Sam's presentation in that I'm
not going to talk too much about the
methodology and stuff
um it's just gonna mostly be a big
technical dump of the bug and how he
exploited it but just we mostly followed
the typical tooling stuff that you do
for Linux kernel
uh debugging and whatnot I guess the one
thing that's worth noting that I've
noticed some people don't seem to know
about is that the Linux kernel sources
include some um helper Python scripts
that you can import into GDB that
actually let you analyze a bunch of the
structures so like if you have a
breakpoint and you want to only trigger
the break point if the user land process
is a specific one they basically provide
you structures for that version that let
you
um do that check inside of GDB which is
really nice but otherwise it's just
pretty typical stuff PA hole for
structure analysis we did end up using
code ql for some
um querying structure sizes and members
and stuff which I'll talk about and then
I guess the other big thing was we did a
lot of like slub cash or slab cache
analysis
um
during the research and at first we were
using F Trace which a lot of people seem
to be using but we found that just the
information it provides in the level of
analysis I let
but uh as do wasn't quite what we wanted
because we're used to using some other
tools that we had written in user land
so anyways we ended up writing our own
um tool based off some other open source
tool called slab dbg
um that just works on the latest kernels
and stuff and it's much nicer for
analyzing all sorts of stuff on in the
slab allocator so we're going to release
that uh open source eventually but it's
not quite open source yet but
um
stay tuned for that I guess so yeah I'm
basically just going to go over like the
net link net filter and NF tables parts
of the Linux kernel just like a
whirlwind up to the point of like
um knowing enough uh
to understand the bug and and then we'll
just talk about how to exploit it and
then look at how they patched it
um so yeah basically
um most people that use Linux are
probably familiar with this userland uh
utility called nft which is used for
configuring the the firewall
um and basically like if you want to add
a rule for something like dropping a TTP
Port 80 you just run a command like this
and it's really well documented and
fairly easy to use compared to the tools
in the old days but we're interested in
like how does this work underneath
because parsing like the logic of these
types of rules and and building
structures based on them and stuff is
quite complicated
so basically everything is built around
netlink which maybe people are familiar
with but basically you can just create a
socket and then
um you can send packets to that socket
to talk to various parts of the Linux
kernel like networking subsystem
um and there's a really nice userland
library for helping you build the
packets because it's kind of annoying to
do by hand and then net filter
is just basically like a bunch of kind
of hooks into different parts of the
Linux networking subsystem so things
like Network address translation and
what we're interested in the the
firewall stuff and basically you can
just create packets
um
that talk to these different hooked
portions of the kernel and then finally
again what we're interested in is NF
tables kernel module and yeah basically
it's like the newer new Wiz in like 10
years or something
um firewall in the in the Linux kernel
and um it replaced IB tables and again
there's a pretty nice userland library
for constructing the packets and stuff
because it's also quite annoying to do
by hand if you have to tweak anything
um and most importantly
um access to stuff like
um net filter and NF tables is
um based on whether or not you have the
net admin capability and I'm sure a lot
of people are aware on Ubuntu you can
enter
um namespaces as an unprivileged user so
you can enter a network namespace and
basically obtain this capability and
then expose the functionality that you
wanted to Target
so yeah recently this like NF tables
module has been pretty popular
um just especially this year I think we
started buzzing it specifically around
when David Bowman released his blog and
if you're interested in any of the NF
tables internals and stuff and follow up
on the re like what I present here
definitely read David Bowman's blog
because it goes into the most detail
just about net Lincoln
um NF tables packets and all that kind
of stuff but it's all pretty interesting
reads if you want to go deeper and
interestingly at least one team team
Orca which I of C security which I think
is from Singapore they ended up
exploiting a bug in the same component
successfully at Pawn to home so that's
kind of cool and I'm sure there'll be
more in the future
um so yeah basically I'm gonna have to
explain a whole bunch of structures that
are used internally so that we can
understand the bug
so basically everything is grouped into
tables which people that have again used
um nft will be a bit familiar with but
basically a table is just a group of
chains and they're typically associated
with like a specific networking protocol
so like ipv4 will have a whole bunch of
chains associated with it and then the
chains typically just have like a
default policy of accepts or drop and
then the chains themselves hold a group
of rules which
um you know explains how to
um actually process the packets
themselves
um and and basically the the rules are
just made up of a group of Expressions
which are more discrete pieces of like
Logic for um processing the actual
packets themselves
um and there's a ton of different
Expressions again the blog by David
Bowman um goes over a lot of different
ones and there's too many to cover
um but really we're just interested in
these three that we use during
exploitation
um and I'll go into them in more detail
in a second
um and then there's the concept of sets
and so basically the idea is like if you
create a rule that um
like is going to Blacklist a list of ips
or has a you know a list of ports or
whatever basically those
um sets of like numbers are represented
in the kernel and just like a data
structure and they they call it a um set
so nft set structure
um and basically yeah the elements
inside of the the data structure are
just referred to as Elements which I'll
mention a couple times
and um yeah given the name of the talk
um we're specifically interested in this
set structure and it's quite a big
structure there's a lot of different
fields too many to go over but these are
the ones who are mostly interested in
and I'll go into some detail about them
um yeah so that there's there's a a
member called list which is basically
just a doubly linked list and uh of sets
that are um associated with a table so
if you have multiple Like rules
referencing different sets of data
they'll all just be linked on this same
doubly linked list associated with
whatever table they're part of
um there's also a doubly linked list
called bindings and basically if you
have some expression that's referencing
some element in the set it gets bound to
um the set and it it by being bound it
basically means it gets added to this
doubly linked list
um when you're interacting with a set
through an expression or whatever you
need to look it up somehow so there's a
name which is important
um if you end up corrupting things later
there's like a reference counter
um and when basically when you're when
you're creating this set in the first
place so you're building this netlink
packet that you know
um is talking to NF tables and say okay
I want to build this set they give you
the the ability to add some arbitrary
data that you can store inline inside of
the structure that ends up going on this
um this lab cache and you can also read
this uh data out from the set after the
fact which will be from userland which
will be useful later and so then there's
a length field that says how much data
did you actually store there and then
interestingly there's the like a
function table pointer for doing
operations on the set like adding
deleting elements and stuff like that
um and so by default again it's a fairly
big structure so by default it's stored
on the 512 byte um so like slab cache
but because of the variable length user
data you can supply you can get it onto
the 1024 byte slab cache um which is
useful
so
um we want to take a bit of a closer
look at the bindings member specifically
so when an expression references the set
it gets bound to the set and so
basically any expression that's capable
of referencing a set will embed this nft
set binding structure and it basically
just has The List member and that's what
ends up being put onto the bindings list
and so the entries on it each list point
to that list member of this structure
rather than the beginning of the
expression itself which is kind of
important
um
and so then Expressions themselves
um basically there's like a a more
um generic structure called nft
underscore expression and basically
every type of expression in the kernel
extends from this so that it just has
like its own little function pointer
member and then an inline array that's
going to contain the actual specific
expression type so like at the bottom
you can see we're going to create an or
we want to reference an nft lookup
expression and so it calls this function
to just pull out the data member of that
more generic structure and this is only
just noteworthy because
um If you're sort of analyzing the
structures in the kernel and you want to
know what slab cache structure is
allocated on
um if you don't include the size of the
nft expression structure in that
calculation you'll you'll be wrong and
you'll be looking at the wrong cache so
it's worth worth knowing
um so yeah the Expressions we're
interested in the lookup one basically
the idea is that it just fetches some
value from a set and it's a 48 byte
structure so allocated on that subcache
and we're mostly just interested in the
fact that the binding structure entry is
the last entry in the structure we don't
really care what else it's used for
um and similarly the dynamic set
expression we don't care too much about
anything that it's used for
um except that it can reference a set
Again The Binding
um structure is at the bottom of the
structure and this one's a bit bigger 96
byte uh slab cache
so
the way this would normally look is
you've got some set
and then you've got you know you send
some Expressions over netlink and they
reference the set so they just get added
to the bindings list
and going back to the um beginning I
mentioned the there's the list doubly
linked list as well so in this case okay
there's a table and there's multiple
sets associated with this table and each
one happens to have Expressions linked
on to the bindings list so that's just
like a high level overview of what you
can think about it uh in your head
so there's another sort of important bit
which is like when you're creating the
set originally you send the packet
over net link you can basically say that
you want to embed certain Expressions
inside of the set itself and this is a
little bit different because I said
expressions are normally used to process
um the actual packets that are coming in
over the network but in this case the
expressions are meant to get run when
data in the set is being updated but
there's only a limited number of types
of Expressions that can actually be
embedded in a set and they're called
stateful expressions
um which will be important so that's
basically like a quick Whirlwind of like
the the structures involved in how to at
least enough to understand the bug
so
um yeah we basically were fuzzing I
think after we read David Bowman's blog
we decided to spin up like this is
called fuzzer specifically targeting um
NF tables just because it seemed like a
fruitful area and this bug was
specifically compelling because
ciscollar wasn't able to automatically
generate a reprofile because normally
it'll give you like some C that you can
run to trigger it and in this case it
couldn't
um and because we already got burnt
twice with bugs we figured this might
mean that other people didn't want to
look at this bug if other people had
already fuzzed it so we decided to do
that and basically it's a use after free
while handling Expressions on the
bindings list that I that I just
explained and it's quite Limited in so
far as as we'll see you can basically
just write one pointer that you don't
control to an uncontrolled offset
somewhere
um and after we disclosed it and stuff
and it was patched someone else noticed
interestingly that Google's fuzzing
infrastructure had actually found it
already in November 2021 which we didn't
know about and it was automatically
closed as invalid which I actually have
no idea why maybe because there's no
Repro so it figured it wasn't real
um but yeah so basically I I mentioned
that when you're allocating a set you
can you can embed certain Expressions
inside and those expressions can only be
of a certain type otherwise this this
set is considered invalid and so this is
the function responsible for that and
interestingly we can see what it does at
the top it calls nft expression
initialize and that will actually
allocate the expression structure like
on the slab cache and call an
initialization routine and only after
we're like after it does all that it
checks the flag to see is this
expression legit or not like for this
for being embedded in a set and if not
it Just destroys it immediately and so
this is actually kind of interesting
because if there's any desynchronization
between the initialization routine and
the destruction routine because it's not
maybe normally called in this type of
context there could be some interesting
bugs so we need to look a little bit
closer at what happens so the
destruction routine itself
um basically
um the only thing that's important is
at the bottom it it just ends up calling
into the destruction routine associated
with the given expression that's being
destroyed
um and then at the top like after it
calls that helper function it just frees
the expression and that's all it does so
we need to look specifically at the
Expressions destroy routines
um and yeah so these two expressions I
mentioned
um when when they get initialized they
end up getting bound to the set that
they reference so they call the NF
tables bind set but neither of their
destruction routines actually removes
themselves from the bindings list itself
the normal context in which they get
called they get Unbound first and then
destroyed
so
um this leads to a use after free
because they get destroyed and there's
there's still linkage on the bindings
list pointing to them and that means
that any update to the the linked list
after the fact will
um up like potentially write to a free
chunk or something that's been replaced
which means that we can either write the
address of a set or one of the
Expressions into freed memory or
whatever replaces it
um so this is just an example of like
the dynamic set initialization routine
we can see that it calls the function
that's binding it to the set bindings
doubly linked list the other stuff
doesn't really matter we just know it's
on the list that we're interested in
and then the destruction routine
is a little bit more complicated but
um you can just basically avoid calling
the the first for Loops function
entirely and then it just ends up
calling this NF tables destroy set which
tries to destroy the set itself but only
if the set bindings list is empty and
it's not empty because the expression
just got added to it so basically it
doesn't call it and so effectively the
destruction routine does nothing
um in this particular case so it just
frees the expression and leaves the
entry on the bindings list
um so yeah if if we want to like walk
through the steps of how we would for
instance write the address of a set
um to a free chunk basically you need to
create some valid set that Expressions
um Can reference during the
initialization so that there's a
bindings list that exists for them to
get added to
and then basically we we create the
expression to bind it to that set which
gets added to the list and then we
create a new invalid set
and that invalid set will embed one of
these buggy Expressions
um and so the buggy expression gets
added to the bindings list and then the
code will say oh it's not stateful and
then it gets destroyed
um
and then uh oh actually there's one I I
forgot to mention when I said the second
Point there's an important point when
you create the valid Set uh or initially
if you want to be able to write the
address of the set into the free chunk
you have to buy you have to first bind
some legitimate expression to the set so
that there's a pre-existing
um entry on the bindings list and then
when you create the invalid set the new
expression gets added after that valid
expression entry on the linked list
um and then it gets freed so you've got
a dangling pointer
and then what you do is you destroy the
good expression on the list which
updates the linkage and so basically
it'll it'll write the address of set
bindings into the free pointer or the
free chunk but it I know that that's
kind of hard to understand so I'll go
over it visually because it'll be a bit
easier so in this case on the left we've
got some a valid set that we're going to
get Expressions to reference and then
we've added some legitimate expression
that's just on the bindings list and
then on the right we've got some invalid
set that we're creating and embedded
inside of it is this Dynamic set
expression which is not an okay
expression to have but we can see at
this stage it's already been bound to
the bindings link list
so then the set is deemed invalid so
um
the the dynamic set expression gets
freed and so now the valid expression
has a dangling pointer and now what we
do is we free the
um the valid expression and so then it
updates the prev pointer of the free
chunk with the to point backwards into
set bindings which is our use after free
um yeah and that's basically it so it's
it's fairly Limited in so far as what
you can write um and it doesn't give too
many options to how to exploit it
um so yeah I'd like some ideas
um because we can write a pointer it
would it would kind of be nice to be
able to overwrite some length parameter
so like replace the free chunk with some
other structure value that happens to
have an overlapping length that maybe
gives you an out of boundary to write
that would be like ideal but we didn't
find something like that
um
another idea is to overwrite some
pointer in a structure with the new
pointer that points to set or points to
another expression and maybe let us
build a better use after free primitive
um and then the other obvious thing
would just be to write the pointer into
some buffer that we can leak back to
userline to at least get a limited
um memory revelation
um
so the the first thing we did just for
an easy win and just to help build the
memory model because when you're doing
this stuff it can be confusing so it's
nice to have anything that works we
decided to just leak the address of a
set or expression
um into some like into user land
so how do we leak the data so there's a
pretty popular technique that people
have used in the past for Linux kernel
stuff like this basically the Linux
kernel includes like this key rendering
service where you can just build keys
and add them into the kernel and um you
can basically add your own arbitrary
data into these um
Keys which get allocated using this user
K user key payload structure and because
the size that you provide is variable
you can kind of control which slab cache
it gets allocated on and then you can
read the data back out the the the
um
you know the payload data that you
provided you can read it back out into
userline after the fact it's using this
key cuddle syscall
so
um yeah this when we trigger this bug
using the key stuff I'll refer to it as
use after free one and the set that
we're gonna abuse is called set one
so again exactly the same as before
we've got set one which is uh like the
thing that people our Expressions can
reference the legit expression and then
we're going to use our use after free
Dynamic set so we trigger the state
where it's dangling
um on the bindings list and then we
replace it with user key payload
um and then we unlink the legit
expression
writes the address of set one bindings
into the user key payload and then from
userland we can leak the address of set
one bindings which is nice
but it's not that nice I mean what do
you do with like some random slab cache
address not much
um but it's it it's a good start because
you know like
um you learn how to like you know
exploit the bug a little bit and stuff
and build up the methodology for doing
something a little bit more difficult so
the next step is to try to free some
other object in the kernel
um
so basically the goal here is we want to
find some object that lives on the 48 or
96 byte slab cache so that we can
replace the lookup or dynamic set
structure and we want whatever object we
find that can live there to have pointer
member that happens to overlap with the
offset that we can write during the use
after free write
but the main constraint here is that not
only does there have to be an
overlapping pointer but it's got to be
one that when we destroy whatever the
object that we're writing to it will
also try to free that pointer and that
way we can build like an actual free
primitive so we can freeze something
else
um so basically there's two options here
um because the the pointer you write
um points to the bindings member itself
um and not the beginning of the
expression
um or or the the set it's it's a little
bit quirky so what happens is when you
free it
um you're freeing like
at a misaligned address inside of the
expression or set and so part like the
free will start there and it will
overlap into the adjacent object
um and in the case of the expression
because the bindings member is the last
member of the structure it's actually
kind of quirky and potentially
unreliable and I don't go into too many
details why we didn't use it we'll
release a Blog with details about why
but in the in the case of set the
bindings member is just the second
member so you're basically freeing you
can free all of the set from the second
member onwards and you don't have to
rely on any adjacent object uh being
there on the same slab cache so it's
more reliable
um
yep
so the the question is okay so how do we
find like a structure that actually
meets these requirements um so we use
code ql
um
so basically we just wrote this codeql
query
um and basically you can
um just use queries like this to
um find stuff inside the Linux kernel
matching a set of rules and basically we
just say okay find us some structure
that's allocated from one of the heat
functions that we're interested in that
happens to be of size like 96 bytes so
it's on the right slab cache and the
offset says are the members at specific
offsets are referenced as pointers so it
meets our constraints and then basically
this spits out a list of candidate
structures
um that you still have to go through
manually and then you're looking for
like
um you're still looking to see okay this
structure seems to maybe match can I
allocate this structure from userland
because if not then you can't use it for
like the uh the attack and then also is
the the overlapping member actual
actually freeable on demand
and believe it or not it we did find one
um so there's this C group FS context
structure
which is 96 bytes so it's on this the
right slab cache and basically there's a
member called release agent that happens
to perfectly overlap with the prev
pointer of the bindings
um doubly linked list entry and you can
um you can just allocate them from user
Land by calling this FS open syscall and
then
um when you close the file descriptor
associated with it it will just free
that
structure and it happens to also free
the release agent pointer
so this is just what this structure
looks like you can see there's a name
and release agent members and it
actually both of those actually overlap
with next and prev so we could use
either one and then this is the
destruction routine
so when you're closing the C group this
ends up getting called and we can see it
calls K free on both the name and
release agent member and then it finally
frees the actual structure itself so
this is exactly what we wanted
unfortunately the members line up okay
so so for okay so we found a candidate
structure but we have to actually create
the primitive first to abuse it so this
setting up the Primitive I refer to as
use after free 2 and we'll use a
different set for it so again same as
before we've got Now set two legitimate
expression and some use after free
Dynamic set we free it to trigger the
dangling pointer scenario
this time we replace the free chunk with
C group FS context then we unlink the
expression and now we've got a release
agent member pointing back into set two
at the location of bindings
um and that's basically it like that's
our new
um free primitive it lets us free set
too and so in order to be able to
freeset two
um
yeah we refer to it as use after free
three because it's yeah you can still
operate on the set after it's been freed
because you still have a reference to it
and so we're going to replace that two
um and the what we replace there we
refer to it as fake set one
so this is our free primitive that lets
us free set two basically all we have to
do is close this C Group which will free
the C group FS contact structure and
then basically what happens is
everything after the List member of set
2 is freed so we can replace it with
something else that we want
um
and in this case we use the fuse
userline
driver and a Sysco called set X adder
and I'm this is a really popular
technique lately but basically the idea
is you can create some file in user land
and cause when you when you call like
set X Adder you can supply a path and in
the process of trying to access that
path it goes up through the kernel and
back into userland in a fuse
driver that you basically control so you
can basically pause the kernel while
it's copying data into a chunk and it
allows you to just replace some chunk
with uh effectively arbitrary data at an
almost arbitrary size so it's easy to
create a chunk of the size that we
needed like nft set and just replace it
all with completely controlled values
um so from here what we want to do is
get some sort of memory Revelation
because eventually we're going to want
to bypass kslr and stuff and so if you
think back to the first years after free
we did
um we we leaked some address on the slab
cache which at the time didn't seem that
useful but now it's useful because maybe
we can use that as a
memory Revelation so when we replace
that too with the fake set we basically
can set the U data member to the address
that we leaked from the subcache of set
one we can set the length to the size of
the set one structure and there's one
constraint which is that the name has to
be valid and we end up clobbering it but
you can since we know the address of set
one already we when we create set one
initially we can just pre-populate part
of the user data with some fake name
that we'll use after the fact and then
when we continue to use we access
um set two and fake set via net link we
have some legitimate um way of looking
at the set after the fact
so this lets us leak the contents of set
one back into user land
um which is nice it leaks us the NF
tables
um kernel module data pointer because of
the function pointer table but
unfortunately that is fairly limited for
Rob gadgets so it's not actually as
useful as we wanted but basically this
is what it looks like so when we create
the fake set and we've replaced set to
the name just points to some
pre-existing value that we had populated
in set one during creation U data points
to the beginning of the set we've got
the length that encapsulates the full
set and then that gives us like a
limited leak at least of nftables.ko
but we can do better than that because
we want ideally
um a full kslr bypass so get the address
of VM Linux
um so if you recall way back I said that
there's the the linked list of all the
sets associated with a table
so
um when we create the sets we can
basically put them on the same table and
so when we leak set one we can have the
next pointer of The List member actually
pointing back to the fake set so we can
leak the address of the fake set as well
which will be useful in the future
because then we know where data is we
fully control
a little bit later
and then um on the previous slide I had
said well we can say UD land to the size
of set one well actually it's not
limited to that size so we can leak uh
objects adjacent to set one as well so
basically what we found a good candidate
was was the these tdys uh structures
that live on the 1024 byte slab cache
and basically you just open this
pseudo-terminal path and every time you
open one it it
um allocates one of these structures on
the slab cache so basically you can just
spray a whole bunch of these structures
then allocate set one and be reasonably
sure that there's a TDY structure
adjacent to it and even if there's not
you can start from scratch the one
exception to it would be if when you
allocate set one it happens to be the
last
um
object on the slab cache in which case
there's not necessarily going to be
anything adjacent but because we leaked
the address of set one early on we can
actually compute Which slot it is on the
slab cache and if it's the last one we
just try again basically yeah
um so this is nice because it will allow
us to leak the address from VM Linux and
this is because the TDY structure has an
Ops function
um pointer table and this structure has
also been used previously in a couple
public Linux kernel exploits so it's
fairly well known but so this is what
basically the op like the modified
scenario looks like is we just have some
TDY structure adjacent to set one on the
slab cache and we've just modified the
user data length to encapsulate both
um
chunks and then we can just read it all
and in this case instead of like reading
set one to Ops we read ddy strikes Ops
and that gives us the the dot data
address to bypass like in VM Linux which
allows us to bypass kslr
um so so the next phase is like okay we
bypass kslr how do we actually get code
execution out of this
um so the idea is like we need to put
the kslr adjusted pointers in memory
somewhere
um but fortunately we just leaked the
address of fake set one uh while we were
reading set one itself and because of
fuse and set X Adder we basically can
choose when we free the chunk and we can
just reallocate it so basically we can
just free fake set one on demand and
replace it with a new fake set but this
time we know the address of where it's
going to live so we can put the kslr
adjusted pointers into fake set two
um and so this case because it's yet
another new chunk that's replacing set
two I call it use after free four and
then we're replacing fakes that one with
fake set two basically and and the idea
is we can just now point the function
pointer table of fake set two back into
itself at some offset inside the inline
data and that area can have the kslr
adjusted point owners
so yeah basically we just free the set X
Adder chunk by unblocking fuse and
letting the read complete and then we
just use fuse and set Etc again to
replace fake set 2 in the exact same
slot on the slab cache
um and then that basically lets us
control the function
pointer table so now the idea is we're
going to call one of these function
pointers from this function pointer
table but it's fairly limited as far as
like register control goes and stuff
basically half the functions you have
RDI and R14 pointing back into fake set
two and then the other half is RSI and
R12 but because fake said 2 is
completely controlled in memory it's not
too bad because you can maybe find some
Gadget that is referencing interesting
data at some offset from those registers
and then using it
um you know in an interesting way and we
just use the Rob Gadget hunting tool RP
we didn't do anything fancy for that I'm
just gripping for the the relevant
registers
and so yeah we ended up finding of not
so much a gadget but an actual function
um which is just basically responsible
for unlinking something from a doubly
linked list
um and so again I I had said that RDI is
one of the registers that points into
fake set two so you can see RDI plus
hex60 will overlap with some of the
fields and it get read into Rax and
uh hex offset 68 gets rid into RDX and
then it basically just writes Rex to RDX
so this immediately is like an eight
byte right primitive that we can use
um and then as usual with unlinking
something from a doubly linked list it
will also try to write the other pointer
back so in this case RDX will be written
back into Rax which is a potential
problem because it will oops if Rex is
actually like an arbitrary value
and so the question is does the oops
matter
and it does not because on Ubuntu they
basically use this CIS cuddle setting
called Panic on oops and they set it to
zero and so basically as long as like an
oops happens in like a non-critical
kernel path the kernel just says okay
just like pause or terminate that thread
and then just keep going but at that
point we've already triggered the first
eight byte right to a control like a
controlled address so that's kind of all
we need
interestingly like afterwards I think
fairly recently Star Labs released a
Blog that they talk about using a
similar function called list delete I'm
pretty sure it's almost identical
um and they did something similar but
they actually could avoid the oops by
abusing fizmap which I don't have time
to get into it was really cool technique
so worth reading about that as well but
we didn't need to worry about his map at
all because fortunately the Ubuntu was
the Target and we just let it oops and
there's a like a little stack Trace in
in D message and that's it so we don't
really care especially for something
like pone to own
um so then so
um the question is how do we invoke the
gadget so we chose to use this garbage
collection initialization routine just
because it was with the values that we
overwrite in nft set in order to use the
gadget it had them the least constrained
sort of code path to trigger but
basically you just need to
um
initialize some expression that has this
garbage collection flag associated with
it which there currently only seems to
be one in the kernel called connection
limit
um and as long as like when you're
initializing that expression this flag
is set then it will just call GC in it
um yeah and that's pretty much all you
need to do
so probably
um unsurprisingly we targeted mod Pro
path just because it's like the path of
least resistance no pun intended
um and it's super well documented
technique by now and basically the
kernel just has a writable string
that and the string is basically used to
run something responsible for handling
module loading at runtime so userland
tries to trigger some functionality and
there's no module loaded so it tries to
execute this path as root
um
and so you can just overwrite it so in
this case we are limited to eight bytes
but we can just write like temp slash X
um and just we control temp X on the
system so we can run that as a root
obviously like in real world scenarios
like outside of something like pone to
own there's some limitations with like
being able to write just a short string
like this for instance temp might be
mounted as non-executable
um and then like if you're
um trying to exploit it from inside of a
container for instance your slash temp X
is not going to be the same light path
as what the uh whatever is running the
module
um
like the mod Pro path binaries temp path
is going to be because typically like
they'll use overlay paths and they'll be
like a guide or something so like you
wouldn't control temp X in the actual
um
the right context so but in our case we
didn't care because we were just trying
to do it for bone to own so it's enough
um yeah so basically that's what it
looks like
um
once we've crafted fake set two you can
see that now the Ops pointer points into
the structure itself which we can do
again because we leaked the address of
fake said to when we leaked the contents
of set one
um and then we just have like the fake
function pointer table where GC init
points to the gadget and we can see that
the gadget will reference a couple
members in fake set 2 field count and
use and then number of elements and
another one
um but fortunately for the code path to
hit GC in it the none of those members
actually get referenced so we just don't
care we can just put arbitrary data
there and that's basically enough to
overwrite mod Pro path
um so just to go back from the very
beginning so there's basically four use
after freeze I guess
um that are getting triggered the first
one we
um we end up using the user key payload
in order to leak the address of set one
in memory
um the second one we end up uh also
triggering the use after free of a
dynamic set and replace the the
structure with a c group FS context
which lets us overwrite release agent
and then when we destroy the really or
the C group it ends up freeing release
agent which allows us to free most of
set two
um and then we can replace that too with
fake set one
um and then that allows us to read set
one's
um
yeah structure from memory which allows
us to bypass kslr
and then finally we replace fig set one
with fixed two in order to execute the
rock Gadget
um and then yeah over a mod probe and
then all you have to do from user land
is try to trigger some functionality
that there's no module for and then you
basically get root
um yep
so
um basically the way they patched this
was a little bit different than we
thought because we thought maybe they
would just modify the destroy routines
to unbind
um from the set but they did something a
little bit more robust which is that
they don't initialize the non-stateful
Expressions at all when you're creating
the set so basically they're never gonna
do the allocation or anything so you
basically avoid any case where you have
desynchronization between initialization
and destruction which is good because
well good and bad because it also fixed
a separate bug that we had found also
related to the desynchronization and I
think there is probably a lot more there
um I wouldn't be surprised if yeah other
people had found some of those
but we can see in the patch
um basically when it's doing the this
expression initialization stuff what it
does first is it parses out the
information about the the expression
into like a little structure without
actually calling the initialization
routine or allocating it and then it
checks the flag from
um
the the data it collected first and then
uh if it's non-stateful it exits and
only afterwards will it actually try to
allocate it if it's the right type
so
um yeah in conclusion I guess
um I think NF tables is probably going
to have a lot more bugs like uh I showed
there's quite a few blogs about it
already I won't be surprised if there's
more this year
um and as far as like what made it
easier obviously like unprivileged
namespaces are bad
um so I guess people should disable them
if they can
um
in which some distros do this Panic on
oops thing seems dangerous
everybody's been using fuse server and
sedex Adder ever since user fault FD got
killed so it seems still super powerful
and mod Pro path is pretty common
um I guess one of the things that's kind
of interesting aside about exploiting
this bug aside from the fact that it was
kind of limited and and so far as what
you could write
um to the free chunk is a lot of
exploits lately have been using this
message message structure in order to
build like arbitrary read Primitives and
um write Primitives and stuff but in uh
well in this case we didn't have to use
it but actually in this case we couldn't
use it anyways because
um you know Ubuntu 22.04 when they
upgraded to 5.15 there was a change in
this lab cache
sort of um layout so message message is
now I think accounted there's like some
new accounting like bucketing for slab
caches so
um you basically can't allocate the
message message structures to replace
certain types of other objects you might
want to use during use after free so
it's kind of interesting just that we
didn't have to use it because everybody
likes to use it lately and yeah if you
just spend enough time understanding
the underlying code and stuff like Sam
mentioned in his presentation you can
find typically ways to abuse you know
the place that you're already working on
to find Primitives and whatnot
um yeah so as far as like some
mitigations go like how to avoid these
there's some pretty obvious stuff I
think the thing that was surprising to
me the most was probably that I when we
first had the idea of like freeing set
bindings address or expression bindings
address I assumed that given that a slab
cache is
um broken up into like objects of the
same size it would check whether or not
you're freeing a misaligned address
because I don't think there's a
legitimate reason why you would ever do
that maybe there is and I'm not aware so
if you know tell me but I feel like they
could probably just prevent that in the
future which would at least make things
a lot more annoying and then there's
other
um
mitigations that are kind of coming out
or been around for a while Jr security
has one called Auto slab and I think
like last week or something Google
posted some information about some
experimental mitigations that they're
working on that are coming out of the
kctf challenges which is for targeting
like kubernetes
um sandboxes and using kernel
exploitation to break out but the idea
is like
um all slab caches will have like OB
will be object specific so if you
allocate like the dynamic expression
structures on some slab cache and then
you free one you can't replace that with
a different like some C group FS context
structure it will just prevent that
entirely
um and if you're familiar with stuff
that people have been doing like in the
last year or so with targeting like the
buddy allocator you might think okay
well even if I can't replace the
[Music]
um
the object with a different type maybe I
can free the entire slab cache and
replace it with a new slab cache after
the fact
um well with totally different object
types and and people have been doing
that already lately I think there's been
a few blog yeah three blog posts maybe
in the last year
um but I think autoslab has some
functionality to avoid this and and
Google's mitigations
um their proposal anyway seems to have
some ideas about preventing this
so any memory that's ever been used for
a slab cache of a specific object can't
be used for a different type of slab
cache after the fact so that will be
kind of interesting but I don't know
um if I'll actually make it to uh
Mainline anytime soon because there's
lots of cool mitigations that exist that
don't make it which leads me to like
control flow Integrity so that's been
around inside Android for a while
already but I haven't heard lately any
like movement for getting that on x64
and that would at least prevent the rock
Gadget execution stuff
um and then other obvious stuff you
could set Panic on oops to one which
would at least prevent the um the gadget
that we use but there could be other
gadgets and stuff and I suspect in the
real world it's pretty inconvenient
because if you just occasionally look at
your D message output you might notice
things like Ubuntu
um semi-regularly well oops and then if
every time that took your box down it
might be kind of annoying
um and then yeah so there is like a
config option called config static user
mode helper which
um makes mod probe path read only and I
don't know why it's not used by default
on Ubuntu and certain other kernels if
you know why it's not by default I'd be
curious because I don't know a
legitimate use case that people are
regularly doing
um that warrants being able to update
the path I assume there's one but I
don't know what it is and then yeah like
some distros just don't allow
unprivileged namespaces which just
removes this entire attack surface which
is I guess better than almost anything
else
and then you could always get rid of
userline view server support and stuff
but there's a fair bit of stuff that
relies on fuse now so it might be a
little bit harder to do
um yeah so that's basically it um we're
gonna release a Blog with like a bunch
more details
um and a few more diagrams and stuff
and this was a team effort so like I
said it's a team of three
um so
different parts we we all worked on
together so it's Cedric and Alex and I
did it together and we are hiring we're
looking for a fourth person so if you
find this kind of stuff interesting and
potentially want to do it with us you
can check out the link in the slides
when I share them or
um you can find me
um yep and one last just random tidbit
um which is not related to anything I
just talked about but
so for the last like maybe 10 plus years
I have really bad repetitive strain
injury and so about two or three years
ago like I had to basically stop using
my hands for using computers entirely
and the most and so I've been doing all
of my research using a voice coding
framework and an eye tracker machine for
like tracking my eyes instead of using a
mouse and I use this free tool called
Talon which is amazing
um and there's a lot of Open Source Code
surrounding it to help people that have
these kind of disabilities or whatever
use it and keep doing research so I just
wanted to give a shout out to that
project
um because otherwise I probably wouldn't
be able to keep doing my job at all and
just say like
um try to take care of your hands and
your posture and stuff because if you
don't 20 years later it can catch up
with you and it really really sucks
um yep so that's it this should say
questions but
oh thank you very much Aaron for that
talk will you give me a round of
applause
[Music]
[Applause]
so we have a couple of questions up on
the screen here and just a reminder if
you are in the room and you'd like to
ask any questions you can use slido for
doing that
so we'll start off with the top one
there what does your process tooling for
searching and enumerating New Primitives
look like for example is it
predominantly automated via code ql
manual auditing or a mix
yeah I would say it's mostly manually
auditing
um like a lot of it is first just
trolling the existing
um tooling or and and blogs and stuff
that exist because a lot of the time
like there might be some one-off
scenario that someone already talked
about and at the time you weren't
interested in what's in there so a lot
of it is just like actually reading
stuff that is at least Loosely related
to the same topic that's not exactly the
same Target just to get some ideas I
personally mostly just look manually
like I try to understand
um and I mean manually like grepping for
stuff or whatever
um but
um Alex specifically has had good
success using code ql for automating
stuff and and in the case of like
finding this C Group C or FS contact
structure it really worked well so I
think
um we'll probably start using it more uh
I had not used it before so I think it
will become a mix more afterwards yeah
awesome thank you very much
and second there in your view have Linux
kernel vulnerabilities been increasingly
hard to find over the years if so why do
you think this trend exists or does it
not
um I I would say not and but like
um
I I mean it's hard to say like so a long
long time ago like say 15 years or
whatever you could just kind of grab the
source code and just find bugs like they
just fall out of this guy
um and so in that sense it's easier but
now that there's good fuzzers like if
you look at the amount of bugs that
something like sis caller can drop out
and if you look at the results of
something like that like sizzbot which
is Google's like fuzzing infrastructure
that uses sis caller there's tons and
tons of bugs that are just not even
triaged
um and and in the example of the one we
did it turns out it like it just closed
as invalid which clearly it was valid
um and and so in that sense I think
because of the
um Improvement in the ability of fuzzers
to find more harder to find by hand but
like manually find bugs like use after
freeze it's actually become easier
um and and I think it's just easier to
augment fuzzers and stuff now than it
used to be because there's such a good
Corpus of like uh like there's a whole
Community like you know in our industry
that loves fuzzing and they share tons
of details about how to customize
grammars and all this kind of stuff so
in that sense it's become easier I think
I would say that there's more
I remember like before maybe
it's just less more attention now less
attention in the past but I remember
like times when maybe in a year you'd
hear maybe like two or three cool Linux
kernel bugs but now I feel like every
other week there's some potentially
exploitable bugs so yeah I think it's
gotten easier
um and yeah I don't hopefully that
answers the question yeah thank you very
much for the detailed answers and thank
you to those who have asked questions in
the audience please join me again in
thanking everyone again thank you
[Applause]
[Music]