so
I'm really excited to present this topic
today in Singapore and
it's really an honor to be in person at
hack in the Box again so really liked it
last time was in Amsterdam I'm really
happy to enjoy the conference
um who am I so I'm Thomas
picture of me here
um I'm focusing on embedded iot security
related Technologies so hacking iot
stuff reverse engineering embedded
devices and I was speaker on various
conferences um like in the box of course
and idcx which is a local conference in
Austria and I've also published several
security advisories regarding embedded
devices regarding iot devices Also
regarding printers and if you remember
the keynote talk
um all of the devices which you Heards
their plcs and so on
I like them because they are insecure
so
the outline of my talk is
um just foundations so Baseline so what
you have to know about internet of
things security stuff and also digital
twins so
a lot of stuff like that
um
OT
infrastructure and typical OT security
assessment I'm trying to combine now
digital twins operate operating
technology and security vulnerability
research
all together in this talk and that's a
bit challenging of course the
construction of digital twins
a bit security testing uh
one thing the security vulnerabilities
are not published yet because the
vendors take a bit more time to fix them
but
those are really really easy
vulnerabilities and if you are
interested you can find them too that's
not a problem and of course a short
conclusion regarding all those topics
so what is OT some of you might know
it's operational technology like it
which is informational technology and
um you have a lot of devices on a lot of
levels in the OT environment that are
rtus plcs hmis engineering stage the
scada service historians and so on so a
lot of devices
and some of those are iot devices you
call them industrial internet of things
if they are placed in such an
operational technology network of course
can the IP cameras print those routers
and so on you also have them in operate
operating technology environments but if
those are industrial routers sensors
actuators industrial environments or
maybe cameras which are observing a
process like melting metal or whatever
it may be then it's of course called
industrial internet of things so the the
border between those two things is yeah
not not really not really hard
and you have digital twins
and during this session because there
are a lot of types of digital twins
during this session digital twins are
meant to be um
real
um it's like a copy from a operating
system from a real device because all of
those things are computers of course
um which is
running like a real system so you can
start it
but you don't need the hardware
sometimes digital twins are
um are just
um simulations of processes so that's
the difference so there are a lot of
different definitions of digital twins I
also call them firmware digital twins
because you're just copying the
operating system of the device from the
started or modified started and then it
runs like a real firmware of course you
have about
some implications but I will come to
this later
so in the early days
OT was just a field plus technology a
bit modbus a bit profit pass a bit can
bus systems which were cables just lying
around in the in the Fab and you
connected those devices together and
then you have just sent out your
messages via this bus technology you had
plcs with one programming interface a
com Port like
cables like this you know that the dsop
and a few kilobits of memory sometimes
so it was really a small computer really
basic
and
um supervision was implemented via
analog technology so maybe you know
those big rooms where you had lamps
where you had some kind of networks
everything really analog and the light
was just blinking if the process was
failing or whatever so supervision was
really done in an analog way
um in early days you had all those
things but nowadays
it gets more complicated you have
ethernet all around your Fab which is
sometimes doing supervision of uh
whatever power memory sensors actuators
and so on uh you have manageable
ethernet switches all around the
infrastructure so on all all those
levels so from Level zero to level uh
four and level five
in the aperture model of the OT system
and you have also because it's not
complicated enough you have also to add
routers firewalls to connect the IT
world with the OT so that it can export
data that you can access from the it to
the OT which is sometimes not a good
idea but it's
constantly done by a lot of companies
and you have a lot of peripheral devices
the iiot or the iot
so far as the goods what are the
differences between it and OT
from also from a Panthers Panthers
perspective you have a lot of network
bandwidth you have a lot of business
related information software time and so
on in it so that's the traditional it
system if I as a pen tester walk into a
company and do a penetration test some
of you might know in it systems you can
have a lot of fun it's really a lot a
lot of fun to do penetration tests and
yeah usually
no processes no physical processes are
dependent on those I.T systems so if the
server just reboots then okay some data
is lost but it reboots and it will work
next time
if some clients will just
um yeah be be stuck have denial of
service because you are doing a scanning
of the of a part scanning of the device
then yeah it's okay just stuck and
that's it you can reboot it no problem
in the OT world you have not that much
Network traffic you have a low bandwidth
you just need some signals to indicate
whether process is running whether
sensors or actuators are running are
just communicate some some signals in
between or to the scada server or from
scada server to the historian and so on
but it's it's not that much you have
also
industrial related information so it's
not really like okay in the next few
seconds I want to trade what about this
stock it's like
um
the sensor or the actuator says one or
zero so
um the motors or the engine is running
or is not running or the pump is doing
its work or not and you have also hard
real time so if you are not getting the
information of the current temperature
it may be too late in the next second
and
other things of course so if if a short
system failure is proceeding then maybe
it's it it's too late because
um
yeah the process already uh
turns down your whole Factory and you
can do you can spend the next
um two weeks or more just to build up
the process again to clean all the the
yeah all the whatever it may be so it
can be a manufacturing of
um I don't know some some parts for for
washing machines or it can be a bottling
company or whatever
you can spend a lot of time to to bring
it up again and sometimes even months if
it's a chemical Factory because yeah
then you have to clean a lot
and
the thing is upgrades are only are only
coming during maintenance windows and
maintenance Windows
[Music]
um are not not really often in OT
systems sometimes once a year sometimes
just one time in two years or in three
years or whatever because the factor is
is really really important and for
typical OT security assessments you have
to be careful you can have to lock all
your network traffic what you are doing
because otherwise it may be
um yeah the the
OT
um
the the the guy who's uh who is doing
the management of the whole OT network
uh is saying to you okay you have um
broken that process and now we have to
pay a lot of a lot of money a few
thousands of dollars or whatever and if
you can say no I have to lock my network
traffic and it's not my fault then of
course that's fine because otherwise you
yeah you have to pay all the money if
you have no good insurance and
um do not use automated security
scanners for it because those security
scanners may just break everything so I
I had
OT security assessments where I just did
support scan of course during a
maintenance window so it was not the big
problem but about
200 plcs were just rebooting that moment
that's bad if it's during the during the
daily work because then
yeah it may break a lot
uh
I have talked about the departure model
so you can see um some some kind of
purchase model in this figure so that's
also why
why I'm I'm telling you about faking at
level one because level one is this
section here so plcs rdu's and whatever
and you can see Enterprise I.T
infrastructure which is
the it World
um is connected here at level four so
really a high level after the whole
OT environment which you can see here
and usually it's also separated by
firewall and
um all the the stuff which is here below
is the whole OT Network infrastructure
which is composed by level three level
two level one level zero and sometimes
there is some kind of level 3.5 which is
the gateway to the it and you can see
there are a lot of devices here
engineering station
historian application station and so on
and here you have also your engineering
station where you can program the plcs
which is going down here to level one so
there are links in between of course
because otherwise you wouldn't be able
to connect those devices and you
wouldn't be able to to program them and
do supervision
and
the problem is sometimes our customers
just
um
don't do this kind of
um of
separation between the levels on the
horizontal or on vertical or anyway and
then you have all those devices in one
big Network which is sometimes a real
really big problem one of our customers
had just one one problem with one of his
switches which were broadcasting all
information all all packets through the
the whole switch because
we don't know maybe that the switch
table was flooded or or not we don't
know and then the whole OT network was
uh stuck was just in out of service of
the whole network so it's not even a
malicious attack it was just failure
that's it and for that cases it's it's
really wise to do this kind of
separation between those levels so how
do we do
um OT security assessments
pretty straightforward so it's like in
an I.T system but you have to to be a
bit carefully because it's like heart
surgery and not like knocking on all
doors in an apartment's house and yeah
it's a bit different but
the steps are the same so information
gathering then active testing and
afterwards reporting so for information
gathering you can also use the the
blueprints so reviews of the network
blueprints you can collect information
about all the system about the firmware
Doing Network sniffing but you have to
be careful and for active testing that's
yeah that you have to be really careful
um I would I would suggest to effort to
to to do step-by-step tests so just
trying to access the web interfaces then
trying to access
some some ports but not trying all in an
automated way
and it's also possible to use tenable OT
they have created some kind of
special scanning systems or like Nestles
but just for OT systems but
um in the end if something fails then
you know of service destroyed devices
um
yeah power supply and
even home in life can be can be put at
risk
so
if there are issues also in OT scanning
software like tenable
yeah if some some issue arrive arises
then you will have the problem as
penetration tester and your customer
will have the problem that the process
is just shut down and yeah can be a real
problem
so
so a possible solution for all those
problems because you can see it's it it
can have a lot of implications is to
make a digital copy of the whole OT
Network
of course not of all
um 100 of the devices but at least of
let's say 70 or 60 or 80 percent of the
devices because if you have a digital
copy with digital twins
um then you have the advantage that you
can put they can do a real pen test on
the digital copy and not on the OT
system of your customer so if that
device will be shut down or just will be
crash whatever for whatever reason
um that you are doing on the on the
network interface then yeah
it's not a problem because it's the
digital copy it's not the the real OT
Network and
such technique would be some kind of
virtual pen testing so there are also
vendors in the OT environments which are
using this as marketing passwords but
um
I asked them and it's it's not really
virtual pen testing it's just
um collecting uh from the from the
versions and collecting the the CVS
which
have been published of this firmware
versions
and
you know if you are using virtualization
so the digital twins a digital copy of
those um of those devices of those
infrastructure then it always has a
certain Gap so you will have a gap
between the digital twin and the
physical device because you cannot you
cannot really copy all the the iOS so if
you have some relays or if you have some
some signals going out and going in to
the device of course it's digital it's
it's just a copy it cannot simulate all
all stuff like this but you can emulate
the firmware and that's the the big
Advantage advantage and you can also
access via this Ethernet or Wi-Fi
interface to the digital copy which is
really great and
of course it's
um it's really difficult to do a digital
copy of all those different devices I
mean that's that's really really
a problem sometimes but it still pays
off if you are doing this because then
you have
the digital twin of the device and you
don't have to break the whole OT Network
and you don't have to pay a few Yeah
okay or more for just putting down the
operation of your vendors Fab
so
how is it possible to create some
digital twin to construct all of this so
of course we have heard that today you
can extract the firmware but you can
also download the firmware from the
Internet or from from the vendors
website you have to analyze the firmware
and prepare it for virtualization
because sometimes it's not working out
of the box and
then you have to to start at the desired
virtual way in in virtualization
environment to create the digital twin
there are open source tools and you have
to run the digital twin
um you can see a lot of tools here there
are more there's also uh there are also
derivations of those tools but all in
all
um maybe you know some of those logos
you have emox or Amex and Medusa
chilling and fermentine where there's
also a new version of this one or an
extended version which is called firm AE
I think it's from a Korean University
and you can see all of them or most of
them are specialized to creating digital
Twins or doing re-hosting because it's
always called in a different way
from Linux based firmware so
if you if you look for
emulation of some kind of real-time
operating systems of course there are
some tools out there but they are not
really easy to handle and if you are not
um if you are not an expert or if you
don't have any expertise regarding
regarding this topic then it's it's
really it's really hard to dig in there
and it's it's really hard to do
emulation of real-time operating system
but all in all those tools are some of
those which you can use for creating
digital twins
there's also a gap also in in those
tools of course as I have mentioned
before on the physical device you have
the chipset you have vulnerabilities
sometimes in in implementations of
drivers and and so on but you cannot
always emulate all of those chips and
sometimes you will not find some
vulnerabilities which may be present on
the real device
you have IOS
sometimes you cannot access access to
those iOS because they are not present
on the emulated device and you have the
emulated firmware
so
all in all
um virtualization of devices helps a lot
together the idea the big picture of the
whole device and how it works and that's
really valuable even though sometimes
you can you cannot emulate everything
but some but really often you get an
idea how it works how the processes are
connected to it to each other and
sometimes if you start the emulation you
will immediately see some strange Port
listening
on on the network interface and
sometimes it connects back to some kind
of telnet listener and then you know
okay there is a backdoor
and it happens really often
so
I've mentioned it
Pro you can do parallel tests live
debugging and so on
but Khan you have a lot of work and you
you can put a lot of time into cloning
the device
and it's not always possible for all OT
devices and it's also not really
possible for 100
but it's
um
it's it's really nice if you are able to
put a digital twin of your whole OT
Network and if you do pen testing just
on this digital twin instead of the
whole
OT environment
so
if you are doing security testing and if
you are doing security testing on Linux
based machines I guess you will know how
to do a white box test you you will also
know how to do queer box test because
sometimes you don't have the source code
of all the applications
and
I have brought some examples
so
um yeah because of the time I will not I
will not show everything but
that's not a problem
um you can see here two pictures on the
right hand side it's the
it's the web interface of a running
digital twin and on the left hand side
you can see all the open ports you can
see the listeners you can see the
processes you can see also
um the CPU info of the of the running
machine
and
I can show you also a live
emulation
so
here is I've used Medusa because it has
a web interface and
yeah it's really nice you have two
running firmers so from two different
vendors
and ports are also set for the serial
port
not for any any SSH telnet or whatever
listener it's really for a Serial Port
of the device of the digital twin
and I connected
um to the it's a bit slow because it's
via the mobile phone
um but I connected to the to the serial
Port of those devices and for me it's
now possible to type those commands like
ifconfig like
um net stats
and yeah just just look
um which ports are open which processes
are running while using PS for example
and
um I can also access to the web
interface of those devices
so
I'm connected via wirecard so that's a
nice thing
okay I'm not that good in Chinese to be
honest
but that's for example a device from
Delta Electronics
and
if it loads in time then you will be
able to see the web interface of this
OT device and that's
one part of a full digital twin from a
full OT Network
if you have multiple of those
controllers
managed switches routers and so on which
are part of the industrial internet of
things which is part of the OT Network
you can create a full
um a full or not a 100 but for example
70 percent duplicate of your customers
Network and then you can
um you can pen test those devices
instead of pan testing the real devices
and of course you can do it with Medusa
you can do it with thermodyne you can do
it with rmx all of them are based on
some kind of qimo on some kind of build
system and all of them can be used to to
create such
emulations such virtualizations of
embedded devices and with those
technique you're able to really to
create a snapshot of the of the network
and Pen test it and you can also see it
works for a broad range of devices
because a lot of devices are based on
Linux and that's the reason why it gets
more and more easy to just use this
technique so I guess it's yeah it's
really slow so it's it's one of the the
mobile phone while the hotspot and yeah
but
using this way you can also do port scan
you can also use nessus you can use just
any tool and you don't have to to lock
all your network traffic I mean I would
recommend to do it but you don't have to
do it for reasons like being sued from
the customer and paying a lot of money
because your breaking processes and yeah
that's that's really nice
so I had some some other devices from
Red Lion from
[Music]
um
prosoft from moxa so that's that's the
switch which
um also were emulators for 70
and that device was around ten thousand
dollars I guess and I just downloaded
the firmware and did a pen test on the
running firmware found vulnerabilities
and so yeah just told them that they
have vulnerabilities in their devices
and they also fixed those
vulnerabilities in I guess six other
device series because they are using the
same firmware base and yeah
that's that's really nice if you catch a
lot of them because then you have you
have
um helped to increase the security of a
lot of OT networks but uh
backside of this is the maintenance
windows are just once a year so
they will install it maybe next year
let's see so a lot of devices were
tested via this technique so by me and
by my colleagues and currently pending
out those two examples which I have
shown to you right now and sometimes you
have the well-known reactions if you
communicate those vulnerabilities to the
vendors which can be no it's not there
or just no reaction or an endless ping
pong process which goes to Nowhere
sometimes and that's the special case
for digital twins they say no it's your
controlled environment so the best thing
is just to not say that you have tested
those vulnerabilities on digital twins
because then the vendor will just say no
that's not possible
so
to sum it up if you want to do complete
OT security assessments it's always
challenging it's it's really hard to not
break anything
if you're using digital twins
you can build a full clone and you can
use this technique
to test iiot iot or printers or whatever
you want to test and you would not harm
any OT networks because you're just
testing a clone you're testing a
virtualization
and you can also find really easy new
vulnerabilities and communicate to the
them to the vendor without having the
device and that's that's really nice
and yeah they're also responsible or not
responsible vendors and you know that
from for from uh communicating
vulnerabilities to them but that's
nothing new so
thanks for listening my presentation and
if you have any questions I'm around for
the next day and and for this day and if
you want to talk about digital twins I'm
highly interested just talk to me and
yeah thank you