foreign
first of all I want to say thank you to
Dylan and the organizers and the
Fantastic Team in the back here for
helping me get everything set up this
morning turns out presenting from an
iPad is not just straightforward but
it's working
um as Dylan mentioned I have a keynoted
hack in the Box twice in Amsterdam and I
think both times I talked about
security for newsrooms and for recorders
and I am going to touch on some of that
today but I also wanted to take a look
at some of the security research I have
done in the past some of which you may
or may not know about and sort of look a
bit at
just the lessons that have that I've
learned along the way and sort of key
themes from that so
let's see if this works
um so if you don't know
um who I am I am originally from Oslo I
now live in New York and have lived
let's see I moved out of Norway 12 years
ago so it's been a while I'm very
passionate about journalism and security
I'll talk a bit more about that later
previously worked with the tour project
freedom of the press foundation and the
New York Times
currently the founder of granite also an
advisor to Ford foundation and cesa the
cyber security infrastructure Security
Agency in the US
one of the projects that I also kicked
out during the pandemic is journalism
spy on Instagram so it's an account that
profiles spies that used journalism as a
cover
or journalists that were also a spice so
it has me doing a lot of interesting
research there's a lot of like obscure
names that keep popping up a lot of
interesting books that I now have on my
bookshelf and in my sort of pile of
books I've been meaning to read that I'm
not sure I'll actually get to
um another thing that happened during
the pandemic is I got a very cute cat
named pumpkin
so um oh and as uh Dylan mentioned this
is my first time in Singapore so if you
have any recommendations for food
especially or good coffee or cafes or
anything like that I would I would love
to hear about it
so
with that
um I figured I would start with a story
uh going back to 1995
at the Office of Naval Research in the
US so
militaries around the world and
typically do have like a research lab
trying to come up with like different
ways in which to keep people safe
different ways in which to advance
either technology or weapons or anything
else that they have right that's not a
surprise so back in 95 Office of Naval
Research in the US
had this one goal
of building a system for internet-based
connections that can resist traffic
analysis eavesdropping and other attacks
and I think it's it's important to
remember that this was 1995 so before
end-to-end encryption became commonplace
before that sort of became the default
in a lot of different products
now after a lot of back and forth the
system that they came up with which may
look familiar to you
can be simplified like this
you have
um two individuals Alice and Bob and
between them they have three different
nodes to which they send their traffic
through
this is now also referred to as onion
routing which I'll mention in a second
later became known as tour so the way
that this works is
Bob over here will take whatever data he
wishes to transfer to Ellis and wrap it
in three layers and send that off to
three layers of encryption and send that
off to the first node the first known
will just know that here's a packet that
came from Bob
we'll peel off that first layer and see
that this packet needs to be routed to
the middle layer the metal layer will
then receive this package
see that it came from that first node
know that it needs to pass it off to the
third node but will not know that it
came from Bob or that it's going to
Alice
third node there will receive that
packet peel off that third and final
layer we'll know that it came from the
middle node and we'll know it as going
to Alice but will not know that it came
from Bob or exactly what it contains so
in the system that they then developed
um
the sort of early early prototype 4 they
were actually managed they then managed
to create the system to resist traffic
analysis eavesdropping and other attacks
so 1995 they successfully came up with
this model
um which then called onion writing what
they then later realized is
um
that
yes in this model in this context
um any outside party that can observe
the communications going between Alice
and Bob will not be able to see exactly
what it is that they're communicating
about because all of that information is
encrypted
but if they can see that Bob is using
the system and that Alice is using the
system and they know that this is the
system that is developed by
the Naval Research office and that this
is the system that is only ever used by
the US Military
you're not necessarily as secure or as
anonymous because granted anyone
observing the traffic cannot see exactly
what it is that they're communicating
about but they will know who's actually
using the system
so
in 2004
um Roger Nick and Paul then presented
tour the second generation onion router
at a conference and released sort of
this initial foundational paper on tour
and the concept of onion writing so that
was back when
um
the U.S naval research lab effectively
decided to take this system that had
served the goals that they set out to
achieve back in 1995 that was working
pretty well but they like I said found
that if you can see who's using the
system and you know that it's only
available to the U.S military you could
actually do a lot better for yourself
they then decided to open source
um tour open source the code make it
available to anyone everywhere
around the planet and it's actually
pretty interesting paper to go reads if
you haven't looked at it
um at any point in time I think it would
be a pretty interesting
thing to dig into so now
why am I telling
the story
so when I was sort of thinking about
like
the work that I do today and the
research that I've done over the years
and
especially thinking about what Chris
mentioned yesterday in his keynote about
curiosity and puzzles
um for me it really all comes back to
Google summer of code in 2009 and tour
so first I just want to say that Google
summer code is still a thing so if
you're a student you should definitely
apply to that next year it's a program
that's is set up by Google that's been
running for over a decade at this point
where Google will accept
um open source projects as part of this
Google summer of code program where uh
students will then effectively be paid
by Google over the summer to work on
projects for
for example tour so that's what I did
back in 2009 and when I first
when I first found tour or rather I
found Google summer of a code and I sort
of knew that this was a thing and I was
looking for a summer job and I was sort
of scrolling through the list of
projects on the Google summer code
website trying to figure out like what
are all the options what looks
interesting and I found this thing
called torque
and for me I became really curious right
away thinking like it is really cool
that you can use lines of code
and Technology to be anonymous online
that was sort of my starting point I did
not consider exactly the sort of impact
that tour has in the world I didn't
consider the many different ways in
which people use it I didn't consider
the upsides or the downsides or what it
what it meant to people for me initially
that that hook was just
it is really really cool that you can be
anonymous online using using this type
of tool
so it's been interesting then to see
over the years
how different ways of using Torah sort
of really
increased and and change going from that
very initial here's this thing here's
this browser or here's this program that
you can use to be anonymous online to
yes that is still very much a part of it
I think over the years we've also
started talking about using Tor to
access censored sites or to access
rather to bypass censorship in different
countries or on different networks I
think the bottom three points on this
slide is pretty interesting because
that's sort of how tour has developed
over the years
um there's the use cases of tour have
developed over the years so Michael Lee
who I think was yet the eff for many
years and is now at The Intercept
developed this tool called onion share
which allows people to securely share
files using a tour in a fairly like
um drag and drop kind of way and so it
sort of made file sharing in a quick and
secure way really really easy
um secure drop is now a tool that's
maintained and developed by freedom of
the press Foundation that allows media
organizations to set up the system for
receiving tips from the public that are
Anonymous and that whole system will
leverage the tour Network to allow
people to be anonymous if they if they
want to
um when I was at the New York Times
um starting in like 2016 towards the end
of 2016. we then set up the tips site
for the New York Times so on
androidtimes.com tips you can then see
different ways in which you can securely
or in some cases anonymously send tips
to The Newsroom and that includes
um sticker drop before that
time if you as a source wanted to send
something to the New York Times you had
to rather to a reporter you had to First
figure out
who you want to send it to she sort of
had to do some research on the reporter
that you wanted to reach out to
you had to figure out how do you how do
you even get in touch with that person
like maybe their email address is
available online maybe you can DM them
on Twitter maybe you just have to like
call the Main New York Times phone
number and ask to talk to this reporter
and and hope that they actually take
your call and even when you figure out
how to contact them you had to sort of
write whatever you wanted to send in
such a way that they were actually going
to to be interested in in talking to you
and
when that was the model not just at the
New York Times but it crossed
all insurance
and I think it's safe to say that a lot
of newsrooms did miss out on some really
good information simply because sources
either didn't know how to contact them
or they contacted them but people just
weren't that interested
and so by setting up this lab tips
Channel
um that includes secure drop it means
that there's a team of people that are
dedicated to them reviewing the
information that comes in across these
different platforms figure out is this
spam is it a cute cat photo is it a
legitimate news tip and then try to
figure out well
for anything that looks like a
legitimate news tip who in The Newsroom
should this go to and then there's a
secure workflow built around and how to
communicate internally in The Newsroom
with that information and so
back in the day
initially I want to say there was
probably about a dozen newsrooms using
secure drop and then over the years that
sort of become this gold standard for
for newsrooms like that that if if The
Newsroom wants to portray itself as one
that will protect its sources and allow
people to securely communicate with its
reporters it will have a secure up
instance in the desert and I think
that's been that's been really really
cool to see and also a good friend of
mine named Alec Muffet has developed the
Enterprise onion toolkit which allows
um really anyone to take a website and
set it up as a DOT onion site so that
would be a website that has um
long random address ending in dot onion
instead of.com or dot net that can only
be accessed if you're using the tour
browser and so over the years
um a lot of newsrooms have set up their
eotk site the CIA has set up a eotk site
as well and so like the number of ways
in which the people used for today has
like really really increased and really
changed over the years and
it's been it's been really fun for me to
sort of see like going from that initial
point of like hey like here's a tool
that just allows you to be anonymous
online and that's really cool to
over uh over the years you're seeing the
impact that tour has in the world and
what it allows people to do and the
types of technologies that can sort of
be built around and on top of this
now it's also been done interesting to
see over the years how
technology how encryption how tools like
tours sort of help change the narrative
around
security around encryption around online
anonymity especially and I'll say
especially in Europe and in the US and
so I think that what I've put on the
slide here is sort of my take on it in
my perspective I don't know a whole lot
about how the narrative
may or may not have shifted over the
years in this region so if anyone has
any thoughts on that that they want to
share with me later I would I would love
to hear about it
um in Europe and in the US the debate
around using tools like tour and using
um
any sort of online anonymity tool using
encryption and sort of gone from like
um
people saying well if you if if you're
using this tool if you want to be
anonymous online then like surely it's
because you have something that you want
to hide
I don't have anything to hide so I don't
need to use these tools to now it's it's
fairly common for that argument to just
be uh well I'm using this tool because I
have something to protect because I just
don't want you to have access to that
data it's not data that you need to have
about me
and similarly like the the way that we
talk about
if you have a home you typically do
close the windows
before you leave and you lock the door
so that people can't just like walk
right into your home and take whatever
they want and similarly you encrypt
everything that you can because it's
your data it is private there's no
um
why should anyone else have access to
that right why should anyone else see
that and so just the way that people
think about and talk about encryption
has shifted over the years
um I remember
many many years ago talking to people
about using Tor and one of the first
questions that came up was like well if
I use Tour on this network then I'm
going to stand out because I am one of
the only people using Tor and I think
that that is that was and still is a
good argument but I think today using
Tor or using any sort of encryption tool
has become far more common that in some
cases not using that
is going to make you stand out on the
wire as opposed to standing in because
you're using those tools
um
end-to-end is becoming the new default
so
years ago I remember when signal first
came out and I installed signal on my
phone
and I was trying to figure out well how
do I how do I get my friends to use this
this app and
um
option one I couldn't sort of explain to
them the benefits of end-to-end
encryption and what signal can do for
them and how amazing the tool is
um I don't know if they would be too
interested in that so I just told them
well hey if you install this this app
and use it then you can call me for free
and that was sort of like a good enough
hook
but these days encrypting uh data
end-to-end by default is now becoming
display this new standard that companies
are actually moving towards you have
signal into an encryption by default
WhatsApp end-to-end encryption by
default meta recently announced that it
is working towards into an encryption by
default for Instagram messages and
Facebook messages as well and it's
to the point now especially in the US
whereas new technologies roll out that
enable Communications between two
parties that there's this immediate
question of like does it support
end-to-end encryption by default and if
not then why
so if you've been following all the news
around Twitter
um over the past especially six months
but
um also just this past week there's a
lot of questions then around
um if so many Engineers have access to
the production environment and so many
Engineers have access to personal data
and then potentially also direct
messages why hasn't Twitter done more to
ensure that that data is encrypted by
default
another interesting point is
um years ago again the argument was well
if you're providing people with a tool
like tour that allows people to be
anonymous online then bad people can do
bad things
and that is still very much
um an argument that I hear but sort of
less so or less often than back then and
I don't know if I still have like a good
answer to that argument I think back
then I would say
um that
it does enable
it enables people to be secure online
and to do whatever it is that they want
to do in a secure and private way and I
think that that is worth doing even if
some people do bad things I think just
because there are people in the world
that do bad things does not mean that
the rest of us should just give up any
right to privacy or online anonymity
to sort of maintain
um
to make it easier I guess for uh law
enforcement to catch the bad people I
think similarly like any sort of
Technology can at some point and will at
some point be misused by bad people to
do bad things that does not mean that
the rest of us should just sort of give
up any right to good
security
um and it's been sort of very
interesting just to see the debate
around that over the years
if you're interested in certain the
arguments or the history around and to
an encryption by default and exactly
what end to end really entails
um Alec Muffet has written a fairly long
paper really looking at a lot of
different arguments around end-to-end
encryption defining what end-to-end
encryption really is and I'd recommend
you go read that I think I have a link
to it at the end of my slides as well
it's also been really interesting just
to see how like the
The Narrative around hackers in the
world has has changed so back in the day
hackers with the black hoodie that's
still definitely a thing but we are uh
thankfully getting better stock images
now but I think the public view for
quite some time was that hackers were
just destroying the world there was no
Rhyme or Reason or purpose to it we
weren't really up to anything good and
we were just out here causing trouble
and I think now over the years we've
sort of demonstrated that sure yes we do
we do those things because we can
because it's fun and I'll share my
examples about that in uh in a bit but
there's actually a lot of good work in
what we do as well and
I think cyber security today equals
National Security as well I think that
there's so much now that is just
intertwined with the work that we're
doing in the space that we're in that
there's definitely this like framing of
like here's all these people that for
years we deserve us people that are just
destroying the world who are actually
now making a difference which I think is
really really cool and it says something
about just what we can do with the work
that we're doing and the way that we're
talking about it
um and how people
are more likely to pay attention to what
we're doing and what we're seeing now
than perhaps what they were 10 years ago
so
sort of on that note
the work that I do today and and have
done for about
a decade at this point is focusing
around securing reporters and at-risk
people around the world so back in
I think it was 2011 tour project got
some funding to train reporters and I
ended up leading that project and
initially the goal there was just to
teach reporters how to use the Tor
Browser
and we very quickly found that it's not
super helpful or super impactful to
teach people how to use Tor if they're
not also familiar with other security
best practices like good passwords and
two Factor authentication and software
updates and what a network admin can and
cannot see on the wire for example so we
ended up building up a curriculum around
that and it was that experience that I
later took with me to freedom of the
pest Foundation Building The Newsroom
security program at the New York Times
and now also at Granite so the way that
I view securing a reporter is that being
a journalist is more than nine to five
right
you are
at the movie theater you're still a
reporter at that point you're traveling
you're still a reporter you're on your
way home from the office and something
interesting pops up on Twitter
if it's something that you're covering
you're probably going to cover that as
well then because that's just sort of
part of what you do so being a
journalist is far more than like a
nine-to-five job it's an identity and
the work that a reporter is doing then
requires support from others so like the
business side of the immediate
organization
take it
with the endpoint securing the end point
legal for any sort of legal threats that
they may be dealing with security for
securing any accounts and systems and
devices that they're using Engineers who
are developing the content Management
Systems they can actually publish their
articles there's a lot of work that sort
of goes be goes on on the business side
of a media organization to support the
work that the reporters are doing and
what's been sort of interesting over the
years is that
a business will often then take
um
will take this idea that they are there
to provide whatever the business needs
within the hours of nine to five
Security will focus on securing the
corporate systems and assets and
accounts that the individuals are using
but if you're a reporter and that is
your identity I can assure you that you
are going to use accounts and systems
that are both your personal
and the corporate ones another question
becomes how do you then secure the
how do you enable someone to do whatever
it is that they're trying to do in a
secure way regardless of the device that
they're using so that is sort of some of
the work that I'm looking into like how
would you secure someone doing
anti-corruption work
whether it's on a personal device a
corporate device traveling maybe they're
not
um a lot of it comes down to the
security sort of Basics I would say the
updates and two-factor and passwords and
knowing what kind of devices or accounts
to use and what not to use if I had to
prepare for a trip
but in many cases
um
what it also comes down to is just how
you think about all of those things and
how you can like put all of the right
pieces together so like going back to uh
Chris's keynote yesterday and thinking
about it as sort of being really really
curious about how to make this puzzle
work that is sort of what I really get
away
um take away from this work because
let's say uh someone will come to me and
say hey we're going on a reporting trip
to North Korea in two weeks
what do we need to know
and that isn't an opportunity like I
then viewed that as a puzzle to figure
out while you're traveling so like
you're leaving the country you're
entering a new country
um here's what I know about your trip
the type of people that you're more most
likely to talk to or the places you're
where you're gonna stay here's the type
of material you're going to gather on
your trip that we then need to keep safe
for me that becomes this like one one
big big puzzle we tried to figure out
well how do you then keep this
individual and their identity safe from
a physical digital emotional and legal
standpoint
and that I think is work that I find
really really interesting and it's sort
of been really fun to see how that's
evolved over the years from you know
people at the tour project teaching
reporters how to use the tour browser to
now uh Media or organizations
having dedicated security teams having
people dedicated to supporting the
newsrooms and also being able to do the
work that I'm doing now
so
like I said that is a big part of what I
do and it has like this great Mission
and big impact
curiosity and puzzles
but when it comes down to puzzles
for me it's sort of always like started
with this question of like what happens
as a kid I would ask like a billion
questions about what happens if I do
this what happens if I do that
why does this happen why is this a thing
um and I think that sort of drives a lot
of the type of work that that we do as
well it sort of all comes down to the
Curiosity and sort of having the ability
to just ask
what happens if and then actually trying
it out
so
back in 2015 my husband and I hacked a
Wireless
powered uh sniper rifold and
um like I said I grew up in Norway my
husband's in
um he's American I've always been very
very fascinated with like stereotypical
American things
so in 2014 like a year before we
presented the research and he just went
and said hey you've never been to a gun
show I was like no no I'm not sure how I
feel about that but
why not sure let's go
so we went to this gun show in
Washington DC and
looked at all the different vendors and
I came across one
um from a company called tracking point
that showed off this like rifle
that to me looked like a fairly standard
rifle I'm not familiar with like weapons
or guns or anything so to me that just
sort of looked like a fairly standard
rifle but they were like talking about
it as if it was like this really really
fancy new Innovative thing
um and as it was flipping through the
brochure in the car on the way home I
sort of saw that it has
um mobile apps
the software updates it has USB ports uh
it has Wi-Fi
it has a little computer inside of it
um and I just turned to my husband and
said hey you know we should we should
buy one hack it and present it blackhead
and Defcon next year
and uh to my surprise he said sure
so we bought two of them
um and have have them sitting on a
kitchen counter for about eight months
sort of half open with like cables
coming out of it hooked up to the
battery hooked up to the laptops the way
that this rifle works is that's like a
stock
Remington rifle
with the scope that tracking Point has
then built and put a little computer
inside of it that's like a beaglebone
black
and then it has technology going to the
trigger where you have the red button so
the way that this works and you can
really call it sniping for dummies is
that you line up whatever you want your
target to be then you press the red
button to tag your targets
um also add that if you're standing in
the back and you want to sit down there
are seats up front as well so don't feel
like you have to stand for the rest of
the talk
um so you will
tag your Target by pushing the red
button
at that point the trigger is locked
so you will be applying pressure to the
trigger and when the little computer has
calculated that if you release the
trigger at that point in time you will
hit your target
so
me with like no experience whatsoever
um firing guns can hit my intended
target every single time
that's sort of how it's supposed to work
now what we ended up doing is
um we started off first looking at like
I said it has two mobile apps it has one
app that just allows
um one person to see
what the shooter is seeing inside the
Scopes it's just like a live feed
basically of the same screen that's one
app the other app then allows you to
change some of the settings for like
wind and temperature and the type of
bullet that you're using
um so that the computer can use all of
that info to set you for Success
essentially
um
and then it has like I said USB ports
um software updates and things like that
so we started poking at both the
hardware side and the smoke collabs
trying to just understand the
communication between the two parties
trying to figure out what might be
possible what kind of assumptions the
developers have sort of put into the
creation of
um of these apps and this
technology
um and we got we got sort of Fairly far
on our own but but at some point we did
um
we did
take the rifle with us to a hackerspace
where we met up with a bunch of friends
who just really helped us out by helping
us gain access to the file system which
um was unencrypted and at that point it
allowed us access to a whole lot more
interesting data and I think that that
is sort of one point that
if there's one thing that all these
years later I still think about when it
comes to this research it is the number
of people that you sort of jumped at the
chance to like help us out with this and
even as we got access to the file system
which was sort of our initial goal at
that point their response was cool well
we got access to the file system what
else can we do now to help you make your
talk even more awesome
and the fact that there are so many
people in this community that are just
willing to help out and
make someone else's talk uh really
really cool or help them find like that
one thing that is just going to make a
huge difference in your research I think
it's just fantastic and it's definitely
a project that we had a lot of fun with
um definitely going back to the sort of
question of like what happens if
so
um I will say that over the years as I
sort of talked about this this research
one question that keeps coming up is uh
does it run Doom uh no it does not but
um one of the things that we were able
to do was
when we looked at how it does software
updates
since we had access to the file system
the updates themselves so the way that
the software update would work
is that the rifle would communicate with
the mobile app to request an update the
mobile app would then connect out to
TrackingPoint server
to request the update the update would
be downloaded to your mobile device and
then passed to the rifle and all of that
that update would be encrypted so it
would be decrypted once it hit the file
system on the rifle once we had access
to the file system that we had access to
the private key to decrypt the software
update and we also found that it's the
same it's the same key on older
rifles so if you have access to one you
have access to the key you can create a
custom software update for any tracking
point
firearm
so we created our own update that
instead of showing the update screen
shows the game over duck hunt screen
I'll also say that while we were not
able to fire remotely
we could do a bunch of different things
like we could we could lock the trigger
so that you could not fire at all until
you had rebooted the rifle which sounds
ridiculous but you had to reboot the
rifle to undo that change we also
through the software updates could make
persistent changes so that your rifle
would just like by default be slightly
wonky we could change the values for
wind and temperature and type of bullet
beyond what was available in the mobile
app
to the point that it affected how the
rifle would fire so instead of thinking
that you're going to hit your intended
target you actually end up hitting two
and a half feet to the left or to the
right without there being any indication
that this is going to happen whatsoever
and
a lot of this work sort of came out of
that like initial question I'm like well
what happens if I do this like what is
actually
doable and
this is perhaps my like favorite vendor
response
um ever on the day that we presented Air
Research in 2015 the official tracking
Point website had this statement on it
that says it's Contin it's safe to
continue using the Wi-Fi on your rifle
if you're confident there are no hackers
within 100 feet
which I will say that the company
shortly after I think uh
went bankrupt I don't know if they're
still around today
um I don't think that they did very well
but
um
yeah
definitely one of these like projects
that I
um
very much enjoyed doing
purely
because we could purely because it would
be like such a fun puzzle to deal with
and uh also because I had always wanted
to speak at black hat in Defcon like
growing up in Norway that was something
that I just like saw from
afar saw from a distance and that this
was like this really really cool space
really cool event and I like really
wanted to be able to one day
give this amazing
talk just because at blackhead and this
was very much one of those projects
where like we were very clear from like
the get-go that this is more of like a
stunt hack type of talk it doesn't have
um a whole lot of lessons learned there
aren't necessarily a huge like societal
positive impact or benefit from this
research this is like purely because we
can and so we did type of work and I
think there's a lot of value in that as
well
so the next example that I have then
um along the sort of I wonder if I can
do
X
a couple of years ago Patrick Wardle
started working on this book about uh
Mac malware and how he can get started
in analyzing militia software for Mac OS
and he initially set out to sort of
write this book as this publicly
available Google doc Open Source book
that once he finished that no starch
then offered to sort of print it up into
an actual book book but so when when
Patrick set out to do this work he at
one point tweeted and saying you know
like anyone that can help me edit edit
this book
is it sure it sounds it sounds like fun
it's not a topic that I have too much
experience with I think that editing the
book would be a great way for me to one
read the content but also learn a lot
along the way
um
and
um Patrick and I then made this deal
that I would edit the book and then the
year after at his conference objective
by the sea I would then get to take the
training which is follows the book as
well so that was like this really
interesting uh collaboration that we set
up now when reading through the book
which like talks about like how to set
up a malware analysis environment the
tools that you can use a lot of them are
um his tools that are free and open
source and great like it sort of talks
you through how to set up the
environment
how to get started where to find samples
what you should be looking for in the
different samples that made me think
back to
um this story from 2017 where
um
Wikileaks released this trobe of alleged
CIA hacking documents and also hacking
tools so this was what was known as
Vault 7 back then
um and over the years I've been very
interested in stories like this and
especially cases where tools are also
being released
and I had been sort of thinking about
um
one one in particular that so shortly
after like this article was published in
March of
2717 about a month later semantic and
then later Kaspersky published then
their research saying like hey here's
the thing that we're aware of that we
call the Lamberts what we know about the
land Birds tracks with what Wikileaks
has now published
um
saying that this is the CIA we do
believe that these are the same here's
the research that we're publishing
semantic published their work so like
here's here's what we have
um and in in reading through that there
was sort of one thing that
um stood out to me
which is uh
green Lambert so uh Kaspersky had sort
of called the collection of tools as the
Lambert's toolkit and specific
samples within the toolkit then have
like a color so you will have black
Lambert and I think white Lambert and
then green Lambert where they noted that
the green and Lambert family is the only
one where a non-windows version has been
found
um compiled for OS X almost uploaded
from Russia to a multi-scanner service
which in this case just means virus
total in 2014. so it had been around for
a while but this is for the first time
that someone was actually linking it
back to the land Birds by name which
then
um
we all assumed was the CIA
and so I had been like seeing this story
over the years and I thought it was
really really interesting that like
here's a sample compiled for OS X that
has been around since 2014. this article
came out in
2017. I was going through like Patrick's
book uh trying to sort of learn uh what
is possible and how I can get started
and so I figured well
what happens if I look into the specific
sample
um I'm sure that there's people who have
been doing this type of work for a very
very long time will be able to find far
more interesting things than than I can
but surely if no one's published if no
one's made an attempt and published
their findings then
why don't I give it a try and
that then resulted in this talk that
this drone talked that Patrick and I
gave at objective by the Sea a year ago
looking at U.S by agencies Mac OS
implants so I looked at Green Lambert
for Mac OS and Patrick looked at some of
the NSA tools that have come out over
the years and this is very much this
like type of project where for one
Patrick was very very patient and very
helpful he's been doing this this table
work for a very long time I'm just like
sort of kind of
um getting started but also managed to
find some what I think are pretty cool
things so
foreign
I did for the sample was sort of just
look at the strings in the sample just
to see if there's anything interesting
there try to see if
um if there are things that we can learn
about how how it works
um and there were some like options for
like how the sample would like gain
persistence
um that it would do something with proxy
settings that you'd use xcode 2.2 which
was released in 2005 and what I also
thought was really interesting is that I
found this like one of the strings says
error from lib event when adding events
and I knew from my work with the tour
project back in the day that that is a
library that is also used in Tor and has
been created by some of the same people
that created tour initially so I
remember when talking to Patrick about
this this output and he was just sort of
checking to see if there was anything
else there and he's like oh well like
this doesn't like mean anything and this
doesn't seem all that interesting and he
just stepped over this part but to me
with my tour experience and tour
background that made sense to me and it
was something that I felt like including
in in the research so that just sort of
goes to show that even if you don't have
any sort of experience with it with
malware analysis that doesn't mean that
there aren't things that that you can
bring to the table
um and find as well
so in in mapping and sort of going
through the strings for the sample and
trying to figure out like what actually
looks interesting and then looking at
what do we know about
when Wikileaks release the data when the
data was taken from the CIA
the different versions of libivent and
xcode the type of version of Mac OS so
this sample would most likely run on
we then managed to create this timeline
of a sort of
most likely development and use timeline
for this piece of malware so we can like
work backwards from Wikileaks publishing
the bolt 7 dump
um to when it was first detected by
Kaspersky to when it was put up on
buyer's total versions of Mac OS 10 7
and 10 8 back to xcode and live event
and then show that it was most likely
developed and used sometime between 2007
and 2013.
and
um
one interesting thing I think with like
looking at really old samples especially
ones that no one's really looked at is
one it does say something about the
capabilities of in this case the CIA
back in
2017-2013 which sort of does make you
wonder whether up to now
um but it also just talks about like
what was possible back then and and the
different sort of assumptions and
techniques that malware authors would
have to leverage and to do whatever it
is that they that they wanted to do
um I spent
a good amount of time trying to get a
version of OS X up and running that
could actually run the sample so sure
there's like so there's only so much
that you can do with static analysis and
I also really wanted to find a way to to
run it after Googling a bunch and
struggling a bunch uh without like
getting anywhere just like I can just
like spend a hundred dollars on eBay and
buy this really old MacBook and run it
on that and that actually worked out
worked out
very very well so uh in in doing that I
was able to then both get the host name
that it reaches back out to and the IP
address and make that available which is
information that to that day had not
been made public before all from just
taking the sample and putting it on this
really old laptop that I got off of eBay
um I also
about a year ago on my research blog
Matt
the sample to the miter attack framework
so if that's type of research that
you're interested in that's available
there as well
but
and I think this is like a big big book
I think in this industry there's a lot
of talk about apts and Odes because yes
it's it's sexy it's really cool it's fun
it's really exciting it it does
um
it does draw an audience
but I think that looking at all the work
that I've done and all the different
sort of security research I've done over
the years there's yes there's definitely
work that I've done just because I can
that's fine just to prove a point or
just to even show to myself that I can
figure it out and that I can learn
something new and find something that
other people have not either not found
or at least not made public but I think
that so much of the work that we do
especially as as I mentioned earlier
with cyber security also now being equal
to National Security I think that it is
really important to remember that the
majority of the work that we do is not
all apts and OD is that there is a whole
lot of value in what we do and the
things that we're talking about and
presenting especially at events like
this
so
the
the thing that I really want to leave
you with
um and I was trying to figure out like
if I'm talking about my security
research over the years and sort of
things I've learned along the way what
is the takeaway that I want to leave you
with and it's that I think it's really
really important that one that you do
things that you enjoy
with other and sister really being in a
sort of Greater purpose to it you do it
because it's fine you do it because it's
exciting because you're curious about it
because you wonder what happens in yes
and I also think it's really important
that you do things that you don't know
how to do in part because you get to
meet a lot of amazing people along the
way you also get to learn something new
and more often than not you'll find that
all the experience that you have to date
will actually at some point help you in
this new thing that you're just now
learning how to do there are so many
good talks and resources and workshops
out there to help you get started in
whatever new space of cyber security
that you want to look at it's also a
pervade Community to ask for help I
think both with the gun hacking and the
journalism security work and the malware
analysis like I wouldn't have been able
to do half of that if I hadn't had
access to this great community of people
also again say that Google summer code
is still a thing so if you are a student
keep out keep an eye out on the Google
summer code website
um I think they'll announce a new round
maybe beginning of next year and then
the application period will probably be
around
March April so keep an eye out for that
and uh check out the tour project still
very much around there are different
ways to get involved with that project
and also uni which is the open
Observatory of network interference so
if you're interested in looking
specifically at how tour and other tools
and sites are blocked in different parts
of the world and how different
authorities censor these types of tools
and sites and there's a lot of data
there and a lot of different ways that
you can contribute and get involved
so
with that
I hope you have a great rest of your
conference thank Adrian to Dylan and
team for having me and if anyone's got
any questions either now while I'm up
here or later today I am happy to chat
thank you
thank you Aruna so we do have some
questions cool
um the first one is do you see a future
where anonymity being script perhaps by
government authorities due to malicious
attackers using this future to their
advantage
foreign
well not really I think that what we are
seeing and what sort of has been the
case over the years and continues to be
the cases or this like friction
um in in that particular space is there
are and I think we'll always will be
people who who see that here's this type
of technology that allows bad people to
do bad things
we cannot allow that to continue and
there are people that are willing to
compromise on the security and privacy
that everyone else gets because there
are bad people to do bad things I don't
think that uh that is a group that is
going to win I think that end-to-end
encryption for example is going to be
the new default but I think that that is
like a very consistent debate that we
are going to see over and over and over
again
all right and the next one by Tolkien
the Keynotes have talked about reversing
of propriety hardware and or firmware
binary blobs in some countries the law
is fake and open security researches to
possible lawsuits and stuff like
curiosity could you give any advice to
those that are curious but want to stay
out of the way of the law
there's definitely an aspect of that
that also speaks to what is what is
legal
um because when it comes to security
research there is strengths to some
extent right we're taking this step out
like saying well what happens if I touch
that button what happens if I do this
thing and also legally
can I and is that something that like
I'm willing to
um to challenge so I know that security
researchers in the US can uh can and
also often do reach out to the
electronic for Care Foundation to get
some
um support there around like what is
doable what is the legal how do I
approach this type of work
um I would say that if you know of like
an eff equivalent where you are reach
out to them and sort of see if they can
help you out with that part of your work
initially if you don't know who to reach
out to reach out to the eff in the US
and I'm pretty sure that they can at the
very least try and help find someone
that can speak to the laws in whatever
part of the world you are for the type
of research that that you want to do
all right thank you is talking here by
any chance for a gift
all right a positive after this
um the next question by Gemini regarding
hacking tracking points water gun were
their fears concerns regarding while
eating any user agreement Clauses
restricting reverse engineering
luck
yeah
thank you so thank you
um
any concerns I did I did speak to a
friend who's a lawyer before we uh I
think it was after we bought the rifle
before we did a bunch of things that we
didn't know how to do uh so probably in
the in the wrong order but uh were there
really concerns not really were the
things that I just sort of double
checked with the lawyer before we
started doing yes so I had a sense of
like what would be more or less
contentious as part of the research
um the next one how do you get the
general public to care more about
privacy moving from nothing to height to
something to protect
that's that's a fun one because I think
that goes like hand in hand with like
how do you get people to care more about
security
I think
if you spend a lot of time on securing
the awareness and education you'll
you'll find that different messaging
different ways of explaining things will
land with different people so like
through this big room there's a way that
I could explain the benefit of
end-to-end encryption that to some may
make total sense just um like either
don't get it or don't care
and that has nothing to do with like
people not being interested in the topic
it's just like sometimes you just need
the right message with the right words
with the right examples to land with the
audience and I think when it comes to
then getting more people to really care
about privacy I think there's two parts
to it one is to consistently deliver the
message that you have it is it is really
something that you just need to keep on
doing again and again and again and just
be very consistent with I think another
part of it is also for for us to focus
on building and security and privacy
defaults in the products that we're
shipping so that people don't have to
think about
privacy and security they don't have to
focus so much on it they don't have to
care as deeply about it as we do because
it is just a part of their world and
their life and the products that they're
using
fair enough
um the next question what are your
comments on e2e instant messaging
systems which use keywords such as on
the endpoint are there any IM systems
using it today
some searches on the endpoints
is the person who has the question here
can they elaborate on it
[Music]
for example search for bomb or I don't
know so breaking the end-to-end
encryption by checking the unencrypted
messages on the endpoint
like that verse some talks about it that
this might happen
to be compliant with some compliance
laws but still end-to-end encrypted
yeah it's I think that sort of goes goes
back to this like question around like
when you're talking about e2e so you
have end to end
what do you define as an end
and is end to end between two devices
only or can an end be multiple devices
but owned by the same individual and so
I think
um it's sort of always interesting to
see uh like court records in which
someone like in which law enforcement
suddenly has access to uh WhatsApp
messages between two parties because
people will then ask well isn't WhatsApp
end-to-end encrypted and the answer is
yes it's just not going to extend to you
taking your WhatsApp chats and putting
it unencrypted in Google Drive or
something like that so I think that like
that is
um it's it's an interesting topic that I
do think that we need to talk more about
so that people understand like what what
is the scope for end to end or end too
many ends
um and and what are things that it still
cannot achieve but happy to talk more
about that one okay
and the final question hi Runa thanks
for the great keynote I was curious
about your IG at journalist and spy
could you tell us a little bit about it
do journalists make good spice and vice
versa
thank you
um
so that was
I've always been like a big fan of uh
True Crime and Espionage and and that
type of uh stuff and so at some point
during the pandemic I sort of had this
idea that I was I was reading some book
and it referred to a spy that used
journalism as a cover and and I sort of
thought that well that's not entirely
uncommon it's it is a really really well
cover to use for one it's the type of
cover that like if you're an
investigative journalist you can walk
into any conference
any space anywhere in the world and just
automatically by default by having that
title it can be internally normal for
you to just like go around and ask a lot
of questions and be very direct in your
questions and meet people and socialize
and gather information
um so I think that invalid in that sense
um journalism
um
Aid workers human right Defenders like
all of those uh profession also do make
really really good covers I do think
that when they're used as covers by
um intelligence service it does do a
huge disfavor to
um
to those people though
but yeah so the project just sort of
came came disservice was the word I was
looking for
um
the project just sort of started out
because I was really curious about
surely there are more individuals that
have been using it either as a cover or
reporters that at some point in time
have
started working more closely with the
intelligence service and I just wanted
to see how many there were out there and
I now have a pretty good list that I'm
building out but um happy to chat more
about it also if there are more
specifics that you want to know
all right thank you
add any more questions from the crowd
none okay um is matahari and Gemini here
we have some prizes for you as well
no okay
um I guess thanks again Rona let's give
a round of applause