welcome to my presentation
today I'm going to show an explosion on
Apple Mac diverse just from one click to
complete takeover
first
let me make a brief introduction
I am Mickey G
a security researcher from Trend Micro
my main job is to analyze some mobile
and hunt for zero day vulnerabilities
now I had many effects on the security
of Apple products
over the past two years
I have submitted over 100 reports to
Apple
and got more than CBE credits from them
I usually enjoy reversing and debugging
and this is my Twitter Handler
h1t
welcome to follow me on Twitter thanks
okay here is my agenda
first
I will explain the motivation to take
such an explosion
then I will cover some related texts in
the real world
next I will talk about the challenges I
encountered and how I overcame them
then there are the details of the
vulnerabilities I discovered for this
expression
I will provide an awesome demo by
changing this box together
before the end I will share another
vulnerability which I discovered during
the research
finally I will make a summary and show
the code Repository
so
why do I want to dig such an explosion
the reason is simple
apple offers General spark bounties for
explosions
here if my chance can be divided into
two categories
one click and zero click
and the Apple has already give given the
definitions one click refers to an
exploit
requiring user interaction to
successfully gain access or execution
for example the user collects a
malicious link or opens a malicious file
zero click prefers to exploit
requiring no user interaction to do that
for example being our Network or in
proximity is sufficient
sensitive sensitive data refers to some
privacy items that should be protected
by TCC
such as contacts nodes photos and so on
so you might be wondering is there any
related attacks before
next let's take a look at some place
classic case about zero click and one
click in the real world over the past
two years
here are two zero click attack cases
the first one is about a message
exploitation
this is a classic research by Samuel
grope from Google project zero
the root cause is a memory corruption
issue in the NSR cable API
triggered by the deterioration of a
message data
after exploiting the bug for remote code
execution he attacked the mountain box
process to escape the sandbox by reusing
the same bug
finally he found the iPhone remotely by
sending some crafty iMessage data
without any user interaction
the second case is the Pegasus firewall
which is developed by an ISO group and
disclosed by citizen app
it is used at least two zero days in the
attack
the first one is cve 2021-30860
[Applause]
it is used for remote code execution
it is a very common integer overflow
vulnerability in the core Graphics
framework
triggered by passing jbq2 stream in PDF
from a message attachment
but if exploitation is really advanced
in order to bypass AFL and Pac it builds
a touring complete machine inside a PDF
document file
and the second zero day is CV 2021 31010
which is used to attack the nonsense box
xpc service
to escape the sandbox
finally
the attacker can also take frog control
of the Target's iPhone without any user
interaction
next
here are two one click attack cases
the first one is a watering hole
Campaign which is discovered by Google
tag
it used and and day and a real day in if
exploitation
City 2021 1789 is the end date for
remote code Fusion
this is the jit compiler optimization
issue in webkit
triggered by opening a web page with a
malicious JavaScript payload
and then CBE 2021
30689 is the zero day for local
privilege escalation
it is the port type confusion
vulnerability in the xmu kernel
triggered by the Xenu system called net
message
the second one clear case is about
gatekeeper bypass
the blog post titled audio maps are
belong to us gives the details of CDE
2021.00657 which is actively exploited
by malware flare in the white
in the bypassed Mac OS file content
GateKeeper and the notarization
requirements
once the user opens a fake document it
is pumped
after studying the old classic cases now
I want to dig a one-click exploration by
myself
here is my summary of the flowchart of
the challenges that need to overcome
first whether it is a zero click attack
or one click attack
the goal is to gain the ability to run
arbitrary code remotely on the target
machine
of course the execution permission at
this stage is often very low
and the way we are likely be restricted
in an application sandbox
so next we usually need to find a
vulnerability to escape the sandbox
and again privilege escalation through
another vulnerability
to execute actually Kono code
execution is the highest privilege of
the operating system
so if we can break the kernel then we
are the king of the target machine
in addition to this there are two
Network specific vulnerabilities there
are sip bypass and TCC bypass
I will discuss them in detail later
foreign
so these are the vulnerabilities I
discovered for the explosion
first I exploited lcv 2022
22616 to bypass the protection of macro
Escape keeper to get the ability to
execute code remotely
then I will get get root privilege
escalation by exploding CBE 2022
next I will bypass the system Integrity
protection to modify some critic system
files by exploding cve 2022
[Music]
2671-26712 finally I can get actually
Chrono code execution with the Sip
bypass primitive I got
however the last one is related to
another Untouchable day so I couldn't
share the details here at this time
so the first step is to get a remote
share
here I will exploit a gatekeeper bypass
issue to achieve it
okay let's take a look at the details
about Mac OS GateKeeper
it is designed to ensure that only
trusted software runs on your Mac
for apps from the App Store Apple
reviews each app before it is accepted
and signs it to ensure that it hasn't
been temporary or altered
four apps outside the App Store there
are three three security features for
the protection
file content gatekeeper and notarization
file contains is the security feature
introduced in OS X Network
when a user first opens the downloaded
file such as an application file content
will pop up a warning dialogue to the
user
that requires explicit confirmation
before allowing the file to execute
the idea is to ensure that the user
understands that they are indeed opening
an application
even if it looks like a picture or a
document
it should be noted that even if the
application is signed and notarized the
file content prompt will still appear
unfortunately naive users keep infecting
themselves
they often ignore the fire content
alerts
then Apple introduced another security
feature gatekeeper in OS X Lion
it is built based on file content
it checks the code signing information
of downloaded items and blocks those
without a developer ID
if the prompt
if if the downloaded application is not
designed sign it will prompt a lot
Direction like this
however mobile could still be resigned
with the value that developer ID
to compare this
Apple requires the legal software
to be notarized since Nicholas Catalina
macquest developers have to submit their
application to Apple for notarization
then Apple will scan the application to
make sure it is not a malware
once approved the application will be
awarded with the ticket
the tickets towards Miracles caregiver
that the app is not right by Apple
and could be trusted
finally users can be confident about the
software they run doesn't contain no
mobile
if the software is not notarized then it
will be blocked and the system will
prompt the alert dialog like this
you might be wondering how does Mac OS
know to analyze the file in order to
possibly display a file content get
people or notarized prompt
the answer is the special file extended
attribute
com.apple dot quarantine
all the files downloaded from the
internet
will be attached with the special
quarantine attribute
also if the downloaded file is active
then all the files inside should also be
contained
note that only the applications with the
quarantine attribute will be scanned by
GateKeeper
if a file doesn't have the continue to
build Mac OS will assume it as a local
file then none of the checks will be
performed and thus no problems will be
displayed
we can use the system command a HTTR
to access the extended attribute of a
file here we can see that
in addition to the quarantine attribute
there is another attribute that because
the UI information you downloaded
Network system browser Safari has the
default feature to open State files
automatically after downloading
the save files include pictures
documents archives and so on
in my opinion this is a dangerous
feature for two reasons
first
open files automatically makes remote
attack easier because save files are not
really safe
a large number of file format passing
vulnerabilities have been disclosed in
history
and second it is especially dangerous
for acute application bundles
because system launch service will
automatically register the URL scheme in
the info playlist file
hello attacker could then access the URL
scheme to prompt the user to open the
downloaded application remotely
therefore it is recommended to disable
the feature in Safari preference when
you go to a new map device
CBE
2021-22616 is the gatekeeper bypass
vulnerability I discovered
the POC here is simple
I just created an application that pops
up a calculator by using a batch script
and then compressed it into a gzip file
after the GC file is downloaded by
Safari it will be authened
it will be automatically decompressed
due to the dangerous feature we talked
before
and then the Arcade files will be
changed after the compression
we can check the
attribute to quarantine attributes using
the system command
here we can see that the gcp file itself
is contained and the extended attribute
indicates that it is downloaded by
Safari
however the inner zip file is not
quarantined
and that's my POC application is not
continue to
therefore my POC application can bypass
all the checks from file contain get
keeper and notarization
it could be launched without any prompts
the root cause exists in the xpc service
sandbox broker
it is responsible for decompressing our
kids automatically
as you can see from the unactive method
here
it writes the decompressed data directly
however it forgets to apply the content
attribute
now the patch for the issue is also
simple
it just duplicates the current thing
attribute
okay now we can run arbitrary command
remotely on the target machine
luckily we don't have sandbox
restrictions but we need more
permissions
so next we will escalate our privileges
there are some no ways to escalate
privileges
the first is to attack the system Corner
directly
we can hunt for some memory corruption
issues from the Xenu kernel and the
connect extensions surviving
but since some new medications were
introduced is getting harder to exploit
the second is to abuse the features on
some root processes such as spelling
child process
reading or writing some special files
and so on
the third is to attack some root demand
service via IPC
and there are many other ways for
example Dynamic Library hijacking
abusing the suyd binaries and so on
here I will try to attack a root demand
service because it is a common way and
easy to exploit
I found an attractive package demand
service named Su her body
it is a helpful process for software
update
it has many attractive advantages
first
it is not sandboxed
this means we don't have to take the
sandbox restrictions into consideration
after we compromise this demand service
second
it is rounding at the root
it means that we can get the root
privilege as expected once it is
compromised
third it has the special entitlement
com.apple.rooter installed in store
which grants the process special
permission to bypass SRP restriction
additionally
it explodes some IPC service routines to
unprivileged clients
last but not the least some other
vulnerabilities have been reported in
this demon service before
the main logic of the DMM process is
implemented in the class as you helper
either register an IPC server named
com.apple.subd while the API bootstrap
checking
the IPC client has already been
implemented in the private software
update framework
the class as you have a proxy
encapsulates all the client-side
interface to communicate with the IPC
server
if you use API bootstrap lookup 2 to
open the IPC Connection by the service
name
there are 45
service routines implemented on the
server side
and it has the corresponding delegate
method from the client side
we can review them one by one
24 for possible
memorabilities
however not all of them are available to
unprivileged clients because the server
has a right authorization mechanism to
verify whether the service request is
from an from the legitimate client
next let's see how the authorization
mechanism works
before the client requests the IPC
service routine it needs to generate an
authorization object through API
authorization create
and then make it as an external form to
transform the operation object to the
server for verification
next when the server receives the
authorization object it determines
whether the specific rise can be granted
to the client by checking the
authorization object and the uid of the
client
the following is an example of a service
routine handling flow first when the
client requests a service routine it
costs a specific method of the Su helper
proxy class
and then serialize the request into a
mac message buffer which is then sent to
the server side by the system kernel
when the server receives an IPC request
it will check whether the specific
rights will previously granted to the
client yeah
it will call the real service routine
through the class as you helper
otherwise it will reject the IPC request
the issue exists in the special IPC
interface named the prepare install
assistance with pass
it costs the rear service routine
directly without validating the client's
rights
after diving into the internal
implementation of the service routine I
found that it will try to load a bundle
named OS installer setup framework
however the boundary path could be
controlled from the IPC client
so my first attempt was to load a
malicious founder into the demand
process
in order to in order to to share its
good privilege and the special ruthless
entitlement
but I found that having the wrong time
is enabled by default for system
processes
and only episode Dynamic libraries are
alluded to load
however if we can find an older version
vulnerable and apple science Dynamic
Library we can get it loaded for
exploitation
my second attempt was to let it load the
original framework as expected
then I found the method
startup server will be called
immediately once it is loaded
in this method
since suvd is running as root we will
enter the Earth branch
then it will submit a job in the domain
of system launch d
so the job to be launched we are wrong
we are also wrong as a root user
through debugging I found the job path
is an accurable named OS installer setup
d
it is inside the directory controlled
from the IBC client
so we can directly write arbitrary
payload in the job path to enjoy the
root privilege
I put the PLC and demo
for your reference
now Apple addressed the issue by
validating the client's right before
calling the
special service routine
next step is to bypass the system
Integrity protection
system Integrity protection is a
security feature introduced in OS X EI
capture
it is also known as ruthless
this means that even if you have root
privilege
it is not enough to make some
modifications
it protects the entire system from
temporary from multiple perspectives
first if it denies your debugger from
attaching to Epsilon process
second it prevents you from modifying
creative system files
next it prevents you from loading online
extension
and it will also restrict some retrace
actions
it is enabled by default
and it can only be disabled in recovery
mode
which means a reboot is required
file system protection can be sort of as
a special sandbox applied to the entire
system
the configuration can be found from the
file named brutally storage config
take the location slash Library slash
apple as an example
from the output of the system command
EOS we can see that it is restricted
and it has a special extended attribute
chrome.apple.rooter list
and if we try to touch a file inside
this location it will return the error
operation not permitted even if I
execute the command with root privilege
you might be wondering how does the
operating system update the system files
the answer is within the special
entitlements
entitlements are embedded in the code
scan nature of the actual rule when
cosine
it is used to Grant special permission
to the actionable
we can use the system command code PSI
to check the entitlements like this
some special entitlements can only be
used by Apple
here the entitlement
com.apple.realist.install is only signed
with a few system commands
this entitlement grants the permissions
to modify system files for special
purpose such as updating the operating
system
the next entitlement is more powerful it
not only has the permission except
before
but can also be inherited by all of its
child processes
so I wrote a script to scan all the
applicables with the special
entitlements from the entire operating
system
and from the following list as my
candidates for sip bypass
finally I choose the xpc service system
sharp Service as my target
in normal scenario and xpc service
should check the signature and the
entitlements of the incoming client
in the delegate method named should
accept new connection
if the incoming client doesn't miss
certain requirements then the FC service
should reject the client's Connection by
returning node
however in the system shop service I
found that it has no validation of
incoming clients in its delegate method
and is always written yes
this means that any process can make xpc
requests to the service
it accepts connection from clients by
using SV sharp service protocol
the protocol has only one method named
shavu is option
so we can make a malicious xpc request
to the service and ask it to help shaft
from Shopify from one place to another
place
in fact there was already an xpc client
in the system
the sharp command within the packaged
package kit framework has an uppercase X
option to connect to the privileged
system shop xpc service
so the POC is very simple
and requires only one line
invoke the sharp command with the
uppercase X option
to read and write the Sip protected
files directly
Apple addressed the issue in two steps
first
remove the shaft service framework
and of course along with the vulnerable
xpc service
for the system command shaft
remove the options for xpc
the patch seems perfect
but is it enough
the old mannerable xpc service is still
signed with the special utilities
entitlement
so can I launch the old vulnerable xpc
service from the new OS
if yes it will be a bypass again
to Peru my concept I developed a new
application from the xcode template with
an activity service inside the
application bundle then open the build
application from the directory replace
the build xpc service Bounder with the
other vulnerable one finally the
application can launch the order
xpc service and send malicious xpc
requests to the twitch to bypass FIP
after I submitted this report to Apple
Apple adjusted it again and assigned cve
2022 32826
now there is no xpc client from the
system
so I have to implement the xpc client by
myself here is the code
first create an xpc connection using the
xpc service name
then set the remote protocol
and finally called the special xpc
service routine with the connection
proxy remotely
now the patch is adding an additional
validation for the auto sign excavator
in the amfi cone extension
it prevents though it prevents the old
vulnerable activity service from
launching
finally I can get actually kernel code
execution via the Sip bypass primitive I
got
unfortunately I couldn't show it here
right now
due to another unpatched field day
however
we can directly bypass the TCC
protection via the Sip bypass primitive
to access the user privacy
TCC is short for transparent consent and
control
it is a security feature introduced in
Mac OS Mojave
it is designed to protect your privacy
from the following items such as
microphone camera address book
private private photos and so on
you can set the Privacy permissions for
each application from system preferences
this is an example of the TCC prompt one
song application wants to access your
address book
in fact
all users configuration data is stored
in sqlite database named pcc.db
there are two locations
one is for the global
which is restricted and the Sip
protected
we need the router is related
entitlements to modify it
and the other one is for each user
it is protected by TCC itself
we need the four disk of success
permission to modify it
from the access table of the database we
can see the service column is the
specific TCC permission items
the client column is the boundary ID or
absolute path to the request Target
the Australian column is the decision
zero means denied one is all known
two means a lot
there are two tcct demand service
running on the system
one is for the global running at the
root
the other one is for each user
running as a normal user
the team name process is responsible for
validating the entitlements hold by the
main actionable
and handling all kinds of xpc requests
if we are query the database to decide
whether the requested TCC permission can
be granted to a specific process
and it will also update the database
when user changes the TCC configurations
from system preferences
has the ability to modify the protected
database because
the special utilized entitlement
there are some special entitlements for
tcc2
the entitlement TCC or law grants the
permission to access the TCC items
directly without prompting the user
the value for the entitlementer key is
an array which lists all the TCC
permissions it has
when it needs to access the
corresponding TCC item CCT demon process
will approve the access requests
directly without querying the database
the second entitlement TCC manager
allows the client to request the tcct
team service to update the TCC database
foreign
there are many ways to bypass the TCC
protection
we can directly exploit the design flaws
of the tcct demand
and the most frequently frequently used
method is abusing the special TCC
entitlements mentioned earlier
moreover there is an awesome blackhead
topic related to TCC bypass
the link is here
you can learn more about KCC bypass from
their presentation slides
here I just modify the protected
database directly to bypass DCC with the
Sip bypass primitive I got
now let's watch the demo
huh
first let's take a look at the file
directory structure on the hack server
then using python to start a HTTP server
I have created a claim virtual machine
using the app
we can check the target system variable
and the Sip status is enabled
now the temp directory is empty
checking the TCP configuration in the
Target system
no application has been granted any TCP
permissions
now the victim is trying to access the
phishing URL Safari is downloading the
Json file from the efficient URL and
automatically decompress it after
downloaded
currently no NC command is running
now the victim is trying to open the
downloaded a fake image
it will open a real image and create a
reverse share
now the attacker connects to the reverse
shell to app to execute arbitrary
commands as a normal user
the next stage of the pillows are under
configuration have been deployed to the
temp directory
before executing the Erp exploit for
root privilege acceleration
we can check the target system
now no down statement registered and no
root shell
now running the Erp exploit
and express successfully
the Erp exploit register a long
statement named the Comm dot
demo.reverse shell
and the drops and Equitable named root
share
the reverse root shell will connect to
the health server on Port 1337
creating a hack server listening on Port
then the reverse root share connection
is successful
the hack can run arbitrary commands as
root
trying to touch a file in a root-owned
directory
and the file touches successfully
all right
trying to access the private desktop
directory which is protected by TCC
but no permission
now trying to take a screenshot on the
Technical Machine
and the capture screen is then empty
checking the TCG configuration in the
Target system
is not granted any TCC permissions
now replacing the protected TCC DB via
the Sip bypass primitive
aggravating and restarting the reverse
root shell for the TCC configuration to
take effect
now we can see the root shell has got
the TCC permissions
restarting the hack server on Port 1337
trying to access the private desktop
again
and now we can go get the secret files
inside
and try to take a screenshot again
screenshot successfully
and you have been helped
[Music]
okay yes
let's back to my slides
before wrapping up I would like to share
another vulnerability to bypass TCC
which I discovered during my research
now let's recall the demand loader
through the process as you have a d we
talked about earlier
it has the special ruthless entitlement
and this means it has more privilege
than for disk access permission
there are 45 survey routines
and all the motto of most of them
requires root authorization there are
still great targets for PCC bypass
the issue exists in the service routine
named registered personalized manifest
for product key in foreground
it is only available to root IPC clients
note that the parameters
manifest manifest directory and the
product key can be controlled by an
attacker
and then the service routine will copy
the files from the Manifest directory to
this location
foreign
parts are controllable
so I have two expired ideas
the first is to make a more formed
product key for path traversal
in order to overwrite arbitrary sip
protected files
but it failed
because there is a sanitization for the
product key
here in the math in the function it
checks for special characters to prevent
path traversal attacks
my second attempt was to have the
Manifest directory point to a TCC
protected location
the demon service can read the TCC
protected contents due to its
entitlement
then the service will help me copy the
TCC protected contents to the
destination path
and the destination path is readable by
everyone
the POC is simple with a few lines of
code
after generating the root authorization
we can access the IPC service routine to
register personalized manifests for
product key
then have the Manifest directory point
to a privacy location
finally the Privacy data will be copied
to another location that we can access
we can also watch the demo video
the Sip status is also enabled
trying to access the address book
directly from the terminal
and don't Grant the terminal TCC
permissions to access the address book
learning the exploit program to still
date from the address book
then we can read the address book data
from the directory
okay
let's come back to my slides
now the patch is adding entitlement
checks for the incoming IBC clients the
required the requesting clients must
have the entitlement
com.apple.private.flt
okay let's make a summary
from the previous cases we will now
realize that Apple systems
including Macos and iOS
are not as skilled as we thought
so remember to keep your device up to
date
and and don't click don't click on the
URLs from Uncharted strangers
and don't use priority the software
watch out for the children's inside
next for security researchers
I think logic bugs are very powerful
they are easy to exploit and can work
across platforms both are inter and arm
platforms
you can get more by chaining back
together
the source code of my story chain was
submitted to the Galaxy GitHub
here for your rep for research purpose
only
here are the links for your reference
and thanks that's all
thank you um if anybody wants the links
the slides should be uploaded in the
next few hours or by the day so you
don't have to take a picture I'll be
online
um we've got a couple of questions Tim
Apple
is there an easy way to run arbitrary
programs in the Mac OS sandbox
it would be nice if Apple made
sandboxing easier for regular users
running untrusted apps that don't opt
into a sandbox
uh running archery programs in sandbox
within the sandbox restriction
and there is the case to attack the
system corner from sandbox directly
so
some some next service can be accessible
even Inside the Box the sandbox
configuration is in a
config file
so it is it is possible
by editing the config file yeah okay
steam here
no nothing Apple okay
um and Anonymous uh great talk your
presentation was very clear and easy to
follow I'm curious how long did it take
from start to finish to discover the
entire exploit chain also were there any
parts that you initially found promising
that turned out to be dead ends thank
you
hola
um I can't remember
months days hours
month month
any any parts you found uh promising
that turned out to be a rabbit hole a
dead end
um
no no okay
everything turned out to be an exploit
any other questions guys
no thanks again Mickey