hello everyone
um
what would you think if I told you that
it is possible to stealthily create
invisible accounts and win the systems
hi I'm Sebastian Castro and today we're
gonna be discussing uh this question
with this research called suborner a
Windows bribery for invisible
persistence
I'm super excited to be here this is a
research I released two weeks ago in Las
Vegas at black hat and today I am
expecting to share more details about
this new attack
so I hope you enjoyed this talk as much
as I do
so this is a little about me
um infosec nerd I've been working in the
information security field for about 10
years
um terrible of Microsoft Paint you will
notice that later but I use it to
explain myself better
um I'm doing my PhD in Computer Sciences
and also I'm working currently with the
product Security Office R D team at AMD
and I have presented before different
conferences like black hat besides Derby
Cannon other talks other conferences
this is a really little disclaimer and
this is a research that uh belongs to me
it not it has nothing to do with any of
my responsibilities with my current
employers and everybody everybody does
not necessarily represent my employer's
ideas
acknowledgment uh thank you for everyone
that supported me family and friends uh
researchers that have contributed to
this area that for sure has helped me to
be here
um especially in the people that have a
lot of mimikatz by the impact team the
Microsoft team have been discussing uh
this attack with Microsoft incident
response team
then the stack Overflow of course and
the infosec community
all right so uh this is going to be the
agenda of the talk
first of all I would like to I would
like you to understand exactly why I
believe this research is important and
why I decided to start
This research of trying to support
Windows
after that I would like to explain you
what is this a new attack what it's all
about and share some details about the
attack itself
um in the middle of the presentation
I'll probably deep dive the details of
how I ended up finding a way to create
some uh let's say a
yeah this is kind of stealthy accounts
um I'm planning to do later uh live
demonstration against the latest Windows
11 system I have just updated it like 30
minutes ago so I'm planning to do a live
demonstration I like I like the more
like you know the video so
hopefully it's going to be uh been good
and after that we're going to discuss
about what's next for this attack
all right so let's start it so let's
talk about first why
I decided to start to start this journey
so back in the day like 2007 when I
wanted to about to become like a lead
hacker when I was starting pretty much
one of the very first Google queries I
did was how to create an invisible user
on Windows
um
and despite of trying so hard to find a
way to you know to create an invisible
account I couldn't find
something that actually helped me out to
create an invisible account
15 year later years later if you do the
same query in Google you'll get around
for 439 Million results
so ideally you respect okay probably
someone has found a way to create
invisible accounts
so yeah let me show you some of the main
the principle the posts that do the
answers of these questions that you will
find in Google
so this is a post from uh the windows
Club where someone is claiming that you
can create a hidden administrator
account by creating these bad files so
everyone that knows a little about like
Windows knows that actually this does
not create an invisible account right so
probably this is not the best way to do
it
what about this
um apparently someone else is trying to
figure out a way to create invisible
account as well and in this case this
user wants to create an administrator
account hidden
right
and then we see that
um a 10 years awarded Windows MVP says
that he only knows two ways to create
invisible accounts and the wind systems
and apparently they only are hidden from
the sign in the screen which is not
ideal right
in a more Cooperative perspective if we
think about the my tree attack framework
that covers 19 persistence techniques
that I have classified as the identity
manipulation at and external implants
and none of them actually refer to ways
to create invisible accounts so let me
show you I have classified this 19
persistence techniques as identity
manipulation which has to do pretty much
of modifying the identities that are
being used in an operating system on any
piece of software
um you know in this case they're
referring to account manipulation create
accounts and these embellied accounts
which involve attacks that are from are
familiar to all of us like golden ticket
silver ticket simply creating a new
account and things like that
and there are a whole bunch of different
persistence techniques that are
referring to external implants that
actually require to install an
additional software to the
to the victim so it can be you know
batching uh any something in the race we
created a new service uh even
compromising the you know firmware
things like that so it's additional for
software right so from all of these
persistence techniques if we take a look
at a unique procedures that are being
described they might throw attack
framework 63 of the 85 unique
procedures which is pretty much the apts
that are being uh
described
as a way to explain this persistence
techniques in Mitra 63 of the 85 you
somehow a an identity manipulation so
definitely
uh the identity manipulation persistence
techniques are the way to go they're
being used by uh
by many uh adversaries right now
and that is why there have there has
been so much so much research about uh
the identity manipulation so we know a
lot of tools like mimikats rubias in
packets a lot of tools that uh there are
modules that Metasploit Implement to try
to modify the accounts and the
identities that are being used in the
operating system and I mean
it's it's expected this is expected
because that's the process that the
actual operating system uses to
um give permissions and privilege to
their users right but what's the problem
here
as far as I know none of these tools
actually craft an invisible local user
Windows systems right they can for sure
extract some sensitive data from the
accounts like the ntlm hash some uh
cached hashes but none of them can
actually craft or create a hidden local
account right
foreign
ER attack
suborner persistent attack uh
it's a new persistence technique that
will allow us to stealthily Forge custom
invisible accounts
that will have the capability of
impersonate any identity that is already
in the victim
and it's gonna work on every Windows NT
system so this works from Windows XP to
Windows 11 and this works from Windows
Server 2003 to Windows Server
2022. I haven't tested this in Windows
95 for obvious reasons but uh I ideally
this would work on all of them I've
tested this and all the other
anti-operating systems
so the idea with this attack is that
only who created the suborner account
will easily know the username and the
password
this is the authentication process and
after the authorization the subordinary
attack will impersonate any account that
it's already there so we are getting
stealthy right in the process of the
authentication I'm getting so and we are
getting some stealthiness after the
authentic authentication and
authorization
so this is how it looked like I'm gonna
be brief here because I am gonna be
doing sharing some details about this
later so this is what we are doing we
are pretty much creating something that
looks like the machine account
we are specifying the password
specifying the RIT of the account
um here we are we can see that we have
just created this account
and after that if we try to authenticate
to the victim with this new pair of
credentials we'll see that in this case
we are using PSX at the in packets
version of PSX
we'll see that we will get a
custom uh
common prompt remote a remote system
command prompt
and we will see that this new account is
not going to be visible in the net
user's interface we're going to be uh
deep typing this a little later but this
is the whole idea so before talking
about how uh what's this process done
let me share you
um sorry to share with you how it's
usually the creation of accounts and
manipulation accounts here so for to do
this I would like you to think about
this super basic scenario where we have
an attacker that has already compromised
a victim
but there is an administrator that is
constantly looking inside the Spectrum
for any indicator of compromise
start simple let's take a look at the
very first initially scenario which is
pretty much adding a new user uh I think
we've done everyone here probably have
has done this creating a basic user via
the comma prompt
so if you as a user be at the net user
application
you can do it super easily that's the
API that is exposed by the operating
system for you to create the account the
so when you do this you you create this
new identity that you can use to access
the machine later
but unfortunately this is going to be
reported as a Windows Event in this case
it's going to be the 4720 event and of
course this is easy to spot via
administrator or an EDR or any solution
that it's installed there
if the administrator takes a look takes
a look at the net users interface you
will see that this new account has been
created
and of course it's going to be super
easy to remove the access to the
adversary right
so this doesn't work
so let's see what happens if we append
the dollar sign so this has been a
technique that has been recently uh
popularized but some researchers like
Ben 10 from trust attack and the thing
is that when you create a username an
identity that has a dollar sign appended
and is in its username this account is
going to be interpreted by the operating
system as a managed service account
so if we try to do the same thing net
user but only adding a dollar sign at
the very end
we'll get the same event uh registered
in the event log then it's going to be a
4720 but if the administrator wants to
take a look at the net users output
it was there's not going to be like the
account we have just created but
the event it's gonna be registered in
the event log right so in this case it
was a slightly more
stealthy but it was easy to spot due to
the analysis of the Windows Event log
so again it's not possible in this way
to create an investable account right so
this also failed
so let's get a little more advanced and
let's try to create a machine account by
directly calling the net API 32 function
as a net user ad so what we need to do
this it's pretty much
uh create this structure that will
contain all the data of the account we
want to create so as you can see here we
need to specify for the user info one
for instance this is one of the
structures that you use to call the the
net is red function from the net net API
32 API
um
you need to specify the username you
also specify the Privileges which is in
this case is zero one or two this will
Define if the user's administrator a
username or a standard user or a guest
and you specify the flags that will
Define the type of account so in this
case
1000 stands for uh workstation trust
account which is the flags that
represent the machine account
so if we do this and we craft somehow an
executable that will try to create this
account
and we execute it this is going to be
registering a different event in this
case it's going to be 47 41 Which is
less uh commonly uh monitored as 4720
but still it's going to be registered in
the account if we if the administrator
takes a look at the net user's output
the account is not going to be there
but it's also possible to see that
someone created an account with this
different identifier right
and of course it's possible to remove
the access to the adversary so none of
these three scenarios worked what is
wrong the this battery account is
detected right after its creation
Through the Windows events or if there's
something like an EDR that is something
uh like a API called sequence analysis
it's easy to spot that someone has
invoked the the API that in intended to
create new accounts and it's also easy
to spot after risk creation but some
user management application applications
like the net users
and what's the thing if you want to
persist a high privileged access you
will need to
add this account to an admin group
which is also a easy to spot
and the other problem is that the API
that is used to create new identities
in bits to modify all the attributes
that are actually involved in the
account creation process
so what can we do
it would be ideal to find a way to you
know just uh bright micro bright windows
and say
um
why won't we create when we create an
account without you know reporting that
to everywhere in the you know the event
lock and things like that
and uh to do this we need exactly who to
buy from the old the authentication and
authorization process
so if we take a look up a hike level
overview of how the authentication and
authorization process works with Windows
this is a high level
um these are like the credentials
management applications that are being
used to create accounts in this case we
are using the net user ad API
um so if we try to create an account
we're going to be communicating
communicating to this API
then the information is going to be sent
to the lsass process that will try to
query the LSA policy to define the way
we are going to be creating this account
and after that it everything
went well
all the account information is going to
be written into the sum so this is the
important part here every all of the the
details of the local account uh are
going to be registered in the Sam and
right after this they'll say it's it's
going to be calling the event logger
that is going to be reporting the
account creation
and if everything uh went well the
account is going to be done so this is a
high level overview of the process
so the idea of the supporter attack it's
really simple not that we notice why
don't we try to write this time directly
with the data that we already know
that it's needed or the operating system
to create a new account
and let's say try to pay your bribe to
the event logger to not saying anything
this is the whole idea of the attack
it's it's super simple
um so we provide to write everything of
the all the account information to the
Sam without calling the event logger and
uh try to make this account as stealthy
as possible so we'll I'll try to explain
all the details uh
later so
the support on dynamically crafts this
subordinary account without using the
net win32 API in this case for exploring
says that they'd use a rat
we are adding some extra style to the
subordinary account by appending this
dollar sign because remember every
account that has this username uh with a
dollar sign up and it's going to be
interpreted as a managed service account
and we are going to be leveraging
something that is called the account
control bits that will Define the type
of account we are creating
all right so that's another view of the
whole attack
so let me talk about the process you
know I already had this idea so
I would like to develop it and this is
like the the one when the struggle
begins so what I try to do first is try
to understand the authentication and
authorization process or local accounts
all right
so this is the high level overview that
I have just uh showed you
but actually this is a little more
complex if we take a look at some of the
modules that are actually involved in
the process of an account creation I
mean there's a lot you can see that the
credential management applications
involve many dlls and many executables
that uh we are not going to be
discussing right now we can see that
also we are seeing some authentication
providers that are related to the active
directory authentication in this case we
can see that uh there are some
authentication providers like the
kerberus dll the kdcsurface.dll
and uh we also see that there's a
communication to the
um domain controller via the the ntdsa
dll but we don't care about that right
now because we are focusing
on the creation of a new local account
so we can ignore them for now
so we would like to focus on on the
authentication provider msb1 odll which
is in charge of the authentication
creation and communication with the Sam
service to create local accounts
we're going to be talking about the risk
security reference Monitor and all the
credential management applications that
are being involved with this process so
let's make it simple let's try to
go step by step with the authentication
process for a local account so
whenever we try to authenticate against
a Windows system we can do it with
different types of let's say inputs we
can specify a username and a password we
can do it with a with a pin we can do it
with a smart card and each of these
processes uses something called a
credential provider so in this case if
we are using a username and a password
we're going to be using a specific
specific credential provider in this
case let's say that we are using the
credential provider that it's intended
to authenticate via username and
password the basic one this is going to
be processed by the win logon
module
that after
processing the username and password
entered
the credential provider is going to
translate the password to the ntlm
version of it and after that the win
Logan process is going to add the login
Sid which will describe this particular
login attempt
for this username and this path for for
yeah for this particular specific event
after that the local process is going to
be sending this information to the LSA
service
which will also try to communicate and
send this data to the authentication
provider called
msv100.tll in this case win logon is
going to be calling uh the LSA logon
user function that will set this
information username ntlm hash and the
login Sid that will describe the login
attempt
then this information is going to be
sent to the Sam service which will try
to retrieve all the information of the
account so pretty much what some service
does here is try to verify that there's
a username that exists exists with this
inside the sap database and it will
verify the password the ntlm hash
actually matches
if everything went well
uh the same server is going to say uh
yeah everything apparently it's it's
it's good and the msb1 oh it's a
validate the information that has been
sent against the information that has
been stored in the Sam registry High
since we had a successful Authentication
the LSS process is going to report these
two events to the event logger saying
okay someone authenticated successfully
and it's the register uh it's going to
be registered uh the event of the
authentication is going to be registered
in the security lock
after this this the authorization
process start
so now that we had a successful
Authentication
we had a username password with a
specific login Sid that will describe
the slogan attempt
and since it was successful the lsas
process will append this luid identifier
for this session saying okay I am
creating this uh I'm starting this
authorization process for this
particular log on Sid attempt and this
luid will describe this process
so what is going to happen is that uh
the security reference monitor that is
being a
nursing communication between the LSA SS
process and the security reference
monitor that starts at the very
beginning uh it's an alpc connection
they are going to be communicating
together to forge what will describe the
principle uh the primary access token
the primary access token it's gonna be
the way that the operating system has to
describe the permissions of the account
right so in this case after a successful
authentication and the start of an
authorization there's going to be a
creation of the very initial access
token
and then after that
the LSA as a service it's gonna try to
add some of the additional permissions
that this initial access token doesn't
have
based on the the policies that are that
are described in the LSA policy all of
the permissions of this uh this username
are going to be appended to this access
token
so pretty much this is the process
um it's a high level overview so what we
need here is a username
we need a password or an nclm hash and
we somehow need to know exactly how to
craft the access token this is the basic
idea that we need to know to
successfully create a standard account
right
so now now that we know that
um what I did later was try to create a
local account writing directly to the
Sam so what we need is a username an
ntlm hash and somehow try to craft this
access token that will describe the
security context of the user after a
successful authentication and
authorization process
so we know also that this information is
somehow stored in the sum right but we
didn't know initially exactly where
so what I did here is okay this is how
the registry Hive looks like for uh an
account that it's in Windows 11. but
what I did is pretty simple I you know
travel back to time and I tried to
analyze how the sound looks like in a
Windows XP machine and they only have
these two particular entry switch which
are the F entry and the B entry right
so what I guess is that okay probably
the information I need it's only there
what's the problem here of course so
um if we take a look for instance at the
B binary
we don't have like an actual structure
of actually how the information is
stored in here right so one of the
processes that I did was try to
recollect as much information as I could
from you know internet resources and
reverse engineering and try to release
uh sorry to describe the uh the
structure of this
B file so what this is how the structure
looks like
um
as you can see here there are a lot of
information like username the full name
the comment and uh there's also uh an a
version of the LM hash and ntlm hash and
until and history starting here and one
of the problems here is that the V size
is dynamic dynamic
and this makes sense because of course
the username values and uh comment
values like this they don't have a
specific fixed size right
so the structure actually looks like
this if we take a look at the username
we'll see that the very first part
contains the headers of which value
if we take a look at the header the
structure is going to describe initially
an offset uh from the ox CC let's say uh
address inside the the binary it will
also contain the length in unicoid in
Unicode of the value that we are storing
and there's like an unknown value that
is also installing here because I mean
remember that Windows is closed source
of of course these structures are not uh
you know open source so you don't have
we don't have access to them so this is
pretty much how it looks like for now I
have I don't know what this unknown uh
field uh is intended for is intended to
but uh it's not necessary for all
purposes so this is how the headers look
like and then the values are
in the offset from oxac if we take a
look here uh
in the particular case of the username
we see that F4
which is uh 244 decimal it's going to be
pointing to the actual value of the
username field right so in this case
um this is the suborner and the dollar
sign Unicode only code version we'll see
that the length is 18 and we don't care
about the unknown value so we know that
this is the structure of the B value
entry right
this is pretty much how it looks like
but remember that we don't need to
actually try to understand all of these
values we only need to understand the
username
and somewhat
the ntlm hash so we know that the B
binaries cannot contain the username and
it's going to contain the ntlm hash
so I know how to craft a username but
the ntlm hash was a little more tricky
so what I did was try to understand how
the tools uh extract the ntlm hash from
the sum so I try to analyze okay what
does mimikat do when trying to extract
the secrets from the sum reviews uh
sorry packet and Metasploit and try to
analyze how this Sam hash is uh
used to store the ntlm hash so what's
the problem in the sum the
the ntlm hash is not stored as it is
there are some uh ways that the
operating system converts it from ntlm
to a Sam hash that it's Unique for each
system
so what I did is pretty much try to
extract the information try to analyze
how many cuts for instance extracts this
information and try to replicate the
process that the operating system does
to actually convert from an ntlm hash to
the Sam hash that will actually contain
the password
that it's going to be a unique some hash
for each system right
so this is how the process looks like uh
initially it will
uh verify if there's a Windows 10 uh
version uh 1607 or greater
then it's gonna try to calculate the
ntlm hash so in this case we're starting
from the password uh to the Sam hash so
we're going to calculate the ntlm hash
and it will split it into halts
and each two how each of the halves is
going to be calculated with a desk key
that uh that takes some information that
it's Unique for each operating system
um like the boot key and things like
that and uh all this information is
going to be encrypted and contacted as a
new Dash hash
and then it's going to be the
calculation of the sampkey that is going
to be uh pretty much used to calculate
the very last Sam hash so before Windows
10 uh 1607
you Windows used to use md5 to do this
hashing after that they are using AES so
that this is why we are doing the
validation if the system we are
attacking is Windows 10 1607 or greater
and after calculating the Sam hash we
know for sure that we have crafted
uh successfully this Windows system so
this uh the the conversion from the mtlm
hash to the Sam hash key
right
so after this we are going to try to
write these changes to the B structure
right
so
this is how it looks like a process we
have just done is try to write the
username
to the v file
we try to convert the ntlm hash to the
Sam hash key and try to store it in the
B binary
but what we do with the uh
way to describe the you know the the
security context how can we how can we
try to
um somehow
patch
the permissions that they want to
impersonate in the in the registry hive
so after trying to create an invisible
account what I did is try to make it
invisible
so now take a look let's take a look at
the if F binary
their finally it's easy because the size
is fixed so they this binary does not
contain any particular Dynamic uh let's
say uh all the the sizes of the values
here are fixed so it's easy to forge
but we are only interested in two
particular values here
the first one is going to be the rid
copy
that this is going to be used by the
security reference monitor to actually
craft the access token
and we're gonna be interested in the
account bits that will
pretty much describe the type of account
we are going to be creating so
what I did so to impersonate an account
is to leverage an attack that I released
four years ago also at black hat 2018
which is called rid hijacking
so what we do with this attack is we
abuse the way that the security
reference monitor crafts the primary
access token
and the problem with the the pro the way
that Windows creates this access token
is that they base this creation
and this particular rid copy that it's
stored in the F binary so
what I we are doing here it's specify
what is the account that we that we want
to impersonate I'm not gonna Deep dive
in the details of the already hijacking
if you if you want to take a look at
this there are some
blog post I have written about it but
this is what we are doing to pretty much
uh impersonate any account that it's uh
in already there in the system that we
are attacking okay
so to sum it up what we are doing is
okay we are somewhat forging the access
token to impersonate any account in the
system by leveraging the rad hijacking
attack
we are also creating a username with an
appended dollar sign and try to write it
to the B structure
and we are oh sorry I forgot and we are
also writing the data
um of the password to the hash
to the Sam hatch and writing that to the
V structure right
but wait yeah there's more so
after this
what we try to do was analyze exactly
how
the net user API actually describes
the type of an account and how the type
of account we are creating and how this
reflects in the Sun
so what I did is pretty much analyze
okay this has to do with the account
bits so this is pretty much the values
of the the current values that are being
used to describe some uh of the account
types that we can create and the
operating system
so
what we are doing here is
try to understand okay
if you remember the example that we took
a look at at the very beginning when we
try we try to craft our own account by
specifying the Privileges and the flags
what happens is that the net user
netizer ad function it's gonna write the
type of account in this particular part
of the F binary so if we change
um this value to let's say 80 this is
going to be interpreted as a machine
account right so to sum it up the simple
the simple way to see the subordinary
attack is this so we have a username
that is going to be appended with the
dollar sign so it's going to be
interpreted as a managed service account
we're gonna try to craft the ntlm hash
and to a Sam hash and write it directly
to the sum
we are going to somehow leverage their
ID hijacking to actually impersonate any
account that it's already there
and we're gonna leverage the account
control bits to describe this account as
a machine account
so that that's the to border attack
in this case uh
we successfully created a custom account
without using the win32 API limitations
and as you can see
we can we could modify some of the
attributes that are not modifiable
through the win32 API
right in this case for instance we're
modifying the rid that is being used for
the primary access token degeneration
so okay okay demo time
um this is what I have developed to
automatize the attack so what I did is
create a c-sharp solution that will
Forge this account it will try to craft
all of the sound register crease keys
that will describe and and
local identity without call without the
limits of the API
and it works on all windows and 36
entity systems
so these are the parameters of the
current tool oh right now we can create
uh specify a username we can specify the
password we want to set to this account
we can specify the rid of this account
we can also
specify the account that we want to
impersonate
we are going to copy some of the values
of an account on already sister and we
can set that in the template parameter
and we can also uh
decide if we want to create this as a
machine account or no
this is going to be the demo scenario uh
it's going to be super simple so it's
going to be an attacker machine and a
big the machine it's going to be a
Windows 11 system that I have just
updated like one hour ago
um I do like the excitement of live
demonstrations instead of videos so
this is gonna be the
attacking machine it's a black Arch
Linux super simple this is going to be
the
um IP address of the machine
so these machines are
they have visibility one to each other
and this is gonna be
the windows 11 system we're gonna be
attacking right
so let's take a look first at the users
that are here that users
we'll see that we only have
administrator account
we have the user account that this is
the one we are using using remember this
is a persistence attack so we have
already compromised the system we are
trying to factor somehow this system in
a stealthy way
now let's take a look also of the early
user manager
oh sir
so this is going to be another user
interface that will show show us what
identities are here we see that we don't
see any work identity here
um if we take a look at the
administrator this is going to be the
account that we are going to be
impersonating
we see here that this account is
disabled
but still despite of being disabled will
have the capability of impersonating
this account
right
let's also take a look at uh
something that is really important let
me show you that this is an updated
Windows system
I updated this like uh yeah one hour ago
let me show you the patches here
system info
mm-hmm
so these are the patches
you want to double check
oops
okay
all right
so let's also take a look at the
Windows 11 user management interface
so if we take a look at the users here
other users
will not see any particular account
um
so yeah we only have these accounts and
let's also take a look at the event
lawyer
this is the current status of the event
logger we don't see any particular uh
strange strange event so let me take
this real quick
there we go
we don't see anything weird here let me
some some a little bit
this is the current status we're going
to see in a particular event ID
I'm sorry about that line I told you I'm
terrible at Microsoft Paint and you know
drawing
um
so yeah this is it
so what we are gonna do
is try to create a subordinary account
right
so
I'm gonna be using crack my backsec to
uh validate that we have created this
account
so this is a target IP address
the account we are going to be creating
is suborner dollar sign and the password
is going to be password.1 and we are
going to be trying to query the LSA
Secrets right so
let's try to run this command just to
show you that I have not
somehow created this account
before the demonstration right so we'll
see here that for sure we don't have
access
we see the status log on failure
because of course this account does not
exist
right
so if we try to burn windows we can use
the solution I have double load and C
sharp
you can specify the username in this
case it's going to be subordinary
let me extend this a little bit
and password is gonna be password dot
one right
and we're all set we have just created
our own account we can see some of the
details here
we are creating this account uh to
bordner dollar sign we're specifying the
password
the rid is going to be automatically
assigned based on the accounts that
already sister
by default it's going to be uh trying to
impersonate the
500 rid account which is uh is the
built-in administrator
and it's going to try to copy all of the
other
attributes of the account and we're
going to specify that this account is
going to be a machine account
we are creating the account we're
forging each uh you have a key and the
Via key V key or encrypting password and
writing the changes to registry so yeah
let's take a look at the first at the
event logger
so let's try to
see if there's any change here
okay there's something what is this
so this is the crap of exit uh attempt
that we had early right that's the only
change we have
right
but aside from that we don't see any you
know 4720 or any particular event that
describe that an account has been
created
right
let's take a look at the
account itself uh
here
yeah net users
so we're gonna see that there are no any
supporter account we have the same
accounts that we
had before actually executing this
program
if we take a look also at the user
interface here let me open this again
for it to refresh
we're gonna see that
there is no subordinary account here
either
administrator account this is still
disabled we haven't changed that
right
let's take a look also at the windows 11
user management application which is the
users
other users
so let me try to come to accounts it's
going to be a user and oops sorry and
family and other users yeah we don't see
the account we have just created but
if we try to run this command again
same command user supporter password and
LSA
they're going to be successfully
connecting to the account and retrieving
the LSA information right
we can also try to connect with PSX
with the same account
subordinary password.1
let's define
that we successfully have a common
prompt a remote command prompt with
these particular credentials if we take
a look at net users we will not see the
account even after a successful
authentication if we try to take a look
at the actual let's say let's use
Virtual Warner
we'll see that there's no such user to
burner right
we take a look at the net local group
administrators
will not see the also border account but
despite of
not being there we have successfully got
uh High privileged
common prompt against the victim so this
is how it looks like
I'm glad the live demonstration worked
well
um so yeah let's jump back
you know yeah I like the excitement of
doing live demonstration instead of
videos so yeah
um
of course I had a video you know just a
backup but yeah I'm glad it worked so
yeah uh so what's next for this attack
of course I communicated this the msft
into the response team
um I talked to them before releasing
this to black hat but and they told me
that this is a persistence attack and it
makes sense we have already compromised
system this is not considered as an
actual vulnerability it's more like it's
a persistence inspector so I would think
that they are not planning to patch this
uh in the near future right
so it's all bad so uh one month ago
um I was thinking that probably this
type of accounts can be leveraged and as
a let's say uh offensive defensive way
to our trick adversaries uh let's say
you can you can be an assist admin that
can try to forge one of these hidden
accounts and uh
uh hide them from the from adversaries
and you can use them to pretty much uh
you know try to run services or anything
that it's useful for your uh the
functionality of uh of your system
this of course can be detected when it's
by inspection
um I know for sure that some uh friends
of mine are are working on finding new
ways to detect this uh you know the
pattern that the current solution uh to
burn our solution tries to leverage but
ideally what I'm trying to do is uh you
know improve the way that we are
fortunately the this account uh so the
automated detection is going to be
harder ideal in the future and even
though this is not a local account it's
definitely useful in uh and you know
active regulatory environments right of
course this doesn't work in a against
domain controllers because the
authentication there it's different we
don't actually use the msb10
authentication provider so there's node
actually you cannot patch that directly
a domain controller but you can patch
anything like a server worker station
that it's already there
so what's next ideally what I want to do
it's I don't want to rely on the win32
API
to create local accounts what I want to
do is pretty much have total control of
each of the attributes that a local
account has without relying on the you
know on the API and its limits
this is the initial Vector that I I
found but ideally what I want to do is
use this somewhat like let's say like a
harness for fussing and try to find if
there's any particular
um you know different type of account
that we can create based on the
attributes that now we can control
right and probably this can be useful to
find right now we are creating invisible
accounts that can be detected by some
patterns but probably can end up finding
any other type of account with different
properties that we are not aware of
right
and that's it yeah it's uh I hope you
enjoyed this talk as much as I do I hope
you uh are uh as excited as me to try
this new tool all for yourselves and
yeah let's uh try to support the planet
and uh do some references about the talk
and these are some details if you want
to take a look at the GitHub repository
of the tool if you trust me you can
understand that QR code there's going to
be the blog post there's going to be the
GitHub uh that's information and thank
you so much for coming it's my pleasure
and I hope you enjoyed it
foreign thank you I think we've got some
questions
um so it's the only way to detect this
is scaffold auditing of user accounts in
the same registry
as far as I know
yes I know that there are some people
working on some Powershell solutions to
actually
um
analyze the way we are writing directly
to the to the
to the Sun I know there are some
solutions that
uh
try to trace
let's say um
the registry values that are being used
to uh graft the Sam hash you know so
whenever you are let's say using
mimikats and you try to extract the
secrets from the sum you need to
particularly extract some values that
are stored in a certain places in the
registry so there are some tools that
they're actually leveraging that so for
now it's not only auditing the some
registry uh in the sense of the user
accounts data but also the let's say the
registry hives that are being queried
but some tools like mimikats when they
try to for instance uh extract the
secrets uh and try to you know decrypt
the Sam hash to the ntlm hash I know
that there are some some solutions that
extract this data from different values
that the uh some register types that
have directly to do with the user
account if that makes sense
there's a person who asked this question
here
okay I'll give you a gift shortly
um the next question so it avoids the
windows user account creation event 4720
but when using the Invincible account
remotely would there be a Windows user
logon event
so yes this is going to be interesting
because uh the event is gonna be
registered not as the account we have
created
so that's the account we are
impersonating right so pretty much what
I'm doing is trying to authenticate with
the supporter account and right now I'm
impersonating the administrator account
that it's disabled by default right
so that's easy to detect you know if
someone is trying to log on with an
account that it's disabled that's kind
of weird but this is for example right
but if instead you impersonate an
account that it's already there the the
logon is going to be registered with
that account right so of course I'm sure
there's going to be some uh tooling that
will try to detect some weird behavior
in the Windows Event log but for now we
are pretty much impersonating uh these
accounts right so yeah great question so
whoever who asked that yeah
uh who asked that question you as well
yeah
um can you log in my RDP and windows log
on screen too so yes but this depends on
the account you are crafting as far as I
have tried
um machine accounts oops sorry machine
accounts don't have the
interactive logon that is being used by
RDP and log on the screen
so what you may want to do is create
this account by setting the flag as a
machine account as false you will lose
some stealthiness but you'll have the
capabilities of login interactively via
rgp and a login screen right I'm sure
I'm I'm trying to find if there's any
particular account control bit that I
can modify that will allow me to
authenticate interactively and remotely
as we have shown here
do you know Windows network based logins
would there be logs or still no logs for
64 465.
um you mean for for interactive logon
um I think it's going to be the same
behavior I haven't tried the you know
interactive logons uh just just yet but
my guess is that it's gonna be uh the
same behavior but I mean yeah feel free
to try and please let me know I mean uh
this was that question
okay
um and the last question if the user
account is so hidden invisible how then
can such a persistent be removed or
remediated
oh then okay so
ideally what you want to do here is
constantly monitor the sum register you
have and look for
um
any particular change in the registry
Hive that contains the user accounts
information right so we are actually
crafting an account all by ourselves
so what you can do is after monitoring
if there's any change
any new account that has been created
without using the net user API
or any API that is intended to create a
new identities you should remove that
right
so this attack for now is creating new
accounts ideally what what I'm planning
to do okay it's it's easy to detect like
okay we have created an account we have
created a new identity but with this you
can also somehow modify the attributes
of the accounts that are already there
right
so that's the next step as well I forgot
to mention but this question remind me
reminded me to to I mean to talk about
that like right now we are creating
accounts but after that after this we
can try to use this tool to modify
accounts that that are already there
so we will get some more stealthiness
without you know writing a whole new
account data
that solves the question
all right thank you um any more
questions
sure
yes
yes yes that's a great question I I
think I mentioned that in a the very
beginning of the of the tooling I was
talking about they have described they
have described some instructions
um
some functions some functionality is to
actually
change
the ntlm hash that actually they uh that
tool is an open source tool that
contains some of the
structures I leveraged here to extract
and uh and write the data I know that
they can modify the password and I know
they can uh
for the latest versions of Windows they
can remove the password by removing the
ntlm hash I mean the same hash key that
is stored in the same but they they
don't have the capability of creating
new accounts they have the the
possibility of uh writing a new uh a new
password and removing the password that
I think that's the initial uh intention
that the principal or intention of the
program like changing passwords but yeah
I heavily
um I mean took I took some information
from for this tooling to from the change
change password the solution the Linux
solution yes
foreign
does it list your newly created account
after you've run sabona and if you run
oh and listen listen to this I haven't
tried that I haven't used the the that
tool to to detect this new account but
that that's something that I like to try
yeah I haven't tried that I thought okay
okay yeah probably probably we can use
that tool to detect this type of
accounts yes but I haven't tried it
thank you all right and we just have one
more question that came up can net API
32 be used to remove such accounts
um
I don't I haven't tried it I mean we can
try that right now we have to set up but
uh
I haven't used you know net user this
particular account on delete I don't
think it's gonna work
uh because the account is not being
listed you know if you remember we uh oh
you want me to try it okay yeah let's
try it um
foreign
yeah so
um
yeah
I don't know that's a good question yeah
that's a good thing for the live
demonstrations you can solve
so let user subordinary slash tail
there's no such user until yeah
apparently you cannot remove it good
question yeah but apparently you cannot
remove them with this approach let's
double check if you we still have access
yep no we're still there so could you
show us the event logs from the last
login
um the remote login that you did sure
yeah um
let me see
oh no where is this
oh this one okay
here
you go
any particular thing you wanna
I'm guessing that it's the the special
login that's being shown is that
um your account logging in and does that
show up as uh the administrator account
now
see
details
oops
it's fine
okay
yeah hold on I done
I mean yeah let me show you that later
because
I don't know what's going on hold on
I'm trying to yeah like
oops oh no I'm okay I'm running out of
time but uh yeah let me show you right
now it's it's fine but
foreign
sure sure yeah but yeah thank you so
much any other question you you guys
have
no
sorry with the okay
are you gonna show it or are you gonna
show it outside I'm gonna show them
myself because I'm I ran out of time but
oh yeah
um yeah so who's who's interested to see
that can can yeah sure sure
um we can do some experiments after
let's give Sebastian another round of
applause yeah thank you