greetings everyone
first of all let me start with a very
quick introduction of mine I'm really
into offensive security so if you would
like to follow some of my researches you
can find it here
and I'm also a co-organizer of a Meetup
in Hungary I'm the program Committee
Member at the activity conference and I
am a volunteer at iot Village
uh I have to say that I really love
Singapore this is my first time being
here and I am really happy that I have
been invited to this conference and this
is just a really amazing place I have to
tell you so I I really really love it
um now let's talk about uh what I will
do here and why I'm doing this uh so
actually this is a two-hour presentation
compressed into 25 minutes so fasten
your seal Bots I'm sorry for that
um why I'm doing this I always love
playing with new technologies and I
really find blockchain and very
fascinating uh I really do believe that
it has a future uh but we are not there
yet as you will see very soon
so this presentation is not about the
whole cryptocurrency word is a scam it's
not for smart contract developers it is
not a financial advice on which or when
you should invest into it's not about
crypto exchange hacks like you have seen
some examples from yesterday from David
6's presentation so you should check out
that one and the whole scam and whole
presentation it's not about topics where
cryptocurrency is used as a form of
payment again for example ransomware
all right so how did we get here uh a
lot of people got rich from
cryptocurrencies that's for sure and a
lot of people want to get rich from
cryptocurrencies and the total market
capitalization is around 1 trillion US
dollars right now when I first made the
slides it was two three iron dollars but
that's it
uh that's written in uh
with all the zeros so it's a lot of
money
I don't know how much that is but it's a
lot
uh and actually turns out that it is a
very new complex technology and it has
very crappy user interface
so what could possibly go wrong right
I have created uh this animation
whenever scammers are trying to figure
out what's next what should be our next
scans what should we do
should it be a Walmart scam no
shall we send some adult content spam to
the users no that's boring T-Mobile has
come no one cares about that UPS package
deliveries come
who cares
oh let's invite the user on Discord to
meet some nfts that's hot right you can
get a lot of money from that
let's like this one
all right uh
pretty sure everyone knows Bitcoin and
what it is
but you have not heard uh Bitcoin and
blockchain explained uh like this lady
did and she's a free Grammy Award winner
and she knows a lot about blockchains so
let's hear about her opinion what
Bitcoin really is
a message from cash app and the CEO of
hot girl Enterprise Megan the stallion
digital currency that's been getting a
lot of hype
Bitcoin is a new kind of money while the
cash in your wallet is issued and
regulated by governments Bitcoin is a
cryptocurrency like a wild stallion it
can't be controlled by anyone that means
that no one person or organization gets
to decide how much of it is used how
much of it is in circulation or what
it's worth
[Music]
foreign
there's only a limited amount of Bitcoin
like gold silver or me it's scarcity and
security is what can make Bitcoin
valuable
every Bitcoin is unique and has its own
ID that is certified by a super secure
technology called the blockchain you
can't make a fake Bitcoin no matter how
hard you try
like gold or gas prices bitcoin's value
can go up and down as the demand changes
although there's some other nitty-gritty
stuff that factors in too
that means when people are selling the
price goes down
we want lots of people are buying it it
comes back up
Bitcoin is not hard to get you just
gotta know how you can get it from
another person or from special markets
called cryptocurrency exchanges you can
also easily buy it on cash app starting
with as low as one dollars worth
Bitcoin is an investment so you can lose
money the price can go up and down by
the hour but the more you educate
yourself on bitcoin the better equipped
you'll be to navigate those curves
that's all for now but with my knowledge
and your hustle you'll have your own
Empire in no time I'll see you at the
top
pass
so what I really love about this video
is the number of lawyer hours they did
put into this video like it's not like
the original scans where they promise
you everything they did really tell you
that hey you can lose money on bitcoin
so at least she was not stupid to uh not
involve lawyers into something like this
anyway
um
I also want to introduce you to a new
measurement system I invented for this
however free word and it's called the
lambo meter and you can see a piece of
Lamborghinis and based on the height of
the pile I want to measure how
successful the different web free scans
are and how much money someone can make
from these scams the higher the pile the
better right
so
um the different talking about the
different type of scams in uh the web
free word and cryptocurrencies uh most
of you probably know pump and dump uh
it's very easy scheme uh buy a lot from
something which is cheap and it has a
very low trading volume
advertise this as the next big thing
sell it on top
profit easy game right if it's possible
you can sometimes even short when you
are on top and make double money
it's really cool
um if you are a celebrity you can do
this once or twice but after the first
time probably no one will believe you
that this is the next big thing
Rock pools Rock pools are pretty similar
to pump and dump but the difference is
that here you are the owner or the
developer of the specific cryptocurrency
or token or whatever we call this and uh
by being the developer you can control
more things and for example here's this
very nice chart of a typical rock pool
there was this series called squid game
you probably know this and when it got
popular there was a token called
squidgame.com
and it got pumped pretty high then it
was dumped very shortly and people made
a lot of money from it others lost a lot
more
um and what was really interesting that
uh there was this quantilex where the
county ransomware group was talking
about things and even they knew about
this uh rockpool scheme so that was
interesting in those chats
but again you need some identity to
promote something
um I'm I'm not really sure that uh this
is going to scale for a while
[Music]
giveaways comes uh Twitter accounts are
hacked all the time and also some people
are spamming uh popular Twitter accounts
with different spam messages it usually
goes like hey send Bitcoin to this
address and I will send you back twice
the Bitcoins
sounds legit right there's tons of these
here you can see from Elon Musk scams
actually back in the day someone did
like 2.8 Bitcoins from this very
specific scam
depends on when the cash-old was it can
be okay or not not that cool
sometimes as I mentioned the Twitter
accounts are hacked for example this is
the official Target account doing the
same giveaway scam
um yeah you cannot trust trusted
accounts anymore on the internet
Advanced fifth Road this is one of my
favorites uh I actually received an
email like this and
like I got it for my main email address
I instantly know that this is a scam so
I wanted to investigate
and this is how it looks like that hello
uh your Bitcoin plus has been founded
with some Bitcoin uh you can go to this
website use this username and use this
password and you can get your Bitcoins
uh
by registering they also asked for my
phone number to set up to factor
authentication
um that was I think both for the purpose
of making the site more legit and
getting my text now my phone number so
can scan me later and
once you log in you can see a fake
transaction history and fake bonds and
when you want to withdraw your money
they will tell you that just a very
small amount of Bitcoins are missing
before you can withdraw from this
website so if you fall for this Camp
then you send a little bit of Bitcoin to
the website and you believe that after
that you can withdraw all of your
Bitcoins and you can going to be rich
spoiler alert you want
so uh let's talk about nfts a little bit
I'm pretty sure most of you guys already
know what an nft is
so
no
yeah let's start this
come on okay uh so this is the first and
practically only an FDI boat uh I bought
this like more than four years ago I
bought it for one dollar I believe it
has the same value as of today so I did
not get rich from this but I really
don't want to sell this anyway
right now Twitter allows you to link
your nft to your profile image and
people think this is cool and so
whenever you visit my Twitter profile
you can see all the properties of this
very ugly Kitty uh the reason I chose
this crypto Kitty when I bought it
because this was the cheapest one and
probably the obvious one anyway
as you can see it has some very
interesting properties like
mouth is gerbil pattern Jaguar
first Himalayan
I don't know I don't care whatever let's
see what's on the blockchain right
so if we use etoric scan to check uh how
this
um
nft looks like here you can see that I
am the owner this is my wallet address
um you can see which smart contract kill
created this nft
um
and here is the token ID the token ID is
very important this is practically most
of the time what you buy as an nft from
a smart contract you buy a number that's
the basics of nft and you should be
really careful whenever you buy
something that sometimes this is only
what you buy so let's see the
transaction uh when I bought this what
happened in the background
so as you can see
um
the birth function was called for this
Kitty and then the transfer function
which transferred the nft from the
website from the Creator smart contract
account into my account and as you can
see now I'm the proud owner of this
number
so what's interesting uh with
cryptokitties that because it's a very
old nft they did not store the images on
the blockchain and
as of today no one practically stores
the nft images on the blockchain because
it's very expensive uh but what happens
for example in the case of cryptic
kitties that there is this very long
number which practically defines all the
characteristics of the cryptokitty and
they have a smart contract which can
practically decode these numbers and say
that okay if this bit is set to this
number then this means that it has the
Himalayan fur or whatever
uh unfortunately I won't have too much
time to discuss about ipfs but if you
are interested I think ipfs is a really
cool technology where you can store
files uh you know peer-to-peer way and
nowadays most modern nfts they store
the URL of your nft picture and this URL
points to an ipfs storage and I think
that's the best what we can do right now
but unfortunately there are still
sometimes a lot of nft projects where
the you where the image is only stored
on a Google drive or something like that
and on the blockchain you can only see
the Google Drive Link so that's not the
best way to do nfts
Okay so
let's go back to this
um
quick game uh what do you think who
bought this nft
who's the proud owner of this
say that again
no almost
I can help you she created this nft
about herself
yes
and she bought it for almost 120 Ephraim
last time I checked one ethereum was
like 1700 US dollars
with The Prado owner of this one
is Justin Bieber he bought it for 500 if
Rome
you can calculate how much money that is
actually I like this
art I I think it's pretty cool
what what do you think who is the proud
owner of this nft
it's Snoop Dogg and he pulled it for 200
500 E terms
so that's a lot of money
I mean for art it's
I don't know anyway
and who's this last one last monkey
say that again
yes it's aminam
he only
spent
123 each verse on that all right
now
um
there are also Rock pools in the nft
projects and this is one of my main
uh my favorite story about rap was in
nft projects
um there's this actress called Lana
Rhodes and she created an nft project as
well called cryptosis
and unfortunately uh after a while she
got aggressive comments on Discord and
um she practically canceled the project
and for example here you can see that
someone bought this very beautiful art
for uh four thousand dollars uh and now
what he's saying on Discord that he
practically spent all of his money on
this uh nft and he has no job and has a
two-year-old son yeah probably not the
best investment
and this is a bit another story like to
the same nft project but this is not the
same guy
um
and someone is begging Lana for a free
nft and because she just recently had a
new child then she tells that your
diapers are also expensive so I'm not
giving away my precious nfts so what's
really bad about this story that she had
this roadmap and she was promising a
hell a lot of things like
uh
some merch signed by herself and sent to
the top holders and stuff like that
and because she had this road map and
she never fulfilled this she might get
sued actually for this because she was
promising something to investors which
she did not deliver
okay
um and let's go to my main nft scam
this whole story started that I was
checking Discord and someone complaining
on Discord that he or she got across a
new nft scam
and I was able to see the link for this
Camp so I quickly started to investigate
this camp
if you go to the website it promises you
that you can get some free Doodles which
is another
very famous nft project
and once you connect your ballot to the
website
in the background if you analyze the
traffic you can see that the website
will check all of your nfts you store in
the same wallet and it will check the
prices of these nfts kind of suspicious
right and
what will happen if you click on hey I
want to get this nft for free then
metamask will prompt you with this uh
window where you can either confirm the
transaction or reject it
I myself I'm an I.T security guy I know
that I knew already that this is a scam
but it took me some minutes to figure
out what is going on here and what's
really interesting to see that
the source
of the
transaction is my wallet my nfts and the
destination
um
I mean the
when whenever you do something on web
free you are calling functions on Smart
contracts
and if you want to give your lft to
someone else you have to call the smart
contract and you have to call a function
on that smart contract which created
that nft right
um
so whenever someone wants to steal your
nfts they will ask you to
send a function call to a known trusted
smart contract and I find it a bit
confusing that someone is coming you but
still you are interacting with a known
legitimate smart contract this can be
actually pretty bad for example let's
say you are only into the Doodles and
FTS you have whitelisted
the smart contract for the Doodles nfts
and then you want to meet some new
Doodles nfts and when you click on mint
you will see hey I mean interacting with
this trusted smart contract right so
what could possibly go wrong what could
possibly go wrong that you are calling
the safe transfer from function and not
the mean function which means that you
are giving away all your precious nfts
so at the moment most of the wallet
software they have this pretty bad UI
that it is very hard to decipher what is
going on and if you are in a hurry then
yeah bad luck you can lose all of your
nfts
so I dig more and uh
I found uh that this whole scam kit was
available on GitHub
and
I was checking some of these uh very
vaguely
encoded contents
and I found that somebody is not just
giving away this scam kit on GitHub for
free but he is also selling it on a uh
on online platform
and here you can see all the reviews he
got from his Camp kit for example best
trainer one azuki in three days
so
uh seems like a lot of people started to
use this scam kit
these are all the features it supports
so
I was digging around a bit more and I
found some heavily obfuscated content as
well this is the decrypted version of it
and what's interesting to see here is
that uh on the first row you can you can
see price
then it compares the price whether it is
more than 1.1 which is ether and then
there's this address which is uh a new
address
and practically what happens here that
this is a backdoor code in the nft scam
kit and the
scam kit it will uh
steal all the cheap nfts and it will
transfer all the cheap nfts to the
operator of the scam kit whoever
downloaded it from the internet but all
the precious or more valuable nfts they
will be transferred to the guy who
created originally the scam kit so I
found this very interesting and amazing
and I have found a lot of examples on
the blockchain that this is exactly what
happened that some nfts were transferred
to one address and the more precious
ones they were transferred to another
one
so I contacted this guy on Telegram
and I asked him what are the differences
between the free version on GitHub and
the paid version you can buy on Salix
and I also asked him about this
obfuscated code
but he practically
did not bite
so he didn't tell me that yeah the
obfuscated version is a backdoored one
he just tells me that the paid version
has some extra features included like
you can still
efirm as well with it
so yeah
I think this is how you make big money
because these scales
now let's see it in action
so let's uh we are on this campsite
let's connect our metamask account
and now the user wants to click on mint
nft
this signature it's not really important
we can forget about this one
and when I clicked on claim now this is
the default view of metamask what
happens here and if you really know your
stuff and you'll know what you are doing
you should be able to see that the safe
transfer from function is not what you
want to call if you want to meet a new
nft
but if you are not very familiar with
this you might think hey I'm getting
free nfts so let's go ahead
so we can also check the data part
foreign
of metamask and again
here use here it tells you that
this is a trusted smart contract you are
interacting with you can also see all
the debug
messages stuff like that but uh
unfortunately I was only able to record
this with a real nft in my
um
wallet so
I had to click reject because otherwise
I would give away my precious one dollar
nft and I did not want to do that
okay
um this course cam this is pretty wide
nowadays and uh this is not just about
uh fake accounts
um contacting you and telling you to do
this or that
but nowadays Discord servers are hacked
uh all the time
foreign
for example
this is a list
created by nft herder where he listed
the 107 Discord servers which have been
compromised mostly most of them with
this bookmarklet technique
and after you can compromise official
Discord servers you can send
announcements in the public channels and
people will think hey this is a trusted
Source this is the official Discord
server for the nft project so whatever I
do on this website that's legit right so
yeah Discord security is very very bad
nowadays
foreign
I really like this one about how hacking
happens in movies and what really
happens in the nft world because yes
this is what's happening most of the
time when it comes to scams
uh I only have like one minute left so I
won't discuss so much about Hardware
wallets but Hardware wallets are also a
target for attackers sometimes they can
change for example they open the
hardware wallet set it up they know
already the recovery seed phrase then
write it down and send it to you that
hey this is your
seed phrase use this one
and here's another example where someone
modified The Ledger Hardware itself
and it added an extra flash drive to it
and sent it to uh already on owners who
already had leisure
so these are the best practices you can
do don't trust random people or
celebrities or media always check the
source of the application or the
distributed app you are using don't send
fun someone you don't trust clearly
whenever was to share logins passwords
private key see phrases backup phrases
with you or asking for you to do that
look at them
um be extra careful whenever you
interact with both known and unknown
smart contracts uh you should probably
use a password manager and I bought 2fa
if you have a lot to protect really use
Hardware wallets because sometimes it
can help you sometimes it can't
surely keep your PC model free
um you can also use code wallets I think
the take time don't rush that's the most
important advice I can tell you never
rush whenever signing transactions on
the blockchain and nowadays there are
even uh some security extensions you can
use like wallet guard or Sunrise nft
scan protector I have never tried them
but they looks legit
so this is the conclusion uh give them a
zero day and he will access for a day
but teach a man to fish and he will
access for life this is very true for
the nft word
I also have a white paper uh where I
discuss another like 30 different scan
types regarding the blockchain and the
free word so contact me if you are
interested in those and thank you that's
all I wanted to share with you thank you
for your attention
all right thank you I really like the
means in the presentation today
so uh may I know who asked the first
question uh with all these scams can you
raise your hand yeah so you've got the
most top voted questions so please
proceed to go out in the back oh staff
there he will pass you a cat all right
thank you so we have some time for some
questions so first with all these scams
in web 3 what do you think is the best
way to educate the Layman
don't rush I mean that's the best advice
but I can tell to everyone who's in the
nft world which is already crazy enough
I don't know like there's no easy answer
to this unfortunately there there's no
best way to reach people who are
sometimes greedy sometimes stupid
I don't know there's no easy answer to
this
okay next question what is the best way
to prevent these scams by the community
or online platforms
I think as of today uh the wallet
software developers should improve a lot
like there is this term called clear
signing
what you have seen previously is called
Blind signing where you don't really
know what's going on and the clear
signing design should look like that hey
do you want to transfer this doodle nft
from your wallet to this unknown someone
are you interested in that if yes please
confirm that's that's a clear signing
but uh only very few wallet software are
supporting it some are already
supporting it for tokens like erc20
tokens but for nfts I don't think anyone
is there yet where they can really know
that this is going to happen
all right I think we have a minute for
the last question so do you think that
there's a need for the government's
Intervention when it comes to regulating
rep 3. if the government steps in
wouldn't it be counter-intuitive to what
web3 stands for
no
we really want uh crypto to be
cryptocurrencies and blockchain and web
free to be mainstream yes government
should step in uh unfortunately
governments are not very famous for
regulating stuff uh best ways so I think
in the beginning there will be some
crazy stupid regulations but I do hope
that in time we will get there when
everything everyone can be happy
all right thank you very much let's give
him a round of applause