and about six months ago with how to
sort of provide a little bit more in
nation on what are the risks that
actually deploying a dedicated blue team
would actually stop so when we were
looking at this problem in our threat
intelligence lab basically what we were
looking to do was how could we actually
take just like the generic nature of
risk that's actually out there and
decompose this into a number of
different data points that we could
actually support with some of the
measurements that we actually have
access to so I'm gonna sort of open up
I'm gonna talk a little bit about where
we actually source our data what the
data looks like I'm gonna sort of lay
the cards on the table for what our
sampling biases are in the data set that
we have access to and sort of discuss a
little bit more about how we actually
tackled the problem we'll take a look
and tell the results in this one so the
the big things that we're taking a look
at here are what are the chances that
will experience a breach of like typical
perimeter controls that would require
some sort of sock or blue team response
action we'll talk a little bit about how
many assets we typically see being hit
by breaches over the course of a year
within a particular industry or
geographic location and then we'll also
talk a little bit about in the first
section here what does a breach actually
look like and how are we actually
responding to it so you get a better
idea of what that looks like as well and
this data set can be used to plan a
number of different countermeasures
hopefully it's useful to you in a
variety of different ways but we can
talk a little bit about how we can play
an effective responses how we can keep
the sort of data up to date and maybe do
a little bit of Q&A discussion at the
end of this so just to get things
rolling our data set is comprised of
about 1,800 Network sensors those are
deployed at internet choke points we are
running full packet capture on them so
that we can actually take a look and do
forensic inspection of what it is that
we're seeing and we're running a number
of different IDs tools these are
deployed specifically to take a look at
what the clean side traffic is looking
like after all the perimeter controls
are actually running through on the
endpoint side for visibility there we're
talking about 87,000 endpoints that we
have out there those are CB response
agents and we're running a number of
different feeds on them for detection
purposes as well as some additional
tools of our own design to try and take
a look at
some of the raw data in a different way
so this data set is taken from 600 or so
organizations deployed around 2000
different sites it represents 28
industries 50 countries and about 185
thousand plus users our data set we
mostly are protecting financial
industries so most of the data that
you're going to see taken from our data
set is finance oriented but we also have
a fairly decent sized pool of other and
that breaks down across a number of
different things so if we take a look at
how that breaks down you can see that
we've got two other big sections in
legal and technology but we also have a
slew of smaller data that's coming from
a variety of different medium sized
organizations that are out there we are
definitely talking about mid sized
organizations here not super large
organizations so this is about perimeter
controls and and what it is that we're
responding to on the inside of those for
that particular type of demographic if
we talk about the typical perimeter
defenses like what's ahead of us so
we're not talking about things that are
being stopped by next-gen firewalls
stopped by the IPS systems I mean
sometimes they're things that should be
stopped by those things but these are
the things that we're typically seeing
deployed ahead of our monitoring service
so if we run in there basically we're
looking at things that are behind these
so on the endpoint side typically most
of our clients are also running mature
antivirus or next-gen antivirus
technology in addition to the CBE
response agent so we're not talking
about the things that are picked up and
stopped by those things in terms of what
we're actually doing our side we're
looking at monitoring and hunting we do
periodic hunting exercises that are sort
of ad-hoc where we go and we take a look
at a just like the raw data set and see
if we can find anything else that's
interesting in it we do investigations
into things that are just being picked
up in triage with the internally
deployed IDs to see if anything's gotten
through more permissive configurations
that are set up with next-gen firewalls
and then we respond so typically this is
another part of what it is that we do
and it does actually definitely have a
ramification on the data because what
we're talking about with
is everything that we actually have as a
data point represents something that we
saw and did something to contain so if
we're talking about the number of assets
that are impacted this is going to
assume that you are doing something to
actually contain the breaches I can't
really show you stuff where we didn't
have anybody engaged and then it's
follow-up after we actually detect
reaches we have a TI team that's looking
at you know going in and doing some
additional research into those they try
and do sampling across different
situations that you sort of do follow-up
analysis to get us some additional
characteristics and we can talk a little
bit about that research as well so data
point deep dive basically what we have
here is a tool that'll just sort of let
us run through what we'd be talking
about as a single data point with
interset so we're talking about tens of
thousands of these sorts of incidents
but to sort of walk you through what one
incident would look like and what the
data sort of represents this is just a
malicious document I believe it's a
phishing situation that we can run
through but what it looks like is we
might pick up something where we have a
user who has been successfully fished
they've run a mal doc and we see some
sort of reputational indicator that says
that their machine is now beating out to
a CNC so this is a case where we've seen
phishing bypass the defenses and we have
like a reputational indicator or some
other reason that's being picked up by
one of our detecting technologies that's
saying hey we need to go take a look at
that and we've got like our own sort of
sim in here but I mean this would apply
to anybody's sim if you were taking a
look at it is just a starting point for
your investigation then what we'd be
looking at doing is sort of like
reviewing what's actually going on take
a look at you know just address
information start digging deeper if we
take a look at that you know we can see
if there's any reputation Olinda caters
that might increase the confidence that
we're actually taking a look at
something bad we can talk about initial
analysis where we would be getting sort
of into essentially just sort of basic
triage functions and you can think about
implementing these within your own sock
as well where you're just sort of like
sifting through what are the things that
you would actually do deep response into
and maybe some of the things that you
might discard if
you know obviously benign and then if we
see that we actually have sort of let me
just take a look here sorry one of the
other things that you might want to use
in here is contextual information about
sort of things that you know might be
relevant to your business that can also
weed some of that stuff out but assuming
that we've actually done all those
things and we're coming back with
something that's actually interesting to
take a look at we would probably be
taking a look at raw wire confirmation
on our side which would let us go into
here and see you know well what what
what communication is actually going
back we can see in this case if we're
taking a look at the the traffic around
that we're actually affecting any
document down and then when we go into
it our our side for investigation we
typically look at actually extracting
the file out trying to you know
reconstruct that either out of the pcap
or we could be reconstructing it if you
don't have access to full packet capture
on your side you could also take a look
at just taking a look at like summarized
data that's coming off of something like
bro logs and see if you can reconstruct
the domain that it was actually sourcing
a mail dock from when you have the mail
dock we typically would run some sort of
sandbox analysis on it to try and get an
understanding of what it actually is
what it does there's a variety of
different tools that are out there for
this I think on our side right now we're
using a hybrid analysis tool we've used
kakou in the past which is an open
source project I know there's also a
number of commercial ones that are out
there but all are good things to give
you more information when you're
actually taking a look at it
and then from an end point side you have
the whole side of taking a look into it
from what is actually running on the
local machine can you actually figure
out what's going on in something like CB
response can you figure out you know
were there any weird processes that
respond after they open the document etc
etc so from our side in this particular
case we're taking a look at it we do see
that we see you know some some post
download opening of the file and then
you know some PowerShell commands
actually running and doing some fairly
suspicious things that are actually
running on that particular agent we can
see binary analysis where we're sort of
taking a look at
what what is what is actually coming
down into this machine etc etc so I'm
just I'm sort of skimming through all of
this if we do want to go back to it and
take a look I'm more than happy to
discuss it in in greater depth but I
just sort of wanted to give basically
like an idea of the sorts of things that
actually represent each data point
that's in here so I can talk in in
detail about like some of the ones that
we have for for scenario data this does
not necessarily reflect what every
single incident was but it reflects the
type of things that we're doing in order
to qualify the data that you're seeing
as part of the data set that relief that
we are releasing today so it's taking a
look so process inspection what it's
doing and basically at the conclusion of
sandbox analysis and all of this what we
are taking a look at from this is
essentially just how do we actually
classify the incident so as the analyst
is going through they're taking a look
at it and and we have a number of
different incident types that we're
going to talk about today in the data
set one of them is phishing so when we
talk about phishing we're talking about
some something that has occurred where
we've actually seen a phishing hit a
user and we've either seen and confirmed
that the user has submitted credentials
out to the third party or we've
confirmed that they've actually you know
followed through and installed something
and and run something on the machine if
we're talking about like the malware
incidents in our data set what we're
talking about is something where we've
had an analyst go in there and confirm
that we've actually seen code execute on
a machine that did have some sort of
malicious purpose and from the exploit
site this is actually sort of
interesting I was looking at a talk
today from from Michael Brightman and
what we're looking at is we're just
basically confirming that an exploit was
observed on the inside of the perimeter
and it was interacting with something
that it should never have been able to
actually access so it's you have a
protected server and the protected
server is behind something like a
next-gen firewall or web application
firewall it may be both and still you're
actually seeing you know something
coming through from the internet that's
interacting with that server because it
has to expose something legitimate and
the the exploits are actually being seen
on the inside
our typical response is basically just
like basic host isolation containment
remediation we generally pass off to the
client but the idea here is that in this
data set we're talking we're taking a
look at stuff or once we see something
come through we generally try and deny
the attackers infrastructure that's
lonsurf launching the attack and sort of
limit the damage that it can't spread
within the environment and when we when
we take a look at impact data that's
that's going to become a lot a lot more
relevant so if I take a look at let's
just pull back up here
so the thinking here we're taking a look
at a data set we're talking about tens
to hundreds of thousands of
investigations that look like this and
what we're trying to do is sort of see
if we can draw any conclusions about
what the probabilities are that we're
going to see security incidents at
particular locations over particular
time periods so the way that we approach
this in our study was we were basically
treating each sensor that we actually
had that was out there as a convenient
sample that's taken from a general
population and you can think about sort
of subdividing your data or restricting
your convenience sample to things that
are more relevant to your particular
industry or your particular like sort of
demographic but what we're gonna
basically do then is we're gonna record
a boolean value about whether or not the
sensor was participating in one of these
different types of incidents and
responding to one of these types within
a time window so if we're talking about
something like malware for example what
we might do is you might start
generating data points and we say okay
well did the sensor participate in a
malware incident this month like did we
have to actually respond to a malware on
the queenside this month yes or no what
about if we extend that to two months to
three months what if we look at it in
March and April in May and then you can
think about repeating this over and over
and over again for all the different
types of incidents that we could be
talking about and all of the different
time periods that we might want to
represent in the data set so the the raw
data that we have is actually just going
to be looking at the incidents
themselves and what time that they
actually occurred on but this is sort of
how you can use those that raw incident
data in order to make a bit of a
statistical projection about what you
might actually have seen if if you were
trying to figure out what it is that you
need to go look for so we repeat this
across you know all these different
types and what we're basically left with
is a data set that looks like a sampling
without replacement data set so you can
apply hypergeometric distribution
analysis to that and there's like I mean
I don't know actually how to reconstruct
that myself but unfortunately there are
wonderful libraries in Python that will
that will apply that that statistical
pattern to the data and then what that
can do is it can let us take a look and
see what the confidence interval would
be projecting from data set that we have
which is our observed rate to a
projected best-case
in worst case scenario for what we can
think about the general population
having if we're if we're deciding
whether or not we actually want to
deploy a sensor into a particular area
or for deciding you know trying to make
maybe a budget case to somebody that
would you know maybe I would really like
to implement a monitoring program and
I'm having difficulty actually
justifying the budget then you can take
some of this data and maybe build it
into a case like that
so if we think about how do we like
actually gather the data assess
potential impact from security incidents
over a time period that was a bit of a
tougher problem in the risks I'd like if
we think about risk we're talking about
impact we're talking about probability
we've sort of looked a little bit about
probability right now question is how do
we actually address impact and
ultimately this was this was an area
that we found a bit harder so I'm gonna
share the data that I have and I'm
hoping that you guys out there will have
some data about your environment from
your side that can help you add to this
data and think about what the impact
would actually look like in your
environment but what we can do is we can
show a distribution curve of what the
number of impacted assets and users were
from our data pool so if you think about
what it is that we're doing in response
when we detect an incident we're trying
to contain it as fast as possible and
then we're we're basically creating a
log of how many different assets were
actually impacted so sometimes when an
incident comes in it'll spread sometimes
people will you know not be able to
repair a hole in their general perimeter
configuration and we'll see a repeat of
the same type of breach that comes back
over and over and over again but you can
think about both those numbers that we
have in our data set basically just sort
of giving you sort of like an impact
distribution for the number of affected
assets that we see from different types
of activity and we also have some data
about what is going on on a breach so we
have demographics on things like what
lures are people actually using for
fishing over different time periods what
what our success rates of each you know
what malware is deployed if the Machine
actually does get popped and somebody
runs a dock on it so we have some some
data with that as well that we can share
so if I take a look at actually showing
the incident probability what we were
doing I'm gonna see here so this is
essentially the output of
statistical analysis has just been put
into a tool that we have up on our
website where you can take a look and
you can actually run some some different
filters over the data and you can say
well what does what does the rate of
breach look like for say you know all of
the different client pool or maybe just
like the client pool in the tech
industry or the health industry or the
insurance industry and then sort of
basically draw some comparisons around
that so if we take a look at it there is
is some interesting stuff that we can
actually see so this is just one view on
the data set we ran it as as two
different things one was instantaneous
because we were curious about what was
the like sort of the trend line so if we
see that there's a sudden spike in in
trending information then that can give
us an idea that maybe a particular type
of attack is starting to become more
successful and we can see that in
general for most of the incident types
on a global level over the last year
it's been you know fairly steady we can
we can also do sort of a analysis of
which types of incidents are more likely
than others to occur on any given month
so it looks like malware and phishing or
sort of you know going back and forth
we're seeing that the rate at which we
see malware incidents is a little bit
higher than the rate at which we see for
example general phishing but exploit
being seen on the inside of the firewall
because something is allowed and an
exploit attack to actually get through
is significantly higher than you know
either the other two and that is that is
a pattern that we generally see
consistently across most industries
there are a few exceptions one of the
things that was really interesting in
this data set was that when we compared
things like the UK dataset versus like
the North American dataset some of the
trends actually flipped around and
reversed so in the UK significantly more
likely to see phishing than it is to see
malware actually be successful but
there's that what we're doing here is
we're actually plotting an average case
a worst case in a best case and the way
that we're doing that within our dataset
is we're essentially just looking at the
confidence intervals so if we're
thinking back to that hyper geometric
distribution calculation it's going to
output output basically a upper bound a
lower bound and a confidence rate that
you can say
you're actually going to see that in the
general population based off of what you
observed so we're running a best case
projection would basically be the bottom
of that confidence interval and then the
worst case would be the top of that
confidence interval so with the tool
basically you can move around inside of
that data and sort of see what it is you
can compare a number of different
industries so for example maybe I wanted
to do a comparison and I may be a
finance client and I'm considering you
know partnering up with a insurance
client and I kind of want to see whether
my risk rates are about the same as
their risk rates in terms of general
health so we can take a look at this and
you know you can sort of compare what
those actually look like it's a little
chaotic if you look at all of them
together but maybe we just want to
compare the rate for say malware between
the two and you can see that you know
there's there's different rates that are
actually in here the other thing that
you can do with this which we thought
was interesting was with show cumulative
rates of breach for particular types of
incidents so we were looking at a month
over month and what we realized was that
the month over month rate is is actually
quite a low percentage most of the time
you're not going to see a breach that
actually shows up on the inside on a
monthly level but if we take a look at
that over the course of an entire year
your percentages start to change and
they also start to change if you start
to think about managing more and more
sites so I mean intuitively this this
definitely makes sense if you have lots
of different locations that you have to
protect and do you think about you know
running your defenses on your on your
regular cadence over the course of an
entire year what are the chances that
somebody screws up in one of those
locations and maybe you know miss
applies I don't know an update to the
signatures that are running on your
next-gen firewall well your your rates
actually change on that one so the
variables that you can input into the
tool you can see whether you're talking
about a cumulative case you can see
whether you're talking about an
instantaneous case if you're looking for
trend data and you can also configure
basically you know how many different
sites that you would like to be talking
about inside of the data set
the next section that we actually have
in the data and this is where I was
coming back to that impact data is we
can talk about how many actual assets
are impacted by various different types
of breaches over the course of a year or
any other particular time period this
this particular set is looking at your
lis impacted assets but you could just
as easily from the same data set do it
over a monthly or a quarterly basis or
whatever it is that you wanted to
actually project out and we can see that
there's there's there's definitely
different types of distributions that
are that are out there but what we're
basically seeing here is that we have a
cluster and there's sort of a long tail
distribution for most things where your
average organization that you know
experience is something bird we're
seeing like say exploits showing up on
the inside of the perimeter is probably
talking about 20 or fewer different
systems that are actually susceptible to
those exploits that are actually getting
through and then you can think about
people who are on the tail end of the
distribution curve who are in this case
looking at like 900 different machines
that are actually experiencing something
these are probably people with much
poorer configurations at the perimeter
right so this the sort of gives you a
band you know if you think about how
regularly you actually apply your patch
schedule if you think about how
regularly you are you know updating your
perimeter defenses to block out anything
that's known bad from actually reaching
servers and attempting exploits against
them it can give you an idea of sort of
what that distribution looks like
so see if I can do this without it again
incident demographics in this so I've
actually like so we have that like the
tool data I've also got it pulled up in
here and the reason why I wanted to do
this was because we can also think about
what sorts of different types of
exploits are there so the data set that
we're releasing today is is one where
you can take a look at what are all the
impact distributions for these types of
incidents we also have companion papers
for threat intelligence that are talking
about like what are the specific types
of things that we see those are done on
something where they're there I think
generally released on a quarterly basis
all of this data is really available to
everybody as a practitioner so if that's
something that you're interested in it's
it's not something you have to pay for
but we're breaking it down in terms of
what we're actually seeing in terms of
the campaign's that are actually getting
through and you know you see that there
are some things which are very popular
which are actually still you know coming
through onto the clean side in this
particular instance when we were running
this this is just again some some data
showing it's like we have like the
Microsoft I asked up in the WebLogic
stuff that's coming through fairly high
volume and then we have like a tail and
distribution of a lot of other different
types of exploits in a similar way we
can think about what are the different
types of things that people are actually
running on the machine when they
actually have access to it and we can
see that right now
Imhotep has been enormous leap all
popular for people to actually choose to
actually run on a machine once they
actually get access to it but we do see
a lot of other different types of tools
being run sort of and again that sort of
long tail distribution where you see
little bits of lots of different types
of activity that's coming through in
there fishing so I mean there's lots of
different data that you have on fishing
like realistically this is probably one
of the most popular ways to actually
breach in because you can successfully
get a user to do something stupid just
about all the time and it's an attack
that never really gets old but one of
the things that we were looking at here
is maybe we can talk about some some
data about when you know you can think
that you would have
likely for people to actually convert
over and engage with phishing and what
are different ways that we can actually
take a look at it so you can see that
there are some days of the week where
there's actually significantly less
chance that people will actually engage
with a phishing campaign and other days
of the week where there's you know
almost twice as high a percentage of
them engaging at the phishing campaign
so this looks at basically just link
clicked and credentials actually
submitted out of the phishing data we
can also think about like what lures we
actually see are being more effective so
you know what we see the most of in
terms of lures and then what we see are
most successful in terms of people
actually clicking and engaging with them
so again if this data is something that
is of interest to you there is a whole
bunch of additional stuff that we
actually have within there so ways to
use this run books next steps that kind
of stuff so really when we were putting
this together there's a couple of
different people that we were sort of
thinking about well one if you are
already well represented by one of the
convenience samples that we've
calculated for you please feel free to
use the work that we've actually
produced inside of here but otherwise we
have the raw data set and say you are
you know maybe a mix of like industry
and financial so you just want to see
like a mix of those two different data
sets blended together I'm hoping that
you can take the raw data that were that
we're putting out there you can blend
those together into a convenience sample
that sort of represents what it is that
you want to represent with it and sort
of repeat the methodology that we've
discussed here today in order to give
you some better predictions that you can
use for your own threat intelligence
purposes or again if you're trying to
justify in terms of like a management
decision like what your blue team you
know needs in order to actually do
something and then the impact data
obviously you're going to have to do a
self assessment of how flat your
environment is and how quickly you
actually respond to one of these things
when when you see something get popped
inside of your environment if you
respond relatively quickly and you
contain it fairly effectively or you
have like lots of great network
segmentation then you're probably going
to see something where
you have a fairly similar impact
distribution on on the left-hand side of
the curve if you're somebody who is in
the unfortunate position of having to do
security for a completely flat network
environment with no permissioning and
you know you know lease privileges and
none of that great stuff and you're
probably gonna see something towards the
extreme tail end where you know a lot of
assets are getting impacted but it's a
good way to actually show what that what
that range can actually look like so at
this point if anybody is interested in
the actual like data set in contact
that's the the link up there and then
the the QR code is just a repeat of the
link if you are interested in pulling it
down but without up there I just we have
a fairly small audience today does
anyone have any questions with anything
that I could go into or or explore
yeah so that's that's a good question so
if we're thinking about this the idea is
to try and give you an idea of sort of
what are the probabilities that you'll
you're run into different things so that
you can kind of prioritize what your
blue team activities should be if we're
thinking about a run book one of the
things that we can do is we can
basically detail out what are the
general investigative steps that you'd
have to take along the way at different
stages in order to actually respond to
one of these actually being detected so
if we think back to this fishing example
that we have here there's a number of
steps in here that we can think about
that you would have to do for basically
every every one of these detections
right so this is one we're basically
just looking at a block of a file block
download where somebody's attempting to
download from something that we've got a
reputation indicator for but if you
think about each of the steps that are
on here these are very highly automated
things that you can actually take a look
at doing repeatedly within your
organization so a lot of people are
starting to look at soar platforms in
order to start to automate these tasks
and increase the fidelity of the signal
that the analysts are actually having to
take a look at when they go in to do it
so they don't have to do so many of
these things by hand but we can think
about you know collecting the data about
you know what is it that this this
particular incident is actually having
so pull down data about the ip's pull
down data about the files all of the
steps in this are things that we can
think about doing in an automated all
sort of way so you could do a run book
where for example you were to take the
indicator you were to look at it you
were to you know maybe extract a peak
app around it maybe automatically submit
the files within for analysis inside of
your sandbox application and then maybe
the analyst at the other end instead of
having to repeat all of these steps is
just looking at a report where they can
see everything that's on and maybe they
can just move into a judgment sort of
situation
yes I I would a hundred percent agree
with doing that we often don't have a
dollar value to assign to the assets
that we're protecting so we're we're
outsourced so we're not in a position to
do that but if you're looking at it from
your side and you are like a
practitioner who's protecting just one
environment a hundred percent I would
definitely do that I would also take a
look at like when you're when you're
applying that sort of dollar value think
about the data that's on there and think
about the cost of remediation is two
other costs that you would plug in to
that for your impact assessment
yeah yeah yeah no I can it can
definitely skyrocket up there and in
some cases it can be almost nothing so
any others
okay
[Applause]