can everyone hear me all the way in the
back perfect excellent all right so my
name is Steve Edwards and I'm here to
talk about implementing explicit allow
without getting fired so I work at
Jewish security which is now part of
Cisco Systems and I lead their corporate
security engineering and defensive
security teams there so a little bit of
blue and a little bit of red before that
I was at Eastern Michigan University
where I led the security program there
at duo we have a really great product
and that's not what I'm here to talk to
you about today at duo were allergic to
vendor pitches so I just wanted to tell
you about some of the cool things that
we're doing inside of duo to keep the
company secure and then if you want to
know more about our product we do have a
booth outside where you can you can stop
and talk to us and we'll give you all
the details about it there so you came
to a presentation where the title
included a phrase that I coined so you
may have never heard of explicit allow
before and essentially it's a method by
which all code except that which is
explicitly than that has been previously
seen has been approved sorry except
which has been previously seen and
approve is prevented from running on a
system so it's a more inclusive term for
application whitelisting and I didn't
coin this phrase just because white
listing and black listing can sometimes
make people feel uncomfortable or
excluded but this this allows us to
expand beyond just application
whitelisting
this this principle this concept and so
I think you'll see today why this might
be a better term so I'll take you
through some of the ways that we've
implemented explicit allow @uo and the
way that we did it where no one ran me
out of town with pitchforks so the first
thing that I want to talk about and the
secret to our success is design and so
I'll talk about design at duo and I will
talk about our product a little bit
because we spend a lot of time thinking
about design and I'll share how those
design principles we applied to the
thing to the tools that we built
internal to keep the company secure then
I'll talk through
how where we've applied explicit
allowing practice so on our max our
Windows computers our Chrome OS
computers as well as at the network
level and also for some types of
authentication I'll share a little bit
about what's coming next for the things
that we're building then I'll have time
for Q&A and if I talk really really fast
which I times two then we'll have time
for a demo as well so design it - Oh a -
well we have a strong focus on usable
security and you can see that in our
product people actually like to interact
with it and so we've taken those
principles of user centric design and
applied it to explicit allow and that's
the reason we could roll out something
as a restrictive as these principles
without seeing a lot of backlash from
our end users or our system
administrators so in this presentation
I'll show you some of the tools that
we've built explain the underlying
infrastructure and the philosophy that
we took in our approach to implementing
this at duo so in other words if if you
don't have usable security people will
find a way around it in this old Dilbert
comic more Dex the preventer of
information services says security is
more important than usability in a
perfect world no one would be able to
use anything and then this des logging
into his computer and it says to
complete the login procedure please
stare directly into the Sun that's a
great example of non usable security but
that's what security companies often ask
of our end users and it's a bad
experience for them and then it's a bad
experience for security teams because
they've implemented something that
people hate and so if security isn't
usable it won't work people will find a
way around it if you implement something
that's so hard to mix or make someone's
laptop so hard to use they'll bring a
work from home laptop or if you make it
so hard for them to get at their email
they'll just start forwarding it to
another mailbox and we can go back and
forth and try and add more controls to
make it even harder and harder and
harder but that's not enabling the
business that's not whatever your
company is supposed to be doing that's
standing in the way of it instead of
supporting the mission
so we wanted to take these principles
and apply them to explicit allow duos
focus on usable security can be seen
even in our staffing at duo for every
five software engineers we have one
product designer so that's a lot of
people thinking about how humans
interact with computers and receiving
feedback from people who actually use
our software and people who buy and
implement our software what they like
and what they don't like and what's
effective because honestly that's what
makes effective security so we wanted to
minimize friction we wanted to protect
people without ruining their day and we
wanted to protect people without ruining
our IT departments day if we're pushing
out something to the laptops that IT
manages they're the ones who are going
to get yelled at not us and maybe
they're really good at redirecting it
and I still get yelled at it happens
sometimes but we don't want to ruin our
system administrators day or our end
users day with any of the security that
we roll out we just want to introduce
the right amount of friction when a
risky action occurs but make sure that
it's not too little and too much just
enough friction for someone to slow down
and say hey is this really what I wanted
to do and at the same time provide them
with the best security that we can so
the winning formula and and we've
applied this across all of our platforms
and I'll go through and I'll show you
some examples of each so say this this
starts when an action is blocked so I
feel like I'm playing Tron just a little
bit
yay okay well III liked the trance and
effects actually maybe I'll put that
back later okay so the winning formula
is this any of these start when an
action is blocked because like I said
explicit allow is default deny
everything is blocked at first so say
you try to run an application on your
computer you double click on it and some
scary message comes up and says hey you
can't do this talk to your system
administrator please so a local agent
will send that event to automation and
then we can start doing things in the
background we can use threat
intelligence to start scanning if this
is scanning this application against our
threat intelligence feeds say hey is
this known malicious right now and if it
is well just raise an incident right
away sorry it's blocked so nothing bad
has happened and it's already blocked
but we still want an incident because we
don't want malware on our computers even
if it's not doing anything because how
did it get there maybe something else
maybe maybe a dropper did end up getting
through and landed the software there
but if we don't see that it's a
malicious right away will prompt the end
user and say hey did you intend to run
this because typically we don't want
software running on people's computer if
they didn't mean to do it
unless like we IT pushed that to them
and then we'll have already added added
it to the allowed list so we'll ask them
hey did you mean to run this and if they
say yes then ok it's added to their
allowed list right away and they can
double click it and it will run if they
say no then we'll create an incident and
we'll work through why is software
running without this person's permission
maybe it's just the Adobe updater and
they don't sign their binaries which is
really frustrating so they didn't know
that Adobe was updating in the
background so we didn't so that's that's
a good start and then every single day
at around midnight we go through our
entire list of allowed software and
rescan it against their intelligence to
see hey has something that was
previously unknown been flagged as
malicious so then we can raise another
incident and follow up if that's the
case and you can see with this formula
there's more that we can inject you this
is a great place to start but you can
also work in sandbox saying and you
work in actual system administrator
authorization all through this same
workflow so in practice here's my Mac
I'm trying to run a piece of software
called Stellarium it lets you see where
the stars are in the sky and it's not
allowed yet so on max using Santa we see
this pop up and it looks really scary
and there's a lot of information not all
of it I understand and my only button is
to click ignore that's not a great
experience we didn't build that piece
and the next thing that happens is our
friendly slack security bot says hey
said words we noticed that something was
blocked from running on your machine our
goal is to keep you safe while enabling
you to do your job please direct any
questions to the corporate security
Channel but did you mean to run this
application from this folder if yes
then you'll be able to run it again so
if I click yes it says ok the
applications been added so within the
next 30 seconds you should be able to
run the application again if that
doesn't work you can open up terminal
and type in this incantation and then
everything will work if you have any
problems again please reach out to us
and humans will help you and so after
that I double click the application
again and it opens right off so the
amount of friction that was introduced
here was all of about 15 seconds I saw a
scary message but at the same time my
friend security bot was reaching out to
me to see if this is something that I
really wanted to do and as soon as I
clicked it it was just about ready for
me to by the time I could switch back
and find where it put the application
when I double clicked it it was ready to
run again so this this started from
humble beginnings so here's here's the
original approach is we we started with
just having people see this pop-up and
then take a screenshot and then also
copy and paste out the sha-256 hash
because it'd be a pain for us to type it
in from a screenshot and post it in a
slack Channel and say hey I'm trying to
run this can you please allow it and
then you know we'll do the threat
intelligence by hand
and then we'll get it in there and so
you can see puts the hash in and so T so
Klee there went through and said yep
that looks that looks good I've added it
to the list so now you can type open up
terminal and type in the sinc command
which everyone knows how to do because
they're doing it all the time every time
they run new software and and then
they're good to go and somehow we didn't
lose our jobs for doing this because
because everyone was so supportive I
don't recommend starting with this
approach if you can start with the
automated approach that's that's
probably a better option so let me tell
you a little bit about the technologies
that we use for explicit allow so you've
seen Mac OS already and on Mac OS who we
used Google's open source project Santa
and we've been using it for a really
long time relatively speaking when it
was released it was released as a client
with no server and there were no servers
available for it eventually there was an
open source software called central that
served as a back-end for this so it
would actually at least maintain the
list of allowed software so that you
could centralize that without that you
would have to figure out a way to put
the list of allowed software on every
single person's workstation as well as
the Santa client so we did that for a
little while it was back down
elasticsearch my experience of
elasticsearch is it's hard to keep it
healthy and running smoothly and that
was the experience in this case at least
so we decided to throw it out because of
its poor performance and build something
entirely homegrown that's API driven
entirely serverless
that and it's actually a really simple
bit of software it just it serves up the
list of allowed software to everyone who
asks for it and you can add new things
to that software and then it can also
trigger the automation to say hey this
person saw this block event let them
know that ask them if they meant to run
this software so since that was such a
smashing success and we rolled it out
across all of DL which is about maybe
800 max we decided to
on Windows not because we have a lot of
Windows we probably have about 10
Windows workstations but because Windows
is a target and we do have 10 Windows
workstations so it seems like a problem
to solve so instead of going for
commercial software or even open source
software we looked within Windows 2 app
Locker which my experience in the past
with app Locker has been I don't want to
say mixed because I think that over
sells the the positivity it was pretty
terrible lockers really hard to manage
and historically has required an Active
Directory so for one of my engineers I
posed this I posed this traveling I want
to use app Locker to enforce explicit
allow but we don't have an active
directory we don't want an active
directory what can we do and also I want
it to be the exact same workflow that I
showed you in that flowchart I want it
to only be about 15 seconds for someone
to self remediate if they get something
blocked that they need to run to operate
the business so again was entirely
homegrown entirely serverless no active
directory required and basically it's a
small agent that looks for looks through
the windows event logs for app Locker
blocks and then without even using slack
it just pops up a dialog and says did
you mean to run this yes or no and we've
already stand it against threat
intelligence like virustotal thread
exchange cisco tip and seeing that it
there are known it's not known as
malicious and so we pop this up and say
did you mean to run this they say yes
and they say ok it'll take about 30
seconds and then you'll be ready to go
so here's here's an example so this is
like on the previous layer there's blue
this blue thing is all you get with a
blocker by default so completely useless
not even a way to say hey this is the
thing I was trying to run so we created
a more verbose error message in case
people need to screenshot it to us and
and share it with us so we say hey did
you intend to run this and then if they
click yes it says hey please wait 2 to 5
minutes it's usually much faster than
that and then they can run the software
again so this is essentially the this
small agent just shells out to
PowerShell and interacts with local
policy objects instead of using
your policy Orchestrator it just changes
the local policies for AppLocker so it
converts what we have in our database in
AWS for what the allowed Lister's into
the format that the policy is looking
for and just pushes it in every every 2
or so minutes so Chrome OS Chrome OS is
a good place to start if you're solving
problem if you're solving security
problems on Chrome OS you have you don't
have a lot of other things that you need
to be doing clearly because Chrome OS is
such a hardened platform already and so
we are about 20% Chrome OS at duo and
they're they're managed by G suite and
they're enforced they enforce trusted
dude but with G suite for Chrome OS and
also all of our chrome browsers we
enforce explicit allow for plugins like
Java and flash and basically none of
those as well as Chrome extensions and
then on Chromebooks as well because you
can run Android apps within Chrome we
also enforce explicit allow for Android
apps so we manage all of that through
the G suite console and it's manual for
for plugins because there are very few
that people are asking for and and for
Android apps as well because honestly
although there's a huge Android app
ecosystem at do a very very few people
are actually asking for us to add new
Android apps so Chrome extensions are
the highest volume people want a new
Chrome extension every day and they're
very hard to evaluate so we created a
tool to evaluate in a consistent way
Chrome extensions the team who's adding
the Chrome extensions to our allowed
list is our security operations team
someone sent says I want this Chrome
extension they email the security
operations team they say hey I want to
run Ebates so I can get all of that
money back and so the security
operations team gets that and they can
see it in the Chrome Web Store but
that's really all they had before we
built this tool Chrome extensions are
written in JavaScript our security
operations team isn't necessarily Java
Script experts but even if they were we
wouldn't really want them spending all
of their days like taking apart a
JavaScript Comics
to see what it's doing like the the
permissions are kind of easily available
in a JSON file where you could look
through and see okay well these this URL
means that it needs access to everything
and this URL also means that it needs
access to everything but that's that's a
complicated process but even if everyone
was an expert at doing all of that and
it didn't take them that much time
because they're all humans they're all
going to do it inconsistently so we
wanted to build a tool that allowed our
security operations team to have a
consistent and quantifiable reason for
either approving or denying Chrome
extensions when people asked for them to
be allowed so again we built this
entirely serverless on AWS lambda it's a
react.js front-end and when we started
we decided well we could we could scan
Chrome extensions one at a time or we
could just scan them all right all at
once
and so we said well how many chrome
extensions is that there's about a
hundred and sixty thousand chrome
extensions in the chrome webstore so we
called up our friends at AWS and said
how many lambdas can we run it once
again and we had a few discussions with
them and then finally we hit the Go
button and we scanned all 160,000 chrome
extensions and five minutes later the
tasks had completed and we're like well
what broke but actually we just scanned
the entire Chrome Web Store in five
minutes and so since we've already
scanned all of the extensions we thought
well why don't we just let everyone else
see the reports too so we made this a
free SAS tool that people can use it's
not open source it wouldn't necessarily
be a good idea for us to open source it
it's kind of aggressive against the
Chrome Web Store there aren't some API
so we've done some other things
Google's cool with that but I don't
think they would be cool with us open
sourcing this and saying hey why doesn't
everyone scan all 160,000 Chrome
extensions in the Chrome Web Store every
three hours so we have a closed source
but it is API first because we wrote it
in react so if you don't like our tool
if you don't like
color scheme we have API Docs available
as well so this is something that's
available to you today you can go to
cracks cavae durão which is c RX c AV
8000 r io and you can get started so let
me show you just one of the things that
go excavator does so take for example a
Chrome extension like LastPass we use
LastPass at duo I'm I'm a moderately big
fan of LastPass it's an important tool
password vaults are an important tool
and they should exist as Chrome
extensions that being said for a
password vault to exist as a Chrome
extension it's going to need to be a
little bit risky
so we scanned it with our excavator and
so at the top you can kind of see okay
we pulled some stuff out of the Chrome
Web Store this is convenient to have at
the top here's the picture here's here's
the ratings and things like that nothing
revolutionary but down below you can see
how we've quantified the risk of the
Chrome extension and grouped it into
certain categories and I'll kind of take
you through some of those categories so
at the very top you can see that since
we're standing the chrome webstore every
three hours we know in the versions
change and we can actually plot because
we're quantifying the risk as a number
we can plot the change in risk over time
so you can see after the first version
and there's a funny story there I have
two the first version that we scanned
last passes risk or dropped quite a bit
and so moving on down the page you can
see the first thing that we're most
interested in when it comes to Chrome
extension risk which is permissions so
we list out all of the permissions that
all of the permissions of the Chrome
extension asks for and we've quantified
a risk value this this isn't super
scientific we sat down with Pizza and
determined what are the worst
permissions in terms of exposure that a
chrome extension could ask for and then
which ones are are not as scary Chrome
extensions also have a principle of
optional permissions and we treat those
exactly the same if you're doing
explicit allow and you're allowing a
Chrome extension then you have allowed
the optional permissions and whether
whether or not your end-users are asked
to allow those later
as their element because everyone will
say yes I want to do whatever it is that
you're asking me to do so moving down
the page you'll see this retired JSF
owner ability scan if you haven't used
retire before it scans through
JavaScript projects and looks for
third-party libraries with known
vulnerabilities so it's just really
simple static analysis and we just put
it out on the page and assign risk value
to these as well I have the caveat here
this is not in LastPass now this is that
first version in this line graph where
their risk score was higher and as soon
as we built this tool of course the
first extension we scanned was LastPass
and we said hey did you know that you
have these three vulnerabilities from
your third-party libraries and your
Chrome extension and they said we did
know that we don't use those portions
the vulnerable portions of jQuery and
jQuery UI dialog so technically we're
okay but we will patch this and so we
saw as soon as the next version came out
they did patch it and now it's forever
saved in history and corrects comater
the next thing we look at is the content
security policy and that can restrict
how the Chrome extension can talk to
remote sites for a number of purposes
but the most interesting one is the
connect source because this can kind of
tell you is this Chrome extension
standalone or does it connect with a
sass tool also if you've set up an
organizational account which is free you
can add your virustotal and facebook
thread exchange api keys and you can
scan all of the URLs in the content
security policy to see if they're known
bad and you can also link to SSL labs
reports so if it is SAS and you want to
say ok well like the host this is
probably connecting with is LastPass
comm so let's view the SSL lab score and
make sure that it's you know a plus or
however we want our password vault
communicating with the password vault
server moving down the page it gets a
little bit more technical the further we
go down we look for a list of all the
other possible external communications
even if they're not listed in in the
content security policy the current
version and by the way I should say this
is very beta right now the current
version is a simple red X that looks for
things that look like URLs even if
they're in the comments
that's we'll show it there if they're
broken apart by concatenation we won't
catch that the next a next version
that's coming out of excavator will
actually do AST parsing where it will
see what the javascript is actually
connecting to and will replace this with
something a little bit better below you
can look at the manifest and all of its
glory you can also see if the Chrome
extension is including external
javascript files instead of actually
packaging those javascript files in and
then we can also be entry points and
dangerous functions below that which I
apparently I don't have a screenshot of
we show everything that the Chrome Web
Store says is a related Chrome extension
and again if you've created an
organizational account and you have an
explicit allow list already then not
only will we show you the list of
related extensions but we'll
cross-reference that against the
extensions that you've already allowed
so that means that if someone says hey I
want to run LastPass you can actually
look through and say well we don't have
LastPass yeah but look we have one
password we already have that exposure
in our organization could you use one
password instead of LastPass so our
excavator if you set up an
organizational account you can maintain
your list of allowed Chrome extensions
so you can see if something has been
allowed or if it hasn't and then
cross-reference it with the similar
extensions you can enter your virustotal
and facebook thread exchange keys to and
enrich the content security policy
content you can also deploy a Chrome
extension to every device in your fleet
whether they're on Linux Mac Windows or
Chrome OS and collect all of the Chrome
extensions that they're currently
running this is useful whether or not
you do explicit allow if you don't do
explicit allow this is a great first
step to say what Chrome extensions are
in use today and then you can start from
there and say which of those are risky
and then bill build your allowed list if
you do explicit allow then you can see
what's the popularity like 500 people
use this extension only one person uses
this extension and it looks a little bit
risky maybe we should actually get rid
of it but also in either case if you
wake up in the morning and read that a
very popular Chrome extension like
stylish was solves to a malicious
third-party and now it was stealing data
you can actually find out your exposure
you can say actually we have stylish
installed on these four workstations so
let's go talk to those people you can do
this you can do this with other tools at
CCM will tell you what Chrome extensions
are installed Jeff will tell you what
Chrome extensions are installed OS query
will tell you what Chrome extensions are
installed we built this because we have
we have Chromebooks but also this is a
really simple way to deploy this to a
large fleet of various systems like of
various operating systems and get a
complete list across your entire fleet
of what Chrome extensions are in use
let's see
you can also so if you have if you have
your list of either allowed Chrome
extensions or your list of all of the
Chrome extensions that are run from the
gatherer fleet will also sort those for
you by highest risk Chrome extensions
and most recently updated Chrome
extensions with whatever the Delta is to
the risk score and finally if if you
have explicit allow enabled will show
you which Chrome extensions you have
explicitly allowed that literally no one
is running so you can remove them from
your from your exposure so that's
amazing but why is it in this
presentation everything is about my
winning formula of how it is support
explicit allow right so we built that
too and so the correct screener gathered
a Chrome extension the one that
inventories your Chrome extensions has
another feature so say I want to install
the emoji unicorn theme new tab which
sounds totally legit I go to the Chrome
Web Store and interestingly enough
Chrome extensions can't run on the
Chrome Web Store so I go to a Chrome Web
Store and as I'm going there but before
I go there I see that my history has
been updated that I am going to the
Chrome Web Store for a Chrome extension
that has not yet been explicitly allowed
and so we pop up this notification that
says hey you're not you're about to see
a page and you're not going to be able
to install the extension that's on that
page if I want to install it I can click
the the pop-up and I can go in and enter
my business justification to say hey I
want this emoji unicorn new tab
theme because it looks totally awesome
and hit submit and that's okay well
you'll be notified so it's not not quite
the 30 second remediation yeah but then
in the corrects trader admin panel if
you have an organizational account you
can go in and see here's all of the list
of the people who have requested these
things and then you can go through and
check approved or denied big caveat this
looks like it does it for you
Google has not exposed the API to manage
the Chrome extension allow lists at this
time so this is just for tracking
purposes your analyst or whoever's doing
this will still have to also go into
Google and say hey this is actually been
allowed so I talked a lot about software
in terms of explicit allow but if you
think about it as a concept there's a
lot more things that that you can apply
it to for example networking there's a
lot of talk about zero trust networking
or zero trust access duo duo's using
that in its marketing now - but it's
something that we a duo internally have
been doing for the least five years now
and so essentially the principle is this
if you come to do his office and you
connect to our Wi-Fi you still don't
have access to anything honestly there
aren't that many boxes that are on Prem
but even even when there were more
things on Prem like a wiki or our code
repository things like that after you
got on the Wi-Fi you still needed to get
on a VPN before before you could access
anything but moving that forward moving
that more to the explicit allow module
and here's the product pitch that I told
you I wasn't going to give we have a
product called the duo network gateway
which we originally built internally to
solve a problem for us and so
essentially instead of going through the
connecting to the VPN and then accessing
the resources that you want you just try
to access the resources that you want
and if you're not signed in yet you'll
just be asked to sign in first and in
this process of signing in to the do
network gateway which is just an
authenticated reverse proxy once you
sign in it will figure out what
applications you're authorized to access
and wire up the networking for only
those so you have no net access to to
any of the system's inside duo's network
unless you're explicitly allowed access
through the dual network gateway so this
this is like our modern approach on
networking like in the in the old old
days network security was really easy in
mainframes in consoles your firewall was
made out of cinder blocks it was pretty
simple but as people wanted to start
working on the road and we got to client
server and then cloud and mobile it's
really hard to put a firewall in the way
of in a useful position that protects
all of your assets and furthermore it's
it's difficult to gate access to all of
the apps that you want your users to
access because where your user might be
going to a cloud service from off Prem
and so unless you have an agent on their
workstation and maybe they're using a
mobile device or an agent on the SAS
service which is difficult to do unless
it's at the time of authentication it's
really hard to actually get into that
conversation and have a say in the
security the last thing that we're
working on so this is this is just a
look at the future for us because I'll
be honest we're all friends here the G
suite tenant that I use for Google Apps
is is absolutely haunted I have more
problems with my GC tenant than everyone
else and there was a new feature that
was released a while ago to allow
explicit allow for OAuth grants and it
has never worked in my tenant I know
lots of people who have been able to
work with it and just anything anything
I try to do fails 500s and no one no one
at Google me how to fix it what we
finally got it fixed so we're gonna
we're gonna get back to this but you may
remember a while ago let me see it was
two years ago because I was on paternity
leave for my second son that there was
this well male worm that affected Google
so someone sent and like a phishing
email to Gmail box but instead of asking
for a username and password it presented
them with an elf consent screen that
just asks them to click allow to grant
access to the
contacts and to send mail on their
behalf and if you have an adversarial
mindset and you haven't heard the story
you already know the rest once once that
they had once this program had access to
all of the contents it sent the same
message to everyone else to spread more
and more and more and maybe there was
something malicious that was supposed to
happen as well but it became so
prevalent and widespread a newsworthy
that Google was able to put a put a stop
to it and revoke the revoke the keys to
that client ID but it raised a really
interesting really interesting concern
that Olaf is a type of authentication is
that we're not good at securing or
teaching people how to keep secure we
get people into the anti-phishing
mindset when they're asked for a
password probably and we have lots of
great tools like two-factor
authentication and password managers
that only autofill on the right site but
none of those really help you when
you're presented with an OAuth consent
screen for someone that you already do
business with and like where it says
here like Google API Explorer because I
was trying to get a screenshot really
fast once you access your Google account
like when you create an OAuth app you
can put whatever you want there you can
put duo security there please don't do
that our lawyers will contact you you
can put whatever you want in that field
and there's no real validation and look
at the URL bar its HTTPS it's
accounts.google.com it's all of the
things that we tell our users to look
for but the blue authorize button which
I'm realizing now would have been great
in this screenshot is something that we
don't have people to have people
sufficiently concerned about and so we
want to apply explicit allow to this as
well but again Google gives us the
ability to block unknown olaf's grants
but that's not a great experience so
like many things you can solve it with a
Chrome extension so we've created a
Chrome extension that actually looks for
the OAuth consent block screens so if we
switch to explicit allow and it says hey
sorry you tried to do this but it was
blocked and we'll actually get in
interesting information and send it to
our automation so say hey this person
tried to authorize this client ID and
here are the Scopes that they were
asking for and those are the kind of
things
can find in Google logs kind of already
not if they're blocked but if they do
authorize it but that's missing a key
thing what is it
and with OAuth that's a hard problem to
solve because you can use a client ID in
a number of locations so we also with
this Chrome extension
capture the referrer URI as well so we
can actually see what was it that sent
you to this consent screen to actually
authorize access and with that we have a
complete enough picture to start running
cert intelligence and say okay here's
the risk we associate with send mail on
my behalf or view and review and edit
all contents of Google Drive and we can
do threat intelligence against the refer
URI to say hey this is the site that
referred it this is not a reputable site
or this is a reputable site or this is a
site that we do business with it's gone
through our vendor assessment process
and so we can use that to enrich the
content and have the security analyst
have our security analysts to be able to
say yes this is okay to authorize or no
it's not but in an in a safe way so if
you're thinking about rolling out
explicit allow for anything that I
talked about today or something else
there is a great way to start and I'll
tell you how we did it with Santa on
Macs but this is the process that we've
applied to all of the things that I've
talked about so far if you're not in a
brand-new greenfield environment and you
already have people who are running
software on their computers then deploy
Santa in monitor mode to your entire
fleet or deploy krex conveyed or
gatherer to your entire fleet and get an
entire inventory of everything that
people are running don't go to IT and
ask them what is the software that's
ever that everyone is running that will
be an incomplete list so deploy Santa
collect the entire list of software
that's running run that against threat
intelligence and remove the obvious bad
stuff and then say that's good enough
that is our explicit allow list it might
be a thousand pieces of software but
that's a great place to start because
then the day that you turn it on you do
not lose your job this
yo can still open powerpoints the CFO
can still open Excel and people can open
their games their Ableton mixer whatever
it is that they want to be doing that
will they'll be really mad if they can't
do they'll be able to do it on day one
and then on day two when something new
comes in they get through the process
they start seeing the process of
explicit allowances hey I I want to run
this new software and I need security to
evaluate it and so maybe you can get to
the place where we are where it's
automated and the evaluation happens in
real time for them and they can they can
get their own satisfaction within thirty
seconds but even even if not it's much
easier to start with everything and work
backwards then start with nothing and
have everyone explicitly request access
to everything that they want to run now
for Santa because obviously that still
sounds a little bit terrible right for
Santa and for AppLocker
you can explicitly allow based on the
sha-256 hash or the developer cert so
maybe do ask IT hey what software do you
guys buy and go through and find those
developer search probably on your own
computer you'll probably see most of
them and say ok yep so will authorize
software from Adobe from Cisco Systems
from Microsoft from Apple from whatever
other companies that you're doing
business with so that even if those
those pieces of software update in the
sha-256 256 hash changes people won't
have to re request access to run the
same software that they have been
requesting if developers aren't signing
their binaries which let me tell you a
lot of developers don't sign their
binaries then it will be this process
and that's why it has to be this fast
every time because people are going to
run into this a number of times so I did
statistics and I'm thinking back because
again this would have been great in my
slide deck I did statistics for my boss
last quarter and over the three-month
period I think people interacted with
the Mac explicit allow workflow about
600 times so that's for 800 users
maybe each person did it once per
quarter but I think it's more likely
that several people did it a number of
times a quarter and then a lot of people
didn't see it at all because they're not
downloading new software and other
things are the things that they're
running have already been allowed so
there's just a few things left that we
want to do on the things that we're
working on specifically like we want to
remove some of our external dependencies
to make this more package so maybe we
could share it one day or even just
share it with other business units
within Cisco so like we use slack and we
have slack integrated into some of this
process we have Zendesk integrated into
some of this process but since not
everyone uses it and maybe we won't
always use it duo either we want it to
be entirely self-contained so that well
the santé process uses slack to reach
over the security bot the windows
process is just effective where it's a
pop-up dialog that says hey you tried to
run this yes or no so that doesn't need
to be slack there and then we just want
to build it to scale as as Duo continues
to grow as we share the things that
we've done with Cisco we want this to be
able to scale beyond what what it's
doing right now so we'll continue to
invest in doing it completely serverless
ly with things like lambda and
serverless our RDS and when we have
friend times we'll do lightweight front
ends like react so we can just serve
things out of s3 so let me stop here for
questions and then I totally have like a
couple of minutes to show you a demo
unless we have a lot of questions which
will be even better
yeah
yes so actually probably before they've
even seen the pop up we've already
evaluated against threatened cell
because we can do that fairly quickly
because we don't do Sam vaccine so we do
that and as like as that's completing
the pop-up shows up on the computer but
since that only takes a few seconds it
seems to be instantaneously as we start
to explore how to how sandboxing works
in this metal likely will actually still
allow people to authorize it before the
sandbox completes its run depending on
how long it takes just so that we're
enabling the business even at the even
at the potential of having a few hours
of exposure or something like that but
it's something that we can continue
because it's something that we built
entirely ourselves we can continue to
fine-tune this workflow to whatever our
risk appetite is at the time yeah nope I
have not heard of web proxy
oh so like inside a network what site
people can access versus can't access
now we don't we don't do that I think
there's there's too many different
things that people are trying to access
we want people to be able to access the
games that they like and things like
that we do use umbrella open DNS which
is like the opposite like blacklisting
are explicit and explicit deny where
there is a list of URLs that just won't
resolve because of umbrella and so
that's that's kind of the approach that
we've taken there just because it's such
like it's such a broader like orders of
magnitude that bigger than the number of
applications that we run around our
Chrome extensions that we want around is
the number of websites that we want a
company to be able to visit does that
make sense yes
for the Chrome extensions so all of the
results are posted you can view all of
them at Kirk's kavita IO right now we
are not stating that a Chrome extension
is malicious with Drex go Vader Google
does a great job of actually gating that
for the most part it you can tell
because it's so newsworthy every time
there is a malicious Chrome extension
there's I can think of four examples in
history of malicious chrome extensions
that made the news we were trying to
show what the risk is if a chrome
extension is malicious what it could do
and then businesses can based on their
risk appetite determine whether or not
that's acceptable like I showed LastPass
that's actually a high risk score in
terms of total number of points but the
other part of the story is I've been
doing business with LastPass for years
I've seen them get breached and I've
seen through that how they handle that
I've see I've signed NDA's with them
I've seen their stock too on it so
there's a lot of compensating controls
especially when you're doing business
with the company that makes the Chrome
extension so it's it's hard to say with
the tool that we built this Chrome
extension is malicious that being said
if you find a malicious chrome extension
or excavator is a great way to figure
out more about that malicious Chrome
extension what did you have another
question okay yes yeah
yeah absolutely so there's there's a
couple of ways you can do that the first
is you can continue to view those scan
results via the API we also expose an
RSS feed so you could actually follow
the RSS feed for each Chrome extension
to see as they change but if you create
the Oxford or the Creator enterprise
account and sign into and go to your
dashboard and either you have the
gatherer extension deployed or you have
a list of allowed extensions then you'll
see the list of your extension you'll
see which ones have updated recently and
the Delta in the risk score are right
there to say hey this just updated and
the risk score went up by 500 that's
worth looking at or this just updated
but the risk score remained the same so
maybe you don't actually need to look at
that one yeah absolutely just because
just because we have yesterday's report
and today's report so it's all we're
doing is just comparing the numbers any
other questions yeah so that is half
half of our defense red is whether or
not the user intended to run it and
certainly people will run mackeeper
or something like that right because
they want their Mac to go faster I want
my Mac to go faster so that's why we
have the additional data point of the
threat intelligence so those are the two
things that have to pass before they go
through what we've actually found is a
more a higher false and false positive
false negative rate where people are
saying I didn't mean to run that and
we're raising an incident and then we're
going and saying oh yeah well I know you
didn't mean to run that but that's just
Adobe trying to update Photoshop in the
background or something like that and
there's an unsigned binary yes whoa
not not especially I think maybe duos
too small of a company to have
statistically significant results even
before hand like a compromised machine
like I said was probably just mackeeper
got installed or something like that so
I think I think our sample size is too
small to show a meaningful trend any
other questions yes the Chrome extension
tool could it be adapted to Firefox I
suppose so
I'm not going to pretend that I haven't
been asked that question before after we
had a big launch of correct evader with
press and things like that people have
asked about Firefox extensions but like
I said the things the things that I have
that I've showed you today I have built
for my company and we don't use Firefox
so maybe one day but we have we have
other things we have other problems we
want to solve first any other questions
great well I'm right at time so thanks
so much everyone
[Applause]