your handy dandy PowerShell ISE open and
what I'm gonna be demoing to you now is
how many okay so how many of you are
familiar with internal monologue
okay so internal monologue is
essentially a offensive tool that allows
you to get the current users net ntlm B
to hash from doing an RPC call to LSS
that's the very I butchered that
explanation you should probably take a
look at the github rep oh that explains
it in detail
Elad Shamir did an awesome write-up on
how this actually works so you should
probably take a look at that as well so
what I'm gonna be doing and I'm
embedding the internal monologue DLL
which is a dotnet assembly okay in iron
in iron Python script okay I'm then
taking that iron Python script embedding
that into PowerShell and then I'm
invoking ironpython from PowerShell and
executing the Iron Python script so
that's that's exactly what I'm going to
be showing you and again this is all
possible because all of these all of
these languages and all of these
techniques are based based upon C sharp
and the.net so they're all interoperable
with each other so it doesn't matter
what language you choose as long as it's
a dotnet language you can embed it
within PowerShell you can embed it at
anything you want okay so this is the
internal monologue DLL this is just some
really badly written code that
decompresses the DLL and on base64 is it
we then call assembly that load which is
that magic function that I just talked
to you about which loads it directly
into memory and then we literally just
take we can literally from then on just
call the namespaces that we defined
within that internal monologue DLL and
then execute the actual internal
monologue attack okay and these are the
four deals that I just told you about so
we got the ironpython DLL the microsoft
scripting Microsoft dynamic I'm Python
those get automatically loaded when
PowerShell executed the script and then
down here
we do engine that executes which takes
that ironpython code that I just showed
you and actually executes sit through
powershell europe you're all with me so
far okay
sweet so you execute this and there you
go
so we've executed the powershell script
would then executed ironpython which
then executed the internal monologue dll
and this is my current users net and net
until mb to hash one thing to note about
this particular attack if you were admin
I can actually downgrade it can perform
like a downgrade attack so if I were
admin here and I executed this I would
have gotten in at ntlm v 1 hash which I
can then submit like to services like
cracked SH which basically have created
like every rainbow tables for DES and
you'll automatically instantly get the
clear text password for that hash which
i think is really really cool alright so
that's just one example of and yeah and
just bear with me because it's gonna get
weirder that's just one example of like
embedding payloads within one another
right so let's talk about pooling now
because by far
boo Lang in my opinion is the most
useful of these languages for offensive
purposes for a mostly a couple of
reasons one their documentation is
awesome which is very rare to find in
these languages
ironpython is not as well-documented as
bullying and considering nobody has ever
heard about bullying before that is
amazing you can find it at that at that
link at github and the reason why I like
it so much too is because it's basically
like if Python and c-sharp had a baby
and that's boo lang
so it's heavily inspired by Python
syntax and you can do basically it you
can just call c-sharp net api's directly
through lang and this is an example code
hopefully you can all read that if not
i'll be showing it to you bigger in the
demo
got so hopefully you'll read that but in
this example code what we're doing is
we're calling the mini dump right dump
function which allows us to dump memory
and specifically we're dumping the elf
SAS process here so we're manually
dumping memory of the alsace process
through the mini dump right thumb
function which is a native function that
you can use to dump memory and then you
can take that dump file and then parse
it offline with me me cats to get clear
text credentials from that okay so this
is a perfect example of like how to
weaponize this stuff the best part about
Lu Lang and this is a really really big
deal is that it can call native
functions but those native functions are
all truly in-memory okay so like for
example if you called add type in
PowerShell it will leave artifacts on
disks not with bool and if you call
native function with blank
everything is done in memory everything
is truly in memory and you can still
call native function so this is the
equivalent of basically compiling
c-sharp through Roselyn if you're
familiar with that
Roselyn is a way of dynamically
compiling c-sharp and accessing it on
the fly this is a the equivalent of
doing it with rosin only that it's in
Python and well somewhat Python so like
a hybrid and it's a scripting language
which is in my mind it's a sort of a big
deal so again these you can get these
examples some of the demos I'm about to
show you from that and one repo under
run bouth that's CS which is the c-sharp
version so we're embedding bula and
c-sharp in that one and then invoke
jump-scare that ps1 I thought that was
kind of cute because you know boo VOC
jump-scare okay only me I guess okay so
and then we're embedding boo in into
PowerShell and then we're gonna in this
particular case that I'm gonna die in
this demo I'm going to show you now
we're injecting shell code through boo
to pop calc because we all got a pop cow
and also okay boo requires three dotnet
assemblies to run so you got boo lying
that DLL blue line that compiler that
DLL blowing that parser that DLL so this
is this is again this is like where my
knowledge of this is a part of this I
still don't completely understand how
this is possible but technically boolong
that the boo Lang requires those three
Assemblies but when you compile it
through the actual compiler which I'm
gonna be talking to you in about in a
second
it doesn't need those I'm not exactly
sure why but if you embed it it does
require those if you compile it it
doesn't and it doesn't embed the DLL and
to do anything like that because I
disassembled it I'm not exactly sure why
this works but that's just something to
know and it's a very important thing to
note because there's other implications
to that whatever been talking about in a
second so in PowerShell
you literally just call assembly that
load on those three dll's and that's all
you really need to do to embed boolong
and PowerShell and in c-sharp you could
just hook the assembly that resolve
event and then at that point your worlds
your world's your oyster so I'm gonna be
downloading a pulang payload right now
let's see here okay so okay fine I'm
gonna go over here go into here
PowerShell window oh boy
okay make this huge okay so I got my
invoke jump-scare script here I'm gonna
import that into my powershell session
and actually it let's before I do that
let's take a look at the code here so
we're completely understanding what I'm
doing
and though jump-scare okay so we got our
three dll's
tubulin dll's this is just shellcode
that I got from MSM venom which pops
calc it's pretty straightforward once we
load those three dll's we then have
access to the bulan compiler it's it
does compile stuff in like it's an
engine but they call it bullet and
compiler so that's just yeah you'll find
that - like the terminology varies from
language to language so in this
particular case I am executing blue line
code from a separate file on this right
but you don't even need to do that you
can actually embed like the arm Python
example that I just showed you the blue
line code within powershell itself and
then you just a couple of statements
here that just says hey i want to
compile it in memory don't eat don't do
anything on disk and then you run the
assembly and then you call the main
function of the blue line code which
executes s-- the actual shell code okay
so let's do that real quick invokes
jump-scare and then you should pass it
if I recall correctly the just nothing
okay let's just try let's just try that
compiling executing and then there's
countdown here
and there you go so you can see from the
output here like it took the blank
source code compiled that executed it
injected it in memory using one of the
it there's like three method in shell
code injection methods in that one blue
line file which we can actually take a
look at real quick so you can see that
it's actually pretty pretty similar to
what you'd expect from Python quick
there you go so we just defined a class
this is all blue line a blue line class
we import all of the native methods that
we need to inject shell code this isn't
using it like the cue user EPC if you're
familiar with a that's one method of
injecting shell code they make up the
inject self and then we got the inject
remote so depending on what method you
want to inject you can choose one of
those and again like you don't need to
have this on a separate file you can
just embed it in the PowerShell script
itself so I think that's pretty cool and
it's also really weird and again let's
just there's a reminder the reason why
we're doing this in the first place is
because there is no insight into the
dotnet framework right there's no way of
hooking into with like exception of a
couple of things like etw hooking into
the dotnet framework to view all of
these all of this dynamic code that's
being run okay so you can take the power
of powershell embed it with another
language and just get around all that
usually it should be it's just it really
is as straightforward as that as of
right now at least so clear script clear
script there's a fun one actually
discovered this last month and it's an
official Microsoft project so clear
script is literally made from the
description it literally is made to add
scripting capabilities to your dotnet
program okay
so what's very very interesting about
this though is that you can call J
script and VB script from clear script
if that makes sense so by default on
Windows you can access J script and V
script from powershell you can do it
through windows script host thing but
using
script for some reason it seems like
it's not doing any of that and uses its
own runtime to parse jscript and
vbscript what that means is that Windows
Defender for example at least from what
I understand about it as of right now
and from what I've seen is not able to
detect like the squiggly - if doobly-doo
attack if you're familiar with that sub
T's work basically you're downloading an
SCT file using jscript it is not able to
detect any of that because there are no
cooks in place right now in order for AM
Z to actually get in there and inspect
what you're doing through embedded
jscript to clear scripts okay it also
supports the v8 high-performance
JavaScript engine which is also really
interesting but he needs a lot more
simplest for that and this is like an
example of some c-sharp code that you
can use to embed clear script within
c-sharp and we're just calling like W
script shell ActiveX objects W scripts
shoulder which will execute a command
and I'm gonna be demoing a clear script
PowerShell payload right now that
basically downloads a squiggly-doo
squiggly-doo file a CT file ok and loads
that in memory and pops notepad so that
you get an you get an idea of like the
capabilities of this thing what's really
interesting though is that you can
expose the entire CLR to jscript
using this way so what that means is
that you can now call native functions
from G script through clear scripts if
that makes sense and there's a lot of
power from if I do get that working one
day there's a lot of power there because
that would be as if you had like a
dotnet to js4 any of the red teamers and
I know what that meant to Jas is it's
basically a way of calling c-sharp from
J script and usually we use something
from the James Forshaw which implemented
this tool that allows you to do that but
with this method you would be using like
a Microsoft utility to go about doing
that which would sort of be I think a
big deal I'm not exactly sure if like if
I'm thinking about this right but
it's still an interesting way of going
about it so I'm just gonna demo that
real quick wrong one but okay hold on
alright so I got my little HTTP server
up here I'm going to go back to my
PowerShell ISE script go to invoke clear
scripts so we're embedding you download
clear script again this is all open
source downloads true could compile it
embed it load the assembly and then you
have access to this clear script engine
you can also call VB script from kinship
in this case I'm just using J script
yeah the words are flying I know and
we're calling get object which allows us
to download that payload which I'm
hosting on a HTTP server and this
hopefully won't trigger MZ
and there you go pop notepad and just to
give you an idea so like okay so that's
doing it this way right what happens if
I try doing that just straight up with
PowerShell what would happen then I am
there's no way I'm typing that out live
so I copy pasting this and there you go
malicious script has been blocked by
your antivirus software so by going like
sort of by embedding clear script within
PowerShell we get around AM Z but if we
just straight-up called a script from
PowerShell and downloaded that file it
gets blocked by the AV so this is this
is where I'm trying to go with this
right so we're sort of operational we're
trying to get around like the
operational downsides of using C sharp
tradecraft and going back to using
PowerShell only not executing our
malicious code with PowerShell but with
an embedded language if that makes sense
let's go back to the presentation and
also how much time do I have left
okay all right I'm gonna try to go
somewhat fast okay so these are all of
the dotnet languages third party thought
new languages that I am aware of as of
right now and there's some really
interesting ones so if you like coding
in Lua for example moon sharp and and
Lua or your friend because you can embed
the Lua programming language within
powershell for example if you wanted to
jint is another github project that
allows you to bet JavaScript within
powershell well it's really interesting
this is something I'm not experimented
with yet so I'll leave this as an
exercise to you because I don't know
what will happen I'm assuming it won't
work but it would be really interesting
to see what would happen if you threw a
beef hook at an embedded JavaScript
runtime and PowerShell I'm assuming it
would break because it's not a browser
but it still would be interesting it
would be interesting to experiment with
like the concept of beefing endpoints I
think it's interesting dotnet web
assembly this is something I'm gonna be
keeping a close eye on allows you to
execute web assemblies in memory through
net how crazy is that
I yeah don't even ask how this works
because I have no clue and yeah what was
similes in general I think is gonna be
an interesting thing going forward from
a red team perspective because I still
have to read up on it and how everything
works there but I think it's gonna be
there's a lot of shenanigans that you
could probably pull it with some web
assemblies clear script jscript bb's tip
in JavaScript so if you want to embed
those languages clear script is also
something that you can use ironpython to
python - there's arm Python 3 which is
still being worked on do not use it yet
because it's not stable at all but
Python that you can embed Python 3
once that gets stable in net there's
also Ruby whatever one embed Ruby there
you go and then boola-boola is my farm
though I think the most useful out of
all of these as of right now so here's
something I've never talked about before
publicly these languages come built in
with a compiler so every so usually all
these languages have a standalone
compiler what that means is that you can
take any script and just compile it
directly through the compiler they
provide and then you can take that
compiled code like compile executable
and run it everywhere and it doesn't
matter what dotnet version is installed
it'll just run everywhere because it
compiles it in intermediate language
code which means it'll just run dotnet
to.net 4.0 it'll just run everywhere so
this is by far the easiest way to
compile and run your dotnet code and i
have okay i'm gonna demo this for you
real quick so like if you don't want to
embed stuff and just want to weaponize a
real like a real quick blank script that
you wrote this is the way to do it this
is probably the way to do it because you
don't have to you don't have to deal
with the dll's you don't have to deal
with embedding it with the resolving the
dll's at runtime it's just pretty simple
so I have my mini dump code here which I
showed you before okay and this dumps
else asks memory ok straight up just
calls mini dump right up and just dull
and just dumps else has memory to a file
on disk right so what I want to be doing
real quick is I'm gonna be modifying
this in order to get it to compile so
I'm going to make this a static function
in order and that's going to be the
compilers entry point because that's
just how bullying works I also have to
actually call that function somewhere
and I'm gonna give it the arguments that
we pass on the command line
right so when this gets executed it'll
go into the main function it's gonna the
main functions going to receive the
arguments that we pass through it and
over here I am just going to say hey the
main function needs to accept the
arguments as a string array
pretty simple and then down here I'm
gonna say hey I want you to take the
first argument and use that as the dump
file name it's pretty simple right so we
now have our code let's go over to the
folder where I have gulang I'm gonna
open the PowerShell window here and it's
perfect that's awesome
and now I am going to use the bulan
compiler which is not who i see but as
buu see that XE and if you take a look
at the help menu here you'll see that it
has a lot of interesting a lot of
interesting options one of them is you
can embed entire directories you can
embed arbitrary data you can also select
the platform to compile to and those are
pretty much all the interesting
functions that I would say oh and you
can also set the target file so if you
wanted to compile to a win X E or an X E
or like a DLL you can do that through -
through the compiler as well so I'm
going to specify that oh and I'm gonna
say the compiled output should be mem
dump that XZ and then I'm going to give
it the path to my code
that I just got that I just modified
here if I remember where it is desktop
and then mini dum p2 and there you go
that's warning it's fine ignore that
that's just because I'm bad at coding
and we have mem Dom that XE ready to go
so there you go
so that's our compiled executable from
boolean code right so I just want to
point this out like if you have to do
this with c-sharp it would take a lot
more time to do this with c-sharp
because I just edited a bhoot something
through sublime text as opposed to
installing Visual Studio getting
familiar with Visual Studio getting
familiar with c-sharp and then getting
this ready so it's a lot lot faster and
easier and allows you to like write
really quick payloads on the fly that
will just run everywhere and just to
give you an idea that this works I guess
ok let's do it this way let's power
shows admin because I need that to dump
memory perfect
okay
we have our memnon program here and
we're gonna give it converge perfect dum
to converge that dump and if we go to
see the see folder here you can see that
we have our memory dump down here forty
megabytes which is pretty standard for
memory dump so there you go
so we've dump memory using boo lang
which is the this is a lot faster than
going through visual studio and doing
all of that in c-sharp and again if you
take that and run it on a Windows 7
machine it'll or two because is not
embedded you've compiled it through the
standalone compile and it'll work
everywhere okay so weaponizing boo let's
check the time here because okay I'm
pushing it I don't think I'll have time
to done with this for you now but silent
Trinity is a project that I've written
that tries to weaponize a lot of these
concepts so this is the c2 framework
that I've built and essentially right
now it uses bullying and ironpython a
combination of both in order to actually
run code in memory and there's a bunch
of modules that would be interesting
like if you do check it out there's a
Mimi Katz module which is pretty crazy
because it basically runs Mimi cats
through an embedded ironpython engine
which is embedded in PowerShell and then
there's another stager that uses the MS
build whitelisting technique it familiar
that so if that's embedding c-sharp with
an MS build file which is in building
which is embedding ironpython
which is then running Mimi cats it's
pretty crazy but and it works I can't
like surprisingly well so definitely
check that out I've recently released
recently like a few months ago an update
for it it's gotten from the beer where
stage two alpha so like things actually
work now which is good I also all the c2
comms are encrypted using elliptic curve
diffie-hellman key exchange with H Mac
so it's pretty it's pretty solid on the
crypto side now it also has boo lang
support so that allows us to call
native methods directly from the situ
from the actual situ framework which is
really good so if you can take
screenshots we can dump memory we can do
all the stuff that I just showed you
right now right
also tab completes everything and you
can customize the check-in interval and
there's now help menu function which you
know that comes in handy so let's talk
about detection a bit probably the best
way to go about detecting this is
upgrading to dotnet 4.8 I think recently
it came out of beta if I recall
correctly so you can actually put
probably put this in production right
now the problem is anything less than
dotnet 4.8 does not have an g
integration and dotnet 4.5 and this is
installed on every Windows 10 machine in
existence so unless you manually update
all of your endpoints net version you're
not going to have the AM Z hooks
necessary for it to try to detect this
kind of stuff and again this is am G
right so it's signature based detection
for the most part so you have to take
that with a sort of a grain of salt as
well in terms of like detecting this
there's also a bunch of projects which
have come out thankfully to actually try
to get data on all of this on all of the
c-sharp tradecraft and which would allow
you to detect some of this stuff as well
so there's like collect net events for
manifestation which is like proof of
concept PowerShell code that you can use
to detect etw logs which is basically
the only known way I think that would
allow you to collect this type of
information
there's also crabs in DW which is
official Microsoft Project is this C++
wrapper on etw but it's sort of like
it's a wrapper so you'd have to actually
build your own tool there's that silky
DWO has come out recently from fireEye
which is a really good option it's by
far I think the most usable detection
mechanism out there right now module
monitor by a friend of mine the wove or
he's got some really cool stuff he
recently released donut which is
essentially a way of taking a dotnet
assembly and turning that into
which is really really interesting you
should take that check that out when you
have a chance but he also has another
thing called madhya monitor which allows
you to get the data from etw itself and
see what's being loaded into this
current the process that it's running
CLR the actual net runtime so there's
there's ways around that there's also
this awesome talk by Luke Jennings at
blackhat eighteen memory resident
implant code injections is alive as well
as an awesome resource and counter cept
actually released a blog about hunting
for silent Trinity so like did they they
put together a bunch of detection that
you could probably use in an environment
right now
to detect the sound Trinity framework
that I released so there's that oh well
and big thanks to copper that I owe that
compiled a lot of these resources as
well but by far I think like the best
way to go about detecting this stuff is
etw logs and upgrading your your net
version that is I think at least from my
knowledge right now that is by far the
best way also a really dead giveaway is
so if you're not familiar with process
Explorer sysinternals process Explorer
it actually allows you to monitor
assemblies loaded in current net
processes right so this is the app
domain of a silent Trinity stager that's
running in memory you can clearly see
that's fancy isn't it okay you can
clearly see that the assembly boolong
assemblies and the ironpython assemblies
are first of all there but also they
don't have an image backing so that
means that they've been loaded in memory
so I think that is by far like a really
good giveaway in terms of just like
c-sharp tradecraft in general I'm not
exactly sure if there is a way of
detecting if a current loaded assemblies
or don't have an image backing on disk
but this is by far dead giveaway and
also like you know silent Trinity that's
that's pretty that's pretty obvious but
I think like in terms of detecting this
stuff this is probably a really good way
because I'm not a dotnet developer so I
can't really speak to this but I'm not
exactly aware of a lot of dotnet
programs that actually load stuff
from memory so this should not be a
behavior that you commonly see so I
think that that might be a pretty solid
detection mechanism by itself also I'm
in the middle of a complete rewrite of
the tool because I hate myself so
basically I'm going to be writing this
thing from scratch it's gonna be team
server base so if you're in the cobalt
strike it's gonna be using WebSockets
gonna be multi server multi client
support it's going to be using
WebSockets for real-time communication
between the server and the client it's
gonna have a lot more comms I actually
have domain DNS or HTTP working as a
communication method for the c2 implant
which is I think it's really cool
also WMI so if you're on an internal
pentest WMI comes in handy as a c2
mechanism where like they firewall their
endpoints or they don't allow HTTP
traffic so I got that and domain DNS
over HTTP 80% their long term goal is to
integrate a bunch of other tools that
I've written over the years so that you
have a single tool that can manage your
infrastructure and that you can manage
your internal pentest with I think that
would be a really cool thing to have so
you'd have Red Baron and crack map exec
that would be integrated within this
tool and you'd use it as a single tool
to manage everything internal
credentials journals Frank spraying
credentials infrastructure deployment
for red team's that is the long-term
goal that is the pipe dream we'll see
how far I get it to go that way and also
Empire Metasploit compatibility would be
really cool if I get a time around it
and also some of the specter ops stuff
that they released recently I'd love to
get that to work through the sound
Trinity team server at least that would
be interesting to see if I can get that
going and also support from our
languages because it's really cool that
you can just embed whatever language you
want right so if your friend writes a
Lua post exploitation script for some
reason you can just use that within this
framework and you're good to go you want
you have a friend that writes ruby
perfect and better like get compromised
endpoint with a ruby sign on Trinity
agent and you can run Ruby scripts that
do all the post exploitation stuff we
have a lone love and
you can pillage all things questions
alrighty okay thank you
[Applause]