thank you thank you so much so and first
of all hello to the amazing Portuguese
intersect community it's a pleasure to
speak here and the very first thing that
I want to say is like thanks a lot to
all the organizers you are doing an
amazing job thank you so much
all right and to kick it off yeah it's
about pentas deep dive we are looking at
a cloud backup software maybe you read
it already on the schedule just to tell
you a little bit about me so I'm a
technical project manager team lead at
Cobalt we are fantastic as a service
company so we are doing penthouse using
a freelancer network of around about
like 270 pen testers and I'm one of them
like in my free time I'm doing pen
testing in my day to day I'm leading the
operations department and yeah I'm also
an information security researcher I'm a
pen tester I'm a public speaker I'm
usually speaking at emphasized
conferences sharing my research yeah and
I have around about like nine years
experience in information security so
and let's see what is on our to-do list
so on our to-do list today is since it's
like the whole story of a pen test it
start with the scope it continues with
reconnaissance
then it goes to the exploitation part
the fun part and looking a little bit
into remediation this will be a little
bit more generic and then I'll keep it
open for questions and I hope you do
have some so let's start with the
disclaimer that's the boring part I'm
sorry
so cobalt doesn't share any
vulnerability information or publishes
any vulnerability for information the
following content that you'll see is all
my research and is not associated to
COBOL at all the company that I'll talk
about like in the next few seconds was
contacted and they have access to all
vulnerability details
unfortunately they didn't really care
that much so I didn't get a read
received nobody replied so responsible
disclosure was attempt
unfortunately it didn't work away so
let's have a look at the scope and we
are talking about a vulnerable limited
so that vulnerable limited is a company
they deployed AWS their internal network
in AWS like most of my clients nowadays
they really like to go into cloud
because of cloud a sip close cool
everybody loved that and it also easy to
manage you can like scale as we grow and
stuff like that you don't have to buy
servers that's all the stuff that you
have to buy stuff and you have put money
on it that's really cool on AWS so the
client was particularly interested and
yeah checking out if or assuming I'm
sorry
assuming that attackers gain access
through a compromised web server like
yeah the web application there that can
be anything that can be an online shop
that can be no idea in newspaper sites
or some content management system maybe
like a bird press or something so and
imagine that gets now compromised that
web server is deployed on your internal
network so and externally reachable so
with access on that on their web server
you can now like spread out through the
whole internal network so it's
essentially an internal network
assessment on the cloud basically so and
the goal of the assessment was to get
access to sensitive data as always so on
how do you do that you start with recon
sense and the one thing that is pretty
cool when you're dealing with pretty
large internal networks you want to get
something to look at pretty soon so you
start of course a map I mean everybody
starts at the end map and then you start
with a curtain to get some screenshots
to get like pictures that you can look
at where you can easily spot ok that's a
tomcat and if we see a tomcat and I
think everybody here at rise of foster
default credentials and the 99% of the
case that it works
that's it was not that easy that were at
that time and of course we go but
Metasploit just to go like with the
really really really low hanging fruit
like eternal blue usually always works
yeah that's how it started here also and
that's a cool map that a Croatoan
actually then generates when you when
you do that when you do the expert on
the scan so it's you see like hot spots
and they are like similar so when when
you have Hollis your group by and you
it's a little bit it's a little bit more
bold here then you see they are related
so they made my share like the same
software components they might be able
all it might be all tomcat servers or
all the press servers or something so
it's a little bit cool grouping and it
also it's kind of fancy I mean I like it
yeah then it gives also a little bit
more into detail about the actual
services that are found so you can then
scroll through and look at the services
and yeah that's that's the thing that
we'll talk about today
it's the cementum management console and
it's a mana management console when you
look at it I think it feels a little bit
like like it really early days of the
internet it could use the designer I
think and so it's built on Apache and
it's really really agency so and that's
also something that expert one actually
really does a good job at so at this
place you like the HTTP code this place
you this web server that is used and
then some components that web server is
using you can of course then dive into
details like it captures also like the
HTTP request headers and stuff like that
so if you want to get a little bit more
into that you can do that but it's not
really needed at all that picture
already caught my attention and now we
have it a little bit bigger yeah so
that's basically that's basically the
Internet and you log in interface you
log in under the username and a password
and then you have some check boxes that
you can check to automate some of the
actions when you when you log in and
then there are some links to they have
forums and stuff and
yeah that's basically blog on page so on
just to have a little bit over this
explanation what that actually does so
the cement management console is
actually yeah the management interface
of semantical backup and some in the
cloud backup is a software solution to
backup your internal network to various
cloud backup solutions like you can
backup to s3 buckets you can backup to
Google Cloud you can backup wherever you
want basically and Samana is basically
automating that so and obviously if you
want to upload all of that data to the
cloud you have to get that software
access to your cloud credentials and
that's a juicy part we'll look into that
later so but first of all let's just
Google so we go get a little bit for it
and have a look or any default
credentials because that's usually the
first thing that you do when you see
like an login login form and you're
always wondering did they actually
change the default credentials and yeah
of course not
so the default credentials are admin
admin I think that's very creative and
yeah so they also documented on their
dock on their public documentation so
that's pretty cool it's basically the
first Google result so and after trying
them out you are basically in and it
looks like that so then you're basically
going through that and have a little
look about what's available here and of
course you are looking for secret keys
you're looking for all sorts of
configuration files you're looking for
features that are interesting like stuff
like can you maybe execute comments can
you maybe load configuration files
what about like reporting can you export
something or maybe CSV import export
features can you generate PDF files
stuff like that because you always have
to remember that things deploy on
Macleod and it has the ability to choir
to speak to AWS metadata endpoint and
then you can extract even more keys so
even more keys then they the keys that
you already got
- right now so now you already have some
cool areas secret keys you import them
to the next tool that you that you have
to evaluate a little bit what you have
access to maybe those keys are now
you're all ready to execute code if
you're lucky in that case I was not but
you are going of course a little bit
further and you want to look a little
bit what other features are available so
when I was a cool feature that's in the
Advanced tab of it and that feature
allowed to execute execute comments I
think that's some sort of debug feature
that they want to have and it's also
very dangerous so you see it's like
experts only and since I'm an expert I
looked at that of course and it's they
also like display like behind their only
non interactive comments all out they're
very boring so you don't only want to
get restricted to the comments that you
can execute here and I was thinking okay
what happens if a provider for an input
yeah first of all a little bit sad
because it didn't work that way and I
could really only execute the comments
that were vital sit there but there's
always another way so what happens if
you pipe the output of a comment into
another comment what gets then executed
and you see here the second comment gets
executed so that's cool but the second
comment is actually not even whitelisted
so that's working now but what happens
if you do something like that so now we
have a cure request that requests secret
keys of that that AWS metadata endpoint
and that's not even allowed cool you
can't even access people because that
not whitelisted so now you have access
to even more secret keys that's cool but
you want to get code execution like real
code execution
and how do you do that well yeah you
build some sort of crap comment that you
put in front of like you echo like an A
or something or whatever character you
want to have something that you can just
ignore and then you pipe private
basically and to like something that
tree hits your reverse shell and at that
case it's like a Python comment I'm sure
they're like 200 million other ways to
do that that's just the most reliable
and it worked perfectly so if you
execute that you get in my shell and now
you have basically excess code execution
excess on that code management backup
server and that's pretty cool now so but
the thing is you're a little bit limited
I mean there are default credentials
what if somebody changes them that's
pretty that's pretty sad and and you
also can't really automate that attack
that's also not cool so but maybe if
they don't change the default
credentials you can automate it some
sort so there are some prerequisites
like for example you have to know the IP
address of the server that's also
something which is not ideal if you want
to automate it and recognize it you have
to rely on that they changed actually
that it didn't change the default
credentials something that usually
really works because nobody does that
and yeah if you chained it all together
you can basically lock somebody in
because you can't really rely on that
you the user that you social engineers
actually authenticated often the cases
that you target some sort of network
engineer that has no simple clue about
that service so you want to make sure
that just by clicking on a simple link
that network engineer with access to the
internal network compromised the stat
server so and you have to rely on
default credentials now and you have to
know the IP address
I always then it's working really really
really cool so the proof of concept of
write up is available on github like not
right now
but seconds after their talk but now we
are talking a little bit more about
automating stuff so knowledge over the
IP address now that's a little bit of a
tricky one
so you want to have like a proof of
concept that scans you whole internal
network for IP addresses or hosts that
are active and then basically checks if
those servers that are up are basically
some indirect code management software
hosting fault management software so how
do you do that so there are some cool
guys that really do amazing research
around that like Skylands of matthew ohm
they now if you own developed something
called J as reckon that's a pretty cool
tool and that allows using WebSockets to
scan the internal network and you can it
works with basically with timing timing
attacks so you can that you can build up
like a WebSocket connection to an
arbitrary port and depending on how fast
the ready the very state changes you can
guess if that's open if that's filter or
closed and that all you really need to
know because once we know that service
is actually online you can start with
just picking any file any static file
that you can find on that website
maybe the logo the logo for cement that
works just great or any other picture of
file that is pretty unique to that
service and then you hard-code that in
and then you set up no idea you can set
up like an iframe or an image tag to it
just add like an event handler to that
and let it call let it do something if
it's if it creates an error or not so
any of you do that that works pretty a
pretty amazing and I have a little demo
how that's working for IOT cameras I
hope that the video is actually loading
and it is loading nice so that's my
prior research about IOT devices and
that's basically me implementing that
whole attack for IOT camera it's an HTTP
request baseball mobility it's a common
injection and you see now
network is scanned in the background
once the device is found the militias
request is fired and now you got code
execution let's wait a little bit until
the tailored service is up and there you
go so that's the cool thing now since
when you when you keep that in mind you
can recognize every single IOT attack
that is like HTTP request based so like
it's like if it's a get request if it's
a post request doesn't really matter you
built that using WebSockets you build
some sort of fingerprinting in there so
you can even have like a whole attack
framework here you can build that for
IOT devices like in this case it was a
CCTV camera we can build in there like
the cement a bear and backup management
software and you can like if you build
modules for that you can have a pretty
nice attack framework where you just
have to trick somebody to with it that
side so and maybe you notice that in
that in that video that's the only
little downside of that is that once
that scan is running if you have a large
network that takes time so and you have
to trick the user into actually doing
something that doesn't bore them so you
have to provide them a video or a song
or something that they read imagine you
can also combine it with a cross-site
scripting vulnerability and combine it
with a watering hole attack maybe you
know that your network engineers they
read a specific newspaper every single
morning or something like that and you
find a web application vulnerability
there you inject that malicious
JavaScript code and it's running in the
background usually they probably won't
finish the article in like 10 seconds
hopefully if it's interesting so and if
they stay long enough on that that is
totally totally enough to scan your
network so then getting to the
remediation advice here I mean always
change your default credentials I'm
sorry that's not rocket science but it's
pretty obvious and still people don't do
it then the patch management policy
would be really really helpful so if you
deploy some weird cloud management
software onion at work make sure that
you actually
that's always a nice recommendation to
and them I think the last one is pretty
cool that you can actually ask for pen
test reports to every single time that
your company purchases software or they
want to deploy something like push push
them and ask them for yeah the last pen
test report did they ever do like a
security assessment did they ever try to
to show yeah if they actually care about
security make it part of the whole sales
process so if you want to if you want to
buy a tool tell your procurement
department if there's no painters report
I'm sorry won't buy and that would be a
cool cool idea already
and then don't only request the
panther's report send it to your
security guys or to somebody who knows
it and let them interpret dependents
report if that's looking really really
bad maybe consider another vendor there
are so many you don't have to go with
the first one so yeah and that's
basically it if there are any questions
I'm more than happy to answer them
[Music]
[Applause]