focus Kristi better not ready sup
so hi welcome to our talk on teaching
kids program inside of scary I'm darling
tere naam Samson ooh I worker dealing in
this product 30 logo de barros where
sheffield hallam university students
there we've studied computer secure with
forensics we're also part of this
diamond bar for this program which is
one bystander so some mentioned stamina
if the organisation run to the semi
master program obviously stem stands for
science technology engineering math so
we're going local schools do activities
we do gear nine option evenings lots of
advice and part of these things is easy
pc which something to mention so you
know so laughter a link September we
opened the business for easy peasy which
is short for early computer from the
clock our main objective was to go into
schools and teach primary kids
programming using schools using tools
like scratch Cotto oil etc and it was
one of an after school activity rather
than just lucky so our son mentioned we
start this in September last year as a
university project myself and salmon
three other students I manage it we've
been getting a lot of interest with
sword groaning to just this big project
we've got loads of schools in South
Yorkshire at all we've been getting a
lot of interest but also we did it into
a BBC Radio Sheffield a couple of months
ago which was huge and getting is
involved so
so we also part of the National Science
energy engineering week where we went to
school we did a one-hour talk with
primary kids and you basically try to
get them engaged in the program we talk
about the basics of rowing and did some
point exercises games etc so we use
tools like scratch we hooked up the xbox
360 Kinect with it we didn't bring that
here today we just want to show one of
the things we did with that arduino best
blog we also mentioned boops a beloved
lacy one of the world's first program is
in the eighteen hundreds technically and
how women were quite prominent actually
in programming so trying to get girls
interested in this as well we think
that's really important someone mentions
you are signs week a little bit briefly
what we did we did these with activities
such as the one we're about to show you
and we've got some images from that well
so this is often scientific where we
actually want to do schools and the
first 100 kids and we went to exercise
in Widow and they're their own little
Marcus where we you know they can follow
tutorials and they were making games
using if statements lumatek cetera it's
just one of the several talks we did
have a video but we couldn't get
permission from the parents for the kids
so we're going to show that but those
massages i'm going to show you the demo
now
so this is one of the tools we use to
get kids engaged so just a little bit of
back on before I start it it's a make
you scott and maki maki its best on an
arduino leonardo bootloader and all it
does is probably plug in crocodile clips
to certain keys on the keyboard I don't
hear what we do is we show them on this
on the screen what a certain sort of
like been driven programming and we show
them like so what does what does each
key do it plays a no so if i go to see
which is the octal a pleasant noise on
the laptop you trust your key and we
talked about all the logical so how it
changes the logical concept of
programming it changes the costume and
left and but before we do that with them
we actually so you hurt yourself I knew
it wouldn't work one engine stopped
imagine there we go and usually works
quite well well this morning didn't very
well that one's not connected sorry
and that's what we do with kids it gets
them really interested in it and there's
so many things you could do with it we
had self pac-man with some blue tuck and
you can do an up-down left-right I'm
when they press it and the birth
themselves they can play pacman so it's
really interesting so we played for a
while then we teach them the code behind
it that's the idea ok all right so why
are we doing this and I don't want to
bore you with loads of from the Nats
from the national curriculum in England
framework this is coming to place in
September 2014 and it's replacing the
ICT subjects for air to call computing
and be learning programming that's the
theory behind it so this is the key
stage 2 framework and basically kids
will be learning coding or using cuticle
kids will be learning log in to the
basics of programs have to be programs
how they simply work they're also be
learning a lot simple networks and the
world wide web and how to use browsers
to get data etc again breaking the rule
of loads of text on the screen but this
is Key Stage three the key point we took
away from it were secondary school is
Key Stage three sort of been doing
boolean logic and doors or not so that's
sort of going to electronical engineer
as well but also as the main concepts of
program as well and to textual programs
it's supposed to use and so pythons of
in walnut a lot of schools using nothing
that's really cool I'll university
should start using that move from C++ to
python and also binary digits so this is
the plan but there is a big problem so
we did a lot of research to do this and
we looked into a lot with us and we were
to academic anchorwoman report and if
you for the next slide these are one
reports we looked at this is the uk's
cyber strategy landscape
by the National audiobus last one in
terms of text on the screen a shortage
of ICT with focusing on cybersecurity
and how we think is gonna be a shortage
of ICT skills and IT skills and kids
understand how a computer works and
that's gonna affect cybersecurity so
trying to get kids more involved with
that younger age that's not the only
problem thinking many other problems is
that I'm in the government and the all
the education initiative they are trying
to push the national curriculum into
school but the problem is not with them
is with the teachers make the cat can
teachers really teach computer science
the answer would be no I mean often it
all research into this and they are
officially many statement that there's a
skills shortage amount ICT teachers and
they don't really know a lot about
computer science they're used to
teaching Boyle closes in packages
databases presentations etc so it is
considered a big issue so means some
compared our education we did ICT never
got any guidance in programming it was
all off my own back and Sam's on back
it's all word processing and can they
deliver on it no the car there's a
shortage of the teachers that can
actually do this is even a theory that
mathematician should be teaching
computer science so that's the mannequin
what we like to do is we like to have a
sort of analogy with it where we got a
computer's like a car so I ct's how to
learn to drive the car but computing the
wrong is going underneath the car lock
in the car bro sort of how can we
manipulate a car and change them for our
own users that's the main idea that we
put pull forward to it so before we gets
a solution what we think what should be
done about it we took some quotes from
various academics professionals and
cybersecurity and and IT that we've got
quotes from alive network with Sam's
network weapon you in your place on so
the first one is from dr. David day he's
at our University of Halla is a lecturer
in forensics and also security
consultant for quite a lot of
high-profile retailer
to work that and also is quite common to
catch up on lost eight members so he
knows what he's talking about in terms
of security right so David learn
programming from BBC micro computers
rather than learning ICT like we did and
David does agree with everything we said
and he he called students these days
code aerobics and he believes University
students these days when I'm afraid of
programming because they never learned
from a young age so now they find it
really difficult I mean he'll two things
coding is a big part of UK security and
use another quote from this from dr.
Nick blundell he's the chief software
engineer with step 1 so we spoke with
Nick I'm going into a role at SEC one in
June as a pen tester and he's obviously
it was in higher education before so
we've been speaking to me talking about
how developer training materials of the
start Albert inherently insecure I mean
he teaches them but they move that onto
their advance careers and they're always
already embedded with vulnerabilities he
mentions of rubber floors sequel
injections and we're going to be talking
with them about teaching college
students if we move into college
students from any CPC and develop
tutorials and exercises that we can
teach each safety as well as cyber
security as well so the next quote is
from Jasper jerk and opposite critical
watch he's the vice president of
research there in the USA and I reached
out to him we speak on linkedin quite a
bit and I just expected a call but he
actually wrote an article for LA on his
blog on this so we haven't got a whole
link link to this we just took really
important things we thought really
useful someone mention these two so just
from payson agrees with the fact kids
should be learning computer science at
an early age he also think that a kid
should you know do gamification play
games to learn security like capture the
flag security chance etcetera rather
than just sitting in a classroom
learning theory but here's an obvious do
clash of one mind that he thinks he
should choose what they want to learn
where we think every student should
bloom computer scientist and mandatory
so the next quote is from Christian
senior manager or product of
inconsiderate so I know Chris personally
I've been fronting who Donna Citrix with
them I'm a good friends now you
mentioned micro model BBC micro model
computer and that's also what David
dimension so we seem to notice a theme
how when computers came to the masses
how a programming happened quite early
on and then this seems to be shift in
the past 10 to 15 years on ICT and how
you know how to use a copy of this
program isn't it from our fashion so it
means to bring that back in now
especially with cyber Skerries we can
integrate foreign language before we get
cyber security in their 2-1 benefits the
industry and the economy in the UK not
and also mention I'll Citrix do a
primary age child visits to camp on
campus in Cambridge which is why the
best citrix the next quote was from
Darren fuller at least director of SEC
West information security so Darren
basically knows all about the national
curriculum change and he he agrees with
the fat kid children computer science he
also talks about how Kate o-tar from Key
Stage one they learn what basic or QT
programming with games and they need
when they get to keep these three
they'll be learning python visual basic
and more text or program so next one
goes from harmony peace and managing
diperkosa this is my favorite quote it's
really concise he just saw sums of what
we feel about in terms of cybersphere in
secure coding he talks about cross-site
scripting floors for example in web
applications and how like cement like I
mentioned earlier about how developers
when they're learning they don't think
about security and then we'll later on
to the Korea need to be retrained and
they're not hold it securely
straightaway
so the next one Peter pollywog into
lecturer Ship Bottom University he
teaches software engineering and Vicki
recording this was a last minute while
he gives robotics and teaches kids takes
real boxing and we're going to be doing
stuff with steel hunt if you come in to
steal calm we're doing stuff works with
kids there because we're stem
ambassadors we have DBS typically
Shelby's so it can do this and he thinks
it's really important and all these
quotes you can see there's a blog online
that ourselves you can look at but he
feels it's really important because he
was the British computing society with
this so two minutes like so what's the
solution british computer society are
helping with this with the curriculum
change we mentioned how teachers may not
be able to deliver on these demands for
computer science and they're going to be
doing 25,000 pounds collar ships which
is a massive incentive to get teachers
in this company in society we fill of us
really important so II skills UK salt
oil from the government to create a
cybersecurity learning scheme where the
teachers icd teachers can go in and they
will learn a robot computer science
cyber security etc this way they will
have to be knowledgeable and they will
be able to teach students the coming
future if you go on ear skills search
google e-skills you care big ambitions
as a cybersecurity game they're for kids
it's really really interested you want
to look at it and how to teach the kids
if you've got your own kids off your
work in schools there's cold club as
well which is similar to what we do it
easy pc it's enough profit organization
volunteers run it's not nationwide but
we need more help from you guys to get
involved this and solve this problem so
the government is also working with
institutions who can do stuff like cyber
security challenge capture the flag etc
i think you should be more going through
the gamification just to learn security
rather than going to theory when the
last one is a really most important
point I really would implore you guys
you from a security background or even
IT get involved with stem nights free
the semi bastard program not
specifically and this is from the UK
cybersecurity strategy report they're
going to continue for an instant now so
it's not so it's going to disappear due
to funding costs because they think it's
really important so get involved you get
free DVI certificate
of your local local schools you get free
airport is going to reward your cv make
you see me back rewards the school's the
kids the teachers everyone benefits
really perfectly and we use cold cold
oven scratching yeah thank you for
listening and we've just been zoomed out
on a laptop I son there and Ollie are
called the courts are on there on the
blog that's a blog I'd yourself launch
ting coinciding with this and our
Twitter handles our LinkedIn handles
there any questions yeah