everyone my name is Gareth I'm going to
talk to you about the Tor network
pacific time I talk to you about
vulnerabilities in the Tor network how
you can d anonymize people and so on and
so forth a bit of background about me
I'm not able to work a PowerPoint there
we go I'm a career academic academic
seem to get a rather bit of a bad press
so hopefully I'm here to to change your
mind when I volunteered for the talk
I've got it I've got an email through
from the personalizing the talk saying
you're not academics please don't talk
about fluffs a living oh so hopefully I
hopefully I'll show academics in a
different light and I'm going to talk
about some of the technical details
about tour but I'm going to sort of sort
of drop in now at the technical details
so if you're not a technical person you
can keep up and if you are hopefully
I'll fill that need I can't run the
digital forensics course at University
of Portsmouth I teach everything as
pretty much every lecturer does from
forensics to cryptography but it's a
most academic staff even if you've been
to university you see the academic staff
teaching you the academic staff
typically also spend quite a significant
portion of our time doing research and
this is doing publications and things
like that and my Pacific interest is in
reverse engineering and memory forensics
but about six or seven years ago I spent
a good five years or so doing research
into very large decentralized systems
not that dissimilar too tall so I'm
going to talk to you today about how it
all works i'll talk about how the actual
infrastructure works how the network
works i'm going to talk to you about how
something called hidden services work
and how you can dnr mais not only
visitors to hidden services but hidden
services themselves i'll show you how
you can DN onam eyes users generally and
then also talk about finally the what's
commonly known as the FBI exploit even
if you followed tool you'll know about
about this and I'll show you they
actually exploit itself and some of the
shellcode from it as a show of hands how
many of you have used tor so that's what
about 80% keep your hand up if you run a
relay keep your hand up you run an exit
or you guys deserve a round of applause
yes you really do
oh and if you're not quite sure why we
clapping these guys and a few if in a
few slides I'll explain to you why they
deserve very much a clap and why they
may not be here next year so I I guess
for a security conference mostly of you
who have been following the Snowden
leaks over the last year I mean it's
been a rather interesting year to be
involved in security and any sense of
the word and there have been I think
about three documents leaked on tour
where GCHQ NSA five eyes essentially
I've been working on trying to be
anonymised people from tour and export
the Tor network I wanted to pick out one
slide with a rather notable point which
says that they can DN analyze a small
fraction of users but can't DN onam eyes
everyone and that's essentially what I'm
talk to you about today is how they can
some of the techniques you can use the D
anonymize people without cheating
essentially but also tell you how you
can cheat although that's not really
what what the talks about so just a
primer for those of you who haven't used
tor tor aims to essentially provide a
couple of properties it's an
anti-censorship tool which essentially
means if you live in a country which
firewalls the internet or filters
internet traffic you can use tor to
bypass that internet filter and i'll
talk to you let me look later about some
of the countries which have done that
and and how we're trying to fix that but
in it but the sort of two primary
features really that Torrez are analysi
and privacy a lot of people confuse
these two terms and think they're
actually the same thing they're actually
very different privacy essentially means
that someone can't see what you're doing
but they may know who you are anonymity
mate is you know they don't know who you
are but they might be able to see what
you're doing now tour provides both of
these but not necessarily at the same
time all right dependence very much
weight where you are I want to give you
an example before we specifically talked
about tour perhaps the way initially
that you may wanted to to get these two
things online before tour existed or if
you didn't know about tour was what via
proxy or a VPN you can go online and get
cheap VPNs that sort of forward your
traffic through Australia or some
country with
different-different Ross two hours now
the way a VPN typically works is you've
got you on the left-hand side here so
here's all the users connecting into the
VPN the VPN receives all of the
traffic's from the users and then spits
out to the different destinations which
they want to be going to now any
observer looking from the outside can
see that's what you're doing I was
wondering what you were doing I thought
you were talking to someone in the
audience right so you get your sorry ass
so you can I thought he's talking to
that guy for a long time why are you
just going game right so you've got all
the users on the left-hand side they may
be doing something on the internet but
typically the traffic from the user to
the VPN of the proxy is encrypted in
some way so even if you're sitting on
this side of the VPN and you can observe
all the traffic coming for the user you
know who they are but you can't
necessarily see what it is that doing so
that sort of stuff comes in through this
VPN and if you can observe traffic
coming out of the VPN you can see what
the people are doing but not necessarily
who they are you can see they're
visiting Twitter or WikiLeaks or
Wikipedia and so on you don't
necessarily know who they are so
normally provides privacy on the
left-hand side so therefore the VPN so
an attacker this side doesn't know what
you're doing but provides a normal
anonymity on the other side because
necessarily traffic in many cases to for
example work guess it's now to Twitter
but I think it's even to Wikipedia so
these are pretty bad examples and but
lots of sites obviously it don't use
HTTPS encrypted web traffic so you can
see what they're doing and what they
visiting on these websites now of course
there's one really fundamental problem
with this and that is that if you own
the VPN or you can in some way
compromise the VPN then all bets are off
right you can see which user is coming
in and exactly where they're going out
to which site so the question is you
know which VPNs do you trust or which
proxies do you trust a big question mark
there's loads of them ones could hide my
ass of all things you know which one do
you trust they will put on their website
we don't keep logs but there's many
jurisdictions where you're required to
keep logs and just because they say they
don't keep logs why would you trust them
so tour essentially attempts to solve
this problem where you bought this sort
of entity which is forwarding or traffic
but you don't necessarily trust that
entity in some way
so tour is an open source project that
means you can go online and get the code
it means I can go online and get the
code and change the code to do stuff to
try and poison the Tor network to do
other stuff which is fun and i'll talk
to you about that little bit later tor
essentially provides these two
properties the anonymity and the privacy
but slightly different points in the
network so you think okay these are two
things that really you know say for
example a nasty government doesn't want
people to be able to do so who sponsors
tour well one of the big sponsors of
tour is actually the US government even
though tour itself as a real pain in the
ass for some aspects of the US
government so it's a bit of a bit of a
funny thing that's not to say that tour
is compromised in any way because of its
funding stream and that's not the case
well as far as I know anyway and as far
as many of us I guess probably probably
suspect but who ever really knows it
isn't compromised necessary for because
of its funding stream choice a couple of
different funding streams but one of the
main ones is from from the US government
and the US government want essentially
there to be some sort of privacy and non
inity tool because they want to promote
human rights they want people in Syria
and Iran and China and so on to be able
to read websites which they shouldn't be
able to do to try and sort of bring
democracy as it were on the world as a
whole now the idea behind tool is
there's no single Authority there's no
single person in charge of it there's no
single computer which is in charge with
it the sort of the responsibility for
the Tor network is distributed over a
large number of nodes there are some
authorities which I'll talk about in a
bit there's no single authorities is the
main point that I'm trying to take now
in the previous slide I showed you that
the proxy was that was that weeks was
that weak spot right that was the thing
which if you compromise the the proxy or
the VPN server all bets were off so tour
times to sort of mitigate this risk so
here we've got a nice cool typical
Alison user Bob scenario we've got Alex
use our user we've got a website or a
person with whom Alice wishes to
communicate called Bob and instead of
just going through one hop to get to Bob
she goes through several hops in this
case her message is her request for web
pages etc are going through three
individual nodes across the Tor network
the idea being that you know to come to
sort of read bot Alison Bob's traffic
you know just controlling one of the
nodes doesn't suffice just controlling
one doesn't suffice you need to have to
control one of more than one node from
the Tor network to do
memorize people or to view what they're
doing on the internet now the weight or
provides this is it so here we've got
again Alice I use it on the far
left-hand side we've got our three hops
through that tor network now typically
we call on the guard the relay and the
exit the guard node is the first hop
from the user so this is who the user
talks directly with that then goes
through a second hop typically cool just
to relay in fact all of these are relays
but you know a gardener is just a relay
that's in essence just the first hop in
the network and then we've got the exit
relay which is where Alice's traffic
exits from the network now the way in
the sort of that sort of resilience if
you like to compromise of a single node
is provided is through encryption sort
of several layers of encryption layers
of an onion if you've ever seen the
taller go expecting an onion it was
originally called Onion Routing all that
sort of deviated up from that little bit
now so here we've got some data which
the user wishes to send out to a web
server all the way down this hand side
what this user does is she encrypts it
to the first node and then she takes
that encryption to the first node and
encrypts that so wraps it in another
layer of encryption to the second node
and then takes that and encryption yet
another layer encryption to the final
node so what's actually coming to the
guard note here is the data encrypted
three times this god node can unwrap the
outer layer that has been encrypted to
him as one of the layers so you can
unwrap the outer layer and work out
where next the traffic is going to go to
so in this case it can forward the
traffic on to be but again bc's the
traffic it's wrapped in two layers of
encryption it can only unwrap one layer
of the encryption and then run wraps
that tells you where it's going to next
and so on and then it gets to see can
unwrap the last layer encryption which
actually gives you the data and then
this final exit node sends it out to out
to your destination now the idea here is
that any individual node in this path or
in this circuit only knows about the
node before it and the node after it
doesn't know about any other nodes in
the circuit so even if you built a very
look much much longer path you couldn't
work out you know where those nodes were
so you weren't even sure which one is
necessary to compromise now let's do
about a couple of things so dunno what
differ hominis so if i told you that the
exchange of cryptographic keys was done
with diffie-hellman what would that mean
who's talking it's not know because it's
really it is because it's authenticated
different it's authenticated if ammonia
perfect forward secrecy is the thing
that I'm looking for what that means is
that if for example you're able to
collect all traffic going through the
Tor network and store it you had a
massive data center I don't know who
does that obviously you know store that
over time right and then at some point
in the future you're able to find out
one of the keys for the tour note one of
the tour nodes you wouldn't be able to
decrypt traffic going back into the past
and that's what you said quite correctly
with perfect forward secrecy this is a
property of a diff we harm and key
agreement protocol which is I guess
comes under the umbrella of asymmetric
cryptography along with our essay RSA
doesn't provide this and that's why
there's sort of a shift at the moment to
try and push people to use differ
hammond with our web servers and so on
because it provides us you know you
can't decrypt stuff going back into the
past there's very nice property for for
taught a half so before I get on to
actually doing that the anonymizer taps
and so on for those of you that may have
had sort of a loose experience with tor
you know something might have visited
the website you might used it once and
thought yours is really slow I'm not
going to use this anymore in any way I'm
not doing anything and I'm not trying to
bomb somewhere anything anything like
that essentially there's a different
there's a whole range of different sort
of code projects associated with to the
core one really the most important one
is the torque or program and this
essentially does all the functionalities
to be one of those nodes and to be one
of the clients essentially connecting
and using using the network there are a
couple of other tools if you've been off
the tour website you've downloaded
something the tor browser bundle is
probably what you've been directed to
first this is a web browser packaged
with the tour client so essentially it
makes it almost pointing click to use
the tor browser and it provides loads of
other safeguards against some of the
sort of you know easier attacks that
we'll talk about in a few slides times
if you use tor like a couple of years
ago so you know that's going about three
or four years
the Dahlia was a control mechanism to
control the tour pro and gave a nice
little GUI interface to use it and so on
tour affiant or socks are really nice
their command line programs that allow
you to route essentially any TCP
application through tor so for example
you can root ssh traffic through tor you
could route IRC traffic if any RC
network didn't block tour which is most
of them do unfortunately you could rely
see traffic through tor and so on and so
forth so you can essentially take any
application that's really nice at the
university is what I lab you can't ssh
out of the lab because the firewall
people are a bit crazy and they think
it's dangerous so you can go into the
lab and you can run tour and you can
tell at all we've got a fascist firewall
that only allows certain types of forts
out and it will try and route the
traffic via report which is allowed in
all of a sudden you can ssh out of
things who's use tor recently it's too
slow who's used toward ten years ago was
tour slow yeah so if you use tor ten
years ago it was really really slow
right now it's not so bad you actually
probably get used to it using it
everyday if you chased and we talked
about why you might want to see the
village Bellator arm is just a command
line version of Adalia sort of a
ministration tool for relays and so on
or bot is a an android client for tour
so you can download that off the android
marketplace you can make all of your
traffic anonymous coming from your
android phone you can browse the
webinars anonymously and so on those run
exit relay what's exonerate er if you
don't know what exonerate is you
probably should do so if you want a tour
exit relay which means you're it's very
last hop in the chain anything a user
does on the internet through your
through essentially through your relay
appears to come from your IP address
right so you're running this on running
an exit relay someone you know publishes
a terrorist manual or some of those
lines you know the FBI seized the
website learn to hold my IP addresses in
the in the logs sharing our it was me
that uploaded the uploaded the terrorist
manual to the website right exonerated
essentially is a database of all tour
nodes which ever run and where they're
running and whether allow exit traffic
from that node so if you were ever to
get arrested you
now keep in mind those are you running
an exit relay I commend you for running
an exit relay I really do commend you
for running an exit really however has a
real potential to screw up your day
right I mean you may sit there thinking
in your chair you know what you know if
the police come to my door yeah they're
going to be you know think it might be
me but you know I'm just going to tell
them they're you i'm using tor and
they're going to go away it's not going
to happen right they're going to come to
a house i can take all your equipment
you know you're going to be an under
investigation for six months because it
gets put in the drawer no one looks at
it for six months and for that six
months you're going to think i'm going
to go to jail or not you know it's
really a really life-changing sort of
consequence I know a couple of people
who have run tour really so actually
essentially been through that situation
so you know think very carefully before
you run an exit relay you don't have to
run an exit relay right you come running
out any other relay and be completely
safe but if you do run an exit relay you
really are you know well done but oh my
god not something I would do right I'll
talk if I if we get some time at the end
I'll explain some precautions you could
take and maybe you guys who contribute
some good proportions you can take on
trying to minimize the risk from from
running exit we do so it's on rate if
you ever get arrested you can point the
police exonerate ER and they can look it
up and if they knew what to laws which
they don't they could tell you that
you're on an exit relay and then they
just send you home and give you a
computer's back which they were so in
terms of the tour program so as I said
the tour program is the core thing it
runs on the android it runs on linux
windows etc etc essentially the same
codebase just with some minor changes
for the different platforms the tour
program itself depending on the
configuration opens up four ports which
you can use if you're using it as a
client essentially you're going to use
the Sox port which is just a socks socks
proxy is just a standard type of proxy
you can configure our web browser don't
to use it you should use the tor browser
bundle if you want to browse the web
because your web browser will leak
information which of whether a second
and the two other ports to port and
directory poor directory port we talked
about and sec the tort is essentially
for all of the tour traffic which is
going across across the network and then
this is final port called the control
port who knows smtp and pop you know who
if i give you a telnet turn looking type
an SMTP commands but so if I told you
the control port was essentially an SMTP
like protocol you know essentially what
I
right you can type commands and in text
you press enter it tells you okay or no
a very very simple protocol and you can
control tour you can tell it to
establish different routes to the Tor
network you can change all the settings
at all and so on so start so forth so
really nice port to use if you want to
fiddle around with tor and get to do
some interesting things and do some
research at all and so on so I took one
of the slides out from some of the GCHQ
NSA leaks from tour I actually think I
don't work for GCHQ NSA so I don't
really have an insider view onto this I
think actually GCHQ NSA are actually
behind the state of the art in terms of
where academics are in terms of the
state of the art for DN on amaizing toys
they are using you know they've
essentially got taps on you know big
pipes coming into and out of countries
all across the world you know they can
see all the traffic they can inject
traffic they can do essentially stuff
which is cheating in my view you know to
do the ID anonymize people so I said
earlier if you want to browse the web
with tor don't configure your web
browser Google Chrome to use tor use the
tor browser bundle that one reason for
this is if you're using tor right you
want to be anonymous right you don't
want anyone to know who you are now you
might use google chrome to browse the
web and then a little bit later you
change the Google Chrome settings to go
through tour so you'd be anonymous but
then your browser starts fetching the
ads and the title bars of pages you know
double click ads for example they have a
unique tracking cookie which identifies
you and some of the NSA slide showed you
know there's a list of nodes you know
here they are using tor and here they
aren't using tor and here's the double
click tracking idea it's the same thing
well we know it's the same person we
know exactly what they're doing every
time they go on I'll go on the web so
the tor browser bundle tries to protect
you against these sorts of things a very
simple way on honor how you can sort of
the anonymous people if you've got that
sort of super access to the network
which really most people don't don't
have I put this in quote marks I should
have put this in quit marks dumb users
or naive users really I should probably
say so you know users going on to forums
and calling themselves Gareth are in for
example you know as they username and
doing it through tor I mean that's
really dumb and stupid but i'm going to
give you an example of someone a little
bit later who essentially essentially
did that we know the NSA it from from
the league's is actively involved in
exploitation so we're going to talk
about one of the experts
they developed for a little bit later
but you know essentially targeting
either hidden service websites just
because you'll run a hidden website
which automatic so it doesn't mean it's
not what it doesn't mean it's in
venerable to sort of traditional
exploits and so on what primarily we're
going to talk about is what called
traffic confirmation and correlation
attacks these are essentially what what
i would call fundamental weaknesses in
tour rather than you know sort of round
the edgiest types attacks side-channel
attacks against or you know which are
essentially cheating in a trying to
exploit firefox or things like that i
kind of consider those cheating although
you know them and they're very effective
and if you're if you're the NSA or GCHQ
then of course you know they work so why
wouldn't i wouldn't they use them um so
looking at the sort of the NSA GCH site
at GCHQ slides it suggests they've had
some success at doing something called
traffic correlation academia has had a
much much greater the other success and
sort of trying to rd anonymize people
without doing any kind of exploitation
or any kind of cheating or cheating on
on types of types of things so in
explain precisely what they is in second
but first of all let me explain to you
how you build routes through the Tor
network how do you figure out what your
hops are going to be through that tor
network well essentially if you run a
tour relay when you first turn it on it
has to publish its information with the
directory authority there's essentially
ten authoritative directory authorities
you know they're essentially the
gatekeepers if you like to the Tor
network and they vote on relays that
register with them so if a really you've
set up a relay you register with all of
the director authorities and then they
all vote on that relay so they observe
over a period of time some of them were
trying to establish circuits through
them and so on and so forth and as they
do this they'll vote on the reliability
of that relay for certain certain types
of properties now these directory
authorities vote on this information and
this voted on information is called
something mythical called the consensus
which is just essentially a list of
relays in the Tor network which have
been voted upon by these directory or
thorities so they're kind of like the
trusted in inverted commas relays if you
like so the director authorities vote on
all of these relays and the properties
which they've been assigned to them and
then they each of them signs the
consensus with a cryptographic key and
the public key component of this is
embedded in
the tour client so anyone can verify if
you've got a genuine copy of the talk
line you can verify that consensus is
correct and what's in there is correct
now if you run a relay each relay and
we're talking too fast or you'll let me
slow down a little bit ago so when you
run a relay a relay it's just you know
something which relays traffic right a
guard node is a relay and exit node is a
relay a relay is a relay and so on and
so forth but what the directory
authorities do is give each of the
relays flax or certain things which they
should be able to do or certain
properties which they had exhibited and
so on and so forth so if you run a tour
relay and you run for eight days and you
offer a certain amount of bandwidth
after some time after eight days the
directory I thought you'd say you're now
eligible to be a guard node you're now
eligible to be that very first hop in
the chain and then over time over the
next to a couple of weeks or so you know
people are start using as that using you
as their very first hop in the chain all
right likewise if you run a tour relay
and you set up tore up so that you can
allow traffic to come out onto the
internet from your don't you can run
allow traffic to come out of your your
things onto the internet right the
director authorities will vote you as an
exit node and say you know these nodes
are eligible to be exit nodes so went or
clients select that path that's okay
well I'm going to slip my first hot from
this got a set of guards I'm going to
select my exit node from the set of exit
exit nodes and I'm just going to pick
one randomly front from the remainder
that are there so as I say the directive
authorities vote on these they give them
certain types of flags and if you'd be
running for eight days you get the guard
flag if you allow exit you get an exit
flag when would you get a bad exit flag
yeah so if you're running an exit relay
right you can see all the traffic coming
out onto the internet from your node if
you start trying to man in the middle
ssl traffic there's a script which runs
once through the exit nodes periodically
trying to establish SSL connections out
of the the tor exit nodes and picks up
essentially you know fake ssl
certificates coming back for the
different things so at the moment or in
fact as of Sunday there were
at least seven bad exit nodes noticed
you've been flagged as bad exit because
they're doing these SSL
man-in-middle-attacks in fact a couple
of weeks ago there were 25 so this sort
of fluctuates up and down as tight as
time goes on but in theory your tour
client should never select a bad exit
node as an exit node rights because
they've been flagged already that
doesn't mean there might not be an exit
node which hasn't yet been flagged as
one you know there's a bit of a lag time
with much of this so let's talk about
some obvious attacks in terms of D
anonymizing people when I'm not talking
about you know doing exploitation or you
know into stealing cookies or anything
on those ones I'm talking about a
fundamental weakness isn't all so if we
look at the tour the tour diagram for a
typical typical circuit if if you could
control or three of the relays then
rather obvious right you can d anonymize
people you can see what they're doing
but what a slightly worse than that is
if you control just the exit and the
garden oder node you can with high
probability still d anonymize people
what we're essentially doing is looking
for traffic patterns we're looking for
packets coming in here that have say you
know for example you know five packets
with these particular delays between
them for example coming in the guard
node and then if we also control neutral
the exit node water looking for that
sequence of packets coming out the exit
node and then with Korra correlating
them now the longer you establish a
connection through the tour node the
higher that probability becomes that in
fact you are the same person essentially
doing that traffic so it's very much a
probabilistic attack it's not saying
it's definitely this person but over
time it becomes much much much closer to
certain that it is in fact that person
so really these are sort of truffle what
caused traffic correlation attacks we're
trying to match the traffic coming in
and the traffic going out up essentially
can be used by a very powerful adversary
I couldn't imagine one of those that has
no could have taps everywhere but
essentially could be used by a very
powerful adversary now it's slightly
worse in the case of the NSA and gchq
because if you've got taps and lots of
pipes in fact you don't even need to run
relays you can just watch traffic going
into an existing guard node and watch
your traffic coming out of an existing
exit relay and in fact you can actually
set traffic here as well which pushes
the probability up even higher that in
fact it
the same person so when you've got a
very powerful adversary you know I don't
to say all bets are off it's still the
best thing we've got but it's certainly
not going guaranteed now the really
interesting thing to note is here we've
got three hops right if you edit the
tour source code you can change the
number of hops that your tour client
bills and sort of the nights or the
natural way to think about it is well
okay well if three hops isn't enough
maybe I'll make it four I'll make it
five or six or seven or eight I'll have
as many hops as I like in my particular
circuit it turns out in fact actually
that doesn't increase your decrease very
much your chances of being d anonymize
because i stay we're still doing
correlation attacks we're just doing
them at the exit and the guard relay it
doesn't really matter how many tops how
many hops are in the middle it just
changes the delays essentially between
the garden the exit node that's all the
time is taking the traffic to travel
between the two nodes through the Tor
network so it makes a little bit harder
but not really significantly harder so
the default case is to run three relays
through a circuit and that's generally
considered to be sufficient provided all
of them haven't been no more than two it
no more than one of them is being
compromised so what's the question is
how do you get to be at or node in
someone's circuit if you want to do
naanum eyes them like say we're not a
powerful adversary I'm just me and I
want to start d anonymizing one of you
how do I go about doing on amaizing one
of you I need to control the guard node
and I need to control the exit load to
do this traffic correlation and D
anonymize you the question is how I get
to be your guard node and how do I get
to be your exit node right I can't tell
you which route to take through the tour
node Tor network but essentially I can
just run a large number of guard nodes
and a large number of exit nodes and
just hope with it by chance you happen
to pick my garden load and my exit node
right just by just by chance and then we
can do the correlation attack and work
out in fact if it is you so tour tries
to make this a little bit harder and try
to make it really a lot harder and say
if you control the guard node and the
exit relay we can dear naanum eyes you
right so what tour does is we says when
when you first start up tour you will
pick three guard notes and you'll keep
them for a really long time
and we're talking between one to three
months typically you'll keep these three
guard nodes as your guard nose for
between one and three months that means
that either on day one you're screwed
because someone's got your guard node or
you're not right so with high
probability you're not going to be
screwed right on day one and for those
three months you're going to essentially
going to be safe now the reason why I
kept for three months is because if Iran
loads of God nodes and every time we
established a new circuit through the
network with different guard knows you
know at some point you're going to pick
my garden out yeah I can't deal
otherwise all of your traffic but I
candy anonymize the traffic youth but if
you sent through my garden owed at that
particular point in time so it's kind of
like an all enough thing you know we're
either going to get you on day one or
we're not going to get you at all and
this the guard knows tries to provide
this scenario really is there any sort
of way of fixing this traffic
correlation there is something called
high latency networks where you know you
might go on to ww waddup curl UK you've
got to wait until tomorrow to get the
homepage right and that gives a much
much longer period before you know
you're going to get the homepage and
makes these traffic correlation attacks
really quite impossible works fine with
mail and those sorts of things well it
depends how urgent emails or I guess but
it works works sort of okay with mail
but not with real-time traffic where we
want real-time traffic sort of web
traffic and so on and so forth so high
latency networks are essentially a
partial solution to this but not not
particular particle the alternative is
we can start injecting traffic into the
Tor network at different places we can
start putting padding in so rather than
just sending the sort of the the raw
traffic between you know this node and
this node this mode mode might choose at
random to inject padding traffic into
the connection this node might choose at
random to inject padding traffic and so
on and so on and so forth it's just
dummy traffic gets dropped to the next
so makes this traffic correlation much
much harder a present or doesn't do this
primarily because it overloads the
network with traffic and traffic on the
Tor network is really constrained I
don't have a huge amount of traffic
traffic capability or bandwidth father
so at the moment it's not done but it
could provide some resistance but not
not really foolproof so everything I've
talked about so far is okay yeah okay
you can do the traffic correlation it's
um
realistic and so on and so forth now I'm
going to talk to you about something
called no I'm not going to talk to about
this first and I'm going to talk about
hidden services it's much easier to do
non mais people with hidden services and
they win the 10 says I'm gonna talk
about censorship first day so I said
tour can be used to bypass censorship so
if I'm sat in China and I want to read
about a particular website which is
blocked by the Great Firewall of China
you know I could use tor for example I
can root my traffic through tor China
can't see what I'm doing because my
traffic is encrypted through tor and as
long as I eggs out onto the internet in
a different country to China it should
in theory be okay so there are lots of
countries which are trying to block tour
because of this because it can be used
to bypass the censorship china is one of
them they are in fact three or four
others this is a graph showing the
traffic out of a certain type of nodes
out of the Tor network coming from China
and you can see there's a rather big
drop at this point and never really
quite recovers China have been actively
trying to block short tour and they've
tried a different sort of different
touch techniques one very easy way to
block tourists just download this
consensus of all of the Reuters and say
okay well I've got a list of all of the
rooters I can just IP you know IP
firewall them so that no one can contact
them right very very simple way to
firewall all the nodes out China and of
course we can download this consensus
once an hour and just update the
firewall rules very very easy to put to
stop people accessing tour that way so
tours try to counter this by introducing
something called bridges bridges are
nodes which don't appear in the
consensus they're essentially guard
nodes for not but essentially God knows
which you can use to connect into the
Tor network but I'm not inside the
consensus and they're not widely
publicized so what you do is you go on
to the tour website and you have to
enter a capture and you get given one or
two I think that's three actually i
think you get given a list of three
bridges which you could use to connect
the Tor network now you got to go
through a capture to get that list so
it's very difficult to automate it you
can't wow there's a guy it was just me I
wasn't there showing you how to rate
captures haha yeah it's a bad example
right i mean it's a harder right hard it
harder with captures so the idea is you
know it's not publicly available so or
not easy to get the full list very very
hard to get the fullest so in theory you
can't block all bridges and in fact you
know I could ask a friend in the UK to
run a bridge not tell you an hour
art it not go to China and I could use
his computer to connect to the tour node
it's not public anywhere so it kind of
allows me in so China has got a little
bit cleverer so China has this thing
called the great file is called the
Great Firewall of China I don't think
it's actually called the great for
waterfowl of China but everyone calls it
the Great Firewall of China so i'm going
to call it a great firewall of china so
the Great Firewall of China sisters like
round China sees all of the traffic
coming out of China and they do deep
packet inspection which means they look
at the content of packets the content of
the protocols going across the net and
do things based on the content of this
traffic really sort of resource
intensive thing so initially China
started just inspecting the initial
connection into the Tor network the
initial connection into the Tor network
is done over SSL and they sort of look
for sort of triggers inside that initial
connection it turns out that or
initially had certain characteristics
about the initial connection which were
fairly unique to talk so it's trying to
would use those as sort of an initial
trigger and then it would actually
connect to that node so sorry i'm in
china i connect to a node connect to a
rehearsal cell and i send these sort of
unique triggers the thing I that sort of
like all almost identifies it as tour
traffic we're not quite and then I you
know start sending my tour traffic to
the Great Firewall of China records that
connection and then about 15 minutes
later another computer in China will
connect to it and try and start talking
tall and if the computer comes back and
says yeah I'm tour what traffic do you
want to route then the great for why
will a china blocks here right this was
spotted by some research as a couple of
years ago this is a little graph showing
how long after the initial connection to
a bridge the Grateful wild Wall of China
came in and actually scanned the node
and tried to talk tried to talk to eat
otter and it was typically on 15 minute
intervals throughout the following hour
depending on the load of Trina depending
on the time of day and if China was
particularly busy you know let's see
traffic come out there might add this no
to a queue and so you need to check this
later on and they'll have some computer
somewhere else that would connect to LA
today you know with
next hour or so try and talk tour and if
it was that block it and they just
researchers do some really interesting
things you know they took that they sort
of recording all the IP address which
tall was connecting to all these bridges
and there was a large number of IP
addresses so and it's definitely right
it's definitely a nation-state type
thing they also try to cover other
things they fragmented the packet so if
any of you doing sort of low-level
networking stuff you can break a packet
down into smaller chunks by a process
called fragmentation it turns out that
if you fragmented the packets the great
wall of fire water China didn't do
fragment reassembly to reassemble the
packets and actually check the content
of it just ignored it so you know I mean
that's expensive right for a firewall
where you're you're doing like a whole
country so they find you could fragment
the traffic and that let it through
there's also something if you look
through the tour specs tour have a
couple of RFC's type documentary stay
right great stuff to send you off to
sleep but if you it is sort of paying
attention and your spot in there there's
actually a section on there something
called authenticate which means when you
first connect to a bridge if you can
figure this option the bridge will sit
there and it won't do anything until you
send essentially the correct password
you can send it anything you like and it
will just ignore you until you send the
correct passage that means now the great
for Wyatt Firewall of China needs to
know about the bridge in advance and
needs to know the password for it to
scan it and see in fact if it is a tour
bridge amor but you know you can kind of
see this is kind of end up going to be a
cat and mouse game you know where you
know tours going to change something
China's going to catch up towards me I
changed something it's going to just
keep going like this forever for tall
project or implementing something called
pluggable transports where essentially
you can have you know a thousand
different modules that implement or
perhaps over a custom protocol over an
existing protocol etc etc and users can
just plug in them into tour and you use
a particular type of protocol to talk
out of China so it can't get pizza I the
firewall so let's get on to hidden
service is really the thing I want to
talk to you about who's who's beans with
hidden service okay about five or six of
year I mean that's there some D
anonymization for you they're busted
right so
here we've got alice alice is our
typical use is you who wants to browse
the web and so on and so forth and here
we've got Bob Bob might live in China
and wants to run a political bought a
political blog opposing the government
right I mean you don't want to run that
on your own home IP address because the
Chinese government's going to come and
get you so you want to run it in a way
which no one can find out where you are
if no one can find out how where you are
how people that want to talk to you
going to find out where you are well
this is essentially what hidden services
they try to solve this problem in the
case of hidden services we have a user
visiting a website called Bob and both
are anonymous to each other so Bob
doesn't know who or where Alice's and
Alice doesn't know who or where Bobby's
anything well how can that possibly work
I mean it's actually quite simple so Bob
when he first sets up his web server he
establishes circuits to something called
introduction points the three nodes
which he picks randomly from the
available tour relays and he picks three
of them called introduction points and
he builds a circuit to them so a typical
three hop circuit to that introduction
point so none of the introduction points
know who Bob is and then Bob Bob Bob Bob
Bob publishes the list of introduction
points to a database which we're going
to talk about in a second and then it's
available in this database now when I
just wants to talk to Bob she goes to
the database she gets a list of
introduction points so she builds a
circuit to the introduction points and
it essentially says meet me at a
rendezvous point and then the rendezvous
point is essentially another node in the
network and both Alice and Bob build a
three hot circuit to this rendezvous
point the rendezvous point doesn't
halaal I see is the only important sorry
the rendezvous point has chosen by ice
but the rendezvous point doesn't know
who Bob is because Bob's built a 3 hop
circuit and the rendezvous point and you
know even if you could compromise well
maybe the point it makes it a bit
difficult to find those sorts things out
later now what we get our focus on is
this database right at the very top what
is it that gets published in this
database and what can we do with it
because this is one of the techniques we
can use the D anonymize people is
actually this this database itself this
database is not stored in one place it
is distributed across the torn-out and
there are thousands of nodes upon which
this database is distribution so those
single place where the entire databases
is stored now i'm going to digress a
very little bit and explain something
called distributed hash tables behind of
you know at distribution table is okay
so I'm not preaching to those already
know ok so imagine this scenario right
you have a list of files and you've got
12 computers you want to be able to
distribute these 12 files across those
12 computers just for sort of load
balancing and in essence right you might
have each computers got you know 20
gigabytes of 20 terabytes of storage and
so on and so forth so I list the files
you want to distribute them across 12
computers now the question is how do you
distribute them across 12 computers
without having a single computer is
essentially in charge of allocating
where it goes and we don't want to n
talk as tall as a decentralized network
we don't want a single computer in
charge so the idea where they're
distributed hash table is we want to
distribute these files across those 12
computers but in a particular way at one
way might be circular would take the
file name and we take the very first
letter from the file name and the very
first letter from the file name dictates
which computer the file gets stored on
and then if someone wants to retrieve
the file at a later date they generate
the file name they pick the first letter
out and that tells them which computer
it's going to be stored on there's a
fundamental problem with that you know
how many files do you have beginning
with Zed I mean I don't know probably
not very many already have a lot more
beginning with G than I do with Zed for
example so it doesn't evenly distribute
the files across those computers which
you know if is used for load balancing
that's essentially what you want so the
idea whether a distributed hash table is
instead of taking the file name and
using the first letter we first hash the
file name and then that dictates which
computer of those 12 computers is going
to be stored on now hash function is
what we call a pseudo-random function
the output from the hash function is
random in essence is randomly
distributed so even if I have Gareth one
and Gareth too if I hush both of them
you get completely different hashes
right so in essence it essentially
evenly distributes the files then across
the computer now tour use this for
storing the descriptors for these for
these hidden services so this is a tor
hidden service website address all of
the tor hidden service website addresses
auto onion who knows what the bit is
before
doll and like oh I can think I could
almost remember the bit before the door
is essentially just a hash of the tour
nodes public key is that's why it
doesn't look like anything particularly
particularly useful what we're going to
do is we're going to store that
somewhere on a large set of computers
now we want to try and do it in a way
which we can allow computers to join the
distributed hash table and to leave the
distributed hash table that's caught was
going to work with a very large network
like this so what you do is we draw a
circle and this circle represents the
hash space as it were so you can imagine
the circle goes from zero all the way
around to fffff right zero all around to
ffffff and what we're going to do is
we're going to map hidden services on to
this circle and then we're going to map
nodes in the network onto this circle
and that will tell us which nodes are
going to store the ticular types of
stuff so we take that hidden service
address we map it onto the circle by
units between 0 and F F F essentially
and then we take our relays in the
network we map them onto the circle and
the weight or works it says okay well
the hidden service is going to be stored
on the three nose to the right in the
circle so we plot the circle which you
can do because you've got a list of all
the relays and you pick out the three
nose to the right and you're going to
publish your descriptor to those three
nose to the right and then you're also
going to store it in a different part of
the circle as well just by changing the
hash a little bits there's a little bit
of redundancy and that essentially means
now nodes can leave and join the circle
without essentially causing this hidden
service to go completely unavailable so
I'm going to skip over this because I
think we're short on short on time we
did a bit of experiment earlier this
year we had a bit of spare time so we
thought what would be an interesting
thing to do so we thought we look at tor
hidden services or the big question is
tor hidden sir I'll taught himself as
evil for example as is the content on
them really bad so I thought well it'd
be really great to look at tor hidden
services and find out just exactly what
is on tor hidden services so my initial
thought was well we take some of the
directory sites we're point a web
crawler at it and we collect all the
results but I thought well you know the
nature of tor hidden services some of
them aren't going to be in directories
we're not really going to click the full
list so I thought okay well we need to
click the full list of all of the all of
the nodes we know it is stored in this
distributed hash table so in theory if
we put ourselves on the
stupid hashtag at different points what
actually happens is you know I've said
the tor hidden service appears here it
actually changes day by day so every 24
hours the position on the circle changes
so in theory if I just sat at one
position in their circle given an
infinite amount of time I'd collect all
of the hidden service addresses and I
could start looking at them and seeing
what's contained on them so actually
what we did was we ran 40 nodes we
distributed them around their circle at
different points and we just SAT and
waited and we just SAT and waited for
hidden services to register with us we
store them in a database but what we
also able to collect if you think about
it hidden services are publishing to us
but also people are coming to us to ask
for the hidden service descriptor so not
only can i register the publication of
the dot onion address but I can work out
how many people are visiting it as well
so I can lock up the number of hits as
well I can't view if you view all the
details on who it is because because
there it's encrypted but essentially I
can register hits and I can register all
the onion dresses what do you think I
found so we've got a database there's
around about 50,000 onion addresses
which will be in published to our
servers over the last of the three
months I think there's probably about
10,000 more which we haven't yet
collected it just takes a little bit of
time to collect all of these things does
anyone know what Stefan it will shine it
off botnets essentially botnets those
are a presentation of black cat a couple
of years ago on using tor hidden
services to run botnet commander control
service thinking well you know you can't
trace the website so you can't shut it
down so there'd be a really good place
to run button it botnet come on and
control servers and ever since then
loads we will started writing botnet
botnets that use tor essentially to host
these hosts these things it turns out
the top 40 results are essentially
botnet command and control service and
you can see you know the top one there
had 1.4 million hits a day a day right
that's a day right and this particular
bottner setting it doesn't just have one
tor hidden service addresses got loads
all right so it's not just 1.4 million
hits a day it's actually much much
larger that's pretty close to five or
six million hits a day and we picked up
a couple others Skynet is a rather
notable one the botnet master who runs
spynet did something called
I am a witch would never heard of on
reddit which is a done what it stands
for ask me anything right so you can go
on this reddit site and ask people
anything so the guy that round the
skynet taught Skynet botnet went on on
it on this reddit thing and ask them you
know you can ask me anything right you
know i mean there's a really foolish
kind of guy anyway it sounds anyway he
got locked up in december this year at
this ever last year i'm not really sure
why but you know and he was on twitter
as well and who runs a bot there and is
on twitter he'll seriously so we've also
sort of ranked the other other sets of
sites as well if you've been involved in
tour you'll know that some of the tour
content is really not very nice stuff
unfortunately straight after botnet
stuff or a particular class of abuse
sites we ran a crawler which didn't
fetch any images just fetched HTML
content and this sort of stuff was
easily identical using keyword searches
through the images unfortunately this is
the second most popular stuff that we
collected by in terms of hits so the
number of people visiting these sites
straight after botanist and then
straight after that came essentially
directories linking to other tour him
sites some forums some sort of like I
guess what I classes hacktivist type
websites those sorts of things and
there's a full of search engine in there
as well if anyone is interested looking
at the full database I'm quite happy to
share it to you late and you can see you
know if you've got a particular oniony
really want to look at and how many hits
it got for example per day and quite
happy to show you to show you that so
how about d anonymizing tor hidden
service users people visiting tor hidden
sites right even in many ways you think
this is the holy grail right we've got
really dodgy sites and really dodgy
people visiting the really dodgy sites
right so if we can work out who they are
then right win-win it turns out it's
actually really easy to do in on my
google visiting tor hidden services
really really easy so let's look at how
a tor hidden service connects to a tor
hidden service so a user connects to a
tor hidden service a user has a guard
node we've got the hidden service
directory which is that distributed hash
table spread out throughout the the Tor
network and then we've got the tor
hidden service itself which again is
separated from the network by the Tor
network so when I want to visit this
website I go into the Tor network
through my garden node and I connect up
to the hidden service directory and say
I have the descriptor for that tor
hidden service the list of those
introduction points where it's available
and the in-service rectory sends it back
to me now think about this just for a
second right I can position myself on
that distributed hash table so that I'm
the node responsible for a particular
website right I can position myself
where ever want to be so that i know i'm
going to receiving a request for a
particular type of web sites so I now
control one end of this connection all
right the user is talking to me and I
know that are looking for a particular
type of site and you can think of these
kind of like there's request for these
descriptors perhaps very similar to DNS
requests and respect you if I get a
request for one of these sites sites you
know they're doing it at the initial
point of wanting to visit the website
just like you would do with a DNS
request so i can send the user or
whatever I want I should probably send
them that the hidden service to ship to
which they asked for which I'm going to
you right but I can shape the traffic in
a particular type of way as I could send
them you know just 20 packets for
example or I could put it in 30 packets
and so on and so forth so if I control
just the hidden service director node
and the gardener stay with me on the
garden owed point right I can send
traffic back down this pipe with a
particular characteristic and I can spot
that a characteristic on the gardener
and I candy anonymize someone that's
visiting a particular website I can't
tell what they're doing on that website
but I know who that who they are in
essence now the question is how do I
control the garden note well think back
to that GCHQ slide isolated on the very
first thing where I said we can dear
naanum eyes some people some of the time
but it's very difficult to do naanum
eyes someone specifically right so I
wanted D an unwise you you know it's
very hard for me to do that but if
you're all visiting at all hidden whip
website the chances are some of your
going to be going through my guard note
and eye candy anonymize all of you yep
know exactly who you are now some of you
sit there thinking really really i've
been using tor I thought it was
foolproof right here's a google map of
everyone visiting a particular website
particular toilet in service right this
is all the original IP addresses run
through a geoip database and plotted on
a map right i mean it's that easy right
really that easy if you control the
guard node and just by the rules are
probably at some point you're going to
control the guard note for some of the
users right so
this was actually for a botnet this this
wasn't me this was someone else so do
you normalize them it was essentially
for a botnet and the guy guys theorize
that you know at the time Silk Road was
quite popular so you could d anonymize
everyone visiting Silk Road and you
could say well you know people selling
drugs and people buying drugs are going
to have different behaviors really we
want to go after the sellers and they're
pretty going to login what once a day
twice a day three times a day but it's
going to be fairly regular everyday type
thing suggested by on the frequency they
visit the websites and how often was you
could probably figure out whether
they're a buyer or seller and then
selectively raid just the buyers rather
than the sellers so how about d
anonymizing the tor hidden service
itself can we use the same technique to
dear Nala mais the tor hidden service so
again right the user can send data to
the tor hidden service right so we
control one end of the connection right
the toilet and service is talking to me
and i can connect as many times as i
like right so if if I'm the user and I
control one of the guard nodes the
hidden service happens to use then I can
send a signature of packets down through
the network and I can watch from the
guard node and if I see them that tells
me that's probably the hidden service
running that particular hidden sir
running that particular hidden service
and think okay well what are the chances
of your being the guard node for the
hidden service you know the hidden
services keep them for three months
typically between one and three months
ago it's quite hard some guys are
showing that in fact you know even with
moderate resources sort of like five or
six thousand pounds in server capacity
on average you can d anonymizer hidden
stair lessons in eight months and
actually work out who they are all right
it's really not that difficult so let me
just just just backtrack very very
quickly right this signature we actually
send is so here the hidden service node
or whatever it is sends a particular
sequence of packets to the user now the
gardener can't decrypt that traffic but
what we found is that if you send for
example just 50 packets so you send
exactly 50 packets you can you can pick
up the number of packets going down a
particular circuit the guard knows
anything okay well what are the chances
of there being another connection with
exactly 50 packets coming through might
I think it's pretty high where are some
researchers in Luxembourg essentially
set up 300,000 connections that didn't
do this and found
of them had exactly 50 packets right so
it's not a still a probabilistic attack
but it's a very high level of
probability that it is in fact the right
site or the right person doing and you
can imagine doing it over a couple of
months you see the person coming back
and coming back and coming back you know
it gives you a high degree of
probability big question mark I over
whether that would be sufficient to get
a warrant and see someone's computer I
don't know whether it would or not
they're not certain I seen any test
cases on this I don't think the police
are even doing this I'd anything GCHQ
are doing it at the moment but it's
certainly possible this is a fundamental
weakness at all you know I mean this is
a problem that's also very difficult to
fix very very difficult to fix padding
is one way to try and mitigate the risk
but doesn't really solve the problem
completely so just the final thing I
wanted to get onto is with silk road I
said I'd talk to you about the FBI
exploit itself Silk Road was essentially
ebay for drugs right the sellers were
selling drugs and the buyers were buying
drugs and it was a tor hidden service
which was essentially facilitating this
and the guy running Silk Road was
essentially you know taking a bit of
profit from from each transaction you
know much like paypal might do right you
know really a real business entrepreneur
just with the wrong business really to
sort of sort of sort of make money so
it's sort of estimated that silk road
over its lifetime had around just over a
billion pounds in revenue and that this
chap that ran it had about eight million
dollars in profit all in bitcoins though
and if anyone knows how to cash in
exactly 80 million dollars of bitcoins
please come and tell me without causing
a crash in the price of bitcoins I don't
know how you do that but he had 18
million pounds worth of bitcoins and he
lived in a dinky little flat in San
Francisco someone and the police
actually if I actually tracked him down
not by weakness and tour but actually
just by sort of traditional detective
work it turns out he'd been on a forum
advertising his website and it signed it
Ross Albert Hall bricks with his name is
on the forum and they're sort of a time
to sort of collected this information
correlated it all identified him the
sort of identify ways going to that also
managed to pick up a few other things
which gave them a high degree of
confidence that in fact was him that was
doing it and they actually arrested the
amino in a library in Santa san
francisco essentially caught by his own
foolishness and in fact one of the FBI
agents at the time pose doesn't assassin
because he was trying to get someone
nated you know no honor amongst thieves
really so I don't if you can see that
yeah so so the FBI we know in fact no it
was the FBI because the court papers
have been released the FBI took
advantage of this silk road was run on a
set of servers called the run by an
organization called freedom hosting
which ran a whole range of hidden hidden
websites so the FBI in their ingenuity
thought you know I got opportunity here
we've got freedom hosting servers you
know they host actually some really vile
content as well so we could do naanum
eyes people from you know actually
visiting these websites so it's a bit
unclear as to who exactly develop the
exploit itself it's either GCHQ NSA or a
combination of the two and then they
have the FBI deploy it essentially there
they took the freedom hosting websites
and they put a zero day on the web page
and then anyone that visited the website
running the tor browser bundle
particular type of version would Firefox
would run that exploit and it would
feedback that details back to the FBI
server and essentially dear nandi
anonymize them essentially a couple of
guys caught it a few days a few days
after and there was a JavaScript exploit
in there anything sexual essentially
exploiting a very complex plug in la
Firefox works I'm going to talk to you
more briefly about the sort of look
about the shower code itself because
that's the really really good thing
that's interesting the big question of
course is is this legal is it is it
legal to exploit a large number of
people on a large scale some of whom are
doing something quite innocent and
freedom hosting hosted some innocent
websites incidentally and if you're SAT
home right and the FBI exploit your
computer and you have no anything wrong
is that legal does anyone go to jail for
that if they do that I mean probably
should right i mean i don't think that
they don't think I will this is the
reason we know that GCHQ the essay were
evolved involved one of the leaks from
from Snowden actually referred to it was
called egotistical garage giraffe the
actual exploit presumably because tor
users either too egotistical and
presumably because Jeff's got a high
head which shows where it is i'm not
presume so i wanted to show you the shit
of the shellcode very briefly I've also
put on this this web link here is a copy
of the shellcode an annotated copy of
the shellcode and a sort of a walk
through in text if you're not familiar
the reverse engineering on exactly how
it works if you look at the JavaScript
code here
you can see a long list of hex
characters in a string I mean that's
characteristic of shell code for these
types of exploits and if you take that
code out just as a guest that is in fact
the shell code and disassemble it it
does turn out to be shell code so when
you run it through a disassembler this
is what you get so this is run through a
disassembler called indus azum and if
you ever disassemble shellcode not
really that familiar with this assembly
you'll be like what the hell I have no
idea what's going on right those strings
no exe to load up new dll is being
loaded anything that you just see like a
blob of instructions you might what the
what the hell is get what the hell's
going on so I'm just going to very
briefly talk to talk me through how are
you rehearsed engineering and then and
then we'll finish up so the thing with
shell code is shell code is injected
into another program right so normally
we want an exe file vxc headers say you
know bringing this dll and that he ll so
you know where all the DLLs are in
memory so you can run you know and call
the windows api and so on and so forth
shell code doesn't have that luxury it's
injected into a process it doesn't know
precisely where all the DLLs are so it's
very common to have something called an
API resolver embedded in the shell code
and you call this API resort to find out
where different windows API functions or
where the DLLs are loaded so you can
actually call them it's fairly common to
see this sort of this sort of pattern we
push a series of hex digits didn't leave
eight hex digits and then make a quarter
a register that patterns quite common in
shellcode the register EBP points to the
shellcode resolver and the hash or
whether this number here actually
describes which API function we're
calling us out actually calling so the
process of reverse engineering the show
cave is essentially saying okay well
find out which API resolve is being used
and then look up these hash functions
and go through and comment them and say
this is this API that's that API and so
on and so forth and then you end up with
something like this this is the same
shell code the only difference is I've
added some comments to the right hand
side and exactly what's going on so
there's that hash there's that core to
the 85 is over and this hash essentially
maps to wind sock which is the sort of
internet connection dll and the
connection function so we know at that
point that it's establishing a
connection out onto the internet
somewhere the question is where is it
establishing a connection to if you ever
written any C code you know when you do
a connect you have to set up that
horrible sin address structure and as
does not prettiest thing in the world is
it but that of course is going to be
where the IP address is stored so
typically when you see a call the
parameters are pushed onto the stack
just before it and one of these things
which is push on is just that sinner
dress structure so we find it in memory
there's the sinner dress structure looks
like a series of bikes but when you know
what the sin addressed structure is you
can comment the shellcode and say okay
well this is the IP address that's the
port and this is the IP address it was
vs. somewhere in Vancouver I think not
Vancouver VA what's ba the state code
Virginia that's it which is not that far
from one of the contractors for for the
effort for the FBI and incidentally but
we're not quite sure who was running
here I mean you look at the who is stuff
you know who's who's running it but the
interesting thing is what the shellcode
did right i mean most shower code is
going to try and get some sort of
persistence install some mera on the
computer that's the typical pattern for
shell code this shell code doesn't do
any of that right it literally phones
home so it contacts the FBI server or
whoever service was and it sends them
your mac address your computer's
hostname and a unique reference number
AKA everything that could be used to
identify you right and then it stops but
that's not how malware typically works
right i mean listen you know you're
running the business right you're not
going to make our money by collecting
people's MAC addresses obviously it's
not going to get me to be profitable so
I Canton will I put this on the website
but it's fairly easy to patch this code
if you look here there's the offsets for
the data and you can just patch the IP
address by just for changing the bites
you can patch the port you can run
netcat and then you can execute the
shellcode and the shellcode will send
just the HTTP request so here was a get
request made to the FBI server this
appears to be some sort of unique
reference number possibly which were
links you up with a particular visits
that all hidden service so they could
identify which toy in service it was he
went to at what time etc etc and then in
the header you've got this cookie ID
equals this is actually your mac address
and the host is set to your computer so
you know everything which ties you are
essentially right you have to i now have
your IP address to have your mac address
they have your computer's hostname and
if they can't trace you've our IP
address then i could trace your mac
address through the supply chain etc etc
etc you're done
all right essentially so so the website
there the full source code there and
everything if you want how to play with
it and have a look round it how is it
helped with the Tor project I put the
first when it's used tor right most
you're sitting there thinking why the
how do i need to use tor i'm not some
terrorist or doing anything dodgy right
well actually there are people that
really need tall we went around China
surrett cetera you know who really
depend upon't or if you use tor right it
makes the noise bigger all right there
in amongst the noise if only bad people
use tor then you know simply by looking
at tor you catch all the bad people
right I mean it's like a honey trap type
thing obviously if genuine people use
tor who aren't do anything wrong it sort
of mixes them against the noise and mix
them essentially more more anonymous
consider running at all relay you don't
need a huge amount of bandwidth most
people can run it quite comfortably on
that home broadband without any ill
effects in terms of you know reducing
that bandwidth availability yoona can
easily run a couple of hundred kilobytes
or hundred kilobits about you know relay
at home without it really impacting you
don't run an exit unless you really do
like pain or law enforcement visiting
its folk in the morning but I don't like
early mornings so it would really peed
me off along with the investigation as
well obviously consider developing for
tor tor is an open source project so you
can contribute to it and you know really
sort of contribute to or you can develop
alternative product projects like you
know that is the tor browser bundle as
the dahlia etc etc these are sort of
like a successor eat or projects which
you can contribute to or build or build
other types of things this is then 18
you get free t-shirt if you donate sixty
dollars there's nothing that's great
value for money but incident if you want
to talk if you on a t-shirt you can run
at or relay for two months and you get a
free t-shirt that way if that's the way
I've chosen to go promote it right come
and give talks about tor it's a really
great thing for people who in countries
where you know actually really is a
matter of life or death for them to be
able to use tor or consider doing
research on tour making it better right
i mean i don't want to do non of my
school from tour for fun right I want to
make tour better and anyway you make
tour bettis by breaking it and then
fixing it right now unfortunately don't
know how to fix it very well so you know
I broke ok any questions then I'll just
say if you want any code right here's
the link to my github on there is the
modified tour client which collects all
of those hidden service address
is as loads of scripts a crawler
etcetera for going through all the
hidden services and then there's a link
for the FBI talking any questions sorry
I've broken into a break a little bit
tase old tales sorry yeah so there is a
there's a live CD version of live CD
version of torque or tails which is a
debian distribution with tor built into
it such that traffic can only go by a
tour or not at all right so that means
that if for example the FBI had written
an exploit which worked against firefox
linux and you would have been
invulnerable to it because that sort of
phone at home would also gone through
torrid tour as well so yeah very good
very good point is that is the tailless
thing as well so if your stairs doesn't
log anything as well seen if you don't
want to get caught after the fact when
you're the computer season you can use
towels as well and any other questions
then what why would you want to do that
we're an exit relay into tall I don't
see the value I don't see why it would
be useful sorry there's another question
was a no yeah
no because by the time I got to it the
server had gone down so you know I mean
that would be more useful you know could
you exploit the FBI oh no that's not
good idea is that I don't know what I
don't know if there will be no value it
there was no response process in the
shellcode so it wouldn't be no value in
the response itself now that would be a
bit interesting thing so you know
towards leave your toys a really great
project please support it right it
really does help people that are really
in really nasty countries it's also a
tool for us right if you really care
about anonymity and privacy right it's
really the only real solution we have at
the moment that really that really works
so I mean the only the only way that I
know there's two ways you can fit this
two ways essentially you can fix it one
is by adding padding but that overloads
the Tor network and you know there's
very constrained capacity available on
the tour now it doesn't really fix it
completely it just makes it much much
harder you know and the other one was
higher high latency network which again
you know who's going to use tor if it
takes a day to get a web page no
protect yourself when you yep you can do
you can root all tcp traffic through tor
so you know a standard vp8 well a tcp
based VPN you could easily route through
the exit mode then you know do you trust
your VPN provider yeah I guess that we
are I guess from my point of view kind
of assume that you've got a very
powerful adversary you know and that if
you're going to use a VPN and through
tor you see what I mean you just kind of
move in the goalpost of it you're not
really fixing the fundamental problem if
you say whatever ceiling mean that's for
ya so there's a quick solution maybe
yeah i mean i don't really trust VPN
providers personally
so that's a very good point so when you
when you went the tour client picks a
circuit to know any two nodes in the in
the tour circular aren't allowed to be
in the same / 16 subnet so you know you
could say psycho it's pretty not true
nowadays but at the / 16 something is
moving one IP one on one isp a couple of
ISPs so tour tries to minimize the risk
we're separating across you know much
much you know make sure that two nodes
aren't in the same subnets they're much
less likely controlled by the same
adversary and you can configure tour to
pick entry nodes in a particular country
and exit nodes in a particular country
which would you know might be useful in
some circumstances you know there's a
lot of configuration you can do with
tortured interesting things
what sorry I'm not familiar with that
I've road I'm not familiar with it okay
there is an alternative talk to tour
called IPP I thinks I PP ly two piece I
mean any any solution any solution which
helps these two aims you know the
privacy and anonymity it's got to be a
good thing you know tour I think of the
state of the art at the moment in terms
of in terms of technical solution and
certainly might in my do and may be
wrong on that of course I mean well you
know I may be right i mean generally
it's a general generally it's a bad idea
to mix your traffic with other people's
traffic you know if you run an exit
relay and you also browse the web by
that same address you know when they
come after you for doing bad stuff you
could say well i'm running exit relay
but do you browse the net through your
address as well yeah so you know there's
so much it's done yeah I see your point
maybe question I think about it more any
other questions quite the services when
we
couldn't we use like anxious to so for
the distribute hash table the way it
works is if you've been running for 25
hours and you offer more than I think 50
kilobits our bandwidth you're eligible
to participate in the distributed hash
table so the idea is that by requiring
50 kilobits of bandwidth and requiring
you to be on for 25 hours it kind of
route increases the amount of resources
and attacker needs to be needs if they
want to you know put a large number of
nodes on the district has table clear
doesn't stop it because we've got 40
notes but you know we've only got 40
notes because a student was runs a
hosting company at loads of spare
capacity was like here you go how about
you know stuff you know but it makes it
much more difficult it wasn't attack
from the University of Luxembourg which
showed that you could actually fake
nodes onto the distributed hash table
without using very much resources at all
but they they told the Tor project about
it and they fixed it so you know at the
moment quite expensive to run a large
number of nodes on the dish p dash table
vector we have to compromise lots of
machines how much yeah yeah yeah I think
that's all there's lots of things we can
do to make it a lot more difficult and
tour does do quite a lot of things to
make it you know generally i guess a
verte or it more difficult but it is you
know it is a process of making it more
difficult rather than impossible if you
see what I mean you know so okay thanks
very much