okay so here it started before I get
started let's finish the stupid
questions first does anyone in this room
not now what cross-site scripting is and
I I feel really stupid asking this sorry
okay I assume everyone that's great so
my talk is on CSP analysis or content
security policy and one knows what it is
content security policy okay we'll cover
that so short introduction to Edward
perfect to myself my name is Frederick
I'm 24 and I'm from Munich I work as an
information security officer at chip
digital so if you might may know the
site chip de smoothly German you can
find all the examples on the source code
of what I'm showing you here on hash to
execute calm / CSP so you want to check
that out the exclusive and you can ask
me questions anytime later or on twitter
at hashtag security ok so content
security policy is basically an HTTP
header so if you can request the side
you get a response from the server and
the server sense you're in the response
sends your HTTP header that says example
here Def Con dot org they have CSP
enabled and as a consequence e default
source self which tells your browser
you're allowed to load sources like
JavaScript files like style sheets
images stuff like that only from our
server they could specify from facebook
com or from wherever you want but
basically it's a whitelist so the goal
is cross-site scripting mitigation so
you can't just specify from evil calm /
give me all your cookies yes you can
include it if it's not here in the CSP
so obviously that's a nice thought but
not enough to mitigate cross-site
scripting just whitelisting sources
because if you have a cross-site
scripting vulnerability you could just
add your own code in line
so what CSP does besides whitelisting
sources is it blocks all inline
JavaScript so if you enable CSP on your
site it will probably not work anymore I
don't know I guess a lot of you guys
have a website that uses JavaScript and
probably not everything has been moved
to JavaScript files and included but
sometimes there's just the typical
script card script tags and then
javascript in between right in the dot
PHP HTML file so this won't work with a
CSP enabled other stuff that doesn't
work i am sorry to make it work as I
said you need to move it to a script
file and include it like this other
things that won't work is all evil
functions are blocked give all this evil
everyone should know that here don't use
it if you have CSP enabled you could
enable it on purpose of like opening all
ports on the firewall kind of destroys
the the purpose of CSP and another thing
which most people is really interest
interesting Lee enough sorry about that
don't know bar my function equals new
function that kind of declaring function
in JavaScript doesn't work as well it's
blocked by CSP and you can't enable it
the reason why most people don't know
this is because most people actually
don't take a look at the request for
comment but let's just go for blog posts
and it's not mentioned in most of the
blog posts so you might run into
problems with that okay yet another
thing that is blocked by CSP and you can
enable that as well is inline CSS so if
you have any we're on your side
something like this and header line one
headline one tag with the inline
cascading style sheets like font color
equals read this is a basic cross-site
scripting example we have an unsanitized
user variable and we can just add
anything after Bob and what I did here
is I added the one that they had a one
line with a style font color
was red and as you can see the header
defaced is added but it's still green
because by ocsp of course HTML is not
blocked will be disastrous but CSS is
blocked ok you can see all the
violations to your content security
policy in your browser which doesn't
help you that much if a user comes to
your page and browses it and stumbles
across a CSP violation but that you can
set up actually a report your I where
all these reports from all users are
sent to and you have detailed reports in
a lock which is kind of nice it's
supported by almost all browsers yeah
guess that not internet explorer these
are the only guys who haven't
implemented it yet at least not fully
they have some features but it's very
experimental and not really supported by
E actually I tested it with e IE 11
doesn't work so they're still behind
there ok so the question what is CSP as
frustrating it's really frustrating to
implement it you're gonna really going
to have a hard time doing it and if you
do please do your research first
otherwise you will break your site and
angry people will be at your desk
definitely so the question I want to
answer here is it worth it if it's
frustrating do we really want to put
that much time and effort into it for
that I want to take a look if it
actually does what it says it does so I
gathered all the information I could
find on attacks on CSP and try them each
one by one and let's take a look at that
so we have injecting javascript of
course sorry encoding javascript of
course there's always a way to try to
bypass stuff by encoding it we have
injecting into service I files if we can
inject into the files that are on the
server most content security policies
state that our own server is fine of
course why wouldn't they so we can
inject into those files then you're in
the clear if you can upload malicious
files of course that's another great way
to do it or if you can just
manipulate the CSP head itself okay so
first up this is actually interesting
because we're not encoding the
JavaScript to bypass the CSP so in order
to hide that we're using javascript
we're just encoding it so we can put it
in the URL field without breaking
anything and the meta tag is an HTTP
tagg and is therefore not blocked
because CSP can't block and HTML I'm
sorry HTML so what we do here is
http-equiv refresh' we telling we're
telling the browser of our victim to
refresh the page not any page we tell it
refresh the page base64 and that's our
JavaScript base64 encoded and wonder
what the victims browser will do is it
will take the base64 string decoded and
execute it so we're not on this side
with the cross-site scripting anymore
but we're still able to execute
JavaScript and the in the victims
browser which which is at least
something okay so that's the the most
basic attack another attack of course is
trying to inject into the JavaScript
files themselves so we have to move
everything from inside JavaScript to out
of line or inline JavaScript to out of
line JavaScript how can we inject
directly into these these documents so i
tried some stuff I tried evil which is
blocked but I tried it anyway I tried
VAR my function equals equals new
function which is how I stumble across
that this is blocked and I tried with
the help of a colleague of mine parent
node insert this actually works I'm not
going to show it here because it's just
a bunch of code and it's not that
interesting as I said I put all of the
content all of the code examples online
you can you can check that out if we
want it's really really awful code so if
you you shouldn't stumble across this so
the last example you shouldn't stumble
across this type of vulnerability in the
wild because we we really put a lot of
effort into making this
vulnerable enough for us to bypass CSP
so this was all important purpose and it
still took us a lot of time if you do
however if you take a look at it if you
find it somewhere in a while please tell
me because if it's out there I want to
see it let's hope not ok so another
server site injection is Jason because
changed Jason much more obviously it's
used for storing data and for reading
data from it so this is a basic PHP
commenting system it is vulnerable I
made it a bit more vulnerable not
because I needed to bypass ESP but
because it's more convenient that way I
don't have to think about encoding stuff
it's just as an easy example so you can
just store type in your comment post it
and it's stored in the JSON file and
what the chaser five looks like it's the
first line these are two comments in the
chase and file so you basically you have
a laser pointer here you have your text
field and then first comment which is
here and then you have the second
comment and what we want to do is we
want to close the chase in with the
square bracket add our JavaScript and
then open a new for further comments
what this does is it gives us valid
JavaScript and valid Jason so nothing
breaks if you just use this one so if
you the highlighted the gray highlighted
area it would just post this as it is
Jason will when Jason angkong code is
called will encode it and what you get
essentially is a comment like this but
you've not broken it because it will
escape all double tix so it's not going
to work if you charge you executed what
we can do is usually have seven encoded
and I actually never worked with UT of 7
before this so I was something new for
me what you get is this exact same
payload is now this string and if you if
you take a look at it there are no
double quotes no double ticks in there
double quotes right
so it's not escaped so we can't just
inject it and this is the exact same
string as will be stored in the JSON
file so it's not been altered so the
first three dots are just the first two
comments I've stripped them away for
better readability but this is exactly
what we get if we take the whole JSON
file and UT of seven decoded so
everything that's been stored in the
chase the file before and is decoded you
tf7 won't change so it's still the same
thing so that quite that works quite
well if we include it via we're the
script tag source equals and then our
comments JSON file and then type equals
application / JavaScript what what
chrome will will tell us is you can't
execute json file this JavaScript it's
not going to work because you have
strict mime type checking enabled and
that's not not allowed so what Firefox
says is this well that's quite
interesting I have to think you're a bit
with it actually if firefox gives you
this response only on firefox 4.1 4.01
and below the reason for this is mozilla
stripped all you tf7 support from
firefox 5 and the buff to be html5
compliant it still tries to execute the
Chasen though it just can't read it okay
so that brought me to another idea if it
takes anything you give it want to try
to upload that image and there are a lot
of vulnerabilities out there that think
you're uploading it in an image because
it's called dot jpg so what else could
it possibly be than an image right so
this is a really really basic examples
i'm sure you guys can think of a lot a
lot better ways to inject code in the
into images with this for simplicity's
sake we have a file called evil Dolce
pack actually it's a text file with
alert one in it and suppose we can
upload it to the server it's
theoretically of course
and then we can just tell Firefox if our
victim uses firefox of course otherwise
it will break to load this as a
JavaScript file and it will happily
execute it I tested it on Firefox 28 no
problem so this is still a possible
attack okay um let's get to the last
part who here knows whats ER LF
injection or carriage return line feed
injection asst okay basically what you
have is you have a new line thanks and
this the characters percentage 0d
percentage see ray which tells this is
the end of the line and now comes a new
line what we do this the the coda part
is basically an HD a PHP redirect page
so all it does is it takes the URL
parameter and tries to redirect it to
this source and what you can do is you
can call the side I call it read your
PHP and your l equals site this is our
side with the cross-site scripting on it
you can add the cross-site scripting
parameter if you can add them in the URL
and then just percentage 0d percentage
0a and don't put a line break in there
it's just for better readability because
otherwise the line would be too long
this is actually one line add your
header option which you want to to add
to the response from the server like
content security policy equals script
source unsafe inline we're just allowing
inside inline JavaScript to be executed
so we're telling the CSP allow inline
JavaScript which is as I said before
much likely allow evil function bad
never do it on purpose depends on the
side you're on right so what we do is we
add two crls at the end and tell the
browser header and everything that comes
now just forget about it this is the end
of our head
it works on certain machines depending
on the PHP version you have installed
because PHP actually fix that problem it
still works even though PHP fixed it in
some versions of Internet Explorer up
but I don't tested them because internet
explorer doesn't support CSP in the
first place so why bother that would be
any gain of it so it still works but
aside from PHP having that vulnerability
fixed and still in common vulnerability
so this is just an example which has
been fixed in the meantime but there are
still CRF injection vulnerabilities out
there and if you stumble across one and
there is a CSP in place you could use
this kind of attack to bypass CSP which
brings me to my at the end of my talk
does it work and for me CSP does
definitely work look strange because all
almost all of the attacks if they still
work rely on other vulnerabilities to be
in place so you have the crl f1 ability
that needs to be in place you have the
file uploads vulnerability that has to
be in place in order to bypass CSP so if
you have a secure site and only only
cross-site scripting on the side yeah
secure side and cross site scripting in
the same sentence then it's not going to
work except for the meta tag but there's
nothing CSP can do about that because it
can't block the HTML meta tag and once
the refresh is done it's not on the side
and you're not on the side anymore
that's protected by CSP so it's kind of
a way around it ok so the other question
is is it worth the hassle and that's
really for everyone else to figure out I
can't tell you yes or no for me it's
definitely worth the hassle I know how
much work it is and I know how much of a
pain it can be but if you take the time
and if you get the resources of course
for doing so it can help you because it
not only blocks cross-site scripting
attacks and gives it time to
them it also if someone stumbles across
it by accident it doesn't even realize
it you get a report and you know that
there's a cross-site scripting
vulnerability and you can fix it so for
me it's worth it okay so that was my
talk as I said you can find all the
source code and the examples along with
detailed explanations on hashtag
security of calm / CSP you can ask me
questions now later or on twitter at
hashtag security i want to thank my
mentor day for helping me and also a
colleague of mine who isn't here today
as scott for helping me with a
javascript the evil evil JavaScript and
thank you all for listening and for
having me