my name's Gavin halt I'm a fourth year
older student avert a university all the
way up in dundee and when the organizers
a security three conference happened
January and I'm the outgoing president
of the protein ethical hacking society
so I'll start with a brief summary what
we're covering today so why passport
theft is so dangerous because I think
some people forget other replications
other than already got passport stolen
how passwords are currently being stored
the good the bad in the plaintext ship
it you can buy me a beer later and how
honey words can be implemented what
honey words are the benefits of honey
words why honey words will not save us
all a quick summary of everything
discussed and they'll take some some
questions so why is passport fifth so
dangerous and it's a pretty obvious
answer because someone has your password
so speaks for itself but the less
obvious answer that the shroom will
hopefully not resonate with is because
then someone has your password for
everything paypal did a survey two years
ago 60-plus percent of users use the
same password across multiple websites
so it doesn't matter if Facebook stores
your password securely if it's the same
password for task or any other place
that has a password breach they now have
your Facebook password and directly
there was a three hundred percent
increase in a single quarter and
password theft I think everyone will
remember you know boom boom boom Beck
sites getting here and some of the
numbers are absolutely scary link 10 6.5
million Zappos 12 million ever look 50
million and the infamous adore be fair
to 8 million and some things you wonder
why we bother stealing passwords because
you only need to steal passwords if you
can't guess the password so if I look at
some of the adobe breach it's a
wonderful graphic this online so let's
say the adobe passport data on the left
and the password hints from plain text
so reigns with ass word hmmm sex x 1 so
with that sort of stuff here you do kind
of wonder why we actually still need
to steal passwords and then true geek
fashion there is an XKCD is the degree
is crossword puzzle and history called
the passport ends from plain tags in the
password for safer there's a lot of
usernames and passwords out there if I
know what you're all thinking people
don't store passwords and plain text
they didn't work out and do thee anyone
ever been to that website the amount of
people that store passwords plaintext to
do that you're up until very recently i
believe the GCHQ recruitment system
stores the past or just plain text they
already know anyway I suppose okay but
the bad guys are doing it right so
that's fine your little coursework
website plaintext passwords that's fine
but the bad guys are doing it right
linkedin 6.5 million passwords we're
insulted and even if people do so
passwords they don't always use a pair
use or so all it takes is a 10 minute
trade-off people can regenerate all the
rainbow tables so salting doesn't stop a
targeted attack and for your gaming guys
who absolutely love your new graphics
cards that's great for hackers as well
because password cracking is getting
faster you don't even need to have a GPU
in front of you you can rent for about
two bucks and ever and Amazon Cloud an
instance with a GPU and cracker it that
keyless number of passwords so making
the hashing more complex and
resource-intensive is only part of the
solution to stopping password safe
because when someone's got the dump if
they've determined to use it they will
we can do is target attacks they can
spend lots of time on it but how do you
know if your password has ever been
stolen so if you're a company you might
have IPS you may have ideas you make it
take some anomalies but how would you
know if passwords have been stalling
used and the chances are you probably
want some sneaky sis admins may put some
fake system accounts in the Active
Directory over so for example if Rory
logs and we can assume they can assume
they've been compromised because user
Rory doesn't actually work that it's a
fake account assess admins put in it's a
pretty left the idea honeypot account
but hackers are sneaky they can look at
the user account and see if it's
actually used you can see how often it's
used they can see is permissions because
if you create a honeypot cone this
actually got access to your ad then
you're being stupid
so hackers if they get access to this
account needle to profile it and tell
you fsellege account or not sopheak user
accounts aren't quite to fill proof but
we like the idea of making a high risk
getting game for the attacker that has
your data so what if we had fake
passports so this is where the concept
of honey words come in it was first
discussed in a paper by two guys jewels
and resist over at MIT last me and the
basic theory is after every user account
there are multiple passwords with all
one legitimate passport can we detect
passport left by watching for the use of
known fake passwords in the database so
a traditional unsalted md5 may look
something like this so we'll Gavin's
passwords test one Rory's passwords test
two and Thiago's as password so FS
database was compromised they would get
older database fired up something like
join the rapper Arabic chunky rainbow
table and you'll get the plaintext
passwords back in game they've got your
passwords so let's implement honey works
so how would you even go about making
fake passports they have to be
believable so if you've got 100 entries
and thing to name them a really secure
passwords and one of them's password the
real password stands out equally if the
user have got a really strong password
and you've got cat dog mouth sheep or if
they're all the same case they'll be
taken by animals the fake passwords
become particularly obvious so how do
they make honey works they have to be
believable there has to be some
low-hanging fruit because they have to
be crackable in order for the heck I
have to use them there has to be some
tough passports to leave the attacker
guessing if they've actually cracked the
right passwords are not as I discovered
when I'm rating a technical demo for
this you need to make sure that you
don't accidentally generate a honey
water for the user actual password
that's that wasn't there in to be fixed
up and we need to make sure that we can
identify fake passwords because if you
can then then you can really use them so
i started to dictionary select the
handful of what is a varying lengths and
in order to decide how hard i wanted to
meet the password
crack I mangled it up in lowercase
letters some things pre-painted numbers
and symbols painted numbers and symbols
substituted symbol then so threes and
fives and aces and things then
concatenate what is together and again
making sure we don't accidentally use
our user password so then we need to
take a correct check some of your users
password and we need to create some fake
check sums for all the honey ones will
generate it so a database now looks
something like this so user Gavin Rudy
Tiago and in a separate password stable
you've got your password hashes in your
checksums so our new method of attack
would-be attacker gets hold of a
database files up John gets the plain
text back but another example here the
vulgar one in five twenty percent chance
of getting the right password one in
five still quite a big chance after your
quartz of users lots of data beg
critical system but we can easily scale
up just by adding more honey words so
what would the workflow look like for
authenticating against that you would
start with your web server take the
passport in hash and pass it to the
database server the database error
retrieves the checksum where the user ID
and hash match and pass it to the
authentication server so if you don't
get a hash match on that user ID then
it's just simply a wrong password the
users must type something like that it's
a wrong password it's not a threat if
they do get hurt it takes the checksum
passes it's an authentication server
notification server does is it performs
an additional check the same check used
to generate the checksum on the hash
that was sent and what this does is
compares the hash it was saying the
checks I was saying the checks I'm it
generated to ensure that password that
you've taped in is the one that we took
to be the user to pass about a point
jane everything all the honey words and
that return true or false to the web
server so the web server gets back true
great real users organ they can log in
if it gets back false at this stage we
know that yes the password exists in the
database but no it's not our users
password therefore we know there are
password database has been stone so in
order to in a hundred percent
ft the attacker would have to get into
all three of these boxes and
reverse-engineer all the functions to
get a checksum to see which passwords
correct so now we need to know where so
nobody know rather when I password it's
been popularly additive database is used
we can only take password theft easy is
that so I'm afraid I won this thought
this was going to be really technical
and clever it's literally just more
passports and so what else can we do
with it we can do some clever things so
what if we regenerated the fake password
to periodically could we use that the
Chairman way in the password database
Pistone internally also companies have
different login systems may not all use
single sign-on so what if you could use
this to determine may need a password
breach and forth users to get the
passwords across the board so if you're
the central api api is the most common
type of honey bee by the way interesting
fact and because when you search api use
honey words doesn't come up with much
apartment picture 2 b's and essentially
pi/4 service to use so you can pass all
the knowing user IDs of compromise users
into this service i'm really tryna thin
take in something else in your
organization we can detect the potential
their passwords been compromised enforce
a visa across across the company so what
are the benefits of honey words they can
be used to detect password theft I don't
this is based on my dissertation I don't
quite about reading on it natalie and
that doesn't appear to be any other way
of detecting password theft reliably you
can use IDs you can I PS you can see the
data is exfiltrated you can see
successful login attempts from places
you might not expect about as far as I
can tell this is one of the few ways you
can actually detect passport theft it
can be used to prevent the use of stolen
credentials if you know password has
been stolen you can present prevent its
use across your organization invade
warnings to other services that s
passwords potentially getting reused and
it can be used the ter attackers from
trying to compromise kings
but I see the star honey words as a no
magic solution honey boards isn't going
to save us from everything honey words
won't stop your service being
compromised if I've got your passport
fail something has went wrong before
know if I'm able to acyl treat this data
from your database get a hold of your
passport fail get access to your ad to
dump the hashes some things went wrong
before now honey words won't stop the
passport from being cracked people will
still potentially get the plaintext
correct password so it's not stopping
people from the sling passwords to
taking their theft honey borders won't
stop attackers from gaining the legette
passport by other methods social
engineering keyloggers or if the users
password as just a passport it won't
stop someone from just breathing it
honey words are not a replacement to
strong password policy and user
awareness if your users are still
generating really really crowd passports
or are still being allowed to use really
really crap passwords and honey buns
will not save you Stanford University
nice two weeks of published crackfield
paper and their theory is the longer
your password is the less complex it has
to be and if enforced us across the
entire campus so if you've got eight
character password that has to have two
offers two lowers couple of symbols has
to be a certain level of complexity if
you've got 27 character sentence that
can be all lower-case so they're not
looking security get in the way of good
passwords they are allowing people to
have really good passwords about the
people who are going to try impact
rubbish passwords well the stopping them
so in summary honey words allow for
detectable passport there by seeding a
database with known wrong passwords
watching for these passwords in the
system allows detect when I've had the
database stone by modifying passwords
periodically honey what should be
varying difficulty disguise in sales I
think that's one of the most important
things if you try and take this away to
implement as your honey words have to be
uncrackable right down to low hanging
fruit because if watch thick so you've
lost the point over honey words are not
a replacement for strong password
policies
strong storage mechanism or getting your
users to secure themselves has anyone
any questions about honey words or
implementation you're saying that the
wrong path will look legitimate yeah and
if somebody has I'm actually sort of
rounded looking password and then you
add the wrong address to be capped off
sheet etc it's very noticeable how
important so it's somehow the mechanism
to generate wrong password should take
into account the correct password to try
to make a graphic that looks similar
dish or not to read yeah but that ends
that part of your system will know the
plaintext password at least while it's
processing the wrong yeah well
absolutely didn't system eek lingos the
plaintext password when it's hashing it
is you just get the krabby patty today
quickly for to make sure it stays in the
system
yeah yeah we'd be plain text and memory
for it also be longer
that's something I've not worked out yet
if someone has a dictionary and they're
Britain then potentially they could but
we should be real a meeting attempt
saying ma saw the chances of it being in
the four attempts five attempts are
unfortunately slim again if it happens
and if the system resets itself and
that's something to look at the
threshold perhaps of when you were
triggered on the layout for theft
anymore I'm led to believe lunch is
impending doing the mean for you so I
think if you head down there after this
is lunch it just after ten past one