thanks for having me I'm very excited to
be here I want to reiterate a couple of
things that the leadership said one
besides I think it's part of who we all
aspire to be and it represents the best
of what it is we as a community want to
be this is volunteer-led they're running
a not-for-profit if you see the core
organizers the volunteers give him a
high five give him a hug thank them
number two the rookie track go and
encourage those guys I don't I hope they
weren't all cancelled hook just a couple
okay just one cancelled excellent go and
encourage those guys finally go think
the sponsors spend some time with them
thank them for sponsoring it takes a lot
of money it takes a lot of energy it
takes a lot of resources to do something
like this so go visit with them being
encouragement and thank them for their
time and investment viruses malware and
threats oh my lions and tigers and bears
I have no idea where this title came
from very briefly a brief introduction
my name is Trey Ford on the global
security strategist for rapid seven I've
held a couple of different roles inside
of the industry probably much like many
of you I wasn't in any one of them for
too long as consultant or a solutions
architect I worked with a lot of very
smart people as a product manager I
talked to a lot of smart people and
incident response I hired a lot of smart
people and in general management Iran
spreadsheets and recruited a lot of
smart people I considered the security
community family and the primary role I
have at rapid7 is one of advocacy my
jobs to be a resource for our partners
in for our customers so one of the
things I want to drill into very deeply
today is the TBI are you guys downloaded
in red latest version oh come on if our
industry had an NTSB this would probably
be the right document right we don't
have reams and reams and reams of
actuarial data to dig into as a
community cyber insurance is based on
what where do they get these numbers
from if we look back into the history of
info SEC there's kind of the spectrum in
place
in the early days we looked at the
theory of self-reproducing autumn otta
this theory that code may echo we saw
creeper and Reaper following to clean it
up the term virus was coined in 83 a
couple years later Morris worm was
released hey hey hey hey that ran on
like Linux or UNIX right that's safe
from viruses I run OSX I know I'm fine
Morris is actually interesting in the
United States what brought Morrison to
play what later became as the Computer
Fraud and Abuse Act this this notion
where legislation said hey this secure
this computer stuff these hackers we
need to do something about it we need to
create a way to manage that it was in
response to this Morris was actually the
first person thrown in jail under the
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act in the 90s
we saw dos and windows viruses 2000 was
fun because through the 2000s we saw all
kinds of things i love you slam slammer
my doom in that time zone we went from
where we were cleaning up viruses how
many of you guys can like to just rattle
off all the the registry key hives you
need to go through and clean out when
you're manually removing a virus like
this was old school like not old school
I'm young old school for me that all
changed with Code Red Nimbus a sir this
is where the notion of we can't clean up
to get to a trusted computing base
things changed a little bit so we went
to the nuke and pave timeline but
thankfully antivirus saved us
this isn't being recorded is it is it
alright shout out to Dave Marcus I love
to give him a bad time so we saw an
evolution the storm botnet Zeus crime
where this is where things started going
from research and amateur work to
professional spy eye apt it's our
favorite acronym Stuxnet became a
reality so we're talking weaponized
government-backed malware spy I Bitcoin
mining and dexter point-of-sale one of
the things that we I think we all would
acknowledge and one of the things that
we're still trying to help people
understand this isn't about prevention
this isn't about blocking things out
this isn't just about hygiene a
determined adversary will find their way
in whether on purpose or accidentally we
will have a footprint given up in our
environment no industry no vertical no
infrastructure is resilient enough to
prevent it so the question becomes what
do we do about that so the classic
discussion is knowing your opponent I
think we're all somewhat aware of these
guys have to choose to the ice cubes
it's like the rudest thing I could do
we're not going to talk about the dbi
are I think the dbi are is very
important data I think it's something
that we should all spend time studying I
think there's a lot of relevant wisdom I
think there's a lot of data that helps
tell a story executives the business
these individuals all like to be able to
compare themselves I think the dbi are
is the first data point we have or we
can actually reference this where we can
actually look across the industry and
look at the largest coalesced incident
report and kind of share here's common
threads here's common points of failure
hears things that we know people are
blowing it on so what I would like to do
is spend some energy talking a little
bit about the good and the bad and how
we compare ourselves a little bit and
how we're different our opportunities so
criminal economics I think we're all
aware that money comes with
specialization we're all aware that the
bad guys the criminal hackers the bad
guys
evil ones I want to think of them as our
opponents they've specialized
specialized very simply there are groups
that right the mall where there's groups
that build the exploits those that
wrangle the bots those are actually
responsible for the attacks you don't
have to be an expert in any one area
matter of fact you can be a solid
business man or business woman and
gather by up recruit train work with
each of these people people from around
the world with their expertise their
bias their infrastructure and run this
business outsourcing every component of
it and we're all aware that most of them
are in it to make money this isn't the
hacktivists discussion or doing it for
the lulz this isn't talking about
whether or not they're in it for the
money it's a question of what in your
environment what infrastructure to you
and your clients your customers work to
try to protect the FBI recently
announced that the healthcare industry
is considerably further behind than a
lot of other verticals and in discussion
one of the things I wanted to underscore
with those asking for thoughts on this
was that if we take a look at this and
this is not very clean this pulls
information we're all familiar with how
databases work we spent a lot of time
messing with sequel injection finding
ways to interact with interpreters
finding large tropes of data data that's
easily parsed easily identified you can
write regex to identify and pull off
this is how target Neiman Marcus all
those kind of guys ran into problems
what's interesting about this is payment
systems are designed to detect fraud
they have a single point of
identification if I and the people in
this first full not for row that first
four rows are empty but the first 10
rows if we all shop to the same place
top to the same coffee shop on the way
here this morning and one by one our
card started being used for fraud they
would have a single point of purchase
they would say hey all the cards within
this window of time had been compromised
we're all aware these systems right how
does this work in healthcare
we guys evolved into a clinic seeing the
doctor and our information may or may
not be in a highly structured database
I've seen a lot of paper flying around
in the United States we signed a HIPAA
form I know that you guys have something
similarly you but when people start
taking copies of this information home
they don't just have my name my social
security number my national ID number
they have my medical history the names
of all of my friends and family
addresses I've lived in because they may
need that from a thorough history I
can't change any of that information
they've got everything it takes to apply
for credit on my behalf what's nice for
that attacker is that from the moment of
data collection to the moment of attack
the moment of actual compromise when a
credit lines open a credit cards
received a loan is place those sort of
things happen there's a large window
from the initial theft to that actual
compromise they have this large window
padding and protecting them we're all
familiar with the intrusion kill chain i
believe it was Lockheed that put this
together the cyber kill chain I think
this is important I think we're all
aware of the different types of defense
mechanisms that plug into each of these
I assume you guys almost all have
aspects of this would you consider
yourselves truly expert in any one or
two of them seriously give me a hand
here like some of you guys I know we'll
have a level of expertise in some of
these defensive areas all right almost
all of the incidents in the new DVR did
talk about deployment from all where
they also talked about compromise of
credentials use of stolen credit forcing
or reuse of those credentials there's a
couple key pieces that we all need to
keep track of but throwing away all the
statistics if we acknowledge at some
point they're going to get in I think we
need to have a discussion about how we
over emphasize or have historically
overemphasized prevention and we need to
drive a balance for response so I want
to talk about the good guys I believe
that we understand our adversaries I
want to talk about how an ounce of
prevention is not the same as an ounce
of response I want to talk a little bit
about why I believe as a community we
have a little
bit of a myopic focus so us this room
this family our brothers and sisters our
colleagues around the globe at bsides
I'm gonna lump in black hat because I
consider them family the trainer some of
you that are here present today were the
professionals people look to us for
guidance for perspective and I think
we've got a pretty solid understanding
of our adversaries we understand what
inside our environment there after we
were fairly confident how they use the
data that we house the data that we
don't own the data that were custodian
zuv how they monetize that how they
value that what they're going to do with
that I don't think we need to dig into
that I think we appreciate respect our
businesses I don't have to hash the
fundamentals you guys all know what your
business values how you guys make money
and how our job is to support that I
don't think prevention and response are
necessarily the same I've come to
appreciate that I believe response is
more important there's nothing I could
do with my team at black hat to protect
the network we were going to deal with
incidents sometimes you take these
things on the chin but i think that
detection containment eradication and
communicating openly about this stuff is
every bit as important in managing your
trust that you have with your customers
and your business partners are you guys
familiar with the term shadow IT some of
you I'm getting some nods we all used to
talk about going open source we used to
talk about going sass
but we don't control that anymore my
wife has the green business she has a
her masters in divinity my wife's a lot
smarter than I am far more educated that
I am far more eloquent that I am she has
no technical background zero my wife
runs IT for a medium-sized business
three four hundred employees global it's
kind of scary she runs their exchange
she runs their exchange she runs box she
runs all of their enterprise
architecture she does the new hire
training she has got access to
everything did I mention my wife's not
technical honey I want to talk about
octa what sochta what single sign-on
that's interesting why would you want
single sign-on Meg well I would have one
place to control people's login so i can
set them up and it goes everywhere if i
change their password it goes everywhere
what sounds interesting why would you
want to do that I swear I didn't start
this well I don't know I think it's
important it seems like like it's gonna
save me a lot of time well that's great
and when people are having issues i'll
have one place to go that sounds really
smart and last week when we had to let
this guy go it took me like 45 minutes
to clean this stuff up and we saw that
he was still logged into some things
that sounds bad why is that bad what do
you want to do about that this is
interesting to me my not technical
although extremely bright wife is
explaining to me things that you and I
know one of my best friends Quentin he
always says if you're explaining you're
losing I found that if i try to explain
anything my wife I've already lost and
when she starts articulating to me core
principles of what you and I would
consider to be good hygiene now we
haven't got to this patch thing for her
buddy but you know I'm not really their
CSO I kind of coach and throw things
over the wall like a this heart bleed
then get on it it's kind of amazing
because when they own it themselves the
conversations different are
with me so there's this other thing user
accounts a human to an account this is
not a one-to-one ratio how many of you
guys use personal accounts for work too
you're lying stop it all right how many
of you guys only use your work account
for LinkedIn yes what I thought now
marketing professionals deal with us all
the time most of this infrastructure we
don't have a one-to-one ratio we're all
accustomed to spoil too I'm an old
novell guy I can't say old olds not real
I believe in novell I love novell there
is this idea they had the NDS like the
the directory architecture right really
brilliant gj's remember getting excited
and active directory when you could drag
and drop a user into another oh you that
was awesome yeah we had that like I
don't know in 2001 maybe before nds old
school management it's all based on the
x-type 500 standard I come to appreciate
marketing in light of Novell because
they had some really bragging stuff
brilliant stuff remember that argument
that broke out between Apple and windows
we came up with the UI the GUI well no
that's not true hey guys if you want to
fight just letting you know i'm over
here at xerox that actually came from us
they under how much ever in the world
would be if they invested marketing
communications and this is something i
think we're starting to resonate with
insecurities so that the point I'm
trying to make with the users not being
a one to one thing we talk about users
we talk about accounts the thing is
that's not a clean one to one ratio the
enterprise we have a new higher ticket
that's generated we're all doing this
enterprise thing right we're all
compliant with our socks or whatever
international standards were using new
higher ticket comes up we set them up
accountant active directory that
populates out that Salesforce and Oracle
and all the other infrastructure items
they've got all these all these accounts
mapping back to Leni human but then
there's also these other accounts that
are outside of the environment that
aren't mapped to central login and maybe
octa and things like that are kind of
cool but how are we tracking this stuff
how many of you guys where whether
directly by title or by volunteer
fireman type
uniform and incident response title for
your company come on get your hands up
be proud of that you're my people yes
all right god bless you guys how many of
you guys have dealt of that group or how
meant the rest of you how many of you
dealt with accounts that weren't
corporate accounts you're finding out
that personal accounts on some level are
affecting corporate resources it does
happen well that's more hands than I are
all right this is a serious problem
we've got to be thinking about how to
keep track of this what I'm finding is
that you know I'm not going to talk
about d perimeter ization there's too
many syllables in there for it to make
any sense I want to think about this
notion that partnering with the user
empowering the user championing of their
safety becoming their trusted
counterpart I don't think that there's
any greater cause and there's something
that we're going to have to shift in our
attitudes and I'm going to go there in a
second we as a community I think have a
myopic focus on the technical why do you
think that is it's not something we set
out to do I don't think we all aspire to
be Dilbert is Dilbert international do
you guys do Dilbert over here okay I
don't ever know it's easier it's more
constrained we know exactly what's gonna
happen I'm not a very good unix admin I
came up in Windows did a lot with novell
nivelle apparently has some unix roots
but what I found in managing systems is
I asked it to do a lot of things and
with the constrained bit Martin's dead
on when I asked a system to do something
I provide a script an installer a GPO
there's a fairly structured amount of
behavior that I expect to come back out
of that right how many of you guys have
made the jump from the technical track
to the management track and I want
things successfully but you're you're in
the batting cage swing it at it a
handful and those are lohan's there's a
lot of them though all right I like
technology because it is constrained I
do have a measure of expectation but
what's interesting about this is I spent
my entire life
firing to it I studied my maths that's
how they say it here right Matt's I did
a lot of science I took a lot of I don't
know I didn't take a lot of programming
as much as networking and systems
management but I studied this forever I
banged my head on a hard table forever
I've broken my share of keyboards I've
always been working this I'm always
reading new materials studying the
latest technology stuff that's coming
out we all do this we do this nights and
weekends but I think this is an
aspirational thing and because this is
something we've spent so much energy
pursuing I think we elevate that now
when we make this jump over to to
management historically in infosec we've
not really respected so greatly our
management counterparts there's a lot of
csos out there there's a lot of middle
management out there I think they get a
pretty bad rap man my manager just not
very techincal I don't doesn't
understand what we do why were you in
the office so late Oh what was it like
golfing buddy I mean like we're trying
to fix stuff it's like they don't
understand this right now in this moment
in this chapter of history I think we're
in a really deep place because we're
seeing more and more executives more and
more senior management in infosec and IT
that have moved over made the jump from
technical contributors to management
these people understand us they've
fought our battles they've bled in the
same dirt they've had pager duty and
they know what that is I had a manager
when I was an IR come back in at three
in the morning he personally didn't
dispatch his admin he actually brought
us coffee showed up brought us coffee
brought us some warm food and left
literally came by once you guys know I
appreciate you I know what you're going
through who's at home sleep in and what
time of the yep look I'll check on them
that that's means leadership that was
amazing middle management technical
management they get a bad rap how many
of you guys have said the following
that's crap that's crap
middle management brought you something
your boss know your boss doesn't always
sit on the Executive Board they don't
know it doesn't go from god of the CEO
to them down through don't know at their
middle management something I'm guilty
of all too often and I'm sure that you
face this as well they've come to you
with something a directive decision that
we don't agree with and of course being
the strong infosec type we let them know
we laid it out because clearly I don't
get it we're not in that age anymore
what I think we lose sight of is that
these managers they listen to us they
care force they support us many of them
have walked a mile in our shoes maybe
five miles in our shoes I mean come on
guys we're in the next generation most
of us are standing on the shoulders of
giants some of those Giants are in fact
our managers and we lose sight of the
fact that these managers are bloody on
the side that we're not looking at
because they went to management they
fought the fight and they gave every
argument we just gave and more are we
guilty of that I'm guilty that I don't
want to be guilty bad but I am I have to
eat my dog food on this and so there
have been times I did this in I are of
course IRS kind of emotional and when
you're sleep deprived your extra stupid
Club monta doesn't help that at black
hat I did it but this is interesting
right because we lose sight that we've
worked so hard to educate our managers
and our counterparts that they lose
track they don't know what we're doing
they've fought the battle for us and
it's our job to help educate them on hey
making sure that you're articulating the
arguments correctly and there did you
remember all these other points and
sometimes you just have to take it you
pick your battles and that's their job
not ours oh dear imposter syndrome who
here has imposter syndrome don't reach
your hand I guess we all should
Marty I love your sitting in the front
the first stranger and you probably only
men in the room you're my boy imposter
some germs interesting because I think
with our pursuit of technical knowledge
technical mastery we achieve a certain
level of I clearly don't know enough is
it not true the more you learn the more
you understand you don't know crap is it
not true when you meet with these
trainers this this is this was probably
one of my favorite things that I'll
never live down at black hat working
with the trainers and the more senior
speakers I've never met a more humble
community of people that will meet you
wherever you are I promise you working
at black hat you don't know crap you're
talking to trainers you're talking to
researchers especially the new kids
there come in man I got this what does
that even mean you already black hat
well no you don't understand dude like
you're one of three people get it can
you use small words and talk slowly and
help me understand what's coming out of
your mouth right now because I do not
get it imposter syndrome is interesting
because i think in product management i
should do a blog post on this and
product management i learned about the
curse of knowledge you're a security
professional you're a security
professional year security professional
when you go talk to your wife your
spouse's your girlfriend your neighbor
the coffee shop girl whoever about
anything you do for a living start a
stop watch and see how long it takes for
them to glaze over unbelievable dude has
met all kinds of time figuring this out
it's awesome why don't you care the
curse of knowledge is awesome because
once you know something you just assume
people know it's so clear I figured it
out scariest position I've ever been in
coming offstage from doing a big talk at
black hat fired up nailed it I think I
nailed it and some dude walks up he's
like hey so that that application you
were talking about did you find this in
this and how did you get past it I'm
like oh shit it wasn't as deep as I was
Oh help so what's interesting about this
is one when you're doing this research
when you're finding something not only
are you doing something that is rarefied
air you're one of a handful of people
that may or may not get it number two
when you go on stage to talk about it
you're one of a few people the room that
it's actually going to keep up let me
illustrate my point dan kaminsky on
stage opens a terminal window I did not
say pop to shell opens terminal terminal
inner pops terminal standing thunderous
applause of black hat can you explain to
me what that's all about how often do
you could open a command shell at work
do you hear applause your stalker
tweeting over the energy no there's
nothing happening so the curse of
knowledge just be aware of this and
don't assume don't be upset when people
don't follow but just be aware of this
this curse of knowledge it haunts us
everywhere so when I think about the
middle manager when I think about the
presentation that we give to IT when I
think about lining somebody out even
inside my security team that understands
me you guys know this is i can promise
you when i did a google search to find
permission to reuse this graphic i
cannot find a copy this so this is not
going to be the official slide deck it's
coming out muhammad ali's standing /
sonny liston you'll want to lose your
money a better bet on Sonny how often do
we walk into a meeting fired up because
we've done the homework people often
misunderstand us because we're cocky or
smart I think that doesn't necessarily
map to the best the best traditions the
honor that is the community the
shoulders that we stand on the Giants
that have held us and coached us and
support us and lifted us up I think that
we're often miscast because we speak
from a place of conviction it's actually
humility and passion we stayed up all
night we read the rfcs we banged on
until we got there and I think we're
often misunderstood
so what separates the bad guys the
hackers the criminals from the good guys
it's not the relentless pursuit of
accuracy relentless pursuit of actually
popping a shell success in an attack
even necessarily even success in our
business objective which by the way
isn't necessarily breaking the damn
production environment after Muhammad
Ali laid out Sonny listen you got to
walk away to only 28 years old look at
me not a mark on the face the criminals
are in it to cash in they have a
singular objective a singular focus
that's what makes them successful
clarity of vision they know what they're
out to do they're driving a business
they're driving revenue they're cashing
out those for the lulz they've defaced
your page they didn't take anything
that's great all right good game but
that's that's not us the thing is when I
think of infosec when I think of the
community that has been so warm and kind
to me to welcome me and my peers and put
up with me and I wanted to tell my first
trip as a PCI auditor story to you guys
I don't know that I've got the guts to
do it that's probably for another time
but when I think of information security
I think of a picture more like this what
is her name Meghan Vogel winning the
argument drop in science that's not
success Meghan Vogel is a track athlete
believe this was in high school she's
run in a race she's not doing so great
the gal that was in the lead drop she
collapsed she overcooked it I think we
all come out of the gates a little hot
sometimes I'm just starting to get back
to running I hate running I still hate
it so Megan's coming towards the last
round and you know rounding towards the
finish line towards that last straight
100 meters are so out this gals
collapsed track has rules it says you
don't offer assistance to any other
athlete that's basically designed to
prevent you know me from boxing someone
Alex I'm slow and out of shape so my
track star athlete can pass megan stops
and picks this gal up
totally crushes her opportunity of
putting up a solid performance but this
gal she was leading it she had a bad go
picks her up and helps carry across the
line being right proving someone wrong
god help us embarrassing somebody that
that's that's not who we are it's not
what we want to be how many of you guys
control the pl and the resources in the
IT department two hands see me
afterwards I'm buying you beer I got to
learn your trick your secret I don't
know how you do it for the rest of us in
the audience guys our success is found
in our partnerships in our counterparts
we've got to support these guys we do a
lot of self-policing we and we have to
as a community and there's a right way
and a wrong way to do it I'm healty of
this I was poking somebody this week
they shall go unnamed and my attitude
was wrong and the wolves were true and
real but as a community I think we need
to find ways to partner to pick each
other up to support and courage find the
right way to call people out but at the
end of the day I think we're all kind of
focusing on the same thing how many of
you guys during the heartbleed incident
got on the phone with a competitor or a
peer outside of your company to compare
notes hold your hands up higher stand up
guys give these guys a round of applause
please
you know there's nothing in this
industry that encourages us to do this
I'm not going to ask for the number of
hands bound by multiple NDA's in this
house how many of you have to clear with
legal before you can do a talk let alone
put something in writing let alone a
customer-facing email it's hard but in
those moments remember we're entrusted
with this data this isn't ours that's
not my credit card number i gave it to
us we did a transaction but we're
custodians it turns out our competitors
down the street this isn't competitive
advantage this is protecting the greater
good right I think this is important and
I think these conversations have to
happen so when I think about things I
want to think about how some of what our
opponents are doing are better than what
we're doing I know it's against the
rules you're not supposed to put a bunch
of words upon the slides but I don't
know how bad jet lag is going to be
something to cheat I'm sorry playing to
your respective strengths specializing
the bad guys turns out the best exploit
riders aren't the best botnet herders
aren't the best money mules they
specialize right early on as a pretty
decent systems engineer wasn't too bad
with windows management group policy was
pretty decent and troubleshooting a
network I don't want to think a very
good at excel but I'll be dogged at
black hat if I didn't get really good at
excel that's where I live my life but I
think we need to find ways to specialize
to drive energy into that we need to
capitalize on our natural strengths the
criminal enterprise has something a
little different in terms of competitive
issues and having beer with a grog and I
recommend if you ever have a beer make
it one those of you that know the drug
you know that that's the right solution
hey Marty when we partner with
organizations we partner with other
professionals when you hire your partner
when you're interviewing and meeting
with security talk to the IT team and
figure out who you're going to be
working with their your lifeblood when
you partner you don't have to worry
about them present potentially being a
snitch what you're doing is on the most
part up and up most of the time
when you do something stupid it's
different we clean that up later but you
don't have to worry about them being a
snitch or necessarily trying to cut you
out or double-crossing and stealing your
money criminal enterprise has a
different trust barrier trust
architecture and liability structure
than we do so finding ways to make it
safe for your research team to do
research making it safe for your
communications team to communicate how
many of you guys work in marketing
working communications I don't see I
know you're lying there's two of them
over here turns out I now work in a
marketing crew my jobs to help with that
but it's very strange because how many
of you actually trust the marketing team
to say hey on behalf of the research
team this is the right thing to say and
I'm not gonna review it I trust you not
a hand it's truth it's scary finding
ways to trust find ways to give things
away I think the hardest part about
security is finding the right way to
trust I love that from a user standpoint
users are becoming more suspect heart
believe was interesting wasn't it is
there a Ben and I'm throw this out for
feedback has there been a single
incident in the history of the internet
where people not just techies not just
security folks people at large we're
launching scans against our web servers
banging on our site my mom asked me
about this what is that all about I got
an iPad so I wouldn't have to deal with
my computer questions dude no I'm
scanning this and I'm well is it safe to
log in to cox guy got to pay the cheese
and use cocks but i want to login and
pay my bill can I do that I don't know
mom won't you call and ask who do I call
I don't know figure it out home kind of
cool like this isn't just like I don't
know the NSA general Alexander giving us
the opportunity go talk to our families
at the dinner table this was different
right it became personal finding new
ways to expand their gifts the bad guys
have it a little easier than we do our
opponents have it a little easier than
we do I'm trying to get to this gender
neutral messaging and I'm doing a
horrible job I like my fighting and war
medal
I got away from bad guys that's 12 sorry
they have it easier because they could
just specialize in very lucrative ways
don't they how many different hats do
you have to wear in a daily basis those
of you and I are wearing at least a
dozen but how many of you guys have one
clear job function let me get this
straight your job is to fire up a vm
login to tour check in 23 encrypted
email accounts move some funds around
and get off the internet and get back
across town now it's the drug the rest
of us should checking the page or check
of the cell phone check about Twitter
check on the facebook check on the
LinkedIn check the corporate email
checking the giro checking the
confluence check down never stops what's
interesting about this is how many of
you have spent time outside of our
technical pursuits exploring how do you
better communicate to our business
counterparts have taken managerial
classes may be worked on an MBA for
those of you they don't believe that
stuff jumped in into like advanced Excel
classes worked in public speaking even
it's something silly I started take an
improv and let me tell you if you want
to get past your notion of I'm
uncomfortable on stage they make you do
everything stupid in the book
unbelievable make up a sci-fi creature
enacted on for the next ten minutes
horrible but it helps you communicate a
little differently what's very strange
about this is an improv I come to
appreciate that it doesn't have to do
with the science I drop how eloquently I
hit my messaging how very clearly I
articulated a solution and architecture
a problem or business case remember that
thought if you're explaining you're
losing communication is what the
listener does communication is what the
listener walks away with has nothing to
do with you has nothing to do with how
you did or what you covered the meeting
is literally about getting them to walk
away with ownership of a problem I want
to move to centralize authentication
when you move to octa it's mind numbing
I don't know how it happened I wish I
could figure that out my wife is so
smart
so sometimes when I start looking at the
problems we're facing in infosec I think
of Dave Marcus and ichante channel my
spirit animal Dave Marcus and I realize
some of the kids coming out of college
right now have been watching us turns
out Twitter remove that veil of
brilliance where we sounded so smart on
the mailing list we spent a lot of time
certain things out our own networks and
talking to peers in IRC these kids are
coming out with far more expertise
running incident response for zynga I
assure you I've worked only a handful
via our incidents but hiring these kids
out of like CCDC are you does your path
like at CCDC kind of thing CCDC
collegiate cyber defense competition
it's basically like a red team exercise
for college colleges all right dude you
guys got to get in on this all right so
what they've got is a bunch of
universities that get together and
they've got it's like a CTF environment
they're running a full-tilt capture the
flag just like Def Con or anywhere else
you'd attend except it's organized
college teams do these kids know how to
lock down a bsd box they've learned web
app sec they've learned exploit
development i mean like these guys know
everything that we spent forever trying
to figure out or for me sitting back and
watching what's interesting is they have
all these skills but they can't
communicate it they can't message it
they they can't put together a PNL the
profit-loss sheet they can't communicate
it to the business they're excited to
want to take over the world they want to
do it all right now one guy literally
tore apart our entire puppet
infrastructure owned the puppet platform
and was literally rebuilding aspects of
the git repos in production without
talking to anybody honest lunch break I
cannot articulate what that meeting
would like but my boss called me in to
say I do what's going on puppet you get
it people can't get in they don't know
where stuff when it's like the Chipmunks
Alex
amazing the things these guys teach you
so I've got to be sensitive time I want
to wrap this up so you guys aren't late
getting started how do we live this
something that rapid7 CEO and I don't
always love how things are positioned
but I love the sentiment behind it Cory
in my interview process and i spent
seven weeks reflecting on do i want to
go to rapid something to work there
they've had a bum rap they've had some
rough sales history in the past
launching and this company has made some
hard decisions and made some big
investments something Corey has he's put
this into the minds of all the employees
all the teams and something he does
himself every week he stops and reflects
in the question what am i doing what
have I done this week right now what is
on my calendar for this week that makes
me more relevant what am i doing right
now and I'm not talking existentially
through my job duties in the umbrella
organization of a part of what am i
doing myself right now it makes me more
relevant how am i changing the
information security space how am i
doing to leave what am i doing to leave
this better than I found it and this is
something that I think we have to live
and we have to is still this in our
teams and our peers and we need to
demand this of ourselves we need to hold
ourselves a candle to this idea we need
to find and create heroes these are
people that are going to stand for what
we believe is going to be the best in
information security these are the
things that we aspire to personally and
professionally this is something that I
really got into something I really think
makes a lot of sense one of the things
deals with helping others seek to do the
right thing doing a good job is
marginally more expensive than doing the
job and exponentially more effective I
have no idea where that quote came from
these aren't like statistics where you
can make him up on the spot somebody
said this I feel bad I couldn't find
them a source some of my favorite quotes
usually come out of chats with mercurial
you guys know or if you've got a phone
look him up on Twitter and fallen he's
awesome earlier when I talked about
reaching out to people outside of your
organization for feedback I get in
trouble for this I
love to reach out to people i know that
our experts in my opinion smarter than
me in areas that i can learn from that
will challenge me that will stretch my
perspective or will call me out Trey
that's crap I understand you're upset
but that comes out of your mouth you're
going to fail that's not going to be
effective you're not going to win people
over they have to own it help them get
there we've all talked about this I
wasn't there like some support that says
it costs like ten ten or a hundred times
more expensive to fix a bug after its
release to production than it was in QA
it was one of the source code production
reports I don't know that we've sold any
of those problems we're making progress
but i think the sentiment carries that
if we're going to do something you know
this probably flies in the face of agile
methodology that's a whole different
philosophy we're not going to get into
that today but doing something right is
worth the additional investment rich
came all the way from San Francisco
today rich is I called him the director
of Awesome he was my senior marketing
guy at black hat I used to preach
something called virtuosity anybody know
what virtuosity is she got up my pee all
right so virtuosity this is the notion
of doing the common uncommon Lee well I
don't know why it's always like a little
asian kid on the piano or the violin
that I always think of little childhood
virtuoso they pick up an instrument they
sit down and they play they play
something simple and they played
elegantly doing the common uncommonly
well I didn't help found I didn't help
organize black hat I was only there for
two years I had the honor to and the
privilege to work with the team to try
to help serve a community in this role
and there's no one on earth that wants
to put on a t-shirt with a bull's-eye on
the front back and say I can run this
that's why I hid in the back I didn't
want my name out there virtuosity what I
thought our keys for success what our
table stakes were to stay in the game
was to focus on core components where
every time we touched an attendee I
wanted to be the best experience we can
make it I wanted to try to find and
distill
execute on what we felt the core
principles were I think this applies to
every aspect of life I don't know who
originally came up with this I'm pretty
sure every coach I ever played football
your football not America's football
every coach I ever played for always
preach the same thing we're going to
focus on the foundation a little shuffle
step or you kick the ball back and forth
you do the little dance moves with the
soccer ball football doing the common
uncommonly well and I think this applies
to everything else when we tear apart
the dbi are and we look at the failure
report card now don't think this is
because we're focused on fail don't let
anybody feed you that when we focus on
the report card what we're studying is
lessons that we can learn from other
people's beads right we're falling down
to the fundamentals who here has
patching nailed and I mean nailed and I
mean nailed yeah what's up let's not go
there so I'm not going to hammer this
any further if it's worth doing it's
worth doing right and maybe it's worth
doing right the first time that's the
department of redundancy department OD
is always fun and I like to argue Oh day
we get into this discussion a lot around
major conferences I think aloria if you
guys are following what's the little
gift Twitter stream yes security
reactions that's awesome follow it not
always safe for work but you guys are a
little relax in Europe security actions
awesome because always make fun of like
the one person that's dropping Oh day at
a conference and there's like the cat
freaking out and all the puppies
crawling all over the cat dropping O'Day
is important and interesting how many of
us in all seriousness literally fire off
red alerts to our teams and launch into
action every time an oday is discovered
all right some of us are full of it
you see we're all aware and I think we
all believe this on some level but we
have to articulate this clearly at any
point in time there's always Oh day
floating around out there we can't be
responding to this Oh day is simply a
sanity check we have to be prepared and
be defending against the sort of stuff
we need to be prepared to instrument
when we find things the most interesting
conversation about heartbleed was how do
i really know like can I figure out not
just am i being hit but who maybe is
more interesting well it doesn't have
really artifacts of attack didn't have
intrusion indications we're going to
land in one of these departments gin
savage probably had one of the most
succinct thoughts and this came through
probably around midnight last night when
I was rebuilding my powerpoint deck
manual tasks you don't do regularly
aren't emergencies I think the salient
point that she's making here is that I
don't know if we always do the most
effective job of automating the things
that need to be done frequently how many
of you guys are tracking I'm not talking
logging actually doing something with
the data that comes from successful
login attempts we have two people here
that know about PCI two of them
successful login attempts are terribly
interesting for those of you with
production environments having a jump
box is great because idiot lateral
logins that didn't come from that box
lights on let's go right these are
interesting thoughts how we leverage
data that's available yet another quote
from mercurial I'm going to wrap this up
pretty quick resilience in the face of
failure is better than planning 40
failure resilience in the face of
failure how many of you guys have ever
dealt with a water or power outage mass
hysteria and the streets dogs and cats
sleeping together it's like the worst
parts of the Bible right no dude you
fired up here where you guys call them
torches here right your flashlight and
you're fine IT departments are not
motivated in that way how many of you to
this day have IT departments that are
motivated they get their bonuses their
additional income based upon uptime
percentages raise your hand Martin
almost everybody right it's all about up
time it's all about availability this is
hard because resilience doesn't always
dictate safety doesn't always dictate
being online of being available you got
a couple giggles there come on bro DV
chaos monkey you guys know what chaos
monkey is right this is bill burns 501 C
3 on Twitter chaos monkey is literally a
script design in production to turn off
servers to kill processes to break
things in production why is that a good
idea how many of you are in pin testing
red teaming attacking keep your hands up
y'all yes I'd yell I'm wearing cowboy
boots get off my lawn how many of you
guys have how many of you do not have
scopes of work keep your hands up when
you do an engagement you don't have
anything that's out of bounds come get
some I got a couple shaky hands a couple
shrugs and a couple of real big smiles
attack just don't have scopes of work
they don't and I had a discussion of the
CSO and I'm praying and hoping and I'm
pushing and cavorting I'm going to find
a way to blackmail them into doing this
there's a CSO prominent organization on
the internet that we all know and love
and use that is advocating the
elimination of this notion of scopes on
his red team entirely we all do tape
backups we do online backups ever to use
in VMware virtual Hardware cloud
infrastructure backups are totally
different how can we can't test this
stuff somebody gets inside what do we do
I think we would all agree with this
this is an interesting problem I'm
hoping I can talk this guy into doing
this I keep wanting to say his name just
a force them I can't bring myself to do
it this next bullet is brought to you by
America's TSA
I hope they're not a rapid 7 customer
100% defense is not possible so parting
shots I request I think was Kevin Mandy
at RSA is said the Air Force taught him
that you can only give three bullets so
I'm going to blow that I'm just going to
be a whole bunch more respect criminal
hackers as business professionals we
need to honor that our opponents are
focused their diverse their specialized
and they're efficient what they do we
need to achieve virtuosity on the
fundamentals this isn't something we do
on our own this is something we rely on
our partnerships and those were
supporting and we're investing we carry
those that have fallen and those are our
partners and we're there for their
success champion response in prevention
part of this means discussing otay
better not using it as a fire drill item
but as a sanity check and discussing
well this has been out there fire bleed
was heart bleeds out there for two years
this is interesting what's our solution
set for this automate where you can
winning isn't enough give up on being
right and challenge each other to expand
your skill set things that aren't just
technically oriented I'm not saying
everybody needs to go middle management
about saying everybody has to jump from
being a technical contributor to being a
people manager but we need to help those
guys that's a hard transition it's hard
to do it's hard to be successful it's
hard to be happy doing but help expand
your gift sets long ramp I think I'm
right on the money you got 10 minutes
left any questions we rotten tomatoes or
eggs guys it's an honor and privilege to
be here thank you so much for having me
you