[Music]
hey guys
thanks for coming out to my talk I'm
gonna be talking about breaking
detection with exit 86 is a specific
malware
my name is Chris Hernandez it's my
twitter handle i'm the red team program
manager at code 42 former sysadmin pen
tester and built a few red team programs
company in the u.s. called target and
before that i was a consultant at
various group adaptive threat division
done some that group has done some
offensive PowerShell development that
you guys might be familiar with but for
today's agenda what we're going to be
talking about is the state of detection
malware detection in the enterprise the
state of AV evasion or what adversaries
typically try to do to you know hide
their payloads I will go into a high
level overview of the x86 is a and go
through some thought process hypotheses
and testing and then finally we'll have
a few proof-of-concept videos so before
I get started I wanted to acknowledge a
few researchers who've done really
interesting work on sort of like
similarly themed topics so Josh Pitts
and Travis Mauro have done some really
interesting work on genetic mal warlike
keyed malware and then Christopher Domus
has done a lot of really interesting
work just on x86 in general and this
talk tries to kind of combine both of
those tracks and then one of the quotes
that kind of got me thinking about
actually presenting this research is
from matt graver and he said as an
offensive researcher if you can dream it
someone has likely already done it and
that person isn't the kind of person who
speaks at security cons
so here I am talking out a security con
so sort of the genesis for this idea was
really I wanted to ask the question can
I make sure that my malware or my agent
runs on my target and not other places
to the best that I can control and what
can I do to ensure that this doesn't
take place in code because if your
malware sample gets caught by any sort
of Detective capability right eventually
it's going to get to a reverse engineer
and you know really no malware can
sustain the you know the work of a group
of trained reverse engineers for long
enough but as somebody who does
adversary emulation my job is to really
make that make their job as hard as
possible so that I can like persist and
have access as long as possible in order
to achieve my objectives so this is kind
of what the state of malware detection
looks like in most enterprises or most
enterprises that care about security
will do things like block suspicious or
malicious domains check DNS will block
suspicious or unusual emails and
attachments with some sort of mail
security appliance now we block
untrusted code with either you know app
white listing or black listing or
certificate validation we might block
malicious code with machine learning or
signatures or magic pixie dust whatever
the newest you know trend is in the
detection space
hopefully we're scanning and ingesting
all of the unusual traffic that we see
in our environment so whether that's
files crossing the you know crossing the
wire or unusual files on an endpoint so
for example there's a number of like
next-gen
solutions that like if you drop a binary
to disk and that binary has not been
seen by that software before they
immediately grab the binary and ship it
back to their sand boxes for their own
analysis and then presumably you know
your organization might be subscribing
to some threat Intel feeds looking at IO
sees and then searching for those
particular IRCs
IO sees in your environment pivoting on
that and trying to find bad stuff so at
a high level the state of malware
detection in the enterprise kind of
looks like this the the bottom level of
the pyramid is just an alert gets
generated and something about that alert
is interesting to a triage analyst or
your entry level analysts in your sock
and our job as red teamers or as
adversaries is to either make our
payload look as normal as possible try
to hide the evil that we're doing or if
that isn't possible make their job of
understanding our payload as difficult
as possible so in this case our goal is
if an alert is generated we want that
alert to get passed to a triage analyst
so you want the triage analyst to not be
able to understand what's happening and
we want them to escalate that to a more
senior analyst or a reverse engineer all
of those steps are going to be buying us
adversaries a little bit more time in
your environment so that's on the
detection side what does the offensive
side typically look like so things
you've probably seen before are your
some of your payload or some of your
payload stages being encrypted along
with anti debugging techniques anti VM
techniques obfuscation and environmental
keying or that's that genetic malware
that Josh Pitt's had presented on and my
thought was that like all of these
things are current
deployed in code and yes it's a computer
so you can never fully get away from
code right ultimately it has to execute
at some point I thought was what if the
code that I'm trying to execute is
allowed to execute on my target systems
or specific target systems that I'm
interested in and due to some form of
hardware incompatibility it's not able
to be executed on things like the
sandbox or even even better the
reverse-engineer system so in order to
set up this testing environment there's
a few you know few things that we had to
think about and that is that the x86
instruction set is not a static
instruction set you've probably heard
that it's a Sisk architecture meaning
it's complex and more and more op codes
or registers or features can be added
it's also a fact that if you have a
newer x86 CPU it might be capable of
doing something that older systems are
not capable of doing and that's actually
taking place in hardware like if there's
new registers or new instructions
specifically registers like those things
wouldn't exist on the older cpus and so
the other thing to consider is there's
probably no environment that anyone uses
that's a monolith meaning everyone has
the exact same computer on workstations
and servers and in the cloud so
typically we have different CPUs and as
a result different ISA features on our
desktops versus our servers versus what
we're using in the cloud some of that we
can control and some of it we can't so
as I mentioned before x86 is a complex
instruction set over time there's more
and more op codes that get added to the
instruction set some can even be taken
away there's lots of undocumented
instructions and then there's some
really old research on
thirty two-bit malware and legitimate
binaries that was done in 2006 and where
roughly 90% of all the opcodes present
in the binaries that were tested was
accounted for by like 14 opcode so the
majority of x86 instructions while
there's like hundreds of actual op codes
available there's very few that
typically get executed in your your
average you know executable file format
so as I was doing the research I I
realized that there's a lot of
similarities between what we're doing
here and keed malware right but I think
the key difference is that for Ketan
malware you're deriving you're deriving
the key from something in the operating
system or something that is part of
maybe the network or the domain or a
driver and typically you'll read that
key and then use that key to decrypt
your second-stage payload here I would
call something like this maybe is a
keyed malware because what we're doing
is we're not we never read a value from
the system such that reverse engineer
could never wouldn't be able to see like
oh the this binary is say for example
reading the domain name and using that
as the key to try to decrypt this stub
so if I supply the right domain name I'm
supplying the right key in this case a
reverse engineer would have to supply
the right CPU so there's definitely ways
to you know work around any of these you
know techniques however it's a little
bit more complicated to go find the
correct hardware than like patch a
binary again in software so historically
what we've seen is that
intel has added new registers and new op
codes or instruction sets with every
major release of CPUs and what I thought
when I started doing this was that each
CPU was going to iterate exactly on top
of the next one meaning like every CPU
that comes out today will be backwards
compatible with all of the prior
instruction sets and when I was looking
into it that actually wasn't the case so
you can if you think of our CPU
fabricators as software developers
they're trying new things instead of in
code they're fabricating CPUs and some
of those things don't work and so they
go a different direction much like a
developer would so here we can see in
the early West aamir Xeon processors
they added support for 128 bit registers
and enhanced SSE instructions and then
the xeon e5 family added support for the
AVX instruction set and 256 bit
registers previous the next generation
after that added additional AVX
instructions still at 256 bit registers
and then something interesting happens
in the middle there's the Xeon Phi
coprocessor and Intel came out with this
it had support for 512 bit registers
however it had no backwards
compatibility with any of the previous
instruction sets and then at some point
Intel realized that that wasn't really a
good idea so they sort of abandoned that
architecture and in the second
generation of the xeon phi processor
they they changed that and they went
back to backwards compatibility as well
as adding avx-512 instructions and on
the last column the important thing to
note is that they added some avx-512
instruction sets from the previous xeon
phi processor not all of them and then
added new ones so in the in the recent
years there's quite a variety in the
number of in the types of op codes that
your processor could actually support as
a result there's a ton of different
registers that exist on your CPU and I
realize that this slide is pretty small
but on the right hand side are all the
registers that you might be familiar
with like the instruction pointer stack
pointer base pointer all those kinds of
things however on the left hand side
those are all the things that we're
interested in using for is a specific
malware because those are the
potentially missing registers in certain
CPUs so on the right hand side the blue
column are the 128-bit registers purple
column is 256 bit registers and the
final pink column is a 512 bit register
so there's actually a lot of registers
that have been added and as somebody who
hasn't done a lot of like assembly
programming that was pretty interesting
to me so now we need to move into
testing our hypothesis so in my
environment our testing sandbox was
running an older xeon e5 processor so op
codes that we might want to test would
be 256 bit or 512 bit op codes and using
either of those sizeof registers as well
but first we've got to do some
baselining so we're gonna generate some
like standard vanilla x86 malware and
see how our sandbox is score it and then
we're gonna see if we can enumerate the
hardware on certain sand boxes without
having access to it of course our test
sandbox we do have access to but as a
red teamer
or adversaries potentially won't have
access to your sandbox so they need to
figure out a way to get that data out of
the sandbox so okay
our basic test case with general generic
like x86 and x64 opcodes it was a
meterpreter linux reverse shell we
uploaded it to a couple of different
sandboxes and virustotal
and it was scored appropriately so out
of you know a hundred being completely
bad it scored at 91 or ranked malicious
and then 11 out of roughly 60 AV
engine's detected the file no surprise
there right some interpreter second test
case was the same thing only for Windows
and it actually scored worse even though
it's essentially the same thing
different operating system and because
it's a Windows binary we had support for
more sandboxes uploaded to all the
sandboxes and it was appropriately
scored as being really bad stuff so you
know we ran into the problem of again we
could test our own sandbox and
intuitively know what type of hardware
it's running but how can we get that
information from other people's
sandboxes there's a really easy way some
of them some of the sand boxes will
generate a report for you certainly the
free sandbox is will and they'll take
screenshots so in this case we uploaded
a payload that just popped up the cpu ID
the cpu version and the specific is a
instructions that are supported so the
the font is really small it was taken
out of a report but on the left hand
side there's a commercial sandbox that
is running a xeon e5 processor and the
interesting part is on the left hand
side it's I believe is like Intel Core 2
CPU which is pretty old is a free
sandbox and I'm not sure if they're just
like running it on donated hardware or
you can't if it's if it's actually
running in a VM certain VMs allow you to
like patch the
their response back from the CPUID
instruction that might be possible but
there's still ways that we can really
understand and figure out what CPU is
actually running on the system whether
or not it reports it as such so what if
you don't have access to your report one
option is to create a payload that again
runs the CPUID instruction base64 encode
that value and then creates a web
request and connects back to your web
server makes a get request for the
base64 encoded value and then you just
decode that and it's your it it's the
string of your processor another one
would be any sort of sandbox that makes
a report on what DNS or what HTTP
requests your payload makes then your
the CPU string is the base64 encoded URL
in the network communications section of
the report so we made this sort of proof
of concept payload and sent it to
virustotal to see what we could get back
and these were our results the number of
sandboxes that executed our malware was
a pretty good amount and for the most
part they were roughly running the intel
core processor we didn't deduplicate it
so I think actually that that bottom
column is the same sandbox running it
multiple times but if we were looking at
making malware they could generally run
on most systems and avoid detection in
most sand boxes I would again target
something like the AV X 256 instruction
set or avx-512 because there were there
was only two xeon cpus in the in the
results that could possibly execute
those op codes so now we need to
now that we've gotten our hardware
information out of sand boxes we need to
create our proof of concept and get a
hopefully a shell and to do that I took
the reverse shell payload and compiled
it with the visual studio compiler
adding avx-512 support and so this is an
example of the payload running in a
system that doesn't support the avx-512
instruction set so its core i9 desktop
processor and we see that double click
on the payload it just crashes we'll go
into our debugger look at the
instructions and see that I set a
breakpoint right before the avx-512
instructions where what we're
dereferencing a value and putting it
into an avx-512 register because the CPU
physically doesn't have an avx-512
register it just throws an exception and
so now what does it look like when we
have support for those instruction sets
here we're running on a Xeon Platinum
system in AWS and for good measure we're
running our Windows Defender and double
click on the file and we immediately get
a shell back where administrator and we
can see that we have access to files in
the local file system so as intended the
payload is running on the system that we
want it to but not running on the
systems that we are trying to avoid so
in in order to see how this would work
in the real world we took our avx-512
compiled payload and uploaded it to all
the sand boxes that we could find and
there is really you know no good
analysis or detection on it we did get
information that analysis failed or that
there was an exception to engines scored
it as malicious although I'm not
really sure why I hadn't heard of those
AV engines before so they might score
everything pretty aggressively so what
are the detection options that you have
if you run your own sandbox in your
environment and you detonate a payload
in cuckoo sandbox for example you'll
record that an exception was caught
it'll be a null exception address and a
hex five exception code so you could
potentially look for that if you are
using a cloud-based sandbox you could
potentially download any faulting or
failing samples for your own analysis
and I think the important thing to take
away from this or that we took away from
it is that any code that executes in
your sandbox but fails doesn't
necessarily mean that the binary was bad
we need to go and investigate why those
payloads failed or why those binaries
failed and not just assume that there's
not an issue there so future research
for me at Intel is sort of branching out
and a lot of into a lot of really
different ways one of the interesting
things is there they have some CPUs with
embedded FPGAs so again you could
potentially do some really weird stuff
where on a traditional x86 processor you
have access to an embedded FPGA and
they're doing a bunch of other stuff
additionally I thought there would be
ways to combine the leaking data from
the sandbox piece with delivering the
appropriate payload so you asked the CPU
like what version of the x86 is a ru and
then your second stage payload would
ship it the most appropriate is a
version payload for it so we've got one
minute left does anybody have questions