[Music]
[Applause]
so we had another year another two days
I hope you had as much fun as I did
there were some amazing moments I
especially like the proof of concept or
get the out Church moments and head
is talk it warms my heart
Jason's talk was amazing it really hits
at the core what we stand for and you
guys like amazing as always
however all good things come to an end
so I would like to start this closing
ceremony by inviting the captain to the
bridge
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you thank you very much so we had
a small competition here called
scavenger hunt and there was 19 teams
registered and playing so it was an
excellent on the first time event here
so it was a really really closed event
and the winner cuz was just divided by
one point damn yes exactly
the total point the boss 165 and the
winner with 127 points is catapult sheep
[Music]
will come on the bridge congratulations
so so I need to do now something once
per moment
[Music]
[Applause]
and now the breach is yours thank you so
I have two mics now right no I mean
obviously no so next up is the CTF the
CTF was was it good this year yeah it
was it was really good and it was close
it was really close this year we would
like to thank all of our CTF players
there's be more of you than ever before
but more than that we would also like to
thank everybody who contributed to the
CTF in the form of flags or challenges
thank you we could not have done this
without you as you as you know we like
to give big prizes and this year we have
over 60 million grams worth of awards
which is why I needed an assistant to
carry them so without further ado I'd
like to announce the third place of the
capture the flag 2020 disobey contest
which the team called extol 10
[Applause]
this my friend this my friend is a
hydraulic bottle Jack that can lift
12,000 kilos or 12 tonnes if you will be
careful not to break it it's very
fragile and also some use the stairs so
you don't break the jacket thank you
guys the extra prizes which actually
worth something are provided by lab 401
who we thank immensely for the
contribution and then to the capture the
flag
second place also a hydraulic bottle
Jackie 12 tonnes is the following team
called they've got the coil
[Applause]
Wow there's lots of you through hackers
any hold two of them at the same time
you realize the joke about Tom Costello
right yes yes once more for our ladies
okay he's sick he's too sick to carry
them anyway and finally the Award winner
of the capture-the-flag 2020 disobey
contest the team called
[Music]
got the whole sheep
[Applause]
with a combined lifting weight of twenty
four thousand kilos to hydraulic bottle
jacks and also some award prizes given
by lab 401 which delle cool hand out
shortly thank you guys it seems that we
have assembled the bubble jacks
ourselves it kind of shows alright once
one great show guys happy winners
welcome back next year
and then for our last price of the in
well not well yes last price of the
evening
unfortunately all net hunters will die
the badge pass all wasn't solved all the
way true
the evil mega-corporations will be able
to use soul killer and we will all
perish however there is hope because we
were close and as a community if we band
together with the winner of the badge
puzzle this year I'm sure we can
overcome it by the time the after-party
ends so the winner of the badge puzzle
for this year it's a team called so
kamijo
[Applause]
if anyone from so kamijo
left in the building no we have a some
proxmark devices from lab 401 for you
guys and we'll hold on to them until we
find so kamijo I think I can find mine
[Laughter]
so come here of course means good sweat
sweat
okay that's almost it that's almost it
like we like to do before that yes
there's there's one award we like to
give to a staff member who's provided us
with a service that we could not have
done this event without and that staff
member is our glorious chef Alex
abdominal who get some good rolling
bottle Jack worth ten thousand grams
kilos twelve million grams
unfortunately alex is downstairs washing
our dishes right now so you can't come
up the stage but I'm sure we'll have a
video of this later on YouTube probably
not though thank you Alex
thank you Alex II and then I would like
every sound one more thing five times
been five times disobey oh
more than four years of organizing so me
and the boys we wanted to give you
something a little bit special well I
did not betray pull this one out of my
ass just right now
[Applause]
[Music]
right so like like I keep saying you
guys do all the work and I get all the
credit
as a very real representation of that I
would like every single volunteer or
participate or person who have developed
a puzzle or contributed in any way to
organizing and making the event makeup
possible sorry I'm losing my words
please come to the stage you come come
on everybody
staff members audio people Network
people infrastructure people you guys
[Applause]
no no I'll take the picture yeah so yeah
so it's it's not me it's you
and like none of this would be possible
without you I need to take a picture of
you I hope I know how to use this thing
say something
[Applause]
[Music]
holy there was a lot less of you
when we start started
Wow okay thank you thank you thank you
thank you I will make sure all of you
who drink gets very drunk at the after
party so where did I put the thing
anything I would say after this would be
meaningless so thank you thank you thank
you I hope I'll see all of you are more
next year and I hope I'll see some of
you at the after party thank you so much
we truly do love you and this wouldn't
happen without you showing up so
[Applause]