[Music]
hey guys welcome everyone to disobey
I'm allergic ovitch coming from Hungary
and this is my first time at this obey
or rather in Helsinki and I have to say
I am it's cold here so yeah I've been
having a runny nose all the day so bear
with me please
this talk is about a malware that made
some waves not so long ago back in last
year in August and I just want to give
you guys a short primer to it this will
be a technical synopsis with some
technical details I hope you enjoy this
so a little bit about myself I coming
from a what I like to call it a
traditional blue team background I
started out there's a security analyst
went on to senior incident responder
then I joined the Navy company and over
the time I've spent learning all these
things I sort of developed a keen
interest in memory forensics threat
intelligence reverse engineering and
malware analysis so that's that's where
I'm coming from I've been doing mostly
reverse engineering the past year and I
made two reports during that year one
for an information still remember and
now for dark red version two which is a
a basically red I think this is my third
presentation overall so I just started
presenting last year and yeah I'll try
to keep going so let's talk about the
origins and the source of the malware
basically when I
first encountered the smell there I try
to sort of ascertain that it's coming
from and what I gather it is it's mostly
some joint work from previous malware's
for example it was the absent loader and
the light HTTP these were sort of the
inspiration for this malware and those
previous members were both made public
on github so you can look it up and
learn the bits about themselves
those humors basically made for
educational purposes and I think the
developer of this malware took a lot of
inspiration from those from those two
mothers oh yeah you got a lot of these
disclaimers it seems like every rare
developer putting up some sort of
disclaimer now you know they try to
avoid some sort of responsibility by
saying you know this software is not to
be used maliciously for example while on
the other side its whole purpose is to
be used maliciously so it's kind of
interesting and basically just one
question remains if it's it's all
illegal then why it is advising only
otherwise advertised on underground
cybercrime forums yeah I guess the
developer doesn't even know that until
the week there's a big huge collection
of never source code on github now under
the account the tlg IT I think he houses
a really big collection of leaked nether
source code and dark rat was also
amongst those those codes and the
developer of this malware went to the
trouble of opening several pull requests
and issues on this repo you know saying
hey you're not permitted to share my
malicious code which is kind of weird
she also says this isn't open-source and
I'm like what why this is malicious code
and he again goes to the trouble saying
you know this code is vulnerable and
it's for educational purposes which is
kind of dodgy then the maintainer of the
account you know replies the infection
saying hey I doubt your venti or local
government to register your illegal
activities so yeah she's fair point but
he keeps bargaining you know leaving his
account so he says please try to add me
here and let's talk about this so he's
trying to get the contents or the
malware's source code to be removed but
I guess the maintainer won't won't
remove it so one of the source for this
malware was the light HTTP malware which
is HTTP botnet and once I started
digging further down into the origins
and the comings of this malware
it became clear that the guy took a lot
of inspiration from these previous works
and basically as you can see that's how
the first version of the dark red came
to be the guy just basically went and
changed some parameters renamed some
classes functions and that's how the
first version came to be which is
honestly is a bit lame but I like these
comparisons for two reason two reasons
one of them is it just goes to show that
how easy it has become to develop a
simple matter for example in C++ or C
sharp you don't really need to know code
that much you can just basically take
code from already existing report repos
secondly this kind of shows that you
know these
there's perpetrators or you can call
them script titties don't really know
about operational security and this just
shows that you know github never forgets
so you can find all sort of information
on early pull requests but who is this
guy
he goes by the name dark spider and he
had multiple accounts on many social
platforms like github base beam but all
of these separate accounts could be tied
up into one single identity because his
object was so bad on on the github
account
he states that you know he's a web web
developer and a security researcher as
well which kind of brings me to the
point you know I'm not sure if you saw
the matrix but there's this specific
scene with agent Smith and you know mr.
Anderson being apprehended and agent
Smith just goes like you know hey mr.
Anderson it seems you're living two
lives now you know in one of them you're
a programmer for a respectable software
company as the guy claims to be on the
right side on the slide on the other
hand at night for example he's most
likely a hacker or he who knows probably
he's a vigilante at night and you know
in real life he's Bruce Wayne living as
a playboy so the product or the malware
was mostly advertised on hack forums and
some other small-time or underground
forums and this guy would often you know
bolster up the fact that he's doing
quality coding he would often post
screenshots of his machine or the
development environment he was coding in
and again just the
just show some amateurish level of
Maverick coding and as you can see on
the slide he would post some screenshots
of his desktop and obviously when this
opportunity comes you can spot some
really interesting things like he's
using some German language like cogent a
William is a bish Lawson obviously is
coming from a German keyboard or alia
Laila layout so we can kind of put a
picture together that this some of
German origins
maybe he's residing in Germany
Switzerland or Austria who knows these
are some of the functionalities that the
malware heads I think you guys can
already sense there's some really script
kiddie amateurish level behind this but
there's been some interesting
functionalities among the way and these
are some of the interesting functions
I'd like to detail one of them which was
kind of interesting for me it was hiding
the c2 server address this guy
implemented the rather interesting
process where he would have a base being
URL a encryption key which turned out to
be a rc4 encryption key both in the
sample and the sample would go out to
this space being URL grab the contents
which was as you can see on the
screenshot a base64 encoded string the
sample would decode that and it would
give out a binary blob now that blob
would be decrypted with the rc4 key and
then you would have the c2 server
address so it's kind of a I would say a
small-time or alpha station but I think
it had some real creativity which was
interesting for me one of the many
features was having some sort of anti
debugging capabilities
I would say these are really simple
checks for checking whether you're in a
debugging environment and all of these
could be a sort of could be avoided or
circumvented on the fly
by just patching the few bytes even went
to the bank to use some interesting
instructions like the RTT SC instruction
where the sample would count the elapsed
ticks for example and these checks again
could be circumvented by simply just
replacing a few bytes in a debugger the
mother also had some functionality to
detect and if sort of a vs on the
machine it was using a built-in function
or feature the WMI command sets
specifically the wql and this feature
felt like a real a bit a little bit
incomplete because the simply would just
report back the status grab the name of
the AV present on the machine and send
it back to the c2 server so I think it
was kind of incomplete and the developer
meant to further develop this part of
the code the sample would also have a
capability to save deletion which I'm
sure you guys see it was really
amateurish pumping a CMD shell and
basically just forcing a quiet deletion
of the file from the disk it also had an
interesting technique that it was using
it's called a process hollowing they're
basically any malware now can sort of a
map or hollow out a memory
from a process and basically just
overwrite or switch out that legitimate
memory of the process with certain
malicious code these are some of the API
calls that he would use to do to achieve
this now
this developer would go and also sell
his source version of the malware which
means basically he would grant access to
the source code and also supply
customers with the Builder itself
builders come into picture when you're
trying to deploy at mass for example you
want to sell the product or the malware
to more and more customers and basically
you want to switch out for example the
mutex is the user agent or the spread
tags the page being URLs in this case
and it's fairly easy to use these
builders after the builders are solved
basically I noticed that this guy would
start developing certain plugins for the
c2 panels for example the guys would
have plugins for example a DDoS module
monaro minor or even a steal or that
would steal students credentials from
your browsers um this is how the panel
looks like got all of these colors and
these are the tasks that you could run
or execute from the c2 panel basically
you had the capability to update the
malware uninstall it kill the
persistence of it or even to deploy the
Monaro miner launch the DDS DDoS module
as well now once you face a c2 panel as
a researcher or a male analyst or a
threat Intel guy first you would do some
sort of animation
on the c2 server see you know what kind
of resources are available and in this
specific case it's it was quite
interesting that you would find a
resource under that get slash config
which obviously is a big no-no
this again proves that the guy doesn't
even know about operational security
death match and as you can see on the
screenshot the whole panel though or the
source of the panel was hosted under
this URL so basically you could just
clone it and get all the files that
would go with the c2 panel or for this
matter you can go ahead and call /index
that who that would list all the files
and basically could just parse the name
parameter from the files and put
together all the lists all the files
that were present on the c2 server now
it turns out this panel also had
specific vulnerability in it but first I
have to start with the disclaimer if you
start to play around panels you have to
be very careful because in some in
certain countries this is not allowed
and obviously I just grabbed the copy of
the panel and played around this on a
local VM so again this is a local
proof-of-concept so the main question is
and you might be wondering how would you
get access into these panels obviously
they would come with some sort of
username or password login and there's a
way to circumvent that on the right side
you can see a screenshot that shows once
a machine is infected this is the kind
of c2 traffic that would be sent to this
server it would contain this request
parameter and as you can see this is a
base64 encoded blob
now upon decoding this sort of base64
blob you would get these parameters as
you can see it collects for example the
computer named GPU named CPU name from
the machine and as I started playing
around this and you can spot on the
screenshot you can just basically insert
a script tag to the computer name
resource and I'm sure if you're into pen
testing and know about the XSS this is
the first thing that you would try on on
a site and as you can see on the right
side it was successfully sent in so
basically once you record this these
parameters and sending the request to
the c2 server up on the next time the
administrator is logging into the panel
this window would open up with the text
1 so that means the exercise was
successful there's certainly a window of
opportunity here and we could further
exploit this by exchanging that script
tag with something more advanced so
let's say we can switch it with a iframe
that's pointing to a external resource
now in that external resource you can
put any code basically but in this case
generated a CSRF birth payload that
would create a new years new user on the
c2 panel so once this gets encoded again
with basics before and it gets sent to
the c2 server the next time the
administrator is logging into the panel
he doesn't even know there's a new user
created so that's one way to sort of
achieve this now I'm coming to the point
where I think we need to discuss about
something
it's about IO C's and TTP's
because I'm sort of starting to realize
a common theme here you know there's
this vicious circle it starts by a bad
guy or a perpetrator writing code then
releasing it then the researchers come
into play and analyze the malware they
sort of release IOC ste TPS around it
because it's new stuff and everybody
needs to know about these so I'm not
sure if you know but obviously
perpetrators and my other writers also
read these blogs and iOS's TTP's and
they sort of react to it in a way this
sometimes creates challenges because
your advantages are now gone and the bad
guys are often you know realigning their
techniques migrating from
infrastructures and this creates real
problems sometimes now on the 5th of
November
basically I released some sort of gist
and I OCS to github and Twitter as well
and the developer of the nether sort of
approached me on my social account which
you could say is a bit dodgy again
because I'm maybe not upset aware on the
8th of November again after a couple of
days this guy also announced that you
know he would retire and he left a
goodbye message on one of the discourse
server that he was using I just wanted
to briefly touch on a topic that's I
think really important in the community
once I release these iOS's and TTP's I
get a lot of positive feedback from a
couple of the guys from the researcher
community and I would like to also
inspire you and advocate this sort of
behavior because I think
this field is about sharing knowledge
the more you know the better detection
you can write basically or even react to
sort of brie cheese or pentas and I feel
like we should keep on doing this we
should keep releasing
iOS's TTP's and i really liked how
others complimented my work added some
additional comments to it
other i/o sees I wanted to finish off by
stating a couple of ending thoughts one
of them is as you could saw in the
slides these perpetrators are really not
upset aware they don't have any sort of
cyber hygiene and I install the cases we
were able to bus these actors you know
we found holes issues we see two panels
and exploiting these in a way and
learning more about these issues we
could really find these guys pass the
information of to law enforcement for
example but what will happen when these
guys learn more about operational
security
I feel like eventually we need to find
other ways to bust some of these some of
these perps
keep iOS's PDP's do an inner circle
that's a question I feel like once you
release I OCS and TTP's the advantage
you have will certain this appear over
time these guys overreact change tactics
migrate from infrastructures to
different infrastructure and sometimes
you know there's a real opportunity when
these guys overreact to react because
that's the time then they may also make
some mistakes and you can fight some
again some issues holes in their
infrastructure
but there's a real question here whether
you should release it publicly you know
hold it to your inner circles perhaps or
even not shares anything at all
engaging thought talking to perpetrators
I would say that's definitely a big
no-no don't leave a surface for them and
I kind of felt like I was in the
crosshairs when he approached me some
would say you know there they would be
flattened by by an Alfred
if they were to approach him but in my
case I felt like I may have missed
something on the operational security
side because once he approached me I
felt like you know I was a target also
you should check your local laws whether
it's allowed to hack into c2 panels I
know for a fact for example in the u.s.
it's considered hacking back under the
CFE CFAA law so you should really not
attack this sort of c2 panels if you if
your government doesn't allow it and
finally I feel active force tech
community is one of the best communities
out there and I would urge everyone to
cheer information spread knowledge let
everybody know if you have something or
you've worked on because I feel like
everyone can just chip in and Continent
the other versus work and I feel like
this
that's that goes a long way
thanks for listening thanks for having
me thanks for the disobey organizers
it's been an honor to present here don't
forget it's Valentine's Day kiss your
loved ones and thank you guys
[Applause]