[Music]
good evening disobey do you ever get the
feeling that there has to be more to
life than just computers and hacking a
great thing about this obey is that this
isn't only for us who enjoy breaking
things this is also for creators and
makers today is Valentine's Day and what
would be a more beautiful thing to make
than love so let's get physical but
before we do that we would really like
to present our latest research on
credential theft we will start the
presentation by giving a brief history
of the evolution of credential theft
attacks and the related defenses and
hopefully this will show you why we felt
that a new approach to stealing
credentials was needed then we will
share the story of how we developed a
new tool called fist meme to profit
which is designed to steal credentials
directly from the physical memory and
this is something that your open
sourcing today so you are the first
people outside f-secure to see this now
hopefully this is all very interesting
for those of you in the audience who
self-identify as attackers or red
teamers but what about the defenders for
the defenders we have three key
takeaways number one we will advise how
to approach this kind of new and novel
attack techniques in general keep our
number two we will give recommendations
on where to focus your detection ever
and finally keep on number three we see
both attacks and defenses moving lower
and lower on the technology stack and we
believe this is a trend that benefits
the defenders but it does require action
from you if you have any questions
during the presentation I kindly ask you
to make a mental note and we're more
than happy to answer your questions in
the Q&A section at the end of the
presentation my name is Tim O'Hara
Vernon this is my brilliant colleague
Robert Baer speak
Robert moved from UK to Finland about a
year ago and he's such a good fiend that
we've already given him the Feeney's
name Robert Carter hula but that's not
the reason why he is here Robert is the
father of the idea behind all this thank
you mate
so recently Timo and I was struggling to
get code execution on a red team
operation and the reason for this was
something called attack surface
reduction which is part of the advanced
threat protection suite offered by
Microsoft
according to Microsoft's attack surface
reduction is a tool that prevents
behaviors that malware often uses to
infect computers with malicious code I
found this frustrating but I also
thought it was quite interesting so I
started reading about it my wife went to
bed I carried on reading about it and
what curiosity led me to several other
tool sets as well why found is that
these modern defensive security software
or solutions are effective they're
sophisticated and they're really
focusing on the right things
the problem for me was the the things
they're focusing on are so pivotal to
the success of our red team operations
made me realise that the game is
changing it's time for us to sink or
swim and it made me realize that I just
wanted to kind of push back so I set the
message to my good friend and colleague
Timo and I said Timo the game is
changing it's time to sink or swim I
want to push back an hour Timo spent six
years specializing in reverse
engineering and exploit development than
the last three years doing red
operations so of course he immediately
just said yes let's do that where do I
begin and that's ultimately why we're
here in front of you today here we have
the kill chain was originally developed
by Lockheed Martin as a way to
illustrate the stages of an intrusion
into a computer network and what we mean
by stages our intelligence gathering
activities the delivery of a weaponized
payload the execution of code on a
victim system the ability to control
that victim system remotely the process
of obtaining persistent access to that
system internal enumeration of an
environment the movement through that
environment and finally the actions on
objective exfiltrating data modifying a
database something along those lines
now f-secure has released public
presentations and tooling around most of
the elements of this kill chain most
notably at command and control with the
release of c3 last year some of you may
have heard of c3 already essentially the
team behind c3 found that their command
and control channels kept getting caught
by defensive security teams and
defensive security products and so they
wanted a way to push back they found
that they could tunnel their
communication the command and control
channels over existing communication
channels that are often present within
the enterprise things like Microsoft
teams and slack and to my knowledge
they've been using it successfully ever
since today we're going to be talking
about lateral movement lateral movement
is made up of a number of things
arguably one of the most important of
those is credential theft this felt like
the next logical step for us following
the success of c3 but it also just felt
like a really interesting space for us
to investigate based on the attention
and the focus that defensive security
solutions place on lateral movement
credential theft is the process of user
using privileged access to an operating
system to obtain credential material
here we have a computer and inside that
computer is an operating system inside
that operating system our services that
support its operation the most
interesting of these for us as security
professionals is the local security
authority subsystem service or else a
CXC L SAS manages the local security
policy of the operating system it
manages local users and groups as well
as their passwords and it facilitates
single sign-on so that users don't need
to keep entering their passwords to
access resources ultimately that means
that it contains interesting things
within its memory space things like
passwords password hashes Kerberos
tickets certificates these things can be
used to authenticate yourself on a
computer network verify your identity
and so they're interesting to us as
attackers because if we can compromise
them then we can impersonate legitimate
users and expand our access to a target
environment this fits into lateral
movement because if we compromised a
workstation and we want to gain access
to a target database we find some
credentials for an administrator of a
server called server one so we use those
to authenticate to server one and we
compromised the credential material
stored within its memory space of alsace
we get some credentials for an
administrator of server two and this
cyclic or process this iterative
approach to credential theft is
essentially what makes up lateral
movement it's made up of many things but
you can see that it's at the core of
what happens here so we authenticate to
server 2 we obtain the credential
material and we find some administrative
credentials for server 3 we authenticate
to a third server we do the same thing
and we find some credentials to our
target database and we can authenticate
the purpose of this slide is really just
to show you how credential theft fits in
with in lateral movement it was a lot
harder to retrieve credential material
from an end point until Benjamin Del P
released mini cats in 2007 essentially
mainly cats is a tool that allows you to
extract condense credential material
from an endpoint and this is one of my
favorite quotes from the InfoSec
community essentially mini cats was one
of the greatest contributions to InfoSec
and Benjamin Delpy did it to learn C
which is quite remarkable as I said you
can run me me caps on an endpoint and it
retrieves credential material in the
glory days it was possible to do this
directly and you could just obtain all
that lovely credential material but
obviously security products wanted to
prevent against this they didn't want
this to happen and this kind of started
that struggle between the red team and
the blue team where the red team wanted
to carry out an offensive operation and
the blue team wanted to prevent it
or detective so to begin with the red
team started applying simple obfuscation
to the tool things as simple as renaming
it to mini dogs and ultimately in
certain situations that was enough to be
able to run it and bypass the antivirus
software as you can see here but this
couldn't go on forever and so the red
team needed a way of pushing back again
and what better way to push back then
not to run the tool on the endpoint at
all essentially Benjy Benjamin Delpy
introduced support for something called
a process dump which is a file that
contains the memory of a target process
essentially if an attacker could create
a process dump of their target system
they could download it's they're
attacking machine and they could run it
through mini cats far away from any
defensive security software that was
getting in the way this might sound
complex but there are legitimate reasons
to create a process dump of a process
and that's why Microsoft provides this
functionality the most simple of these
is task manager as you can see here you
can right click the process click create
dump file and ultimately create a
process done for the process you can
always see also use proc dump which is
part of the system eternals toolkit and
administrative tool kit for Windows
environments and there are of course
custom implementations of these tools
that do the same thing they might use
different techniques but ultimately they
result in a process dump that can be
used with many cats here we have mini
cats and you just say I'd like to use
this process dump and it uses it instead
of using the local host in some cases
this process can even be automated the
else a see is a tool that was recently
released and built on top of the impact
in packet framework so that this can be
done at scale this is a great option
when you don't need to bypass EDR
products where you're not trying to
bypass detection go undetected but
obviously security software I wanted to
prevent against this as well and they do
this using something called function
hooking which I'm going to briefly
describe here because it sets up some
concepts that we're going to talk about
a little bit later on there are two
modes of operation within a Windows
environment user mode and kernel mode
user mode is for date for users to carry
out their day-to-day business activities
like checking their email running Google
Chrome things like that and kernel mode
is reserved for critical operating
system components it's a kernel-mode is
a highly privileged environment has a
complete view of the operating system
and its memory and essentially is home
to the core of the operating system that
provides services to user mode
applications when an application wants
to interact with a file or communicate
over a network it does it requests this
service from the kernel and the kernel
happily obliges now to provide some
stability Microsoft introduced a set of
api is called the windows api x' and
essentially they handle this
communication with the kernel on behalf
of the user mode application and this is
where hooking comes in
so these user mode applications when
they request the windows api these
requests can be intercepted and
redirected and this essentially lets
security software intercept and redirect
certain API calls that they're
interested in and assess them to
identify whether they are malicious if
they're considered to be malicious they
can be prevented but if not they can be
allowed to continue
so attackers wanted to obviously find
ways around this and one of those
options is to unhook these hooked API
calls if you can identify them there's a
tool called Andrew special if you look
for that on github it's effectively at
all based around unhooking a certain
security product and another option is
to just not use the wind yet windows api
is at all just used sis calls directly
bypass calling those windows api s and
actually there's a company in Holland or
the Netherlands called outflank and they
have developed a tool called dumper that
does exactly this but defensive security
solutions are aware of this of course
and they have a component of this
software all security software has a
component of its software running in
kernel mode essentially what this allows
it to do is register to the operating
split system for something called a
callback and the operating system will
notify the security software each time a
certain event occurs the purpose of this
slide is not to show you new techniques
on how you can dump credential dump the
else's process the purpose of this slide
is to say that these techniques are
nothing new and what we want to
illustrate here is that things have
gotten Heron T complicated they've
become quite complex and this is
ultimately why Timo and I asked
our selves is there another approach to
doing this is there something that we're
missing
could we be could we do this differently
like Robert explained ADR has all sorts
of methods for monitoring access to the
LSS process a key observation for us was
that the EDR is monitoring the LSS
process not access to the credential
material and this let us do the
following problem statement how can we
access the credential material without
interacting with the LSS process if you
look at all the existing tools for
credential theft they are all focused on
illnesses and the virtual memory around
it but what is virtual memory basically
it's just an addressing method just like
a street name and a number is an
addressing method for your home that has
a specific physical location it's the
same thing with the credentials yes they
do have a virtual address but ultimately
they live in the physical memory so we
decided to target the physical memory
instead so the existing attacks they
work on the virtual memory layer we went
one layer down into stack and targeted
physical memory deal directly in other
words we went in from below the approach
isn't new this has already been done by
criminals and not the kind of criminals
you would expect in 2005 the central
bank of Brazil was robbed and the
interesting part is how they did it it
has absolutely nothing to do with
computers instead of trying to access
the vault by going through one of these
massive doors or trying to explode a
hole in the wall they did something very
different they dug two hundred meters of
tunnel and access the vault from below
now this approach
was very successful for these guys
because this is one of the biggest bank
robberies in history and it remains to
be seen whether this approach is equally
successful for stealing credentials so
the recap we did the same thing and as
the bank robbers and went in from below
and targeted the physical memory now if
you want to make any sense of the data
in the physical memory who you gonna
call ghostbusters no you call your
colleagues in the incident response team
because they know how to do memory
forensics and they will tell you that
the in practice there's two good tools
volatility and recall so we started this
research by comparing these two and
after a very brief evaluation we had a
clear winner because volatility was
super slow I mean just running the image
info command that took ages and that
gives you only the high-level summary of
the image now you might be wondering
that is the speed really relevant here
the way we look at this is that we
wanted to create something that people
actually want to use so it doesn't
really matter if you have really cool
technical tricks but your tool is so
slow that nobody likes to use it so we
decided to go it recall so what we do we
steal credentials using a tool that
defenders typically use at the other end
the other end of the pipeline we knew
that we want to be able to produce mini
Dom's because like Robert explained
earlier mimikatz has the capability to
analyze mimi dumps the mini dumps and
extract credentials from those in
addition we already had developed
internal automation where you can just
give it a mini dump it uses mimic ads to
extract the credentials and then
forwards those to our post exploitation
toolkits these are also the reasons why
we didn't use an existing tool called pi
pi cuts which on paper dance made this
use case but there is still something
missing in the middle we have all the
relevant date
and we know that there is a specific
file format that we want to use but how
to connect these two this is exactly
what the first proof of concept of this
memory prophet did it used recall to
analyze an image of the entire physical
memory it located the else's process
then snipped out all the relevant data
and then say that in the minidom file
format now most of the development
effort here went into writing those
minidom files and I can tell you that
that's not really the nicest the easiest
file format out there so we used a
Python module called construct but still
it was it was quite a lot of work
however the end result was quite nice
with the first proof-of-concept you
could steal credentials in three easy
steps
first you use those existing established
memory acquisition tools like dumb bit
or wimpy mem to dump the physical memory
you give that memory dump the fish mem
to profit and you get a mini DOM and
then you give that mini dump to mimic
ads and there you have your credentials
the beauty of this approach is that
we're not interacting with the else's
process of the target system in any way
and what that means is that it's very
difficult for EDR to detect this now
even though we didn't really have to
write that many lines of code for the
proof of concept the minidom file format
is a pain so there was quite a lot of
troubleshooting and debugging involved
so I can tell you that when we finally
got a valid mini dump gave it to me me
cats and got those first lovely cringe
credentials that felt pretty great that
was a good day so we could steal
credentials by accessing the physical
memory what's more it didn't cause an
alert in our detection platform which
kind of gave us the encouragement we
needed to continue and we thought this
was pretty cool we thought this was
pretty pretty groundbreaking but then on
closer inspection we realized that we
perhaps had a - a few too many
similarities
to the bank robbers in Brazil than we'd
care to admit they created a fake
construction company to excavate all the
dirt from the tunnel they were digging
to the bank and our initial proof of
concept was quite similar to this
because we would create an image of the
main memory of our target and then we
would excavate that across a network
essentially we'd do this with dump it or
wimpy mem to create that main memory
image you know luckily for the bank
robbers the neighbors didn't notice
anything suspicious about this dumper
truck going back and forth but we have
to contend with modern security products
and modern security teams and they would
definitely notice such a huge amount of
data coming out of their network we knew
that this wasn't very elegant from an
operational security standpoint and
ultimately we knew that we needed to do
better but we also knew that dump it and
wind pea men had to have a component of
their software running in kernel modes
because they had comprehensive and
random access to the memory so we
thought well what if we lose the
executable could we interact with that
kernel mode component directly and it
turns out you can so we developed a fizz
mem to profit c-sharp server component
that runs on our target host and exposes
the physical memory of the device we
then run our fizz mem to profit client
component and we mount that physical
memory as a fire we do this using the
file system in userspace or fuse via the
fuse py Python module essentially fuse
py or fuse PI offers a simple interface
to fuse and with less than a hundred
lines of Python we were able to achieve
our objective
what we do is proxy our read requests
over the TCP connection we can then use
office mem to profit client component to
analyze that physical memory find the
LSS process the bit we're interested in
snip it out and create a process thump
that ultimately we can use with mini
cats at this point we felt a lot less
like the bank robbers in Brazil and a
lot more like Leslie Nielsen in Naked
Gun the final in
so I'm really hoping there's some people
who are familiar with Naked Gun in the
audience he was digging a tunnel out of
prison and that's how he smuggled the
dirt this all sounds great but as I
mentioned kernel-mode is a highly
privileged environment has a complete
view of the OS and its memory and
ultimately even though we were using a
tool like wind P mem which is a robust
and comprehensive piece of software
sometimes if you're using a really
powerful tool like a chainsaw you can
lose a leg or end up with a blue screen
of death but we were able to overcome
this and ultimately create a proof of
concept that we're going to share with
you now so here we have F secures
detection platform on the left you see
Fizz mem demo1 and on the right you
fitzy Fizz mem demo - these are two
windows 10 workstations that have our
agent installed on them we go to our
attacking machine and we RDP into Fizz
mem demo one we run hostname so you can
see which endpoint we're talking about
and then we run proc dump which is
commonly used by attackers and red
teamers around the world and will cause
a severe detection in our endpoint
platform as you can see here on the Left
we go back to our attacking machine and
we RDP into fizz mem demo - we run
hostname once more so you can see which
endpoint we're running on and then we
run our c-sharp fizz mint a profit
server component we give it an IP
address so it knows which interface to
listen on and we give it a port you
don't have to do this at will default to
port 8080 but we wanted to be modular
and flexible so we give it port 8080 it
all starts listening we cancel out of
our RDP session and we go back to our
attacking machine we run our FISMA into
profit client component which connects
to that tcp port loads the kernel mode
component exposes the physical memory
mounts the physical memory analyze it to
find the LSS process snips it out
creates a process dump and drops it into
the output folder as you can see here it
is important to note at this point that
we did speed the tool up for the
purposes of this demonstration the
typical run time is around two minutes
we go back to our detection platform and
you can see that no detection occurred
we can then use the mini dump with
mitty-kats
and you can find out my super secret
passwords down below you might be able
to see the floor with our plan here
though they're introducing something to
our target operating system we're
introducing a driver that wasn't there
before and windows event ID number six
driver load it doesn't happen that often
so a defensive security team would
probably start looking into that because
it seems quite suspicious and so we
started thinking to ourselves what's
present on the operating system already
that perhaps has access to the physical
memory and then we remembered that EDR
products are commonly present in
enterprise environments and they provide
functionality that supports Incident
Response which ultimately means they can
access the physical memory and then we
thought well we can't just poker a
competitor's EDR products because that
wouldn't be very fair just to come along
and release a tool that targets them but
we could and should as an objective
consultancy target our own so we did
what we found as I mentioned earlier is
that our IDI opera EDR products had a
component of its software running in
kernel mode as I also mentioned Fitz
meant a prophet has a component of its
software running in kernel mode on
closer inspection it turns out that Fizz
meant a prophet uses the same kernel
mode component that our EDR product does
and so essentially we turned up to rob a
bank with a small drill and there was a
diamond coring machine already present
we are really excited to say that his
mentor prophet is available as of right
now on f-secure labs github there is an
accompanying blog accompanying blog post
called rethinking credential theft on
the f-secure labs blog but we would like
to stress at the moment that his mentor
prophet was not designed to be a silver
bullet for all edr products that are out
there what we wanted to do with this
research was just rethink credential
theft propose an alternative approach
and release a tool a framework that's
modular and
extendable to support additional drivers
that have access to physical memory so
that perhaps one day it could become
part of the red teamers toolbox on the
note of extending Fishman's prophet we
were having a conversation I was talking
to the team oh one Sunday and we were
saying you know we want this to be a
community project we want to make sure
people contribute whether they just tell
us there's a bug in it or whether they
just tell us they don't like it but we
want people to get involved and so we
said well you know we should really test
out how modular this is is it possible
is it easy to extend it and Timo said
yeah you know what I'm going to try this
I'm going to try this tonight I'm going
to see if I can just add some
functionality or add support for another
driver and then 30 minutes later I get
this text message which for those of you
who aren't from fillin that you work
with fins you'll know that a smiley face
in a text message means he's literally
jumping for joy and those of you that
work with Timo or you know him
personally will know that this text
message sums him up perfectly you'll be
working on a complex challenge and he'll
come back to you in quite a short
timeframe and just tell you he's already
done it yeah this is actually a true
story it was my wife's turn to put our
son to bed so I had some free time I
started googling searching for drivers
that would allow access the physical
memory and I found this
awesome blog post titled reading
physical memory using carbon blacks and
point driver this is quite nice because
during many of the read in red team
engagements that we've had we had to
evade carbon black and in this book post
you have all the necessary technical
details to read the physical memory
using carbon black so not only teach you
maybe evade carbon black you could even
abuse it to steal credentials and for a
red teamer that's that's really cool for
those of you wondering whether the
author of the blog post
disclosed these issues two carbon black
according to the blogpost yes he did the
reply from carbon black this is not a
security issue because you need to have
admin privilege seized so fair enough
now to secure the issue let me show you
how easy it is to add support for this
driver in face memory profit when you
run the tool you see those output lines
saying registered command all you need
to do is implement three four different
commands and that's as simple as
creating a single c-sharp class in
hearing inheriting that from a couple of
other classes and then implementing
those methods let's start with the
install method you probably didn't guess
this but it installs the driver with the
wind pmm driver what we do is we use a
service to install the driver but with
carbon black this is easier because the
driver is already there so we just need
to call create file and we get a handle
to the device object so all the code
needed for this step you see here on the
screen the second method you want to
implement is called map and the purpose
of this method is to return the list of
memory ranges that can be safely
accessed if you access a memory address
outside those ranges you will get one of
those deadly blue screens that robert
showed earlier that was the root cause
so yeah you need to implement this
there's three device IO control calls
the first one authenticates with the
driver and this is a requirement that's
specific to the carbon bag driver this
is a special case the second device IO
control there we set the acquisition
mode and what that simply means is we
select the technical method that is used
then access that physical memory and
then finally in the last device IO
control call we request from the driver
the list of memory ranges and then all
you need to do is parse the response
from the driver and there you have it
again all the relevant code here on the
slide the third and final method you
probably want to implement is free
and that's the one that surprise
surprise reads the physical memory you
give the driver a physical address and
the number of bytes you want to read
then you get the response and that's it
so not that many lines of code 30
minutes and suddenly carbon black EDR
becomes the red teamers best friend I
like that thank you yeah we were pretty
pretty happy about this so we were
celebrating this like high-fiving and
being like this is the greatest
credential theft ever we were so proud
of this and then we have a colleague
Charlie Charlie coming to us saying guys
I'm I'm sorry to interrupt your
celebration but have you have you guys
heard of credential guard and then I was
like haha sure we have heard of
credential guard but that's not a
problem I mean you need to have admin
privileges on the box anyway and if your
admin on the box then you have access to
the entire physical memory and the
credentials needs to be somewhere in
that physical memory so it's not a
problem
sounds logical but there was this minor
thing that we didn't quite understand
how credential guard works
so here's credential guard for you it
uses a feature called virtualization
based security so what you have is a
hypervisor layer and then all the daily
operations that you do on that computer
in reality those happen inside a virtual
machine so all the daily stuff you do
you do it inside a virtual machine and
you don't even know it because this is
totally transparent to the end-user
but this also means that if you have
those admin privileges you have admin
privileges only within that virtual
machine now where do the credentials
live I have good news and bad news
the credentials is the good news the
credit
shall still live in the normal world now
the bad news is that those credentials
are encrypted so it doesn't help you
much unless you know the encryption key
and by now you probably already guessed
that the encryption key lives in an
other virtual machine called the secure
world now if you want to decrypt the
credentials and bypass credential guard
you would need to escape a virtual
machine and then read the encryption key
and you probably know that escaping a
virtual machine is a pretty difficult
problem in fact it's so difficult that
Microsoft is willing to pay two hundred
and fifty thousand US dollars for any
reports of such more abilities so in my
books this is a difficult problem the
great news is that if there is something
I really enjoy doing it's solving
difficult problems the other good news
is not at blackhat 2017 Intel
researchers gave this great presentation
about why passing credential guard by
exploiting a vulnerability in firmware
and I I think the information in this
presentation is really golden I think
this presentation is very underrated so
if you're interested in the topic please
go and check out the presentation they
also detailed what are the crypto
methods used by credential guard to
protect the credentials there's two key
concepts and I will explain this very
briefly one is he derivation and then
the other one is authenticated
encryption now those key derivation
functions are a challenge from an
attackers perspective let me explain why
each and every credential is encrypted
with a unique key and those keys are
derived you have a master key and then
from that master key you derive unique
keys the problem here is that if you
somehow get access to the memory of the
secure world and try to find those
derived keys those are not
there they are not in memory based on
our experiments my theory is that those
keys are derived on demand so those are
derived on demand and as soon as you
don't need a key anymore it swipe from
memory so you cannot find those keys in
memory which means that you need to find
that master key you need to find that
and then you also need to know how
exactly those keys are derived you need
to know the exact details of that key
derivation function that's the
challenging part the good news is the
second part and that's the authenticated
encryption what that simply means is
that for each encrypted credential there
is also a message authentication code
that comes with that credential and what
that means is that if you try to decrypt
something you always know whether the
operation succeeded or failed you don't
need to guess whether you have the right
key you will always know whether the
operation was a success or a failure and
what that means is that if you're able
to successfully decrypt the credential
it means that you had the correct
derived key which also implies that you
must have had the correct master key so
this is a nice way of checking whether
you found the correct master key if you
look at the output from mimikatz on a
system that's running credential guard
the line at the bottom there
that's your encrypted credentials that's
the cipher text the line above that what
mimikar mimikatz called Anki I have no
idea what that means in that field you
have the message authentication code and
also the needed input for the key
derivation function so mimic ATS is able
to give you all the needed input values
except for that master key now the nice
thing here is that the data in the
secure world the amount of data is only
around 50 megabytes so what you can do
is to try a value from each
Avery's offset you try that as the
master key and at some point the
decription will succeed and you know you
have found the man the master key so
here you have all the needed details of
the creep though to decrypt those
credentials and even though the black
hat presentation by Intel researchers
they mentioned the Windows crypto API
sand they they talk about the creep
though they don't give any code examples
and they didn't share any tools so uh as
far as I know here you have the first
public implementation of decrypting
credentials from credential guard you
give it the output from mimikatz place
it in the correct variables then you
place your guess as of the master key in
the boot key and then you just run this
in a loop for all the values in the
secure world and at some point you get a
hit and you're able to decrypt the
credentials but this is the easy part
there's nothing nothing difficult here
the challenge is getting access to the
data that's part of the secure world
because like you remember even if you
have admin you're still inside your own
little virtual machine so how do you get
the data from the secure world the Intel
researchers they exploited a firmer
vulnerability and the thing is that we
didn't really have any experience in
exploiting Firma vulnerabilities but hey
come on how hard can it be
turns out pretty hard but we got lucky
we find this found this noise firmware
vulnerability from 2015 and here's the
result this system is running credential
guard you can see the encrypted
credentials there then we run our tool
and what it does first is it tries to
access now remember this is running
within that virtual machine in that
normal world it tries to access each and
every page of the physical memory if the
access fails it probably means that that
page is part of the secure world
so it collects a list of these pages
that cannot be accessed from the normal
world once you have the list then we
exploit that firm of our nobility that
allows us to modify a script that is
part of the firmware and that script is
executed when the computer receives from
slave so when the system receives from
sleep our code gets executed it copies
all the data from the secure world back
to the normal world so we can access it
normally and then it's only a matter of
running that Python algorithm you saw
earlier trying the key from every offset
and at some point you get a hit and then
you have the credentials from a system
protected by credential guard thank you
now the key thing here isn't the
technical details of this particular
firmware nobility the key thing is that
if your firmware is not up-to-date
credential card cannot help you in the
beginning of the presentation we promise
to deliver three key points our first
key point is that we might be able to
bypass a particular protection and go
undetected at a specific point in time
but attackers don't perform one action
they perform many and they perform them
all along this kill chain it's the
combination of man and machine
well-trained threat hunters with modern
security software that's important what
we actually found is that F secures EDR
product did contain information that
could be used to identify the presence
and the operation of Fizz mints profit
we've of course notified them and
they've are the developers of the EDR
products and they've been busy building
detection ever since team I actually
tested the tool yesterday I think in the
in our test environment and it
identified the tool which was great now
we just need to figure out how to bypass
that again
our second key point is that attackers
will always steal credentials whether
that's through social engineering
whether that's because they dumped them
from a file server or whether perhaps
they just found them on a file share
it's the misuse of these credentials
that's important if we have a file
server admin who authenticates to a file
server to carry out their day-to-day
business activities and we have an email
server admin and he authenticates to an
email server to carry out their
day-to-day business activities if these
two users have no legitimate reasons to
cross paths and they never have done
before but all of a sudden the email
server admin authenticates to the file
server and starts a numerating the local
system that would be a fairly good
indication of something that should be
investigated a third key point as Timo
mentioned attacks and defenses are
moving lower and lower on the technology
stack initially we were stealing
credentials in virtual memory we then
stole credentials in physical memory
Microsoft went one layer down and built
credential guard to defend against this
and finally we went one layer further
and attack the firmware in order to
steal credentials credentials on the
only thing that Microsoft is trying
separate use is trying to protect with
virtualization sorry app the defender
application guard can now run Microsoft
edge in hyper-v enabled containers which
means that if you browsed to a malicious
website and it exploited your browser
and ran some ransomware for example then
the ransomware
would run within the container in your
files would not be encrypted but
Microsoft cannot do all the work for you
and if you want to coerce a attacker in
to write it to it using a vulnerability
worth 250,000 dollars then you need to
keep your firmware up-to-date we
recently ran this presentation at an
internal event in London and when we
asked the room how many people keep
their operating systems up-to-date
everyone raised their hand but when we
said how many of you update your
firmware as timely as you update your
operating system no one raised their
hand which is fairly telling so our call
to action
is this a deployed credential guard and
keep your firmware up-to-date and with
that we would like to say thank you to
disobey for having us and open the floor
for questions
[Applause]