[Music]
hi how are you mr. Kurata good hi my
name is auntie correcto
and I'm going to be talking about
something way less technical than it was
did and I hope we are happy with that
so I work with Nixa corporation now and
it's the digital forensics and Incident
Response Team Lead before that I was
working with the government for eight
years
so I've been working a lot with users
and trying to help them and I have to
make a confession I really like
computers I really do
I've liked them since I was a young kid
I think I got my first computer when I
was six years old and it was a c64 I
always been fascinated with them and I
have no idea why and I want to ask you
guys a question
do you like computers yeah because a lot
of people don't but it's quite quite
obvious that you guys do because you're
here you're all hackers or wanna be
hackers future hackers past hackers
government people all sorts of people
but most of our people who use computers
don't really like computers that much
and why why is that why is that a
problem I'll try to explain to you why
that might be a problem because we ask
the people who create basically all the
software and hardware and all the
devices that we use we have this kind of
this mindset that we like the stuff and
we understand it now we speak the
language of computers and that's
actually really hard really really hard
and it takes a lot of time and a lot of
effort to learn that so isn't that just
great that we make everything as we like
it I'm not sure it is it's all good cuz
as technical people and engineers we
have a way of approaching these problems
so we designed software or a device and
then we give it to the user and the user
needs the computer to do their job these
days every job requires the use of
computer
well not absolutely every job but most
jobs I'd say most white-collar jobs at
least and a lot of blue-collar jobs too
so let's say you're a carpenter and you
want to sell something to somebody you
need a website then you need an email
address and you need all these technical
infrastructure when actually what you
want to do is build things out of wood
which actually is a great hobby but if
that's your passion you should also for
some reason be passionate about
computers to be able to use them very
well so what our solution to this
problem has been security training like
we be into security trainings I think a
lot of people here have actually held
security trainings for their users on
people or at least try to explain their
mom or sister or dad why security is
important and how to use the Internet
securely and we have these problems okay
users make mistakes and those mistakes
turns into security incidents so what we
do is we educate the users some more
okay they make more creative mistakes
because our education is well to be
honest it's it's failing pretty badly
and why is that why is security training
failing so bad I think there's a bunch
of reasons to this and one of the
reasons that usually comes up is that
the security training itself is not
sufficiently complicated
well complicated maybe it's a bad word
comprehensive and users don't want to
learn it I think that is that is one of
the key points the learning resistance
because if you're not passionate about
computers and care deeply about them
understand how they work it's really
really hard to teach you how to use them
securely as everybody is here at least
about my age have learned to play the
recorder at school remember that it's
this plastic device its main purpose is
to drive parents and neighbors mad and
how many of we us still play that
instrument well I'm not seeing a lot of
hands one hand well done sir
professionally just not
yeah professional recorder player back
there that's beautiful but not a lot of
people but you've all been there sitting
in the classroom with a bunch of other
kids getting this plastic thing shoved
in your mouth and told to make music
doesn't really work I said well you
weren't that interested in the recorder
you wanted to play the guitar because
you listened to Iron Maiden and you saw
the guys on a stage and thought that's
really cool okay now some of you are
probably thinking but I trained my users
and now they are better they actually
know how to use the computer more
securely and that is true it has small
benefits because you can teach muscle
memory to people you can teach them what
to click and what to avoid but the
problem with muscle memory is that it
doesn't adapt at all
it's just a series of movements that you
teach people and when the security
paradigm moves and the things change
well the muscle memory can't keep up
there's a bunch of I call these learning
gaps like when you're trying to teach
people how to use the computer properly
because computers are extremely
complicated so we have a cognitive gap
there it's trying to teach somebody how
to use a computer it actually takes a
lot of intelligence to understand the
conceptual complicated abstract things
that make up an operating system or a
file system or how a software works or
how the internet works so if you can't
bridge that gap if the person just well
to put it bluntly if they're not smart
enough to understand the concepts how
can you teach that person how to use the
computer will you go back to muscle
memory go down and left and click and
then you type word and then you press
ENTER and there you have word processor
and you can write your letter to Grandma
there you go another gap is of course
the interest gap if you're not
interested in computers there are
nuisance to you something that you have
to use because your job requires it your
boss requires it and well every job does
now it's really hard to bridge that gap
get somebody interested in it and of
course there's a generational gap I've
should have put too
here because I don't think it's only
true to say that old people have trouble
with computers so I think young people
can have as much trouble with computers
as old people as we think okay digital
natives they're born without smart
device in their hand and that is the key
actually they're born with a smart
device in their hand they're not born
and you are using general-purpose
computers anymore that much they have
smartphones and they use those and using
a smart phone doesn't really teach you
anything about computing and using apps
doesn't really teach you much about
computing you have to use a computer and
you have to be interested in the
computer to learn how it works and of
course with older people your hearing is
getting worse your eyesight is getting
worse your hands aren't working so well
anymore
and if you get to bridge all these gaps
then sure you can train somebody to be
good but if you can't what what should
be done what what solution do we have
the problem of getting somebody with
let's say two or three of these gaps to
use a computer securely they might be
really good at what they do they might
have very good professional competence
they might be CEOs of a company and we
probably can think of examples of CEOs
of a company doing something that for us
to secure cybersecurity professionals is
amazingly dumb like sending money to a
Nigerian prince because well they might
be smart but they're not smart in the
right way and as the people who are
creating the digital world we I think
our baseline is in the wrong place our
baseline is somewhere over there in the
middle because we're up there being
linux penguins and understanding all
this stuff and being really really up to
date with everything and all the threat
actors and threat hunting and whatever
we know that stuff so we think that our
regular users are just a couple of
notches below us incompetence
perhaps so that's where we put our
target but at least my experience has
been
that even very intelligent very smart
people are quite less competent with
computers than what we think about so
we're down somewhere over there they can
open an internet browser but good luck
having them explain to you what's the
difference between the world wide web
and the Internet some of them don't know
what the difference is between Facebook
and the internet or how to behave in
very Facebook and I think there is
something that we can do about it so I
was thinking about this subject and
trying to see what other people smarter
than me have thought about this and I
really didn't find much so I came up
with a word so I didn't find a proper
word so I came up with my own and I call
this logical depth and this is all the
accrued ways of using computers that
were founded years and years ago decades
ago actually like remember this one
weird guy he's a perfect example of the
mindset that we have we call this guy a
floppy disk it's neither it's a rigid
square but it's a floppy disk for us for
some reason it has a disk inside it and
the previous version was floppy but this
is still a floppy disk and even today in
word in 2020 I still click a picture of
a floppy disk to save my files which to
me of course well that's obvious it's
always been a floppy disk I've had this
but talked to a 20 year old ask them
have you ever seen a floppy disk they're
just gonna think you treaty printed a
Save icon and this kind of stuff is
really prevalent in our computing
environment like all things that we have
built into the muscle memory of our
users and told them that this is the
paradigm of using a computer this is
what you have to do you take that weird
Square and you click it and that will
save your file and this is what I call
logical depth and I think this is one of
the things that we should start trying
to get rid of I think the relationship
between people and computer
for not us it's it's not abusive for us
but for a lot of people it is an abusive
relationship because a lot of attackers
take advantage of the fact that a lot of
people are intimidated and scared of
their computers and I think they're
gonna break it
that was well previously in those days
you made a wrong command you could
actually break the whole thing but with
a Windows 10 it's kind of hard to break
it well of course we try cuz we're
hackers we try to break it in different
ways but a lot of people are just
worried that they're gonna do it by
accident now we have a lot of outdated
concepts logical depth technical depth I
think it's just way too complicated like
these buttons here these are actually
security controls that have been boot
put into Microsoft Word to stop people
shooting themselves in the leg but are
these actually what we should be doing
like putting buttons there just enable
editing it actually means run all the
magma macros and the other thing is if
you want to print the document and you
think I'm not gonna get affected by a
piece of paper well you're probably
right about that but you have to enable
anything to be able to print it makes
absolutely no sense at all even to me
and trying to explain to my mother why
these things work like that and what
these buttons mean it's it's a
non-starter I can't do that I just don't
click it just don't click it but I have
to click it sometimes oh okay well if
you have to then you click it they tried
to fix that once remember this one a
Windows 8 yeah Metro it's a beautiful
user interface I think is one of the
worst things I've ever seen it's
absolutely terrible and they they
thought about this issue too but they
were thinking of a different paradigm
they weren't thinking about usability as
such they were thinking about
touchscreen-based usability because the
writing was on the wall tablets are
coming the iPad is coming we are going
to start using our index fingers to
interact with the computer instead of
the mouse so that's what they came up
with everybody hated it absolutely hated
it and they came got rid of it pretty
fast
and for good reason of course and
Windows 10 brought back the Start menu
with a big round of applause from
everybody and I think the reason for
that is that it was in muscle memory you
go down and left to the lower hand
corner and you click and then a menu
opens and all your software is there and
just a couple of weeks ago my dad guys
asked me that can I pin or put this
program somewhere else than the Start
menu he's been a CEO of different
companies for a long time I was like
dude of course you can and then I showed
him how and he can't still do it he
can't do it it didn't go through his
muscle memory so I had him do it and now
he knows how to do it so please when
fixing it just think about the actual
issue because this this is just it's
just making it worse but they did
something really cool cuz Clippy
remember that guy yeah
the older gentleman in the front who
remembers Clippy Clippy was an attempt
to help the user because okay our user
interface is so complicated people don't
know how to use our software so we'll
just put this cartoon paperclip there
and you can ask questions from it I
didn't of course didn't work this was in
the 1990s we didn't have the computing
power we didn't have the machine
learning algorithms or the web back in
which it could use or crowdsource or
anything but I think well something like
this should be brought back using modern
technologies where you could actually
get help using the computer just give it
tasks like take a small step towards
talking to your computer like on Star
Trek instead of messing around with
Excel yourself you can just tell it'll
get correlate all the names here and
it's it's gonna be done so bring it back
one day maybe not that guy but maybe
someone else I think the problem is in
part that it's getting really
complicated it's really really complex
computers today general-purpose
computers can do so much you can browse
the web you can play games you can do
whatever with them and in the world of
IT it's driving really deep specialist
because we have experts on one domain
and another domain and those domains
don't talk to each other we're very well
because if you have to be a really deep
expert on one subject to know all about
it we don't really have more of these
general computing experts anymore
even better er bina used to be one of
those people like he knew everything
about computers but who here knows
everything about computers now
like everything software and hardware
you might know everything about the
let's say the tcp/ip stack and that's a
lot of information you have to have and
I think we're clinging to really really
outdated abstraction layers like does it
still in this day and age make sense to
talk about files like individual files
that we put in folders in directory
structures on our hard drive and is that
really are we doing that because we've
always done it that way we evolved to
that it's been decades of computing and
we still do that we just put files in
folders and we're really happy about it
it used to have an analogue in the real
world where you had folder cabinets
cabinets filing system where you had
files when you start your computer you
end up on the desktop well that made
sense when you had stuff on your desktop
and now you have that stuff on your
computer but now the thing that you have
on your desktop is your computer it's a
bit outdated there too and well just
look at the keyboard and the mouse all
ancient things and it's just what the
users need a want or should we start
thinking about other solutions and just
start fresh maybe most of you know what
this is about it's about the number of
transistors in integrated circuits
basically the power of computing chips
over time and it's a logarithmic scale
so every step is a tenfold increase this
is excel in 1992 running on a pentium
looks kind of complicated and hard to
use okay we increase computing power
exponentially forget the next version of
Excel
still really complicated to use the
basic idea is still the same you have
the cells here and a bunch of buttons up
there and god knows what they do you
have to go to a training course to find
out what they do okay we increase our
computing power yet again now we get
more resolution basically the same thing
again same buttons a bit more colors
looks a bit prettier and here we are no
we decided that we don't like colors so
we went back to gray and a bunch of
buttons basically still the same
software meanwhile we had a thousandfold
increase a thousandfold increase in
transistor count but we're still
thinking about software the way we're
thinking about software in 1992 not sure
if I'm alone here but I just think
that's weird maybe we should put all
this computing power into better use
instead of just putting the colors into
Excel and then removing them up
absolutely it has new futures now it
does things that it didn't do before it
has 30 million lines of code I think now
the whole office suit that's huge
absolutely huge so what happens if you
want to simplify things just make them a
lot more simple look I'm not trying to
bad-mouth this dude whose tweet is here
I was just thought that there was such a
perfect example of a tech guy's attitude
towards towards simpler things if I
think we need simpler things and the
customers think they need simpler things
so when Apple came out with the iPad
they didn't have much trouble selling
them his users love them he just poked
at it and it works I have a member when
my kids were two years old and they were
able to use an iPad a slap a Linux
computer in front of a two-year-old and
you get a traumatized child and you give
them an iPad they can just though I
press here the picture of the mouse and
I get the mouse game and then they press
the home button and they get to choose
another game beautiful perfection in
there for a child but for us as hackers
can't sideload stuff that's
I don't get to configure my window
manager I don't get to do all this and
that stuff and and we're the guys who
are creating software helping users and
our mindset is so different from them
because they love iPads and iPhones so
Paul for it a Microsoft guy really happy
about the new Windows Phone well we know
what happened there eight years later
who has a Windows Phone by the way a
show of hands please
Jesus Christ okay well that's nice a
couple of you still have one forensics
yeah good reason to have one hates yeah
what happens is that the tech press
treats you like you're a retard and I
don't know well luckily this being the
Internet somebody summoned the
anti-sexism ghost and he got booed which
was good but the point is not to be an
Apple fanboy here it's just to say that
they I think they shifted the paradigm
there they didn't start creating a
Windows desktop optimized for touch
screens so that your Start menu just
takes you in a different planet and then
you see all these squares of colors and
then you're back on the desktop with
your app that you start from that they
started from scratch and they did
something else and once you get it right
there's not much reason to shift it
around that much anymore
after that there's an iPhone from 2008 I
think it's the first iPhone and there's
the latest iPhone 12 years later and yes
you can see it's been quite the same
they got rid of the home button now you
have to swipe up but that's not a very
big barrier of entry took me like three
months to master that and just swipe and
I'm kind of technical I don't want to
brag but you know but it's essentially
the same thing a customers love this
stuff when my elderly relatives or even
younger relatives asked me at what kind
of a computer I should buy just ask them
why would you want to buy a computer but
why would you do that and they're like
well I'm good question but exactly buy
an iPad and I do that for absolutely
selfish reasons reasons
once they buy an iPad they never call me
again to ask me about problems with it
they don't have problems with it just
runs and if it doesn't run well do a
factory reset everything's in iCloud all
your pictures and everything you don't
have to talk talk
tell them how to copy a punt bunch of
JPEG files from a folder called DCIM
which obviously means your pictures
right it's just all in iCloud as I had
an Android phone because I was a nerd I
wanted to get this coolest smartphone
and I got one and I was really happy
about the fact that I could sideload
apps and I could manage my files and I
could put folders there and do all this
cool tinkering stuff and I changed the
launcher and everything and when I got
an iPhone my first thought was where are
all my files well where are they how can
i browse this device and how can i get
deeper access india then I realized I
can't I took me a while to shift my
thinking about this that I started stop
thinking about JPEG files and started
thinking about my photos and I my photos
leaving the iCloud and the photos on
their Android phone can't find them
anywhere
I'm not sure where they are we've been
looking for them baby pictures there I
would have wanted to say but I did
something stupid put them on a hard
drive somewhere and then just chucked it
away I guess them I don't know it comes
down to this age-old question basically
for us as people who love to have the
freedom to use our devices any way we
want we have a desk full of people there
who will tell you that it's one of the
most important things in the world to
have freedom and I agree to a point is
when you take the rest of the population
not spending their weekend getting drunk
with other hackers and ask them would
you prefer a secure device or a device
that you can compile the kernel on it's
quite an obvious answer and instead of
trying to shove our way of thinking down
their throats and trying to get them to
understand this is the security the way
we understand it maybe we should give
them what they want a walled garden
stuff sinks to cloud biometric login no
passwords
nope in codes because I used to be a
detective at the Helsinki Police
Department and one of the easiest ways
to crack an iPhone is just to check the
suspects date of birth that was usually
their pin code slug and these are people
who kind of care about their operational
security sometimes but still when you
had a thumbprint thumbprint it's a lot
harder to crack we have to hold them
like this but still it's the question I
try to ask here is like why does
somebody who works in HR need a
turing-complete spreadsheet software
because the most I'd say 90% of Excel is
being used to compile a list of names of
people that is usually I've actually
designed a whole exercise using Excel
that's not what it's supposed to do if
you can't even type into the cells it
starts doing all this kind of weird
magic you have to start with a tick it's
yeah okay somebody's yelling their lap
oh yeah a bad user user interfaces this
it sounds like a trivial thing but when
you take this to the physical world we
have examples of bad user interfaces
being fatal and I'm gonna use a few
classic ones one is a country singer
called John Denver who died in 1997 he
was an avid pilot he loved flying planes
and he had built his own plane and the
cockpit configuration was such that
there's a fuel shutoff valve if you have
problems with the engines you can shut
off the fuel and you'd usually put it
somewhere in front of you but he had
decided or somebody else had decided I'm
not sure who to put it over his shoulder
and I'm not sure if you guys fly planes
but they have rudders and when you press
the rudder the plane does something like
this and when you have a fuel shutoff
valve over your shoulder and you have to
quickly press it do something like this
and then you press down on the rudder
and then you lose control of the plane
and then you die and that's that's a
person killed by a bad user interface in
my opinion another one was this it
always liked to play this
what if they changed the way you drive
your car as often as they change how you
run your computer like how your
operating system works or software works
and they've done this a couple of times
but they'd still the basic configuration
is the same because it doesn't need to
be changed you have the gas and the
brake and the clutch
if you drive a manual car but Jeep came
up with this ingenious shifter that
stays in this place I think they gave it
a really cool name like mono static
shifter or something like that basically
it has just lights on top of it then you
push it and you hold it it goes to park
and you press it once it goes to reverse
and then it always returns to the same
position where it is and then you have
to check it with your eyes instead of
using your hand and you can feel where
it goes and Anton Yelchin was an
American actor born Russian actually who
played Chekhov in the new Star Wars
movies if you've seen those of course
you've seen those he was killed by this
actually killed they think it was
because of this he was got out of his
car and went to open a gate and the car
rolled over him and crushed him to death
and they recalled 1.1 million cars
because they had hundreds of accidents
just because they'd made a slight tweak
in the user interface of the car I think
this is something yeah we had one case
about this where I actually just saw the
headline so I'm not sure what happened
but I think there was a case even in
Finland where somebody was endangered
because using I'm not gonna say anything
cuz I'm not sure but this case was
confirmed is there was a bunch of nurses
who were giving chemotherapy to a young
girl and they needed to hydrate her cuz
it's it's really rough on the body
especially if you're young and they
forgot to hydrate her because the
software they were using to control and
monitor the treatment was so confusing
that these three nurses with over 10
years of combined experience none of
them in different shifts didn't pick up
on the fact that she hadn't been given
any loo it quits because they were using
something that looks like this
that's just terrible in my opinion just
to be using something like this and
especially when your job is that your
job is being a nurse you're not a
technical person you care about people
and you want to take care of people and
they force you to use complicated
software which endangers your patients
lives and one problem that they have
with medical software is that sometimes
they just change the positions of input
input boxes or calculations or results
or something like that and people in
hurry they read the wrong numbers put in
the wrong numbers and patients pay the
price so this is my basically the point
that I'm trying to make here with all
this pointless or non-technical rambling
is like if it's difficult to use it's
difficult to use securely so maybe we
should start asking that how often our
security issues are actually usability
issues and why are we demanding
basically impossible things from our
users like asking them to learn how to
use a computer really really well to
keep themselves secure when that's well
we've been doing that for the gate
decades now is it working I don't think
it's working
I don't think anybody think it's working
but it's still the only thing that we're
doing because we have this mindset we
have this hacker techno guy mindset that
we're fascinated with these things and
we love them and we want to work with
them all the time so here is a bunch of
symptoms what people think about it's
the year of Linux on the desktop it's
been several years yeah exactly
thank you sir you may get up and please
no but exactly we never never gonna see
the year of Linux on the desktop
have you used Linux on the desktop of
course you have yeah would you install
that to your elderly mother no way well
yeah some people do and some people have
relatives that know how to use them and
you can configure it but it will never
be the de-facto user interface
of modern computers for people it's too
complicated sometimes it feels like I'm
playing an adventure game that's the
only goal is to humiliate me when I'm
using it and I'm kind of a technical guy
not to brag but you know I'm free and
open-source software
great idea great for us great for them
but getting a community of technical
people to design software well I tried
to learn how to use GIMP not that easy
when you have usability experts I don't
think they really work that much on open
source projects they work for companies
and they come up with stuff like iOS
doesn't look like free and open software
and the Android while technically
superior often than the latest iPhone
doesn't really matter because the iPhone
is still the same and still works the
same way and people will still buy
iPhones and of course there are more
Android Souls than iPhones but that's
because an iPhone is expensive and you
can get a hundred euro Android from
anywhere and well social media will they
want to talk too much about that but we
see when people who really shouldn't be
on the Internet get on the internet and
start using social media we have 17th
century disease is coming back because
anti-vaccination is obviously a thing
have you heard that the earth is flat
trump's president all kinds of stuff
like an email security we haven't fixed
that e-reader we run or our whole
economy on email and we haven't fixed
the security we have PGP well s/mime we
have secure mail we have different kinds
of solutions to this but none of them
have been actual solutions they're
technical solutions to a technical
problem but they're not a solution to
the problem of us not being able to send
a secure email by default without
messing around with all kinds of weird
PGP keys for example and the next
generation will come and they will go to
the workplaces and they will have these
same problems we can't just wait for
time to solve this for us I say that my
kid is always only smart
he's gonna be perfect at work it's never
gonna have any problems with email or or
any of this it's not gonna happen and
don't get me started on Bitcoin because
I've been hearing all about it it's
about to go mainstream any day now
but when ransomware operators attack
they have to get a fix at least this
long to explain to you what is Bitcoin
and how to use it it's just too
complicated and then they hire
consultants for that it's just to
complicate you can run a multi-million
dollar company but just getting Bitcoin
working is it's a lot to ask it's not
gonna be a mainstream solution any day
but a lot of people think it's gonna be
so I have a few suggestions just
radically simplify the user experience
if you're working with some kind of a
software product don't think about more
features just think what is the minimum
amount of information I can show the
user and they can still use my app just
radically not just a little bit remove
features if 20% of the users use 80% of
the features and 80% of the users use
only 20% of the features and a lot of
the features can be security risks why
ships off soft ship software that has
all those features maybe just stripped
them down and cloud services for example
you don't have to maintain a computer
like an iPad for my parents good choice
it's maintaining a computer is hard work
and you have to understand the computer
to maintain it and please get get rid of
the password when I was working for the
government we had and we have this
campaign like longer is better just
talking about passwords obviously so
we've been doing this for a long time
just trying to get users to use good
passwords users are still not using good
passwords they will never start to use
beauty passwords we have to come up with
something else maybe a shorter password
and then force multi-factor
authentication to all your services
where you can and maybe just set your
skillet expectations lower like when
teaching the users how to use software
secure
just don't teach to your peers I don't
teach just a notch below your peers just
go down enough and try to see the
problem from their eyes and try to teach
them something more and stop trying to
train your way out of this problem
completely and think that the problem is
that we just don't have enough security
training if we've done that for decades
it won't work
it hasn't work it won't work in the
future so I think it's time for a shift
in the paradigm now we're seeing the
dark and this is typical security advice
but they have a problem it's okay
I'm trying to go to this website I get a
certificate warning and then okay
brace yourself I'm gonna explain to you
what a certificate is and how it works
and how the chain of trust works there
and what a sefer suit is and and the
user doesn't really care at all about
this all they care about they can't
access their mail because they get a
certificate warning and browsers have
been doing good work here like modern
browsers won't let you bypass it without
going through hoops and jumping through
hoops and going through a very
complicated procedure of clicking open
menus and some browsers I think that
this day won't even let you do that but
then we teach the users you just click
accept and yes I know the risk and then
you just go so maybe start thinking
about this thing like a rabbit and start
thinking this is what my users are
thinking and my browser won't let me go
this website I'll just take my business
elsewhere
because this is what they're actually
thinking they don't care at all about
certificates they just want to do
whatever they're doing buy a pair of
shoes yeah that's basically my message
yeah it's a hotel chain logo that's
right actually an example of what
paradigm shift is when your perception
of something shifts and you see
something else does anyone want to ask a
question
[Applause]