[Music]
okay hello everybody I'm really excited
to be here thank you for coming to my
talk shadow reloaded where I'll talk
about how we revived shadow attacks in
order to escape sandboxes and evade
endpoint security products so a little
bit about myself my name is Ron I am the
engineering lead for Accenture security
Israel as part of the R&D team so now
let's dive right into the matter at hand
so a bit abettor about the history of
shadow attacks how it all started
Soto started in one rainy day in 2002
where this guy crisp packets published
an article titled exploiting design
flaws in the win32 api for privileged
escalation or shadow attacks how to
break windows so in this paper he
describes this attack that he has where
he uses a WM time or Windows message
sent to a target process and that
message has a pointer to a callback that
would be executed now this callback he
injects some code using a an edit box
control and then the pointer to the
callback points to that code the target
process would usually be some win32
service running as system and showing
some GUI to the users the way this
attack would work is first of all the
attacker would find the Edit box in the
target process and call send message to
it sending it the WM set text message
this segment set text message would
receive a buffer which would be copied
over to the target process this buffer
would obviously contain the shell codes
now the second step he would find the
shell code inside the target process so
he could do that in one of two ways
either by scanning the memory of the
target process or just running it in a
lab environment using a debugger and
assuming that the address will be the
same always which was true at the time
once he has the address of that shell
code he would then send a second message
to the target process this time a WM
timer containing a pointer to that
address that he found thus achieving
code execution now Microsoft saw this
and they said okay how can we stop this
so eventually what they did is they
patched the WM timer so that it won't be
able to execute any timer that wasn't
previously registered with the set timer
API also they started a move to stop
those services from showing GUI to the
users because that's a bad practice but
that's not good enough because WM timer
is just one example of a Windows message
that can do that because there are other
Windows messages that also receive a
pointer to a callback and then just
execute it so rich edit controls has a
few ListView has one for sorting items
and a treeview also has one for sorting
its children so let's take a step
backward and see why were these attacks
even possible in the first place so the
first reason is that there were no
access control mechanisms for Windows
messages between processes in the same
desktop so any process even one running
as guest could send a Windows message to
any other process in the same desktop
even one running a system the second
thing is that there were services
running inside the users desktop so the
same desktop has both user processes and
services running our system the third
thing is that some services running our
system expose a GUI to the user and
that's bad because if they expose a GUI
that means they can be interacted with
by normal users and fourth remotes
windows messages could contain pointers
to a shell code that will then be
executed by the target process so the
combination of all these together allows
us to achieve this shatter attack then
came Windows Vista and Windows Vista put
in a few security fixes to prevent these
things from happening so the first thing
they did they introduced a mechanism
called user interface privileged
isolation or you IPI this held something
called mandatory integrity control or in
other words each process will receive an
integrity level low medium high or
system normal processes would usually
get normal sorry medium level elevated
processes would get high and system
processes would get system
and this mechanism would prevent Windows
messages from being sent from a one
process to another if the target process
has a higher integrity level another
thing they did is a introduced Windows
session zero isolation
so if until now the first years are
connecting into the computer logging in
would log into session zero this is no
longer the case now a new user would
receive session one two and so on
and session zero is reserved only for
these system services also they
introduced the interactive service
protection which is a mechanism that
said if there is a service that tries to
show gooey to the user then it will open
up this ugly message box this ugly pop
up and say to the user you know there's
a service trying to show you some user
interface on another desktop do you want
to go over to that desktop and see it
and this kind of forced all vendors
Microsoft and third-party vendors to
stop showing GUI in their services so
this basically put a stop to shatter
attacks being able to escalate the
privileges so then they were soon for
God and never to be used again that's
until we came along so we looked at some
modern use cases and saw how we can use
shatter attacks in them so a first use
case is a commercial sandbox that we got
to check now how this sandbox worked it
divided all the processes in the
computer into two separate groups
trusted processes and untrusted
processes trusted processes are
basically or your corporate apps so
every app that has access to your
corporate data and those apps would not
have access to the Internet or external
facing networks then you have the
untrusted processes which are everything
else basically all the apps that come
from unknown sources or all the ones
that communicate with the Internet
and these would not have access to your
corporate data now the isolation would
be implemented over multiple domains so
file system and registry for example all
untrusted processes would receive a
different view of the file system and of
the registry so they wouldn't be able to
see all the files that are naturally
there on the computer so if you have
folder with some files an untrusted
process might see that folder open or
not even existing at all and also write
operations would be isolated also on
network isolation as we said trusted
processes could not access the network
the isolation was also on process
boundaries so opening another process
for writing was no longer possible it
was possible for reading sandbox did not
stop opening another process for reading
and more about that later but we
couldn't open it for writing so the
usual use case of say virtual a low key
X to allocate some executable memory in
the target process and write process
memory to injector shekel our shellcode
into it didn't no longer work also
sending messages windows messages from
an untrusted process to a trusted
process that was also blocked by the
sandbox reading a clipboard from an
untrusted process written by in a
trusted process printing the screen such
as with bit bit BLT all those were
blocked by the sandbox so we looked at
it a little bit more and we said ok what
can we do with it how can we still
exploit it so we looked at the file
system and registry and we saw that
those were pretty well implemented they
used mini filters in the kernel so we
couldn't bypass debt then we went on and
we looked at the process boundaries so
can we open another process and write to
it and that will was also implemented
pretty well they use the mechanism
called object callbacks or the function
Oh be register callbacks and what that
function lets it lets you is it lets you
define a callback that will be called
whenever according to configuration one
of the following happens either you
create open or duplicate the handle to a
process thread or desktop so they could
set a callback that will be called
whenever someone tries to open a handle
to an existing process and if that
request is with writes access then they
would deny it so again we couldn't
bypass that so how can we still escape
that sandbox so then we looked at
sending Windows messages and what we saw
is that this sandbox
implemented this isolation using user
mode hooks now the problem with the user
mode hooks is that they are found in
user mode that is entirely inside the
user mode memory space and thus since
they are in our processes memory space
our process can remove those hooks it
can it's gonna unhook itself and that's
exactly what we did we unhooked
ourselves from these user mode hooks and
lo and behold we could now send a
Windows message to a trusted process
does this scenario ring a bell
can't see how that could be useful so
bringing back shadow attacks from the
dead we researched a little bit and we
found this triple in attack and this
attack what it did it is is it used a
different Windows message from the
original chatter attack it used TVM sort
children CB which is a message sent to
tree views and they would inject their
code using virtual a low key X and right
process memory to get their code into
the target process and then use this
window message to the tree view in order
to pass a pointer to that callback and
execute it so this is nice but we need a
different method to inject our code
because we cannot open another process
for writing so let's assume for a second
and we'll soon see why we need this
assumption and what can we do with it
let's assume we have a trusted process
in the machine and it has an edit box a
status bar a tree view and some readable
writable and executable memory sounds
far fetched I know but wait for it so to
inject our shell code first of all we
look for the Edit box and we call we
send it to our Windows message of WM set
text to send it our of shell code now a
small improvement that we did is that
instead of sending it instead of calling
the normal send message a function we
called the unicode version of it and
then we can pass any shell code that
even has nulls null bytes just not
double nose so that was a small
improvement then the next stage we would
find our shell code inside that target
process now since the sandbox did not
block opening another process for
reading we can open it for reading go
over all this allocated memory
and find our shellcodes now back in the
day in 2002 depth or data execution
prevention did not exist yet but today
it does so once we injected our
shellcode into this edit box buffer
that's no longer enough because that
memory is not executable so we have to
somehow transfer it into some rwx memory
so what we do is first of all we find
this rwx memory that we assume that we
have then we use the status bar that
again we assume that this process has in
order to do the following we send it to
Windows messages the first is a set text
message and the set text message to
differentiate from the edit box it's a
text edit box a set text message assumes
that the pointer gets points to a memory
range in the source product process for
a status bar that is not the case the
pointer points to an address in the
target process so set text to the status
bar means copy something from somewhere
inside the target processes memory range
into the status bars buffer so we send
it the pointer of the shell code of our
shell code that we found earlier and
then we send it another message this
time get text and gave it a pointer to
the rwx memory that we found to some
code cave that we selected in there and
that would copy the shell code from the
status bars buffer and into the rwx
memory once we have that we have our
shell code inside rwx memory and all
that is left is to send a treeview a
message of TVM sort children CB give it
a pointer to our shell codes and our
shell code executes now apparently a new
Windows 7 x64 has all of the above the
Windows Explorer Explorer it out exit it
has right there on the top right it has
an edit box where we can search for
files on the left we have a tree view
where we can see a nice tree of all the
files on our system on the bottom we
have a status bar it's actually not the
one you see there the real one is hidden
and we can't see it but it's there and
that's all that's important we don't
need to see it in order to interact with
it and
this explorer.exe had one single page of
rwx memory right there off the box you
know no change is needed it already has
all these things so we can then move on
with our attack basically given a
shellcode that doesn't have any double
mouths what we did is first of all we
find the addresses the handles to all
those UI elements that we need so the
Edit box the treeview and the status bar
we find the rwx memory region inside the
process and we select our code cave
inside it in this case we chose the end
of that region then number three we
create a buffer that will serve for the
window message for the TVM sort children
CD message because it needs to receive
some struct with the data and number
four we created a buffer that holds our
shell code and that buffer from number
three together so we can inject it
number five we sent the Edit box the WM
set text message with this buffer to
inject it to the target process we scan
the memory I was explored at exam we
find our shell code inside it then in
number eight we send a message to the
status bar of set text and give it the
address of our shell code and get text
from that to copy that shell code into
the rwx memory that we found in step
number two finally we send a treeview
ATVM sort children CB message giving it
the pointer to our circle our shell code
inside that our WX memory and again we
achieve code execution now this worked
fine for proof of concept but when we
came to weaponize it we encountered two
small problems now the first one the
first pitfall is that the compare
functions could be potentially called
many many times why is that because if
you have a treeview and it has a lot of
children then all those children need to
be compared to each other to see what
the sorting of the tree will be so what
we did to solve this is we added this
assembly line this move by PTR our EP -
7 0 XC 3 we prepared our shellcode with
that and
that line does is basically it's over
writes the first bite of the shellcode
or rather the first bite of this line to
be a ret opcode and what this does is
that every subsequent call to this
shellcode will just execute ret and
return back to the caller so then our
shellcode would run only once now the
second thing we saw is that sometimes
the Explorer the File Explorer window is
not open now if the window is not open
then we have no status bar no edit box
and no treeview to interact with so we
have to open one of our cell of our own
what we did is we called shall execute
giving it a parameter of open and a
valid path such as C cones
yeah backslash and gave it a parameter a
flag of SW hide this flag tells the
system to open the window in a hidden
mode so the user would not see anything
we then inject our shellcode as before
and we can even close the window because
now our code is running from the memory
space of that process so that was the
the first use case that we saw for this
chatter attack this sandbox and the
second use case is that we wanted to
inject code and whilst evading EDRs so
modern EDRs or endpoint security
mechanisms they are very sensitive and
they really don't like it that you try
to inject code from one process to
another and if for example you try the
classic method of code injection using
open process you open the remote process
for writing then virtual alkie x to
allocate some writable memory inside it
a writable executable sorry write
process memory to write your shell code
into that process and create remote
threads to run that shell code that you
injected any self-respecting edr today
would block you from doing that thing
so shatter attack to the rescue however
this test was not done in Windows 7 was
done on Windows 10 and apparently in
Windows 10 it is no longer true that
explorer.exe has some rwx memory inside
it so we said ok we need our WX memory
in order to execute our code from so
what can we do with that
so what we can do is we can send T VMs
or children's TV messages and what those
do is they receive a pointer and they
call this compare function according to
the pointer that we give them so let's
look at the signature of this callback
function so this callback function right
on the bottom it receives three
parameters l / m 1 l / m 2 and l / m
sort the third parameter it receives
from this truck that we provide to the
TV m short message so children CB
message so if you see on the top we have
this truck this TV sort CB struct and
its second field is the pointer to the
compare function the third field is the
L / M that will be passed as a third
parameter to all calls of this compare
function now the first two parameters L
program 1 and L / M 2 are received from
the treeview items so if you want to
compare two items we need to get some
data from each one of them in order for
some comparing logic to occur so
basically each element in the tree each
child there has an L / am Val you and
those L params are passed to this
function so what we can do is we can
remotely enumerate the children of this
tree view and we can call set item for
each of them thus setting the value of
the L / M so that way we can control all
the values that are passed to this
function only small problem is we don't
know the order in which windows will
decide to call to compare the elements
so maybe if we have two elements maybe
this will be the one called for L / M 1
and this for l / M 2 and maybe this one
will be for L / M 1 and this 1 for 4 l /
M - but we'll so see why we don't care
really about the order between the first
two elements so but bottom line is we
can call any three argument function
that we want so we need some rwx memory
so in order to generate some to allocate
some readable writable and executable
memory we looked at virtual Alec which
is the obvious choice for this only
problem is that virtual Alec gets four
parameters
and the fourth parameter is the one of
the protection flags the one in which we
need to specify that we want this to be
an rwx memory so we must control this
parameter and since we can't then this
function is not good for us also the
other versions of these of this function
very whether it be virtual Alec e^x
virtual key X Numa virtual Alec from app
virtual Alec to virtual Alec to from app
and even the lower level ntdll
NT allocate virtual memory all of those
receive at least four parameters and we
need to control at least one parameter
which is fourth or higher so then we
said okay if we can't allocate some new
rwx memory maybe we can change some
existing memory to be readable writable
and executable so that's what virtual
protect is for however virtual protect
also receives four parameters now it
seems on first sight that the
interesting parameters of are the first
three because you got the address of the
memory that you want to change the size
of it and the new protection flags and
the fourth parameter is simply a pointer
to a D word that will receive the old
protection flags that were true for this
memory range now we thought okay maybe
we can just like wing it somehow somehow
pass null to it and thus are telling the
function that we don't care about the
old protection flags but Microsoft were
pretty clear in their documentation and
they said that if this parameter is null
or does not point to a very valid
variable the function fails so we must
control this fourth parameter as well
and we can't use virtual protect either
also the other versions of virtual
protect are also not good for us virtual
protect DX and virtual protect from app
and ntdll anti protect virtual memory
all of those receive at least four
parameters and in all of them we need to
control at least one parameter fourth or
higher so we thought about this some
more we could scratch our heads we
googled a bit we looked around and
finally we found this function heap
create now what heap create does is
creates a new heap other than the you
know you have the default heap for each
process he creates a new one and he
creates is perfect for us and why is it
perfect well first of all it receives
only
parameters and that's great because we
can call a free parameter function now
the first parameter is the options flag
and apparently he creates supports a
flag that is heap create enable execute
which makes all the memory inside the
created heap executable in addition to
already being readable and writeable the
second parameter is the initial size of
the heap and the third parameter is a
maximum size and luckily for us heap
create creates all this memory already
committed and ready to use that thoughts
it's not just reserved or something so
basically what we did is first of all we
enumerated the children of the tree view
and we set item for each of them setting
their L program values to this heap
create and they will execute flag which
is 0 X 40000 because we don't know if it
will be passed as a first or as a second
parameter to our function now since we
don't know the order and and we set all
of them to this value this means that
also the second parameter of heap
creates will be called with this value
now 0 X 40000 is 256 kilobytes so that's
also fine because it's probably not as
large to make an allocation fail but
it's large enough to contain any
shellcode know to mankind and obviously
also good enough for us and third
parameter as we said we can fully
control it so we can just pass 0 for
example which tells heap creates to
create a heap that can grow as much as
we need so then once we have these we
can basically create our own rwx memory
and shatter attack can work as it did in
Windows 7 right
well almost we had one more challenge to
fix apparently the statusbar filters
some bad characters from unprintable
characters so any character any white
character of the form something null
byte where something is between 1 and 0
X 1 F except for nine which is tab all
of those would be converted to 0 x 20
and in all bytes which is a space
now this is okay if we only need to
transfer a shell code because shell
codes can be encoded to only have
printable characters or alphanumeric
characters or not have no bytes or not
have bad characters but we also need to
transfer our set item structs or TV
items trucks which are needed for the
set item calls and those trucks have
sequences of null bytes and they have
all these bad characters in them and
they can't be encoded they need to be
transferred as is so how can we solve
that
what we did is some special handling for
those white characters so let's say that
we had a source buffer that is the one
here AABB 0 5 0 0 and CC and we want to
transfer that structure that buffer to
the target process so we looked at the
first we look at the first white
character and we see it's a ABB which is
not a filtered character so we can just
transfer it in the normal way we can
call we can send the Edit box set text
message then set text for the status bar
from the Edit box and get text from the
status bar into a target address now we
looked at the second we look at the
second white character and we see it's
zero five zero zero now this is a
filtered character so we can't just copy
it as is so what we do is we go 1 byte
backwards and once we do that we see
that we have BB 0 5 that's a character a
white character that we can copy so then
we copy that over but not to offset too
but to offset one of our buffer so then
the BB overrides the previous maybe
that's fine we don't care and 0 5 is
also appended to that buffer we go on
and then we see that we have 0 0 and CC
that's not a filter character so we can
just copy it as before through the Edit
box and the status bar that way copying
one white character at a time and going
back one byte if needed we can copy
any buffer that we want even one with
multiple null bites in a row and with
bad characters so once we did that we
managed to copy or TV items structs for
set items we can set all the items l
params and call heath create to get some
readable writable and executable memory
and then we could continue as before and
achieve code execution once again so we
want to check this on those EDRs so we
took one leading EDR in the market and
we said okay let's see how our code
behaves with it so first of all we tried
some good old create remote thread to
load library injection to see that the
EDR indeed works and does what it's
supposed to do
so as expected we did that and all the
alarm bells went off and the EDR said ok
I saw that this process is trying to
inject some memory into explore a DEXA
and run it with creative mode thread and
that's bad and I'm stopping you from
doing that so that was blocked then we
said ok now let's try our code and when
we tried our code there were no alerts
so what the EDR did find is it found
that we did open process on ourselves
and NT protect virtual memory and front
find first file uxw which are all part
of the PI to X's loader setting up the
embedded Python interpreter then he saw
that we did create window exw which is
probably caused by the shell execute
that we ran in order to create our
window and the query system information
to find the PID the process ID of
Explorer dot X ax and finally open
process for Explorer dot X ax but a read
only open and he does not VD or did not
consider that as malicious and let us do
it and that was the last thing he saw us
do everything else went completely under
the radar so once again code execution
win so to recap what we did is we took
an eighteen-year-old security-related
design issue in the win32 GUI we brought
it back from the dead to see how it
could be you
in modern operating systems and in
modern use cases and what we saw is that
basically the root cause for this to be
able to happen is that there is all this
complex and dangerous behavior with
pointers inside Windows messages so
sometimes a pointer is considered to be
pointing to data in the source process
like in the case of the Edit box as it's
a text and they did that data should be
copied from the source process to the
target process sometimes these pointers
were pointers to data inside the local
process like the status bars set text
and get text those meant that data
should be copied inside the target
processes memory range and sometimes
these pointers point to a callback to
some code that should be executed by the
target process combining these together
we could and we had enabled the allocate
rwx memory write to arbitrary address
and execute arbitrary address primitives
and with those we could inject and
execute any code so some possible
mitigation ideas well one thing we could
do is we can hook send message and
prevent or block all kinds of dangerous
win32 messages so for example things
like set text and get text for a status
bar coming from a different process or
the TVM store children CB coming from a
different process or any of the list of
messages that contain a callback they
should not be coming from a different
process so if we hook this and prevent
those from happening then that could be
better however as we said user mode
hooks are not good enough because they
can just be unhooked so a different
thing we can do is use a mechanism from
Windows called windows hooks which is
called by calling the set window hooky X
callback sorry a function and we can
call it with either the call win proc or
the get message
arguments what those would do is they
would inject DLL into all the processes
inside this desktop and specify
that would be called whenever either the
windows procedure is going to be called
or a messages are received in a process
and that callback could verify the
safety or the security of this message
coming along and could lock any
dangerous messages so luckily for us
Windows has this mechanism it just needs
to be used so a few closing thoughts
first of all we should not rely on user
mode hooks because they are not good
enough since Windows introduced patch
guard we can no longer hook in the
kernel we can't put kernel hooks so all
that is left is just user mode hooks but
that's not good enough that's a gap that
exists here because any user mode hook
can be unhooked or detoured in some way
so Microsoft really needs to come in
here and put in some new mechanism to
allow security products to secure us by
hooking the correct functions but not in
user mode in addition I believe Windows
can really benefit from something like
Linux as LSM or the Linux security
modules which is something that allows
to implement things like app armor or
SELinux above it those will allow to
define some per process per API policies
and they can mitigate or stop certain
kinds of attacks certain kinds of
dangerous operations from happening so
before we part to finish up let's watch
a little demo
second
okay
so there we have Windows 10 machine and
I'm gonna run our code which what's it
gonna do is basically it's gonna do all
the steps that we saw before so it's
gonna call shell execute in order to
open a new hidden Windows Explorer
window now because it's hidden we won't
see anything on the screen and will then
find all the controls all the UI
elements that it needs its sighted so
the Edit box the status bar and the
treeview it will then enumerate all the
treeview children and for each of them
it will copy a buffer over to the other
side and call set item with that buffer
the setting the L program value to 0 X
40000 once that is done it will send the
treeview a a message of TVM sort
children CB that will with a pointer to
the heap create function that will call
heap create with the correct parameters
and allocate us some readable writable
and executable memory inside the process
then it will inject our shellcode with
all the like how we saw it with the edit
box and the status bar
full injector show code into the target
process and finally it will call TV it
will send another message of TVM sword
shield Rijn CB with the pointer to our
shell code that will run our show code
where our shell code does is simply just
pop up a message box which we will see
that it opens up from explorer sorry
will run this code one second
yep there we go
and a message pop message box pops-up if
we look at the source process sorry one
second wait I lost it
oh there it is if we look at this
process we can see that it comes from
Explorer Alexa and we can also bring to
front and see that it is and one second
wait that's not good and we can see the
icon here on the bottom which is
explorers icon so there we have it code
execution from Explorer
so I thank you all for coming to my talk
and we have some more time for questions
if anyone got it
[Applause]
sorry how much time so the the sandbox
was about one month of research and Edie
ours was maybe another few weeks any
more questions
okay thank you very much
[Applause]