all right so we're reaching the end of
the day so obviously I would like to
thank everybody who made this conference
possible so first of all I want to thank
our program committee who reviewed the
papers and made it possible to do this
conference today and as well I want to
thank all the speakers who came here
today also thank you thanks to all the
workshop organizers and our organization
committee and the volunteers who made
this day possible also thanks to all the
sponsors so here they are the thanks to
them for their financial support so
what's next interesting information
so right now there is a cocktail right
there
there will be the workshop at 6:30 in
the building H which is over there
information you have to take a batch
like this because we have it now so you
can take it before leaving this building
so just go to the entrance ask for it
and then you'll be allowed to go in the
in the H building also for the people
who do not have a workshop we'll have a
small stand with someone teaching you
lock-picking so if you're interesting
into this you can try or just try to
learn how to play baby food or whatever
and there will be pizzas at 9:30 and the
CTF will start at 10:00 p.m. so thanks
again and we will see you next year
[Applause]