thanks a lot
I hope the sound is okay all right so
yeah
my name is summit and a very warm
welcome to day hack and it's pretty
chilly out here so I hope the warm
welcome helps you my talk is going to be
about what for those of you who are not
aware what is an open standard for
token-based delegated access put in
simple terms it means that if you are a
resource owner you can grant a
third-party application access to the
resources that you own using OAuth so
the talk is going to focus on the
implementation pitfalls that we observe
generally very frequently and it's going
to focus on the attacks and we're going
to talk about how to mitigate against
those attacks so without further ado let
me just get to my intro as Florent
already mentioned I work for the product
security team at Citrix also I lead the
blue team so basically my job is to make
Citrix products a little more secure and
I am a web and mobile application
security enthusiast and I've spoken at a
bunch of conferences including in Sec
world
romhack security fest Def Con China
blackhat Asia and apps like us in the
past so the agenda for today is to cover
both what is it and why do we need it
we're going to talk about access tokens
and identity tokens how they are
different from each other and when they
are used i didn'ti tokens are
specifically used in open ID connect but
we're going to cover that as well so and
we'll also touch upon the various ground
types that Earth has to offer and we
will also look into how auth flow works
for mobile applications finally we will
come to the attacks and discuss the
mitigation and we'll end up with a short
Q&A sessions so why do we need in the
first place let's
try to understand this with the help of
the scenario where you're logging in to
linkedin.com
you enter your LinkedIn credentials and
you see your dashboard
now what if LinkedIn wants to access
your gmail contacts you know just to
increase your contact list on LinkedIn
so in order to do so you would have to
give linked in some sort of
authorization to access your gmail
accounts contacts one way and a very
silly way of doing it is to just give
credentials to LinkedIn and it goes
ahead and logs into your Gmail account
gets your contact details and just sinks
it up with LinkedIn so LinkedIn is your
third party application here Gmail is
your resource provider and it is hosting
your resources which are the contacts
and you are the resource owner so this
is a very silly idea you shouldn't be
sharing your credentials with a third
party application what are the problems
that you see or why is it a silly idea
because the knowledge of your Gmail
password allows LinkedIn to do far more
than just fetch your contacts it can log
into your drive scan your photographs
and do pretty much everything that you
would do with your credentials also
access cannot be revoked from a single
specific third party application because
similarly you would be sharing your
credentials with multiple third party
and if you want to revoke access from a
single third party you will be doing
that by changing your credentials and if
you change your credentials so the
credential will change for all the third
party applications not just one so you
can't revoke access from a specific
third party application another drawback
is that linkdin would be required to
store your credentials and you shouldn't
be trusting it with your Gmail
credentials anyway so that's a bad idea
and Google will be required to mandate
really support password-based
authentication so that's where
came into being and it's a protocol for
delegating authorization supported by
all platforms web desktop and native
apps native apps include mobile apps so
the advantages of auth is that the scope
of access can be restricted to a
specific third-party application you can
just allow access to your contacts only
so that's one specific advantage and
access granted can be revoked from a
particular third-party application with
the wot it avoids sharing of your
credentials with the third-party that's
a major win and finally it lays down a
foundation for an authentication
protocol which is also called Open ID
Connect so before we start discussing
the flow of Earth I would like to
introduce some of the entities that are
involved in a typical earth flow the
first one is the resource owner himself
if this is the end user who owns the
resources then we have the client or the
application or the relying party all
these three terms are synonymous and are
used interchangeably and this entity is
basically the one which is requesting
access to the end users resource and
this was linked in in our previous
example then we have the resource server
which is the server which hosts the
resources of the end user
this was Gmail in our case authorization
server is the entity that is responsible
for authenticating the user and
prompting for authorization and once the
end user grants that authorization the
auth server risk is responsible for
generating the access tokens and sending
it back to the client or the application
and the relying party and this was
Google in our case finally the user
agent this is nothing but the browser
so we also need to understand that
before the entire or the OAuth flow
starts the authorization server also
needs to know what all client
applications are going to interact with
it and this is a mandatory step called
client registration which is required
before proceeding with the workflow so
what happens in this step is that the
client tells the auth server that see I
am going to try and authenticate using
your service so here are my details just
register me for your OAuth flow so the
client communicates application name
website and the redirect URL to the auth
server the auth server generates the
client ID and the client secret for the
client the odd server also stores the
client ID and the redirect URI mapping
with itself and the redirect URI is
basically used to send back access
tokens to the client after when the
client when the client is actually
trying to access the resource so the
redirect URI is used by the auth server
to send back access tokens or
authorization code finally the client ID
and the client secret is returned to the
client now this client ID and secret is
used for client or authentication with
the auth server and we'll see where that
happens in the entire flow but this is a
mandatory step required before we begin
the OAuth flow so and of course as the
name suggests the client secret is a
confidential information and should be
kept secret by the client itself for
those applications that cannot keep the
client secret confidential like a mobile
application or a single page application
the client secret should never be used
and the reason for that is that mobile
applications can be reversed engineered
and the client secret can be figured out
easily or even you can intercept the
traffic and find out what's the client
secret
so whatever application is running at
the end-users device cannot be trusted
with the client secret and the client
secret should never be used with it so
let's just see how earth works in a
nutshell and I've listed down all the
entry
the odds server here when we have the
relying party or the client application
here which is Stack Exchange then we
have the resource server and the end
user here so the end user visits Stack
Exchange and Stack Exchange shows this
option of logging in with two different
odds servers because it has previously
registered with Google and Facebook as
the odds server so the client has
registered with Google and Facebook
let's say that the user chooses Google
and Stack Exchange will initiate an
authorization request and redirect the
user to the auth server where the end
user will be expected to log in and
after logging in an authorization prompt
will be shown to the end user where
Stack Exchange is trying to access some
information of the end user would you
like to grant it or not and once the end
user accepts this authorization prompt
an authorization code is generated and
sent back at the clients redirect URL
that's where the redirect URI is
actually used the redirect URI is
nothing but the URL of the client
application and once the client receives
the auth code it can hit the token
endpoint at the auth server to get back
an access token and the access token
again is sent back to the redirect URI
now that the client has some form of
authorization which is basically in
terms of the access token it can then
hit the resource servers endpoints using
the token and fetch back the resources
so that's how our typical workflow works
and the Open ID Connect flow is pretty
much same in nature except that in step
5 you will also see an identity token
being generated in addition to the
access token now the ID token is not
used for authorization it's an identity
token and contains some information
which convey the identity of the
end-user who has logged in and this is
consumed by the client application
itself to populate the UI
with the username and other user details
so the ID token has never sent the
resource server in fact the Reis
resource server doesn't need the ID
token at all the client consumes it the
odd server is generally opaque and when
I say opaque you can't really make sense
out of it
you cannot decode it to figure out any
other information or inferred
information from it it just conveys
authorization and it is consumed by the
resource server as we just discussed
whereas the identity token is a jot and
if you decode the jot you will get a lot
of user details about the user who
logged in and as I mentioned before it
conveys the users identity information
like the user's name email address etc
it is consumed by the client for
displaying on the UI details about the
user so this brings us to the various
grants that worth has to offer there are
primarily four different grants of which
the top two are the most favored ones
where famous ones the authorization code
grant and the implicit drug these grants
are used in different scenarios
I have a short diagram which explains in
what scenario to use which one and but
throughout the presentation we'll be
mostly talking about auth code grant
flow and the implicit grant flow so
which grant to use when simply put it's
like if the application is the resource
owner itself so let's say that Facebook
wants to effect some resources that
Facebook itself is owning like the
banner or some details or the just the
templates or whatever so Facebook is
trying to fetch its own resources so
that's where you go for the client
credentials grant and like in the
previous example where we had a third
party application called LinkedIn and it
was trying to access Google resources
from of the end user that's where the
authorization code grant is used and
this is the most famous one you'll see
across website
so if the application is absolutely
trusted with user credentials then you
can go for a resource owner password
credential grant which would mean that
if we consider the previous situation if
you are willing to share your Google
credentials with LinkedIn then you can
use this one which is called resource
owner password credentials run and
finally if the application is a mobile
app or a single page application you go
for the authorization code grant along
with something known as proof key for
code exchange which we'll discuss in
detail later on this is also abbreviated
as pixie ekc he for single page
applications previously we could have
used implicit grant as well but off late
this technique has not been used in
practice because it's vulnerable to a
lot of attacks and it leaks the access
tokens everywhere in your browser
history and in the reference so it's
always used to it it's always good to
use authorization code grant with pixie
for single page apps as well so I'm a
big fan of Marvel and I made this small
analogy with Avengers infinity war so
the resource server will be played by
the soulstone and as you would know if
you've seen the movie the Red Skull
owned or knew or had possession of the
soul stone so resource owner which is
Red Skull has the soul stone and then we
have Thanos who wanted access to the
soul stone and then we have Gamora Hyun
who knew where the soul stone is it was
on war meat and she could supervise
access to it in a way so she'll play the
role of the auth server so let's see how
we just saw the flow in a nutshell now
we'll discuss more details on it so
client what Thanos wants to access the
soul stone or the resource he hits the
resource endpoint and gets an
unauthorised message because he doesn't
still have any token to them access to
so the client then redirects the
end-user to the authorization server
where the end user is going to
authenticate and grant the authorization
and once the auth code is generated and
sent back to the client
we know that the client will now
exchange this for an access token at the
token endpoint get back the token and
finally hit the token and finally hit
the resource endpoint with the token and
get back the resource so if you notice
the client credentials are also required
in this step for authenticating the
client with the auth server now this is
where the client ID and client secret is
sent to the auth server so Tanis is
happy he gets the soulstone finally and
if you see the traffic on the wire
you're hitting in the authorization
request you are hitting the auth
endpoint on the earth server along with
some parameters in the request which
includes the redirect URI the scope and
the state so the redirect URI is nothing
but the URI of the application or the
client and the scope is else the auth
server what kind of details the client
is trying to access in this case the
client is trying to access photos of the
user and the state parameter is used to
avoid CSRF attacks and we will see how
later on so in the response you will see
that the authorization code is returned
and the state parameter is reflected
back as it is then finally when the
token exchange steps happen step happens
the auth code is expected in the request
parameter along with the client secret
and the client ID client credentials
basically and this is the token endpoint
which is being hit and as a response to
it you will get back the access token so
what are the advantage
of using the odd quadrant flow number
one it provides the ability to
authenticate the client what's happening
right here next are the access token
never really gets league into the
browser's history or in the ref low head
oh that's because it comes in as a post
response to the to the client itself and
it never goes through the users browser
so this brings us to implicit grant and
if you see the entire flow it is pretty
much same except that there's no
requirement of the authorization code
it never gets generated except instead
when you are hitting the authorized
endpoint or token is def generated and
sent back to the client directly and if
you notice the traffic on the wire
you'll see that the authorization
request looks pretty much the same in
the response there's no earth code
instead the access token is directly
sent back to the application well there
are a few disadvantages of this there's
no client authentication involved and
the access token can end up in the
browser's history because it's coming in
as the response it's in the redirect
URIs parameter so it can end up in your
browser's history and it can also leak
in reference when you are redirecting to
a different third-party application so
this brings us to earth for mobile
clients and the blueprint remains the
same or the client initiates the earth
request end user authenticates and
approves server returns the control with
the auth code the auth code is exchanged
for an access token and the protected
api's are invoked but let's go through
the details on how mobile applications
are different from web applications when
it comes to earth so here I have the
resource which is the cloud API
endpoints and we have the auth server
here and this is the mobile application
on executing on the client device and
the
so once the client needs to access some
resources it will invoke the browser and
redirect the browser to the authorized
endpoint of the auth server where the
user will of course authenticate and
once the user authenticates an
authorization prompt will be shown to
the end-user on the native application
once the user approves or sets of this
authorization the auth code is generated
by the author and sent to the browser
now this is where things get tricky
because the browser needs to convey the
auth code to the native application and
it needs to figure out which application
should I send this earth code to for
that we have something known as custom
URL scheme so every application can
register a custom URL scheme on the
operating system which is nothing but a
callback handling mechanism so the
browser when it gets a URL starting with
XCOM my caught my app it will know that
this is the particular application that
I need to convey the code to so every
application can register for certain
custom URL schemes let's see how that
happens so in the manifest file on
Android operating system you can declare
a scheme with XCOM my coop app and
whenever the browser sees any traffic
coming in for this particular scheme it
will redirect it to the native
application that registered for it so
once the native application gets the
authorization code it can then hit the
token endpoint and get back the bearer
token in response that's the auth code
there in the request and the client ID
grant type of the application and
finally once the native application gets
access to the access token it can hit
the endpoints ready the resource
endpoints with the token embedded in the
authorization header
so we've talked a lot of theoretical
stuff already and time for some action
so we will talk about some attacks and
how they can be mitigated we'll start
with the authorization code intercept
attack and this specific attack is on
mobile applications and the precondition
for this attack is that the client
secret shouldn't be provision and since
it's a mobile application we already
know that client secret is not even
provision for mobile apps or is useless
it can easily be figured out that's one
precondition the other one is that the
attacker should be able to install a
malicious application on the mobile
device of the end user so here on the
left-hand side on the end-users device
you have a legit app and then you have
the malicious application the third
assumption is and it's also possible
very possible because the malicious
application can register for the same
custom URL scheme as that of the
legitimate application and there's no
nothing hindering that so you see where
this is going now because when the
author authorization request is
generated and the auth code is sent back
to the browser the browser now knows
that there are two apps that have
registered with the same custom URL
scheme and it will redirect the auth
code to both of them and now the
malicious application can also exchange
this auth code for an access token and
get access to the users resources so how
do we mitigate this attack so there's
something you should not use custom URL
schemes at all
because there's no naming Authority and
multiple apps can register for the same
custom URL schemes instead you said you
should always use claimed HTTP scheme
you are every direction
now what's that so in with claimed HTTP
scheme the scheme remains HTTPS followed
by the fqn of the application now every
application when it registers for this
particular HTTP scheme it needs to prove
that it owns the fqdn so at any point of
time that
not be more than one application that
registers a particular STD and you are a
so basically the destination app is
guaranteed by the opposite operating
system to the auth server but still if
you are still using some legacy apps and
you have a lot of custom URL schemes
being used then what you can do is use
proof key for code exchange also known
as pixie and it adds on some elements to
the typical worth flow if you go through
the RFC you'll notice that there's a
code verifier that needs to be generated
by the client which is nothing but an
alpha numeric value pseudo-random
alphanumeric value and the hash of the
code verifier needs to be sent along the
authorization request along with the
hash method so T underscore M is the
hashing method and the code verified is
the hashed value of the code verify also
known as the code challenge so once this
value asked value reaches the server the
server stores it as the code challenge
value and in the response the
authorization code is sent back to the
client and as we already know using the
auth code intercept attack the malicious
client can also get the authorization
code but in the next request to the
token endpoint the auth server expects
the code verifies value from the client
and once the code verify reaches the
server it computes the hash again and
matches it with the previously stored
code challenge value if they are equal
only then the access token is returned
so the malicious client can never get to
know the code verifies value because it
has been generated by the client the
legitimate client and therefore even if
the malicious client gets the auth code
it cannot make this request successfully
and get the access token value because
it doesn't know the code could verify
value now this is known as pixie and I'm
going to demo a vulnerability I found on
Microsoft's identity provider
which was a faulty implementation of
pixie and I'll talk you through that so
if you notice here there are three end
points I'm hitting number one is the
login windows.net this is the fqdn of
the microsoft's identity provider and
you'll notice that there's a login end
point I'm hitting there is an authorized
end point I'm hitting and then there's a
token end point as we've already seen in
the what flow these are the endpoints
that are hit so if you notice in the
request you will observe that there is a
code challenge value which is the hashed
value of the code verifier being sent in
the authorized request and there's a
redirect URL which is nothing but my
mobile applications redirect URL in the
response since the end user is not yet
authenticated I get redirected to the
login end point and once I log in the
authorization code is generated and sent
back to the redirect URI that I
initially mentioned so this is the
authorization code and it is being sent
back to the redirect URI of my mobile
application and in the next request to
the token endpoint you will notice that
the code verifies value is being sent to
Microsoft's IDP along with the
authorization code to get back the
tokens refresh tokens identity tokens an
access token so I put it in the repeater
and as you can see in the response you
will get all the tokens now the problem
with Microsoft's identity provider was
that even if you remove the code
verifies value it was still responding
back with valid I tokens refresh tokens
that any tokens an access token and
since the authorization code is not one
News I could replay it as many times
without the code verifies value to get
back as many refresh tokens and I need
cloak ins as I want and therefore have
lifetime access to the end users
resources and you know and this
Microsoft's identity provider was being
used by all probably like multiple
mobile applications so you could if you
leaked one authorization code you get
lifetime access to the resources of that
end user because of the access to the
Refresh tokens if you read through the
RFC for both for native applications you
will notice that it mandates the use of
pixie for such mobile applications and
the auth service should always support
pixie so like it so it was a big goof up
by Microsoft and which brings us to the
second attack which is called the
cross-site request forgery and you must
have you might find it very similar to
login CSRF this attack happens on the
client redirect URI and the attack
results in the client to believe that it
is accessing the legitimate users
resources where in reality it is
accessing the attackers resources so
I've created a pictorial representation
of the attack to understand it better so
let's say the malicious or the attacker
publishes the malicious website and the
end user with this visits this website
attacker.com now the malicious website
needs to generate a force authorization
response and in the response it needs to
replace the code with the attackers auth
code the attacker can initiate an
authorization himself and replace the
code with the attackers orth code
instead of the legitimate end-users code
because he can't figure out the
end-users code but he can always replace
it with his own code and now what will
happen is that the client
we'll think that this is the legitimate
end-users earth code and try to redeem
it at the token end point on the auth
server and get back the access token
which belongs to the attacker now and
when it fetches the resource the
resource will actually be the attackers
resource and not the end users resource
so as a result the client thinks it is
accessing and uses resource but in
reality it is not its accessing the
attackers resource so how do you
mitigate this is simply by putting a
CSRF token in the state parameter which
goes in the auth request and this is
since the author request is generated by
the client it can never be known the
state parameter value can never be known
to the malicious website so the client
generates it and expects it back in the
auth response and in the author response
this is replayed as it is so reflected
as it is so the malicious website can
never get to know the state parameters
value and as a result if the state
parameter is missing here the client
will get to know that something is fishy
now this brings me to the most famous of
all I mean the widely the most widely
spread attacks that happened on earth
which is basically occurring because of
client side open redirects and as a
result of this attack generally you end
up losing or leaking your access tokens
and authorization codes so a few
assumptions that I'll make here to make
this attack more understandable because
it's a pretty complicated attack so
we'll be using the implicit grant but
this attack is also applicable to auth
code grant flows and in North quadrant
flow you will be leaking the auth code
instead of the access tokens but an
implicit grant you'll be leaking the
access token then I am assuming here
that the client has registered this
particular URL with the auth server
client some site example /cb question
mark star so there's a wildcard at the
end and this wild card will be misused
by the attacker and we'll see how
and the client supports open redirect at
this particular endpoint with the help
of a redirect to parameter so basically
if you hit this endpoint you will be
redirected to example comm so let's get
to the attack now so the attacker Oh
before that here's the client domain
client some site example which it has
registered with the auth server when the
server sits on server dot some site
example so the attacker publishes a
malicious web site evil dot example and
the victim visits that fqdn now once the
victim visits it the malicious web site
generates an authorization request which
contains the redirect URI and it is the
clients genuine redirect URI followed by
the redirect to parameter with the
attackers domain in it client evil
example so if you decode this URL you
will get client some side examples /cb
question mark redirect to client evil
example and once this request reaches
the earth server the server matches it
with the pattern that was registered and
the pattern was exactly same client side
example /cb question mark star and this
pattern matches this particular value so
the odd server approves of the
redirection and redirects the access
token back to the client and since the
client has an open redirect exposed it
will redirect this particular access
token back to client evil example so as
a URL fragment you will get the access
token and the attacker can easily
extract that value so the only
mitigation is to not expose open
redirect at all because you lose your
access token the Northcote anyway so
please don't do that
that's a point you should always note
so next one is fishing using users trust
in the auth server and there are a few
steps that the attacker needs to take he
just needs to register a client he just
needs to register a domain which the
attacker controls with the odd server
and then he misuses the trust that the
class that the end user has in the
authorization server so the author could
be Google or Facebook and once the
attacker registers a particular redirect
you arrive with Facebook or Google he
can just create this URL
starting with authorization servers
domain followed by the redirect URI of
the attacker domain and when the victim
clicks on it it'll be redirected to the
attackers domain where the attacker can
create a phishing page and extract
whatever details at once so it's the
responsibility of the authorization
servers to inform the end user that it
is going to redirect to a third party
application which is this particular
domain and not always will you see that
happening also generally don't care
about it so easily the phishing attacks
can happen because of the trust that the
end user has in the odd servers now this
one is interesting attack and try to
stay with me here because it gets a
little complicated again so this happens
when the client application has
registered with multiple authorization
servers like Facebook Google etcetera
and one of the auth server turns
malicious and the intent of the
malicious auth server is to get access
tokens which are generated by the other
legitimate auth servers which are not
malicious and the Poli precondition here
is that the client has registered for
the same redirect URI for all its hot
servers so even for Google it has the
same redirect URI even for Facebook it
has the same redirect URI and that's
what causes the attack
so I have various entities listed here
will be assuming that the end user is
trying to access resources from the same
odd server so I have Facebook and
Facebook's resources Google and Google's
resources here and the end user has
resources on both both the auth servers
and the client has registered with
Google and Mozilla Facebook so once the
user let's say chooses Facebook as its
earth server LinkedIn will initiate a
North request to Facebook's ad server
and Facebook is malicious so what it
does is that once the request reaches
Facebook it will instead of showing the
prompt to the user itself it will
redirect to Google's authorization page
and Google will show you the
authorization so if the end user is not
attentive enough to see that the
authorization problem is coming in from
Google instead of Facebook what happen
is that after approval the auth code
will be generated by Google's ad server
and sent back to LinkedIn and LinkedIn
will know is that the authorization was
started with Facebook so it will try to
redeem the auth code that Google
generated at Facebook's end point and
Facebook will then redirect that or
token to Google's endpoint and the token
that they generated will be sent to
LinkedIn and LinkedIn because it knows
that Facebook is the one that we started
the authenticate or syndication
authorization flow with it will again
try to redeem the token at Facebook's
end point Facebook's resource endpoint
so now Facebook has got the token access
token that was generated by Google and
it can easily then access Google's
resources on behalf of that user so
that's how the mix of attack happens and
there's a simple fix to it you should
never use the same redirect urs for
different auth servers you should always
have different redirect URLs on the
client expose for different auth servers
and to show you how this works how this
fix works
the initial authorization request is to
Facebook and once the auth code is
returned to the clients redirect URI
because it's Google redirecting so it'll
be Google's redirect URI which will get
the auth code so the client will
immediately notice that there's a
discrepancy the initial auth flow was
started with Facebook and the redirect
URI is of Google and because of this
discrepancy the client will not then
redeem the auth code at at Facebook so
just to summarize what is used for
delegating resource access to a third
party application and access tokens
prove authorization and identity tokens
prove authentication for web apps stick
to authorization code grants and for
mobile applications you could use auth
quadrant flow with pixee and then we
also talked about how what works on
native applications and of course a few
bunch of attacks and the mitigations and
if you want to get started with OAuth
and OpenID connect there are a bunch of
references these are good starting
points and of course I'm there so if you
have some questions then you can get
back to me as well and okay so here are
my contact details just in case you want
to drop me a message and if you have
some we can have some good interesting
discussions so thank you so much that
was it thank you for paying attention
[Applause]
so we got three minutes for our
questions maybe you can we can we can
get more in case so do you have any
question for some it so I just one just
one one questions with apparently or
what is pretty complex to implement do
you know is there
Anthony work in terms of a formal
verification of that protocol and what
were the output of it that was for you
okay so personally I have only seen gone
through the RFC's so if you're talking
about like probably mathematical
formulations that have that verify the
protocol itself I doubt that exist but
there is a RFC committee obviously that
sits and goes dude and threat models the
entire protocol flow so that has been
done throughout a long period of time
and there are various RFC pages which
talks about what are recommended what
are the recommendations and what are the
best practices that you should always
stick to so as a pen tester you should
always be looking up for it but yeah
okay so no question so thank you so much
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
from your failures are they generally
communication or in HTTP so how do you
see the token exchange or data exchange
between the client and the server so
you're asking me that the exchange is
happening over TLS how do you see the
data or the traffic right is that your
question my question is that generally
your communication between the client
and the server are in HTTP yeah so it's
encrypted yeah so it may not be possible
to to get the token order to cook right
yeah so if you're talking about mobile
clients then you can still intercept the
traffic between the client and the
server because mobile client is
executing on the end-users mobile device
you can easily place a proxy in between
and in start intercepting because you
can install the certificates and start
decrypting the traffic so you'll have to
install the proxy is certificate on the
web you'll have to install the proxy
certificate on the mobile device so that
you start decrypting the traffic so
that's possible but if you are trying to
intercept the traffic between a web
application client and the auth server
that is that is not feasible because
it's a server to server call and the
attacker can't intercept that okay thank
you senator