okay so my name is Eric and I have five
minutes to tell you about a pitiful
story which is more or less a kind of
sad fickle drama in four acts so let's
start with act number one so everything
started on October 12 because we add
miss with my friends the first wave of
ticketing so this this day was the most
important one we wanted to get to the
tickets to grey acts so we were already
on time everything was prepared in text
editors to fasten the copy/paste
operations who have synchronizes in
whatsapp everything was cool even the
refresh because if you refer to mush
maybe you can be blamed by the seller so
we didn't know but everything was okay
and at 1000 refresh so on my side
nothing changed so mmm-hmm
panic so maybe it's a JavaScript bird so
I started another browser no UI change
so how can I buy a seat so in post
brothers doing refreshes and nothing
changed so it was really a kind of panic
and being on the phone my friend said we
have with tickets and so on my site I
did last reversion it was finished so I
can I cannot make the wiki now but it
was it was horrible yes I was a little
bit upset so thank you for the wiki so
blame or not blame so I chose to be
cooler of course because I was not the
only one so but there was a bit upset so
act to Monday back to work so with my
friends so of course the friends have
bitter drugs and they said there are
your pros are not talking and so on but
the friends are also cool because they
are looking at the site and I didn't and
you could steal by a benefactor of
tickets from the site it was still
available and the guy said oh hey you
can choose the price you play and you
can control the price you type and it's
only a JavaScript with mean you got no
seriously so in that case you have just
one refreshed to start of course Firebug
and so I was very curious because you
could have some kind of a biscuit in
JavaScript or things like that so let's
go so if you don't know how to use
forever you click the magic arrow you
click to the to the widget then if you
look at something coffee and in the
source no seeing so you try again as a
upper-level component once twice on the
third try I found something super
interesting so I said no Trudy is not
possible so edit the value and set the
price that I should have paid on
Saturday and so I said cannot work is
not possible so I click because I'm
curious so it seemed to work so yes yes
yes so so are you sure so because it's a
little bit illegal you know so so the
balance is that on one side you have
with this event which is not the victim
because I'm using abusing the system but
the real victim is good a great team and
it's the security conference so I said
ok maybe I could negotiate so so as I'm
ridiculous I try to click on by and of
course he didn't work also it works of
course and so I was a benefactor
[Applause]
[Music]
but Austin we have a problem because due
to the ticket number maybe I was the
first one so it means that the team
would be curious about how much I paid
to the cause because you could choose
the price but I didn't choose the good
one so will I be caught or not act 3 I
know before I Street just in case more
you know that already so x3 so of course
so I received an arrow it was a yes it
was 22 p.m. so it was a moment it so I
have led the velvety Mia
so for non French people I will
translate so I'm not going to die today
so the price was very little people had
fun with that the mayor also suggested
that I had to make a responsible
disclosure to the people from with event
because they are a little bit problems
on the outside and there was a fun
punishment number one you should present
a ramp
okay so and and of course you should
present the exploit so now that you know
the exploit so maybe I would run geek at
as yes as a fact here my levers minus
one and the scale of famous scale of
safety so thanks master so this is
clearly not affecting a level eight and
of course on the more under Moreau
I sent a maid in the morning to receive
aunt and say I tried to explain not
explain the problem but said there is a
problem and so fortunately it was
already fixed but at night at night so
very late because I was it's curious
about what would be the reason the
response so once again for non French
people are we're not going to join today
and there was a second punishment so you
have to make an advertisement that we
have eight eight position open and
outside and I think that the in this
kind of conference people will be very
very happy to to contribute so else okay
so at number four today
so guess what I have to make an
advertisement for eight positions so I
invite you to click because it's super
interesting on the side I will not tell
you what you will guess if you look at
the positions and that's it ok
[Applause]