hi so I'm going to speak about VBA today
let's get one thing first out before we
start VBA means Visual Basic for
applications and I'm actually talking
about office macros so why office macros
in 2019 first I would present I will do
some shameless shameless self
presentation then we're going to have an
introduction into my office macros are
still a subject now we don't look at a
motet a malware that is using macros and
obfuscation techniques that are used in
macros to hide what they're doing and we
don't look at it in and play an
implementation of security framework
that we developed to run macros and see
what they're doing and finally I'm going
to have some reference for references
for you and I'm going to accept your
questions ok so first of all Who am I I
have done my PhD degree in the South of
France in Eureka and I've worked on
embedded systems vectoring hard drive
and testing firmware now I'm in taro
since at Cisco and I'm much more on the
malware side on PC and we're doing
detection analysis and defense okay so
why analyze VBA macros they should have
been dead long ago probably well there
are a couple of things why they're not
dead so first of all to clarify what
we're speaking about here we're speaking
about Visual Basic for applications
there's also another type of macros
which are extra 24.0 macros from 1992
those ones are also used in malware and
they're pretty interesting but there are
out of scope for this work
and the problem or the why we still have
macros around is because there are many
legitimate uses for it in a company
people want to express custom formula or
they want to connect to a database fetch
fetch data into the excel sheet and then
manipulate it there and this is actually
wanted and I think this ambiguity
between not having macros because they
can contain malicious code and the
legitimate use is carried in this small
yellow bar that Microsoft is showing
when you open a document with macros it
tells you do you really want to run them
because normally you don't want to run
macros that come from the internet but
if you click yes then you still have the
ability to run macros and malicious code
might use hooks to automatically execute
itself just when you open the document
when you click a cell and so on and yeah
so now I've answered why macros are
still around but why are they used by
malware way are there threat so imitate
is escort that is has been around since
2014 I think initially it was a banking
Trojan and then it evolved to our
delivery platform and one way in motor
disinfecting machines is via office
macros so we could go and we could just
dump the code that is behind the
document to extract the macros and see
what they're doing there are tools for
that there is Philip laga decks or levy
ba and the Viper monkey only VBA is a
tool to just statically look at the code
and try to extract things that are
suspicious viper monkey goes a step
further and parses code snippets and
then translates them into Python and
execute them in Python
to see if if they have malicious
behavior the
is that the Viper monkey is an
approximate tool and thus fails if the
code is heavily obfuscated and all EVB a
as it is a static tool if the code is
obfuscated cannot do anything the
problem is that we could also do dynamic
analysis dynamic analysis currently
means that we load the document into a
virtual machine start office on this
virtual machine run the document in
office and then collect all the
observables inside this virtual machine
that happened during the execution there
are several disadvantages first of all
we need to spin up an instance of VMware
or whatever and run over to a machine
which is expensive we don't really know
when the execution is terminated because
we don't know when the macro code has
finished executing because we don't have
visibility into office and then we get
tons of observables that are pretty
noisy we have the operating system
artifacts we have the artifacts from
from office and we have somewhere inside
the artifacts from running our code but
then you need to extract them so the
idea we had was to interpret the macro
code ourselves no ok but before we go
into interpreting the macro let's look
at how a typical a motet infection looks
like to get a feeling of what we are
faced with
so typically everything will start with
an email like the one you see here the
emote head is pretty good in social
engineering in that when it infects a
machine it extracts hundred 888 days of
emails and it will contact the persons
that the emails were written to and just
reply to the existing email thread so
you get an email from a person that you
know you get an email thread where you
have sent messages yourself in that you
recognize and this makes that the email
thread is quite believable
and that you will probably open the
document that is now being attached by a
motet okay so the next step is you
clicked on the attachment word is
opening and you have this yellow bar
here where it says enable content and of
course there is a nice message in the
document saying yeah this document
cannot open you need to click this bar
otherwise you will not see what is to be
seen so you will click the bar and then
the VBA code starts executing the
easiest way for all the way in what that
uses is it just uses an auto open
function which is executed when the
document opens and then this is a bit
tricky with micro so then what the code
will do is it will get an instance of
win32 process windows management
interface class and with this instance
it can open a process and as an
additional goodie it hides the window
window of this process so that you don't
see that the process started in the
background ok then we create a process
that is powered power shell with
something encoded and base64 blob and
that's it so the power shell code is
actually being executed you can see here
you have a couple of sorry you have a
couple of URLs here and the code is just
cycling through the URLs trying to
download an executable from the URL if
the executable is downloaded
successfully it's invoked and we're done
and then you install the actual
executable which will then go on and
download later stages it will steal your
credentials it will exfiltrate the 180
days of mails to attack
your contacts it will spread laterally
in the neck network for example the
eternal blue or some other
vulnerabilities and since since 2015 I
think a motet is also delivering other
payloads so it's not the in the most
malicious payload itself anymore but it
will for example deliver trick pot or
ransomware all stuff and at this point
we're pond so of course the code that I
showed you there was very legible the
code that we get delivered in the
document is not the same so let's look
at the opposition techniques that Emmet
had uses to hide its code first one is
that code so typically there there is
huge amount of code but only very few
lines will do what a Matata wants to do
and one trick it uses is that variables
in VBA are by default fails so if you
reference any variable that hasn't been
initialized it will evaluate to fails
which is handy here in this wild
condition where just some two variables
that haven't been initialized I used the
whole expression evaluates to fails the
code block is not executed and this just
confuses tools that are not able to
understand this logic so yeah that code
is not doing anything plus there are
line break there's the line continuation
character this is used excessively this
is also just to confuse tools because
you need to interpret this whole thing
as it was on one line it's like the
backslash character in C okay
another technique is constant operate
for example we can take a string and we
can make two strings that are being
concatenated or we can use dummy content
that we insert inside the string and
then we just use a replace function to
remove the dummy content from the string
or we can use a a lot of useless
typecasting like you see here with the C
bar that actually it doesn't change
anything
and will confuse tools another technique
that I have seen in new document'
documents from the imitate infections
that started in September is this one
here Visual Basic is pretty special in
the way it can do error handling when
you have a function or a procedure you
can say at the beginning on error resume
next or on error resume and the label
and it will go to the error handler you
specified so if you say on error resume
next it means if a statement fails then
just execute the next statement that
follows the current one you can imagine
this a bit like having a try/catch
around every instruction and if you have
in a statement like here and you cast
something to an end that is clearly not
an int it would result in an error and
the instruction will be skipped so just
like it wasn't there and this is all so
confusing analysis tools okay another
thing that is pretty annoying is the way
a motet stores its actual content the
powershell part that is then being
executed so you have the main office
macro code that is stored inside an OE
object inside the document if the
document is
office 97 to 2003 document then it
itself is an oily document and all the
VBA projects and so on will be stored
inside that if it is a later generation
then the document is a zip file and
inside the zip file is an e document
that contains the vbe VBA project okay
and inside this same old
efile we also have a couple of
serialized form elements those can be
used to create forms like you can put
text boxes comment buttons and so on and
there is a specification from Microsoft
that is open on how to parse this
content and if we access the additional
streams inside the Olli file where this
content is stored we can parse the form
elements and emote head stores parts of
its contents in the for example in the
caption of a tear of a comment button or
in the text attribute of a text box I
haven't seen any tools that decode these
streams and in in the one we implemented
we're decoding this but we're just
looking for the part that contains the
emote head strings and there is also
some obfuscation of the PowerShell code
there are first of all PowerShell uses
backticks instead of backslash
characters to to signify escape
characters so if you have a backslash n
this is a new line but just inside a
string if the backtick end is outside of
a string then it is regarded as a line
continuation character just like the
underscore I showed you before or like
the backslash in C and if the backtick
is not at the end of a line it is just
ignored so the code here actually you
can just remove the backticks and you
have the valid code then
location technique is it's not really an
operation technique it's just a format
confusion when you pass base64 blob to
PowerShell it will automatically figure
out the encoding so if you pass
something that is utf-16 encoded like
here then it will automatically
understand it is utf-16 and will
correctly decode it and that's a bit
annoying because we need to do the same
thing if we get the content and finally
the same as in vba you have constant
operations and case insensitivity so
that this expression here which is one
string gets split into an array of
several strings and you need to handle
this correctly okay so those were the
problems that we have now let's find a
solution yeah so my first thought was
let's do it simple we just go into
instrument MSV BM v b vm v l-l which is
the dll that contains the Visual Basic
virtual machine and I found this
function it looks like this function is
just taking an opcode and doing
everything so I decided okay we're not
going to use MSV BM v b BM & dll also
the problem is that the integration
between Visual Basic and office is quite
tight so my initial thought was that
maybe I can just take the dll I invoke
one function in the DLL I get my code
executed and I do this in a small
sandbox environment so that I can see
what's happening but since the
integration with office is very tight
it's not easy to just call a function in
this DLL so different approach so this
is where we went ahead and said okay
let's try to interpret the code
ourselves and we looked for existing
interpreters that are around there for
Visual Basic for applications and there
is actually
in libreoffice which is called star
basic it is quite old the Parsis
handwritten it works but it is the the
star basic is very tightly knit into
Libre Office so whenever you try to
access something when you try to tear
out the star basic code from LibreOffice
you will have a lot of dependencies that
you need to resolve and assuming you
know so I managed in the end to make the
code run standalone but then you still
have a lot of you know objects which is
the LibreOffice version of all objects
that are not present because they were
originally in Libre Office and I didn't
take them over because they have too
many dependencies so in the end I gave
up on trying to make this code work with
a patent rocker and look for something
else okay so the second attempt after a
while I found a repository in github
from guy named in choix I don't know
anything more about him I I just mailed
him to tell him that I want to use the
code and he told me it's fine but be
very careful with the code it was never
meant for to be used so why this code
what's the advantage of this code over
the other one first of all it uses
antler which is a passage generator and
I don't trust myself to write a puzzling
so I would rather have a parser
generator that does that for me
and fortunately the grammar that was
inside this project this comes from
robotics which is a plug-in for
analyzing VBA in a graphical interface
and also the specification is open and
microsoft itself has provided an
antelope grammar for alongside the
specification so that's pretty cool
the project is written in Java again I
don't trust myself to handle handled
memory objects correctly and to handle
the two always check the sizes so I
prefer Java oversee simply for this and
the project has a pretty cool interface
to invoke Java methods from VBA but the
the problem with this code was that the
guy tried to make everything compile so
VBA is pretty dynamic in its nature a
bit like Python so you can invoke you
can evaluate code at runtime and you
have a lot of objects that don't have a
type that are known at compile time and
for these objects it is hard to try to
compile it statically so I had to amend
the project in this respect so this
yielded our implementation where we
start with the document with mouth
closed we have a parser that is
generated by our parser generator from
unplug Rama we get an abstract syntax
tree that is actually never exposed
explicitly but is directly compiled to
opcodes then we have an opcode
representation of the program this is
pretty similar to what LibreOffice is
doing we're running this on our
interpreter and finally we get a couple
of observables in our report so yeah our
implementation is a hybrid between
libreoffice and this VBA interpreter
project the parser is a lot slower than
the libreoffice parser because it's
nothing beats a handwritten parcel but
hopefully it is also a bit more adherent
to the specification and
more secure yeah and the opcode
representation as I said is inspired by
LibreOffice and the advantage of this
implementation is that since everything
is a result at runtime it is pretty easy
to handle dynamic types and it is also
pretty easy to handle objects where you
don't know what a motet expects them to
be so if you want you can do something
like slightly like a slide phaser where
you give a motet an object that is not
initialized and when it invokes a method
on this object then you generate warning
in the log from that our interpreter is
a stack based interpreter the
instructions are expressed as opcodes
values are stored on a stack and a
nested structure of dictionaries are our
context our our scopes where our
variables are stored there are lots of
intricacies that need to be handled I
showed before the on error zoom next
instruction so we need to handle this
correctly in the interpreter and we need
to make sure that if an instruction is
aborted during execution that we clear
up all the artifacts that were generated
during the execution and the function
return values are a bit tricky in VBA
so the way VBA denotes a return value
from a function is that you just assign
something to the function name itself so
it's like there is a secret variable
that is initialized in the beginning to
empty and then you assign to the to
itself and then when you return vba will
read the secret variable and put and
return this value unfortunately if you
implement it exactly this way and you
have a variable for that it means that
this variable will then shadow the
function name itself so when you try to
recursively call the function after you
have set a return value then
my implementation will find the return
value instead of the function name so
this requires also some special handling
and the argument notation in Visual
Basic is positively annoying if if you
have something that is just a name it
means it can either be a variable or it
can be a procedure that is invoked
without arguments so whenever you have a
variable you need to invoke the variable
just to get its value because it could
also be a procedure that you actually
need to invoke in execute code so yeah a
couple of things that are annoying okay
let's look at how the implementation
works if you're already familiar with
Java how the java virtual machine works
then this is nothing new for you I think
we just start with a very simple program
we want to execute a equals a plus B and
we first push a string a on the stack
then we have the find instruction that
fetches us the variable named a from our
dictionary of variables we do the same
for variable B that we push the string
on the stack we find the value of B in
our dictionary retrieve the value and
then we have an add instruction that
just pops the toups top values of our
stack execute the addition and puts the
return value back and finally the write
instruction not then we push again a for
the variable we want to write to and
finally the right instruction takes the
two top values and writes the value to a
so that's pretty simple
what we get out in the end is a report
like that so what we have done is we
have instrumented all the functions that
are doing something that is malicious we
have the process window height
instrumented
we have the process start event
instrumented and of course we don't
execute them in the system so this is an
advantage of our sandbox compared to if
you execute the VBA in in a VM inside
office that there you actually need to
give the document access to the Internet
if you want to see what it does or you
need to emulate an F network traffic
here we can just extract the events like
that and then we can go ahead and decode
the PowerShell blob with simple
heuristics and be done with it so how
does this fare compared to our previous
solution of spinning a BMS well I'm
pretty satisfied the just this prototype
that I currently have takes 1.2 seconds
for a document the whole just from the
execution from the command line
startup till finish and memory usage is
around 300 megabytes and country well be
m/s are also easy to paralyze but here
you just spin up several processes on
the same machine they don't influence
each other and you can you can have a
couple of hundred processes on the same
machine if your memory does does allow
you that so the performance for just the
prototype is pretty ok of course that's
not everything there are some
shortcomings so one thing I didn't
mention in the beginning is that office
documents carry several versions of
macro code inside there is the source
code that is textual but there is also a
semi compiled version that is called P
code and sometimes there is binary code
about this part I'm not a hundred
percent sure when it carries binary code
or not if we have some time I will go
deeper into the P code but for the
moment let's keep that
the code is currently in a very hockey
state
I plan to clean it up and to have it in
better shape but that takes some work
and lots of stuff is not implemented so
currently I only looked at the runtime
functions I need it is pretty easy to
add new runtime functions a lot of them
are currently just commented but this is
what it needs to be done and yeah there
is still some small things like current
and correct handling of recursive
functions the project future is that I
hope that we can put this as an internal
service at first where we will allow
people who have who are doing
investigations to submit documents and
also I would like to hook our sample
stream we have inside Cisco we have mail
gateway and we get documents from the
mail gateway so we we have a couple of
thousand documents per day out for a
motet alone that arrived and I would
like to plug those documents inside the
emulator and get the results from it so
that we can directly take them the URLs
extracted from these documents and and
get the binaries marked MSE motet and
carry carried the good detection that we
have through the system and currently
the interpreter is optimized for a motet
I would like to also see that it handles
right X and other natural malware well
I've provided you with a couple of
references there are articles about
imitate there is the original repository
that I used the libreoffice repository
pico dump is a utility that is very cool
to dump the peacoat representation
inside the document viper monkey and oli
tools are the tools from Phillip backlog
addict
and not now but on Monday you should be
able to download the code of this
project here I will also provide the
slides so as soon as the slides are
online you should have the URL okay
let's go and have a look at the tool
running so first of all I want to show
you the output of all e tools and Viper
monkey so that you have an idea of what
is tools currently do ok so this is the
source code as its extracted from all
eTools you have something that you see
that is missing here is the class class
module which is not correctly well it
doesn't have any code attached it only
has variable assignments attached but
these variable assignments are not
exposed by only tools you have the code
that is being extracted and in the very
end you have a list of observables that
all it will extract from the document a
lot of them are very useful like this
here says it has an auto open function
and it recognizes a couple of suspicious
functions but the problem is that now
the emote head authors know that people
are analyzing with these tools and they
also embed a lot of fails observables so
you have a ton of IP addresses here that
I'd try to figure out just with the
Whois if they target specific people
with that but it doesn't look like that
ok then
hey then we have Viper monkey
so Viper monkey is just looking for
certain expressions parsing those
expressions and executing those
expressions it also works fairly well
but you will see that it will also
exhibit some fails positives and in
addition it is not super fast its Python
and the already the parser generator and
Python is pretty slow so you see it also
found the auto open it found a couple of
interesting functions like the caption
and the win32 process but it doesn't
show you the command line that is being
executed okay so let's get to our tool
so this is a presentation of the source
code that is being dumped by our tool
what was missing before is the project
description and this section here which
is the class module which contains all
the objects that are serialized and
finally you also have in the end in the
end you have the serialized object
contents so this is where the actual
imitate PowerShell code is that is then
being used and
this is what the tool execution looks
like so you see it's quite fast it dumps
you the whole block of of code here and
now you can go on and analyze what is
inside you can get the URLs and you can
handle what's going on so this brings me
to the end and in the end are your
questions
thank you so much we have time for
questions so if you have any question
yes thank you for your talk you said
that your tool was specific quite
specific for ma tête
in what way and what would you need to
add to be able to analyze other tools
other malware so right but specific to
imitators because I used emotive
documents to go along in the development
and to see what's needed
what is mainly needed for other
documents is library functions and yeah
so library functions plus looking at the
library functions what you should not do
on your system so for example if it
writes code to a file you need to neuter
this and you need to just write it in a
temporary path whether you can analyze
it then of course at some point the
malware authors will come and they will
write a file just to test if they're in
the emulated environment but this is
something that I will see then also if
if this appears very soon in e motet I
know that they're following this
presentation which is interesting
another common question yes
still about the topic of response of
malware authors how hard would it be for
them doing that such tools are being
used to hide interesting behaviors this
is the same question as for any sandbox
it boils down to a cat-and-mouse game so
at some point they will implement
defenses against the sandbox and then we
will implement defenses against their
defenses so
it so first of all it depends on if they
see us as a valid threat and once they
do then we play with them what's our
question comments we still have time yes
MA
same one in case you might want to adapt
your tools for other mod well how would
you ensure that custom-made interpreter
will implement the exact same and
behavior as the original VBA
implementation including all the corner
cases even the undocumented ones so the
the easy way how at the moment this is
the development stage but my next step
will be that I hook up the interpreter
to the sample path I will execute the
interpreter I will see what observables
I cannot extract and then I can run the
same sample in our sandbox with office
where we get all the observables and
then I can actually cross correlate and
see if I find observables that I find in
my report there and if I find observers
that have been deemed malicious from
there also in my report and then I can
cross validate between the two and for
development I just go into office and at
dry concrete commands to see what they
do and sometimes they're surprising
corner cases for example the replace
function for replacing something in a
string in VBA behaves completely
differently than the Python function
it's instead of going character by
character through and then replacing it
replaces it goes through finds the first
occurrence of the string so it calls the
find function on the string finds an
occurrence then it replaces this
occurrence and then it calls the find
function again from offset zero and they
are actually using this to confuse
people why
are there winning new performances or
something with these tricks no because
okay so I was waiting for this no it
doesn't work
Electric okay this is already enough
thanks
okay so imagine you have a string that
is like this so you will go through
let's say our spring that we want to
replace is a B so we have C a BB abbc if
you go through the implementation of a
visual basic will first find this string
replace it with nothing and then you
have C ABC and then this will go
together so you have this and then it
will place this part and then C C
remains what Python will go through will
at this point replace but then will go
on in the string so you will have C ABC
as a result so just subtly rensis which
one is correct it depends on your
specification no produce the same output
they are not comparable
no but it's well visual basic I think
the specification of Visual Basic is
visual basic so you cannot say that it's
wrong or right ok one other question
sorry the same question but that means
that if you want to replace say name
with some value X now X is actually
named you're just looping that's a good
case I will take what VBA does on this
case yes it's interesting but I think
they have an if to just yeah I think and
yeah in mine so what I did in my
implementation is I have an if in the
beginning to check if the expression
that you're replacing with is the same
as the one you're searching and
I'm just aborting I was a question yes
we go fast thanks for the talk
have you tried to use a MC Porsche and
when we Windows then it's a feature on
partial to block the user execution of
the code and the can can look to block
just just before the execution and you
can catch the first occasion change a
few traces or no identify this this
could be interesting okay yeah
understand you can you can do this okay
one more collaborator for you okay we
talked about the fact that it was hard
to know what was the real ideal behavior
of VBA but did you find some cases where
I don't know office 2003 would behave
differently than another another version
in which case you would be you will have
to handle different interpretations no I
didn't go this far so do you think that
might be the case that there might be
such corner cases so if you want to go
to the extra slide with the P code there
you actually have this corner case
because the P code is a compiled
representation and probably what it was
for is it just when you have your own
document your open it again then you
have a performance cache you already
have the compiled version but what they
do is they check the office version and
the fitness is 32 or 64-bit and if it's
the same then you will execute the P
code and this means you can actually
remove the source code just leave the P
code and if you have the correct office
version the P code will execute and if
you look at the source code reverse
representation it's empty
okay one more question thank you for the
call sorry for the presentation I was
wondering if regarding this did you find
any common code with other amine groups
like AP t-34 like other codes like bond
over for instance like you know there's
common sources because it seems to be
interesting the P code is something
interesting did you see this inside
Imhotep so at the moment I didn't look
at a huge amount of documents this is
the next part of the project to hook it
up to the general sample stream extract
all the VBA code and all the objects
that I have inside with the tool and
then build the database from that so
that we can do cross correlations one
last question
yes so in your talk you talked about
many malware fiends and today have you
ever stood it right legitimate of this
metros possible use of in front
abilities or some limited use cases does
this work all right
does your tool what's fine with them so
I have downloaded a couple of hundred
documents from virustotal that have zero
detections and I'm using those as the
test case for a good way Thank You IRA
first was a question and thanks again
Jonas was a good presentation