hey everyone
my name is kevin from the university of
maryland i just wanted to thank all of
the focai organizers for making this
event possible
despite everything going on now today
i'm going to be talking about a new form
of censorship we discovered recently in
iran
now iran has already had a highly
sophisticated censorship system
we have a user in iran trying to make a
forbidden request
the sensor has already had the capacity
to censor multiple different protocols
dns http https it can do so with deep
packet inspection for keywords host
names etc
it can inject dummy responses or black
hole traffic and it applies basically to
all destinations leaving iran
now outside the scope of this paper in
the past we had developed a tool called
geneva that automatically discovers ways
to evade network censorship
and while running experiments in
february this past year we noticed
something strange
we noticed that evasion strategies that
had worked not one to two weeks prior
no longer worked we started seeing
strange behavior coming from the sensor
so specifically instead of getting
censored after we sent keywords
we started noticing censorship happening
before we had even sent keywords
instead of getting dummy responses from
the sensor we just started seeing a lot
of packet drops
and really confusing this instead of
this happening to all of our vantage
points with uniformity
we're only seeing this happen to some
destinations
after looking into this more in running
experiments what we determined is that
iran has actually deployed a second
censorship system
which is used in conjunction with the
standard censorship and we've been
calling this a protocol filter
now at a high level the protocol filter
matches connections it sees leaving iran
to protocol fingerprints
and any connections that it does not
recognize it just drops
now this only applies to some
destinations and altogether this
this creates censorship in depth in iran
now in this talk i'm going to discuss
how the protocol filter works
how it fingerprints connections how it
sensors connections
just other mechanics of how it works
under the hood in the second half i'm
going to discuss ways that it can be
defeated
and specifically packet manipulation
strategies we discovered
that work from either the client or the
server side using our tool genita
so first let's talk about how the
protocol filter
fingerprints connections the protocol
filter performs deep packet inspection
on packets leaving iran
the filter only monitors tcp udp packets
they're not monitored by the filter
the filter only allows three protocols
dns
hdp and htgps and the filter is only
active on ports 53
80 and 443 these are the ports commonly
associated with these protocols
what this means is that you can use any
other protocol you wish on other ports
these are the only ports
that as of today as the time of this
presentation the protocol
filter is monitoring now i'll note that
the protocol filter does not actually
associate each of these protocols to its
corresponding ports
you can use any of these protocols on
any of these ports
but no other protocols besides these
three can be used and these can be used
in these ports
so let's look more at these fingerprints
and what these look like
in the paper we actually reverse
engineer the precise fingerprint that
the protocol filter matches for each of
these protocols
i unfortunately don't have time to
discuss all of them today
so let's just look at dns so the dns
fingerprint has five requirements
for packets for in order for it to match
the fingerprint
the first requirement is that the tcp
payload of the packet must be at least
12 bytes long after this there are some
qualifications about the structure of
dns itself
the query response field must be set to
zero the question count must be less
than 15
and the answer count must be zero and
finally just
generically it must have a valid dns
over udp header structure
and violating any of these requirements
effectively immediately results in
censorship from the protocol filter
now i'm going to talk a little bit more
about this last bullet now because it's
not a typo
you actually truly must have a valid dns
over udp header
but recall that the filter is only
actually active over tcp connections
so it only will ever see dns over tcp
packets
now the problem with this is that the
structure of dns actually
changes when it's used over tcp and the
way it does that is there's an addition
of a length field at the front of the
header
as a consequence normal dns over tcp
packets
actually violate the fingerprint for dns
the iranian dns fingerprinter is
incapable of matching
valid dns over tcp packets
now this seems crazy and the reason this
hasn't actually caused a significant
issue in iran
is specific to how the protocol filters
sensors connections and i'll talk about
that more in a minute
this is just one example of issues we
discovered in the protocol fingerprints
how we discovered some issue with
basically all of them
and the details for each of these are in
the paper so now that we've established
how it fingerprints
the next question is how does it sensor
so the filter drops all packets from the
client
here we have the client about to make a
request over a forbidden protocol
over a monitored port the protocol
filter monitors this request
and it will recognize that it's not
allowed but it does not drop it yet
does deepak inspection sees that it's
not okay but it doesn't drop it the
packet actually gets through
what it does is it drops all packets
from the client after
the first non-matching packet so the
second packet after it's been triggered
data carrying if it does not match
it will now get dropped and we believe
this is the case
so the filter could be more tolerant to
packet reordering it allows either of
the first two packets it sees
to match the fingerprint this is
actually why dns over tcp
doesn't seem broken in iran right now
because there's typically no second
data carrying packet from the client the
filter is not
bi-directional unlike iran's regular
censorship system
so the response from the server is
unaffected
it only monitors packets leaving iran
and only affects packets leaving iran
what this means is even after the
protocol filter has been triggered
the server is still free to send packets
to the client
basically unimpeded the client will just
be unable to
acknowledge or send any data back to the
server
as a consequence of this this new
censorship system actually requires
vantage points inside of iran to study
this is a pretty significant limitation
to researchers you can't just you can no
longer probe it from outside the country
and see this behavior now there are more
details in the paper about the mechanics
of how the protocol filter works how we
discuss the full fingerprints each of
these connections
we perform some brief experiments of who
the protocol filters sensors since it
doesn't affect
all destinations equally we study how
many packets the sensor monitors we find
it just looks at the first two data
carrying packets
and how long it remembers an offending
flow it's about 60 seconds but that
timer resets with every packet in the
flow
so next i'm going to talk about how the
filter can be defeated
so in order to do this we applied a tool
we'd built in the past
geneva now geneva is a genetic algorithm
it discovers ways to manipulate packets
such that it defeats censorship
these are specifically ways either the
client or the sensor
can change its packet stream such that
the sensor is unable to censor the
connection without harming the original
connection itself
so geneva strategies apply just from one
side of the connection
if you want to learn more i encourage
you to check out our website i'll link
to it at the end
or the citation is in this is in the
slide
so we we wrote a fitness function for
geneva such that it could run against
and create new censorship evasion
strategies for the protocol filter
and i'm going to talk about those now so
the first one geneva discovered was
injecting an innocuous fingerprint
so here's again our client about to make
an outbound forbidden request geneva's
going to catch that packet
and we'll make two of them out of it and
to the first one what it does is it
sticks a load on there
to create a benign http request so get
requests for
example.com for example but specifically
it breaks the check sum of this packet
so when this gets sent the protocol
filter will see this and it will see
that it matches the fingerprint
so once we've got an approval for the
protocol filter it will green light the
rest of the flow
now because this is a broken checksum
when it gets to the server the server
simply drops the packet
now at this point the client is free to
communicate with its original protocol
the protocol filter already thinks
things are okay so it stopped checking
fingerprints and the server already
dropped
our the packet for this strategy now we
actually found three such strategies
that work from the client
um and i'll talk about each of these so
the first is this innocuous request
where you just send some innocuous
requests with the broken checksum after
the three-way handshake
this doesn't actually have to be http
this works with dns or https as well
the second strategy we found is a little
stranger a little it seems odd that it
works
but before the client does it's through
a handshake
it sends two thin packets and this is
sufficient to make the
protocol filter ignore the rest of the
connection now the last strategy we
found is likely
is the strangest in my opinion while the
client is completing the thruway
handshake
instead of sending one ack packet
instead it sends nine of them
and this alone is sufficient to make the
whitelister ignore the rest of the
connection
now we hypothesize this works because
there's some internal limit on the
number of packets the whitelister will
process
but all of these work with 100
reliability across all of our vantage
points
and next i'm going to talk about
server-side evasion so instead of
deploying geneva at the client
we instead deployed it at the server and
this allows us to subvert the protocol
filter from outside of iran without
requiring any client-side modifications
we actually found a strategy that works
for this so during the three-way
handshake what the server does is it
sends
nine synack packets with incorrect
acknowledgement numbers before sending
the original one
the effect this has on the client is it
induces the client
to send nine resets um these nine reset
is now enough
to push the connection push the the
number of packets the
white the protocol filter has to process
over the limit
and just like that the protocol filter
will ignore the rest of the connection
so in total here are the four strategies
you identified to defeat the white
lister
the particle filter and all these are in
our paper
so that's just about all the time i have
today for this talk i look forward to
discussing this
more with all of you at the conference
thank you
you