hello everyone
and welcome to our presentation of a new
privacy first system
designed to provide anonymity by
mimicking
your ip address nowadays
almost all communication over the
internet is encrypted
but ip addresses are still visible to
eavesdroppers
and may leak sensitive information an
adversary
might use this information to identify
clients
to build profiles or even censor content
fortunately there already exists some
solutions for
hiding your ip address network layer
anonymity systems
provide strong privacy guarantees but
they face some deployment challenges
some systems may require extension
extensive modifications to the internet
others like tor and spine require the
cooperation of multiple autonomous
systems
along the path another class of
solutions
like the address heading protocol are
coarse-grained
while they can continue the client's ip
address they work at the flow level
and are susceptible to traffic analysis
attacks
our goal is to design a system that can
provide ipv address mixing
that is both fine-grained and flexible
the properties we desire are to let
clients
change their ip address rapidly to
provide a sort of anonymity in the crowd
clients should also be able to change
their ip address anytime
without breaking their connection these
properties can be useful in a number of
scenarios
let's consider one censorship
circumvention
now suppose alice wanted to access a
censored website
sensor also blocks the tor entry node's
ip address
so alice decides to use torque pt which
behaves essentially like a proxy to the
entry node
unfortunately for ls the sensor can
still identify that alice is using tor
based on the first few packets of her
communication
and blocks packets from her ip address
now
if alice were to change her ip address
in the middle of communication
she can avoid the sensor and access the
censored website
but how will she change your ip address
at first glance this seems difficult
if not impossible if alice were using
tcp
the current cornerstone of the internet
she would break her ongoing connection
and have to re-establish it defeating
the purpose of changing her ip address
but if she were using quick the rising
star of the internet
this might be doable so what is quick
quick is a communication protocol
recently developed by google
it's still in development but it's
seeing increased adoption
over half of chrome traffic to google
servers is already in quick
http 3 which will come out in a few
years
will use quick quick offers a whole host
of new features
but the key feature mimik uses is its ip
address migration
quick allows a client to change the ip
address
without re-establishing the connection
but this alone is not enough there are a
few other problems we have to address
there's a problem of address collision
how can we ensure that different clients
do not use the same ip address
at the same time there's also the
problem of routing
how do we send traffic back to a client
that now has a different ip address
before we talk about these challenges
let's first discuss the threat model in
our threat model
we have a number of clients connected to
the trusted network
client run a mimic agent which can
configure the host's ip address
and talk to the network we also have a
passive adversary which may observe all
traffic between the trusted network and
the server
the adversary may also control some
clients on the trusted network
and view all data available to them
we also stipulate that the server may
not collude with the adversary
our privacy goals with the with this
system are to make discovering the
identity of the client more difficult
and to provide a stronger resilience
against traffic analysis attacks
to do this we provide a property called
client unlinkability
essentially an adversary should not be
able to link packets
to a particular client the key factor in
achieving this
once again is quick's handling of
encryption and its migration features
so let's talk about these challenges
some more the challenges of address
collision and bargaining
to start to solve these problems mimik
has three key features
there's a client agent which runs in the
client's machine and there is the
allocation server
which runs on the trusted network
together
these solve the problem of address
collisions there's also the edge switch
which sits at the edge of the trusted
network and connects to the wider
internet this switch solves the problem
of routing
so let's talk more about address
collisions one simple solution
might be to let clients generate their
own ip addresses
but to do this effectively might require
cryptographic operations
but this comes with a significant
computational overhead
furthermore adversaries might be able to
predict
which ip addresses will be generated if
they have access to certain clients
how mimik approaches this problem is to
have an agent
run on the client's host which talks to
the allocation server
and retrieves ip addresses it can modify
the client's ip address and trigger
connection migrations
we also have an address allocation
server that runs on the trusted network
most edge networks have address servers
such as dhcp servers so this is not
unusual at all
one important benefit of this setup is
that i require it requires no
cryptographic
operations furthermore it makes it
difficult for the adversary
to predict which ip addresses will be
used
we also randomly assign a lifetime to ip
addresses
a client starts using an ip address at
the end of its lifetime
and after a delay the ip address is
recycled
and assigned to a different client
perhaps even at the same time
the other challenge we face is the
routing challenge
to solve this we assign a switch
identifier to each client facing switch
each switch has a unique and fixed sid
which is embedded in the ip addresses
assigned to its clients
the allocation server also maintains a
routing table
of these sids in the edge switch this
allows us to drastically reduce the size
of the forwarding table
on the edge switch instead of
maintaining an a mapping
of each client's ip address the edge
switch only needs to keep track of these
sids
here's a quick example of our writing
system we have a mimic agent running on
the client
in the event of a connection migration
the agent sends an ipa request
to the allocation server the allocation
server generates a new ip address
and embeds the sid into this address
it sends the ip address back to the
mimic agent which changes the client's
ip address and triggers connection
migration
meanwhile the allocation server updates
the routing table
on the edge switch when the network
receives return
traffic all the edge switch must do is
get the sid from the packet and forward
the packet
to the corresponding switch the switch
then forwards the packet to the correct
client
let's now talk about quick's connection
migration
quix connection migration migration
process involves sending a relatively
small token
for path validation which does have some
overhead
but this token is encrypted and looks
indistinguishable from data
furthermore quick provides some measure
of unlinkability across connection
migrations
packets have connection ids but
endpoints are required to use a new
connection id after migration
furthermore the negotiation of these
connection ids is encrypted
so an adversary cannot tell which
connection id will be used after
migration
quick also requires that congestion
control be reset
in the event of a migration this is
important because an adversary cannot
use
the congestion control window to track a
client across migrations
but this might have an impact on
performance
to measure this we set up an experiment
with a single client and a single server
we use no allocation server because we
only wanted to test
the performance impact of migration
we had multiple bonds of the experiment
and in each run the client sent 1000
requests
to download the index.html file of
example.com
the thousand requests together added up
to about 2.7 megabytes
across these runs we change the number
of migrations
as well as the propagation delay in the
network
here's a summary of our results
on the x-axis you see the number of
migrations per hundred packets
and on the y-axis you see the throughput
measured in kbps
each curve represents a different
propagation delay and each point in the
graph
represents a throughput for that
particular frequency of migration
and that particular publication delay as
you'll notice
the performance penalty becomes less
severe as propagation delay increases
for example for a round trip time of 50
milliseconds
only ten percent penalty for a migration
frequency
of four essentially migrating every 25
packets
we believe that 50 milliseconds is a
realistic propagation delay
and migrating for every 25 packets
should be enough
to beat most attacks
we also built a prototype using a dhcp
off-the-shelf server for the address
allocation
with this prototype the client was able
to successfully communicate with the
server
and perform migration multiple times
without having to re-establish its
connection
in other words it worked
in the future we hope to implement a
prototype
that scales to the larger networks we
will also conduct
a thorough security analysis and
systematically evaluate the
effectiveness
of mimic against traffic analysis
attacks
in conclusion mimic uses quick
connection migration features
and some routing mobility to allow
clients to rapidly change their ip
address
while minimizing the performance
overhead and deployment barriers
thank you for listening and please reach
out to us if you have any follow-up
questions