hello everyone come on some love please
yeah so uh if you look at my last one
you might think I'm German actually not
originally from Paraguay and before
starting this I want to ask you if you
know what is the biggest the greatest
contribution of our wife you hacking
anybody you will never get so let me
just show you what it is it's actually
right here not this actually thank you
okay
so my talk is called cooking monstrum
hijacking a social lawyer I was
introduced I work at a pen tester and
but apart from doing that I also enjoy a
lot giving presentations to not the kind
of people that you are but people who
are not very aware of IT security I
enjoy that very much
um and more often than not I get asked
the following question when I'm doing
these type of presentations that is can
you have my facebook gmail Outlook
whatever I'm sure most of you can relate
with with these type of questions if you
tell them you're working in IT security
um so if I die and every time I get
asked this question that would be a very
very rich person so so one day I decided
you know what I'm going to try to figure
out how to do this because I was tired
of giving the same vague answers to
these people all the time so I sat down
I started saying okay how am I going to
approach this this issue and the first
thing you might think of it's probably
good for fishing some credit harvesting
maybe you saw kilo bearing your victims
machine maybe grab the password from the
browser storage browser storage of the
password manager if you know some
forensics you might find a memory dump
maybe just do plain all guessing right
so nowadays security in a web
applications get better and people are
being more aware of
the things that hackers are able to do
so more often than not you're gonna be
facing this little obstacle which is
called two-factor authentication so
since I had to deal with this when
giving the answers how I would approach
this hacking your web application
account and I didn't want to tell them
that okay let's just go for some social
engineering techniques to try to grab
your tooth back to talk now I need to
find something better something more
more simpler and effective so then it
came to me that how about cookies I'm
sure most of you are aware of what
cookies are I hope but for those of you
who are not don't know what they are and
also for those of you at home watching
so let me give you the cookies 101 to
the web browser authenticate show
website you stand your username password
and you send it to par toward education
token and then the worst of all evade
your authentication mechanism and will
set back a token cookie to the browser
just basically just a long random string
that with in essence become the password
that all the credentials are your
browser will use to the web application
for the duration of that session now
let's focus on the fact that the
authentication part happens here and
that includes the two-factor part of the
dedication and the cookie is only
generated after all of that has already
been validated so that gives you a hint
that if you somehow manage grab the
cookie from your victim then you most
likely will be able to bypass most 2,000
indications protections we use nowadays
so how do you do cookies doing so if you
want how to the cookie so then you
probably go to Google and do a search
how do I do cookies in it so the first
one or two pages which is pretty much
older exists because the third page in
Google um they will tell you something
that can be briefly summarized in this
list
have here let's read it an attacker can
use a variety of methods in order to do
facial implication cookies depending
upon the net worth at least song blah
blah so and the only mechanism
protection against this the real way the
only way to do it is to use encryption
HTTP so it was very surprising for me to
see that most literature on the web only
talked about cookie stealing as a
network base attack but what about the
jar so this obsession with network based
cookie stealing and such a hijacking
attacks means that people forgot somehow
that cookies not only live in on the
network on the traffic but they're also
store locally for each browser so here
you can see an example from my Google
that's a the cookies file which is
located somewhere in your user folder
and windows which is just patreon SQLite
database that contains all your cookies
and you will have the same example
Firefox again
SQLite file somewhere in your users
folder same the same principle so let's
take a closer a closer look so this is
the Firefox table of the database and
the most cookies that contains the
cookies information very straightforward
just have a table that has all the
cookies here with different properties
and the values of the cookies here so
that's great that means that if you
manage somehow to gain after the file
system of your victim then you can
easily steal the cookies because they're
just lying there um now let's go to
chrome now and we can see that they're
doing actually something more about
protecting these cookies so if you see
the value column here you will notice
that is used most of the time you'll
find it empty and if you take a look to
the right you will see there is an art
column called encrypted value so chrome
goes like I said that it a bit further
with with particular cookies and they
actually encrypted but at least for
Windows what they use is a key that is
associated with the windows profile the
user that
Kuki so that means that if you are able
to run code within the same context of
the user that it owns that cookie then
you are also able to decrypt that cookie
so the fact that this attack vector has
largely been ignored by most of the
elite defensive security people ah means
that at least up to my knowledge there
was not a good to develop to help you
are retrieving these values from the
file system so since I couldn't find a
tool then I just said well one just make
a tool so that's why I started the
European cookie module so what Cookie
Monster oh just a simple PowerShell post
exploitation script it means that you
have to compromise your victims machine
obviously why do we need this well to
help an attacker tester obviously
quickly down the local cookies storage
and I identify active sessions so the
tools should support different browsers
and at the moment is pouring Chrome and
Firefox on Windows of course should also
be able to target popular web
applications such as Facebook Gmail auto
feeder or the big ones and also should
be able to target customization tokens
which I'm still working on so let's just
have a brief demo time so you can see
how the the tool works so let's hope
this time it doesn't screw up so here we
just help um yeah so this is a Windows
machine that's been compromised ready
the file system is compromised so let's
log it into this Facebook application as
you can see two thousand litigation is
enabled
so if you want to remember the browser
limit this doesn't matter you can choose
either option here so as you can see we
have a valid session now with Facebook
and we're coming from this IP you can
see there one it starts with a 1 a 1 so
now let's go to my commanding control
machine which is located somewhere in
the cloud it's running Empire so now
view her Empire PowerShell framework
it's a really cool framework for using
PowerShell to hack computers so this
partial agent which is already running
on the infected machine is has already
the Cookie Monster script loaded and
what we're going to do is just run it
you might be a little hard to read but
it just says invoke you tomorrow we're
targeting specifically faced with in
this case and we want to make the output
of its portable so that we can use it
later to load it in our local machine so
this would be the output of the tool I
will just tell you the cookies that
you're interested in the ones are using
to handle session power of Facebook and
it will give you a nice crib that you
can run locally on your machine to
create a cookies file that you can later
load into your attacking browser so
let's see this in action which is going
to copy that little script from the
command and control server when I run
and locally in our machine so we created
this cookie file now I'm going to change
window a little bit in so I change the
IP done coming front so you can see that
the IP doesn't matter in this case so as
you can see I'm going from a complete
different IP which is looking in a
different country I'm going to load here
the cookies with this Firefox extension
for hanging cookies and just going to go
to Facebook as you can see the session
hijacking it's it's achieved despite the
fact that we're coming from a complete
different operating system as you can
see this magdhira most windows very
different browser Firefox as post Chrome
and I complain differently in different
countries yeah so that's pretty much it
very simple
so not everything is unicorns and
rainbows when it comes to cookie
stealing there is some other stuff that
is you consider as well so sometimes the
victim should stop to have an active
session today whatever applications
you're targeting so what can we do in
this case well if you have AK to the
file system and that computer is used by
the victim to to log in to that specific
website that you're interested in it's
very easy to just student wait wait
agree right so that's the what I have
implemented in the tool it's called
waiting steal just you check every n
amount of time until you see that the
cookie database contains the cookie that
you're interested in when that happens
the cookie that you've just seen is
retrieved
very simple very straightforward another
thing that could happen is that the user
the victim can invalidate the session
that you have stolen by logging out so
you can think when you retrieve the
cookie from the victim both the victim
and the attacker will be hand would be
in possession of the same cookie the
same two different sorry two copies of
the same cookie so what can we do in
this case well very simple we just use a
simple remove cookie which will
basically just delete the cookie from
the database of the user and as an
attacker you will be the only one
holding a copy of the cookie so this
actually has some serious implications
at least for the case of Facebook and
all the mainstream applications they do
some good session management they allow
you to end
sessions manually if you don't trust
those active sessions but you can think
of applications that you might develop
or that you might test if you're a
tester which don't have these session
management controls so if I steal a
cookie from you that it has an active
session to a web application that is
important to you and if you don't have
access that took anymore how do you kick
me out of your vision so that's
something to think about
so another reason why I focus so much in
these mainstream applications like
Facebook Google and the others is that
they are not only when the Health
Education days don't only
handle their own authentication but they
also provide simple social login so I'm
sure you're familiar with the issue
maybe use it how many of you use social
login to login with your Facebook and
Google accounts to other account
don't be something I do it I do it and I
and I wrote this so I wrote this
presentation anyways so here are some
examples now let let me give you a
little secret about social logins you
don't really need to know the username
and password of the of the the account
that you use your social login with in
order to hijack the session of the
application that relies on the on the
identity provider in order to hijack the
session so we have a look at this little
graph here that explains a little bit
how the flow typically looks in these
implementations of social logins we can
see is step number three that if the
cookie is available for the identity
provider and you have a valid session
then automatically you will have a valid
session with the older application that
relies on the data provider as an
authentication provider so let's see
this and a little bit in a demo here so
very quickly I'm just going to log in to
Google to photo indication again Twitter
again to further education navel and
Facebook same thing two thousand
occasion navel on this victim machine
yeah so we have now a valid session with
all these three these three sides so
this time we're going to run Cookie
Monster except we're not going to target
any specific application we're just
going to dump the whole cookie database
makes it easier so here we have the
entire cookie database for that
particular user same process when I copy
a we're going to copy the little script
when I put it on your local attacker
machine
and we never say proceeded to hijack the
sessions so here we're creating the
cookie file in your local machine and
now we're going again to our attacker
machine when I load the cookies I'm
going to change their IP so you can see
they were coming from a different place
so all these session hijacking thing is
nothing new by the way this is a well
known issue but most a lot of people
that I show this to they actually not
aware that you can do this and that is
why one of the reasons why I decided to
try to take this issue around and then
show it to people so just how many of
you know that you can do this ok so
you're aware of this here that's cool
so now we have this session hijack and
then I'm going to look at the we're
going to take a look of the apps that
are connected to this so we go to face
we go to the settings and apps and we
can see an example here Expedia that
they allow for login with Facebook so
for Gmail we go to my account we go to
connected apps inside and as an example
we have our here Dropbox which is
connected to this account and for
Twitter it was so hard to find an
application that actually relies on
Twitter but I found one MySpace yeah I
haven't use myspace in so long so let's
go to a speedier now sign in sign in
with Facebook and as you can see now we
have a valid session with the with the
Windex pds hole which is relying on
Facebook as an authentication provider
so these are just examples there's many
other applications out there any
occasions of the security implications
of this depends on what application
we're talking about now let's go to
Dropbox same thing we can sign up not
sign on this case this actually stands
for sign-in because the account already
exists
and now we have a also gain answers to
that Dropbox account now with my face
and this is what my face looks like in
2017 so I always loved all those cookie
messages here because it goes so well
with the anyways so same thing Twitter
in this case and now we are logging
again again as the user yeah so that's
pretty much it so of course this attack
will not work will not be effective at
least on some of web applications that
implement strong session management
control such as short sessions grades
and time outs not allowing current
sessions binding session I need your
user properties etc now the question is
how many of the main two publications or
duplicates that use available
applications that you test on your daily
life actually implement all these
controls and it's a very hard thing to
do because it's a very big question and
a very in a balance that you have to do
between usability of your application
and the security applications so yeah
it's not it's not an easy thing so I've
been talk with the with Google I wrote
Google Facebook Peters and all some
orders around investigating as well to
see what their take on this and
basically the answer can be summarizing
this is this is beyond the control of
any of what we can do because once
you've lost control of your file system
then all bets are basically off so
there's not much that can be done about
it at least yeah so as a conclusion to
this I want to say that most
conventional knowledge will argue that
using social logins it's safer as we
tend to believe that the strong
authentication controls that these
identity providers implemented will make
well we'll make our accounts more secure
now I really don't want to argue against
that or for that but I just want you
guys to consider that this is a factor
when you are deciding whether or not to
sign up for social login providers so
before I finish I just want to leave you
with a final question and that I asked
myself is it okay to have locked session
management practices on sides our
authentication providers so I will leave
that to you to answer yourself and maybe
we can have a discussion after anyways
but that's all for my presentation at
least if you want a copy of the tool is
available my github claim or as you can
write me on Twitter as well there and I
actually then I presented this a piece
has given as well but it was in one hour
presentation back then so I had a chance
to do more demos some cool things so you
want take a look your insert that you
want to see more demos then you can
check out the cool Cooper's filming of
beside Ljubljana yeah anyway that's all
for me thank you very much yes she sent
out an email when you're walking in from
a different device yes so this has
always at the look inside most of the
controls including the Gmail control and
the phase loop controls are only done
god that's indication at least from my
experience I mean like you can you know
more about this to judge the Google guy
here yes he talked about secure cookies
morning as well so I was on a different
perspective anyway so most of those
controls at least from what I've seen
and what I was doing the testing us only
happening during this login so that's
why I wanted to emphasize if you're
coming from different IP at least
Facebook and Gmail are not complaining
so much and they only complain when you
do the authentication and that's what
almost the checks are done at least from
my experience so if you have experienced
something different that will be very
interesting
you seen that because this leads to use
agents comparators well that's exactly
that's exactly what I that's exactly
what I asked when I was talking to them
and they told me that they didn't think
that was the right way to go about it
to do any property bindings to the
cookies the thing that was there was an
effective solution I don't know why and
I'm not going to I'm not going to say
why they think that I just what I did
the answer that I got from them I think
it has to do a lot with usability
because you don't want your session to
break every time you change a piece if
you have a mobile yeah when you have a
key inside there may be user agents
different yeah just just to user it
doesn't change if you change your team
like you remember on our altar the
things that you can also lose those so
the other day it's really a protect I
mean it will it will hire a little bit
the security but it's not really a
solution so so what's your
recommendation anything well yeah
actually one thing that I seen work in
this case if you're really paranoid you
might want to browse in only use the
internet on where is it safe laughing it
go incognito mode that's it because
according to mode doesn't flush the
cookies to the hard drive it only keeps
them in the memory from what I seen so
at least until I figure out how to
structure from memory you're safe yeah
so that's a little thing that you can do
what other wise I just don't have your
computer hack basically I identify thank
you
yeah so the product yeah that's a good
approach but the thing is like like you
saw there ah one of the things that the
to implement is that you wait until it
sees there is a cookie with an active
session in which is seal it so that
would not really protect you so what the
tool will do is it will just complete
check and what is it that you log on to
that side that I'm interested in it will
it will actually first will have to
crush the process of the browser in
order for me to be able to delete it
from the cookie because the browser has
a lock on the on the cookie that way so
what I do is across the the browser
process I retrieve the cookie I delete
it and then you can log in again so I
have another session to your so with
like I said with Facebook yeah so at
least with Facebook and Google and your
the big one you can still go there and
manually delete the other session if you
think if you actually realize that you
can have but there's many other websites
out there that don't have this control
so that's why if an interesting is an
interesting thing to think about okay
let's call it break time now just five
minutes so you can have a cup of coffee
not statistically break yet that comes a
bit later but just as we have five
sessions in a row and then if you want
to keep discussing with Martin we've got
breakouts and Purdue's back you mark yes
no problem sex thank you
[Applause]