let's get started um yeah I I think
besides Vienna and that is always an end
of year like last two editions already
um and yeah I'm from Vienna I always
describes Vienna like the city of come
on no no yes to be armed Teddy foods
know what is up with you ethical
architecture and classical music yeah
but it's the only way how we can win
anything around dizzy anymore so I work
for elastic the company behind left
research classic stack and I'm part of
the infrastructure team so internal
cooling AWS docker containers all these
things and then I always say and this is
a unique type I kind of pipe that into
developer advocacy so I'm doing lots of
conferences if you have any questions
articles on come to me quickly because I
need to head to Russia in the afternoon
and yeah and I was running so meters in
Vienna what about databases and what
about the various inside of soft light
papers do you have a papist Munich group
there between the Munich it's kind of a
worldwide thing you you read an academic
paper each month and then you just
discussed it like the new study group
and what you hated it at university you
kind of do it voluntarily now and yeah
so I guess everybody knows that one
little Bobby tables so no sequence not
on the SQL where you generally don't
have as you can without SQL no SQL
injections right problem solved who
thinks that it's kind of true like there
is no way square I obviously know SQL
injections with no injections energy
people is anybody ok I will see arm
so let's talk about manga DB because its
most widely used one and because those
are web scale maybe if people still
remember that one in the heydays of no
sequel like there was this comic we're
making fun of mommy to be like oh you
need to use it because its web scale and
throw away your SQL database yeah stuff
has changed since then but still most
widely used and let's see how it goes
there so X K injections are probably not
since there is no SQL but you can do
stuff like that if anybody still
remembers diaspora that was the sex lots
of years ago that the Facebook killer or
whatever the decentralized social
network stuffed with garlic billion
dollars venture capital I think and then
nothing ever got out of it but if you're
interesting to fuji articles for example
is they I think it was Ruby and they had
stuff like that so they have defined
dollar where where the kind of define a
condition for more gdb and then they
just throw a string against it and while
it's not an Afghan injection obviously
that is a script injection whatever you
put in there you can just yeah close
whatever you're doing and run some other
arbitrary script there so don't do that
that was found in the Astro script they
got rid of that eventually but it didn't
help them they didn't really make it so
stuff you should watch out for if you
rise mommy-to-be queries for example is
these a BB evil kind of the obvious one
but the others as well like if you run
any of these and you pop in some strings
you just do it down the string
concatenation we promptly have injection
problems or you could have them because
it's just running some random script
don't just take that and sanitized you
can turn off scripting and I don't
really know why it's an able because
it's normally really bad performance
wise and security wise not great either
but yeah you can either pass it as a
parameter to the momma Dee process or
you can just a blip in the script in the
conflict or you can if they have these
weird code w scope blocks like you can
put script into that and
we properly escaped I've never tried
that but normally it just seems
scripting any database like why would
you even have stripping images and and
then we had something from solid 2015
when they just can't the internet for
open MongoDB database simply followed
quite a lot of them and as it often
happens like academia is first and then
it takes some time to actually get out
to the real world and in probably
January this year it was pretty much
that's far when people's guarded
ransomware attacks of business doors so
they would hopefully backup the data
somewhere then heat it and leave a note
on page pairs that amount of money and
you will get your data back so from what
i heard sometimes they don't actually
take the backups and they will just
delete your data and leave the message
and yeah if you pay your you're not
getting your database um but that's just
accidental so that is not what you want
um quick show of hands who thinks that
mom will be only binds to localhost
nobody but they do and I can recent
versions like I think they changed it
two or three years ago already ahsoka
demek was learning experience before
they bounced going interfaces just be
easy to get started but for two or three
years they have been binding just
localhost by default so anybody who can
be attacked over the internet actually
change that setting sun at some point
who thinks that authentication neighbors
by default unfortunately that is not the
case so there are the protection is they
will find just to read localhost and if
you change that you're supposed to
change the authentication as well and
and obviously nobody does it so let's
see what do they even have to even have
something like authentication
authorization um yes but you need to
enable it with all true witches love
that hard they had one implementation
preview
p which was the challenge sports movie
thingy and in more recent versions they
have a new implementation called Graham
shell one which seems like just from
looking at it very solid using an
official standard and they've added some
nice features so you have stuff like you
can define the iteration count for
hashing you have a salt per user now and
not only per server anymore they had
finally gotten rid of md5 and also the
server authenticate against the clients
and look only the other way around so
that looks very promising you just need
to use it and just to show you
unfortunately it's a bit of it and dance
around the system to get it started so
these are the predefined both there are
lots of roles you can just use them you
can create your own this maybe even too
many because it's a bit confusing ah but
how do you enable them so normally what
you would do is you start your process
with the north / so you can log in for
the first time and sort of pretty much
as people parameters and then you can
just say I'm creating a user fill your
passwords and I have the role route on
the MU database and then you exit it so
first you create user and you exit it
then we started a tab it again that's
the first line and instead of North
we're just saying all so we're all Senta
cating against it now if I then just do
the Mongoose or Moody's always the
server process and Mongo is the client
process so if i use mumbles local admin
i'm trying to collect i connect us to
the moment be processed on local o
people caught us yet in database if i
run any man live show db's it will throw
me an error because you're not
authenticated now you really need
authentication so we're trying again
with that line i'm actually providing my
user it will ask interactively from a
password and then i can create another
non admin user
who can repurpose it and write every to
therapy and then we can leave that again
because you probably don't want to use
real admin user for anything because as
soon as somebody gets that you're done
again so then L is authenticated and
with this line work here what we have in
here any guesses so we have said read on
pet a and reprise on Pepe so that is so
we're connecting to test a you're trying
to try something that we fail then we're
switching the device here will work then
we're switching to the database in an
example yes we can write we can read
then we're switching to the seagate can
I even switch you to see database do you
think yes but you can unfortunately
replacement that makes scripting pretty
difficult because you can't switch to a
database but you don't have any
permissions on it and so here will only
happen here if you do define so yeah but
that is kind of the dance you need to do
to create the root user and to create
dedicate user for whatever you want to
do and then you can use it in a secure
fashion ssl as far as i know it's silly
commercial but the commercial part is
only like the binaries don't contain in
it but the source code does so if you
compile this device other source code
yourself you can have as a self support
yeah everybody needs to make money
somewhere I fight it with decision but
yeah anyway continuing to readies
anybody using ready it's so simple and
nice right and it has some very unique
security features do you think defines
to all interfaces who thinks yet who
thinks no so it does but with a little
trick um since a pretty recent version
like yes
year ago they added something called
protected mode so it will bind to all
interfaces but you will only respond to
queries are unlocking doors with the
actual result and for remote viewers it
will just throw a message like oh you're
not properly authenticated and your
remote system in fix that so it's not
not working but it's not working
correctly either it's just showing you
what you need to do which I find
actually in can kind of a user friendly
approach is not just blocking you but it
will tell you okay you need to change
that to work but by default if we bind
to all interfaces and yet they have
something like authentication but there
is no authorization or like pretty
binary yes-or-no X's and even in their
documentation they call it a tiny layer
of authentication which I find very nice
coat like so tiny because nearly doesn't
exist so what you can do is you can say
all password if you have set a password
in the ready configuration file and then
you can run your command problem is the
password is stored in plain text in the
reddit com I think it's also transmitted
plain text and there is no ssl
encryption or anything by people and
there's also no rate-limiting so you
read it is very fast so you can also run
this off command very fast so you can
pretty much just start from forcing that
one password there is yeah but that's
the authentication they have and the
other feature i find very nice is hiding
commands so they have you set it in the
configuration again and you need to
restart the server to change that it's a
bit security through obscurity so what
they have is if you have to come on
cough it you can say rename the command
post it to my secret config name so it's
just like the commander still there you
just don't know what it's called and one
common approach is that you take the
the parameter or the commands name add
some salt and then just md5 hashes and
then you know okay that is the hatch and
if I use that ash i'm using actually
decimal yeah but since the networking is
not encrypted like anybody listening on
the way I can just see what you can
answer call but yet it can rename
commands which is an interesting
approach what might make more sense is
that you can kind of remove commands you
can just say they have an empty name and
then they're gone then you cannot access
them anymore so that is kind of their
approach of removing features or
limiting the use of specific features
and have some some commands they
normally advise you to remove so they
have commands which make sense for test
service where you just drop all the keys
you have in your key value store but
probably that's not what you want in
your production system and this poor Lua
scripting and obviously don't pass in
random doing scripts otherwise that
stuff would happen okay and electric
search well what do we are um we have
some security issues over the years um
yeah they are on our website so we try
to document them as yeah publicly as
possible and if you take a closer look
um these are the most severe ones and
they were related to scripting that
somebody could break out of the search
box so in the beginning we had groovy
scripting because it was since epic
search is written in Java that was very
easy to add abuse and you have just
scripts is very hard to contain improve
escape to the general-purpose
programming language you can do lots of
interesting stuff and that turned out to
be very hard to contain to a sandbox and
for example an ex work colleague of mine
he once had an electric server so
electric search server running somewhere
and yeah somebody I don't know which one
probably the middle one the groovy
sample is escape and somebody took over
his box and started spamming the world I
think it was sending so many mates
even in sage into the box anymore be
closing that the connection was so
unstable yeah so that was kind of a
problem and elastic what kind of like
maybe we should do something it's not
the way we want this to go so we added
something called payment to literally
take the pain away so pain that is our
own scripting language and yeah so we
hired a developer and we put him into
exalted for a year and he developed
painless there because there's not in
enough scripting languages you can only
hear always have n plus 1 and painless
is our n plus 1 and even wrote a blog
post afterwards about that why we the
brand new language shooing they're
always so many out there we still did
because we kind of thought it worth it
or because we thought that there are no
really good alternatives for that so
there is two goals and security and
performance security and no more dvds on
sandbox escapes and scripting is
possible and performance problem the
brewery scripting is I think it's
interpreted every time it runs so there
is an overhead to that which we want to
get rid of and so those were the two
main goals of writing custom scripting
language so just to give you very
quickly sample of what that looks like
the top line is a document and I have
played and some I don't know what it is
ok no I don't know I scored like I
played three games and I score some
goals and I am about many cities and now
in our scripting language you want to
know how many goals did I score in total
so since it looks pretty familiar and
the only thing that must be weird is
that you take inputs document that
targets the documents we have set up
there yes use goals yeah and then we
operate from that and we just add all
the goals we have and that is our final
result so this point is just have a
general purpose is a language which
cannot escape sandbox and
forward so it has some features which
don't really make much or too much if
internet security concepts unless unless
every value so we have methods and feet
level whitelisting so only it's certain
stuff that we think makes sense is
allowed because I think that much
business in the past so you cannot say
class full name to just load any random
class you have on the glass pass and
then do with stuff with it so only kind
of sensible stuff is allowed and
everything else is like visit so you
should not be able to escape that and
that was kind of the main point of
creating that programming language by
now paying this is a default in the
current version we still have scripting
language the other scripting languages
most people use groovy but we support
Python and JavaScript as well so they
are deprecated and will definitely go
away in the next major version so
anybody doing scripting there we try to
force you into the right car it's all
works and yeah and then we have this
authentication authorization and
encryption thing I know it's called SL
we refactored on all the encryption
stuff in the latest major release and I
don't really know why but unfortunately
we caught the premise and now everywhere
ssl because before we had TLS and ssl
mix and obviously it is TLS but we still
call it as a cell so don't be confused
by that if it's still apps that we just
call it into self for whatever reason
but it's the same everywhere and so how
does it work out with elastic search
unfortunately that is how my seller is
being paid so those are the commercial
features we have and just to show you
how this came out end up let's do we do
something live so should I guess
everybody knows okay sorry I'm trying to
touch anything I guess everybody knows
that back right you can't just find
stuff on the internet is just scanning
what is out there and then you can try
using that so we can do can just put in
elasticsearch here and I hope my wife I
my yeah so we have some stuff called
elastic search but it's mostly for a one
so they have a reverse proxy in front of
that so that is not going to help us so
we can just start searching for 200 and
we should get some more results and it
actually tells less than 600 results now
and I early this morning I try to login
into those and most of them I don't know
our either more text or are probably a
honey pot anyway like I'm pretty sure
any pretty much everything of that this
is a honey pot anymore so I didn't find
anything that was too revealing there
anymore but what I guess all the script
kiddies has used those up already so you
can't just switch to port 9000 planet
which is the default elasticsearch port
and I'm going forward to hundreds now
and that leaders should lead us to more
results the demo birds are not with me
oh come on no showdown is broken yeah
probably too many results okay since i
since i have tried it i think i have one
working IP in my cash in my command
history so assume the site is up and you
get like with that search i got i think
more than a hundred thousand results you
get an IPS and now you just were just
looking no touching just looking weird
let's see what we have so on since
elasticsearch is just providing a red
space interface is very easy to just
interact with it with curl you don't
need any fancy tools i just found the IP
address 54 blah blah blah
hold 9200 and then i'm using the API
underscore kept it slides kept the
command line tool just show you stuff in
mep consumable session and images I'm
just interested in which indicates does
this elasticsearch register have and the
question might be is just turn me the
header information for that as well and
if I run that it will tail tell me we
threw the challenge jobs and then please
read and please read has a document
count of 1 so that is kind of the design
that somebody has been here and done
something let's see what is in that
document so i can copy that power can't
say no yeah you we're very polite so um
so this is all red space this is the
next we want to use now I want to search
this and I have a query just show me
everything and i'm adding a pretty so
it's nicely formatted as well and we
should close there and if I didn't miss
type what wide awake um please research
clearly pretty much come on live spoken
as well you ? before cookie yeah sorry
usually putting some are people ready
correct on this great this song yet oh I
edited yeah that was yes tube type of
yeah and what you didn't get is
something like this and yes 0.5 second I
don't know what is it today 600 600
Europe so the problem is there is no
reason aren t that
Rebecca and I've already seen instances
like they're just a few weeks ago there
were there was not only one team or
person doing that for multiple ones and
they left different messages and so kind
of somebody deleted you later and left
that message like please pay pay that up
and then somebody else left another
message so they didn't remove the the
one message which which like the
original ransom message but they just
would add another ransom message and
then you probably would end up with two
or three random messages and then you
will need to decide like who was there
first like who probably has your data or
maybe not like you don't really know and
then you can just start paying a loss
and hope for the best yeah but let's not
let it get that far so we've seen those
so the first thing you should do is so
by default like everybody else by now
but that also changed like one or two
years ago only our electric search is
only found two local hood you will
explicitly need to change the
configuration if you want to bind in
somewhere else just put it on a private
network only like with any data store
there's no real point in having it on a
public IP put a firewall in front of it
even though I've like people think me on
Twitter and said Oh our firewall kind of
like we had some bad rules and the
firewall was just down for an hour and
somebody still took download data during
that one hour so firewalls are also not
not helping you all the time and what
you can always do is you can add a
random force but again this is more like
security through obscurity which might
help your like give you a long a chance
to avoid problems but yeah it's no real
solution and what you can do what you
can do for fries you can just use your
breasts proxy so since it's all
http-based then everybody has lots of
experience with HTTP you can use engine
X H a proxy whatever just put a sender
and and basic off and run that or we
have
ex extension for that as well and the
commercial extension can also do stuff
like fifth level security or document
level security which you cannot easily
deal with reverse proxy so and that is
part of the cluster already because one
other common scenario where people has
problems if they had their nice little
proxy somewhere but then there has some
some other way around that to access the
data store and yeah the proxy didn't
really have them and if something bad
happens and please make backups like if
you don't have backups you shouldn't be
in charge of anybody stay there anyway
so you can always read next from another
source or just restore its nature if
you've taken and and it's the only way
to guarantee to get your data back like
from what I thought the chances if
somebody will remove the data it might
not be dead great even though from the
things instance you can find my now most
of them are just forgotten testing
sentences or honey pots anyway so I
guess there is no point in starting a
new resume tech now if anybody feels
very motivated I guess like these feeds
has been harvested pretty well by now
okay to conclude um yes injections are
still a thing even though no sequel
doesn't have SQL or some have added kind
of SQL Lite interfaces by now as well
but injections are still a thing don't
pass in any I escape stuff that just
executing the datastore that is more
something for the providers or vendors
like please enable security but I guess
this is pretty much a learning
experience my secret didn't have
authentication authorization in the
beginning then it didn't have that
enabled by default and I think the notes
equal world is kind of going through the
same cycle as well we're at first you
don't have much then then you just find
to localhost and at some later point you
decide okay maybe we need to enable this
security security just slightly for
creativity can be interesting or not
like reddit is always I'm always a bit
torn like hiding the commands that
cruise
another cool feature on the other hand I
find that just answering queries are on
localhost and for remote series just
show you know fix that and configure
that that is final an interesting
approach yeah elastic we think that
custom scripting can make sense so far
we didn't have any security issues yet
we'll see what time brings in the long
run yeah and it's just I guess
development thing like most of the
relational database has been around
since the 80s and had lots of security
issues over the years and no sequel is
kind of going through the same growing
pains i would say just learning
experience ah which you unfortunately
cannot really fast forward with
somewhere you need to pay that price
yeah I don't know that I have lots of
stickers here if you want secret there's
one of my main obligations at tested
student tickets are throughout Europe I
don't have any questions by the way who
is using MongoDB who admitted okay ready
okay that is more elastic search source
or more ok very nice um hey has anybody
been renting no I'm always interested in
stories from the beach any questions
well well okay then okay I have a few
questions okay so you just think about
how a single database or database
systems have sort of a hardened can meet
a security model that's grown over time
naturally and so my question for you is
this you talk about authentication
schemes and for you sort of lost over
though the elastic search authentication
scheme what are some of the features of
the authentication scheme there so
things
this is a basic off basically so yeah
you have to baby if you have the paper
news you get TLS encryption but most
basic off and then you can limit that
down to G Nixon like d mix was the
please read thing we've seen and or in
the highest plan you could even limit
this down to fees so you could say okay
everybody can see all the feeds of
employees but only the management can
see the speed salary so you could limit
that or just document where you could
say stuff like everybody can see all the
documents but if the B was over ten
thousand euro on this is 50 FPS and then
it passed example is not in reverse
proxy from the fish that is really part
of the culture and there is no easy way
to circumvent this so we have stuff like
a year scism to target multiply there's
a remain soft but there is estimated
time up in the course you can work
around that in any way and then my next
question would be as a pen tester I
would be interested in paying okay so
you have an authentication scheme that I
can't quite find pounder so do you have
the fruit horse protection oh nothing
I'm aware okay then my next question
would be you have a way okay as a pen
tetra I have the next question do you
have a way to set up a password policy
such that people actually create or
Fergus for basic authentication yes
let's think about it for suit so must be
13 characters long at least a mixed case
numbers special characters when I don't
think so buddy it's only a REST API so
depending on how you interact with it
you can set up your own like we can hook
into a supply as FX directory like we
can reuse that so if you have a purse
apology i will just reuse that actually
no i don't have eggs and yeah it would
take two minutes to start off Jesus we
had web interface I'm not sure if we can
set up a password policy item and get it
just like whatever you had
in things is manageable but heavy Kings
had such apologies innovation databases
thank you yeah for example my people you
can head up a password policy it has a
polygon your day I'm i will get to ask
em another where if you came in this
okay does anyone else have any questions
or difficulties sorry certificate
benefited yeah it was wait hey but where
would you pinned it on in your
application I mean that's yeah that's up
to your application then I mean it's not
a it's not a porosity you cannot use a
browser as tificate pinging no I mean
well macquinet indignation house is just
like server so many like when you come
again then you just be sure what I'm
talking yeah but that's pretty much part
of your client application right that
would need to be implemented in your
kind application yes tell me today
schedule from somewhere oh but but but
when you get the right child back with
the certificate as well then but I think
he's working with my hsps whether a lazy
eye yeah but setting age hsps like in a
client application no because HTS better
would be on the server certificate
pinning hell he's talking about the
certificate thing yeah
be sure what server on top tables verify
and its origin that the header and the
reporting don't tell me like what you
should be questioned exit interview in
turn into the yeah II you should be able
to be cutting out of you so if there is
a way to insert the hell up also what
you can implement the public answer yeah
philemon you're talking about security
bed including this shield yes so we kind
of did a renaming strategy and in the
beginning that before 50 everything was
called up the marvel comics and stuff so
it was called she's marvelous cetera the
product and we kind of renamed that two
more generic boring names and so what
was shield is now security and what was
marvelous now monitoring because it's
like she's kind of methods for people's
but marvel was not really obvious what
is what his mother doing and what sure
was the alerting thing and it's called
now is that so yeah what was she is now
security um that's kind of did to be
branding there as well yes running okay
so internally it doesn't talk read it
has its own binary protocol so that's it
like 9,000 trying to rest api which you
expose the outside and the internal
traffic communication is 9300 that's
just John protocol and that use the
security internally as well but it's not
basic off because it's it's not wrist
anymore
how does it know when I were I was it
uses a tenant you have the credentials
as well the inside the cluster
appreciate you yeah if there is a so
there are generally two ways to set this
up you can either have configuration
file but there is not very convenient to
add new users and provide the rest
interface and thank the kind of story
inside elasticsearch so we have a
special index keeping the users and
credentials so you don't always need to
edit files especially if you have lots
of service you don't want to edit files
on all of them that can be cumbersome
any more questions thank you very much
thank you
[Applause]