alright would you like some honey with
that thank you very much
and thank you for being here after lunch
break I hope you left a little bit of
space in your tummy for just a little
bit of honey and probably some of you
will be very sick after that and don't
want to hear the word honey at all for
quite some time so Who am I just very
briefly I work as a security engineer at
a company in Germany called dot if we
are doing mainly software for text
consultants so if you've never heard
about us and you are living in Germany
chances that actually your statement at
the end of the month was printed by us
are really good a short disclaimer that
I need to say my views my views on my
own and whenever I'm using examples I'm
not really saying they are good or
especially bad they're just examples and
the mother
show disclaimer because we have the
earlier security our honey things
generally security through obscurity and
security through obscurity as many
people will say me included is no
security at all at least not in my
opinion but in the case of honey stuff
it really works better the fewer people
know about it so you're not really
basing your whole security
infrastructure and honey stuff at least
I'm hoping you're not so it's just an
additional form of an early warning
system and as such not really security
through obscurity in mind or as we could
put it first all the fun stuff you
talked about how to stuff which is kind
of not what I'm doing here but I'm
talking about stuff before we get to
things we have to look at the
traditional honey pots they really look
like a vulnerable server at first and it
can easily become obvious at a second
glance that's not what I signed up for
oh that's not a real server but by then
it's too late because you already
glanced at it or you already have to
contact the honeypot traditional honey
pots come in various stages like from
low interaction too high interaction and
a low interaction honeypot probably just
uses an IP address on your network and
you can ping it you can connect it sort
of it supports the services up to OSI
layer 4 and once set up and running they
do not require a lot of maintenance
these are honey pots that are not
advertised in your network so there's no
legitimate service on them
so whoever connects to a honeypot
actually is considered to be an attacker
because there's just no sales running
their meeting interaction honey pots
take it to a slightly higher level
because they will simulate services like
FTP or telnet and they also will allow
an attacker to connect to those honey
pots and leave their credentials that
they wanted to use and maybe look at the
files the attacker wanted to have and
they are a little bit more maintenance
because you have to look at them and you
can put a high interaction honeypot on
your network very often these are
machines that are connected to your
back-end
so high interaction honeypot just think
about it is a really heavy monitored
machine they really try to find out what
the attacker is going to do but the
attacker that connects to that machine
won't really be content with a cat
picture they want the real stuff so you
have to connect it to your databases so
they get some real data as you can
probably see these require a lot of
maintenance and monitoring and this
means that high direction honey pots are
for very special places there are honey
nets as well and I'm briefly touching
onto them just in a minute but all those
honey pots have one thing in common once
you connect you already triggered an
alert and this goes so far that when
talking to to another machine on the
network I the first thing that I need is
the MAC address of the machine so this
connection typically comes from the
switch if it's a segmented network but
this will trigger and already because
the machine
the honeypot really sits in the network
doing nothing it's kind of like what we
want to do when you're money two of
those things do nothing and before I
come to the honey nets why is honey
stuff important or why do I think honey
stuff is important so detection is the
new protection is something you might
have heard the funny thing is that
companies and enterprises are really
really good at protecting the perimeter
because that's what they have been doing
for years and years and years but the
funny question is where the heck is my
perimeter nowadays because people bring
their own devices that connect to the
network
I've got cloud services that deal with
my data
I've got partnering with others and so
to define where the parameter is can
actually be a daunting task so it's
easier actually to well easy and it's
not easier and bosses do not like to
hear that you should really assume that
you have been breached and you want to
detect that stuff and the honey pots or
honey stuff is one method of doing that
and I really need to stress that no
honey pot or honey stuff at all will
prevent an attacker from attacking you
but you will know about it in instead of
having of knowing about an attack a year
after it has happened you might get
Intel about the attack while it is
happening and that is can be very
important so the first stage that an
attacker does usually is when they have
a foothold in your network they will try
to spread out without a lot of noise so
the group if you're on Twitter you
probably are familiar with him said and
many other people have said that as well
you only need one exploit and once
you're in you move laterally so whenever
one mission is breached and you're
trying to find out more interesting
machines to attack there's one problem
in modern networks if you've got a
really nice amount of network you've got
the friend internet here because I
basically got sick of the red internet
that is evil so I made it a little nice
and you've got different networks
someone's like the orange the green the
blue and you've got second segments
you've got firewalls the firewall also
has an IPS IPS and the reason why I
combined those two is because most major
vendors will do that when this purple
sauce fire they put the whole source by
intelligence on the NSA so you probably
will look at the network traffic when
every crosses
network boundaries like from orange to
green or green to blue but what you
usually won't see is if somebody managed
to reach your first file or whatever and
this has compromised that machine and
the sitting on this machine and it's
just spreading out without touching
network borders
how big are the chances that you will
miss the connection from the internet to
that server and I would like to say very
high because who didn't notice that this
machine got exploited so it's easy for
an attacker to peena-pod if you've got
honey pots and they get touched then of
course you get another and you know
there's somebody there a very brief
excursion to honey nuts I've put some
links in the links slide yeah about
waterworks in the Train
these are two projects that really took
the concept of honey pots to another
level because they build whole networks
and fake water works for a small town
that could be attacked from the internet
because they wanted to know what would
an attacker do how would they many plate
the pumps how would they actually try to
break stuff and the same for the honey
train this was a model train nobody knew
it was a model train but it was on the
internet it was a big story about six or
seven weeks ago I think because they
managed finally to derail it which for a
model train is okay but in the real
world
[Laughter]
when we are talking about honey stuff we
are talking mostly about decoys and
deceptive strategies and that's an
asymmetric relationship between an
attacker and the defender because the
attacker probably has all the good stuff
on their side and that's that as a
defender we've got a really good
advantage that we rarely take use to
make use of and that is we should know
our networks better than unfortunately
you know the boss of the NSA said that
there is a knows networks of companies
better than the companies do themselves
but let's just assume you know get work
and you can tell the decoys from the
real machines that take account until
they connect now that we've talked a lot
about traditional honey pots let's see
what else we could do to have these kind
of strategies and how we could get
results when we are putting honey
somewhere else so how do we get an
attacker to actually attack our honey
sites or whatever we do we just have to
think like an attack at us and if we've
got a website we just have the
robots.txt and we put something in there
like this allows - besides might help
dot ppt I hope you are familiar with our
robots.txt that is for the Google
spiders and cameras and it tells a robot
where to go and where not to go
if a human looks at this and somewhere
there's disallows leche et Cie past's WD
password the password file they will go
and check it out human attacker might
check out those sites that are
disallowed and of course you monitor
those and send an alert if somebody
touches the file a concept I really like
is the concept how many people if you
are well probably wherever you you are
from you've heard about the CEO fraud
where some social engineers really get
people to pay lots and lots of money by
just pressurizing them into it there's a
company from the town where I work in
Newark who lost 40 million last summer
by that
basically it works like that the boss
called somebody our rights and human
says I'm in foreign country X and I
really need 40 millions now hand them
over to me probably not that easy but
that's the the gist of it so if you want
to see you whether somebody is trying to
contact employees at your at your
company then just create a fake profile
about you for those people on the same
or LinkedIn using an email address that
fits your company and give them a phone
number too and format both to your
security team as your security
operations center because whatever calls
up that phone or whatever sends them an
emails either somebody who's a really
aggressive marketeer or someone who's
looking for an easy target for social
engineering you don't really have to
update those pages just every now and
then just don't do a lot of work with
them but may give them an interesting
Chuck position not the CEO obviously you
can get into a lot of trouble for doing
that but some kind of personal assistant
because these are usually the people
with the power anyway for social in
Chinese put honey in some DNS so create
a few plausible yet unused supplements
like lab your site example admin
WordPress whatever you're not using this
kind of eats the purpose if you allow
the in a song transfer but I'm assuming
you don't so whenever an attackers
checking out your web page and trying
out subdomains that you might not use
they might stumble upon a honey DNS page
as soon as your DNS of a resolver says
hey I got a request for lab your side
exam to the dog you can actually set out
on a lot and having pictures I've
briefly touched on that as well if you
have a web page chances are very great
you've got an eval page somewhere about
HTML so why not call it about on let's
go retune HTML and use that and of
course you will have an about underscore
v1 HTML that you are not using that is
not linked anywhere but that is one of
your honey pages and you alert whatever
this is triggered because again an
attacker might see your about page that
is version two if I have a look at
version 1 what are the differences who
were people on version 1 that are not on
version 2 what could I use for social
engineering and things like that so it
might give you some insights
then there's something honey data for
database use where you create a few fake
people actually with free email accounts
you put them together with other made up
data in your users databases or wherever
whichever table in your sequel or no
sequel server you can think of the
purpose of these people is just to see
whether the database has been breached
because if anybody ever writes an email
to that or you see the email on page or
wherever it is leaked you know somebody
has breached the database or somebody's
able to read your database this is
something with very much of the honey
stuff it might just sit there for years
and do nothing and you can't really know
whether it has been breached or not but
if you get a mail which is one of those
emails you know that it has been
breached
so it might give you that slight
advantage you can put honey in files as
well for example an interesting file
like license top TST lying around on a
server where you assume that could be
breached from the internet and whenever
somebody touches that file to read it
you just periodically check the access
times I've got the example for Leno's
here it's the same on other operating
systems so whenever the excess time
changes somebody has a resolute file and
you can say that on alert and you know
the server's compromised we're coming to
the concept of honey bitcoins and this
is a very interesting concept I've read
about that some time ago and I thought
well that is pretty you just put a honey
Bitcoin wallet on your server with a
small amount of Bitcoin and whenever
that what it gets stolen or them
it's transfer you know hey this server
has been breached and I thought well
wouldn't it be even more interesting to
put a lot of money in that say five
hundred euros or a whole Bitcoin because
as an attacker if I see something lying
around would I would I touch a wallet
well I I might if I from previous
experience no other there's really money
in it but then again there was a company
offering that as a service and they went
out of business so I guess the idea is
rather to a paranoia a little bit
if you are a manufacturing company have
so many products for example have data
sheets for a new product you're putting
out this summer again this is not linked
by your regular website this is just if
you have product pages like pronto three
dot HTML and just make a fraud oh six or
something like that describe your
product but nothing detail and ask the
attacker for their credentials if they
want to have more information like an
address I'm pretty sure you feel like
winning the lottery if it works out but
it's not far-fetched because if you've
read cliff stalls the Cuckoo's egg
that's exactly how they captured their
attacker by just saying we've got a new
product and please give us your address
if you are interested in it and one more
thing that I would put would like to
cover in honey are QR codes so if you're
especially paranoid and you think that
somebody's thinking through your trash
wherever you work and looking at all the
stuff that you throw away and just put a
QR code in there and again this pointing
to your honey website of use and so if
somebody really goes through your trash
scans that in and costs so that website
you know hands are the person of
importance because they are digging
through my trash cool and you also of
course know that you are attacked
so the question is should you put honey
on everything yes
yeah please keep the original goal in
mind as defenders or generally as people
working in the IT industry we tend to be
effective not lazy and we're looking for
ways to actually catch an attacker that
doesn't cost us a lot of work so if your
honey stuff generates lots and lots of
false positives then it's probably not
the correct tool for you
oh that's useful if your honey stuff
needs a lot of maintenance and it
doesn't give you any important
information like you've got a honey net
set up and nobody's connecting to it
then it's the wrong tool as well so just
find out what works for you and stick to
that there are many more ideas where you
could put honey into so really find out
what works for you
this just one rule I'd like to stress
and that is be creative being don't be
too obvious
if the following you serve is called
luring this Kitty or hoping this $4,000
somebody might get suspicious at least
if you've got an interesting and
intelligent attacker and they might not
touch that stuff so try to make it
plausible something that could be on the
server and everybody at your company
that are on that server should know this
is honey stuff they should be connected
and lasts like more or less is honey a
double-edged sword having stuff and of
course it is like everything in our tea
if an attacker knows you're employing
heavy stuff they can abuse that if for
example I was in a tech and I knew that
there are five honey pots on the network
I could send them tons of alerts because
the security operation center would get
swamped other words from a honeypot
should be shouldn't be false positives
and so they could trigger their attack
somewhere else the thing is I think
you've missed the point in time where
the home stuff is useful at the point
where you miss the attacker who found
out about
and also if an attack is going on and
you get tons of alerts on your honey
pots you know an attack is going on you
just ignore the honey pots for that
moment and you look for the real culprit
I've put in some links as well the water
works one is chairman the rest is mostly
English and I can can really I can't
figure out that yeah
the awesome list of honey stuff there's
reading more about honey that anywhere
else
so thank you very much for your
attention
yes you are
[Applause]
let's say more abstract therefore more
likely to be related to strategic dating
of money first that's like like chronic
person or money tokens we just need to
understand there's something like solid
that we could use for for starting with
these things I in in the case of how
many persons like don't think so in case
of everything else you should have a
look at the things canary jokes because
that website is really cool they also
sell stuff but you can get a lot of free
honey tokens that you could put
somewhere on emails where you know that
if that email with with that token unity
ever gets triggered then you get an
alert as well the downside to this is
that much of the info goes back to
things so it's not really something that
you have fun
in the case of honey people please also
talk to your management if you give them
a new personal assistant they have no
clue about they tend to get a little bit
upset if you fireman on scene of course
I probably should mention that if you're
doing that then also read the license
agreement or the agreement you have with
linked and of saying whether you're
allowed to do that and decide whether
you care or not questions you're
choosing that guy in the back forgotten
his name yeah I think I probably would
choose the easy path and not put a
honeypot somewhere where it can be
reached from the internet because when
you're getting scanned from the internet
you're getting false positives so if you
put honey pots say on RFC 1918 networks
only and then the attacker will already
have breached you and there will be less
false positives because I think
everything that can be reached
reasonably from sites like children or
Google or something will generate false
positives that's why men you shouldn't
use sites you link to just put the HTML
pages there and usually shown and Google
are not as creative enough to just do
what a human attacker will do great so I
suggest if we can to continue discussion
in one of the breakout rooms there's got
a really tight schedule this afternoon
does everybody know where the breakout
rooms are in case they want to continue
the discussion was step on out of the
room here to the right past the workshop
to the right and right there okay thanks
[Applause]