right now we have Steve we're be up here
talking about from chaos to bliss
so please welcome him to the stage
well that's what eight hundred people
clapping in a room that only holds 300
on a Sunday morning sounds like a whole
day like this
can everyone hear me okay from chaos to
how we solve security in just 20 years
take you back on a journey over the last
20 years to talk about how we
collectively solved this security
problem
oh I have not had all the coffee I need
to have this morning apparently all
right so yesterday I hooked up my own
adapter because this adapter would not
work I may need to do that so when the
technical people suggest that I hook up
my own adapter I'm gonna give it a try
which I got a free thumb I could use a
new one so I think there's a lesson
learned for a growing year so I've been
in the security field about 20 years
since 99 yeah I'm a noob and I know that
if there's something that can go wrong
at a presentation it will so I was so
pleased with myself that I brought my
own adaptor this time and yesterday I
connected it make sure it would work
after the one that was up here didn't
work and the fool that I am I tried the
one that was up here so we wasted a few
minutes any case yeah so I'm the noob
but I look around the room I see some
people they're younger than me so some
of you are probably too young to
remember the primitive antiquated
primeval world of the second millennium
we're gonna be talking about the second
millennium some of you are probably just
new to the world of security I see some
people in the back and I fit the bill
and for some of you others maybe the one
that called me a noob it's possible your
recollection of the last 20 years has
probably just faded a bit
all right
the font seems a little light I'd ask
you if you could read it but it doesn't
really matter what your answer the
question is because I'm not going to be
able to change it okay so let's do a
quick comparison between 1998 and 2018
and you see I made things pretty easy
for you I use some visual cues I have a
red font on the left and a sad face and
a green font on the right and a happy
face by the way there is at least one
person this room who I've just realized
may actually appear in my slide deck if
you recognize yourself I want you to
jump up and shout out so it's not gonna
be for a while so in 1998 it was pure
chaos we had to deal with tremendous
problems like website defacements and
worms lots of worms today we have things
pretty easy we have fishy and crypto
jackin social media hijacking it's not
too bad 98 there all we had four tools
available were passwords firewalls
antivirus and we had documents we call
policies even if they were standards or
guidelines today we have all kinds of
awesome acronyms we have Cass B we have
soar we have a machine learning and AI
or at least those are buzzwords that
security companies like to use and throw
around the claim they have these things
and we have blotching blockchain
something that can pretty much solve all
your problems in 2018 when I look back
in 1998 I remember was a much smaller
security community there were roughly
2000 people in security I knew most of
them there's one older guy here I don't
know but I'm not sure he was around then
today we have roughly three billion
people in info sack and that's a pretty
significant amount of growth over 20
years back in 98 we only had one cert
was the CISSP
some people don't have a lot of positive
thoughts about the CISSP but was the
only one we had at that point today we
have hundreds of certs and back in the
day the senior most people and
Information Security usually had titles
like Network AB
or security guy or they were the guy
that was not in the room during meeting
got tapped to do security
today we have lofty titles like Cecil
and CSO in 98 if you ran into the CIO
and you're in security they typically
would have no idea who you were you were
just that guy that worked in the
basement today the c-suite this the
senior most people whether their titles
are director see ISO are definitely very
well known to the board in the c-suite
they spend a lot of time together in
most organizations and they do things
like strategize in 1998 and this is
really to paint the picture for you of
how much different things were in
ninety-eight there were four cons this
was one of them there was Def Con there
was hope there was Shenmue I might be
missing one or two if we wanted to talk
about security there were three or so
mailing lists in IRC today we have a lot
easier there's literally 1,400 different
conferences there's multiple conferences
on every day of the year worldwide
there's several right now in the United
States this weekend and we have Twitter
if you want to get information there's
your information you have social media
you have slack we have a lot of ways to
communicate it's a completely different
world they're also in ninety-eight we're
very few if any laws or regulations PCI
HIPAA data breach notification laws at
the state level none of those existed in
98 today we have a lot of laws and a lot
of regulations it's even very complex
and complicated because regulations and
laws they are written by nations and
states that are outside of where your
organization might reside will still
potentially impact you based on the
information of the citizens that you are
the custodian of and in 98 we call the
information security now we call it
cybersecurity so I think we can all
agree that we're on solid ground here in
2018 we've pretty much solved the
security problem
right but to a degree it really depends
on how we look at what the word problem
means if we can redefine what the word
is is then we can probably redefine what
the word solution means so finding a
solution basically means finding
something that's causing difficulties
and finding a way to address it or
finding the reason or reclamation for
something if you think about those
definitions it doesn't really mean that
we mitigated all the risk so I like to
interpret interpret solution that way
all right so some of you have a
skeptical look you're questioning this
truth and I'm presenting it to you and
you're probably asking yourself what
makes me a credible authority well I've
been in security for a long time on the
thought leader it's even in my title
that I wrote about 10 minutes ago at the
bottom of my slide also I'm up here and
you're not so pretty much that's really
what it comes down to that's that's how
it works in the security world that's
how it works in the world today in 2018
all right okay I was just kidding a
little bit so really this is a talk
about the last 20 years not a particular
team I'm not looking at this from the
perspective of laws or technology or
people it's just kind of a potpourri but
there's a method to my madness I really
decided to take a look back the last 20
years that the problems we ran into the
things that we did better and try to
figure out what we could learn from that
so what I'm hoping to do today is help
you revisit some things that you may not
have remembered from the last 20 years
or may not have been aware of it all and
I'm hopeful that you'll be able to
leverage that to look at what you
accomplished in your time the security
field what we've collectively
accomplished and think about what this
means as you move forward into the next
20 years all right basically I'm showing
that you probably saw before I said 98
to 2018 well this is how the math works
out I'm gonna start it really 99 because
you don't understand the math here it's
probably cuz it's a Sun
morning ask a friend all right so to
paint the picture that I want to let you
know what was going on in the world so
I'm taking these years two at a time
because that's the way I decided to do
it in the 99 mm period
federal agents went in and took ahold of
Elian Gonzales in Miami gave him back to
his father he ended up going back to
Cuba everybody had to have this thing
called a Furby President Clinton was
acquitted
there was the y2k bug which was really a
whole lot of nothing and there was a
tragic event in Columbine at a high
school and then this dude right here
naked Richard Hatch won the first season
of Survivor alright so there's a lot of
viruses I could talk about because this
was the era of viruses vaanga talk about
one is not as notable and that's a
Pikachu virus and I want to talk about
this one because it's believed to be the
first virus that targeted children so if
you think about this being 18 years ago
the children that were into Pokemon
let's say they were roughly 10 or 28
today so they're almost full-grown
adults they're Millennials so you know
partially full-grown so this really
started a new era because before we
didn't really have to worry about our
children encountering malware but that
was the dawn of the Internet age and
children that grew up in that era the
Internet was pervasive they used email
they accessed the web it's something
that we take for granted today but back
then it was a pretty new thing this is a
pretty naive piece of malware though
what it essentially did is wrote a
couple lines to the autoexec batch file
on windows and attempted to delete a
couple of Windows directories on reboot
it prompted the user do you want to
delete these directories so it's not
believed to have
a significant impact then again it was
children that it was targeting so it's
possible that some of them did click yes
and delete most of their windows
directories other threats that exist in
this time period include the Melissa
virus I love you and cih I love you was
a worm this was a period of worms and
viruses viruses and worms and they got a
lot of notoriety the public got very
concerned and antivirus companies made a
killing off of these forms of malware
cih was pretty interesting because it
tried to do two things overwrite the
first megabyte of the space on a hard
drive which would generally cause the
system to crash will not perform on
reboot and it tried to overwrite bios
and it wasn't able to do that
successfully for all BIOS chips but when
it did it rendered that piece of
hardware useless and required generally
a technician to repair the computer so
it wasn't quite as easy for your novice
user to figure out how to address when
we think today about denial service
attacks one of the first ones that
occurred was in his time period as
performed by a teen in Canada that went
by the name mafia boy and it's not
really known exactly how many computers
he controlled to perform these
distributed denial service attacks but
it's likely estimated it was roughly on
the order of a hundred you think about
that he was able to bring down Yahoo
CNN eBay a few others or some he was
unsex unsuccessful and bringing down but
he only controlled roughly a hundred
computers largely in universities you
think about today the controls that we
have in place in large organizations to
mitigate distributed denial-of-service
attacks I mean certainly there's still a
problem
what takes significantly more than a
hundred computers to send junk traffic
to websites to knock them off the
internet
that doesn't show up that well but
that's a screen shot from the software
back orifice mm it's a the second
version of an administrative tool that
was distributed by the cult of the dead
cow at DEFCON seven personal II think of
it as a rat
it was often labeled as a Trojan some
people argued that it had legitimate
purposes and certainly it could be used
to legitimately manage computers but
that clearly was not the intent with
this particular program one thing that's
interesting and a lot of people don't
remember is that within about an hour at
DEFCON CDC hit burned 20 or so copies of
it to CD this was back when you add CD
ROMs and you burn things to CD and you
had to be careful not to fill up more
space in the CD you could handle they
burned about 20 copies handed them out
other people took those copies and then
burned them to new discs and handle now
and it kind of went viral within a short
amount of time people were reporting
that the cd-rom was compromised and
infected with the cih virus that I just
mentioned well a deal dog and others
from CDC thought that possibly could not
been true it must have been somebody
that had taken one of the discs either
intentionally or inadvertently
introduced the IHS on to the copies of
back office 2000 and that was their
story they got a hold one the original
discs put it into a machine without
checking it with antivirus software I
think this is an awesome story it really
paints a picture of that particular time
because these are hardcore security guys
wrote software like this did really
advanced security research and they
didn't actually run antivirus because
their paradigm was we didn't put the
malware on the CD well long story short
it turns out that the original CDs they
distributed did have cih and they
believed that an individual that they
had asked
to duplicate the original CD to make
those 20 infected those original 20
whiskey ih probably not intentionally
but for me the big lesson there is don't
make assumptions right they assumed that
their CD was clean and it wasn't now in
the complex world of 2018 it's very
important not to make assumptions I
think today that's a very fundamental
one we would not make we would obviously
check our our source to see if it was
compromised check to see if the hash is
matched up to a known hash but that do
not occur in that particular case all
right and these are seven of the members
of loft Heavy Industries a number of
these folks have gone on to quite a bit
of notoriety the one that looks like
Rhenish Brown here Jesus is co-founder
and CTO of error code which was
purchased by somebody and now as part of
CA he has much shorter here now and a
few of the others work for organizations
we know and are still fairly well known
they testified in front of Congress to a
congressman that went on to be a DA on
law and order which is kind of odd and
basically said that any one of the seven
of them could bring the entire internet
down in 30 minutes so I got a tremendous
amount of attention within a short
amount of time loft merged with at stake
and eventually a stake was purchased by
Symantec for me when I look back this
was a critical time period because up
until this point hackers and security
didn't have quite the era of legitimacy
that they did after this and I'm not
saying it was overnight in it happened
everyone went from black hat gray at the
white hat this is one of those key
moments because some of these
individuals cut their hair off and
ensure they were wearing suits here but
that was not a normal thing for these
guys and they need join to cut me
provide
consulting services and security
awareness in doing things that are
pretty mainstream today that was pretty
uncommon back then another interesting
thing that happened this period I'm
gonna spend a lot of time on these two
years and then less on the subsequent
years was that sequel injection was an
attack that was detected or described by
an individual that at that point went by
the name rainforest puppy and it's
interesting he he published his findings
on it very excited on frack but did not
actually use the terminology sequel
injection here's a screenshot from part
of the frack article doesn't mention
what it was actually called at that
point in his article I think I have a
note here oh yeah so he uh he titled his
article NT web technology
vulnerabilities so he didn't actually
call it sequel injection so it's
interesting how things get the
terminology that is pretty widespread
today
he later referred to it as batch sequel
vulnerabilities and I think that pretty
much described what he was observing he
was able to do he's able to string a
couple of sequel statements together and
have both of them execute he also passed
this information on to Microsoft and
Microsoft kind of laughed he actually
did this through a colleague of his and
the word got back to him that yeah
yeah we hear you this is not a problem
it doesn't need to be addressed
so Microsoft's actually come a long ways
I have a lot of respect for Microsoft
today in 2018 they are nothing like the
Microsoft of 1998 but 1998 and I think
that was a big deal sure you could
pretty much take ownership of the sequel
server and do inserts and updates and
deletes and create tables not a big deal
and though he actually published in his
frac article at least a couple of
different ways to mitigate sequel
injection attacks we still have sequel
injection is a pretty large risk today
I think it's lumped together on the
OWASP top 10 now is just injection
because of many kinds of injection and
sure it's been it's solved in a lot of
organizations but you have a lot of
people that I have to move fast or
they're just not security conscious so
even though the solutions are out there
they don't implement the solutions or
they don't know what their solutions are
so even though we had fixes for this for
20 years
sequel injection is still a problem
today that that we're faced with in the
same time period the first Pompey da
Trojan materialized when I thought about
that I found that pretty interesting for
a few different reasons one it took me a
moment to remember what PDA actually
stood for I felt like I was kind of
losing it because there was never a
problem for me did I remember oh yeah
palm was a thing until blackberry came
around and then blackberry was a thing
until Android and iOS came around but
back then palm was a thing the
interesting thing about this particular
piece of malware was that it was a
Trojan that claimed to be a crack for a
piece of software that was emulation
software for I think it was Gameboy to
run on Palm OS the really fascinating
thing about this piece of malware is the
individual that wrote it was co-author
of the software it claimed to crack so
there's a whole backstory around that
and different versions of what his
intent was and why he did that
but pretty odd that 18 19 years ago
somebody created a piece of software and
then create a piece of malware targeting
his own piece of software
the software is called Liberty in case
you want to look it up alright so this
is something I didn't remember until I
started to look into it a few weeks ago
well across that well I knew that
cross-site scripting was something it
originated about 20 years ago what I
didn't know was that Microsoft played a
critical role in discovery and naming of
C of cross-site scripting and so ten
years after their discovery or reporting
of it they disclosed that they had come
up with a number of alternate names for
it and in the security engineers and
Microsoft got together and decided
cross-site scripting fuels like the
right one so URL parameter script
insertion doesn't quite roll off the
tongue as well synthesized scripting
fraudulent scripting not bad names and
so they passed that on to cert and
coordinated that certain did a
disclosure on this particular type of
vulnerability a couple a couple of weeks
ago afterwards they to describe it using
some different terminology and then
ultimately describe it in quotes as
cross-site scripting so if you're
interested in the history of how it got
its name
you can thank Microsoft continuing the
Microsoft theme an individual named
Scott Culp who at one point really was
the public face of security for
Microsoft and I feel bad for the guy
because this was a time period where
Microsoft was just taking a beating from
the security community he published this
ten immutable laws of security and I
think it's kind of fascinating to look
back at it if I was to come up with a
list today these wouldn't necessarily be
my ten that probably wouldn't be at all
but I think most of them still hold true
with the exception of a couple of them I
would say for me
it's number three if a bad guy as
unrestricted physical access to your
computer it's not your computer anymore
sure that's hypothetically true and I
understand understand that hardware
could be modified but for your average
consumer and your average organization
if encryption is in place and we do
threat modeling then in general this one
is not as true as it was not anywhere
near as true as it was 20 years ago the
other one for me that I get a little bit
of a chuckle out of is number eight and
out of date virus scanner is only
marginally better than no virus scanner
at all today I think most of us can
probably agree that signature based
antivirus which is what existed at that
point maybe with some things claiming to
be heuristics which really weren't is of
nominal value today and typically you
probably would consider not even
architecting your organization with that
kind of technology it's one of those
things that's kind of hard to make the
case to get rid of it's kind of like
back in the day you went with IBM
because no one ever got fired for going
with IBM it's very hard for most people
to exercise a political capital to say I
want to turn off AV though I am aware of
a number of organization of the people
I've been doing that over the last few
years it's still not that common so for
me those are the two that really stand
out he updated this list five or so
years after that didn't make a lot of
changes I think he changed antivirus to
anti-malware but you know a lot of this
does still ring true today
and so you can look at that a few
different ways maybe we haven't
accomplished a whole lot or certain
things are just really pervasive
all right moving on to 2001-2002 lore
the Rings came out 9/11 happened Michael
Jackson was still alive and almost
killed his kid dropping him off the
balcony of a hotel he didn't do that
find our energy that didn't exist before
that he had a drink a thing called Jolt
Cola or just caffeine pills we invaded
Afghanistan and honestly I didn't
remember Neopets I guess it's still
around but Neopets at this point in time
at that point in time was the fourth
most trafficked website on the internet
Google was number 12 Flash was extremely
pervasive in 2001 2002 gonna kind of cut
to the chase here there was an issue
reported in flash and macro media's
response so Macromedia owned it at the
time Adobe went on to purchase it
Macromedia response was it's simply a
software crash it's not a security issue
and flash is a constrained environment
by design you would never get the virus
to work well if you remember anything
over the next decade or more after that
there were constant vulnerabilities in
Flash that were being exploited it was a
constant race to upgrade machines in
patch and put in workarounds in there
were days so this was a pretty
enlightening piece of information but it
really is a sign of the times
Microsoft Adobe Macromedia and others it
was a common response no big deal that
thing ate of vulnerability it's not a
security issue it's a crash as a
performance issue turns green blue won't
do anything bad it's not like it's
taking Social Security numbers
so you've a little bit more flavor of
this time period interbase was a
database package that I had a compiled
in backdoor with the username
in the password correct right so Ola
stop ten came out in 2003 it's had a
number of iterations since then thinking
most recently in 2017 gets rejiggered
around there's a lot of political
infighting kind of takeaway here is boy
a lot of these vulnerabilities are risk
because they've changed the terminology
have persisted over the last 15 years
sure some of them were renamed and
combined or split apart or removed just
because certain people were sick of
seeing them in there and who's gonna pay
attention if it's the same ten every
three years we got to throw something
new in there but it's not something that
involves all that rapidly all right
there's a sort of the peak roughly the
peak maybe a couple years later of worms
and viruses we weren't as creative with
coming up with names of malware back
then you know today you have to have a
logo you have to have a slogan there'll
be hell to be paid if you don't have a
dot-com domain with it so probably at
least a day has to be spent concocting
all that back then you didn't do any of
that usually the person who wrote the
piece of malware came up with a name and
if the AV companies gave a different
name they were pissed off and wrote a
new version and had a bunch of
back-and-forth but hey Code Red was
named after a pretty new mountain dude
wreck and nimda was admin spelled
backwards so I thought hey that's pretty
cool cross-site scripting we think about
today and a lot of exists there's
different forms of it one of the
earliest cross-site scripting incidents
involve hotmail before was bought by
Microsoft
it was injecting JavaScript into the
from field of the sender and to get that
execute all that had to happen was the
user that received that email had to
open up their mailbox they didn't have
to hover over that email they didn't
have to click on it then
to do anything the rendering of the
sender in HTML with the JavaScript when
they open their mailbox caused that to
execute that gives you an idea of the
state of security at that point of time
I mentioned before there were mailing
lists one was called full disclosure
existed for a long time then went
dormant and then restarted a couple of
days afterwards a few years ago back in
the day they were unmoderated semi
moderated and moderated lists for
sharing information it's it was a
different world than exists today and I
think that's an important thing to
consider now whether it's threat Intel
or anything related security there's a
tremendous amount of information
willingness to share we probably have
more of a difficult time finding
information its current accurate and the
the best information to use but
previously there were only a few spots
that you really had to look obviously
there were smaller private communities
but it was not as diverse and readily
accessible as it is today yeah so that
is one of the things that's changed
right so when we when we think about
what's changed there are a lot of things
that are good and bad that changed too
right we talked about encryption
encryption we weren't able to do
encryption for a long time because of
export laws that limited limited the key
strengths our ability to use encryption
outside the United States Bill Clinton
eliminated most of that I want to say
that was in 2003 2004 I don't cover that
in here and now we kind of take it for
granted that encryption is free there's
millions of encryption certs that you
can get off of free services that was
not possible back in the day it was very
difficult to implement very costly so a
lot of things have changed both for good
and for bad
we we know today there's a lot of bug
bounty programs
and third parties allow for reporting of
vulnerabilities then they will then
share with a vendor I defense in this
time period was either the first or one
of the first independent programs they
would pay individuals for reporting
vulnerabilities and then they would
coordinate that response with the
affected vendors tor was something that
came out in this time period and moving
on 2003 to 2004 we had a space shuttle
explode Trump at a TV show Paris Hilton
was famous for a lot of bad reasons Ken
Jennings won a bunch of games on
Jeopardy and we invaded Iraq and that's
how I sum up those two years well then a
really great tool came out Metasploit so
before Metasploit there are a bunch of
independent scripts I wouldn't say it
took a lot sophistication to get a hold
of scripts and exploit vulnerabilities
but there was not a platform that was as
readily available as was the case after
a Metasploit came out with plugins
allowed other people developed
additional exploits and and this entire
platform was built up if anyone could
easily download and run follow some
simple instructions and it really
reduced the barrier for individuals both
with positive intent negative intent to
compromise and exploit vulnerabilities
and I think we have a lot to owed to
where we are today to HD Mor HD more
Metasploit and all the other individuals
that were involved in Metasploit in the
early days and it really drove the
concept of pan testing and the ability
to perform offensive attacks on
organizations to test their security
posture up until this point though we
didn't really have a lot laws so many
organizations didn't want do anything
because they were compliance focused
well yeah we understand it's the problem
but we're here to make widgets and won't
happen to us and we have other things we
need to spend our money and resources on
California where we are today was the
first state to implement a data breach
notification law involved personally
identifiable information like social
security numbers
his licenses and names the way it was
written meant that a large number of
organizations in other states were also
impacted because they had customers or
records of individuals in California so
this started a whole downhill snowball
effect where other states began creating
data breach notification laws
interestingly I think the 50th state
didn't do so until either earlier this
year or last year there were three or so
holdouts the last four or so years but
California was the one who really paved
the trail in the same time period HIPAA
came out was it security rules PCI came
out with its data security standards and
you know is that point there was a whole
lot of compliance that organizations had
at least start to consider at least
those that were impacted within a few
years there was hardly an organization
wasn't impacted some degree and so that
was that was really what led to a lot of
change it was kind of slow change but it
led to a lot of change in the field
information security for these two years
there were a lot of worms sequel slam
are so big they all kind of run together
you can look them up if you don't know
them all right so moving ahead a little
bit yeah truthiness was a word there was
this guy that was a meme this guy died a
couple guys retired there was a flood it
was a humongous deal and then the VP
shot his buddy accidentally so that's
what those two years were all about we
take for granted now where we are from a
oh s int perspective but Johnny long was
pretty instrumental at raising awareness
of the concept of Google dorks or Google
hacking he came out with a book and it
became very popular to perform searches
on Google to look for information it is
something we still do today it's not the
only search engine we use we moved on
from search engines to other
applications to perform the same types
of tasks we do
they're things to create puppet accounts
and get access to data in other ways but
we're mining publicly accessible or semi
publicly available information and the
attackers are doing it the defenders are
doing it too and this was an early point
where this was occurring backtrack was a
platform debian-based had a bunch of
security technologies on it and morphed
into Kali which pretty much anybody on
the offensive side security uses today
if they're not using it there quite the
contrary in in the same time period
there is a guy last name and Chetta he
was the first person charged with
controlling a botnet he had about a half
million computers under his control so
we're talking a whole lot more than
mafia boy with his hundred and he was
sentenced to five years in prison I
don't actually know how long he served a
lot of these people that were sentenced
to these prison terms end up serving in
quite a bit less than what they were
sentenced to you so 2007-2008 where
things really got interesting from my
standpoint because iPhone was released
Android was released and ow oh my god
there's mobile cloud had already existed
but cloud was starting to become a big
deal we had Rick rolling a couple of
fast guys in the Olympics Obama became
president and since we're in the like IP
a capital of the world here I would be
remiss not to mention this was a time
period where there was a worldwide hops
shortage hops became very expensive you
cannot make beer without hops well
really can't make IPA without hops so
this was kind of a big deal and so at
this point many people and I'll say I
was one of them I fought mobile I fought
BYOD I thought cloud I'm like well now
to secure this we can't do this yet well
damn that was a mistake a lot of us made
that mistake if we look back that was
something that set us back at least five
years because we didn't recognize that
that was a freight train that was coming
it was going to happen in I say no
repeatedly just took away all of our
credibility
we've been better positioned
to acknowledge it something that was
coming find ways to test it small inform
the stakeholders about the risk and get
our asses in motion to figure out
solutions that's not what we did
probably in my mind the biggest failure
in the history of information security
it was that time period before the DB IR
I didn't really think a lot about most
security publications that came out from
security vendors by the way I work for a
security firm now so I'm saying this I'm
not pointing a finger as any one
particular but let's look at more like I
have a lot of admiration for the folks
at Verizon together the DB IR because
they pull together a tremendous amount
of information got other orgs to share
information did awesome analysis data
science great visualization present the
information a really usable actual way
and within a couple years got the point
where if you were in security you waited
for that day the DVR came out and you
wanted that and your executives wanted
it and that's where we are today and all
the guys maybe all of them that were on
that team I think have left and gone on
to some very interesting roles but we
still have it here today and it's really
set the bar higher for others that are
producing reports and publications it
it's a you know definitely a different
tier than it was before that point you
could get in a lot of trouble if you
posted this short string of information
the NP double a and double-a CS would
come after you so a lot of people posted
it and it just kind of got out of
control this was also a time period we
knew that federal agencies and others
were surveilling us but a published
affidavit came out revealing that the
FBI was tracking the source of an email
bomb threat via a program that was
uncertain to exist confirmed their
spyware capabilities and quite a few
other things came out over the following
two years that validated that this was
occurring so it wasn't like we waited
till Edward Snowden to go oh yeah whoa I
didn't I didn't know about this I talked
in 10 years before the fact
2009-2010 Kanye and Taylor Swift had an
awkward moment the iPad was released the
vice presidential candidate invented a
word repudiate I thought that was no no
it's like a mash of refute and repudiate
and who might be like refugee 8 and she
said that Shakespeare coined word so why
couldn't she Tyler Tiger Woods had his
mind on other things besides golf
Lindsay Lohan was having troubles and
and there was a big oil spill Barnaby
Jack meant to give a presentation in
2009 to blackhat and he wasn't able to
give it he gave in 2010 did a couple of
exploits of vulnerabilities one remote
one requiring physical access caused a
bunch of fake money to spit all these
machines it was pretty awesome if you
were there and you know it was a real
threat it affected financial
institutions and if you look even over
the last few months there have been
incidents involving people exploiting
ATM machines eight-team machines getting
the spit out money and they coordinated
and you can make a lot of money doing
this he was involved in this research he
was an early researcher in medical
devices unfortunately he left this earth
prematurely five or so years ago but I
have a lot of admiration for him and in
the trail a paved show dan was a thing
that showed up about eight nine years
ago it was a search engine for computers
that was a little different it's it's a
huge deal today you can find the
Internet of Things in physical
facilities and webcams and everything
under the Sun using it and it does a
fantastic job surfacing a lot of issues
and the media runs with it I think it's
fantastic and it's run by a team of one
or at least at least I believe is a team
of one all right we're getting closer to
today a bad guy died and another bad guy
died we killed a bad guy
she's singing a song about six feet
under something party rock was in the
house tonight and oMG lol entered the
Oxford Dictionary
yeah that's pretty legit then a couple
of platforms launched to allow people to
earn money by finding bugs in companies
services where they were quite happy to
pay money to have this happen and there
were bug bounties before this kid Nima
Soros from Microsoft set up the first
one a Microsoft she later went on to set
up on it or with a with other people at
the Pentagon you know way they weren't
really a prominent bug crowd hacker one
and some others have really led a lot of
organizations to set up bug bounty
programs some earlier than they probably
should and has made it so that people
can earn a living
performing bug bounties now it's harder
today because there's a lot more
competition and you may find a bug as
somebody already found but this is now a
very pervasive thing today that's not
going away five years back the
government shut down we all know about
Snowden there was a Malaysian plane that
got lost a bombing at the Boston
Marathon and Isis surfaced and Taylor
Swift that we saw earlier she's like a
stage security individual that has a
Twitter presence for the last five years
and that's a lot of really profound
things that people cheer out she has one
hundred two hundred thousand followers
she has one hundred two hundred thousand
followers she runs a site called decent
security which is pretty good for
consumers and I'm actually aware of some
corporate organizations that use it to
coordinate their fishing takedowns and
reporting of malicious URLs so yeah
Taylor Swift she's doing a lot for the
community already mentioned Katie
sometimes she has pink hair sometimes
she does not
Krebbs used to work for the Washington
Post he got fired probably the best
thing could have ever happened to Bryan
because within a day started up Krebs on
security and pretty quickly he started
breaking huge stories like the target
data breach from the Home Depot data
breach in having awesome conversations
with Russians and the cyber Underground
who would tell him about other
competitors of theirs to get them busted
and vice versa and then they'd get mad
at him and SWAT him and since watch
means to his house and so he's had to
move and take a lot of steps so that no
one can really find where he is that's
the downside that's the downside of the
situation but he's done a lot to get
information out about security incidents
and so he's played a really key role in
security over the last 20 years all
right getting closer we found water and
ice on a couple of planets and moons
took worldwide extreme poverty below 10%
eliminated rubella in the Americas and
then we're able to observe wavelengths
of gravity to validate Einstein's theory
so a pretty awesome F in time it's been
all this great stuff and then we came
out with these amazing contraptions you
could ride without a handlebar but they
caught on fire and mattresses that you
could roll up and have shipped to you
and that's I mean you got to have that I
mean mattress is that you can roll up
right and so there been a lot of
security companies like the last few
years they have had these crazy ideas
like hey that's new and so they get
Series A funding or seed funding and
it's just not really a viable idea or
you don't really know what's going on
behind the hood there was cool
visualizations and everybody loves it
and I'm not really sure exactly what
happened to Norse I know the CEO wasn't
quite sure what happened when they media
asked him hey what happened here cut me
but they had this a really cool map and
did things and then a couple of guys Bob
Brutus who used to be on the Verizon
Dvir team and Alex Pinto a big data
scientists through some code up on
github and you can build your own now
and then threat but came out and it has
one you come
look at it's really cool and Asheville
and useful and then there were some
breaches like the Democratic campaign
the me2 movement some dictators Elon
Musk's smoked pot in California Elon
Musk twenty other things
Putin Trump and it canceled two Broke
Girls hate that show I just want to see
if any would you laugh of that
apparently not nothing happened in two
thousand seven two thousand eighteen so
we'll move on from there
and actually so crypto jacking became a
thing and then that kind of moved to
cryptographic leverage it leveraging
your computer to do crypto jacking
taking your CPU and GPU to use it to
mine coins so you think about this like
it was pretty quick that it went from
ransomware which is still out there
still effective to that because the
economics were such that it's easy just
to switch and move to that model there
were some free tools made available you
didn't have to have any sophistication
you just grabbed some JavaScript code
stuck it on your website stuck out on
websites that weren't yours and made
some money renting other people's
computers out that they didn't know
about big advances in OPSEC I think are
gonna happen soon if you think about the
the GM of the 76ers he has some fake
Twitter accounts posted some things some
attribution was done it turns out was he
a man or his wife and he lost his job
why people are like all about the
blockchain now I'll like thing about
like this if all you have is a hammer
everything looks like a nail
yeah I'm not sure everything is going to
be solved by blockchain if you have a
different theory talking to you after
this presentation I'd love know what
your theory is so these guys circled
around 20 years later earlier this year
went back to Congress you know look
little Club more cleaned up have gray
hair and talk about the state of things
so that was it was kinda nice alright so
kind of cut and wrap things up so we're
kind of resetting things to zero right
that was the last 20 years we have the
next 20 years so maybe we haven't solved
everything over the last 20 years
I really do believe we've made
tremendous progress there's been a lot
of rapid change on the business side
technology side threat landscape we
continue to and we will continue to
encounter lots of friction resource
constraints and all kinds of other
challenges that's the way it is we're no
different than any other form of risk
management whether it's safety or things
that deal with pollution or anything
like that it's the same thing those are
just fuels that are 100 you know 50 100
200 years older than us we're in our
infancy still we have amazing tools
commercial and open source the hard part
now is figuring out like how do you how
you integrate them do you reduce your
your vendor portfolio and go with less
best-of-breed
how do you get these things to work
together but a lot of organizations are
realize if you're gonna sell a tool to
somebody you better have a really good
API because people aren't gonna buy it
so you know we have some interesting
challenges in front of us I think it's a
really really awesome time we still
don't have a good handle on IOT
especially in the enterprise even large
organizations manufacture IT to IOT you
don't have a good handle of it you know
those that are Krauts were still don't
know what they're doing at all so that's
not gonna be a problem for us we got on
the containerization bandwagon grew fast
realized this train is gonna happen we
better not do what we did when clown
general came out so we were in ok shape
will continue ization but serverless has
hit us and we're not really doing a good
job there and so we should ask ourselves
like what we can learn from the last 20
years and and what we can do differently
we're not gonna have control over
everything but you know really the best
we can do you know when faced with these
complex changes is it do what we can
control
don't hold on to the paradigms of the
past I know there's probably still some
of you in the room that still believe
you have to have an eight character
complex multiple composition password
that you change every 42 days and you
better memorize it not write that down
and it has to be unique and not like the
one before come on now that's not that
doesn't work that in work 20 years ago
I've been telling people for like the
last 15 years that I
mine in my wallet I say it's good enough
for my credit cards why isn't that good
enough for my password sure there's a
attack vector or threat scenario where
somebody could get me hit me over the
head there's a comic strip about that
but if I'm dead I don't care that's
somebody else's problem if I wake up in
an alley I'm gonna go change my password
so not that big a deal for me so a lot
of this information was sourced from
today and InfoSec which is a twitter
account that i and the custodian of if
you're not familiar with it you'd like
to know about things that happen on this
day or we're announced on this day in
the year past check it out
and yeah emoticons that's all I have for
you I appreciate your time thanks for
having me here at torque on
[Applause]
[Music]