so next up we have a pretty cool talk if
you give a container capability and this
is a tale of container exploitation by
Vikas Kumar and Rob Glu please give them
a warm welcome
[Applause]
all right hello everyone I'm Rob glue oh
this not go on
all right we're good there we go all
right so I'm Rob glue this is Vikas
Kumar this is our talk if you give a
container capability we are basically
going to be going over what makes a
container container what security
boundaries I put in place to keep things
separated and where that tends to break
down in actual container deployments
just a quick blurb about us we are both
security consultants at NCC group and we
do hacker things but let's just get
right into it so this is just sort of a
high-level overview of what we will be
going over for this talk we're gonna go
basically we're gonna start with a
process that is just running completely
uncontained and we're gonna just start
with sudo process one sudo process two
and then add one layer at a time and
sort of explain what protections get put
in place at each at each layer we're
gonna give a high-level summary of how
these protections are actually
implemented in real container solutions
and where it sort of deviates from the
ideal then we're gonna sort of outline
how you check for these things if you're
just a consultant or someone who just
gets dropped in a container and you want
to sort of figure out how you might be
able to get out or mess with the hosts
and other contain processes and finally
we are going to release a tool to sort
of help check with all the things that
we go over so quick intro to what a
container is in case you're not already
aware containers are lightweight
alternatives to virtual machines and so
the idea is that you have a container
running on the shared kernel with the
shared kernel with the hosts and other
containers on the machine so that you
can sort of run different flavors of
Linux on the same host and this is done
over using like a full virtual machine
because for a full VM you need to run an
entire another kernel on top of your
host kernel which obviously has a good
chunk of overhead now sometimes
containers are used as a security
boundary so for if like for example your
cloud provider and you want to have your
customers run arbitrary code you might
say let's just run it in a container
because it'll be a lot faster and it'll
be much better and finally these
containers will allow your processes to
run as route or what appears as route to
them but still be heavily restricted and
what they can do on the host so another
quick summary of what these protections
that were going to be going over are we
have basically pivot route to make these
processes think they have their own
dedicated file system we have
capabilities to limit what sis calls
someone can make set comp to limit that
even further and then we'll add
namespaces which sort of restrict what
resources a process can actually access
and then there are other random
protections that are not as significant
but still don't hurt so for our sort of
theoretical situation here we are sort
of looking at this from the perspective
of a cloud provider who wants to run you
know customer code and you know these
customers need to have all the access
possible they need to have root access
they need to touch all the system file
systems they need to be the only process
running on the host well from their
perspective they need to perform some
sis calls that may or may not require
root privileges and our theoretical
cloud provider is going to say we're
gonna use containers to sort of keep
these things separate obviously some of
the customers might be malicious and so
we want to make sure that there are
enough protections to keep one customer
from going in and stealing all the data
belonging to other customers so this is
just sort of a visual representation of
what we're working with we have two of
our tenants and they are you know both
have access to system resources they
have access to the kernel CPU memory
network file system etc and so what
we're going to start out with is our
naive approach where we just run sudo
tenant one sudo tenant two obviously
this has tons of problems they the two
tenants have access to each other's data
they can kill each other's processes
they can pee trace each other they can
access the full house file system they
can just
generally wreak havoc and you know so
this is the exact opposite of what you
want to do here because all the problems
we worry about are a problem here
so the first step we're going to take is
to make these processes think they have
their own file system so we use pivot
route for this which is sort of very
similar to a CH route but it basically
provides a more separation and so the
intent of this is to create our custom
route file directory that will put our
container our containing process in so
in the example on the right here we have
you know an example at sea SSH config
setup so on our host we create our slash
new route and then we put a fake let's
see SSH SSH config into it then we call
pivot root and then according to the
contain process it just sees that etsy
SSH SSH config you know at root so what
this perfection or what this protection
does is it lets us convince our contain
processes that they have their own
dedicated filesystem so when we create
this new file system we set up all the
system files we provide everything that
the process needs in order to do in
order for it to look like it's like a
full Linux system so when it comes to
real containers they just do this they
use pivot root and create a new mount
namespace and they use pivot root over
stay true because it doesn't have as
many security guarantees and this combo
basically just disassociates the process
from the hosts file system so and then
while it sets everything up the
container solution will copy relevant
files into this this new new file system
so if you are a hacker just dropped into
a container you want to look around for
files that were explicitly included in
the container solution that should not
have been in so this is things like
access tokens SSH keys you also want to
take a look to see if there any devices
mounted from the host so if they mount
like a whole file system that contains
some sensitive files you might be able
to modify bad things on the host and
another thing that you want to check for
is if you're checking out a docker
solution you want to look to see if the
docker socket is available anywhere
and so the docker socket is a UNIX
domain socket that's used to manage the
docker daemon on the host and
occasionally someone who's creating a
container and running their own software
and it wants to have their software
communicate with the docker daemon and
obviously the most straightforward way
is to just include this socket within
your container but being that this is
the domain socket that's meant to be
used to manage docker itself there's a
lot of very dangerous things you can do
with it and it's essentially just free
root on the host and so if a developer
provides the docker the docker socket in
your container you can just use it to
get a free escape so while this is a
good start and our different processes
can actually run on the same machine and
not stomp on each other's files
it really doesn't stop malicious
processes in any way our contain process
can still make any syscall at once and
so there are numerous ways for it to get
direct access back on like the direct
access to the hosts file system which is
obviously bad because if they get access
to the hosts file system they can modify
files and escape again
and so while things run it's there's
still a lot of things that are contained
process can do and so the next
protection that were going to go over
sort of limits what sis calls a
contained process can make and can be
used to sort of mitigate the effects I
guess so in Linux the root users
permissions have been split off into
finer grained capabilities this includes
like the ability to bind services to
privileged ports or perform mounts for
example this allows you to run processes
that need some level of root access but
not full root access for example you
could run TCP dump as non-root by giving
it the capabilities net wrong net admin
which allow it to sniff packets etc
so if you need if there's a process that
supposedly needs route you should find
out what specific capabilities it needs
and drops everything else drop
everything else it lets you have a root
user or root process that can't actually
do everything root can do so how does
this work in practice
a real container solutions drop many
capabilities on like during the
initialization of the container and the
way this works is they drop them in a
way where they cannot be regained
through normal means specifically
there's this thing called the capability
bounding set which we'll get to like
more detail later but basically what it
does is it says these are the max amount
of capabilities that this process could
ever have and let's say you run a set
UID root binary you won't be able to get
more capabilities than what are in your
bounding set even though it's a set UID
root binary um sometimes in container
solutions like dangerous capabilities
are granted such as decreed search
sysadmin and others listed these are
essentially free escapes in that they
let you call dangerous sis calls that
let you affect the hosts and game code
execution or file access and there's
other dangerous capabilities like net
wrong net admin while they don't
directly give you a container escape
they let you perform network attacks and
lastly um there's this notion of
privileged containers such as in docker
which essentially gives a container all
the capabilities and these are trivial
to escape and you shouldn't do this so
let's walk through an example of how we
can use one of these capabilities to
escape a container let's say we're given
the dock read search capability dock
read search is a capability that lets
you run the syscall open by handle at
which lets you access files or
directories by inode number instead of
path because we're in a pivot root we
can't actually see the hosts um root
directory but we know it's ID no number
is 0-2 so we can use the open by handle
at syscall to get a file descriptor to
the the root directory on the host and
opened my hand a lot syscall basically
takes three arguments first is a file
descriptor to something on the target
file system and the reason you need this
is if you're referencing something by
inode number you don't necessarily know
which file system it's referring to
because if you have multiple file
systems many things should have I know
number zero two so you have some file
descriptor two something you know as
from that file system and then you have
the second argument is basically a
struct that's a wrapper around the inode
number and the third argument are like
flags which is how you deal with weird
cases such as your if you're trying to
get a handle to something that's a
symbolic link or something weird so once
you call this open by hand a lot you
have a file descriptor to the root
directory of the host and you can just
see eight root into it and now you have
full file system access so let's say
you're dropped in a mystery container
how do you find what capabilities you
have you can check what capabilities you
have with the status file in like proc
one status or proc self status this will
have a numerical representation of a
number of different capability sets and
the two you really care about our cap F
which is the effective capabilities and
cap B and D which is the bounding set of
capabilities the effective capabilities
are the capabilities your process has
right now it's what you can currently do
and the bounding set is like the maximum
capabilities the process could have
through like normal privilege escalation
means such as like running a set UID
binary or a set cap binary so we've
successfully limited what the root user
can do by dropping a number of dangerous
capabilities but let's say one of our
tenants needs something that's just
admin can do they need to be able to
mount something in specific but we don't
want to give them all of society because
sysadmin is a capability that gates a
large number of sis calls it grants too
much power so we can use set comp to
limit the syscalls even further this
allows you to block sis calls on a
persist call basis and you can also
block sis calls based on the arguments
passed to that sis call this both can
let you like grant dangerous
capabilities and limit what they can do
but all
so act as a second line of defense if
you somehow escalate privileges and gain
additional capabilities so how does this
work
at a low level this uses the pr CTL
assist call which has like two relevant
modes one is the strict mode which
creates a set cop sandbox where the
thread can only call read write and exit
on this this is like a very good sandbox
but this isn't what's not this is not
what's normally used what's normally
used is second mode filter which allows
you to create a Berkley packet filter to
restrict sis calls and arguments the SIS
calls so what's the birth what's a
Berkley packet filter a Berkley packet
filter is basically VM inside the Linux
kernel that runs this weird bytecode and
it has like a number of uses and that
could basically be its own talk but in
short it's one of the things that
enables is second PPF you can create
bytecode that filters syscalls based on
the SIS call or the arguments of the sis
call all of this is wrapped by Lib set
comp which allows you to create second
policies in like a more human readable
format and like human configurable so
how does this work in practice a lot of
container solutions will have a default
set common profile that may or may not
be actually useful for example Dockers
defaults account policy um automatically
grants exceptions if a capability is
granted to the process for example if
your if you gain the doc read search
capability the second profile will no
longer block the open by handle at Cisco
which kind of defeats the purpose of
being defense-in-depth the logic behind
it is the doctor developers were like oh
if they're granted this syscall we want
it to just work by default we don't want
like to have users struggle or
developers struggle with creating custom
set comp profiles but sometimes when
you're trying to do things set comp will
block what you're trying to do is so
developers will write a bad custom
profile or just turn offs comp so how do
you check your set comp profile if you
dropped a black box into a container
this is difficult one thing you can do
is just enumerate all your Siskel's and
just like do them and see what gets
blocked this will tell you if like a sis
call is explicitly blocked or not but
you won't be able to necessarily find
rules that block sis calls based on the
arguments because bhoot forcing all the
potential arguments that are allowed or
not it's difficult so ideally if you're
pen testing a container solution you
just ask your client really nicely to
give you the suck-up profile another way
you can like add defense-in-depth and
limit what the root user can do is
mandatory access controls this includes
selinux or a Parmer these are both linux
security modules and they restrict
resource access by applying security
context applications or processes
programs and they can limit like very
narrowly what files on like even the
container file system a given process
can access in addition like a Parmer
could block certain or all mounts it
could deny network access and it can
even like redundantly restrict
capabilities so even if a capability is
provided to a container and app armor on
profile could be like the backup and
block the capability so in practice a
lot of the times SELinux or app armor
are not enabled it depends on kernel
version like your container runtime
version and there's a lot of
inconsistencies which will cause su-
drop Armour to just not be supported you
can check your app armor profile from
within your container by looking at this
on outer current file within the proc
file system you can also check your
selinux profile dynamically with LS
Capital Z or outside the container you
could look at the selinux rule set what
the shown path so we've greatly limited
what the root user can do we've limited
their capabilities what's this calls
they can perform but there's still a few
issues here um one is that they have
unrestricted access to consume CPU and
memory resources potentially be
performing denial of service of other
processes on the same host also because
like
Hauk and other system files are mounted
or put into our pivot root fake file
system it's possible that we could still
influence or see or kill other like
tenant processes in addition there's not
really a restriction on network access
both to the like host network interface
and to other containers services so the
next protection we're going to be
putting in place will limit what
resources are contained process can
access so this will keep our contained
process from interacting with the host
processes or processes in other
containers and this is done through
namespaces which is a feature exposed by
the Linux kernel that allow you to sort
of put processes in various groups that
will only let them access resources that
exist in that group so for example a
process namespace will only allow your
if your process is put in a process name
face you can only see other processes
that exist within the same namespace and
so this is what allows our contained
process to think it's the only thing
running on the system when it's actually
not and so there's other namespaces that
allow this sort of segmentation so for
example network namespaces will only
allow your process to access network
interfaces that are in its own namespace
and so this is what allows you to keep a
contained process from interacting with
the host machines network interface so
you just like create a custom interface
for your containers and you only allow
processes in that network namespace to
access that one interface and then you
can have pretty good control over the
traffic that goes through it
there's also mountain namespaces which
only allow you to see devices that are
mounted in that namespace and this is
what's combined with our pivot route to
provide a separation from the hosts file
system there are also user name spaces
which are a bit more complex that we'll
go over on the next slide here but it's
worth noting that for all of the
capabilities the numerated here if you
are granted enough capabilities or sorry
for each of the namespaces explained
here if you are granted the right
capabilities you can just get around
everything
so like processed namespaces Network
namespaces amount namespaces don't mean
anything if you grant the contain
process too much privileged user names
places however are more complicated than
the other namespaces that we went over
so not only do they just only allow
users to interact with other users in
their namespace it also drops a large
number of capabilities and heavily
restricts what sort of sis calls you can
make and how you can make them so the
goal of this is to like once you add
process to a user namespace you can only
exercise capabilities on resources that
are explicitly in one of your resource
namespaces and so for example if you are
in a network namespace you are only
allowed to exercise your net raw
capability on your network two
namespaces it also drops any
capabilities which which are used with
resources that are not associated with
any namespace so for example sister IO
which lets you directly mess with your
the memory of the machine is just
blocked altogether because there's no
namespace which manages the resources
that that capability grants access to
and then finally user namespaces do what
the name suggests in that map it lets
processes running in the user name space
only see you know makes it let's the
process think that it's running it as
UID zero and is the only user on the
machine while outside of that user
namespace the host machine is aware that
it's running as like a higher privileged
user sorry a higher user ID user and it
will perform appropriate security checks
on that so when it comes to real
containers the best approach would be to
just turn on all the namespaces however
when it comes to actual how things are
actually done the container solution may
or may not turn on all the namespaces so
for example docker by default doesn't
have user name spaces enabled and as you
know we spent all that time talking
about all the protections that user
namespaces provide and it you know is
able to provide protections
you grant too many capabilities it
doesn't let you touch anything outside
of your your namespaces docker just
doesn't have it enabled by default and
it can be kind of a pain to get set up
if you are a developer so as a result
developers may or may not actually do
this and so when you are dropped in a
container you want to sort of poke
around and see what namespaces you have
so another alternative for using like a
user name space would be a developer
might just run the process in the
container as an unprivileged user but if
the user gets UID 0 somehow so either
through running a set UID binary or
something along those lines they would
be running as the actual root user and
have all the capabilities that were
granted to that contained process but if
they do ask like to UID 0 they'd still
be restricted by capabilities set comma
mandatory access controls so now is a
good time to sort of look at the what
you can access through the network if
your contained process so docker by
default has all of the containers on a
shared namespace so the containers can
all talk to each other and if they have
sufficient capabilities they can perform
network attacks on each other so for
example doctor grants net raw by default
and so if you're on a default container
configuration you can just sort of
perform these some network attacks on
the other containers that are running on
the host if there's no name spacing you
can just attack the host directly for
those capabilities but you also should
consider what your container can
actually access on the local network so
if you have other internal resources
that are accessible from the server
running the containers you can still
dial out and hit all of those so when it
comes to checking for all of these
namespaces it's generally there's you
can quickly heuristic Li check and guess
whether you're in a namespace or not so
for process name spacing you can just
look in the proc directory and if you
see a whole bunch of processes that look
like they're running on the host you
know process name spacing is not enabled
and you can you know collect data about
those processes that are running in the
host so you can get like what
command-line arguments are passed to
them and that sort of thing the
scientific way to check this is to run l
stat on
Proc 1ns PID and if you get a device
number greater than four it means it's
namespaced
for use the namespaces you can open up a
file which lists all the mappings that
are used for your user name space so in
the example here it maps user ID 0 to
the user ID 0 which means there's no
name spacing enabled if it is enabled
you would see for example that the user
ID 0 is mapped to some high number UID
and that would be the UID if the process
is viewed from outside of the user name
space for network name spacing you can
similarly do a heuristic where you just
do ifconfig or look at this class net
and just see if any of the interfaces
look like it's probably on the host you
can also L stat prop 1 and s net and if
the device number is greater than 4
you're in a network namespace mount
namespaces you can here asically look at
proc self amounts to see what devices
are mounted from the perspective of your
process and then you can also do the
lsat trick on that as well so now that
we have all these namespaces we have our
pivot root we drop capabilities we
implemented of SELinux profile or a
primer profile and it's almost there and
we more or less have our contained
process and our contained process can't
really hit much outside of its container
and it's fairly limited in how it can
attack the host so the next thing we're
going to go over is sort of how you
limit denial of service attacks because
we don't want one process to just chew
up all of the resources and sort of
choke out the other processes so this is
done through C groups it's a system file
system and so you can just go in and you
know look at how much resources you're
allocated one thing that is sort of
counterintuitive is C groups also limits
what character and block devices you can
access and so you if you you set up are
like a C Group device whitelist so that
any process in the C groups in the C
group would only be able to access like
Devi random and Devon all or something
like that and it would it's a second
line of defense if
how they get a handle to dev SDA you can
just yeah so when it comes to checking
this out if you're dropped into a
container you can just read files that
will tell you whether you have your CPU
shares limited you can also read a file
that'll tell you your maximum memory
that you're allowed to use and if it's
some absurd number like 64 gigabytes you
can probably safely assume that you're
not limited at all and you can just
choke out anything else that's running
on the machine when it comes to the
device whitelist you can go through the
devices that list file and it will list
like a what it's a big list of devices
that are a device type a major number
and a minor number and this is you can
basically use a reference table to
figure out what type of devices points
to so for example Devi random has a
specific you know it's a character
device and a specific major number and a
specific minor number and so if you see
that in the white list file you know
that it's you're allowed to use Devi
random dev Nell has like a different
major minor number etc and so when
you're dropped on a container you want
to look at this list file and see first
if everything is allowed and then if
it's not you can just sort of go through
item by item and see what devices you're
explicitly allowed to access and so this
is pretty much there we have a very
controlled process that thinks it's
running his route but it can't actually
do anything it can't access a whole lot
outside of its own namespaces they can't
directly interact with each other's
processes like our tenants are you know
separated we've limited what Network
attacks can be performed on the host but
there is still like a handful of attacks
that you should consider when you set up
your container so one thing to keep in
mind is the core basis of containers is
that all the containers on a host share
the same kernel as the hosts so if you
have a kernel exploit you can like free
escape the container mess with the host
to mess with other containers etc this
is greatly limited like the attack
surface
the colonel is limited by mandatory
access controls set comp like limiting
what sis calls you can call capabilities
again limiting what's this calls you can
call see groups also acts as a kind of
defense-in-depth mechanism for example
if there's a potentially vulnerable
device driver with some character device
with some like vulnerable I octal
handler see groups might limit you from
even talking to that device driver and
exploiting it but it's important to keep
in mind that older kernels may not fully
or properly implement all these security
measures we talked about so it's
important to keep your kernel up to date
so let's say you find a privilege
escalation in the kernel version that's
running you have some way to go from a
low privilege user to route how do you
turn that into a container break out
like a normal issue payload in a like
kernel exploit will be to prepare kernel
creds and then commit them and what this
does is this like replaces the cred
struct associated with your user process
with one that gives you UID 0 gives you
all the capabilities it disables Linux
security modules which like turns off
SELinux and app armor it also disables
user namespaces but it doesn't actually
give you full file system access
immediately for that you need to change
the FS struct associated with your
process however we have the previous DAC
read search exploit and because the
normal exploit will give us the DAC read
search capability we can now just use
that exploit get the handle to the host
file systems root directory CH root into
it and now we have full file system
access of for the host another thing you
should keep in mind in a container
solution is check if you're on
kubernetes kubernetes runs like multiple
different API servers to manage
everything there's like at CD which has
an API and its stores like the cluster
configuration information there's a
cubelet api which is used to like manage
hosts and pods and the kubernetes api
which is what kubernetes administrator
will talk to to like actually configure
their kubernetes cluster an environment
each pod will have a service token which
can be used to authenticate to the
kubernetes api with a service account
and sometimes the this token gives high
privileges in the kubernetes api and you
can use this for essentially a free
container escape you can just tell the
kubernetes api hey spin up a privileged
pod which will have all the capabilities
with the whole file system host file
system mounted readwrite and that's just
an easy escape another thing is that the
cubelet api can have unauthenticated
remote code execution this essentially
gives you like code execution within a
pod and you can kind of chain this with
the previous thing gain code execution
within another pod steal their service
token and try to escalate privileges
that way in addition the HCD api can
sometimes be an unauthenticated and you
can use that to directly modify
kubernetes state and configuration and
kind of related to this you should also
check like what Cod environment you're
in on if you're in AWS can you hit the
AWS metadata service um if the host that
you're on has in and like I am instance
role like assigned to it there'll be I
am credentials present in the AWS
metadata service and you could steal
those if that acts that like network
access to the AWS metadata service is
not limited also sometimes like um
things like chef or puppet will put in
its scripts or like in its certificates
or secrets in the user data portion of
for example AWS metadata service and
container on a host could just steal
that user data and steal those relevant
secrets so we wrote a tool called Khan
machi which is basically a go tool
statically compiles into a binary you
just drop it in a container and it
collects a bunch of information for you
it checks capabilities it Flags
dangerous ones it looks for mounted
volumes it looks at your see group
policy it looks at all the namespace
configuration it sniffs the network to
find out the like IP addresses for other
containers in the host so you could
attack those and it's still in
development we're continually adding
features like kubernetes scanning etc to
it we're open to feed your suggestions
it's to be released
TM so keep an eye out on the NCC group
github for it we're just wrapping a few
things up and going through like our
internal tool release process so now for
the demo so here we're launching a
singularity container singularity is
like another container runtime like
docker and we'll run our tool here and
it's like enumerated a bunch of
information like the Linux kernel
version which we can use to try to find
exploits it detected that the runtime is
singularity enumerated the different
capability sets it found that oh there
might be some potential hardware attacks
on the host it could be vulnerable to
meltdown inspector it's noted noted that
set comp is disabled in this container
and that there's not an app arm or
profile in addition it's noticed that
user name spacing is not enabled it's
listed all these different things that
are mounted from the host that could be
potentially dangerous that we'd have to
investigate it also like note
specifically what capabilities in the
bounding set that could be dangerous if
you get UID 0 and then it notes that the
container is not using process
namespaces so just to sort of wrap
things up from the perspective of a
developer it's worth noting that
containers are much better than nothing
so if your choice is run your stuff in a
container versus just run it straight on
the machine you will want to use a
container because it's security measures
that you wouldn't normally have then you
want to go in and make sure that your
solution enables all the namespaces if
you're using docker make sure you go in
and explicitly enable user namespaces
because that's sort of the big one that
provides the most for you don't grant
random capabilities to your container
don't mount random things in the
container copy stuff instead don't run a
privilege container
don't give your kubernetes pods service
access container and i'll also consider
what your container can access on your
network so
if you're running on a cloud provider
make sure or at least consider that your
docker container may be able to hit the
metadata service and think about what
sort of information exists in there if
you're running it in like a data center
or something consider what other servers
the container might be able to hit
if using docker dropped in at raw
capability which is enabled by default
and if you're using something else
consider what capabilities it grants to
your process and if just drop anything
that's dangerous
ideally drop everything if you don't
need any sort of root permissions
basically just be aware of all the
security controls and make sure they're
all flipped on but if you're a pen
tester this is sort of a short cheat
sheet of what you should be checking for
look at what your you ideas are you UID
0 what your capabilities are any of them
dangerous
what namespaces are enabled and be very
aware of if user name spacing is enabled
because that shuts down a lot of your
attack surface even if you are
explicitly granted capabilities check
for anything that's hosted mounted from
the host and see if any of them could
potentially be system files or other
files that might be read by processes
outside of your container look for the
that includes like looking for the
docker socket look at your C group
policy see if you can just you know chew
up resources if you feel like it see if
that what devices you can access look at
your kernel version and if you have
something super out-of-date see if there
is just some easy pone where you just
like drop it in run it and just get root
because if you're running on an old
kernel there might be some old exploit
for you to get root and just escape from
there although you might have to modify
your payload to a little bit in order to
turn into a container escape rather than
just a privilege escalation look at what
you can hit on the network scan things
sniff traffic that sort of thing and
then again just poke at your metadata
services I think that's it if there's
any questions
all right thank you very much
[Applause]