all right next up we have Yoona Colonel
apocalypse by Spencer Michaels and Jeff
DeLeo please give him a warm welcome
hi I'm Jeff and this is Spencer
we work for NCC group we doing consider
consulting and we're here to talk about
some intern research that Spencer was
doing last summer under my sort of
auspices basically we first and foremost
I'd like to mention that all
vulnerabilities we're going to be
discussing in this talk were disclosed
prior last year and some have been fixed
in some heaven for various reasons but
we defined vulnerability here to be an
issue that it may itself be exploited or
any failing of any security protection
or mechanism that was intended to be
there so what are what are you Nicole's
you know Colonel's are these specialized
applications that bundle all of their
application code and resources into a
single binary that runs is a bare metal
VM where the entire application stack
runs in kernel space and what could go
wrong they're intended as an alternative
to sort of full VMS and Linux containers
and so they the thing above them is the
hypervisor where in containers the thing
above them is the kernel and then maybe
a hypervisor on top of that they have
they reimplemented components so they
tend to have their own network stacks
written potentially from scratch in a
different language than one might be
accustomed to and they're very
specialized and sometimes you can port
code to them easily and sometimes you
can't so why look at them basically
there are very new technology and they
might you know I don't think they're
going to completely replace containers
or anything like that but they
definitely will probably find a niche
that they fit well in and they're being
looked seriously at by people to make
things like cubes OS more secure and
anything that people are doing to make
cubes more secure is definitely worth
looking at especially since some of the
security claims from the people writing
these things are really kind of don't
make sense and don't add up and then
there was this blog post by Brian
control from Sun originally who wrote a
blog post basically saying that eunuch
Colonels were unfit for production
because they were impossible to debug
that last part was very prescient as
well we'll find out so there are a lot
of claimed security advantages to Yuna
kernels things like there's no
unnecessary code that you know if it's
not used it's not compiled in because
they link the whole thing together
there's no shell so if somehow an
attacker got remote code execution they
wouldn't just be able to do Ben SH and
they'd be just out of luck
you know they can't they're not
reconfigurable they're completely
immutable if you want to change anything
about them running you have to just
rebuild the whole thing and reload it
and that there are no sis calls only
function calls so so therefore attackers
need to know the memory layout to do
anything so all of these are basically
completely false on their head the
unnecessary code thing even if they were
talking about dead code optimizations
that's not really true in general and
there are a whole bunch of unit kernels
that add in a whole bunch of modules of
code that may or may not be used by the
application code that sit there the
shell doesn't matter binary level you
know you can you can you should write
shell code for things if you get a
buffer overflow if not if you're in a
higher level you know kernel save
running nodejs and you get like an eval
I'm fine running JavaScript if I need to
you know so I'll do that instead of Ben
SH the reconfiguration stuff will find
out that you know kernels are very very
not immutable and some of them even take
like yeah mo configs on the fly or take
binary uploads and just hot load them so
that's just not true and this is calls
thing it's that's just it just doesn't
mean any it's just not even wrong so our
hypothesis is that Yuna kernels may in
fact reduce attack surface by throwing
out a lot of you know the garbage system
D but you know there's that that alone
doesn't make things more secure the rest
of it has to actually be secure too so
once someone gets in though there's like
no process isolation like you don't need
route you are the kernel you can you can
send you can craft arbitrary packets do
disk IO speak PCI to whatever
godforsaken floppy disk is emulated and
given to your VM you know things like
that so back we were doing this we
started out looking at the low-level
stuff with the
intention to go higher and look at all
of the re-implemented application stacks
like networking stacks and things like
that and we just kept finding things in
the lower-level parts so so that's
primarily what this talk is about so
things like do these unit kernels do
address space layout randomization which
is a protection against code reuse
attacks so which memory regions and
sections have randomized base addresses
do they have page protections things
like DEP or an X that you might be
familiar with so if the pages are
read/write/execute that's probably bad
weather or not relocation read-only or
rel Rho applies in many cases it doesn't
which is a protection on dynamic linking
so that the sort of tables of function
calls that your dynamically linking once
they're loaded they're not going to be
then writable as function pointers for
as an exploit primitive whether or not
their guard pages between the sections
so those are gonna mean that you have a
page or a section between your sections
that is not read write execute at all
and such like a continuous buffer
overflow that goes straight into it
would hit a page fault trap and the
whole thing would die without letting
the exploitation continue and then
things like the null page being mapped
so with the no page it's a bit different
in you know kernel world in the normal
world where people think of kernels and
user space those attacks are about
attacking the kernel from user space by
doing shenanigans with a null page
that's that's not we're talking about
here so in the you know kernels if
someone writes Linux tile
malloc code and therefore doesn't check
null because VM overcommit never what
causes it to never return null it always
returns essentially valid pointer and
when you run out of memory the om killer
just kills your process so they never
check null but in embedded sort of
systems and things like you know kernels
it can return though but no it may very
well be a valid writable readable
address and so if no one's checking know
when malloc returns and multiple things
use allocations from malloc that
returned null they're now sharing the
same section of memory and it's
essentially used after free so that's
interesting
stack Canaries are they used are they
gonna be initialized directly are they
gonna be filled with proper random data
keep pardoning is there pointer
validation is there good entropy for it
are the allocations randomized the
Canaries are they good where does the
entropy
come from is a good entropy is the RNG
itself cryptographically secure
is there any reuse of things in
deterministic ways that are going to be
bad across multiple VMs on the same
hypervisor and standard library
hardening things like your percent and
format specifier custom format
specifiers for format strings may lead
to insecure implementations in the Lib C
itself where there's like write a
section of writable memory that just
contains nothing but function pointers
or even potentially code and whether or
not they support or even use fortify
source so our first target was rump run
it is an interesting research target and
it's fairly well known you know kernel
in that circle and it's based on net BS
t's rump kernels which were designed
back in the day so that when you were
writing your kernel drivers and they
crashed they didn't just take out your
system because there were really VMs at
the time that were in use so what they
would do is they had a very sponge of if
deafs
all throughout the net bsd kernel code
base and they still do that allow you to
essentially take the entire kernel of
net bsd and link it against some kernel
driver code or application level code
and run it in user space as a standard
binary so when that thing crashes your
whole system doesn't go with it rump run
flip this on its head took all that
magic linking in if def magic and then
threw it back into kernel space to run
POSIX applications in in you know kernel
space our next target
always include us it wasn't originally
our next target but while we were doing
this a blog post came out claiming that
they were the most secure thing ever and
it was written in C++ and those two
things didn't necessarily add up so we
decided that we would look at it and
then miraj OS fairly well-known in the
circle and anyone who uses cubes is an
eunuch kernel that is primarily used for
writing Oh camel so that you can write
secure services you know camel since its
type safe and memory safe for the most
part but it also has a CF Fi and some of
those components are written in
low-level code so they need to be secure
as well so we looked at how that was
being protected and then the the next
target that we have which is actually
next on the list and we haven't gotten
to it yet is OS V which is a unit kernel
focused on high performance but also
other
things like being able to run the entire
JVM in ring zero so you can have your
vulnerable Java Enterprise web
applications running in kernel space you
know XSS and kernel space sequel
injection kernel space the world is your
oyster and so we're gonna be looking at
that soon enough so I'll hand it over to
Spencer okay so let's get into the gory
details and gory indeed they are so
we'll start with rump run which is a
64-bit yoona kernel it runs on KVM and
Xen as well as bare metal
we tested on Xen because that's mostly
where people are running this so
Rembrandt has a POSIX interface with the
exception of threads and a few other
small things so basically you can run
most POSIX compliant apps with very
little modification sometimes none
supports all these languages
interestingly it also comes with a
separate repository of a bunch of
packages like Apache and nginx that
basically just build on out of the box
on run they've done this weeks already
but these look sort of like POCs it
doesn't seem like they're updated I'll
get to that in a bit
basically the wave are imprint is
constructed is as Jeff said it's just
like the the net bsd kernel and they
strap that on top of Xen mini OS which
is an operating system that it's very
minimal it basically just does
everything by making calls to the
hypervisor so if you want to make a para
virtualized guest on Xen your best bet
is usually to just build it on top of
mini OS so rump run doesn't have any a
SLR it saved a little bit by LD which
we've taken here to calling the poor
man's a SLR basically what that means is
if you're linking in slightly different
code or like if you know you make a
function slightly longer it's gonna push
stuff down or LTS gonna put stuff in
different places so like if you don't
know the underlying code of a binary
then you don't know exactly where
everything is but you can often make a
reasonably decent guess and if you know
the code of course it's all
deterministic what's interesting too is
because this is running as a pair of
virtualized guest Xen maps the hyper
call page into the very very early on in
the memory space so it turns out you may
even be able to use that to do Rob but
it seems like there may not be enough
primitives we just found that recently
we're not actually sure of the full
impact it doesn't really have any extra
page protections the tech tech section
is not writable but data stack and heap
are all rwx there's a little bit
of protection that the null page is not
our WRX but there are also no guard
pages so you know you can just say Stack
Overflow into the heap or something like
that
there are stack Canaries only in a very
sort of edge case if you happen to get
lucky so the core make files of rump run
actually disable it so like rump run
itself is never gonna have stack
Canaries if your compiler happens to
turn them on by default in your
application code that's built separately
and then linked in so your application
code might have it now the random canary
value is generated at runtime properly
using the bsd sysctl crypto api's but it
turns out that because rump run doesn't
have thread support they didn't
implement thread-local storage of course
and GCC expects the canary to be stored
in and retrieved from thread local
storage so it turns out that the canary
even though it's generated correctly it
turns out to be no in practice it's just
eight no bytes on the other hand if you
have up to eight store copies that will
save you from that but anything else
you're on your own the heat protections
are pretty negligible the allocations
are deterministic and contiguous and
there's no pointer validation of any
kind there are Canaries in the heap and
page chunks but they are a compiler
defines and B they're not even
positioned correctly in in in the one
case where where it actually has a null
byte in that define so essentially
they're completely useless if you want
to exploit them
Jeff will talk about the entropy
situation stares right so rump run and
the ROM kernels have an interesting
system where they have a whole bunch of
if deafs and for some reason when you're
building rump kernels the if deafs
basically mean that your are dear and
your cpu rng is disabled even though
that's not a privileged instruction they
could totally could have run that as a
user space binary so rump kernels rump
run using the same if Deaf's
suffers from the same flaw it basically
has no cpu and our cpu rng so it
completely falls back to the vm uptime
and cpu cycle count which are so
deterministic and how this thing starts
up that essentially at start every time
you are getting the same exact random
values out of dev you random which is
spooky
it's
a little bit by the fact that net BST is
sort of complicated has all sorts of
other entropy sources so anything that
you printf which I'm not sure why you
would do on a unit kernel running on AWS
but if you printf something that output
will feed into the entropy system Mac
headers from packets that the system
sees will get added in although those
are probably gonna be you know pretty
much the same values back and forth on a
sub on a given subject between the the
you know kernel host and the Gateway and
then the host uptime which is also known
to all guests on the same hypervisor the
RMG itself is this sort of weird sha-1
thing that actually has a whole bunch of
code in a code comments saying that it
hasn't actually been like audited or
anything so that's we haven't looked at
that but this is all access to the
standard and fbst ways of doing it so
the bsd sysctl syscalls
and also the virtual file system sets up
dev random and Devi random correctly for
all of this okay so the center of the
library is implemented with BSD from our
sorry with Lib C from net BSD um and
that supports percent and doesn't
support custom format specifiers it does
support fortify source and actually the
net BSD like core make files will turn
that on to the highest level but then
the top level run pro and make files
will turn that off again for debug
builds and it turns out if you use the
like rump run build tool chain and
scripts it will always give you debug
builds and there's no flag to disable
and it just sort of does that silently
so if you if the average person is
building a rump on this is gonna be the
case it also has sis calls almost so
they're not triggered by an interrupt
but there's a function called rump sis
call which you I mean basically acts
just like the regular sis call function
arguments and all and the first 24 bytes
of it when we looked at it and all the
run burn unit kernels we generated are
unique so you can scan for this very
trivially as soon as you get RC and then
just fire off as many sis calls as you
want in addition to that to get initial
RCE the sis call table is a really good
target because it is populated
dynamically on startup and then it's
left in a writable state in addition of
this rump run basically the build tool
chain takes a sort of image config that
tells it what libraries to link into
your final unit kernel and the default
is about twice as many modules as we
could get it to build with
so
they're talking about like reduced
attack surface they don't emphasize that
you need to prune this config down so
reference heap implementation is is kind
of interesting they have a basically
it's it there are two major primitives
which is a memo like chunk and a page
chunk the men mallet chunk basically
represents the chunk of memory you get
back when you actually malloc something
and that the two important fields who
are aligned pad and magic magic is the
canary and you'll notice above it's
unprotected is a line pad and what that
does basically it's the amount you have
to subtract from the base pointer to the
memo Alec chunk to get up to the page
chunk above it and the page chunk has
level which is just like a metadata you
can very easily guess and magic which is
a canary but it's four bytes that are
not null so you can and it's in a
compiler defined so it basically doesn't
exist and the next in previous you can
use that to perform the classic on link
bug there's a lot of details about this
if you're interested to look at the
slides but we're not gonna reiterate
like all of malok malefic arm here
because it's basically just classic on
link so if you want to exploit the rump
run heap but basically what you have to
do is get an overflow in a heap chunk
onto another heap junk that'll later be
freed and you just need to overwrite the
first eight bytes the mhm align pad
field such that when it's when that
value is subtracted from the base
pointer of that chunk that you are now
corrupting it points back to a fake page
chunk in your overflow buffer that
you've written out and make sure level
and magic check out that's really easy
and then just set the next in the
previous pointers however you want to do
a write there is a caveat of course with
this kind of exploit that the value that
you're writing must itself be a writable
address otherwise it's going to cause a
crash on the second right although you
may want that actually as we'll show in
a little bit so basically rump runs
security situation is not good there's
no SLR
everything but text and null page are
rwx the canary situation generally
speaking they're not going to be any and
if there are they're pretty useless the
heap is not really protected there are
Canaries but they don't do anything
in practice the entropy situation is
also weakened particularly if you're
attacking from another hypervisor guest
and while a standard library supports
hardening it's explicitly disabled and
you may be thinking
well here he overflows basically in rump
run they will give you our RCE
under pretty much any circumstance
especially if the attacker has a source
code or binary but sometimes even in
cases where you don't because you could
attempt to brute-force the addresses you
need because while they are not you
won't necessarily know where they are
they're not random you basically like if
you know roughly what's what's in the
rump run image you can guess pretty well
where they are and by the way varmints
also completely unmaintained as of just
a little before we started researching
it last summer basically right now they
only updated every few months to like
add compiler flags to disable new GCC
defaults that would make it more secure
but actually break the old run code so
that's interesting and at this point you
may be thinking well what could possibly
be worse than what I've just said and to
this include us says hold my beer so
include us as a 64-bit yoona kernel that
unlike run front is pretty specialized
it's exclusively for C++ services
particularly web services
it runs on KVM and VirtualBox and vmware
but it's primarily developed for and
tested on linux KBM now it's worth
noting here before I go into saying all
I'm going to that include us the version
we looked at is from summer of 2017 so
they have likely fixed some of the stuff
we're talking about given that it's
actually maintained it's probably more
secure than run run at this point but we
haven't actually gone back to check but
before I talk about what I found in
Rumford let me explain a little bit
about how I actually found it because it
turns out that debugging in include us
is like really really really difficult
in fact I suspect that the include us
developers probably have not ever tested
include us running as a yuna kernel be a
rather debugged include us running as a
yuna kernel because it turns out the
boot script they used to do that doesn't
even have a flag to enable the gdb debug
bridge it's trivial to add but the fact
that it wasn't in there is kind of
suspicious if you compiled binaries with
debug symbols and then actually run them
as include I'll see under kernels
they'll just crash on startup most of
the time and we figured out a way around
this which is like if you run the non
symbols version and then attach gdb and
then load symbols from the symbol
version it actually doesn't work either
most
the time generally it'll die with a CRC
mismatch error and we don't even want to
speculate what what causes this if you
manage to get past this which again just
happens sort of randomly breakpoints
also don't really work you usually have
to just start the guest paused and then
like insert jump zero instructions and
then manually put the original bytes
back when you're ready to continue it's
not good so having gone all through this
rigmarole we find that include us
basically the ASL our situation is
exactly the same as from from but what
makes us more embarrassing for them is
that in that include include haces
secure blog post the CEO mentioned that
include ah scrote randomizes address at
each build and it seems like he's just
confusing the linker with like the
normal linker behavior with compile time
a SLR which include us definitely
doesn't have um he also says it include
us is immutable it's it's not it's like
the most mutable anything can possibly
be because every single page of include
us is rwx so you can I mean literally we
actually we didn't have a full POC for
this but we got far enough to realize
that you could probably like inject your
own tcp/ip stack and then like load a
new include ass image on top like into
an existing include us and then start
running that it's pretty terrible as you
can probably expect there are no
additional page protections either there
are no guard pages and even the null
page is mapped rwx you get the use after
free sort of thing that Jeff was
mentioning the snap canary is they're
certainly more prevalent than in in in
rump run but it's not particularly
helpful so they use f protectors F stack
protect are strong in the core kernel
and also they like application preamble
C make files so everything's gonna have
stack Canaries
but the canary values our compiler
defines that are generated randomly by
the like C make random string function
which is really low entropy not
cryptographically secure and that C make
list that builds it is in like the core
of include us so only when you rebuild
it include us the main image itself does
the canary get regenerated so all of the
images you build against one build of
include us are gonna have the same
canary and it'll persist across restarts
so actually you can just brute-force it
pretty easily especially given how fast
it restarts after crashing and by the
way the thread-local storage bug from
rump run pretty much for appears for
verbatim here so just ignore everything
I said the Canaries are actually
the heap doesn't have any protection at
all it contiguous allocations
deterministic no Canaries no point of
validation nothing so the entropy system
is actually one one thing that included
us did fairly well so it just uses
already ran for everything it does some
cpu feature detection to detect if it
has it if not it falls back to cycle
counts but modern CPUs is not going to
be a problem the art actual orangy
applied on top is basically they took
the internal sponge function out of
ketchup
which is fine that works and but to
access the RNG they actually the way you
just open up Devi random or dev random
and right at the beginning of their open
implementation they actually just stir
Kuster compare every single Slyke string
path that's passed in and just literally
just check if it's dev random or Devi
random and then they return you a magic
file descriptor that goes to the the RNG
the interesting thing about this is that
in the middle of when we were looking at
the updated it a little bit because it
used to be at the the magic file
descriptor was number nine nine eight
but they never actually checked if when
they were incrementing file descriptors
elsewhere when they were returning new
ones whether or not that collided with
the magic one and so if you opened up
enough files eventually one of them
would just be dev and 'm and not your
file that you intended to use but they
they later fixed that so the standard
library from that they're using for the
sealy standard library is Red Hat's new
Lib which was designed for embedded
systems and has basically no security
whatsoever as much like other other
things that they provide so it's got
percent and no custom format specifiers
probably just because of space and
complexity constraints and embedded
environments and has no support
whatsoever for a fortify source alright
so we'd like to bring your attention to
this point the very first sentence of
this include oz post says that it was
written with security in mind we'll let
you decide so probably the most
egregious thing the include us project
did was they decided to throw it all all
sort of knowledge about how memory is
supposed to be laid out for applications
and kernels and things like that
so in the include Oz world the stack is
in low memory followed immediately by
the text section followed by data
followed by heap in high memory and so
if you if you see anything odd about
this you remember that when you have a a
buffer you write to increasing addresses
and so what this means is that if we
have a buffer overflow we can actually
just continue past the end of the stack
right into the text section start
overwriting the code and if you're
really lucky the the actual copy loop
that maybe it's it's you know mem copy
store copy some for loop you know that's
gonna be early on and short enough so
that your buffer overflow will be enough
to actually hit it and so when you
overflow the actual you know move
instruction that's implementing that's
performing the buffer overflow you don't
want to use an OP because you know much
like your your buffer writes code
execute down but it increments the the
IP address so basically you actually
want to use jumps that go backwards in a
chain until you go all the way back to
the start and then run your shellcode
going forward and as our demo shows if
you're not that lucky
well you're still pretty good because
include us the way that it links code
together it puts basically all user
application code right at the beginning
of the text section so even if you can't
get you know mem copy when mem copy
returns it's just gonna return right in
your shellcode and it's never even at
your and ideally your shellcode doesn't
check the stack connector is that canary
just don't do that
where's the yeah so we have a demo that
basically we just break on mem copy and
then on the end of it we have to run
through a couple of them because they're
using the upright bring up of include us
and then we just start stepping it and
you can see us stepping through our
reverse jump chain as we like to call it
extreme not slop sledding until we get
to the very start of it with the final
jump and have our actual shellcode
that's a little bit complicated it
prints out you know hello torque on xx
the only reason this complicated is
because I wrote it so that it doesn't
have any no bytes in it
okay so as Jeff said the include us all
the low-level stuff is implemented with
new Lib this is about as insecure as it
sounds it is basically just vanilla
unlink again if you want to know about
this either
like consultant melech malefic arm it
applies verbatim so basically with a nun
link because of chunk coalescing in free
if you corrupt a chunk you can you can
write one two three pointers anywhere
you want so I do you chain this to RC
turns out that to include us has a panic
handler called on panic which is just a
function pointer that if it's nonzero
it'll get called when the OS crashes
like say on a page fault you can
overwrite this now of course if you want
to jump back into your your code in a
heap overflow the heap in fact it's
actually really deterministic you might
know where it is but for the sake of
argument let's suppose you don't know
what you can do is since you're
corrupting a chunk you can induce a
crash inside free and of course at that
point the pointer to the chunk that's
corrupted is going to be on the stack so
what you can do is use the first write
via unlink to point the panic you
overwrite the panic Handler and then
point it at some any known writable
location which is everywhere because
it's include us it also needs to be
executable actually and then use the
second write to write eight bytes of
shell code to that location and what the
shell code needs to do is just increment
RSP up until it's pointing at the
address of that buffer on the stack and
then it calls ret and then that we're
just returns into your buffer and that's
great but there's one more problem which
is that the again new Lib is made for
embedded devices so it's trying to save
space in the way that the malloc chunks
work is that they're part of a linked
list of course when they're free so they
have forward and back pointers when
they're allocated they don't need them
so the buffer starts from where the
forward pointer is so because this the
chunk that gets that that gets passed to
free that gets unlinked first forward
and back at that point need to be
pointers to valid writable addresses
otherwise you're gonna crash too early
but then you return back into it and you
return right to forward and so forward
and back actually also need to be valid
shellcode and the the eight bytes of
shellcode we have doesn't have enough
space to actually increment anywhere
beyond that so we thought this was gonna
be really hard maybe impossible till we
looked at the first instruction
in the include US binary we're looking
at and it appears to be an 8-byte not
that also happens to be a writable
address so thanks clang we have a demo
for this as well oops so here we have a
vulnerable TCP server with a buffer
overflow on the heap and we assume we
don't know the size of the buffer
overflow so basically what I'm doing
here is a sort of exponential back-off
where I'm just sending bigger and bigger
buffers seeing where it crashes and you
see it four starts really fast so it's
great for brute forcing and basically we
are finding the distance to the next
heap chunk header so we know how to
corrupt it and then we're going to use
that to just write to progressively
greater address addresses incrementing
just about like one pointer length
each time and in just a moment it's
going to loop it's going to find the
panic Handler and there it Sprint's at
our address or sorry our message so
include us there basically aren't any
protections with the exception of like
really half-hearted Canaries the ASLR
that there's no ASLR everything's our WX
Canaries are constant across reboots not
cryptographically random and also
they're no all the time the heap has no
protections at all the entropy is
actually ok except for the NSA case and
the standard library doesn't really have
any hardening at all so basically
include us like it doesn't have any
security features like if you get any
kind of memory corruption or like even
just look at it the wrong way it's
you're gonna get RC now in a better note
we have Mirage OS which is an oak Hamel
based unit kernel and what drew our
interest to it is basically it's
intended to be used probably in cubes os
to create these secure minimal attack
surface VMs and in that case it'd be
running on Xen so it supports both KVM
and Xen but we tested it on Xen just
because that seems the most interesting
for this use case and because of renzo
camel it also supports FFI so you can
you can call native code from the Oh
camel and basically the way that it's
constructed is pretty much like rum from
you take the O camel runtime and you put
it on top of Xen mini OS although they
have their own Fork which has just a
little bit of differences so you might
be wondering why would you use o camel
because it's like sort of an obscure
functional language basically the
argument comes down to
that it supports like also
object-oriented programming and
imperative pretty recently but it's also
reasonably memory safe not as much as
something like rust but it's if you're
doing just like regular oh camel things
it's it's you're gonna be fine you're
not gonna run it like a buffer overflow
or anything although it turns out that
vanilla Oh camel does have support for
some operations that are distinctly not
memory safe but if you're writing normal
Oh camel you'll be fine right well no
not exactly
okay ml has some pretty bad cv ease and
you know this one we're pointing to with
the arrow is a 10 that actually is not
applicable to you know colonel because
it uses environment variables but the
top one is a memory corruption that
absolutely would be useful to us
although we haven't done a POC there's
also a spooky library called Marshall
which is for D serialization and if you
basically like specify the wrong type
quote anything can happen at runtime the
only limit is yourself welcome to
zombocom yes so much like include us we
were having quite a bit of trouble
debugging mirage now because right now
mirage only supports running as a para
virtualized guest on Xen and it turns
out that there are no devote good
debuggers for Xen para virtualized
guests and by no good debuggers I mean
literally there are no debuggers for
para virtualized guests on Zen there is
VM Ida bug which is really nice it's
it's modern it's Lybia my based it's you
know supports lots of nice nice things
unfortunately none of the things we are
looking at it only runs with Linux and
windows h vm guests and Miraj obviously
is not linux or windows or h vm there's
also checks which comes packaged with
Xen and it's like a gdb server basically
but it goes downhill very quickly like
if you look into the codebase you
realize it's using these gdb SX branded
syscalls specifically implemented in Xen
40 DB sx and it seems like after a while
I realize this is probably because the
Xen developer 2 documented their vmi and
debugging API so badly that like they
couldn't find them later and so they
just said oh screw it we'll implement
the syscalls specifically for this it
can also only do peak poke so it also
supports reading registers theoretically
but it doesn't speak the gdb Remote
protocol well enough to talk to either
gdb or LD be when it sends registers
so basically eventually I realized that
using these as a nightmare and it's
actually easier just to go and write my
own debugger so I did I call it the Zen
debug and Jeff's calls it the Zen bag
and I kind of don't like that but it's
stuck it uses this time the correct Zen
debugging and vmi api's which I had to
basically hunt down myself and dissect
the implementation because like wow good
luck if you're like even you're looking
for like the comment at the top of the
header file that tells you what it does
no those are like not they are most of
the time it right now it has its own
repla which works pretty nicely but even
more functional is the gdb server it
it's it's like it's a stub gdb server
and by gdb server I mean lltv server
because it turns out that gdb doesn't
actually speak its own remote protocol
to spec and I'm not gonna deal with that
honestly so right now Zenda bug supports
paravirtualized guests and it can read
and write registers in memory and do
breakpoints and stepping and right now
we're trying to work on getting memory
region info so you can like read the
page tables but it turns out that Zen
actually doesn't have an API for this in
paravirtualized guests so it's gonna
take a little while so I've got a demo
of this as well whoops and right now on
the bottom right we've got a simple
Mirage OS yoona kernel it just prints
hello I'm a test every second a hundred
times and we're gonna run it in the
bottom left and then start Zenda bug
with up with the port one two three four
open and we'll stop the guest
automatically and here we see it's it's
this is actually the syscall page it's
stepping through instructions it follows
the ret even and here we're going to now
search memory for the string hello and
then write a magical value into that
area and then continue and we should see
it's now printing our message fabulous
whoops okay so my OS same SLR is the
same situation as the other two it's
basically like you know public code
yields deterministic binaries the
paravirtualized page thing with rum run
is is also here because it's running as
a pair of virtualized guest as well
what's interesting is that Oh camel has
a pretty big runtime and of course
that's all written in C at some point so
most of the Oh camel runtime is going to
be like deterministically ordered and
placed it like a semi
random like a location that you won't
know necessarily so if you can find any
part of oh camel you probably know where
the rest of it is and you may be able to
do something with that the page
protections are just like rump run text
isn't writable but data stack and heap
are all rwx the additional page
predictions are actually good they've
pretty much done everything that they
should they have unmapped or guard pages
it's hard to tell because we can't
inspect PT's yet between at least the
data data in stacked sections and then
stack and heap and the null page is
mapped but not our WX that's good and
railro again doesn't apply because all
the linking here is static there are no
snack Canaries
so unlike rump run and include us it
doesn't even try here they're explicitly
disabled in the Mirage OS like Cormac
files and then when you use the build
tool chain it also disables for your
application code even if even if you're
like GCC turns it on by default the heap
doesn't have any protections at all with
the exception of a little bit of pointer
validation so it's implemented with X
malloc from any OS and so the
allocations are deterministic in
contiguous there are no nono sort of
like heap or page chunk Canaries
unlinking small chunks has pointer
validation but most code paths don't and
I have a POC for an unlink bug just like
I showed you with include awesome so the
entropy situation is interesting because
there are two packages you can use for
entropy they don't really specify which
of them is good and they really should
because one of them is great and one of
them is terrible the terrible one of
course is Mirage random which is a
wrapper for Oh camels random module
which is not even cryptographically
random but that aside the way it
initializes itself is it gets a seed
from dev you random but because there's
no file system and it like doesn't do
any special casing like crimp run or
include us opening Devi random just
returns one and in fact literally the
implementation for open is just to
return one it will then fall back to the
PID and PID so like parent PID as well
as get time of day but the first two
don't exist because there are also no
processes on you know kernels those are
just hard-coded to return two and one
respectively and so ultimately the only
entropy source that it actually gets is
the current time this is obviously bad
there's also Mirage entropy which is
good
it can do our dear and and our deseed of
course only on x86 and also has
something called the whirlwind RNG which
they refer to with a new research paper
and it says that it attempts to exploit
CPU level data races that lead to
execution time variability of identical
instructions and we're not crypto
experts but this sounds kind of spooky
spectral even where we don't really have
the expertise to assess this aside from
like obvious non crypto issues which we
didn't find but it would be interesting
if someone with crypto expertise could
take a look at this because you might
find something there's no standard
library hardening they got their own
standard library called mini Lib C which
is like a really thin wrapper around
mini OS and it's the usual that supports
percent and doesn't support custom
format specifiers and doesn't have any
fortify source support something
interesting in rather unique tomorrow's
OS is that it's built of course on the
Oh camel like packaged infrastructure so
it uses oh pam as a package manager and
rather like you use OPM to install
packages to build it and that has a Sat
solver based dependency resolution
mechanism and so what this means is it
can install arbitrarily out of date
packages without warning you if you have
something like this diagram you have a
top-level package a that depends on like
package C at version greater than 1.0
and then it depends also on package C
transitively at say less than 1.0 via
another dependency no matter how high
the version of C is currently if you
install a it OPM doesn't let you install
two versus the same package so in order
to satisfy this it'll just install
version 1.0 a package c and it'll you
know the interface will give you exactly
the same readout as if it installed the
current version of package c like it'll
show the version and some little things
somewhere but unless you're really
looking hard then it's it's not gonna
act any differently it won't warn you so
you have to be really careful if you're
developing any stuff for ramaraju s that
like you don't let OPM screw you with
really out-of-date packages so right now
there are a couple other vulnerabilities
like real vulnerabilities that we found
but we can't talk about them because we
just found them in the past few weeks
and we're still in the disclosure
process but rest assured these will be
in the white paper
so in short morocco s has no a SLR
basically no page protections on data
stack and heap text is okay no pages
okay there are no Canaries even if you
try to enable them
application code nothing nothing at all
on the heap the entropy is good as long
as you're using the right package but
they don't actually specify that that's
the one you should use and the standard
library doesn't have any kind of
hardening so basically if you get a
stack buffer overflow you're great you
can get RC pretty much immediately most
types of heap buffer overflow accepts
some stuff with small chunks will give
you an arbitrary pointer right again
keeping in mind that the function point
like the function addresses that you
might want to utilize are gonna be in
slightly different places but again you
can brute-force those or scan the
entropy implementations and the Oh camel
package manager' Oh Pam you have to be
pretty careful about how you use them
because they can shoot you in the foot
easily so given these three assessments
I think it's pretty obvious that it is
not the case that you know kernels are
secure but they are rather hilariously
broken and that's basically because they
don't implement even simple security
measures so to the point that if you get
most types of memory corruption on the
unit kernels we looked at at least they
will lead you very easily to RCE and
oftentimes as like in the included mo
you don't even have to have seen the
binary or the source of what you're
attacking so on top of this is the fact
that everything has kernel level VM
capabilities so like as soon as you get
any control it's already full control
like there's there's no privilege
separation there's no route or anything
as soon as you get RCE
you can start crafting arbitrary packets
do PCI whatever anything the VM will let
you do you can do but with that said
it's worth mentioning that even though
Mirage at a low level is basically the
same situation this rump run it is
actually still an order of magnitude
more secure than any of the native code
you know kernels we looked at because
you're not gonna be writing that much
native code on mirage
with that said memory safe language you
know kernels like knowledge don't need
to be pretty careful about how their
low-level components which are most
likely gonna be written in C are
hardened and they also need to focus on
actually providing like secure api's for
application developers to use because
they can't just rely on being inherently
secure they actually have to like help
application developers develop secure
applications so basically you know
kernel is unlike the claims of many of
their proponents say are not a cure-all
basically their embedded systems running
in a VM and they have about the same
level of security as you'd expect from a
lot of embedded systems so to put it
lightly there's a lot of work that needs
to be done before you
kernels become at all suitable for
production in retrospect they should
have been obvious as soon as we saw that
there basically wasn't a debugger for
the overwhelming majority of Yoona
kernels we looked at and we actually had
to write our own to assess some of the
underlying components we'd like to thank
some people first of all mini Preston of
the Mirage OS project for being super
helpful with teaching me all sorts of
stuff about how a camel's fi works
during the last CCC in Germany and then
Brian Cantrell for being an epic troll
who happened to be right this time
for future work we're gonna start
looking at OS v we have white paper at
least the first one coming out soon it's
like at a hundred pages right now that
are mostly diagrams and exploit
shellcode so that'll that'll be cool
when it drops and then we are going to
be looking more for those higher-level
things where there are issues in the
kind of stack code of when you you
decide to re-implement your own tcp/ip
implementation what can go wrong and and
that's sort of that kind of level of
stuff
is one of the one of the sorts of bugs
that we already found we weren't really
looking for that kind of bug but that's
one of the ones that we we can't talk
about of what happens when you just
reimplementation stack from user land to
kernel to hardware and just throw it all
in bring zero so we're looking for more
of that if there are any questions we
have a little bit of time left actually
so we actually got through this faster
than in our demo runs for ourselves I'll
also add that NCC group is hiring so if
anyone wants to talk to us about that
we'll be around so just feel free to
stop by and ask us questions so any
questions
okay thank you
[Applause]