thank you um so as she said my name is
Austin McBride and today we're gonna
talk a little bit about cryptocurrency
how it's a gold mine and how you can
protect a couple of measures you can do
to protect your environment so first
we'll talk a little bit about
cryptocurrency in general and then
crypto jackin then phishing and then a
little bit about alternate coins and
exchanges and then finally about
measures to protect yourself I'm so a
little bit of about me one I got
haircuts so I look a little different
now but I am a threat analytics
researcher at Cisco umbrella I have a BS
and a data mining and economics I really
love crypto my hobbies are working and
basically algorithmic crypto trading and
of course work so a little bit about the
team that I work with
it's called Cisco guerrilla and we
basically mix data science and network
security and so we call that big
security data we process about a hundred
and eighty billion DNS queries a day and
that's roughly a little bit less than
three percent of daily DNS traffic
globally um so we get quite a decent
sample as far as DNS queries are
concerned we also see a lot of new
domains that have never there have just
been registered and have not really been
visited frequently and now that we're a
part of Cisco before we were Open DNS
now we have all of Cisco's data as well
daily activities for myself and other
people on my team are security analysis
distributed systems Big Data engineering
and data visualization so a little bit
about cryptocurrency so as we all know
cryptocurrency had a pretty meteoric
rise it's not quite there at the moment
it's about 200 billion but within a one
year period we went from 26 billion in
market cap all the way to eight hundred
thirty-five billion which is not
something that we've ever really seen in
other traditional markets so so with
this
there's a lot of opportunity right for
anybody to make money in especially
malicious actors so with the going
mainstream and becoming more popular a
lot of individuals are going to get into
the space and it's going to be a ripe
spot for malicious actors to go and take
advantage of people who don't know much
about blockchain or cryptocurrencies it
is under regulated and it's highly
volatile and there are a lot of
malicious actors that are willing to
steal your funds so I'm gonna talk a
little bit about crypt currency
regulation so to start off with I think
Japan has the most comprehensive
structure at the moment for regulating
especially exchanges and I think it's
great I would say that in most other
countries are not anywhere near the
understanding of blockchain or exactly
how to regulate it especially with the
the different governing bodies so it's
kind of a an idea right we started off
with the mountain ox compromise
anticipate EF guidance risk-based
approach to cryptocurrencies and 15 very
progressive and then the payment
services act in 2017
now everyone goes a lot of people go
through know your customer everything is
complying to anti money laundering
rules and then there are frequent audits
to make sure that the books look okay
then we had coin check of course that
happened in January and then the GVC EA
and March of 2018 generally where there
is money there will be malicious actors
that want to take it from you right and
in this case most of it's going to be
external most of the threats that you'll
see that involve cryptocurrencies in
your environments are probably not going
to come from Japan most likely is going
to come from Ukraine or another foreign
operator that is just operating in your
environment as much as possible to to
steal funds so the reason one of the
reasons that it's actually so attractive
is that it's it's very lucrative and it
can be hard to spot if you don't know
what you're looking for
Krypto exchanges do not necessarily have
his robust security measures in place
the traditional equity markets do stocks
bonds you know etc and so it's it's very
easy for malicious actors who have an
understanding of that to easily
infiltrate and steal funds it's also
very anonymous depending on the coin and
with an asset valuation that fluctuates
quite a lot you can basically steal
coins and in two or three days or a week
they can be thirty percent or thirty
percent more than they were originally
so it's very very lucrative and it can
be used to of course buy Lamborghinis
and things like that but it can also be
used to buy additional malware or
infrastructure to make even more impact
and damages so now I'm going to talk a
little bit about how crypto jackin fits
in to the mix I'm sure you were all very
aware but the basics of crypto mining is
basically you're verifying transactions
of others and then you've rewarded for
verifying those transactions in the case
of Bitcoin it kind of can differ
depending on what coin crypto jackin is
really just the hijacking of computer
resources and there are a few other
speakers that talked about this in the
conference and basically it's just using
your GPU CPU or cloud computing services
to to mine cryptocurrency so keeping in
mind with about a hundred eighty billion
DNS queries we see a day we seemed a
tremendous increase in the amount of
crypto traffic just in the last eight
months and the majority of the traffic
is from Kempton mining pools we see a
lot of manure of course and some other
coins and they actually happen to affect
a lot of different industries it's not
just financial services health care a
wide variety of industries all are
seeing this type of traffic in their
environment and there are also some mmm
malicious actors that are dropping
mining software and it persists in your
environment as long as it's connected
Internet so looking at a distribution of
industry in the u.s. specifically and in
Europe you can see that higher education
energy and utility companies that
typically have hardware that is older
and not necessarily patched as as
frequently as it could be healthcare
have surprisingly and hold quite large
percentages of the amount of traffic
that we've seen cumulative ly over the
last eight months the top industries
kind of fluctuate as we can see from the
last two or three months or every two or
three months they fluctuate but higher
education is almost always on top so
this means students who have free
electricity and then free internet and
their dormitories or running mining rigs
and so this can be costly for our
educational institutions looking at the
kind of geo distribution of the traffic
we see a lot happening in the US and in
European countries as far as crypto
mining goes that is malicious in nature
not necessarily global crypto mining
traffic and as you can see here we've
got a bar chart of a couple of the
different country codes that we see
quite a bit of traffic in I'm so you may
ask yourself what type of company is
most targeted for crypto mining activity
and I would say that it predominantly is
focused on smaller businesses or
medium-sized businesses and the reason
for this is generally those businesses
do not have dedicated incident
responders people who were monitoring
network traffic making sure things are
actually consistently working as they
should and so that is why we see
normally companies 10,000 employees or
less or being targeted for this type of
activity we can also see that with with
the use of mining pools for you know
Minero and some other types of coins
that you can line the market
fluctuations in value and the difficulty
of the mining can actually impact
whether or not you seeing that traffic
environment so when the market is down
and the mining difficulty is high you
will see less you will be less a risk
for this type of activity or environment
but when the market cap is going up and
we're approaching 1 trillion in market
cap you're going to see a lot more
crypto mining in your environments
because it is cheaper to to operate and
more lucrative and we've also seen that
as the market has taken a dip recently
and overall value for cryptocurrencies
we see a lot more fishing so so mining
costs do you think ok you might ask well
how much does this really cost malicious
actors to to mine in my environment and
really the cost is is pretty negligible
using popular web liners like coin hive
or there are several that you could use
generally they'll take maybe 30% of
whatever you mind as a fee and then the
rest of it they can put in their pocket
and then the upfront cost of them
getting this mining software whether
it's JavaScript or physical malware
software in your environment is really
just the cost of how very long it takes
their time and money to get into your
environment this is this is coin high
very popular online miner in mines
monaro and here we can see that really
it's not necessarily just larger
corporations and servers and AWS
instances that are being targeted we see
this happening in smartphones we see it
on websites is JavaScript exploits and
then individual machine targeting you've
probably seen a lot of new stories about
different breaches and hacks some are in
cloud AWS instances with basically weak
kubernetes passwords right but we also
see malicious actors infiltrating sites
that deliver content like video as well
as news websites where they know that
the user is going to be on that domain
for at least 30 minutes to an hour
consuming content that way they maximize
they're machine based on the query so it
means that one either an employee
installed mining software in your
environment and they shouldn't have or
to an external party was able to get
into your environment install software
and they are sending the funds that
they're mining in your environment
externally so with the the second case
scenario is much worse because if it is
in fact the case that someone external
puts software in your environment what's
to say that tomorrow they decide they
don't want to do mining and they want to
encrypt all of your corporate data this
is a way of determining quickly if you
have a potential threat of an outside
incursion so now I want to talk a little
bit about crypto fishing so fishing is
obviously been around for a long time
right we have normal vectors like email
we've seen a huge surge in search engine
ads so Google and other search providers
with AD poisoning and then with a lot of
different communication channels you
know slack telegram discord Twitter all
the normal all the normal ones and so
here is an example of some Google
advertisements they are for my Manero my
manure is a popular mineral wallet and
if you can see here underneath the Y on
the ad URL it's not quite right we see a
little dot and then on the second one
same we see a little mark above vo so
essentially what the malicious actors
are doing is they're using puny code to
simulates a domain name that looks
similar to the legitimate site and if
you aren't paying close enough attention
you put in your credentials and lose
your funds I'm so here here's actually
both of those sites they're currently no
longer live these are the exact copies
of the sites that's the second one
and just because you see it's HTTP it
really doesn't mean you're safe there
are a lot of providers these days that
offer a wild call wild card certificates
and so anything that's hosted on a
specific IP is blessed with the HTTPS
tag and that doesn't necessarily mean
you're safe so don't rely on HTTPS is as
a means of safety and then here's just a
another example of dokko another popular
search engine so to drive this point
home a little forward I'm going to talk
about how is it easy it is to make a
Google advertisement to get people
and this could be this doesn't
necessarily just apply to cryptocurrency
or crypto fishing it could be applied to
any fishing vector it's it's very very
effective so a couple things to note
about Google AdWords specifically you
have to basically the the redirect does
not happen in the ad the if you click on
an ad in Google it has the domain that's
registered here has to be part of the
landing page that the user ends up on so
you have to own it or at least reference
it and then the domain this displayed in
an ad cannot have a different site name
so essentially it you would have to
create a subdirectory or another page on
that site to do fishing so that's what
I've done here I've I've hidden it and I
put wallet slash I'm going to fish you
so in this use case the specific one I
would as a malicious actor have to
somehow infiltrate and get login
credentials for blockchain Don info
which would not be a very easy task by
any means but what I could do is I could
also set up a phishing campaign to get
someone who works at blockchain Don info
who operates their Google AdWords
account and and I hope if I can get
their login information for Google
AdWords that it may also be the same
credentials for their site and I can
then have the website was legitimate pay
for ads that are malicious and I can
have the redirect page to my phishing
site to get credentials living on
blockchain dot info as a as a
subdirectory so you you have to be
careful because malicious hackers will
take them at least two or three
different steps out as far as possible
phishing vectors in order to get
credentials and they're hoping that
you're using the same credentials for
multiple sites
here's an example of of the puny code
being used heavily and Google AdWords
and other ad sites here the is not quite
right and that's how it actually is
displayed when you look up the domain
but of course web browsers try to clean
up those types of things for users all
right so now I'm going to talk a little
bit about cryptocurrency exchanges and
in old coins so we discussed before
about phishing scams so here are some
advertisements for there but we also see
a lot of things happening on social
networks and communication platforms
this is something those mentioned by
Phillip at coinbase yesterday well it's
very easy to entice some people if you
send me point two etherium I'll give you
two aetherium just because me is by a
Nance I love you as a customer right
this doesn't work for the majority of
people but it still works for some and
this is still lucrative enough for them
to walk away with quite a bit of funds
so I'm going to talk a little bit about
finance quick raise of hands anybody
here used by Nance as a trading platform
all right we've got one all right
got a few in the audience good I love I
love finance as a trading platform it's
it's very simple to use easy to manage
they have a lot of security measures in
place to keep you from being fished or
sending funds to wallets that that are
not yours or you don't want them to be
sent to so right here we have an example
on the left of a malicious site and on
the right the legitimate site the only
difference being is that there happens
to be a V and the domain name on the one
on the left which is of course malicious
the infrastructure and and how the
malicious actor set this website was
quite good all of the stock information
updates at the exact same time if you
were to click on any of the links on the
fish
site that would lead you to logging in
within one or two clicks they would keep
you on the fishing site if you were to
look at wiki's or support or information
about contests they would Forge you to
the legitimate site and they did this so
they didn't have to replicate the full
infrastructure of the web site so let's
pretend that I was not paying attention
and I'm gonna log into this phishing
site so I go to the login page I put in
my email and my password I do a little
CAPTCHA and then you say but wait Austin
what about two-factor authentication
that'll probably save you here right no
not necessarily so this is what is known
as a to F a bypass or a
man-in-the-middle attack so I'm the
victim and I am on a phishing site one
of the ones we were just looking at I
him my credentials he Ford's that the
legitimate web site puts them in the
legitimate web site prompts for a
two-factor authentication code that is
sent to me and I don't know I still
don't know that I'm on the wrong side I
put that information into the phishing
site and then the malicious actor uses
that code in order to get into my
accounts and then normally after that
they Forge you to the actual website to
make it seem like there was just a login
glitch so you have no idea that you
actually just gave someone else access
to your accounts and most of the time
they actually do not immediately steal
your funds so if we look a little bit
more closely at div Nantz calm the
malicious domain that we were looking at
using a tool that we have called
investigate we can look at information
Whois information and some other
information as well that give us this
insight into is this actually legitimate
or not or who is doing this um so in
this case we see that the register name
is the Center for Ukrainian internet
names Finance does not operate and
Ukraine and
at the time and so this is very
suspicious the email registration black
13 at unseen is this is a this is a
email that prides itself on anonymity
and it's not what you would ever think
large exchange would use as their email
registration email so there are a lot of
red flags here okay and then what also
is interesting is the IP that this
domain is hosted on is not an IP that by
Nantz uses for hosting their
infrastructure so we're gonna dig a
little bit deeper into who is this black
thirteen unseen at unseen dot is what's
interesting is that you can see that
they're also interested in my wallet so
not only are they wanting to get
credentials for your exchange but they
also want to get credentials for online
wallets where you think your funds are
actually secure but maybe not if you end
up getting fished and down here you can
see a lot of their domains that they
have set up at varying stages trying to
pretend to be financed so some are live
some are prepping to to go live into to
fit for phishing sites I'm so so now
altcoins now now that we have all the
stuff about phishing this is where it
kind of gets really cool and very scary
so another tactic they use is involves
pump and dumps so it is the you you're
pumping the price of a coin and then you
sell all of your coins at the top and
you use a bunch of other people's funds
so what the malicious actors did was
they they fished a couple of hundred
exchange accounts and then they created
Trading API keys and then they didn't do
anything for like a month or two and
then they set up a bot to automatically
trade all of to basically liquidate all
of the coins that were in those wallets
into Bitcoin and then use that to
purchase via KOIN and the reason they
chose if I a coin was because the
liquidity of AI coin was only about 11
and a half Bitcoin so that means it was
very easy for
the actor to buy the whole order book
all asks all bids which essentially
would allow them to increase the value
of that coin by ten thousand percent so
if and what they did is they had a
couple accounts that they had their own
vine holdings in that they had procured
before and just lied in wait and we're
going to sell their own holdings at the
top and walk away with about thirty two
million dollars but unfortunately for
them it didn't happen the exchanges
noticed that ten thousand percent
increase in any asset is very unusual
and they basically blocked withdrawals
and deposits for that for those funds so
they didn't it impacted individuals and
the fact that they they lost a lot of
their asset value when their funds were
liquidated
but the malicious actor didn't walk away
with any of the money but if exchanges
did not have some of those security
measures in place which is the case of a
lot of small exchanges they don't have
halting on trading for huge jumps and
asset prices they could have walked away
with a lot of money so now that I've
talked a lot about well crypt of
phishing encrypted Jack I wanna talk a
smidge more about how you can protect
yourself with with different tools so
DNS level identification of crypto
mining encrypt of jacking is very very
effective so looking through your DNS
query logs to see if things like coin
hive and other mining pools like XM are
minor pools XYZ is a very popular one
you can see if any of your machines and
your environments are querying these and
then you can know that okay well either
an employee went to a website that was
has a JavaScript exploit and mind a bit
of currency or maybe there's a piece of
software in my environment that is
mining that I need to look into for
cloud computing instances and this was
this was mentioned before in one of the
previous talks look for increases in
utilization of si
pee-yew for your aid AWS instances they
would normally only do 10 or 15%
increase and utilization so that when
you get your bill it doesn't seem it
seems higher than normal but it's not
too high and so that they want to
basically operate for as long in your
environment as they can without being
caught or identified and they are also
hoping that as long as the longer they
wait the value of that currency goes up
considerably so one of the models that
we use it briella is the co-occurrence
model and so it's kind of like guilty by
association so if we know that one
website is malicious and we look at the
the time that other sites were visited
basically fifteen seconds before or
after we can basically say okay that
seems a little suspicious if if all of
the users that are forwarding their dns
to our service are going to the exact
same domains within a certain time frame
love each other that's suspicious
and so what we can do is look at once
it's crossed the statistic threshold of
a number of people who are doing the
exact same behavior then we can say okay
this is very unusual we should look into
this and see if it's also malicious the
same thing can be done for legitimate
websites so I had mentioned coin hive
previously which is by the way a totally
legitimate we see misuse of coin hive a
lot of misuse of coin hive but it is in
fact a legitimate service it's just the
way that people are using in whether or
not they're notifying people that they
are using their resources to mine
currency so with coin hive we can see a
lot of co-occurrences with the websites
the behavior similar so we have a lot of
malicious domains that are associated
with phishing and browser redirects from
other legitimate sites we also see
domains that have JavaScript injections
that are running miners while people are
consuming content and then we've got
some other mining scripts where
essentially malicious actors are posing
to be coin hive
and getting you to install software or
put it on your website but hard code
their wallet address oh you basically
setup coin how I'm thinking you're going
to make some money but you're really
just sending it to somebody else so one
of the things that our team at Cisco
umbrella has worked on I wanna give a
shout out for Jeremiah O'Connor and arts
um two of my colleagues they developed
this classifier that's very effective in
identifying phishing traffic so we start
with domains that we've never seen
before we never resolved and when you
use Apache spark in order to come up
with the basis of this model so we'll do
an fqdn classification on the the page
will pull the source code of the first
page of the domain and then we'll start
looking at HTML content classification
and then we'll look to see okay now that
we know what this looks like and have a
general feeling is this being hosted on
infrastructure that we know is
legitimate is a really good IP is that a
good ASN or is it in some shady place in
Ukraine or elsewhere and then we can do
blocking and threat intelligence once
we've gone through that going a little
bit deeper we can see then we're
basically breaking this out into four
steps where we we have DNS queries
coming in we check to see if the
information of that site is listed on
something that we know and we trust and
then we will basically do a check on the
page to see okay is this page that we've
never seen before but looks similar to
something we have seen does it have a
box to input credentials or something
like that and then we will basically
create a tf-idf so this is basically
just NLP modeling's of natural language
processing and then we'll do some latent
semantic analysis and then we'll take
the cosine of the new site that we just
saw with the site that we know is
actually legitimate and then we'll
basically train its
in order to identify domains that are
good or bad
moving forward so here's a little bit
simpler version of it will we'll go look
at all of the exchanges that we know are
legitimate we'll download the code from
the site we'll create a score and then
we will whenever we see a new site that
seems similar we will create a corpus
document and we'll compare it and this
will allow us to determine if this is a
phishing site for a and exchange without
ever having to look at it so here's one
such example this is L coin based calm
and as a score of nine nine point four
and we can see here some other
suspicious things like Quinn basement
never have their email registration at a
hotmail account and that's they would
never do that so we know that this is
suspicious and here here is the live
site which at the time looked just like
coin basis website but it actually is in
fact malicious so one thing you have to
keep in mind is that they're the
criminal organizations that are behind
these types of attacks are using several
different revenue vectors they're not
just going to try to fix your
credentials they're also going to run
ransomware campaigns and they're also
going to try try to install crypto
mining software in your environment it's
very profitable it's pretty anonymous
and that's why they choose to do all of
these different vectors for making money
one such case that we we found and
highlighted a couple of months back was
just purely phishing crypto phishing of
wallets they actually in two months time
made almost two million dollars USD so
it's very lucrative for these malicious
actors and then going to the flip side
ransomware we see we see a lot of
ransomware still ransomware was a little
bit riskier of a business before when
you had to have infrastructure to
process credit card transactions but
with the the invention of
to currency much easier to make payments
more anonymous and you're less likely to
get caught and so I think
cryptocurrencies invention definitely
helped propel ransomware to be as much
of a problem as it as it was and in
still is so for for ransomware
infections normally you would get
infected right you'd be addicted and
then you would respond to the incident
you would restore from a backup if you
had it but if you didn't you would make
a decision whether or not okay I have to
have my data I should pay or no I don't
care I'm not going to pay I'll just lose
the data but let's say that you have to
get it you end up paying and then you
keep the rest of the cryptocurrencies
you have in storage just in case
something like that happens again so now
I'm gonna wrap it up with a couple of
final thoughts and then I'll open it up
for questioning
I'm so point number one we're really
witnessing a huge restructuring in the
criminal economy as far as
cryptocurrency is concerned this new
digital digital asset has really opened
up a lot of vectors for malicious actors
to spread more infrastructure and hit
more people luckily there are you know
any money any money laundering laws now
where if you move more than one Bitcoin
into fiat so yen USD euro you have to
give us a certain level of information
that will allow you to be tracked but
what criminals have figured out is that
they with these laws they have millions
of dollars in cryptocurrency that they
can't do anything with because it's very
hard to get into fiat without being
noticed so what they've been doing is
buying property and things like that to
try to get into an asset and then sell
that asset and then get Fiat second
individuals are encrypted tax or a much
software target
if I was a hacker I would much rather go
after someone who just started trading
cryptocurrencies even if they only have
fifteen thousand dollars invested then
going after a financial institution that
has a lot of security measures in the
been around for a long time so when
you're trading and if you decide to
trade in crypto assets really take your
own security to heart because you are
your own bank and you need to have your
own security measures third thought
there have been some recent shutdowns of
very popular exchanges that were being
used to basically dry in exchange
Bitcoin and other assets in a way that
kind of money laundered it and they've
decided to shift away from doing it this
way and focus on targeting the smaller
businesses that we talked about before
that maybe don't have such a great
security posture and then the last thing
that I want to leave with is protecting
your environment is hard right there are
always going to be new attacks that you
have to deal with but looking at your
DNS query logs is a really good first
step when you know that a specific
attack has to make a request a DNS
request so it's a very good way of
identifying if you might have a problem
but but don't just look for web-based
miners so don't just go look for coin I
of in your your logs right you also want
to look for software based miners like
honey miner that are running in your
environment because they can be a
possible indicator that someone
externally has installed software in
your environment so with that I'm going
to open it up for questions