thank you it's always an honor to come
to Tokyo to come to Japan thank you to
kana and to code blue for such a
professional and amazing event so
because our task is so difficult as
cyber defenders I am trying to draw on
some inspiration from from my and
perhaps your favorite movie spirited
away so Who am I I did 20 years in the
US government I worked for a fire I and
now for Komodo but I look at the
intelligence picture so the higher
higher level of who and why of hacking
so I'm primarily looking at the the
impact and specifically the the
geopolitics and and what I'm going to
show you in this presentation is
actually that I think a lot more of what
you're seeing when you look at your log
files is in fact nation state hacking
right and I think I've got the data to
prove it so the power side of the
equation I think there's maybe three
kinds of cyberattack there's data theft
data denial and data manipulation but I
think they come in that order in terms
of frequency and sophistication I think
a lot of what I'm going to show you is
cyber espionage but therein lies a lot
of power power for decision makers so
just one analyst one company one day
this is what I see right in terms of
malware detection every country 27
malware types thousands of malware
families and it's very international
space so there is only one internet
there's only one cyber space but hackers
are constantly occupying terrain in
other countries giving them potentially
dozens of opportunities to collect
information that their national security
establishment would want to to have
right but from a cyber defense
perspective this is a challenge I sat at
the Pentagon for years trying to figure
out this attribution question much
closer to the year 2000
who is hacking us right and long lists
of IP addresses where to start in terms
of law enforcement and
counterintelligence well there's an
analyst one of the ways I do it is try
to look at data from interesting
perspectives that give insight into how
to understand the data and you can see
here very quickly
you can have a picture of vulnerability
across the planet right Africa because
it's poorer and there's a lot of
conflict zones they probably don't have
a professional cyber defence staff so
they're very vulnerable to worms and
viruses for example but this gives
attackers nice space to operate in right
if I'm an American hacker that wants to
target Japan or vice versa there's a
chance I might bounce through Africa
right and give give me some plausible
deniability some anonymity because the
chances you chase me back are relatively
low right but so when you look at the
planet each nation is uniquely
vulnerable to to cyber security issues
so here is a scale of just four nations
but it's showing you the ratio of
malware types within them and it's it's
interesting to see that if you compare
Switzerland to Somalia for example
vastly different malware types and
families inhabit them in Switzerland
you'll find very
hi highly engineered high return on
investment malware right and South
Africa you can see here very vulnerable
to worms and viruses right so
Switzerland's very tight right they have
a lot of money they have a lot of
experience with security and so this is
the kind of analysis that I'm doing to
understand the space but the cyber
defense advice that you would give to
different countries really is unique
here are some Asian countries on the
same type of scale and I'll just point
out two things viruses in the
Philippines Russia Vietnam you can see
that these countries are more vulnerable
to older code right older malware that
take advantage of either unlicensed
unpatched pirated software right this is
not good for them or for the world but
you can see the state of cybersecurity
within them in Japan and South Korea you
can see some similarity in terms of
ratios but also the the backdoors that I
was talking about and this is indicative
of more wealth in these countries and
more targeted operations to go after
that wealth in this presentation I will
show you a number of timelines because I
find this is one of the most helpful
ways to view your data so if one of your
computers is pinging or sending a
communication at 2:00 in the morning
that's a sign of trouble right on your
network because nobody should be sitting
there so in the same way time lines show
you when things happen and it's very
important especially in national
security to see the spikes in malware in
the
potential causes so Trojans I'll just
show you for malware types these are our
most stable set of malware but you can
see with Ukraine in Egypt someone on on
July 29th and August 2nd was very
determined to get information out of one
of those countries but Trojans we have
thousands they're our most complicated
data set but our biggest as well right
maybe 80% of our detection Zoar
something non-application are our
Trojans the trouble with a Trojan is
it's a Swiss Army knife right you can do
anything with the Trojan from it's just
read email to encrypt the hard drive for
ransomware look at how volatile worms
are right and in general you'll see a
poorer socio-economic profile of these
countries but worms
Stuxnet for example is often referred to
as a worm because it's it's one of its
most powerful characteristics that worms
are autonomous right they can travel the
internet on their own and take advantage
of vulnerabilities at scale right so if
you want to take if you're gonna target
Texas or France you might need a
powerful worm right to go after a large
potentially a large target you can see
here at Turkey India Brazil Indonesia
these are places that are poor and also
you can see in the case of Russia Turkey
in Indonesia these were associated with
elections which I'll show you soon
Ukraine has a real problem with viruses
you can see these are our largest spikes
over the course of a year and these are
going to be associated probably with the
ongoing conflict with Russia
but it's not only a somewhat poorer
country Ukraine but is at war right
viruses are indicative of a poor state
of health on the network but you can see
here that hackers are really taking
advantage of Ukraine through that vector
backdoors as I've said I believe are a
sign of a more targeted operation a
higher return on investment higher
engineering but you can see here so this
unsurprisingly we see United Kingdom and
Italy here but also Russia in so we'll
get into this in a second but I think a
lot of what we see on the networks is in
fact geopolitically driven now these
detection x'
in the UK are they match up fairly
nicely with the alleged assassination of
a Russian spy in the UK you can see here
if you look at the spike here where
where Russia is noted I saw the same
backdoor hash not only in the UK but
also in Russia at the same day and same
time also suggesting a relationship with
with this malware so now for some
timelines in geopolitics so this slide
shows that in the United States over a
six-month period for three malware types
worms Trojans and viruses we had the
highest single day of detection on march
13th so sometimes for a spike I say well
what was the cause of this spike or in
other cases if there's a big event I'll
look for the malware from the other
direction but here I didn't know what
happened on March 13th so I type into
Google
you know the United States March 13th
and it was the day that Donald Trump
announced the new Secretary of State and
the name of the new CIA director and
what this does is it gives fresh meat to
hackers around the world and it's not
that I'm saying this is the Russians or
this is the Chinese what I'm saying is
that a lot of nation-states and their
state hackers or their contractors
subcontractors lone Wolf's you name it
it's the whole collection of them that
all of a sudden have new intelligence
requirements right and this is not one
computer or even a thousand but these
are millions of data points collated and
if you're skeptical on this slide that's
great here is a case in which you can
see very clearly the relationship right
between network security and national
security so these are the annual
military exercises between the United
States and South Korea and on those very
days you see the Trojan detection zin
South Korea they are through the roof
why because not only or the United
States and South Korea and North Korea
probably interested in what's happening
there but also Japan also China also
Russia and some other nations to June
4th in China our largest single day of
detection this year by far and this
speaks to the power again of computer
network operations in this case it may
be some law-enforcement some
counterintelligence but you can be sure
that three-letter agencies in other
countries will also be very interested
in what's happening in China on the
anniversary of Tiananmen Square
revolution in Armenia also brings
interest from
hackers right probably domestic and
abroad and what does this mean for you
if you're in a healthcare right industry
well whenever there's a new CEO
acquisitions stock price mergers
anything that relates to healthcare on a
strategic scale the same thing is going
to happen to you right in your industry
in Belarus they tried to pass
legislation against fake news so we see
a spike on that day no it's probably
some government action and maybe some
foreign governments trying to figure out
what's happening maybe some students
right maybe some potential
revolutionaries but another thing I'm
gonna show you as we move into the
slides is the order of operations for
hacking right you've probably heard of
the cyber kill chain right if I'm
targeting a person in this audience you
know I need to know their their email
address their IP address etc it's the
same on a national scale right and so
what I'm gonna show you is that if
there's an election coming they'll be ad
where there will be suspicious
applications followed by viruses or
worms followed by trojans backdoors this
is the order of operations for hacking
whether it's one person an enterprise or
a nation now sometimes smaller countries
as well it's even easier to see but this
spike in Nigeria was easy I typed in
Nigeria May 24th and they were on the
cover of CNN with a Amnesty
International article decrying the human
rights situation in Nigeria in Nepal May
28th the day that Nepal decided not to
cooperate with
China on developing a international
project Dam in the country here's a
financially motivated attack right in
the little island of st. Kitts Nevis my
daughter actually found this spike and
so then I then I say well what happened
there and it was pretty easy to see on
the same day on march 13th the the
island was placed on a an international
financial blacklist
right so that was on the 13th but on the
12th already we can see hackers busy
trying to take advantage of the
situation as in insider trading right
somebody knew about this and beforehand
and was hacking the country something
related to finances so that was
sometimes looking at spikes and then
trying to explain them but in the next
two cases I so the summit's in Singapore
between Trump and Kim so that's the only
thing in the news for the day so I pull
up Singapore detection and you can see
the interest on the part of hackers
right again most of this will be
espionage but some of it might be more
targeted and manipulative operations you
know it's hard to know but you can see
not only the proximity physically but in
terms of time so same thing in Finland
with the Trump Putin summit and the day
it was announced I saw a nice virus
spike in Finland and in order to further
confirm the relationship I said where
did the spike take place and it was in
the neighborhood of Helsinki where the
summit would take place right because
sometimes you want to be close to your
target right for not only for logical
but physical connectivity I have one
slide it's not in this presentation but
a blow-up of four
Maryland in Washington DC and you see a
nice red ring around the White House in
terms of malware detection right so the
hackers are not behaving randomly but
they have a target that they're trying
to get close to
so the Saudi journalist Khashoggi right
they disappeared on October 2nd
obviously this is a major news story
with international implications
ultimately that could could be regime
changing right on October 2nd already I
see suspicious malware detection in
Turkey which tells me that intelligence
agencies informed ones are seeking
information very quickly about what's
going on right so on October 2nd and
October 4th in Turkey it comes a bit
later in Saudi Arabia but you can see
Saudi Arabia because of its wealth
should be a fairly stable malware
environment but you can see here on
October 14th and October 19th in roughly
two weeks after the disappearance
somebody is very interested in pulling
information out of Saudi Arabia so let's
look at a couple of timelines on Japan
and you can't make this stuff up right
so this is a year and a half worth of
malware detection in Japan just from my
company but I drop it on a slide and
this is what it looks like right one
massive worm spike as I said then
followed by Trojan right you have to
disseminate malware propagate malware
before you can exploit it so in this
case July 15th there is a propagation
and a crescendo of exploitation up to
August 30th well on August 29th
there was a launch of a missile from
North Korea over Japan and
I cannot prove that the two things are
related but they definitely appear
suspiciously correlated on a timeline
here I don't know I tried to find a
relationship but I'm not sure but
perhaps you with expert knowledge on
your own country could figure it out
these are applications and what I want
to say here is our malware analysts at
my previous company and now at my
current company they say why are you
looking at applications and I said well
are they behaving suspiciously yes they
try to change your browser settings or
they try to install functionality in
your startup processes etc well to me
that looks suspicious and it may not be
a backdoor it may not be a trojan but I
see suspicious applications clustering
around geopolitical events so on July
18th or September 11th of this year
maybe something interesting happened in
Japan for which someone needed
information about what was happening so
that's a lot about the power of computer
network operations especially to collect
information quickly I also think that we
have to be realistic about what's
possible when we talk cyber war cyber
attack for example in Estonia 2007 or
Ukraine 2014 we see so many cyber
attacks but are they strategic victories
we don't know right there's a famous
story about a reporter asked the Chinese
Foreign Minister Joe and ly what do you
think about the French Revolution was it
a good idea or a bad idea so Joe and
live responds it's too soon to tell
right
200 years later but we need patience and
a lot of times politics their short term
right in so that's one reason I and we
can see this close relationship between
malware and politics is because we need
information today so in this case March
28th this massive spike in Croatia
occurred the same day that Russia was
very angry with Croatia over expelling
a Russian spy right was this espionage
or was it punishment we're not sure but
is it effective is a whole other
question right but we can see the data
here is Ukraine and for example May 24th
corresponding to heavy fighting in the
east of Ukraine does it aid the war
victory sure cyberattacks are very
capable of gathering information in the
same way that the 13th chapter of the
art of war says that generals and
leaders must collect as much information
as possible right about their
adversaries will they be decisive in
warfare is highly unlikely here's some
cases from the Middle East
and what I can show you is that
especially when international when
nations or international organizations
are active in Syria for example on the
issue of chemical weapons big malware
spikes right so here we see US air
strikes us seeks inquiry chemical
weapons thought to be used these are
instances in which computer network
operations are leveraged he
in Yemen Saudi bombing missile hits
Saudi industrial target missile fired at
Saudi capital right when a missile is
fired from Yemen into Saudi Arabia you
will see a bump so I'm one of the papers
I'm currently working on is showing that
in 2017 there were nine ballistic
missile launches from North Korea and
what we're trying to prove is that each
one of them yielded a bump or a spike in
malware detection in South Korea right
so an event that important the hackers
need to get in quickly to understand
what's happening Palestine the same UN
International Criminal Court us these
are international events for which major
powers and intelligence agencies are
going to need information quickly so
here's one from Iran right and again
Pompeyo Pompeo but the big one on mate
sorry July 24th right coincides with
July 23rd tweet from Donald Trump you
know unless Iran behaves it will suffer
you know consequences the likes of which
no other country has suffered before so
I think these two things are absolutely
related right not saying these are
necessarily American hackers but I can
say that hackers are very interested in
this tense political situation here's
some North Korea data because my company
comodo is 20 years old and it's a
Turkish company so we actually have
beautiful coverage over parts of the
world that some other cyber security
companies know very little about because
of our history
so we have we have installations in
North Korean IP space so I drop it at a
very low level of focus our detection is
in South Korea on a time line sorry
North Korea and you see this massive
spike it looks like a shark fin yeah
and that was the very day that Donald
Trump was at the United Nations and
threatened to destroy North Korea right
so again hackers very interested at that
point in time about what is happening in
North Korea and the more I dig into the
data the more you can see the reasons
for the spikes and this is why I really
do want to suggest that more of what
you're seeing in your log files is
nation state activity than you think
right and less of it is random than you
think
so just the tallest spike here you
probably be interested Trump in Japan
Trump in South Korea Trump in Beijing so
I could do a whole presentation I've
been looking at this data for two or
three years Trump Tillerson Netanyahu
when they travel a cloud of malware
follows them right and this is only
logical right these are major
geopolitical events for which a dozen
two dozen maybe more intelligence
agencies maybe even individual
researchers but certainly contractors
are also interested again North Korea
this big spike was anti-censorship
programs as well as Windows activation
software that we detected and it
coincided when the South Korean and the
North Korean leaders were holding hands
on the border it's totally logical right
it's not random here's one last one a
nice
spike on July 12 in North Korean IP
space when things got really bad between
the u.s. and North Korea we were very
frustrated with North Korea okay so the
final element persistence now if you
haven't seen spirited away the film
please do yourself a favor and watch it
or if you haven't seen it for a long
time because as a cyber defense team and
all of us are family to some degree we
see each other at conferences around the
world and we're trying to protect
computers and as miko put it yesterday
we're trying to protect civilization you
know it's there there is a lot of
malware out there and it is going to
require persistence on our part because
the hackers are all day every day so I
want to show you here the current
research that I'm looking at for
elections because this is a hot topic
and again I find correlations all over
the place right so when Donald Trump was
inaugurated on January 20th 2017 this
all this date all this slide is is all
of my company's malware detection z'
summed by day for six months or
something
not sure three months here point is is
the highest cluster it's easy to see
right but on such an important day
transfer of power I know that your
Emperor for example for example next
year there'll be a change right then
there'll be the Olympics in in Japan so
beware that all of these major events
there are going to be hackers in malware
clustering around them why because it's
going to fall under other nations
and their contractors collection
requirements so even in peaceful
countries like Norway which Norway is
actually a very strategic player in NATO
right there's a lot of games taking
place currently between Russia and
Norway right if you think about it
between global warming submarines
Norway is where a lot of the equipment
for NATO is stored for the event of war
you can see that somebody was very
interested in their election in Norway
in Iraq as well not only for the vote
but for the recount right intelligence
agencies very interested now are they
trying to manipulate the vote it's hard
to say but with with a Trojan you can do
anything right you can steal information
you can block information or you can
manipulate data right you can change
numbers right there might be paper
ballots that could correct the record
but after the election is over there
might be no chance for a do-over
referendum in Burundi a gubernatorial
election that means governor right the
leader of Virginia this was a big race
in America Trump campaigned for his
candidate you can see this is the week
before the election the number of Trojan
detection zhh in this mice state
currently in Ohio we just had a special
election and the various colors here are
Trojan detection 'z by state just
dropped on a time line you can see
trojans the week prior to the election
someone very interested in what's taking
place this is incredible
then I said well let me look across the
planet and see if I can do something
systematic and so I looked at 45
elections over six months at the
national level and about a third of them
had a very tight correlation with the
highest malware spikes so everything
that's left on the chart here is about
30% of the 45 but all of these countries
had their highest malware spike within a
couple of days of the election or
referendum so now I'm digging in to try
and understand this better and what I'm
finding is is somewhat alarming but here
Mali Russia Turkey as there by John
Columbia you can see this same hacker
kill chain write applications they would
be used to gather information right and
I can't think of another way to do it
because the cyber kill chain for an
individual is I have to know your your
email address your IP address your
social media account well if I want to
target Texas or Moscow you know I've got
to be able to do that at scale and so
one way to do that would be adware right
or some suspicious application that I
get you know not all of you to install
but maybe half of you maybe even 10% of
you but then I can extrapolate right
from that to as a sample of the data set
to the larger group but applications
then followed I mean look at Russia
applications right before the election
right so that dotted red line is the
election the blue line is the number of
suspicious applications that we detected
right before the election followed by
worms and Trojans right so Turkey
well the applications came right before
the announcement of the election been
followed by worms and finally Trojans
the day before day or two before the
election so you see the pattern right
and so in the United States currently we
have an important election you may be
aware and Trump is very nervous and the
the country is on edge but you can see
here we have 50 states and these are 13
what we call swing states they could go
Democrat or Republican the other states
don't really matter right every election
is essentially decided by Ohio
Pennsylvania Florida etc so I took the
13 swing states and the 37 non swing
states and you can see six months ago
the math was normal right the 37 had you
know roughly 2/3 times the 13 but as we
move closer to the election now the non
or the swing states are higher than the
than the non swing states so 37 is
higher than 13 right because the
election is just around the corner and
look at this just as we saw in other
countries here comes the adware here
comes the reconnaissance you need
information quickly right so you're
sending out the suspicious applications
and the adware right so one two three
four these are all swing states these
are states that the election will turn
on one way or the other so again here's
four more but you can see as we approach
the election come the malware so here is
just and one effort to see which states
are more at risk currently and you can
see I'll just point out that
Nevada that's envy you can see more
worms are being pumped in there than any
other state right more viruses into MT
or Montana so this may mean that those
states are a particular focus for
hackers who are trying to insert malware
into that Network space right so pay
attention when you look at your own logs
or your own city or country when you see
worm activity especially that is of high
interest right because either by
accident or on purpose malware is coming
in to your space so I'm getting right
near the end of the talk and so all I'm
gonna say is that that the internet I
hope is more good than bad right is
between online education information
sharing etc is information technology
hopefully is great for the planet
currently though I think authoritarian
regimes and dictatorships are using the
Internet as a surveillance tool and as a
means of intimidation right I see you
right the United States evidently just
sent Russian hackers according to the
news an email or a text message saying
we see you please don't influence our
upcoming election right well at the end
of spirited away zero gets the magic
hair tie right that she gets to take
back with her into the human world and
so to some degree information technology
in a modern sense is magic right it
really is if you think about a an attack
that can manipulate infrastructure and
yet on your screen tell you that the
infrastructure is working fine while
this is magic because you as the owner
of the car or the house or the company
thinks everything is ok but in fact the
hackers are manipulating your foundation
right are you our critical
infrastructure so it's hard to know at
this point in time is it mostly good or
mostly bad but we do know that it's
powerful and in many ways it's magic so
I will leave you there many thanks for
listening to the presentation and if
you're interested in this kind of
research by all means send me an email
or a text I've got about four million
machines reporting every day and I pull
information from around the world
looking for this kind of activity and so
as you can see with the swing states I'm
trying to do some prediction as well
right so it's not just historical
analysis but we can see where the
attacks and the hackers are going so the
power the persistence of giro right
think about it as some inspiration ok
and I'm happy to take your questions now
or this evening over a drink or by email
next week thank you
[Applause]
you