thank you very much for the invitation
Thank You Patrick and others for
organizing this this is my second time
in Japan the last time was 17 years ago
many things have changed very glad to be
back
I quickly tell you what I do I run
several cybersecurity
organizations and projects one is the
digital hub cybersecurity which is
located in damage that I'm managing
director we coordinate all
commercialization of cyber security
technology the other one is you might
know that how Nova society's Institute
for cyber security the found of asset
then I'm part of --crisp --crisp is the
largest applied cyber security research
cluster in Europe now we have more than
500 scientists focusing on cyber
security and I'm also part of ESP car
which is focused more on geo strategic
studies in this context I also advise
the German Department of Defense on
cyber security issues so shortly about
Darmstadt why is cyber security located
in Darmstadt which is south of frankfurt
as you see Germany is very decentralized
so we have at least 12 technology
clusters for example in cows who we have
artificial intelligence in Munich we
have mobility which makes sense if
you've ever been to Munich with BMW and
all the car industry and I run the cyber
security stuff in Darmstadt which a lot
of people don't know why is damaged at
the epicentre in Germany for
cybersecurity the reason is that after
Second World War
Germany needed a new center for all
telecommunications technology and that
was established in 1949 in Darmstadt two
years later the Allied forces mostly the
US and the predecessor of what today is
the NSA they created the first crypto
center in Darmstadt in a large military
facility called dagger complex which was
then crucial for all crypto activities
during the cold war with the Soviet
Union and most important the so-called
the white salvation sent from d'art set
which was the first supercomputer in
Germany and the picture you see is the
actual IBM mainframe and a lot of people
my colleagues at my Institute formerly
were working for IBM so this is how our
building looks today we focus on mostly
anything anything in cybersecurity we do
it our largest department I think with
60 people now is focused on automotive
systems security we have a large
Department for network security because
we work closely together with Israel we
have an office in Tel Aviv and we have
quite a few Israeli colleagues that work
with me in this building we do IT
forensics we do cyber threat
intelligence and I'm mostly focused on
cyber strategy and deterrence which is
what I want to talk about with you today
I think in the program it actually says
detergents but it is deterrence
the important differentiation why do i
focus on cyber deterrence because a long
time ago I had a classic military
background I served for United Nations
in Sierra Leone for the Department of
peacekeeping operations that was in 1999
in the war and then in Kosovo so that
was a for cyber and then I was inside in
technology for a long time and now
through cyber security I'm bringing
these two worlds together so why are we
talking today about cyber deterrence I'm
curious who of you has ever heard about
cyber deterrence the Europeans okay got
it
one great so as I see it's a new concept
here in Japan it is becoming a very
important concept in Europe it has been
a very important concept in the US and
Israel for a long time and now it is
spreading the word deterrence most of us
know it from nuclear deterrence but in
the context of cyber it means something
different so let's first talk about the
difference between cyber defense which
is what most of you have been talking
about during this conference and
deterrence so cyber defence is focused
on wakening the effects of a cyber
attack this is what many of you do on a
daily basis this is your business
cyber strategy and deterrence something
different it tries to manipulate the
behavior of your cyber opponent so that
the attack does not happen
and in contrast to nuclear deterrence
where our goal was that there is no
attack at all because any nuclear attack
would be devastating in cyber we have a
different goal the goal is not absolute
deterrence but the goal is to minimize
the number to reduce the number of
attacks so that's an important
conceptual difference between nuclear
deterrence and cyber deterrence that's
why some of my colleagues in the US have
started to call this whole complex of
strategizing cyber coercion or cyber
strategy but I'm using the term
deterrence
because it is a little clearer in the
literature so why is this important why
why is everyone talking at least within
NATO frames about deterrence let's see
in our industry in cybersecurity
there are five generations of products
that we sold or are still selling to
customers the first generation started
in the late 1980s you all know it
anti-virus technology or as we call it
snake oil because it's as we know not a
real technology it was more something to
sell then there was the second
generation in the 1990s the firewall
technology then third generation
application protection technology early
2000s a lot of corporate clients are
still in generation 3 in terms of what
they buy for their corporations
generation four sandboxing anti bought
technologies start around 2010 and now
something interesting is happening we
are focusing on chip level prevention
technology which is not easy to do and
why is this suddenly so important to go
so deep in the Aussie layer to really
care about chip level prevention as for
example Apple is doing it well one of
the reasons is that we are facing
government sponsored large-scale
multi-vector attacks nowadays and what
complicates this is that in the past
these attacks were exclusively within
the range of the capabilities of
governments mostly the US and others but
know how how to do these attacks has
proliferated and now non-state actors or
even small states and criminal groups
can perform these types of attacks which
is a big problem
so therefore not only governments and
nation-states are more and more thinking
about how to deter these types of
attacks but also large corporations Sony
is an example for this now what exactly
do I want to deter
the answer is ambiguous hybrid warfare
some of you might hesitate when I say
the word warfare because we know that we
have not seen a cyber war yet there is
no outright cyber conflict in the
classic sense of the definition between
two nation states yet which is very good
that's a success however what we have
seen is a lot of tit-for-tat a lot of
exchange of attacks on a we call it left
of boom or below armed conflict
threshold level so some people say that
the prelude to war actually is the war
itself in cyber and under this
definition we already are in a state of
at least cyber conflict so some people
call it warfare some call it attacks
some call it cyber operations it all
means the same cyber operations is now
being used by the Talon manual too so in
a couple of years we all might just use
that term so what is ambiguous mean it
means that my actions are deniable I can
launch an attack and later tell my
victim that it wasn't me we sometimes
call that the big Russian lie
the second word hybrid what does that
mean it's a new term in military affairs
basically it means that you mix
conventional forces conventional
capabilities with non-conventional
capabilities so I give you an example
what exactly how exactly ambiguous
hybrid cyber ops
or warfare looks like does anyone know
who this is I know you know this okay
this is the bronze soldier it's a statue
it stood in the center of Tallinn
Estonia beautiful city and in 2007 the
government decided to move the statue
from the center to a park not a big deal
you might might say but it was a big
deal because Estonia has a large Russian
ethnic community and this statue
portrays a Red Army soldier from World
War two and the society in Estonia is
basically torn in half
some think that the Red Army did good a
good job and the others think not so
much so what happened is they announced
to move the soldier the statue and the
Russian media picked up on the story and
twisted it and it turned it into a
different story
so the new story was that this statue
would not be moved to the outskirts but
it would be destroyed in addition to
that they told they they spread more
news fake news for example that the
graves of soldiers would also be
destroyed we call this augmented
information some call it fake news this
was a phase one of this type of warfare
the result was unrest
hundreds of people were injured one
person died thousand I think a thousand
were arrested and shortly afterwards
phase two of this type of warfare
started which was a cyberattack a DDoS
attack which basically took out ATM
machines banking machines slowed it down
communications of ministries and as we
know this was a very important
experience for the nation of Estonia and
changed everything in Estonia we have
seen more grave attacks more grave
ambiguous hybrid cyber attacks in the
Ukraine where the target was not only to
take out banking machines but actually
there they targeted SCADA networks and
electric power grids so this is what we
want to deter because no nation state
wants this to happen it has three kind
of types disruption espionage and
degradation what we mostly focus on are
these two mostly the third pillar
because you might say why would a
nation-state want to deter espionage
because it is conducting espionage
itself however there is a bit of a red
line for example my country was hacked a
while ago who the you know the basically
the high point was last year our
Parliament was hacked and you could say
this is classic espionage however the
German government didn't think so
for the first time in history four weeks
ago the German government issued an
official declaration were it announced
that it accuses Russia of this hack and
it warned Russia that this type of
espionage attack is not acceptable so
these two types of things we want to
stop the degradation and some parts of
espionage by a Modi I mean manipulation
of data
MLP means manipulation of perception and
bi means to alter the balance of
information these are things that
nation-states might want to determine
why do I want to deter this is actually
a big debate you might think that well
it's just cyber it's not so important we
should more focus on nuclear weapons or
conventional weapons or other stuff so
there's a big discussion going on if
these types of types of cyber operations
are something really serious or
something not so important so this
cartoon I think portrays it and
basically what's happening is there's
two camps there are the Hawks and the
doves the Hawks for example Richard
Clarke one of my teachers at Harvard he
used to be a national security adviser
and he says that this stuff these cyber
weapons it's it's a game changer it will
change everything and then there is the
other camp for example Thomas Reid who
is now at King's College he says no this
is not true all the cyber operations is
just a new form of espionage and we
shouldn't freak out
so I'm for transparency in the middle
leaning a little bit hawkish and why is
that I based this on some new data that
we have comprised in our project for our
publications and mostly Brendan Mariano
from the US Marine Corps University who
was one of the groundbreaking scholars
on this topic Brennan and others we have
looked at all major cyber operations
over the last 10 20 30 years and have
basically classified them along
something new which is along their
strategic effectiveness so we were not
so interested in classifying them in
terms of is this a DDoS or a PT or what
is it but we were interested in seeing
and figuring out if these cyber
operations had a real strategic impact
on the enemy and this has not really
been done before and to do this we
looked at the escalation potential of
cyberattacks and compared it to classic
strategic weapons or measures for
example classic military power which is
nuclear conventional forces classic
economic power think you might know is a
composite index for national
capabilities and we also looked at if a
country does a cyber operation and it
has done
many such operations before if that
changes to calculus so that's what we
call past cyber and the result is
interesting basically one of our
preliminary results is that the
strategic effect of cyber operations is
much weaker than that of classic
military or economic power now this is
good it's good to know it means that
some of the stuff we see is not as
impactful as we think it might be
however there is a trend which causes
concern in the past we have seen cyber
weapons that were in terms of intrusion
pretty low low quality in terms of
precision low quality and in terms of
visibility often hidden however we have
seen since Stuxnet a trend towards the
upper right quadrant here which means we
have highly visible highly precise
highly intrusive cyber weapons and they
are proliferated throughout the world
and by proliferation I mean back in the
days this stuff an apt like Stuxnet
could only be done by someone like
Israel and the u.s. now some other
players might be able to do this and
that's a reason for concern for the
future
the second
reason for concern is traditionally we
have been dealing with cyber weapons
within a very clearly defined domain
which is the military domain where I
want to protect airspace maritime and
land through cyberspace and if we have
people from the military here you know
that the main focus of cyberspace in
this scenario is to basically protect
and enable military create
communications and to certain type of
special operations but this is a domain
where the internet is not pervasive so
this is its own closed domain and I
might be able to exert a lot of control
however the new domain that we want to
protect is much larger for example if I
look at this map this is a global soak a
global risk interconnectedness map as a
bit of a mouthful but it shows you risks
that we face as societies and how they
are connected for example there's a food
crisis there at the top there's natural
disaster you know as all these types of
fiscal crises all these types of crises
now cyber as we know has become very
important for many verticals for the
economy for society for democracy some
people say that cyber security overlaps
with physical security and personal
security and corporate security so what
we've seen is that this area is becoming
bigger and bigger and more and more
connected with the rest meaning all the
stuff in red here is connected
- cybersecurity this has led to
militaries all over the world to
redefine their doctrinal approaches for
example in Germany if you read our
military strategy what the German army
should protect it now officially says
not just the classic military domain but
also the so called information space
which is everything and back in the days
we meant critical infrastructure like
nuclear power plans and stuff but now we
mean everything like how Siemens
communicates how we do elections it's
basically everything and that's a
problem because that creates a very
large attack surface so that's the
second reason for concern that what is
currently true that cyber weapons have
so far not you know created a large
strategic effect on the enemy might
change in the future now the third
reason is the matrix last time I was in
Tokyo that movie came out and we all
know the movie The Matrix and the
question is what is the matrix and the
answer is it depends on who you are so
the third reason why cyber weapons in
the future might become strategically
more effective is we might not be able
today to imagine the cyber weapon of the
future one of my teachers he called it
the unknown unknowns we think we can
predict but we might not be able why am
I saying this let's take Stuxnet
in Stuxnet in the Stuxnet case the
Americans looked at Stuxnet and for them
Stuxnet was a proof of concept for a
cyber weapon that can sabotage a
critical infrastructure they said okay
that's my weapon I'm doing this that's
working okay for the Russians they might
have looked at Stuxnet and they saw
something totally different
perhaps they saw that an Iranian admin
at the power plant looked at his screen
and believed the screen more than the
physical data he had and they were like
oh that manipulation of data is the
actual weapon not the sabotaging act so
some people say that Stuxnet was an
eye-opener for the Russians in terms of
how they would hack elections in the
future and others they would manipulate
data they didn't they wouldn't have to
destroy it
so this is a third reason for concern
now I want to quickly move to how to
deter because this is what we all want
to learn what can we do first
the rule of law very important we are in
a legal setting here we have to tell in
manual around 236 pages and now we have
the tally manual to double the size it's
like nearly 600 pages who has read the
whole thing ok nobody has the truth is
the rule of law is not working in
cyberspace unfortunately I have very
much hope it will we have though no
rules for the road in cyberspace yet we
have a couple of my lateral green
u.s. Chinese German Chinese some other
stuff forget it it's not working so the
second tool we could use if we have no
rules we could use the economy this is
what the Israelis do this is from a
friend of mine who is running what I run
in Germany is running that in Israel
these are all Israeli startups so what
Israel has done very successfully they
identified key areas that need to be
protected within their society
you know ecommerce enterprise mobility
cyber posture blah blah blah the whole
thing and then they created startups in
these packets or fostered them or the
investment and they specifically are
facing focusing on the stuff that's red
which is also dual use for the military
so you have basically cyber physical
systems in there other stuff that can
also be used for the military so that's
option one and I know that there is a
growing startup community and philosophy
in Japan for cyber and that's something
very positive option number two is you
want to make smart decisions within your
leadership on what horse to bet on
because there's a lot of stuff going on
in cyber security but what is going to
really be important in a couple of years
down the road well nobody knows but the
people from Gartner
tell us that they know and sell us their
predictions for a lot of money so this
is one of the Gartner so-called hype
indices and it shows you which
technology in cyber security is mature
so you can sell it within a framework of
you know fireEye or Accenture or
something that's on the very right side
that's the plateau of
activity that stuff we already sell and
packaged and then on the very left side
is the stuff that's kind of little
science fiction still and often we see
that these topics are hyped and then
there is a bit of a they call the TRO of
disillusionment you know because often
we see mmm is my threat intelligence
platform really performing you know is
there really machine learning and and
stuff like that so what's interesting is
I think there are three areas that might
be interesting for a society like Japan
or Germany one is hardware based
security chip level basically the other
one is threat intelligence platforms and
the third one is very early but breach
and attack simulations that's again very
useful for dual use so the third thing
you can do is naming and shaming this
photo up there I could tell you the
names of these four people because the
Netherlands this is the Secretary of
Defense of the Netherlands sitting there
one of her generals
just two months ago they did a press
conference telling the world the names
of these four guys and these are Russian
GRU GRU special operative operations
spies basically and this is a photo from
the airport somewhere and they're on the
way to Amsterdam I think to hack the
chemical something organization so this
is revolutionary that a government in
Europe does that it's never happened
before we call it naming and shaming
it's something you can do
Japan can do this you tell your enemy
that you know what he did and you also
tell your own population that you're not
okay with us starting a discussion
within the population
prepare your population for the next
attack where you might react with a
counter-strike so this this is what's
happening right now
Germany is doing the same we call in
naming and shaming also you criminalize
these attackers and pursue them through
the courts through Interpol and other
stuff it's very effective the other
thing is you can do sanctions the
Americans like to do that a lot
economic diplomatic you know we've seen
that Obama and President Obama did this
after the election hack he kicked some
diplomats out of the country that's a
that's another option you have as a
nation-state and finally you can create
a Cyber Command so we did that in
Germany this is the logo of the German
Cyber Command it's it's in Bonn and we
are now integrating it with our
bundesamt facie height psi which is run
under the Ministry of the Interior and
with the intelligence community and it's
very complicated thing to integrate
these players in cyber security and I'm
sure in Japan very smart people are
thinking about how to get this right so
this basically leads me to what my
project has been working on it's a
framework we call it agile cyber
deterrence which combines all of the
above this is our copyrighted not really
definition of agile cyber deterrence
what's important here is that it's a mix
of denial cost imposition and supporting
strategies I'll get to that in a minute
in domain as well as out domain so
within cyber but also outside of cyber
and what's really important is you want
to deter not only the classic armed
attack as the UN
defines it opteka 51 or 2 you know but
you want to also deter the stuff that
happens left of boom that happens before
the actual legal attack takes place so
our framework is based on four pillars
first you want to define what an attack
is and signal it communicate it clearly
to Yanam to your enemy so that he knows
oh if I do this I'm in trouble this
means basically that you need to define
for your society what is really crucial
and what is not and we and Germany
currently focus on the very right end of
this which is got a critical
infrastructure stuff like that but also
an election an election might be a taboo
you know you might signal to your enemy
to hack your election okay it's not a
nuclear power plant but still you don't
want that so this is important for your
society to figure out what is the taboo
and what is not then I don't have to
talk about denial this is what we all
deal with we want to increase cyber
resilience our defenses cost imposition
is very very controversial topic as you
all know how can you do offensive stuff
especially as a country like Japan or
Germany is very difficult to say how can
you at all raise the cost of an attacker
discussion about it we don't have time
to go into this supportive measures is
everything that the intelligence
community does embedded attribution
stuff like that
so finally what our policy options for
cyber middle powers like Germany or
Japan well for Japan it's interesting
because you are in a difficult spot
there's China that wants to bridge the
external gap they want to catch up
mostly with the US so they have engaged
in theft of intellectual property that's
bad you know that's that's fostering
their agenda what's good for us is they
also focus on internal issues they don't
want to have a revolution from inside so
they might be occupied with that Russia
is released as we know they are in a
weak position they want to get bigger
their expansionist but the good thing is
they have a low budget so then you come
to the u.s. they have domain superiority
not just in cyber but in other domains
that's bad for enemies of the u.s. good
for its friends what's also good for the
US as enemies is the u.s. is always very
hesitant to use its capabilities because
they don't want the enemies to know
about it so there's a bit of an
equilibrium him talking quickly because
I run out of time about China Japan is
facing something that my colleagues in
Australia call picking flowers in
foreign countries and making honey at
home in China so one thing that China
and that Japan is facing is basically
they look at technology in Japan they
look at know-how at universities they
might bring it back to their own turf
and use it for their own cyber
capabilities so this is something you
should have on the screen there's a new
study about this from the Australian
Institute for Strategic Studies and
finally there's a lot of stuff happening
in the mergers and acquisitions market
big players I mean you have Softbank but
big players are buying up cybersecurity
startups all over the board it's a boom
for cybersecurity emerges in
acquisitions
the market is now 95 billion its
projected to be 365 billion and 2026
that is huge so you want to get your M&A
market right finally the message I just
want to you know bring from Germany so
to say to you as a cyber middle power
you can actually have strategic
influence if you partner with others
within a network structure that has
specific capabilities assigned to the
partners so there's a long theory in
international affairs about the network
view of power for middle part for middle
powers like Japan or Germany and what's
happening is we apply this to cyber
power so one thing the Germany is doing
right now we are partnering with the
Netherlands with friends with Luxembourg
with Estonia with other middle powers so
to say form coalition's of the Willing
to basically have a better posture in
cyber security visa vie the cyber
superpowers such as China u.s. or with
the US Russia and I think a partnership
between Germany and Japan would be
something valuable potentially valuable
in the future in the space so that's it
if you're bored you can read about all
this in this little publication or send
me an email
I'd love to hear from you I thank you
very much for your time and look forward
to the discussions thank you
[Applause]