all right so as mentioned this is about
remotely cracking bluetooth-enabled gun
safes and verifying the secure
implementation of Bluetooth low-energy
devices I'm Austin Fletcher my lead
vulnerability research engineer at two
six labs this is Dan su he's a senior
research engineer at 2/6 and we both do
software and hardware security there we
work on embedded systems security team
where we do product security for various
IOT and embedded systems and we also
perform fundamental research into
security including Hardware side channel
analysis so we're going to be going over
a brief introduction of the topic as
well as an overview of Bluetooth Low
Energy security will tell you about how
we found these issues in this safe we
have a demonstration and then we will
talk a little bit about how to avoid
making these mistakes in your product so
as mentioned this is about a gun safe in
this case it's a vaulteq v t20i smart
gun safe we're gonna look at some of the
poor implementation decisions that they
made and hopefully teach you some best
practices on how to avoid some of these
in your product so the gun safe is one
of Amazon's best selling gun safes it
has a number of really cool features it
was successfully funded through a
crowdfunding campaign and it's very
popular so popular that one of our
co-workers actually purchased one of
these safes and he was talking about it
and we decided hey that would be cool to
take a look at it it has Bluetooth
functionality and we thought it would be
really neat to try to break into this
safe through the Bluetooth functionality
without actually needing to know any of
the pin code or anything else required
so we spent a couple of days on it and
this presentation is a result of that
work so this safe like I said it
features a Bluetooth but it also
features another a couple of ways to
access it
including biometrics in this case of
fingerprints it has some physical
buttons on the top so it allows you to
enter a PIN code to open it as well as
taking a key and it's advertised as
being securely designed which is why we
really wanted to try to break it so why
a gun safe well in America gun ownership
is very very common almost a third of
all households have a firearm inside of
it and responsible gun owners will
typically try to utilize a gun safe to
keep keep it away from their children
things like that but they still want
access to these safes in the event of an
emergency like somebody breaking into
their house so the problem here really
is that historically speaking secure
systems like this like this gun safe or
bank vault or something would be hard to
break into they would require either
specialized tools or knowledge or lots
of destructive noisy processes to break
into and people got really good at
designing these secure systems so one of
the things that they do though is they
make it hard to actually access the
system harder or time-consuming and
that's something that consumers don't
really like so to address this
manufacturers started adding
functionality like Bluetooth or
biometrics things that allow a user to
more easily access their safe or device
in general adding IOT functionality to a
system that historically has never had
one before and this is of course
increasing the attack surface of the
device which is great for me as an
attacker because increasing the attack
surface gives me four more vectors into
your devices and securing these sorts of
access vectors is very difficult so in
other words we're going to from breaking
into a safe to being something like this
where you
you are actually drilling or being
destructive to get into the safe into a
situation where you have something like
a laptop that's just running some code
that we wrote and it's going to just
connect we have Bluetooth to the safe
and we should see the safe open and
we'll get into how this works but we're
really lowering the barrier to entry
here so we decided to start looking at
the IOT communications of this product
as we often do and we're looking
initially for things like eavesdropping
or the ability to perform a
man-in-the-middle attack or even just be
able to track where these devices are so
in the case for eavesdropping here we
might be able to intercept the pin code
as the user is opening the safe or
possibly replay a valid opening sequence
or in the case of tracking maybe we
could track if a user moves one of these
safes or maybe even just drive down the
street and see who has one in each
neighborhood so we'll talk a little bit
about some high-level Bluetooth Low
Energy security
so Bluetooth Low Energy is very very
popular it's in a lot of devices that we
all have phones fitness trackers watches
your car they're cheap to produce
products with these things just a lot of
commercial system on chips that you just
buy will support bluetooth off the shelf
and typically when people are developing
these products they're concerned with
rapid development and mass market sales
so they're trying to make it cheaply and
efficiently and they're maybe not giving
the kind of respect to the security
aspect as they should and we'll see
later on that Bluetooth Low Energy has
various things that you can do to help
secure product but a lot of these
require additional hardware or have some
impacts on battery life that a lot of
developers don't really want
and so due to these issues a lot of
devices rely on the least secure
possible operation of modes with
bluetooth and security issues are
extremely a common across these devices
so Bluetooth Low Energy is really a
marketing term for like Bluetooth for so
this is kind of split there's a number
of versions it's kind of split between
four point to secure and later and four
point two and earlier which becomes
legacy and so the difference between
this legacy and four point to secure is
how they do a key exchange in the
pairing process so is pretty quickly
identified that there is a deficiency in
the key exchange if somebody observes
this key exchange in the legacy version
they're able to break the future
encryption between the devices and so in
four point to secure they fix this by
switching to an elliptic curve
diffie-hellman key exchange since this
device that we're looking at and a lot
of other devices support this legacy
mode that's what we're going to be
talking about mostly here so looking at
this pairing method it starts off with a
pre connection phase this is where a
device is going to be can out and say
hey I'm a device that you can connect to
assuming that that user wants to connect
to that you move on to phase one which
is where a feature discovery and an
exchange of capabilities is going to
take place this is how they determine
what security modes they're going to use
and in Phase two they start trading keys
and this is where the encryption begins
and then in phase three is where the
devices become bonded together and that
pairing process completes and becomes
permanent so starting with the pre
connection phase you have a peripheral
device in this case our safe it's going
to be beaconing out an advertisement a
phone is going to receive this
advertisement and it'll pop up in the
app and say hey do you want to connect
to me the user is lux that they want to
connect and it starts with with this
connection request moving on to phase
one these devices have now completed
this initial connection and this is when
they're going to start
talking about what security modes
they're going to use in the future
and specifically what association mode
is going to be used for the temporary
key so an important note here is that
the actual device capabilities and
what's actually being advertised might
differ so a lot of hardware supports
more secure or later versions of
Bluetooth than they're actually going to
be using during this pairing phase so
getting to these association modes they
determine how this key this temporary
key is going to be generated the
temporary key is a hundred and twenty
eight bit value depending on the
Association mode it doesn't necessarily
come up with all 128 bits so if that's
the case it'll be padded to 128 bits
with nulls and these association modes
include just works out of band and pass
P starting with just works it uses the
same key as Kanye's iPhone which is just
all zeros it's the most basic connection
mechanism acting as a fallback for other
devices it doesn't have any hardware
additional hardware overhead if you're
following some tutorial online there's a
very good chance that it's going to be
using that just works mechanism it's
commonly used in things like speakers
and headphones and other cheap sort of
devices next we have out-of-band which
is where we're going to distribute this
temporary key out of band so it's not
going to be in the Bluetooth Channel so
this is commonly seen in like headphones
using NFC or in the case of this Apple
watch it has kind of a swirling mass of
dots you hold your iPhone above it and
it captures the motion of this and
that's how it transmits the key it's the
most secure option available to you but
it does have the hardware requirements
either the NFC or a camera or screen
something of that nature last one we'll
talk about here is the passkey this is
where one device generates a key and a
user has to actually input that into
another device it requires one device to
have a screen and another
have an input mechanism I've commonly
seen this used in things like car
infotainment systems so now we have this
temporary key we're going to use this to
form the encryption if this link is
going to be encrypted and we use it to
generate this short-term key the
short-term key is going to be used to
actually encrypt the future
communications going into Phase three
now if an attacker listens in Donna's
key exchange in legacy mode since all of
these values and the equations are known
they can break the future encryption
algorithms so in phase three we perform
a long-term key distribution so there's
a few keys involved here some of them
are exchanged to help devices recognize
the devices over a long period of time
so one of the things that devices do or
they or they can do is they can change
their physical MAC address over time to
help prevent tracking and so some of
these help resolve that over time and at
the end of this the devices are bonded
which means that the future connections
don't necessarily need to go through
this full pairing process again so there
are some built-in mitigation as to what
we've talked about previously in
Bluetooth so for eavesdropping there's
link layer encryption using AES 128 bit
encryption and then in 4.2 secure and
later they switch this diffie-hellman
key exchange which gives a protection
against man-in-the-middle and
eavesdropping they also add this other
association mode called numeric
comparison where you have two devices
with screens and they each display a
number and a user asked to verify the
authenticity of each device and then it
provides that tracking protection by
allowing the device to change its
physical address over time so
mitigations are great but just because
the features are available doesn't mean
that they're necessarily going to be
used
again if you follow some demos or
examples online oftentimes they don't
pay any attention to any of these steps
and the security of the encrypted
channel relies on the confidentiality of
the key exchange for the legacy mode
especially and the Association modes
that are the easiest to exploit are also
the simplest to implement and have the
lowest hardware requirements so as you
start looking at some of the claims that
these devices make like this safe it
claims to use 256 bit AES and Bank level
encryption so these aren't supported at
the protocol layer an application layer
you can implement whatever schemes you
want however doing something like this
takes more processing power and would
decrease battery life it also adds
complexity and so really they're not
going to do this so big red flag for us
so looking at finding the
vulnerabilities that exist in the safe
we start out like we often do with
product security reviews and we start
looking at the documentation for the
device we start learning how people use
it how the developers use it and how
users use it we do open source research
we want to see if anyone has hacked the
thing previously and we want to evaluate
the attack surface so we look at things
like the input output for the device and
what communications channels it uses if
the device is more or less a black box
meaning it doesn't have many of these
things available to us or in this case
our safe a good first step is going to
be to analyze the communications that it
uses under normal operation so in normal
operation we have our safe it's going to
beacon at it's advertisement a user is
going to be using the app in this case
the Android app they'll see the safes
pop up in the app and they can choose to
pair with it
assuming they choose to pair with a
they are brought to the screen where it
wants a pin code and the pin code here
would be the same numeric pin code that
a user would type in on the top of the
safe to get it to open and should be
noted that the pairing in that step step
is actually separate than the bluetooth
pairing that's already happened at this
point and this is an application-level
pairing that happens assuming the user
puts in their correct pin code then
they're presented with another screen
that allows them to initiate commands on
the safe like open it or change the
lighting various other things so back to
this application so like we said the
safes just beaconing out Hey connect to
me
assuming a user wants to connect to it
they're able to so this allows anyone
near the safe to attempt to connect to
it and enter this pin code so right away
that's a bad sign but in doing this
process we realized that the application
doesn't have any penalties for incorrect
pin code entries so that allows you to
do something pretty quickly like are
lousy attempt here just brute forcing
the key since it doesn't penalize you in
any way for getting it wrong you can
quickly exhaust the key space for entry
into this safe since it only supports
four to eight digit PIN codes with
numbers one through five available we
just wrote this Python script and
instrumented the application over a TB
and we're able to log into the safe now
this is a vulnerability but this isn't
what we want it to find this isn't good
enough so where do we go from here
well we don't have too much else to look
at at this point so we're gonna look at
this network communication so let's look
at the Bluetooth level so we're gonna
try to capture user pairing with and
opening the safe so I'm gonna hand it
over to Dan here to talk more about this
bluetooth capture process
all right so the next phase we want to
like Austin said capture the
communication between the application
and the safe so how do we do that so we
use this device called the uber tooth
one it is a USB dongle
that can be used to monitor Bluetooth
and perform analysis on the capture the
capture can be imported into Wireshark
and the device is relatively cheap and
has good documentation online it's also
an open source platform so those are the
reasons why we liked it there's a link
for that there hopefully if you can see
that so what you did was we took a
capture of you know just playing around
with the safe we opened up the
application we connected to the safe
sent it a few commands right unlocked it
you know dimmed the LEDs a little bit it
was messing around so the next step is
we take this capture that we just did
right that contains these various
actions that we took and we opened it up
in Wireshark immediately what we can see
is that the the capture is unencrypted
or the communication is unencrypted the
the write commands that the application
is sending to the safe are in the clear
see the payload they're you know just
taking a look at it briefly there are
some interesting data sequences that are
being exchanged but at this point we
really don't understand the application
protocol so just an example of encrypted
versus unencrypted the image at the top
is just an encrypted capture so what we
see is like an encryption request and
then you know afterwards it's just layer
2 fragments that we can't decrypt and
then the unencrypted traffic right we
can basically see everything that's
going
so that was actually just like a quick
and easy you know when so in the case
where there is encryption you know you
can still deal with that based off what
Austin said right the issue with the
pairing exchange so a nice tool to use
is a crackle this will perform the
brute-force attack on on that
vulnerability and you will be able to
brute force the temporary key using this
tool alongside the uber tooth so at this
point we have a few options that we can
take we can you know continue with the
Bluetooth captures take a look at the
android apk or iOS application another
option is just to take the firmware off
the device ray and analyze that instead
so you know the the step that we took
was just taking a look at the android
apk and this was because sometimes these
apks are relatively easy to understand
and reverse-engineer we can decompile
the apk and hopefully it doesn't use
office Gatien right even if there is
obfuscation there are ways to deal with
that but you know just hope for the best
so it ended up actually that the apk
wasn't up if you skated too heavily but
the tools that we used to analyze it so
first off we download the apk from an
apk archive website there are various of
these around one example that we used
was apk mirror so it just allows you to
download apk is without a phone you can
also grab archived versions
sorry historical versions so once we get
this apk we run a PK tool and Dexter jar
on it this gives us the Java classes
back and then we open those up in ad
compiler
so we used wayton which is a GUI for the
Pratt County compiler there are other
ones out there but just what we used so
opening up the apk you know first we
want to just take a look at what's
inside take a look at the hierarchy as
well as the the class names you know see
if anything pops up and then you know
look for points of interest inside those
classes so things that we're looking for
are just communication between services
you know any type of hard-coded
definitions hard-coded constants you
know interesting strings you know that
might have to do with the safe just you
know anything to interact with the safe
in general so the the first point of
interest we found was in the order utils
VT xx class we found you know various
commands in there with constant
definitions and these seem to be the
application layer commands that the apk
is using to communicate with the device
and you know there are a few in there
there's like command author command info
command finger door right so that kind
of sounds like it has something to do
with opening the safe you weren't sure
about what some of the other ones meant
but you know at this point we just want
to see if these are inside the capture
so unfortunately we didn't immediately
see these magic constants in the capture
but we do know that our Bluetooth
capture right contains these commands
somehow because we did interact with the
safe we did you know unlock the safe we
did messed around with the LEDs so they
should be in there some in some form so
you must be missing something so the
next step is we have to go back into the
apk you know see what they're doing with
those commands and it ends up you know
it's being transformed there's some type
of encoding and packing function that's
being applied before they are being
transmitted
so that's why we couldn't see them
directly in the capture so fortunately
for us the this packing algorithm is
easy to understand what they do is they
they take the command payload they
divide it into 20 by trunks and then
bytes in these chunks are then split off
by the each nibble is split off you know
added to 20 added to 97 and then store
it as its own byte so you transform like
one bite into two there's an image on
the bottom that shows this the image on
the top is just the function that
performs this so we don't really know
why they did this but they just do it
it's real it's totally simple to reverse
image to left just shows us joining
those bytes back together and script to
do that so at this point we want to
apply our decoding to the actual capture
and just see what commands are being
sent so we do that and we we see a you
know a couple of commands and then here
this image shows the timing diagram of
the commands so we see you know it's
doing this like pair command and keep in
mind this is the application pairing
command so not the same as a bluetooth
pairing but it's sending some type of
you know pair command get author setting
the time you know opening the door
opening the safe perhaps and then a
bunch of other commands initially you
know some of them were not that
interesting we kind of glanced over them
like yet author but and if this command
was actually pretty essential and we can
talk about that next slide so again we
initially thought this command stood for
you know get author get author of like
the app I get author of some
type of right requests but actually
stands for get authorization so what you
use this command for is use it to
request an authorization token and in
the structure this command you actually
send it with the pin code to that safe
so there's a field in there if you see
the image that's reserved for that pin
code so immediately here there's an
issue because someone who's
eavesdropping can't see this command
being sent the pin code is in there
right so they can extract the pin code
and identify what that is
for the device so what the authorization
request responds with is the safe will
give you back for by authorization token
using this token you can then issue
privileged commands so a sample of a
privileged command is just opening up
the safe right so below there's an
example of that where you take the four
by authorization token you place it in
the first four bytes of the open command
you send that right and then lets you
open it up so it ends up if all you want
to do is just you know connect to the
safe and open it up the the bare minimum
that you need to do right is just to
request authorization and then you know
get that auth token and then send the
open command with the auth token right
so some of the other commands that we
saw before were not really necessary for
that task so at this point you know we
understand this application layer
protocol a little bit better what we
want to do is you want to you know play
around with it a little bit modify some
payloads see what happens so at this
point we're not using the app anymore to
communicate with the device we're using
our laptops and we chose to use this
no js' bluetooth library called noble
and manly and just due to cross-platform
support you know so using this library
we just mess around with the safe and
also we use a tool called packet logger
on Mac it's just a neat Mac tool for
sniffing or sorry for examining
Bluetooth traffic so so we did is a you
test around with the safe we issue some
unlock commands you know we want to make
sure that we're not hitting some type of
cash or pre-authorized behavior so we
changed the pin code right you know
rerun it see what happens and you know
like the safe opened so it was this was
very surprising to us so you know at
first we didn't you know we thought we
made a mistake or something right but
that ends up that uh the safe actually
doesn't check the pin code of the get
authorization request it just ends up
always responding with an authorization
token you know even if you give it the
wrong pin code so that's that's pretty
bad right that's a that's like this
image right where you have this
absolutely failure for security where
you have you know this lock door but we
can just kind of ignore it and go around
so what what this ends up meaning is
that any attacker can open this device
by just issuing two commands right
and we also verified this by purchasing
a brand new device off Amazon and right
out of the box right worked so the
results I guess these safes right there
constantly broadcasting advertisements
anyone can connect to them and then you
know during normal operation
when a user right tries to open the door
it transmits the pin code into clear so
that's a big issue too
and then you know the really bad one
where anyone can kind of connect to
these devices request an authorization
code with any pin value right get that
authorization token back and then use
that to unlock the device you can also
do other cool stuff right like dim the
LEDs if you want oh and there's also no
remote update mechanism that we are
aware of so this should work quite
reliably with any device in this series
so here's a demo video of this place so
at this step we're just showing the pin
code is set to 5 4 3 2 1
we're running this unlock command sorry
unlock scripts it's waiting for that
advertisement for the safe once it gets
that it's going to issue that
authorization request get back that
authorization token and it opened it and
now we change the password just to show
that you know you don't even need to
know the password to open it so we
change it to 1 2 3 4 5 we're gonna run
the exact same script and it's gonna do
the same process right it's just gonna
wait for that advertisement so here it's
scanning it's gonna wait for the
advertisement once it hits that
advertisement it's gonna issue that
authorization request get the
authorization token back and then unlock
it right so same process doesn't matter
all right with that I'm gonna hand it
back to Austin for the next part all
right so we've seen several failures
that have been made in the design of
this product so let's talk about some
good practices for your products so some
really simple things you can do or that
would have helped here would be
something like even hiding the
manufacturer or name string and the
Bluetooth advertisement so as it is here
all of these safes are beaconing out hey
I'm a vault X safe and now we know that
all these vault X safes are vulnerable
so if we ever see one of these
advertisements we can just open it so
you can imagine driving down a street or
something and just popping all these
open so if that wasn't broadcast out in
the open then I we would at least have
to do some kind of work to figure out if
this device was one of these safes you
want to use a software application
obfuscation so again this applicant riod
application we were just basically able
to decompile and get back readable
source something as simple as ProGuard
or something else would have made it
that much harder to get to that point
and that's really what you want to do is
make my job as an attacker harder so
this isn't a guarantee of security but
it just raises that bar that much higher
and something that would have really
helped here would have been implementing
a pairing enable switch on the device so
just allowing any user to pair to the
safe at any time it's probably a pretty
bad idea
so if there is a key press sequence or
an actual button on the safe that you
had to hit to initiate this pairing at
least the first time then that would at
least require some kind of physical
access to the device and you want to use
the most secure bluetooth version and
association modes available to you so
you want to use out-of-band if you can
it's the most secure you want to use
bluetooth for point to secure mode and
later with that diffie-hellman key
exchange and possibly most importantly
you can't think like these manufacturers
you can't think that they can't break
your encryption if you don't use any
encryption you have to use that link
layer encryption that the protocol
allows you to so some other general tips
you want to keep all of the data that is
sensitive encrypted so even beyond the
link level if they had taken that pin
code and that get authorization field
and maybe entangled it was some other
user to find secret then it wouldn't
have even mattered if we could have you
know captured it you want to assume
scenarios where you have a full physical
compromise of the product so assume that
somebody's going to be tearing apart
your product pulling off the firmware
assume that we're going to be taking
your application and reverse engineering
it because we are and you want to really
keep in mind that the more avenues and
communication pathways and things that
you add to your applications
that's just broadening the attack
surface so it's making my job as an
attacker easier the more things you add
the harder it is to secure in the case
here you want to use really strong
credential policies so having that
really short key space and having the
really small key space allows an
attacker to brute force the pin code in
this case and even if you are going to
use credential policies don't give a
user an unlimited number of retries to
get a get it right give them some kind
of timeout something like that and you
really need to understand the security
implications of subcontracting out
development so in this case when we
started looking at the software
application it became apparent to us
that it was a Chinese company that
developed the application and they
primarily do I owe t subcontracting for
various vendors and that's pretty common
right not everyone has the in-house
talent or resources necessary to build a
product from end to end and so it's
pretty common to subcontract out various
pieces of the development and but you
want to keep in mind that some
these subcontractors don't necessarily
have the same security model that you
might so you need a way to really verify
that they're implementing their pieces
in a secure manner so some other things
you can do for prevention and
remediation so like dansa there's not
really a remote firmware update
mechanism for this you don't want to be
caught in the scenario like this company
where you have to put on your website
that they're offering an upgrade if you
mail your safe back to them so having
user have to physically send the device
back is probably pretty pretty bad some
simple things you can do you can run a
bug bounty program so give out a small
cash award to various parties when they
find bugs in your in your product that
helps increase the scope and talent pool
that you have looking at your product
and usually those are parties they'll
sign NDA's and various other things to
protect your secrets
you can also engage in professional
security audits it's something that my
company does we take a look at your
product under NDA we analyze it and we
come up with any possible ways we can
find to break into it and we help you to
secure these issues going forward and
you want to keep an open communication
pipeline and that's with both the
security community and with your
consumers so if you do have an issue or
a bug that comes up don't deny it
keep be open about it and you want to be
as open as possible the easiest thing
you can really do here though is start a
responsible disclosure program and that
can be as simple as having security at
your domain calm and just receiving
disclosures when researcher finds your
vulnerability so that's really all we
have here here are email addresses you
can feel free to contact us if you want
to talk about product security or
embedded system security or if you want
to hear more about the same
if we also have a blog post written up
about this safe that you can check out
addresses also here