Julia Birkhoff ah I'm a policy fellow
with the European Leadership Network
which is a think tank based in London
and which covers a broad range of topic
topics including European and
transatlantic security as well as the
relations between Russia and the West so
I'm very happy and honored to get a
chance here to speak at this amazing
conference about nuclear weapons and and
cyber risks it's may be fair to say at
the beginning that I'm not having a
specific cyber background instead my
field of interest is rather nuclear arms
control disarmament and
non-proliferation as well as NATO and
European security so the reason why I
want to talk to you about cyber risks
risks for nuclear weapon systems today
is that this is a highly under address
topic in the scientific as well as in
the public and another political sphere
whereby they I think there's a clear
evidence that cyber will become a key
aspect when it when we think about
nuclear deterrence and strategic
stability in the future so I assume that
most of you might not be familiar with
nuclear deterrence and global stockpiles
and NATO arrangements and that's why I
want to start with some very basic about
nuclear weapons and then stockpiles
second part of my presentation will give
you an idea of what do we actually
understand as a cyber threat to nuclear
weapon systems the third part I will
walk you through some examples of cyber
attacks that directly or indirectly
related to nuclear weapon systems the
third part I will speak briefly about
national awarenesses and here the US and
France will be examples and the last
part will be dedicated to some policy
recommendations on how we could enhance
cybersecurity and resilience in the
future now let's have a look at some
basic knowledge about nuclear weapons as
you can see in this slide there are four
categories of state
possess nuclear weapons themselves or
who host them on their soil the first
group is two so-called p5 states these
are the members of the UN Security
Council the US Russia China France and
the United Kingdom who legitimately
possess nuclear weapons under the
non-proliferation treaty or NPT the NPT
is an almost global treaty that allows
only for these five states to to possess
nuclear weapons
the second group includes three states
that never joined the NPT but run their
own nuclear weapons programs bring
programs which is India Pakistan and
Israel I put Israel in italics because
it never publicly confirmed it has
nuclear weapons but it's quite clear
that Israel has an arsenal the third
country is some is a country that made
headlines globally during the last month
in particular which is North Korea the
country joint a NPT in 1985 and
unilaterally withdrew in 2003 in order
to develop its own nuclear weapons
program and since there was no formal
procedure to to withdraw from the NPT
the DPRK is regarded as being in preach
of the treaty and last but not least a
very interesting interesting group of
states that do not possess nuclear
weapons themselves but Hirst in total
about 200 to 250 US nuclear weapons on
the soil due to the so called Native
NATO nuclear sharing arrangement which
is basically a form of deterrence
against Russia and this is caught this
is interesting because these weapons do
not really belong to the countries they
just host them which is Germany Italy
Belgium the Netherlands and Turkey so in
the next slide you can see how many
warheads each of the nuclear weapon
states holds by now except for the NATO
nuclear sharing countries the total
number is about 15,000 nuclear weapons
worldwide approximately 90% of them are
in the hands of the US and Russia both
of them have about 6500 nuclear weapons
in China have about 300 India and
Pakistan between 130 and hundred 40 the
UK a bit more than 200 Israel about 80
and North Korea is said to have about 50
nuclear weapons so to better understand
where there could be a threat coming
from the cyber nuclear Nexus we should
first understand what actually what
actually is a nuclear weapons system and
what what are its components so when I
hear people talking about nuclear
weapons bearden politics or in the media
or even in the academic field they
sometimes only refer to one part of the
nuclear weapon system which is the
nuclear weapon or the warhead itself so
you can see this on the left side of the
slide I put there a small w88 term
thermonuclear warhead as an example or
they just refer to the nuclear warhead
and its delivery system which is
basically aircraft ballistic and cruise
missiles and drones maybe you heard
about President Putin talking about
developing a nuclear-armed underwater
drone but the nuclear weapons system
itself includes far more there is for
example the nuclear planning in case of
NATO it's for example the nuclear
planning group where all NATO states
participate except for France they are
early warning system which is usually a
2-fold system made up of Rada and
satellites then we have of course the
command and control centers we have
various communication channels and
platforms like aircraft carriers and
submarines reen's which you can see on
the top right side so this is of course
a very simplified overview because there
are for example a variety of different
types of missiles and aircraft etc which
I did not include in my presentation
because that would take us too far so
now coming to the question what actually
poses a threat to nuclear weapon systems
maybe you've heard this famous quote by
Donald Rumsfeld in 2002 where he
basically said sometimes we don't know
what we don't know and that's exactly
what should make us absolutely nervous
about nuclear cyber incidents that we
don't know what we don't know so when we
want to understand the threat we have to
look at different aspects so the first
question is who are the potential actors
who might be interested in carrying out
a cyber attack against any nuclear
weapon systems there are researchers who
stick to the point that when you want to
cause a huge physical damage to your
nuclear weapons system you need to have
vast resources you need to have capable
personnel and of course to know that so
it's easier for States to carry out
these types of a text and for
individuals or non-state actor groups
others think that non active groups or
non-state actor groups like terrorist
groups or maybe organized crime groups
might be more interested because they
have nothing to lose in terms of
reputation but if we look for example at
a Stuxnet attack which was probably
designed by the US and Israel to attack
Iranian nuclear facilities or for
example at us who send warnings to the
DPRK that it could infiltrate its
nuclear weapon system then we see that
national actors do it in in fact have a
clear interest in carrying out cyber
attacks as well at least in theory so
second what types of attacks do exist
friendly speaking there's not a clear
definition of cyber attacks in a nucleus
fear so like in any other field it could
range from a sick simple help hacking to
nuisance cyber espionage infiltration
infiltration sabotage jamming and
spoofing to physical damage and on the
top of the letter nuclear escalation we
also have to differentiate between an
enabling and disabling attack so an
enabling attack means that a nuclear
weapon might be launched inadvertently
as a result of a false warning for
example on the other hand a disabling
attack would hinder the launch of a
nuclear weapon and
two possible targets of a cyberattack
and we will speak about this in a minute
is any part of the command and control
and communication structure referred to
as either C 2 or C 3 whether you you
take in communication or not as well as
any state within the nuclear supply
chain including power grids so the next
crucial question is what are the
possible implications for strategic
stability between nation states
especially when we keep in mind that at
least a year transatlantic community
finds itself in kind of a renewed Cold
War situation and key nuclear arms
control treaties and agreements are
about to fade away thinking only about
Iran deal and the INF treaty and maybe
the New START treaty as well and in
future so even in a less tense situation
than we face now the very possibility of
a cyber attack could undermine mutual
trust and understanding and also
progress in arms control globally it
could also undermined a trust in your
own nuclear weapon system because you
you can never be sure it hasn't been
compromised yet it could also contribute
to lowering the threshold for escalation
of course and here we have the serious
program of the attribution of a
cyberattack like in any other field but
despite of all this when we look at
nuclear deterrents as a concept as long
as they're on well the implications are
that grave in the short or midterm on
nuclear deterrence as a concept which
means that as long as there is not a
definite trend towards amaya cyber
attacks nuclear deterrence as the
primary security guarantee for nation
states will not be undermined noble
state starts you to immediately disarm
because they think there could be cyber
attacks in the future but still as I
mentioned above there will be possibly a
harmful effect on mutual trust and
understanding and nuclear deterrence
might get less foreseeable and metal and
possibly less controllable so that means
we couldn't keep on relying on historic
knowledge about nuclear deterrence and
how it works in the best case
ideal setting but in state states we'll
always have to include cyber in their
national planning in the future so with
the next two slides I would like to give
you an idea of where the nuclear comma
command control and communication
systems as well as the nuclear supply
chain are vulnerable to a possible cyber
attack and please keep in mind what a
what I meant that I mentioned there's a
variety of possible types of attacks so
this will never be an exhaustive list of
course but rather the attempt to make
the threat more understandable for you
and to give you some more concrete
examples so you can see the read errors
in the slide each of them symbolizes a
cyber attack or maybe a malware
infiltration the boxes and the symbols
are different parts of the nuclear
weapons system as we already know it
from the slide at the beginning another
question is what what could happen
possibly something that could be done
rather easily is that communication
between key actors is being disrupted or
disabled for example communication
between senior military leaders in the
command and control centers could be
disrupted or between a national command
and control and its counterpart in
Allied countries this applies mostly to
to NATO countries the whole nuclear
planning structure could be compromised
for example if they don't get vital
information about their own system or
about for example about incoming threat
from from adversaries and communication
channels with delivery systems and
platforms could be disrupted as well so
another scenario is that there is a
false warning of attack thanks to cyber
spoofing this is very crucial that's why
I put it in red if for example the right
a sense of warning to the command and
control that there's a missile flying
over to a country they might be not
enough time to wait for sufficient
additional data coming from satellites
so this could force a state to to answer
by launching a nuclear what what the
state thinks is a nuclear second strike
but in fact is a nuclear first truck
next scenario is that a security system
which keeps warheads missiles aircraft
etc safe and secure get compromised
think about a possible theft of a
warhead and of course an attack does not
have to be carried out remotely but
could also come from an insider whether
he does that deliberately or not and one
last very frightening scenario is that
another state or maybe a state-sponsored
group gets access to an adversary's
nuclear weapon systems and gets control
over their nuclear weapons and
authorizes a launch remotely so the
other sensitive area is the whole
nuclear weapons supply chain the supply
chain could be infiltrated at any stage
a potential attacker will always strive
to find a weakest link in the supply
chain so you can see the different
phases again very simplified to make it
less complex in the slide the supply
chain can be compromised at a very early
stage namely the system architectures
and the design process for example a
computer chip could get compromised so
that hackers could later exfiltrate data
from the chip while the chip itself
seems to function normally so computer
chips are indeed a very interesting
example in this in this case because
most of the countries do not produce
them themselves on the National Defense
unit but instead purchased them from the
global markets that's that's highly
crucial here attacks on manufacturers
and private firms can potentially
include efforts to steal data to corrupt
data to sabotage equipment and to
disable networks and although attacks
like the Stuxnet attack and wanna cry
ransom wear are to date very rare
examples of successful and serious
attacks the complexities and
interdependencies within a supply chain
are on the rise which in fact means that
risks are multiplying
constantly and on the level of state-run
nuclear weapons programs if we're in the
next stage remote interference plays an
important role but also insider threat
threats as we as we saw in the last
slide either they are deliberately
carried out or not and a further
critical stage is the process of
maintenance upgrades and modernization
because of course nuclear weapons have
to be captain as modern assays as safe
and secure as they could but at the same
time the more sophisticated a system
gets the more vulnerable it is to
attacks so we always think we make them
more safe and more secure once we
modernize them but at the same time it
carries huge risks for us and of course
the power grid could also be infiltrated
so maybe you still think that a cyber
attack on nuclear or nuclear related
systems are a bit too fictional so to
dispel your doubts a bit let me give you
some examples the first one is that
computer scream of a nuclear watch
officer say in the US indicates that one
or more Russian intercontinental
ballistic missiles are about to hit any
target in the United States so how could
the officer be sure that this is not
just cyber spoofing and more importantly
how will this respond hope will
dispersant respond taking into account
the very short time for a decision so
something similar happened maybe you
remember that back in 1983 when a random
Soviet officer was confronted with five
or more US ICBMs flying over to Russia
and he decided not to authorize a
counter attack and of course this was
just in a computer era at that time but
it's just it's pretty conceivable that a
similar effect could be caused
deliberately by a cyber attack another
scenario is that military officials are
not able to communicate with their
personal
trolling the nuclear weapons during an
international crisis so what would they
think had happened and how will they
respond so again the question is that
plausible there was a similar incident
back in 2010 when American launch
control officers have lost for the whole
time of 45 minutes communication with a
squadron of 50 nuclear tipped ICBMs in
Wyoming so this too was the result of a
technical malfunction but here again
it's possible that a corresponding
effect could be caused deliberately by a
cyberattack and also in general if
officials discover malware on a nuclear
critical system and they suspect that
this was just a tip of the well the
cyber iceberg how will they react what
would they think and this is the reason
why the u.s. National Nuclear Security
Administration stated two years ago the
trend toward a non domestic supply chain
four components of nuclear weapons and
related systems may pose risks to these
weapons and systems so this indicates
very clearly that they are aware of the
risk at least in the u.s. so do you
still have doubts if so please look at a
picture I think you will clearly
remember - that was a computer error a
few months ago and that shocked have I
during the very height of the North
Korean crisis when Hawaiians thought a
ballistic missile was flying over - to
them so in the third part of my
presentation I will talk about some
cyber attacks on directly or indirectly
nuclear related systems that happened in
the past years and again that's not an
exhaustive list it's just a a couple of
examples that might be interesting for
you so I will start with what New York
Times columnist David Sanger described
as the most sophisticated cyber weapon
ever developed and this was the Stuxnet
worm attack which emerged in 2010 and
targeted some 15 Iranian nuclear
facility
he's including the Natanz that's one of
the key Iranian and nuclear facilities
you can see a satellite picture on the
bottom right side from 2003 Stuxnet
infiltrated numerous computer systems
targeting the windows-based step7
software and it was highly invasive and
what it made it so so destructive was
just its ability to replicate itself and
as a consequent about more than 980 year
uranium enriching centrifuge in Iran
started destroying themselves so the
designers are still being unknown
officially but there's a strong
indication that this was a warm attack
designed by the US and Israel who both
had an interest in halting Iran's
clandestine nuclear weapons program so I
mentioned earlier in my presentation
that private sector companies pose a
risk because they could become the weak
link in a supply chain a number of cyber
attacks were carried out against private
private firms during the last years and
some of them were made public which is
not which is not so usable because
normally tech firms are not so
interested in making these things public
because of the fear of reputational loss
but we know of some attacks including
against General Motors Boeing and
Lockheed Martin
so Lockheed Martin is an interesting
example it fell victim to a cyber attack
back in 2011
apparently conducted by a Chinese
businessmen and Lockheed Martin
developed for example the f-35 lightning
ii and f16 aircraft it sells
anti-ballistic missile defense systems
it provides unmanned and autonomous
systems missiles submarines rudder
sensors etc so to take the f-35 35
aircraft as an example it is not nuclear
capable yet but there are plans to
develop a nuclear capable f-35 in the
future which might be purchased by by
European states that host American
nuclear weapons as well
another example being asked whether
there has been an ease I'm not coming
back to you to Lockheed Martin they were
asked whether there has been any serious
damage following the attack and Lockheed
Martin just stated shortly after the
attack was made public that their
systems remain secure that no customer
program or employee personal data has
been compromised but from my perspective
we could never be sure that this is true
so another concerning issue - fighter
aircraft is the statement that German
defense minister was a LOF on a lion
mate during the Munich Security
Conference this year and she said while
it may be hard to use a missile - to
actually shoot down a Eurofighter
Typhoon which is by the way an aircraft
developed by Germany Italy Spain and the
UK and she said it is relatively easy to
bring one down through a simple hacking
the Eurofighter Typhoon again is not
nuclear capable yet but a new Europe
fighter model which will be developed
jointly by Germany and France could be
and a question here remains as to
whether this model will be safe and
secure
regarding cyberattacks so my third slide
on examples for cyber vulnerabilities
and attacks on specific systems is about
UK's nuclear weapons system called
Trident and the terminal high altitude
area defense system called Tod so you
might know there are concerns of whether
UK's nuclear deterrent which fully
relies on for vanguard-class submarines
could be highly vulnerable to a may a
hacking attack so each of these
submarines carries a trident to see
launched ballistic missiles and up to 40
warheads and one reason for concern is
that a submarine command systems updated
version is based upon a version of
Windows XP which has been installed on
all active royal class Royal Navy
submarine classes and we know XP as you
certainly know was the operating system
which was targeted by the wanna cry
ransomware in May 2017 that also
disrupted cards after Nash
Health Service and other companies
worldwide for example it halted
protection at a Honda Copland and Japan
so for certain time systems like Trident
we're perceived as being fully safe and
secure because submarines are air gapped
once they've submerged but it's not true
for two simple reasons first the
submarine is of course not always below
the surface and and breaches could
happen during maintenance once the
submarine is stocked and second air
gapping could easily overcome through an
infected USB throat drive for example
like it happened with the Natanz nuclear
facility which was which was air gap
during the time when the Stuxnet attack
happened now if you look at the bottom
left side of the slide you can see the
tart system which is a u.s. developed
anti-ballistic missile system developed
by Raytheon and Lockheed Martin Space
Systems company and currently deployed
in Guam and South Korea
so in 2017 the u.s. security firm fire I
announced that a beliefs heart has been
hacked by a state-sponsored Chinese
group so a spy
stay a spokesperson with the South
Korea's Ministry of Foreign Affairs
confirmed that it has indeed been an
attempted cyber attack on their systems
originating from China but I wouldn't
confirm that Todd was targeted in
particular and recently I just noticed
something that was that did not happen
last night but it was revealed last
night which was the data of French
construction company called in I don't
know how it how it's pronounced has been
stolen and apparently about 11,000 data
files have been stolen from that company
which builds for example a nuclear power
plants and prisons so I will go through
the next slides very quickly due to time
reason so the next two slides are
trustee awareness for cyber threats for
to national perspective and I took US
and France as examples here because in
the u.s. they are very aware of the
cyber threat for their nuclear weapon
systems they are quite impaired about
the nuclear weapons and about their
concerns per se and I put together just
a couple of notes for quotes from public
sources the first is from the retired
general robert kayla who was the
commander of the u.s. stretch comm which
is responsible for the nuclear weapons
and he said being asked by the Senate
Armed Services Committee in 2013 we are
very concerned with the potential of
size of a cyber related attack on our
nuclear command and control and on a
weapon systems themselves and as a
result in 2017 a task force on cyber
deterrence made a recommendation to
contact an annual assessment of the
cyber resilience of the US nuclear
deterrent including all essential
nuclear thinline components which means
nc3 platforms delivery systems and
warheads and also in April 2017 the Air
Force general John Hayden who is now the
commander of the u.s. strat comm said I
see a top tier cyber threat being Russia
and China in particular because they
have the ability to threaten the
existence of this nation so you can see
there is a very clear understanding that
cyber could become a major risk to the
nuclear weapon system in the u.s. now in
France the situation is a bit different
and that's why I put this as the second
example as I as I know from a few French
researchers and officials there is no
public debate and even the recent cyber
strategy from 28 he does not address the
cyber nuclear Nexus directly rather
indirectly but as far as I learn despite
that there is no political and public
debate military staff and government
officials on the top levels are indeed
aware of the threat but in France like
you probably know the general attitude
is not to talk to
about nuclear weapons in in general and
so it is the case with the
vulnerabilities but indeed France faced
also some crucial cyberattacks the first
one was in 2009 where the marine
Nacional was exposed to to a cyber
attack which was called the configure
warm and it struck important systems
preventing operative units to to
download their flight plans because
databases were infected and another
example is that a French nuclear company
called Aviva has been targeted by a
cyber espionage campaign back in 2011 so
now - - coming coming to the last part
of my presentation and talking about
what what can be done to enhance
security and resilience within crucial
parts of the nuclear weapon system like
the nc3 and the supply chain I want to
look at some policy recommendations in
this last section so given the
complexity of the threat and taking into
account that quite often we don't know
what we don't know as we heard earlier
we have to carefully look at some key
aspects before developing any measures
so first as long as we know that nuclear
weapons exist as and as long as they
serve as the primary security guarantees
of some states and alliances like NATO
the very threat of a major cyber attack
can never be ruled out
and because systems tend to be
modernized and get increasingly
sophisticated and complex they tend to
be more vulnerable in the future
and second the threat of a cyber attack
against any nuclear weapon system is
always global it's it's never just at
the national perspective and therefore
any effective measure has to be taken on
a bilateral or even on a multilateral
basis and third cross sector exchange
and sharing of information is of crucial
importance this includes government's
the military leaders the private sector
but also academia think tanks in
national institution like the UN and
civil society because civil society
could bring the topic to their
respective governments now looking at a
couple of concrete steps and here again
this is just some recommendations some
possible messer measures and not an
exhaustive list first I think especially
when we look at NATO as an alliance we
need to develop a common few and first
interpretation of what actually is the
threat and we need to formulate an
appropriate political or military
response visa be a possible cyberattack
nation's national national States Percy
must develop a narrative why
cybersecurity is crucial for their
nuclear weapons systems and they should
refrain from thinking that a mayor
attack on their nuclear weapons system
is not possible and we need to have
something like a permanent cyber nuclear
task force which is made up of senior
military leaders government officials
and top level experts coming either from
or both from the nuclear policy and from
the cybersecurity side to to share
information to exchange views and to
develop as practice models and of course
as we face a major crisis now we need to
have bilateral measures between the US
and Russia because for because evidently
they are the biggest nuclear weapons
processors we need to keep open
communications channels are
re-established them we need to seek for
mutual understanding and an exchange of
views on cyber related nuclear threats
here and also more this is done very 8
that that's a very sensitive and
difficult area but we need more
transparency on cyber vulnerabilities
and nuclear weapon systems in general so
this is for example important when we
look at a NATO nuclear sharing
arrangements in Europe and on u.s.
nuclear modernization plants and to to
illuminate this a bit I put in another
slide slide about a NATO nuclear sharing
in Europe because here you can see
clearly that we have three distinct
entities first you have the nature
command and control we're 29 countries
have a say then we have US nuclear
weapons and five European countries and
you can see I put in this little picture
of the the modernization plan of the b61
bomb so in the future we will have to be
61 12 model which is basically a
combination of for existing b61 bombs
and this will be a very sophisticated
and complex model so as we already know
the more complex the system get the more
vulnerable it is and last we have
national aircraft and for European
states which is Germany Belgium the
Netherlands and Italy turkey doesn't
possess dual capable aircraft so coming
to some very final recommendations
private firms we heard that this is a
very crucial factors must provide
information to their respective national
authorities and also to research
institution about possible hacks and
vulnerabilities in order to to improve
supply chain security and resilience in
the future we absolutely need you to
establish better education and training
for military staff at any level and
since I'm coming from the academic side
I think that more master's and PhD
programs should focus on a cyber nuclear
Nexus because we certainly lack of
knowledge here especially among younger
people and we need a better exchange
between university research and military
institutions and finally we need to
establish additional program projects
and programs with an institution like
the u & u CBRN Centers of Excellence and
like and new institutional structures
focusing on a cyber nuclear threat so if
you are further interested in a topic
and unfortunately there are to date few
researchers who focus exactly on that I
can recommend this
excellent publications and refer to the
first one for example is a dear
colleague of mine and she has done
incredible research in this area and
also the Chatham House and the anti
publications are worth reading so last
but not least thank you for for your
attention and there's no Q&A session due
to time limits but if you want to to
talk about this please feel free to
approach me and we can talk about this
on a bilateral basis thank you
[Applause]