welcome everyone our topic is about
another kind of duty mode the father
taught our ad and mccoys which we named
passer it designed for for our candle
for Pudwill wicket in table and the
secret world and the seed reproducible
mobile father and it is that I
identified I will introduce our member
understand we will introduce our
solution for path of fasting including
the fast strategy and the scratch mantra
and reduce tragedy and our further plan
and finally we introduce our hunt
practice where our Father hi I'm - I
work for mate when I have six years of
experience in advanced research now I I
focus on research about the order in day
and variability and I've been working on
using or medical assistants 200 advanced
rates log in ammonia and urea I worked
on the Windows platform for employed and
I wanna believe hunt and the sandbox
security analysis and now I'm focusing
on the mobile platform including ours
and Android for one bleed hunt and
research and it is it all remember my
name is Lila and I have a serious
security appearance on ours and micro an
RPG and malware detection okay under the
net part we will introduce our patter
solution in t2 and first of our abou
introduces the fighting - in comparison
to our different kind of passing threat
fuzzing
-
and according to different mentions for
example not - was the Trinity which is
open source
Cisco faster in the user mode and the
AFL the basic l3 so AFL which is the
femoris called courage based funding
system and also the tree force are as
well collar with these are not kind of
code corrida based the fuzzing system
towards the kernel and also the fine
wines are were pather we will compare
different passings according to
different dimensions for example as a
platform for the interface called
curators apart
driven by support and the reproduced
strategy and the depart party according
the platform as we know Trinity the
typical old fashioned the system call
father with different variations with
researchers configured as a system call
for might for example supreme in the tab
or the written tab it'll record and thus
utilize every log of API contest before
coit researchers could only try to
reproduce the crash by collecting the
log whereas since the log review effort
would be huge and reproduced by log
would fail for complex scenarios for
example if the API correlation is tight
so our the reproduce will depends on so
environment so in these conditions it
had to reproduce another kind is the EFL
which is which implies inaudible of a
comparative instruction and generic
method
sorry under the tree falls
he and itself even or override the code
occurred based the thinking of AFL and
it view you could tend it so so fighting
targets into the kernel and there's a
friend of mine in suburb Heather some
and actually we design our passer
according platform so we will try to
wrap our father agent a crowding script
which is quite crossing platform and
also about the funding interface
actually it can't was the youth face you
use mode or the kernel mode both
currently our pattern is not budget
called character but in the future plan
we will consider I just cook right and
in our solution and about the
reproduction but the pattern is piece
answers Eid as we have mentioned before
using using the Sita strategy it can
save a lot of reproduced reproduction
effort ok this is our host illusion
Ginty to our the weakened society is the
most composed by different parts so the
main part is so fast faster agent the
right agent is you can consider it as
executor in the user mode which we will
try to cause attack in the vase toward
user mode or anomaly and the other party
is also quite monitor the current motor
will try to counter the crash or how
information of your target process
according whether your device is the do
bricked or non-jew bricked it has
different strategy under the other side
we consist that we
we will provide our squid squid syrup
because our fat agent is wrapped by is
represented by Python or nodejs
like security language so we can easy to
save our fasting strategy our fasting
scenario informative script and we can
put this all kind of scenarios as quick
as script in the server and when the fat
agent will you try to run to cause a
tacit service interview first loaded so
fasting script are fasting scenario from
the server and run locally the other
party is about a secede because gravity
has the either his own or the other
entities introdution so for every kind
of crash issues review get as the
corresponding unique and identify the
seed so we can see this we can save the
seed all the integral into the seed
server for reproduction okay about the
agent the main function is try
to trigger the fighting interface and
reproduce two crashes the key point in
the framework of our example so active
easy our kid our system call the library
we can all rather give kind of framework
in the security because great because it
has no compile compile of this effort so
we can keep this kind of a solution plus
a crowding platform and also we degrade
our seed reproduction strategy in our
father agent on a studies secrete the
server so secretory is mainly
providing fighting salute updating and
downloading researchers could configure
so fast grid towards fighting in the
face or even updates as grouped at
random when the father agent is running
okay so correct monitor is responsible
for detecting so crash event for father
agent actually by design
after fat event of examples crystallizer
leakage or information leakage could
also be detected by monitoring for view
of passing target
it could be kernel module for example so
axonal acronym driver or the other kind
of model in driver or kernel or any user
mode modules or processes for example PC
or Mac service demons even the target so
is it easy to break so quite monitor
could be deployed inside of the third
device because we have sufficient
privileges to monitor to target the
process otherwise the current monitor is
deployed outside of the device our host
and the normally is a cried Martha could
detect the device crash event with for
example an tuned protocol where are your
USB okay so this server a civil service
meaningful collecting so fighting seed
for reproduction because before the
target device crashes so may the main
some main strategy was for 4c Sidra
protecting site you can use one unique
unique and identify the integral into
value for example 4 bytes according to
specific Pazuzu algorithm you can use
this kind of value to generate or
sequence of data which is decided and
the by this kind of seed you can
reproduce
you can produce the reproduce that data
exactly
okay this is a snapshot of our city so
er you can see that it's the left column
is our crashed Expedia services which
year which is a contoured eyeball and
each one and this is so sweet
we have our collected two what is kind
of module here so you can see that after
running several minutes we can get a lot
of salt maybe hundreds of Aero crashes
kisses you know it's in server sorry
okay you know the odd part is about the
fighting strategy so the first question
is why we fighting in secret and the
second is how a parting security engine
onto mobile devices such as ours and
Android and also and also we will
introduce how we repair the hours or
micro milk okay we can see that actually
for fighting agent there are different
kind of implementation for example you
can implement it using the native native
code such as the C or C++ or Swift or
any other object oriented language
supported by Apple and the other part is
about the script such as jazz or person
and a review compares a different kind
of implementation by different
dimensions for example wine sorted kind
of padding agent is the private crowding
used to crowd use easy to part is the
easy to part two different platform
and why the we can modify the fighting
logic in either random or not and
whether it needs to compare average and
the finally we will choose the riper our
fighting framework of ours or Mike
informative is great and actually we
have for we have some research about
this security wrapper solution on
different platform for example so i TV
framework of kiwi open source free mocha
for our eyes and the kiwi Python for
Android and also the node.js from from
for for both iOS and Android and
actually we have also compare these kind
of open source a framework according to
different dimensions for example whether
this kind of framework needed need more
privilege also platform or wine syrup it
will cause effort to pouting different
platforms and which platform is the
pulse actually this is the snapshot of
code pieces which review pending the
match message our octopus II framework
using Python you can see that it is APR
attacking the attack surfaces in
promoter of expedient method at the PC
Creed connection and occipital handler
and also match messages send and receive
okay this right you guys the basic view
of
so how the attack surfaces attack
surfaces impose you to mode and the
kernel mode traditionally and you can
see that in the left column so system a
PP with hyper-v later how act PC
services these are all a user mode with
high privilege and this al-qaeda driver
access new Colonel and I put which is
the bootloader these are in the kernel
mode there are there are many reasons to
why we did kind of API as attack service
for example for system ADP's for
examples are Safari Apple Store iTunes
because in this kind of system Apple and
for equity services because its root or
high privilege and also it could be
called from low privilege at all sandbox
have abs but al-qaida Trevor because
many of the al-qaeda drivers are tries
to graphical video audio and the other
kind of Jared could be easily called
from a certain box and the axon you is
the kernel which is a cross-platform
impose hours and Mike Mike OS okay
the other part is the passing by
emulation for a long time fast all hours
xpz server is best best on AI device for
example iPad or iPhone but in order to
increase or codec courage we generally
needed to run a large number of cases
due to the limited performance of the
iDevice our efficiency efficiency is not
too high it if we should if
officiousness
master being pro only a large number of
iDevice will be purchased purchased this
is a bigger cost and foremost a team it
should be
should be a big challenge so based on
the based on the hours xpz service
mattify in actually the instruction set
we body purpose the idea would replace a
large number iDevice with armed service
service but uh but at present large arms
over its price is very very high so we
choose a low cost and device it is
raspberry pi there we use a Raspberry Pi
crecer to construct the arm device
cursor which is almost close to the
current mainstream arms summer in factor
there is already a similar open-source
project on github turning is a Translate
translation layer that allows you to run
our modified mac OS paralyzed on linux
in its nature it is similar to the
window wine project he has implemented a
dynamic them loader that you can load a
Mac OS X and runtime system library and
framework relation implementation so to
enable Mac OS X to drum and so on
unfortunately however it can only
support x86 best Metro which runs on Mac
OS the next thing we need to do it later
turning support our base metal based on
low cost because we consideration
our goal is to chess chess plain ism to
the Sperry PI we call it an empire in
order to maintain the name continuity
but we just borrow his source and
rebuild the coder through the through
the transplant we have implemented
dynamic dynamic load that can load our
six and run time system labor like
library and the framily implementations
to enable iOS exe to fraction and so a
factor we only need to realize Raspberry
Pi 2
atchoo for assistant emulation to
emulation by Kumu this is a quick and
easy way with this assistant we further
mature or even some frank fragment
decoder which become easily any i/o any
iris XP server wrong in a bending
independently under our word are in PI
and expose all attacked service we can
use a large number of cases that you
file it and the cold courage is
calculated by recording the call stack
and new cases are generated by
backtracking after the design of such
low cost Holloway emulator we can run a
large number of cases which serve the
cost and improve our efficiency and we
receive a good filing activities should
be extensible and portable which should
be in redmond by
good teacher design and high collar
quality it would reduce your match
effort of falling is the project is well
did I improvement the queries researches
should shoot the pewter or share large
or scenario POC it were the attacked
fighting interface some normal scenario
POC would be completed and URI URI is
the United test case or for video
developers arrays beyond the largest
Corp of securities research the most in
error appears it were the tech interface
you get the moral possibility
possibility you should you trigger or
ability actually the ever hung hung hand
or crash case Oh Doris into the
fisheries you're further hunting because
with high possible possibility the ever
crashed issue would happen again and
again to interrupt your fading we
recommend this where this this key food
which have caught crash be extractor and
another whitelist filter or material for
example Forex PC server back how the
message ID into perfe is good
beautiful filter for expiry funny
next I will introduce some models
including crash - strategy and reproduce
strategy and we also introduce our
future plan to stress in our tools we
all know then passing on our system is
painful scene is about asperity
algebraic uncharted device however
luckily they have already some excellent
to sell implements the ideas protocol
which can help us to communicate with
the ideas such as live mobile device
then we can use AI devices dog to
monitor the system law whether an ex PC
is crushed or exit what small there are
also some one or PT such as kernel box
when we trigger them they will create
ready like ready Diagnostics information
in the crash reporter folder so we can
use the idea is crushed reporter to pull
this information for monitoring funding
status however protea break this system
we can get more privilege so we can
monitor the funding status on device
directory and use the socket mechanism
to communicate between father and
monitored by a demon this is the
frontiers for our modular strategy for
monitor the target so instead hers and
we more we monitor the process causal
instead of wow its sub process what's
more we also at the system also is
freeze free signal into our fuzzing
tours
next we will introduce the repros
reproduce strategy
there are many interference factors to
make crush reproduction hotter including
rest condition API kasra correlation and
environment dependency for example if
the one bid he is triggered by a series
of API switch coding a specific order
it's difficult for us to get by which is
the first API to Costas issue there are
also many measure to reproduce the crash
here we list for including log case
beyond crash dump and seed mission
before we used seed based on procedural
rhythm number generator with Mason
twister algorithm to face the targets so
for each particle we can simply save
those seeds in the server and no need to
sell any middle status or data object
comparison we can found an reproduced by
seed only cost more storage and the
speed is first was more it only spent a
little effort than other measures this
is the implementation for trying to
communicate with servers through socket
mechanism we you need for transfer we
use it for seed transfer during father
fathering we only use the sake to
transfer seeds and an admission seed is
actually a 64-bit data so network
transmission speed is right here not low
compared to disk storage sterilization
what's more the system is hosting the
outside of running target so we can
easily redirect the traffic to any other
service server and ensure its stability
another haunted for using socket is land
we can deploy multi fuzz agent with
different server poles padding server
will create different folders to sell
corresponding data we recommend you to
recall last uncie's for reproduction and
and should not be too small or too big
because it is too small the root cause
root cause is causing target crash will
be missed because the early exit delay
from root cause trigger to final target
crash and should not be too big because
the most audiences may not related to
the current target crash so it would be
time consuming for reproduction English
cast we reckon you to recall bigger
number bigger number uncie's for example
tenses and gives the last and subtract
em details logs for example - in this
way the redoubt and emcees make sure you
could reproduce the crash while the last
and subcode substrate and details logs
can help you to verify the crash as soon
as Papa this picture shows the last
census logs next we will talk about our
future plan we will into we will
integrate the code coverage feed bank
for our browsing to like FL hanging
files Konami
and this is color and we all know nearly
all of ours and Mac OS jars and from
library close sauce and so our dynamic
dynamic and the static binary is true
mission instrumentation is the only
alternative measures were small we also
spoiled we were also small the position
mode like a affair for those fuzzy
interface interfaces which could not
Excel to for linking or privilege or
preventing by Scotty party check
we plan to attach them and hokey related
functions for fuzzy actually list method
have already proved possible by hung
fast
what's more in order to improve the
quality of impulse tell her for father
symbolic ocean will be introduced
together input constraint and they have
been already some excellent open so
tools for assess assembly symbolic
occlusion such as anger we have
mentioned that in pay before imprint his
ice ax PC service always need to
interact with other expiry service so we
can simulate other excuses our will to
implement and communication with the
targeted species always with darling pay
and the files are based on the
simulation we mentioned before finally
we were to close some hunting practice
and tong interface interfaces the tongue
in the first is many in connect PC Damon
demonsaw is and sandbox rich boku no
expectations
here are the Zoey's got by along the
lunch lunch CTL dumb state command these
are so is list with their PID and the
exit code this is the details
information of found objects or
including his port activity LTS the
activists tellers and other detail
information
this is mutational match message body
instance based on highlights see we can
see that multi data are replaced by my
from the ones this is the one our BT we
found and ever have fixes recently we
also some me some cross requests to zdi
so we will raise them to fix later this
here we list the kernel extensions which
can be reached what directory service
unboxed apps encoding for our iPhone X
iPhone 7 and iPad air