limiting data that hackers one so in
order to provide you with the best
information in fact they don't
what industries you are working that
would be helpful so anyone share the
industry that they work in industrial
education retail led cameos on utility
utility the utility okay anybody else
consumer electronics summer electronics
anyone else Garnett's finance is that
like banking finance Callahan okay
though federal like those are a federal
federal like FDA Federal's okay big
brother nor you need to leave Evans City
it's okay okay fair enough fair enough
um what do you guys feel like the
biggest issue is when it comes to
removing the data to hackers one social
security native birds that I'm still
finding it finding it I'm finding it in
terms I want to network or I'm saying
you got a really large organization you
need to like go through and fibers and
sanitize might not always know where
everything is so actually finding it
or something stumbles a time can be a
challenge good point okay finding it
what else brother other issues with
getting the data to hackers want out of
the infrastructure complete well
identifying what is first because if you
just say well I have this data is
important to me that I would use under
wraps and you haven't invited it's
pretty hard to say point to and say well
this is important we need to move this
or security zone
okay fair enough what else
rather the issues with getting Social
Security numbers date of birth credit
card numbers on infrastructure getting
buy-in from management to build and
elitist or get getting buy-in from
management that's our as I rewriting
your problem right budget right how many
uh maybe we're do a monthly security
report for your point your executives
nobody have you ever seen one now okay
stop and talks about 11 explain to you
get the power point if they do so a
monthly security report is a report that
you create to give executives incidence
of what's happening in your environment
because that that report is going to be
your foundation for every argument you
make regarding budget so what which what
do you think that report when it said
they guess about spam how many phishing
emails would block that one I gave the
first example what do you think
guys don't participate I'm going to
singing my son okay so I think you'll be
better off how BIG's your organization
have any spam messages your block
anymore that that was my I'm doing the
first suggestion I think one to report
we should put how many phishing emails
per block that some type of
vulnerability assessment vulnerability
assessment if we have IPS at the
perimeter what can we you can we use
that to say we had estimating porn scans
or this be the intrusion attempts right
right okay so what else in 10 min but
they were successful
if it was just a monthly report yeah
everyone might be in trouble at that
point um so okay we can say if they were
successful with spam a barracuda has a
very uh very interesting feature where
they actually tell you spam messages
that it did not block now if you can
tell me as fam message that you didn't
block why don't you pop hey how to come
up with it but this is what they do so
that would be an incidence where you can
say okay we got to thousands bama tins
this month we had 50 go through now if
I'm an executive I want to know why the
50 went through you gotta be prepared to
answer that type of question ah so cubic
even the security for born what else you
think this chaplain their spam
vulnerability assessment I'm saying what
else what else would scare they have a
lot of an executive violence has found
virus is found perfect example straight
to the point what else data lost data
lost sorry again but you're something
that you're summing doing a summary and
if somebody lost a laptop okay so let's
let's say for example healthcare company
been Reich's we've seen that right lost
stolen laptops that had medical records
that would be a good day to put her own
report how about how much that cost the
company right whatever that would report
to because it's okay i lost laptop we
had to inform a hundred thousand people
of this issue there's going to be costs
associated with that and that happens
more than once in a year that's it
that's a real problem what else do you
baby put on the report help those
tickets related to security yeah give it
let us cecilio the password reset but
you can see hey you know by the way so
these little tacit you're saying it
right that big video this is how that
relates them to security or this is
going to lead to potential problem but
hey well this person keeps getting now
where you know something else on their
machine that can go to your budget or
your argument for your security trade
yeah that rolls into a German in the
back of Samuel yes virus attempts of
things like that so generally the
security report is not in the
presentation but it's a foundation for
every argument to make regarding
security no matter whether its buying
security appliances online buying cloud
based monitoring whatever it is you're
going to an executive and you're saying
I need fifty thousand dollars for this I
needed a hundred thousand dollars for
that and all you providing is your word
maybe if you go to sands and get some
information maybe they've had some
security awareness training your
building on that nothing nothing helps
by the security report so if you don't
do one I'll strongly recommend that you
start on one my contact information is
at the end feel free to reach out we can
work on it together I have a template
i'll continue but it's a really great
idea to help increase oh now just a
where
the attacks that happened but the team
increased budget as well which helps all
of what we're trying to all right so
jumping into the PowerPoint while ago
today data you cannot data that you
don't store cannot be that first we want
to talk first we want to explain what it
is that we're talking about what data
are we talking about we're talking about
data that hackers one the way i classify
this is my classification it doesn't
necessarily align with the way the
industry doesn't so I want to set that
up from sorry p i ah everybody knows
that is first of all identifiable
information sensitive information it's a
general term different in every
environment you going and I want to
explain how I define the two i define
PII by the law and the reason I / the
law is because if there is a piii reach
then it requires a data breach
disclosure by block so keep I keep those
terms together because we know exactly
what we're talking about we're talking
about credit honoring we're talking
about the whole shebang of data breach
aftermath ok so give me by I guess why
driver's license number isn't rape that
varies from state to state
reach walls are the threshold as well as
your announcement it's a good answer it
does vary from state to state but that's
not why anybody else guess while
driver's license numbers in red come on
I'm getting a song ready i'm going to
start singing no okay because it is the
one that most people don't know is on
list as far as those waters concern to
come so I security who doesn't put mine
up but if you ask a financial aid person
or someone who deals with via our
regular basis if a driver's license
number equals a social security number
in terms of data breach they don't know
so that's why I'm ready and we walk away
today and you're going back to your
security duties keep in mind people do
not know driver's license numbers on
that list you have a breach of Jess
names and driver's license numbers that
is a data breach it requires disclosure
and you might have to do some either
need protection from any before you have
a question please stop us and we can
talk about it everything else here
standard SI same credit card number bank
ghana so now sensitive information this
is where we have not fun
that
so as I said I structure my sensitive
information and a base moment of the way
I like it to be PRI goes with the law
period that's the way i do now sensitive
information is very different and it's a
little more complicated first one is
self-explanatory intellectual property
we know that infrastructure invite
something why infrastructures on this
list you want to give it more list of
your assets right addresses or something
that hey if I have a map them this is
important this is how I can connect to
it art architecture any kind of notes
regarding sense of regarding the
infrastructure on maybe service you have
what's in the DMZ you know which
application server does what which
resources have PR all that's a part of
infrastructure information but it's not
p I hi however we need to protect it
like PII so we put it on the SI list
sensitive information list HIPAA is not
on VII this however because of the HIPAA
law we have to protect it it's on the
silence wires then why do we have
fingers up here
that could be a vector of attack how
could it be if someone is able to
compromise the vendor potentially have
access to your this is that home depot
got black right that's the word on the
street but you have the jury still out
so let's use a pro let's use an example
or city with top party George the
bottoms up we're seeing in women's
university right okay so let's say mosey
university uses company a forward their
data center air-conditioned right well
if I know that now I know who's going in
the data center right can't fix it if
you don't go in so if i wanted to do
something hostile well then I might go
get a job at that company or I might
just have to do it up sides here to take
a uniform and go to work for them the
next day whatever the case is however
now I know a third-party way to get
access to that organization their
parties are just as liable to be used as
a tool for hackers just as going
directly to the organization make sense
yeah okay contacts contacts is pretty
much the same as vendors the people you
know if you are one of the great people
on LinkedIn hey I'm assistant
administrator for guy go and then you're
on facebook and you have your family
your friends you know you guys are going
to the local pub that evening all those
are contacts I don't have to come
straight to you I can go to the contacts
around you and and use them as a tool to
get what I mean usernames passwords
spell stems or anybody don't understand
they're all right great dataverse
question of the day why our data burst
here but not on the pii list because the
law does not happen on the pilots now
for this we're talking about Delaware
Pennsylvania and Maryland there may be a
few states that you have but the
surrounding states do not have t.i i do
not have sorry date of birth on the pii
just that's why I gave birth is up if
data burps are breached with names does
it constitute a data breach disclosure
revised like another what if names and
David versa preach does it cost to a
data breach disclosure it's a trick
question yes why yes because so before
you can say yes or no what do you have
to ask yourself what state are you in
okay so we talked about preventing data
breaches preventing data breach
disclosures and all the calls that come
with it the first question how bad
yourself is what state are you in what
laws are you governed by because the law
governs data breach disclosures
everybody understand that okay so we are
talking about some of the industries
that you're in my friend in the
backstage utility okay I imagine utility
might have some unix servers yes maybe
too old for this is probably maybe in a
frame or 10 and so we're going to have
applications that are we're going to
have databases when I have everything
that's listed up in so how can we today
plan over the next five to ten years one
completely removing PII from the
environment using a utility company
let's say a water company you give them
your name date of birth social security
number they do a credit check are they
storing that information yes do they
have two story argh you know who's going
to tell them that though I think the
security professional with their handy
dang
curity report should walk in and say you
know what I think we need to plan to get
rid of this now picture this as a
security broke walking you ask for
funding to protect the perimeter to
protect the data but what happens when
you team up with the infrastructure guys
and you walk in and you say hey let's go
in together but when you plan I want you
to plan this way now you're going in and
you're going in with the infrastructure
budget which is always bigger right oh
it's bigger and it's just a change to
what they're doing it's not additional
funding for security you see what said
so now we're talking about security
budget we're talking about
infrastructure budget to do things a
different way notice your question if
there are no social security numbers
what is your wrist your risk of being
breached for identity theft what is your
risk for having a data breach that
results in identity down if there are no
social security numbers a union bar
so you go and talk to executive you say
hey we have three million Social
Security numbers here that equals thats
a $25 personal security number 75
million dollars then we can check out if
their priests every five years we can
have infrastructure with zero so scared
numbers and that equals zero million
dollars are we not speaking executive
language now right did you not just make
a new best friend you know and you're
taking the infrastructure guys with you
because you're not talking security
you're talking infrastructure but it has
the effect of reducing the risk to zero
now that's a you know that's an example
that will take a lot of work but some
some companies some organizations some
industries they have the ability to make
these changes to remove this data from
the environment completely they just
need someone to start the conversation
so why while you're doing perimeter
defense database security service
security you also kind of say you know
what yes we want to secure the
infrastructure but why don't we get rid
of this data that's going to cost us a
lot of money that's that's what I want
you to think about
this is Michael jr. occasion though he's
my 8 year old twin so hey there process
Apple pay leads the way is anybody know
I have to pay leads the way right glute
you re invite know why we say Apple bay
leaves the way and not google peg not
chase pic not any of the other
electronic payments aiming system us
maybe maybe they get your Apple ID set
up your name they give you a tradition
check today's like a generator atom
number every single transaction yes
virtual numbers to transactions instead
of the actual card numbers we did that's
that's a part of it so break it down for
you iphone 6 plus when i added the car
to him my card went to one place a chip
hardwired to this phone it does not go
to that go to apple service as the first
important point it does not go to apple
service every second the chip like
everything else in apple's iphone it's
segregated it cannot be hacked across
the network so in order to do a mass hat
you'd have to have 50,000 volts now
Apple is upfront about this information
Google is not and if you know who by I
know Google there's a server somewhere
sitting with the garden and you'll
figure it out when they said oh google
pay was preached a hundred thousand card
numbers compromise and then you'll know
they're storing the car okay I'm sure if
that's what's going to happen so if you
are processing cars in your environment
okay please do not store the card
numbers if you need a record of
transaction store the last board if they
can't give the record by the last four
then the record doesn't get got but
we're talking about fifteen dollars per
card number if you have a hundred
thousand transactions a hundred thousand
different cars that's 1.5 billion
dollars for what what what benefited
that provide you know so we really have
to start looking at removing this
information from them from the
environment and if we're not storing it
it's not going to be in Trenton right
somebody brought up target earlier help
me understand how hit numbers got
reached I'm sorry I've lost how do you
reach pinups they're only in transit so
what you're telling me is that not only
did you compromise the server but you
were actively recording network traffic
it doesn't get more ridiculous than that
the bottom line it just doesn't okay so
if you don't store it it can't be in
transit so there's no server to hack
there's no hard data to sniff on the
line again data breach avoided let's
look at the exam how do some of you
example there is a bookstore here well
let's say for the sake of this
conversation the bookstore only accepts
out of it what is the risk of data
breach for the bookstore 00 million
dollars and I like to add a million
because if there was a risk it be a
million collars attached to it so 0
million dollars is the risk if they only
use Apple pay because the systems in the
bookstore never receive the credit card
numbers that's the frame of mind that we
have to get executives thinking how do
we get rid of this paper lastly EMP does
anybody know why he is a joke it is the
punch line and everywhere else so we put
a chip in a coffin and we say if you go
to a terminal it's going to check to
make sure the dead ship is in the car
well leave my shop online is boom I did
I shop online yesterday ah what's the
watching my ass did they check my chip
right how so what does EMV have to do
phone on chopped nothing so how did you
fix the problem oh we did sorry we just
mandated something that didn't fix
anything thanks ogre so EMV yes it works
it keeps people from taking TV banks
nice up debit card printer and printing
cards at home and going to
door and swiping the wet it did not
however touch online banking fraud how
we have a government mandate that forces
people to apply that doesn't fix a
single damn problem I don't know it's
frustrating I'm immediate bringing his
nut okay so it's all about that you are
targeting most know the law do your
research two things I want you to do
when you walk into that executives
office I want you to have a data breach
report that they've been getting monthly
I want you to have the law because that
is where the money comes from it comes
from what data requires the increased
exposure if you align your P I hat the
way i do then in any piii stolen know
that that's a date of reached is hope
that disclosure does Solon encrypted
data count as a day to route anybody
answer that question
was it maybe not even keel no she said a
good team not just in rid of me oh sure
so that goes back to the law some states
were some say say if it's readable data
some say say if the data is encrypted it
does not constitute as a data it depends
on the state law that your organization
is governed by but that has to go with I
don't want to get into encryption in
this talk but encryption is your next
best friend so if you're an environment
where you have limited the amount of PII
in the environment but you cannot remove
it a hundred percent the very next step
is encryption right so you want to take
that in there with you the law says if
we encrypt the data then it's not a data
breach well if you're all your PR is
encrypted and the keys are not on the
same server as the VII I want to
it's here any minute if your data is
your P is encrypted please don't store
the keys on the same server on the same
southern on the same infrastructure put
them somewhere else please ah there are
some state laws that's it if the keys
were compromised it is a day so when a
serious I'd you want to make sure keys
are somewhere safe away and not copied
all over their instruction so what is
the risk right on back to the risk
question what is the risk if well new
social security numbers are stolen they
are encrypted the keys aren't we're not
even still
new construction what's the risk nothing
right my favorite time 0 million dollars
that's the risk so when you talk to the
executives you're speaking executive
speak throw that billion dollars on them
this will cost 50 billion dollars
beatable social security numbers when
criminals career numbers cost zero
billion dollars ever as long as the keys
remain away if there's no there's no
risk so tell me whatever executives
excuse can be what do you think their
excuse can be to that art got all right
you got a thing all you got a fun one
because when you're talking those
millions of dollars what can they say
when does the data breach have to be
reporting very very important various
bass state also a part of your plan if
your PR is stolen you have to know how
long you have to report that why is that
important well if your PR is not
encrypted because you didn't talk to
your executive yet because everybody's
going to talk to their executive when
they leave right yes okay so if that
happens you have to know how long you
had well if your detection time isn't
fast enough well then you have a whole
other issue if it has to be reported
within 30 days and you're only looking
at certain things every 30 days you have
a problem in your process that's going
to cost your organization a whole lot of
money so you want to look at that stuff
so that you're at your process online
with the law what happens if a vendor is
breached for your customer data any
cloud fans in the room
Salesforce take it over the world what
happens if you I want to answer that no
you want me to sing a song a song right
plus I've got a dad's going to happen is
both here no agency thank ya there would
be a lot of money taken from photograph
so the answer is that vendor is going to
say hey excuse me sir hundred thousand
of your customer records wore off where
breaches we're still investigating what
we just want to let you know if it's a
longer process collection of two weeks
have a nice day and we're going to go
and you are going to piss in your bags
and then after that figure out the
aftermath of a hundred-thousand-dollar
100,000 record reach it falls on you the
customers gave you I eat your
organization of the data it doesn't
matter now you can go after the vendor
and say hey you didn't secure it right
for you it's not the toy like
contraction wise i have so like Uranus
up
start out concrete they're saying if it
gets breached so it's interesting you
put that up as anybody seen the man
named from FCC they're going to hold
people accountable for the way cats FCC
anything was up c z TZ TZ thank you
always good at mr. they're going to hold
organizations accountable for not
protecting date so my first question is
no not they're not just going to hold
encounter they have to go through this
audit process or some kind of monitoring
over a set of years and show the FCC
that they are protecting data so my
question is is OPM going to be on that
list do other federal government
agencies also get subjected to that cuz
I'm confused you know I really I'm so
tech to direct answer your question the
FTC is creating oversight for large
organizations um contractually you can
put that evening but understand the
process you against the junior the
customer begins you right the media
doesn't care about the vendor unless
itself sales force does anybody else
waiting for Salesforce breach
interpretation I am it's common just a
matter is I'm so understand what the
situation is going to look like before
it happens take them with you into your
executive meeting we can sue them but
the responsibility falls one of us as
the organization who the customers gave
the data to very very important so here
this is an excerpt straight out of the
Delaware law I just wanted to show you
sometimes in red are what they defines
you gotta see is a little more complex
Calvin number credit or debit card
number
combination with any required code
access code or password that will permit
access to a residence financial account
that's a great area and there's a lot of
legal room for battle in there but for
the most part social drivers license
number bank account numbers now what I
do want you to take away the personal
information does not include publicly
available information so when we talk p
i ah you want to make sure we talk about
very specific yeah we don't want to let
any anyone misconstrue the conversation
okay so anything that might be personal
but is it on the list we want to make
that argument very clear to executives
so because you know they're going to go
somewhere they're going to go to a
conference and somebody's going to say
yeah yeah well if names and phone
numbers are breached that's a data
breach and you have to tell the state
and you have to do a database disclosure
and they're going to come back and be
like I just found this out oh my god
they're gonna call you at three in the
morning we need an Avery since Moser
we're going to be fired uh you know
gossip is going so you need to know the
law you need to be able to pull this up
and say hey no here's the wall names and
phone numbers are not on it go back to
sleep okay you need to know that stuff
there's always somebody who knows
nothing about security putting
information into an executives ear why
because executives control budget it's
an issue every security professional
world has to face anybody experienced
that someone goes from conference comes
back and Bradford anybody has not
experienced it okay great we're all
very little oh so scary number driver's
license number credit card number never
card number same little claws the
combination would require security code
ah there's a new one an individual
taxpayer identification number just in
case someone has I've never actually
seen that but just in case someone has a
number that associates with paying taxes
that's not a social security number that
is included in Maryland law we didn't
see that in Delaware delivery no no the
law no the state's law that government
law that governs our organization this
is Berlin Wall continue same publicly
available information boston
pennsylvania law social crowd license
number the identification number
financial number saved a the term does
not include publicly available
information so going back to executive
support that's what it's all about you
gave it infrastructure team you guys the
badge away over the next five ten years
the organization can get rid of all
scored peacock complete right well when
you go to that executive you have to
make sure you explain the 0 million
dollars that is sure that is your
opening point you're closing point your
punch line you're everything there is
ZERO million dollars of risk if we do
this executives executive support will
lead to project funding why because
we're trying to transition the
infrastructure that's going to take
funding but it's easier to get
infrastructure
finding dinner days to give security fun
we all agree on that infrastructure
serves the environment security is the
red line on the budget that everyone
hates but they don't want to end up on
the news so they pay for the other guy
that keeps getting infrastructures away
yeah exactly infrastructure wanted to
bring it all new stuff and no security
had to get that IPS you know so this is
another way for us to make some friends
we don't get a lot of opportunities to
make friends so we have to take
advantage project funny sometimes it
might be something very small as you
have to do other times it might be
completely it might be completely
stirring the organization's
infrastructure in a different direction
talking about tens 28 hundred million
dollars don't let that discourage once
you have the right people on your side
you can make a change for an
organization that other organizations
have not made yet and having that
executive support will bring the funding
necessary having that infrastructure
support will bring the funding and the
expertise to say hey security guys
handed but hey what he's proposing fits
what I'm doing too so we want to make
friends we want to get that support so
that we can steer our organizations in a
different direction no breaches will
always occur you know it is anyone
familiar with the zero day marketing
anyone not familiar with the zero-day
market everyone's that with it so yeah
it is that's right there are more more
companies coming up that you will not
see on CNBC they are not publicly traded
companies you're not even talked about
like cyber Ark who get paid lots of
money to 50 dates so much that now they
package them in a nice package that is
exploited from the perimeter Cisco at
the perimeter to
an IPS or load balancer all the way to
the data center they'll create a nice
little package with the bow and sell it
for 20 million dollars now used to be
NSA was the only buyer of this
information pretty things bonded now
everybody what do you think your kid as
soon as Edward Snowden started leaking
stuff because you said there and said
hey we're going to put up more defense
because they're trying to take our stuff
Oh knew they'd win bought them some zero
days and they went to war you have each
other cyber war started whenever Snowden
started sharing everything he shared I
don't I don't agree or disagree that I
stay out of that but once you once these
countries found out that the level the
United States has taken it to you best
believe that they stepped it up and this
is how they do there is no other way to
have on a massive scale in the zero-day
market so we thought about improving the
infrastructure is more important than
securing all right and we have about 10
minutes left so what I like to do is
look at some real life examples I share
a lot information with you about
transitioning to a certain place but you
know there's always different industries
and different infrastructure in the room
so anybody wanted to share some
information or tell me why this would be
a problem for them we can engage about
it to talk about it and work through it
new volunteers federal government what
you do place bugs to work it up examples
are the best way we do for investment
group okay I'm giving names give up- a
century asset
management company so they're doing a
lot of stock trades at choice of the
secret sauce as now because they're not
actually doing retail its institutional
they're not going to have the iif
individual social security numbers
however they're doing retirement plan
something like that so there is a tax ID
associated with it which if you're doing
that type of level you're not talking
about mom cause you know 30,000 two
million dollars is two hundred million
dollars at a time then if I got into
this and drain this lots of money other
things so in their case
there's going to have to be some record
that says Brand X company tax ID number
they gave us two million dollars for us
to trade needs to be allocated in forty
percent on twenty percent overseas five
percent room with the rest you know
whatever but they'll have to have some
pretty detailed information so it's not
often talked about immediate but
business identity theft it's far worse
thinking soon honey no no far worse it
doesn't get any media attention okay but
just with the tax ID at home nothing
else not only can you still an
organization's identity you can open an
office a bank account credit card
processing you can even start getting
some of their customers and they're in a
diplomat of the world just from the tax
ID number business verification is a
tragedy right so that in itself is a
good reason to move away a TI tambien
emari right they don't need the EIN
numbers to track the transactions they
need them when the customer first comes
in so until authenticate that customer
right business credit check and then
because of that they then use the EIN
number two the lifetime of the customer
but is it necessary no it's not so in
that scenario I'm looking at a way to
simple customer ID that when a company
comes in and they bring the Taj Amidala
retirement plan you have to accept the
eye and first we have to do that credit
check but after that they get a customer
ID the customer ID follows their money
for the lights on the customer the ein
after that credit check get scoop and
Malcolm out that's that's what I'm
aiming for that's where you start the
conversation with
infrastructure people and then you kind
of work through its not going perfection
and if I say no it can't go away okay
but can we limit it down to one server
or two sir can we determine where it's
going to be in Trinity you know all that
that's when all the nitty-gritty part of
the details comes out but you got to
start the conversation with the
infrastructure folks first that's why I
use Apple pay as an example because the
credit card number never leaves it's a
virtual number you know and so if that
virtual number is compromised it's not a
data breach disclosure and it really
doesn't mean anything because it can do
anything with that is that makes sense
any other examples 10 minutes left
sounds full song i will call somebody
goes over like this before especially
there's a few companies out there that
kind of collect information about you
beaumont your mother's maiden name all
differently good they act as a surrogate
or the verification
has anyone looked into that model where
you have a trusted party that turned out
to be the government you mean I like a
lot kind of like reproducing the credit
check process but without the without
the p I it would be so you know keep it
and nobody else needs to have a date
they would have a key or something that
allowed their trusted together to that
ball so the problem with that is that we
have publicly traded companies that
manage identities I mean I don't
understand how that's allowed that area
experienced one of experience partners
supposedly cause Dave reached bed so
when a data breach occurs in the company
comes out blame someone else do you
think anyone verifies that evening
anyone can verify that the HVAC vendor
cost talk escape route well we can
finally the more compound report is
typing on paper anybody actually go like
a headline shall be the logs logs show
me the IP addressing show me where your
network touches my network that the
nitty gritty details up I don't think so
these companies get on the get on the in
front of the camera like any other time
in the world it's about what's best for
the company not necessarily true so you
gotta be careful with that that's always
it one on one that got Estelle me
or they just say you're going to take it
we paid you enough money over the last
20 years you're going to take this hit
the HVAC company didn't make a public
response that I know so I think that
that's a good that's a good modern look
at even taking into taking social out of
the process of validating a consumer or
ein side of the process of validating
the business now for businesses you have
what's what's the name of the little
company be done abressian private yet
you have done a brass trees which you
have to give your VI in the sign up but
when someone searches you they're not
searching you from uni is researching
from your business name contact
information that's a good start but they
don't necessarily compete with the
credit cards you know so it's it's it's
a great area it's a good thought
something to think about people like to
us can drive that kind of change if we
get that executive support and say hey
when you start doing things differently
in order to protect the company and the
first organizations that do it are the
ones that that they're the pioneers
they're the ones that are going to set
the stage model for
so I have a slightly different context
press press okay you um I come from like
the front line consumer customer service
so just the way I understand it for more
of my job is simplicity for the
customers like number one for most execs
so like we say remove identification
from the you know to America customer um
what would you do to replace like Social
Security numbers because again giving
them a customer number customers don't
remember things and I whoa attest the
thousands of phone calls I've taken you
do not remember things they create
themselves remember the social nothing
else that's on me that's an argument you
would have to overcome it's like cool
but now the customers won't like us
because we make them remember something
else I spend days and people Bruce let
their passwords and they said five
minutes ago and it's really funny so so
I say that and the response is oh man we
don't want your social security numbers
that he stolen by Romanian hackers and
them buying yachts on your credit so we
got rid of that that's why you need
executive support has to be driven from
the top and it needs to be a campaign
not hey here's our policy but hey we are
black water and our organization is
serious about protect your identity so
you're going to need to remove this
information because you can't bring us
your social we don't have access to it
then when you do it from that level from
the top day it will be change but you'll
never end up in the paper for day 30
billion dollars now let's say
there's this other stuff that you can
use that people aren't going to forget
right and the social has been in the
last four of social event you so much
and goodness is everywhere let's say
secret questions right give them the
option to create their own and say okay
well they asked me you know within these
constraints but they create you own your
first school you're not going to forget
you for a school in that you have acne
you know most you remember school your
first crush or different secured mean
I've heard something / like leopard that
being an issue to some customers how you
doing backs like people can find that
information about them oh we have even
been fine the last four years hope soon
where was your way to go to school
Starbucks is though so total so judges i
get a big fight over there right but
yeah line needs to be a part of the
process not lying like just tell live
but hey this secret question isn't here
for you to actually answer the question
correctly per se it's here for you to
create a username and a password but
it's a secret question format right so
if the question is who's your first
girlfriend and your answer is camara or
corvette avalanche or sign something
that's not a day but it's your username
and password
username you're giving them the past
we're back people are the issue and so
in an environment like what you're
talking about we would lose the battle
of Rho completely removing because it
would be too much changed fast but what
can we do we can get a direct portal to
experience now if we get a direct order
to experience on and we're using
information on experience servers are we
stalling it was our risk the data breach
0 million dollars that's why the
conversation is so important security
pros we go in and we started the
infrastructure people are going to push
back that's what they're supposed to do
smile so we can work together and find
another solution but there's so many
ways we do it now past the book xperia
already has the liability you're not
giving them anything that you don't
already have you know does that make
sense yeah so those apartments are tough
and they're going to be hard to change
once University same kind of ordeal yes
students coming in right there they're
build with their life in this university
there are more working students than
there are 18 year olds going on hospital
so these people have a lot going on they
can't do it a lot of change this would
be a perfect example replace that that
can implement some kind of direct access
to a credit bureau to do authentication
and then when they come back to this
system there's no vir it's just okay
we've validated who you are using
experience now we're going to process
the request reset passable references
I'm just going to say what it's worth
the company that I work for actually
does that that's the building thing that
we do is we store pee I I for other
companies so that they don't score p is
nice we give them an ID number and they
can retreat from the ID retreat if they
can use it from the idea that things
like the card numbers and things like
that processor that's awesome all on our
side as long as you I've do yes which is
that one keys are stored on this indigo
visit I personally had a berth on that
you know is they are going to pour the
Salesforce breach it's time I problem
you cannot be plowed that long and now I
preach unless you're out sign they're
not out so that's all time graphs thank
you very much over was helpful to you