I'm talking forever but I made it fun so
if you pay attention you might get
prizes then we're gonna go into the
brain because I'm obsessed with the
brain so you can learn a little bit
about how your brain works when it comes
to gaming and then why gamification
helps security teams and as well as how
gamification is transform lives
so while gamification is basically the
games that work on problem solving
processing speed attention span and
memory and now let's dive into the
history you guys ready for this you
gotta pay attention all right and for 25
BC a dice games were created to fight
major famine and in 3100 BC first board
game was created in Egypt
S&H Green stamp was the first time ever
marketers sold stamps to retailers that
if the customer returns they get a
discount and in 1958 the first video
game was invented and Charles Cora
founded a consulting firm called that
game of work and it brings feedback
loops found in sports into the workplace
and mu d1 is created by Roy at Essex
University it was the first multi-user
virtual world game Thomas Malone
publishes what makes things fun to learn
a study of interestingly motivating
computer games and in 1981 the first
ever 3d video games were released
American Airlines
actually introduces the very first
frequent flyer program and as aid
advantage and how they launched their
first royalty program as well natural
car rental did followed the first car
rental rewards program and 30% of
American households now actually owned
in NES a new generation of gamers is now
officially born and Richard Bartle
publishes who plays mu ace which divides
video game players into four unique
types
you guys ready for this okay the first
person who raised her hand and gave me
the right answer and I had my lovely
assistant over here who's gonna also
help me out here
you ready everyone let's do this in what
year did the first video game come out
yes perfect do you want a Reese's or a
KitKat bye
okay cat thanks a lot and it glows in
the dark you guys because that's we're
all kids we love this stuff right
alright you're ready for the next
question what country invented the first
board game yes huh yep
Kit Kat or Reese's cute
next question what airline did the first
frequent flyer miles
okay all the way down there yep and
which one KitKat Reese's perfect thank
you all right there we go candy hey
ready for the next part all right in
2002 series Damien issues forages a link
between the gaming industry and training
health education and public policy and
in 2003 Nick pelling coins the term
gamification a 2007 bunch ball created
dunder-mifflin infinity it's actually a
game of fide website for the TV show the
office and it receives over 8 million
pageviews within six weeks 2009 quest to
learn accepts a class of sixth graders
into a game based learning environment
and in 2010 dev hog adds a point system
to its website and increases user
engagement by 70% 2010 gamification co
holds the first gamification summit in
San Francisco
in 2012 45,000 enroll and a professor
kevin online gamification course through
Coursera and 2012 Mozilla opens badges
initiative is launched and the open
source badges can be used to mark
accomplishments online 2012 gartner
predicts 70% of the global 2000
organizations will have at least one
gamified application of by 2014 and 2014
m2 research predicts that gamification
will be a 2.8 billion dollar industry by
which is true and it actually went
beyond that and is expected to be about
11 billion dollar industry by 2020 you
guys ready again let's do this kou-kun
the term gamification that would be Nick
pelling next one what was the gamified
website by bunch ball for the TV show
The Office called
yes yep KitKat erases all right is that
racist okay next one gamification is
expected to become a blank billion
dollar industry by 2020 yes yep
Reese's or KitKat yeah so that is the
end of the pop quiz or is it not
hoi Missy but let's just dive right back
into the presentation right now
true fact though is InfoSec has always
been gamified think about it we do CTFs
we do bug bounty we do hackathons so
it's always existed and that's why even
now we have a time line and so in 1995
Netscape launched the first-ever bug
bounty program known to man and the
first DEFCON CTF was actually in 1996
and both battery programs were actually
created and managed
companies such as Google and Facebook
and Mozilla and ponchione started in
2007 and last but not least the bug
bounty programs themselves like those
platforms actually started coming around
in 2012-2013 and for the first time ever
companies didn't have to manage their
own so yeah there's more
about pop quiz here you guys ready next
round the first bug body program was
created in what year Yeah right
recess or kick at recess when was the
first CTF at DEFCON who was it
I think it was a guy with a red coat
correct recess or kick at kick it what
are the three major bug bounty companies
in the order of creation go found close
anyone else want to go to go yes mmm
close very close yeah we could do that
all right you just say it's buck hot
hacker one instant acts so close okay
all right now we're gonna dive into the
brains so first things first we're gonna
dive in and get to know your brain and
the cushions that I asked was actually
focused on that green part of your brain
that's it whatever way you're liking the
green part which is the temporal lobe
and in the temporal lobe if you see this
where the amygdala and hippocampus is
stored and this is the part that's
activated the most when it comes to
gamification so the temporal lobe is
involved in processing sensory input
into drive minis
appropriate tension a visual memory
language comprehension and emotion
association is where gamification
thrives and where the amygdala and
hippocampus are but believe it or not
this is the part that if you are a good
hacker or you work in InfoSec this parts
always lit up the most than any other
part of your brain probably so if we're
gonna do an activity now I'm gonna
basically say a line and you're gonna
shout out what is that word okay
sound good okay let's do this
a plant having a permanently woody main
stem usually growing to a high height
and developing branches at some distance
from the ground you shout out the answer
tree correct the nutritious orange to
yellow root of a plant of the parsley
family good job an article furniture
consisting of a flat top supported on
one or more legs table an institution
where instruction is given mm-hmm a
moving cage for carrying passengers from
one level to another good job a device
for transmission of sound or speech to a
distant point I don't always thinks
radio phone a body of water of
considerable size surrounded by land
like a domestic fowl bred for its flesh
eggs and feathers a shallow usually
circular dish from which food is eaten a
precipitation in the form of ice
crystals snow I wish it was ice cream
any sickly medium of exchange
money so if you sohow the temporal lobe
works is that you are taught in a sense
like this word has this visual so
whenever someone reads a description an
image comes to your head and then you
put a word to it so in the temporal lobe
that's where that happens is where the
visuals are therefore the visual cues to
understand the description to put an
actual image on it and a lot is audible
and also it could be anything that's
written so like I said we're gonna focus
now and amygdala and the hippocampus so
what is the hippocampus it's basically a
short-term memories are transform food
to long-term memories that are found in
temporal lobe so our conscious memories
are actually formed in the hippocampus
taking a snapshot of a short-term
working memory and commit to a long-term
and restore it in the temporal lobes and
yes there's another activity all right
now you got to pay attention to the
screens here everyone ready
take a note illicit items I want you to
read it once then twice and when you're
done look up here
okay next up I'm gonna ask you to take
out your phone so take out your phone
for the first time ever you are allowed
to take out your phone at a talk
congratulations
next step you ready I want you to like
basically get your notes out or draft an
email
you're never gonna sign it trust me
you'll be fine everyone has that raise
your hand hands up when you got it just
keep them up and one's got notes drafts
open all right cool now you have two
minutes to try to write all that list in
at the same order two minutes go
you have about one more minute remember
it has to be an order - you have 30
seconds now
all right
phones down hands both hands up that's
right you're under arrest now just
kidding
all right no changes can happen and
everyone make sure no one makes changes
okay you hold each other accountable how
many of you guys got the 10 in the right
order raise your hand anyone and you
won't even got Ted did anyone get 10 of
them correct nice and did you do it in
the same order or you'd like I would
give you something for that you want to
kick at our rhesus races and did you do
that because you came up with a story
see that is a trick ladies and gentlemen
how you do it is you make a story out of
it so the ones are like incredibly
professional they do this for our sport
and further living they'll come up with
a story for example I was walking in
London with an umbrella and my shoe got
stuck because I saw this cuddly toy in
the store but then I saw right next to
it there was a shop and they were
selling a melon but then when I was
walking I actually ran into almost the
tree because I only slipped on some
yogurt that was on the street because I
was also distracted by that their
apparent just like flew by in London for
some strange reason and I'm just
thinking oh my God thank God because my
laptop would have broken if I fell and I
also would have ruined my red jumper but
then at the end of the day I'm like that
red jumper is okay but it just brings
back those basketball days so you can
come up with story like that and it
sticks in your head so the more odd you
make it the better its
six so if you throw in an octopus
somewhere on that story or anything like
that that's how you're gonna remember
these things so give me the modules such
as gamification that shows that you know
problem solving on time or what not but
the thing is if you want to improve your
hippocampus your short-term memory to go
into long-term memory doing crossword
puzzles work really well and taking a
new route home so you don't use the same
one over and over just walk a different
way and gaming modules and the thing is
to know is about that particular one
that we just did there was timing
involved so that makes you anxious and
if you are a red teamer or yeah pretty
much your red team or you're doing buy
bounties or you're at a hackathon or CTF
timing is its essence and that is where
you thrive so anyone here have anxiety I
do so I'm just gonna raise my hand
awesome so if you had anxiety chances
are you're always like always stimulate
in this particular region the amygdala
which is an almond-shaped part of your
brain which is the fight versus fight
mechanism basically it's very socially
constructed for example if someone told
me okay no one has pink hair in here
right okay so if someone said to you be
careful if someone would pink hair
they're dangerous people what you're
gonna do is when you see someone with
pink hair you're gonna run to the other
side of street you're gonna do whatever
you can to avoid that person because you
were told at a very young age to be
afraid so your amygdala is constantly on
one it has a they see a threat but also
timing is one of those things you know
should say it's completely unconscious
so no time you can actually like try to
train it to go down is when you question
it and your prefrontal cortex or any
time you're in Magdala is like oh my god
it goes right to your head
your prefrontal cortex in the frontal
brain actually turns around it's like
you need to chill out because you
question it and this is a messages back
to the amygdala and say calm down or
fight-or-flight
all right here comes the activity
everyone ready and if you are scared
well I'm not even go there
so there's two parts to this so the
first part let's do this who saw the
keys and shoes the first time has anyone
actually seen this video before okay all
right you ready for the next one for
those that didn't see the keys and shoes
here you go
you don't need listen to him I'll just
tell you I remember that thing I told
you about socially constructive beliefs
at a young age you're told to be afraid
of spiders or snakes and maybe you
weren't told but you actually in the
media you saw maybe these people are
scared of spiders and snakes they're
like oh I should probably be scared of
these spiders and snakes so that is when
your amygdala is hitting really hard
it's like oh my god freeze if anyone's
been in a car accident who's been in a
car accident okay so I don't know if
you've experienced this is where
suddenly it feels like everything just
slow down really slow in that moment and
the reason for that is because you're on
high alert you're in survival mode
completely it's and that's called
amygdala hijack I actually believe it or
not so that is how it is so when you saw
the spiders and those snakes it seemed
like it was slower for some reason right
interesting right yeah that's it okay so
how does gamification actually help
security teams not only does it help
when it comes to your reflexes but also
you learn these things and you put it
into good usage and not just that but
certifications are not enough anymore
and too we need to always be aware of
everything at all times and the new
trends and then we also burnout we have
lack of team members as well on our team
and that leaves us up for a huge
security risk I mean how many you guys
actually experienced a storage on your
security team yeah it's hard because you
have to wear multiple different hats and
you have to do a lot more and that's why
it's really needed more than ever to do
gamification so then you can learn new
skills really fast and retain it really
fast in an effective way because if I
were to be the up here for talking for
four hours of
something you're not gonna pick up
majority of that you might pick up 10 to
20% of that at most so that's why it's
important to actually do something where
it constantly brings you back in so
every eight minutes you need something
new
you know why Family Guy's thrives it's
because it has those random moments
something you know he'll have a
conversation with someone and then a
chicken just comes busting in trying to
beat his ass so I mean and the kool-aid
guy as well so that's why it's so
successful is because people with a DD
and high anxiety you love that stuff
because it keeps you on your toes
so Gartner came out and about in 2020 I
don't have to read this can you guys
read it because I would totally read
this out loud but I don't have my
glasses either all right so now again
you're going to want to listen hint to
the facts here about so fact number one
96% of companies that adopt gamification
the workplace report seeing benefits
which is fantastic and that's four based
odd gamification exercise such as
hackathons capture the flag Red Team
Blue Team like Betty programs as well
and more than half 57% of response
actually reported that using game
increases awareness and IT staff
knowledge of how breaches can occur if
43 percent of gamification enforces team
work culture needed for a quick
effective cybersecurity in 77 percent of
senior managers agreed that their
organization would be safer if they use
more gamification and to address a
shortage in skilled cyber secure worker
the report also suggests that gamers
those engaged in immersed in online
competitions may be the logical next
step to plug the gap and believe it or
not that nearly 92 percent of
responsibility that gaming affords
players experience and skills crucial to
cyber security such as threat hunting
like logic perseverance and understand
how to approach adversaries and fresh
outlook compared to traditional cyber
security team that's why it more often
now when you're going for job interviews
to be on a red team
your future manager will ask you
questions do you play games and if
they're not they're gonna try to find
out social engineer you to find out now
and the reason for that is that they
would rather hire someone who does
gaming then does not do gaming because
it shows that you're effective you're
fast
and 77% of employees find game based
training to be more effective than
traditional training methods such as
gaming standing up here and giving you a
four hour lecture and the most important
thing is that not only does gamification
help so if you do like say for example
before you are employed you actually go
through an exercise and this gaming
module basically test out your speed
your strengths and your weaknesses this
is a game-changing moment to be honest
because I don't know about you ladies in
here for example sometimes when you
submit your resume you're worried that
they're gonna see your name and not call
you for the next interview because
biases do exist and so in a sense we
have noticed that when you do gaming
modules before being hired this is a
really good thing to note because what
ends up happening is the people that
they usually reject based on resumes and
because sometimes they just see
certifications like that person is
perfect but in reality they might not be
the best person on the team and for the
first time ever they're actually able to
see who's gonna do a better job in the
end and that's changing Dynamis because
now there's more women being hired
because of this and believe it or not
even when you're doing gaming modules
even when you're on your team so
sometimes companies they'll like hire
gamification modules to test out their
team find their weaknesses basically do
like some of them have like a Netflix
kind of thing where I set up where you
get to pick which ones you want to do
the courses and so those that do pretty
well on those or they they finally get
flagged and notice that they're actually
someone really good on the team and also
once again another interesting thing for
women allowed that time is the women are
in junior penthouses
positions and what happens is that they
go through this course and then they're
basically their manager sees their
talent and cannot believe that they
actually out beat them themselves and so
that's something to think about is that
this is a way to actually challenge
biases and also like I said we do have a
skills gap it's not just about
certifications anymore and not just that
we are all burned out in this industry
we burn out so fast because we don't we
have weird hours of sleep let's be real
and not just that we're always worried
about a breach and it will cost us our
job or our manager's job or someone's
job and that's why it's really important
to do type of gaming modules to make
sure that we're in the best shape
possible
and yes so if you can answer this
question I have a recess or kick effort
good for it huh
no 96 recess or kick at recess not only
that so I did share a little bit about
some statistics and everything but also
it's transform lives and remember when I
was talking about those biases I have
two stories that actually share these
kind of things
so one is Veronica Veronica was studying
computer science by accident but she was
actually planning to originally stay
Latin and Greek and she was also taking
computer science classes and she just
realized that that would probably better
for her and so when she graduates she
was like I'm in I don't want to do a PhD
so instead she went to youth development
and she did that for about five years
after graduating and she loved it but
didn't challenge her she wanted to be
kind of something that would inspire her
and power her and so one day she was she
saw like this ad with a partnership with
the DoD as a boot camp and they drew her
to it because they said on there we're
looking for problem-solving ability
being able to work on problems were a
long time and willingness to do
discipline - with your learning and
since she loves patterns and puzzles and
whatnot she started out with the reverse
engineering challenge with Escalade and
after she went to a consulting company
for about six months within InfoSec and
her tire was a technology consultant but
she really was a pen tester and so she
actually was approached by 0.3 because
she was scored the highest out of all
and so they brought her on and basically
now she works with us and but the thing
is important to know is that she never
said off to be a hacker she never knew
that that was something that was going
to be good for her until she realized
that from that boot camp Valentina
so Valentina she studied psychology it
wasn't a big fan of math but yet she
took a math class in college and she
realized she had this huge love for it
so she went to go school all to continue
to study math at UIC and she did an
internship at the physics department and
she had to basically learn some basic
coding and took a class in computer
science as well and afterwards she
worked as The Economist as the Federal
Reserve Bank she discovered a passion
for computers at that point because she
thought it would be so cool to tell a
computer what to do and I'll do it for
her
and she just thought I really also want
to learn a little bit more about what
else I can do with a computer so she
thought it would be really cool to
basically go into hacking and the reason
for that she saw the movie hackers who
seen hackers excellent so she thought it
was like really cool and so she was like
I really liked that early computer like
internet culture hacking community image
and it really attracted her to it but
she didn't know where to start and she
also thought like she always kept seeing
this image of you know any time you look
up hacker on Google Images what do you
get is facing cancer redbull rebels true
but I mean let's be real so she saw a
press release from Chicago it was for
the mayor actually posted saying that
they're looking for basically for anyone
who's interested in maybe being
recruited for the DoD and so she decided
she was gonna go and do this and she
applied and she got accepted so once
again this event was sponsored by
escalate and she had absolutely zero
experience beforehand and within three
months she knocked it out of everything
so within three months with no
experience
she actually realized that this is
something she was actually good at and
not just up but the instructors noticed
that she was way ahead of her time and
with the three months she was actually
recruited out of the six-month program
because she was that good and this was a
way to see these things and it's funny
because the like basically those that
were trying to recruit her from that
event during the whole then they never
saw it coming they never thought that
she is the face as someone who would be
a hacker so this is a very different
thing for her so yeah and now she works
at point three yeah I'm gonna share
about my colleagues cuz I love them
they're amazing as she was offered a
software developer position now she's a
wanna be a researcher and yes because
this is my second time giving this talk
I want to get to know your story
if there has been anything that
gamification has helped get you where
you are today and InfoSec I want to know
it and I want to put it on here and yes
we can change your photo and your name
if you like but I would love to do that
and last night at least
who was inspired by the movie hackers
does I remember her name
no cause it starts with a V Valentina
you said Valentina okay I'm gonna go
with you chica teresa's thank you
so from the stories are brain
functioning and history is very clear
that gamification is a necessity right
now and honestly is because let's be
real we're all superheroes wear that
every day heroes
well I breaking things fixing things
we're keeping everyone safe we're
keeping our neighbors safe we're keeping
our families safe and that's the
fantastic thing it's like giving myself
a pat on the shoulder you deserve it
because it's people like us in this room
that are making difference right now
we're keeping breaches recurring and so
on
any questions
does anyone see it has anyone seen this
skit okay good thing because I added a
little bit early so we can watch this by
the way it is amazing any questions can
also ask me at the end it's totally fine
if you're shy don't worry
I got you but I also wanted to ask
everyone a favor if you don't mind if
you see right here there is a huge event
that's gonna happen on November 2nd and
for the first time ever women around the
world are gonna do a virtual CTF right
now we're over 600 women and it was just
announced last Monday and I'm asking for
you guys to share this around tweet it
out share let every single woman even at
your company know about this and it's so
important because it's capped at 1,000
and I basically was just like I really
want this event to happen I want to show
that women are really into this stuff
too
so basically the it's for all levels so
even if it's your first time doing a CTF
it is gonna be reverse engineering and
it'll be a walkthrough
after that it's basically there's
different modules for you to do and it
will be big prizes possibly a full trip
to Def Con hotels everything covered and
paid for and some other really cool
other prizes as well so please share
this around let people know about it
because let's let's make history you
guys come on all right
and also I just wanted to say thank you
to Texas cyber summit so much for having
me and a special shout out to Joseph and
my wonderful volunteers in this room for
making this amazing event and thank you
guys for existing and I always and that
reason for thank you for existing is
because a lot of us have been feeling
like we're isolated and alone and I just
want to let you know that you should not
feel like this at all and if you do my
dams are always open and I'm always
there to listen and even guide you if
you need resources at all
there's also mental health hackers which
is doing great incredible work so if you
need anything feel free to reach out
that is what we need to be more like in
this community is be there and open now
I'm gonna show you a really funny clip
are you guys ready
yeah I was like wait am i come on
where's that energy give you some candy
also I have some really cool stickers I
got some swans because you know swans
I don't smalls are gorgeous and
everything but has anyone try to get
close to this one you know what happens
right they hiss and they will attack you
they're bad asses so I have some swans
and then I have some special stickers
for red teamers and blue teamers so feel
free to come up and I do have some
leftover candy so if you come up and
talk to me I got candy for you okay well
let's do this now I'll take me one
second all right you guys ready for this
I heard someone say they love this I do
too it's my favorite thing in the world
around this time of the year anyway
thank you guys for being here and what
see Anna I have stickers candy and any
ladies here for women hackers raise your
hand all right those that are not in
this room come up and talk to me let me
get you in here it's free and it's a lot
of fun and plus I'm totally down for
getting drinks later with all yeah okay
I'm here all day and thank you guys big
thing