so hi my name is Eduardo Vela I am going
to be talking about Google book hunters
which is the way we call people that
find security vulnerabilities in Google
products
my nickname is heard are cut and I
before I joined Google I was doing the
same thing I was reporting box to Google
products mostly because I thought it was
a difficult challenge and because it was
fun and when I found one by accident I
got hooked and I kept on doing it at
that time Google was not paying for bugs
so I was just doing it for fun what I
got a t-shirt that looked very similar
to this one and it was cool since then
now now after I joined and one year
after more or less I joined there has
been we have had the VRP they would not
really reward program where we pay
people for it they this is our logo we
don't actually have a logo we just saw
this picture on the one app on one of
the internal slide decks and we thought
it was cool
so we appropriated it we added the three
things in the side like the colors over
there can I do that
yes and then we said it was ours but
yeah anyway so I've been in Google for
around 10 years but the VRP only has
been around for a long now nine we are
not the longest-running one Mozilla has
been running significantly faster than
us and in terms of you just generally
bug bounties there's another one which
is Knuth had a bounty of like very
little month money for everyone that
could find the problem in his books so
we are not the longest-running one but
we have been running for a long time and
one of the things that has happened
since then is that our program is one of
the ones that has been running for a
long time that hasn't changed that much
internally like compared to like
Microsoft or Facebook and so on we we've
been growing in the same I don't know
theme to say to say which we think it's
interesting mostly because we have been
lucky enough to make some choices that
have allowed us to grow
consistently for several years with
process 60,000 whenever it is since then
that doesn't mean that we've paid for
all of them many of them are very very
low risk so we just don't pay for them
we've paid for 10,000 of them which is
roughly around $1,000 per reward this is
not exactly this is not completely true
as I will explain in like a second but
this is roughly the case one thing that
is worth mentioning is that chrome and
Android also have a reward program which
we operate independently of them which
means that eight million dollars is what
our program has paid but chrome on
Android together with us have paid
fifteen million dollars and this year
we're going to pay - yes for Google and
probably another - for chrome on Android
together so like 50 percent increase in
the last year this presentation is
called Google bug hunters because I will
be talking about bug hunters there's
also going to be things talking about
our process and things like that but
mostly I want to talk about bucks that
auerbach hunters found and like kind of
introduce them to you his name is Thomas
with yarski he has been reporting back
to Google for around five years and he
is the top earner let's say for the
Google beer P he mostly report success s
but also called execution and so on
every once in a while and he's really
like for him everything is easy so we
just met him like last week and he was
just making a presentation about a
hundred xs/s he found which are worth
around half a million dollars and he was
just saying like this is so easy and he
was going through his lights easy right
easy easy
so he's right he's very funny and we
meet him every once in a while but every
time we do is very fun experience the
other one this is a implement his name
is secret so I will not take his actual
name but he is also very good for this
year he is the top Bach hunter and he
mostly finds logic out by past issues
like largest business logic problems
like we forget to do access control
checks properly somewhere and so on and
one of the things to note about these
tuba contours is that this is
like very very tedious repetitive work
and they they spend a lot of time doing
this and they find amazing things just
because of the amount of patience they
have we we try to do the same thing we
try to automate it but we are not able
to be as effective as there so those are
the bug hunters now this is this is not
these are not work hunters The
Raconteurs were the ones in the previous
lights this is a whale feces researcher
and those guys were there are elephants
vasectomies do you know what they have
in common
anyone has heard this reference before
so they called the third and fifth worst
jobs in science the third is the whale
feces researcher and the fifth are the
elephant's with Septimus --ts the fourth
according to the science magazine in
2007 was our job in our except from
Microsoft so this what is it called the
popular science magazine called the
Microsoft security grant or what we
equate to our team in my in Google as
the worst jobs in science and it was
kind of interesting when I saw this
light this is from Kate emissaries and I
thought it was hilarious
but also I kind of knew kind of why but
then I was like wow like it must be
worse for them so we we have also
full-time roles fulfilling this but we
actually don't have that that problem
like we don't consider our job that it
sucks and I was one of these present the
main purpose of this presentation is to
figure out what made it so that we don't
hate it and and the TLDR is here that we
well now you guys have to see the whole
thing
so we receive an 800 upon elite report
monthly that is valid to narrative
reports that doesn't mean that all of
owner abilities are serious but is yes
it does mean that there's something that
we investigate and something is working
from in some confusing way after three
as many of them are duplicates or not
zero
or whatever so we will pay for all of
them this essentially means that we have
35 vulnerability reports every day every
time every day we work which means it
will be interesting to see how many
people do you think it will take to to
manage this in practice up to very
recently it was one person so how to
avoid burnout so the way that we do it
for one person I'll explain what one
person means because now it's kind of
two but it's complicated so the first
thing we do to make this with one person
is we have a rotation and that's with
twelve people so there is 12 people in a
rotation going once each and the reason
that we need 12 people we have tried
with less and we have tried with more we
tried with 30 at some point and 30 is
terrible you shouldn't do 30 30 because
nobody nobody remembers how to do it and
everyone is super inconsistent and we
tried with ached and it's like the well
vasectomies guy so not don't do that
either
it is 2/12 time commitments which means
before it was 1:12 now we have to 12 so
that means before we only had one person
at any point in time now we have body
teams so yeah
the body team part so before the way we
handle this was when you were in your
week you own the whole queue but that
had some issues when we had an incident
or something like that because if we had
something very serious it has to be done
right now you kind of drop in the floor
everything else so we created this body
system where the secondary we just take
some important things and then it has it
has evolved into a situation where the
primary supposed to spend as much time
as possible and whatever the extra work
there is the secondary works but we as a
secondary to be there as a backup some
people use the secondary differently I
use I am still in the rotation so I used
my secondaries mostly as a whenever
there's a bug that is too complicated to
reproduce I asked them to help but other
than that they don't have much to do
so the other thing that is important is
that we have a helpline so one thing
that is interesting is we have very
senior people doing rotation as well and
that part is important for us because
the more senior the people doing the
rotation the more confident they are on
their responses and the more confident
they are the less time they spend on it
which means that a senior person kind of
spend one hour to 335 reports let's say
but senior person can take many days for
the same for the same amount of work and
they this is just a matter of confidence
and this is another reason why we have
the they work in pairs because then we
can pair up a very senior person with a
very junior one this is useful and this
will help a lot because whenever we try
to put a different role in front either
someone on technical or someone just
learning they just blow up and go back
to the well vasectomies thing so one
thing that like is it's not in
proportional is this prayer is not
proportional they the seniority with the
junior thing is like way signe senior
people are significantly better at it
and if they don't have to be senior at
doing this job they just have to be very
confident on the things that they are on
the technology I know what they are
doing anyway everything we have is a
helpline we have a chat or a rope chat
where everyone asks questions and one of
the most important things that we found
out is that people don't use it unless
the senior people use it all the time so
the more senior people have to be using
it every time so that the other everyone
feels comfortable asking questions and
whenever we forget to use it for a
couple months we notice that the channel
goes that because nobody else uses it so
that that was interesting not using the
channel has been has made us very very
has made it so that they get buried they
get stuck very early and having senior
people use it has helped a lot and
templates one of the things that happens
is that not everybody our team there's a
lot of things that are specific to
Google that even if you are an expert in
things you will not know what the answer
is and you can ask in the helpline if
you want but the easiest way to do it is
to just have a template that is
essentially the knowledge base of our
team and we have like hundreds and
hundreds of templates
it's very easy to write the template
here at the response and then just click
Save and when people do search for the
templates they get to learn something
about that someone else previously did
so templates were also an interesting
learning just having something where
people can search for previous responses
was something that allowed people to
like not blow up so 12 people having 12
people if possible but it I understand
that not always absolutely working in
pairs having a helpline that senior
people use and having a templating
system that people use that people are
stiring responses all the time
has been has been the main way that we
didn't convert into well vasectomies
another thing that's interesting about
everything is that we have a lot of
people but they a lot of people base
their work on the results of the reward
program this helps a lot to justify the
existence of the program but also to
justify the existence of our team
so like privilege escalation Tomas with
yarski the guy I just presented the
beginning he found a way to get a code
execution in inter and some internal
Google things and that led to some
research about how that can we prevent
this from happening so this is a
privileged collation part of the thing
security mitigation sees how to make
exploitation vulnerabilities harder and
the way that they guide their work is
based on how how many vulnerabilities
report to the VRP are mitigated by their
technologies by CSP by sandboxing and
whatever code hardening the way that
they decide or they justify how much
time and effort they spent on hardening
certain types of products is based on
they will not reward program results and
are prosecuted to reviews the way that
we know whether we did a good job or not
is to see for the product that we do
secure through before
how many end up receiving external
product owner abilities so generally
speaking like the Security Response
effort doesn't feel but it definitely
helps the rest of our team justify and
do our work better another thing that
was interesting that we didn't do
properly before and we ended up learning
about it after some time was to separate
the money from the technical details and
this is something that many that this is
that very few other companies do for
whatever reason but this this is very
well this has been very important for us
so epic hunters when they report things
to Google we try to make them only
talked about the vulnerability technical
details and we tried and if they ask any
questions about the reward or anything
like that we tell them we don't know
this is about the panel and I don't know
tell me about the technical details and
the reason is because the person doing
that the triage we call them whoopsies
because our team is cool whoops
they is essentially trying to get
convinced by the external user that
there is a problem because once they are
convinced that there is a problem then
they have to convince a product team to
fix it so the person here in the middle
is just inter is essentially at first
representing Google to the back
continent and representing the book
hunter to the product team so we have
the same incentives in terms of like the
product team to get the bug fix so
whatever it is that they explained to us
in terms of risk we will pass into the
product in the however sometimes people
end up arguing endlessly about money and
by having the person here not have any
ability to control that at all then we
is easier for them to say like it's not
in my control sorry this is going to be
sent to the panel independently of that
and we have the panel which is a bunch
of people including me that I decide how
much money things get the people here
only review things one one week every 12
weeks
the people here review the same every
buck every week so people in the panel
are looking at every buck every week
this is like six to eight people
depending on the year looking at every
single bug that we received every year
every week surprisingly people here this
is a position that people want to be on
it is not a position that we force
people to be on or anything like that is
not even a volunteer-driven thing is
like we have to limit the amount of
people we have in the panel because if
you have too many people is hard to
manage and there is some people like it
is because all the box at this they see
are the valid box that were three
already buy them so they are very
interesting issues we did two weeks ago
we had around 75 issues that were in the
queue because we have leftovers or
people escalate and so on
so this position although it sounds kind
of awkward it is it is very fun like to
see all the issues that come in and out
they another interesting thing about
this is that people in the panel are not
always so one of the things that happens
is that one bug hunters disagree about
the reward amount because we have all of
all of the things that we decide our
public like the criteria we use so when
we decided word amount and the back
country disagrees that means that we did
we don't understand the risk properly
because they we are using the
information that the product team and
the engineer told us to decide the
reward amount so if the bug hunter
disagrees with the reward amount then
that means that the impact is
misunderstood so we encourage very much
the bug hunters to argue for more money
because maybe we misunderstand the
reward amount we will misunderstand the
impact so if we don't if we get it wrong
then that means that we are not using
the severity properly so the bug bite
might not get fixed properly or might
not get fixed quick quick enough so by
arguing by asking them to argue forward
amounts we make sure that we get the
right the right impact and by separating
the the the roles these doesn't burn out
the people in in in triage anyway this
worked out very well and it has helped
us catch issues that we didn't realize
where our series as they were until
later on when the bug hunters explained
us so sometimes in person like last week
we were in in London in event with the
bug hunters and we actually they
actually got to show us like that we
misunderstood something or something
like that in person and that is pretty
much like the ideal scenario for this so
yeah we also tried to whenever we
communicate about what hunting
externally we try to limit the amount of
ways we explain we talk about it as a
function of money because for many of
them especially people that are already
well paid in a normal job this is not
about the money alone this is just about
like cool research or about making
things safer and whatnot but whenever
you you focus all communications about
money then
ually innate and this has happened a lot
several times that we have famous
security researchers contact contact us
and when they see that our
communications used to be money related
they eventually their tone change very
quickly and when we change all of our
templates to not talk about money at all
you talk about the technical impact that
essentially attract that fixed those
type of relationships but it's very easy
to send away people that just want to
help you and don't care about the $5,000
you're going to give them because they
already have some money so one of the
other three ways that we manage to
attract and retain very senior people do
all of these work like the the panel and
the and the triage people is because the
way the way it works in Google is that
people kind of choose the type of things
they're interested in and you cannot
kind of force them to do anything so the
way that you convince them to stay doing
this work is with more reports so the
the the reason this is interesting is
because if you are three aging a lot of
invalid boring reports then it is very
easy to burn out but if you are three
urging very cool and interesting
challenging surprising problems and
vulnerabilities then rather than burning
out you get super interested in them so
we have invested a lot in education and
on ways of interacting with book hunters
to deliver better better reports mostly
as a justification for us to get better
reports so that people don't get burned
out so we created this these are the
three more interesting things one of
them is what country University which is
just a websites in which we teach people
the things are interested in one of the
before we had this so there is a lot of
people that are very very motivated and
keep on sending reports every day for
like months and when you see that when
we saw that some time ago like maybe
five years ago we were very very close
to
implementing something that deprioritize
their reports so that was essentially a
way of saying we do all of the reports
of this person are invalid so we don't
want to delay the response to everyone
else and we have an internal discussion
about it and we decided not to do that
and instead of doing that we just talk
to this to this bug hunter and we told
him what we were looking for
like we just spent some one-to-one time
with them and I mean not in person but
in in chat and it worked they stopped
sending all of the valid reports they
suddenly send us the good ones let's say
which were not that many but that worked
by some that we did but continued
versity in which we figured if we are
not telling people what we actually want
to get from them or we get very very
little information or we don't give them
technical information maybe we just tell
them generally this is the scope but we
don't give them why this is important
then essentially that leads to a lot of
noise and if we have a lot of noise we
burn out our security research hours our
engineers and if we burn out our
engineers nobody will want to do it so
we need it invest in education in order
to keep our staff happy anyway so
current university was just a website
where we have a bunch of stuff of the
things we're interested in form
submission of tips is something that we
do just before the report debauch to us
we do some roller expressions and based
on the things that they say we just show
them some information that this is
likely invalid or whatnot and this cut
the conversation close quickly because
when they send the report they already
know why it is invalid which has been
useful and lastly asking questions so I
went to nuke on four years ago Newton is
a conference in India and everyone from
Facebook Microsoft and Google got sick
after the conference but one of the
there are two things it was completely
worth it even though some of them went
to the hospital it they the reason it
was worth it is because III learned two
things in that in that in that
conference we gave a presentation kind
of similar to this but with more
vulnerabilities
and one one guy at the end came to me
and and as and told me I was on
interrupts I wasn't three as a week
before and we sign our name at the end
so everyone knows that I was the one
that reported so he came to me and we do
triage my blog last week and he was like
well what was it and it's like oh you
reacted it and I'm like why what what
was the buck like it was the first time
I met someone that I had to react to the
bug on so it was like an interesting
encounter and he told me oh it was a
quickie aking in whatever and it when
you are when we are in our computer we
had these templates we had these Bakken
University articles and stuff so we we
can just with a couple buttons we can
just send them a response answering
their question but this was the first
time that I didn't have this and I had
to interact with someone right so I
didn't know how I I was not going to
explain to them or to him the amount of
like how how he was wrong so I just
accidentally asked him why do you think
it's a bug and then I kind of dust his
brain because like essentially he he
realized he hasn't thought about that
part yet he just realized it was
clickjacking there was missing extra
Martians I should report this and when I
asked him why is this important or how
can you exploit this he hadn't thought
about that
which was an interesting insight because
nowadays when we have someone that is
very very enthusiastic we just ask them
to think about those things like why is
this a serious or how is this
explainable because they in some cases
they haven't thought about this before
and when once they think about it they
start reporting box where they can
answer those questions and then it's
less work for us at least and it's very
fast to ask one sent these questions
rather than the paragraphs that we had
to invest him before so that allows us
to scale a bit better another thing that
happened in that in that trip was that I
met this guy
Jasmin there so yes he's one of our top
100 condors
we have like thousands so that's still
very good and when I met him in person
he
I mean he he reports books valid more
often than not but he does he is not all
the time valid but when we asked him he
said that a hundred percent of his that
he has success rate of a hundred percent
and we didn't understand what that meant
right which was interesting because the
way that he figure this is that whenever
he goes after a hunt which is a group of
products let's say and he finds
something out of the twenty reports he
sends he considers that the whole hunt
successful that essentially it's
completely different how we see it
because from our side we don't know when
they are in a hunt we're just in three
days wrong week and we are not able to
see them like do all these reports over
over several weeks so from our
perspective we can see a bunch of
invalid reports and every once in a
while one of them is valid so thinking
about this in this way helped us a lot
because then we created a program called
research runs in which we just give them
money ahead of time and if they find
something or not they still keep the
money and we only ask them to report the
bugs that are ballots and they get money
on top of the of the grant for every
ballot report do they send so there is
no incentive to send invalid reports we
give them like between five hundred to
three thousand dollars and they just
keep it and if they find more bugs
they get more money on top we don't ask
for a report at the end or anything like
that this is just like like we think
that they are going to invest some time
on this anyway and we want them to
invest on it in and and find something
so
thinking the way that he thought about
it actually the fact that he mentioned
that he goes on a hunt and that's how
he's used his time and we started asking
other countries if they did it that way
and they told us all of them they told
us yes then allowed us to create a
program that kind of aligned several
solve several problems at the same time
grants also solved the problem of
duplicates because he's not a waste of
time that you didn't that you find the
same bug with other people and starting
next year we are going to be doubling
reward amounts are that are found
between two people together if they find
them as part of a grant so
essentially like grants is a way to
structure the work a bit better and it
was all thanks to - yes like that one
conversation was like oh my god
one thing that is interesting is that we
have been giving grants for a long time
and the one of the things that we found
out that before we didn't know what what
is the success rate of hunters that
means how often when people go on a hunt
can they find something and we just
realized that it unless your tummy
además the first guy I talk to you about
that everything is easy your success
rate is in average 13.7 percent which is
great because it's almost 1 3 3 7 and we
were very happy when we found of them so
so they the the success rate 13.7
percent means that for every grant that
we give only 13.7 percent of those have
a result and the other 86.3% get nothing
and we still think this is a worth use
of our time because this is the risk
that our book hunters are taking like
when when is 10 of you go looking for
bugs in Google only one of you is going
to succeed or 1.3 of you will succeed so
that's that was interesting for us to
find out and now we know over time
depending on we can slice it in
different ways we can see depending on
which product you go after depending on
which technology open who you are and so
on but yeah that that no number we
didn't have before another thing that
happened and this was thanks okay this
is escalate was an event that we had
last week in London we had three things
happening on it in eg which is a an
event with students we fly students
around Europe to London and we give them
some workshops box what we fly our topic
on tours from around the world to London
again and we have them give
presentations and CTF is just a Google
CTF finals and we have some you know CTF
chat tasks and we solve them or they
solve them we we build them
this is Venkatesh this is also his salsa
from India he's he's from the second
time I went to to know Khan
and Venkatesh reported some bugs in
Google Cloud shell yes you essentially
were able to get a shell injection in
Google clouds through a special URL and
it was a cool blog and everything and we
were having dinner the night before the
present we invited him to go to do an
old con to present his findings like we
essentially talking can you please come
to Newcomb we will tie for your flights
and everything and we want you to give a
presentation about your Google box and
he he said ok he prepared a presentation
we send it to us and then the night
before he told me hey I noticed that the
buggy still works so what's up with that
and we were like all really like yeah
but he got reported it to us like three
months before us on reddit
so we had plenty of time to fix it and I
checked internally and the other team
was were sitting on the Box still like
for whatever reason and so he asked if
he can still talk about it and yeah he
talked about it one of the interesting
things happen about talking about it in
a in an audience like that was that we
realized that actually it wasn't too bad
like people like the book wasn't that
serious the blog got fixed like the day
after and it was still like it was worth
him zero day awesome stage and if
happened a couple times afterwards as
well then I was keeping a secret so now
we have this other event called Escalade
which is the one in London and one of
them is box what were we allowed bug
hunters to talk about on patch zero days
with each other there is no zero day or
and if there is no in the air or
anything people we just trust them to to
do that properly and we also have the
CTF one interesting diversity F is that
we the way that we run it now is that we
train people do we train other Google
engineers to write challenges and there
is a way to do security advocacy around
the company we just teach them they
werner ability they are supposed to
write a challenge for and they write it
and burner ET write-ups many bug hunters
don't like talking about their bugs
so this is a book from the implement the
guy the second guy talked about and this
is the first time he talks about the
book this was bugging chat Google
that he could inspire another
conversations or something like that and
they never talk about their box which is
a problem because without good examples
we cannot show good examples to Bach
hunters that are just starting so we
started encouraging them
we created a theater account and we
started telling people to please do it
but then still they were not doing it so
then we pay a youtuber to write videos
about other people's box and because now
they become famous because he has lots
of followers then people are doing it
but it took us like multiple attempts to
get to get people to talk about their
books and we want people to talk about
their box because we want more bugs
anyway so the summary for this is one
good one easy way to resolve burnout is
to have more cool vulnerabilities one
easy way to not have to handle so many
to not get those with so many questions
is by asking questions yourself to work
on tours especially how is this
exploitable or why teaching is teaching
bug hunters about their bug about
vulnerabilities is a great use of
resources and helps in many ways and
this closure has helped us find more
bugs and get more back indoors with us
and that's it I think I'm almost of
times and that's exactly the time so
thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you for the presentation we have
time for maybe one or two question is
there any question no okay so you can
talk with Eduardo later thank you it
other