Thank You hello hello I think this is
the last talk for today right feeling
tired no okay you might be a little bit
tired after this oh just you know a
little bit I indeed I will complain I
will complain a lot and this is not like
the cryptography talk it's mostly about
software engineering about library
design about specifics of different
languages and different operating
systems so actually when I submitted a
call for papers for this talk the name
was maintained for Africa libraries for
11 languages but now we have 12 so for
the last half a year we have added
another one and I'll show that 12
actually the last one it's not like a
language is a platform we added web
assembly and right now we can cover you
know even all those electron
implications ok so my name is Anna
Stassi and I am such a developer so I
came from Sofia developer world I was
doing a lot of applications and then I
switched the security and for many years
right now I am working in the data
security company working with
cryptography but not on the surface
level more on a protocols level data
protection level so protecting data for
different kind of applications and the
company work called Kazakh labs that's
UK company but of course you can see
some Ukrainian roots there yeah I'm from
Ukraine so that's UK company and we are
vendors of security software mainly
based in cryptography mainly for data
protection usually our software like
other companies integrate other software
to protect data to encrypt data all the
time and the thing is that we have a
really nice cryptography team and we are
working on you know a novel technology
it's not in ciphers but most a new
protocol
trying to solve typical businesses cases
with cryptography so like anyone will
have any access to data for example like
searchable encryption like zero
knowledge authentication like
authentication using zero knowledge
proof protocols like a data
collaboration on and two encrypted data
these kind of things and we put these
research into libraries and we usually
open source it and then based on some of
these libraries we create our software
and then we sell it so it's like
multi-layered thing and today I gonna
talk to you gonna tell here about one of
these libraries we open source and we
support and many other people use
because it's free it's open source yet
another cryptographically library and
how actually you know complicated it is
to support multi-platform library so
let's start yeah obviously encrypted we
trust and by crypto I don't mean lock J
today for this talk for this talk
grifter is cryptography okay okay yeah
so in Cliffton be trust but not only in
like any crypto in usable crypto because
you know all these mistakes developers
do trying to use cryptographic
instruments and we kind of try to
eliminate them today we're gonna talk
about warren crypto about timers as a
library about what the difference
between easy to use and hard to misuse
okay and about security testing and all
these things developers should do like
maintainer should do to prevent
developers making mistakes and they
always always always try to make
mistakes okay so let's start let's start
thinking that we asked the FIR
developers we don't know a lot about
security we don't know about a lot about
cryptography because most of 12 ella
purrs are like this and we have a very
very simple use case we need to protect
the data for simplicity we need to
protect
torrid data so it's data at rest
encryption really easy should be however
as a developers there are really many
things we need to think of trying to
tune to protect this data first of all
which kind of later to protect right
many people like many many many many
people they make the same mistake with
data scope because we have some data
sensitive for our business and we
believe that this is only user PII only
names emails here together but no
usually for some businesses 'likes and
preferences that we as a company
collects about our users is also
sensitive data that we will we will lose
money if we will lose this kind of data
so we need to protect it as well then
the risk rd4 in different kind of
regulations depending on the industry
GDP our PCI DSS HIPPA DPB lots of them
they also push us as a company to
protect different kind of data right and
last but not least the technical data
all these accesses api tokens are you
Malins passwords AWS tokens that we
store in our infrastructure somewhere
and we also my need to protect some of
this bitch
so first mistakes developers usually do
they don't the undies to made this co-op
or protected it but let's let's let's
let's say that you do really the great
job within the risk management and we
know which data to protect like ok now
next step is let's select a cipher and
you know how many ciphers are like for
for dates for simple symmetric
encryption can you know can you name
some of them ciphers for date encryption
at rest
yes right Blowfish good choice 2019
towfish ghost whose neck oh yes oh yes
ok so I
okay let's let's say that is however
which is mode which padding to use what
IV what in it vector we need to use
which killing it a select then when we
say key obviously we mean a
cryptographic key and it's different
from password so how to derive this key
with continuation function to use then
of course when we start having keys we
start having key management problems we
need to exchange this case we need to
store these keys
we need to revoke accesses probably we
will have some key management systems
cameras HSM yet the other depends on our
infrastructure our system last but not
least our small let's protect the data
exercise in a huge infrastructure causes
us to support all the things on multiple
platforms and probably to pick up our
keys and the question is if we pick up
keys how we will protect our backup
shall we encrypt them where to store
encryption keys for encrypted backups
and another the caps you know the thing
yeah you know you know you will you will
end up having a master key as a QR code
on paper in your safe I'm not joking
really this is a kind a good way to do
well not a perfect one but one oh poor
poor poor developers have been there
just to protect the data storage
encryption sure I read this I read this
research like three years ago probably
so the thing is as people analyzed
different vulnerabilities in different
applications and they try to divide it
into two large group the group number
one vulnerabilities in applications
caused by cold inside crypto libraries
and the second group
vulnerabilities inside applications
caused by misusing crypto libraries and
now and now guessing game guess the
numbers so 100% let's get the number
how much vulnerabilities were caused by
misusing clipped libraries
99 good one try more like close enough
but not so bad again 75 okay 99 75 98
close close close enough
83 it but you get the point you get the
point of course after this kind of
introduction it was easy to estimate
right most bugs in applications with
cryptography are not inside
cryptographic libraries but in misusing
telegraphic libraries because you know
there are really really a lot of ciphers
in the world and many cryptographers
yellow jean-philippe many cryptographers
are super excited about making new
ciphers but developers they don't need
new ciphers the don't need worked you
know what developers usually need is
boring crypto concept by Daniel Burge
Bernstein boring crypto of course that's
an idea this imaginary cryptography that
always works that you can't misuse you
don't need to update it just works it's
it stays there it works it's strong it's
usable and you know it's a perfect world
again as a utopia yeah utopian
cryptography so boring okay it's
important boring in cryptography means
good ok
so boring crypt of course this is just a
concept but as around many like
libraries and many developers they try
to to achieve like try to get to this
concept as close as possible because
boring crypto says it instead of a given
side
we should concentrate on use cases as
developers may have how to store data
come securely how to verify the source
of data how to send data protected to
each other right of course we understand
that inside these use cases we still
have ciphers key management's all the
things but they are kinda covered by
high level API and now with all this
nice introduction let's deep into
nightmare of developing and supporting
this kind of high level boring crypt API
so today we're going to talk about temas
samus is this cryptographic library I
maintain and like our company is
maintaining free to use open source on
github used a lot among multi platform
applications and when we were making
Tammis like five years ago we were
inspired by this concept by Bernstein of
course I read I read about boredom
crypto only like two years ago and I
thought oh this is what we'll be talking
about so even you know without knowing
the concept before we can't understand
that yeah this is how I go and the thing
is that in tammy's we use the same idea
we use the same train of salt
we decided that okay let's think about
use cases how developers might need to
use a cryptographic libraries and we
come up with for large use cases that we
call crypto systems very simple very
simple I want to store data encrypted I
want to send data to someone right
directly encrypted
I want to encrypt some long
communication some long session and I
want to authenticate for each of these
use cases we did a crypto we created a
crypto system that uses ciphers like
that uses ciphers but it uses a
combination of ciphers and for
developers the API is very high
so for for storage recall the thing as
secure cell we kind of put data in a
Cell in lip sodium the similar idea is a
secure box you put detainer box to send
someone data to send someone particular
data we call it secure message again in
secure cell we use an is-2 mode and we
have this built in key derivation
function so developers you know can
submit mmm I can use not really long can
use not cryptographically strong keys we
still have a key DF inside for secure
message we have this building in a
generation key management so developers
just need just can you call like hey I
want to encrypt this piece of data for
the user of this that's all they need
it's a little bit tricky for sessions
because sessions are like Peter pure and
for sessions we want to emphasize on
ephemeral keys so the encryption key for
transport is always changing and that's
why you need to have the secret session
to sides but sessions work really simply
for development perspective you just
push date in a session and it's been
encrypted and keys are bill rotated and
all without you even understanding
what's going on there and for
authentication we made a secure
cooperator that is zero knowledge proves
based authentication on social
millionaire problem which is not you
know how zero knowledge proof works well
as it is super simple without going into
math lady is super simple you have
that's authentication right so you want
to compare secret that you have in two
different places for zero knowledge
proof you compare the secret without
actually sending it over the network you
stand just derivatives from the secret
over the network and thus you can be
sure with some percentage you can be
sure that the secret is the same as
there are different zero knowledge proof
protocols interactive and non
interactive some of them I use in
blockchain
we use interactive protocol which means
that both parties need to do several
hopes to make sure that the secret is
the same I don't want to get like inside
the cryptographic details let's more
talk about the library itself and hidden
problems so like the first hidden
problem is obvious crypto systems and it
uses that use different ciphers and that
hide these ciphers from developers
perspective this is how Tammis looks
like as a library so instead of
implementing our own cryptography
obviously we used how cold crypto
backends we use it's large libraries
like open SSL boring gaseous el Libre
SSL this shree we support and as a
stable versions we also did a lot of
experiments bare as a cell evolve as a
cell have you heard about well for cell
it exists yeah whereas a cell
well for cell like live sodium go crypto
Ukrainian of course Ukrainian old
ciphers just because Ukraine have has on
ciphers so the idea here is temas as API
works with different crypto pecans and
we can you know kind of switch them when
we need basically the Cora library is
written on C and it just provides I just
uses these open SSL api's in in a
fashion that from these core libraries
we have very very high level very very
usable very very understandable API on
different languages right so
cryptographic backgrounds core written
on see that works with these
cryptographic backends and then high
level languages like library for
language
let me probably enumerate them for iOS
and Android with a book for iOS that
Swift and objective-c
for Android Java Kotlin for C C++
obviously then go PHP as something
old-school then these hipster languages
Python Ruby JavaScript and now we added
webassembly and of course rust yeah sure
many many cryptographers like rust so
now we have rust and now we understand
why it's not nightmare by the way can
you guess on how many languages of these
I can actually write code I can it's not
perfect code no but it's somehow how
many how many tell me the number how you
how you estimate how good am I as a
developer all of them close enough okay
okay most most of them most of them I am
NOT into PHP to be honest
beryllium I for asked rust for me right
now it's read-only so I can't read the
code but I don't really write and rust
C++ or C++ is a nightmare itself I try
to avoid C++ as much as they can but in
JavaScript of course it's better to
avoid but this is JavaScript is
everywhere so yeah mostly I kind of
write on most of them not all of them
but maybe like six seven fluently but we
have a small team and we have this you
know interconnected skills so we can
support different languages with a small
team but language is just one layer
cryptographic library works somewhere
right and for desktop and server
operating systems we support to go into
Debian CentOS ma class and now we start
doing experimental bills for Windows no
one no one on our team has been those
computer it was tricky it was really
tricky and
currently we have have the support we
even added to the dogs but we still mark
it as experimental because was the
worldö windows is you know very unknown
for us
however okay operating system right but
operating system it's it's not like the
name of the system for all these things
we build and sign packages and of course
this is a suicide like I called it
suicide or desktop right let's remember
about mobile I was too lazy to split
Android because so many versions of
Android so yeah when when you want to
build like a multi-platform library
somehow you realize that there are too
many operating system in the world and
the user is unfortunately like the own
operating system really really a lot and
then it's ready to move to another
operating system just because you don't
want to support it
ok let's move next easy to use and hard
to misuse for cryptographic library if
it were you who are building
cryptographic library which you think is
more important your API your library is
easy to use all your API and your
library is hard to misuse which is more
important ok ok let's what is it to use
hard to miss you oh wow
well for my perspective is both yeah
does it it to the question for example
starting from easy to use
can you guess that's a real thing can
you guess which cryptographic library is
installed this way this is like a copy
pasted from readme which
cryptographic libraries he has these
kind of installation process all of them
yes most of them but this one you know
it you know it you know it's really well
it has SSL all SSL
thank you I close enough well this is
gonna be pasted from open SSL so really
easy to do right
just done all the library around make
make test to make sure it's everything's
fine make install of course there is
they have a way to configure the
installation so you can open their
configuration file and configure all the
things because obviously you need to
configure everything right and the point
is that in developers you know they may
not want to do all the things on all
these machines right especially they
might want to install library if and
only if this library is present in their
favorite package manager and now let's
talk about package managers because
again operating systems are not enough
each of them has their own package
vendor for Windows we don't really
support like a real package manager
right now for Windows you need to
compile the instead installation you
know the Installer and then you can use
nice installer with Windows guai guey
however these are operating system
package managers remember about
languages each of them also has like a
preference default industry proven
package manager some of them have
several industry proven package managers
again developers kind expects you to
support all of them which might be fine
if you use if you work with volatile
languages but which might be a little
bit complicated when you have to follow
them and of course of course every kid
is a special kid so every language is
especially in a very very different way
my favorites is IO s
obviously iOS as infrastructure I was
like Isaiah system I was I was developer
for yet for ages and it's a pain it's a
pain for iOS like 10 MS for iOS has
similar structure it can use open SSL or
boring SSL because Apple doesn't provide
you an easy of them as default options
so you need to install any of them so it
uses up less cell or boring as a cell
then it has this C language like C
library and then it has Objective C
proper and thankfully thankfully to the
interoperable interoperability between
Objective C and Swift we don't need to
support Swift like separately we just
support Objective C and developers can
use it either from Swift or from
Objective C applications which is good
but the problem is with package managers
in iOS world we have the cocoa pods we
have cartage we have new Apple well why
away Swift package manager and of course
my developers still add libraries
manually currently in tammy's we don't
supports v package manager because they
just don't feel the time capable to
understand what going on there it's so
complicated to support if you have see
not only Swift it's really complicated
so I just opened an issue in ASCII now
even github saying hey if someone can
help us to support this package manager
because it requires so much time but in
iOS world things change really really
fast
for example the iOS itself as operating
system a you have we have this new iOS
version every year and we have minor
version several times a year usually
minor versions are not a problem but
major versions can be a problem then as
developers they use Xcode which is a ID
and if Xcode hi Xcode provides Swift
language version and right now it's the
current version is Swift
five point one so it's a fifth version
of Swift and most of them don't have you
know direct easy-to-use interoperability
so with each new Xcode that has each new
Swift version for each new iOS version
for each new iPhone iPad mug a book and
we need to to make sure that everything
is working or to update things that are
broken and then package managers of
course they have their own release
cycles and sometimes they also make
updates and open a seven boring SSL
sometimes they they have updates too
so for iOS it just endless updating and
updating and updating and updating just
to make sure is it's it's not broken on
your latest iPhones it's so fun it's
really it's also fun much fun a lot of
fun especially when you realize that you
you are not working on new features you
just want to make sure it's working as
before Android Android is another kind
of kid so for Android right now for
Android phones Google has born and guess
itself yeah you know the difference
between open s7 boring SSL so long story
short open the cell kinda old but bad
because many bugs many ARMs they still
support old-school deprecated ciphers
and on some points Google decided to
fork open SSL and call it boarding as a
cell and we duplicate it all this all
ciphers remove all the things and Google
X will actually patch a lot of ciphers
like a lot of problems in the garden can
sell faster but Google doesn't says as
it doesn't say you that you need that
you should use boring SSL they say
boring is a cell that's our library of
course it's
open-source you can use it but we don't
promise you any backward compatibility
moreover they don't have releases they
just push everything in master and good
luck if new commits breaks the previous
one so and on Android we have boring as
a cell by default so for alpha time it's
Android we decided okay we will use only
boring Excel again we're in SSL then the
Secor then Java for Java we need this
and Lebanese it Jeanne Jeanne I layer
which provides API from C to Java and
then the Java so Android developers
again luckily to the interoperability
between Java and Kotlin they can use
temas and we can support only Java it's
fine however with jeanne i with this
layer it's really complicated to debug
what's going on either these are the
problems in sea level all these a java
problems and with boring ssl it's really
complicated to support it because of all
these problems with versioning for
example recently they decided they
should not they should stop post stop
support in GCC why because i mean i
don't know i don't i don't have time to
read the mailing list i'm sure they have
the proper like validation of this idea
for me it was it was suddenly because
our builds on CI starts failing with
nice error message GCC is not longer
supported thank you of course we good we
googled and we did a really small fix
which is disabled GCC so we say ok let's
use silver clock from now but it was you
know it's not this kind of things you
want to handle it
in the morning when you see red red
built from CI then we was thinking we
were saying we were saying hey why our
android bills are so slow okay Android
is slow okay hundred
later is slow okay but why building
boring SSL is so slow it can be like 30
34 minutes minutes that's too much and
then we found out that we actually we
built all the things in repository and
boring carousel repository is a huge
huge collection of library itself tests
examples examples tests examples and we
build them all in the like hmm probably
that's too much we only need the library
so we add only like we start building on
the library and we decreased builds time
only to 12 minutes three times mm-hmm of
course 12 minutes is also a little bit
long but better than 34 then boring
Jesus LEM born with the sound of course
as Google they have a lot of libraries
for iOS for example if your iOS
developer and you want to use firebase
which is made by Google
firebase uses boring SSL that's why
developers that already use firebase and
want to use Tammis for encryption they
already have board and SSL and it
doesn't make a lot of sense to add
openness cell at the same project right
first of all why and taken because of
the duplication of the symbols it's
really complicated to compile the
project that has both board and concern
and open a cell because they're Hatter's
a pretty much the same so we did we did
this we did version for iOS for 10
minutes with bonding as a cell okay and
somehow we found out that Google does
not support is XTS mode only for iOS in
boring this is a it just looked there
like bottom gazelle is very different
you know from iOS and not iOS and this
is something Google supports so it's not
like someone's fork and I was thinking
hmmm what should I do
shall I ask Google to to start
supporting is 60s for burdened gazelle
for iOS or like I
decided to do it in a easier way for me
I just found a place in our code when we
use iOS XS and they found out that we
don't actually use it but it we have it
you know as a symbol so we have it as a
header and we did a great thing which is
disabled which is we just used even
define and now we just don't don't
mention OS X tears in our source code
for iOS for that uses boring SSL and
just estimate how many these feature
flags we have in our code for each of
these platforms
okay that was about easy to use so to
make library easy to use you really need
to spend some time let's move to the
heart to misuse you know they're a
different kind of like abstractions
level starting from cypher through
cryptographic library cryptographic
system and a box solution and when you
work on a cipher like level you have
nice flexibility to use two different
ciphers different modes different
partings here the earlier they are but
it's actually a pain and the source of
mistakes so for developers it might be
easy to use crypto libraries or even
crypto systems so they don't need to
make no extra salt and they don't need
to have PhD in cryptography just to
encrypt the data however when we when
you start using crypto system you don't
have this flexibility anymore you use
just just high-level API and you can
actually customize it so for example 10
is we have 40 minutes we aim it to be
crypto system and maybe like even a box
solution so we aim to have really high
level of abstraction why it matters this
is common crypto
native cryptographic library and this is
how to encrypt data in using is in
common crypto one two three four five
six seven eight nine three three eleven
right eleven parameters just encrypt the
data good luck that's another library
and this is copy pasted from rid me of
this library this library is super
popular in iOS world super popular
however one hmm it's easy okay it's
easier to do is encryption here only two
lines not eleven parameters
however oopsie most developers that copy
paste it from readme already make one
two at least two cryptographic mistakes
because these are developers come on
they don't know that IV should be random
they just copy pasted from where hmm
that key should be like a proper key
right
I think the key key key is a nice key so
the thing is that using this library
like developers need to understand is
that even if they copy paste things from
readme they did it wrong right and this
is really popular in iOS world like
super bubble library eleven thousand
stars on github Intimus four hours
we have really simple API like API that
looks pretty much the same
however without Ivy and we kind of say
that okay you don't need to put like
super strong random super strong random
symmetric key we have KDF inside like
please make sure that your key is long
and has enough entropy but we can handle
it and you don't need to care to take
care about ivy the need to take care
about salt you don't need to select the
mode all the things and this is what I
say what I called hard to
misuse because as we support all these
12 systems we have similar API across 12
of them now guess their language do you
see it okay or which we can turn off the
lights if it's not really visible yeah
let's try to turn off the lights if
again just for another couple of slides
who see user mode yeah okay okay so
guess is the language vital no rest no
God no Swift yes yes
next one against the language let me see
I think it's I think it's rust
I think it's rust okay okay next one
Python yeah you see it's fight timers so
the the thing like the idea here is that
we're we have pretty much the same API
for each language two lines of code for
all these twelve languages and we kind
the handle all these choices of
criticises huge mouth padding we handle
like memory management scheme management
and for more high-level functions like
secure session for maha level crypto
systems we even handle a syndication and
work on keys thank you can we please
turn on the light great yeah you're
doing great and so in guessing languages
yeah however as explained there are so
many things to work on probably probably
we should test everything and just to
show you the scale so I made one I made
I counted a number of lines for for
source folder of Tammuz
let's say that we have 35,000 lines
which is like a cold lines not to
comment on the things on the code lines
and to show you the scale for tests
folder we have three hundred forty-eight
thousand lines 10 times more just
because to make sure that all these you
want to make a picture here please I
know the line numbers are fascinating
right I don't know just to make sure
that all these twelve great languages on
all these nice operating systems are
working in the same way who has a huge
huge huge testing process of course of
everything is automated because you
can't see manually like manual key
trying to test cryptography it doesn't
work here so all the tests use our
automated like for each language a lot
of unit tests for cryptography for
cryptic or NIST tests then of course
fuzzing we use this American fuzz has a
loop house code lop yeah we use it to
fast inputs of mainly for high level API
as if we were not really good developers
right and tried to hack our own inputs
of our own API then of course a lot of
linkers sanitizers static Adana analytic
tools memory management tools
integration tests my favorite bugs are
bugs when the same when when application
of python encrypts the data an
application Ruby can't decrypt data so
to eliminate these kind of bugs because
we have we have one of them between iOS
and Android
sure so to eliminate this this kind of
bugs we built in integration testing
between all those languages on all these
platforms
but this is not enough which bit is
missing III give you a hint the library
has been updated time to time which bit
is missing hmm worsening yeah backwards
compatibility tests because again we
need to make sure that the Ruby
application that use previous version on
Tammis and encrypts the data can decrypt
the data if they updated temas again
it's not like we are so smart
we had these bugs all these things it's
not because we're smart because we had
this box and we decided ok better we
write tests use for them then having
them again and these are a couple of
links just in case you will also want to
add some static code analysis things to
you to your repositories and to your
projects I really like the second ones
close oh you know you know like expect
Inspector Clouseau I'm a I'm I don't
know French so I may be really products
in chrome but the idea is that these two
reads through your code and trying to
find out keys and passwords that you
left in your code it doesn't work for us
because we write cryptography and we
have the world key everywhere so once we
run it we have like 300 false positives
and we decided ok not for us but it's
really great and to answer your next
question of course you can't have one
too you know to run all these tests we
use Sokka CI and B tries as as such as
like public tools and another github we
have for each leg pull request we have
tests from circle CI they are really
quick but through the whole 12 languages
we tries we use mainly for Apple
ecosystem for iOS Mac OS tests and we
put Android there as well but all this
integration testing all this puzzling
it's happened inside our infrastructure
we using build boat just because when we
calculated you know
amount of time this tests are running we
understood that we can't afford by an
external services we need to build an
our own because these tests are really
long like nightly tests and of course
last but not least it won't work if you
don't make pay attention on on the code
that's why we try we try to do this you
know security Sprint's just to focus on
specific potential issues we can have we
when we store keys more longer than we
should or when we have like potential
memory like buffer overflow problems and
there is a nice link clipped according
with a lot of ideas how to improve your
code if you handle just in case
cryptography and of course we do manual
reviews and this is fair manual reviews
are like good because we have our own
photographers on board and we use
external audits just because everyone
make mistakes and just automated tests
are not enough let's probably quickly
skip this one because again it's not
enough to have a library you need to
describe how to use it and the lot of
cryptographic libraries have one page a
one-page read name sorry
it doesn't like it mold work kind of and
we support all the things we need to
have separate readme for all these
languages of course and of course people
say I don't want to read with me I want
to copy paste ok ok ok we put real you
know real code snippets in those
documents in those tutorials free to
copy like safe to copy paste however
people still ask questions ok I can copy
paste it but where to put it
fine
we made example applications and again
showing the numbers
1 million lines of code for each this
language we made example applications
and imagine we need to build and test
these example applications as well right
so amount of example apps is I don't
know how many times bigger than the
source code then users are still
complaining because their own app is not
like example app of course this examples
a little bit you know artificial they
show how to use it but as they are not a
real apps they don't have like specific
use case and users that's asking but how
can use it if I am building X Y that ok
we build like tutorials we build a real
applications multi-platform applications
we open source a lot of things we have
this workshop like workshops
everything is open source with nice blog
post explaining things still users are
complaining you know it works in your
app but it doesn't work in my app ok we
said fine and build interactive
simulators so on other website you can
find a page where for example you can
test your encryption so as a user you
have let's say like Ruby application and
you can clip the data there and you need
you want to make sure you can decrypt it
that you can figure everything fine
so you open our web page you put and
click the database successful there you
put your key and you make sure that it
can be decrypted because if we can't
decrypt it on our web it means that you
will be able to decrypt it like anywhere
it's fine it's fine when it's like one
blob of data but as I mentioned
previously users want to build a real
like you know secure session a real
communication between separate several
devices and imagine you have iOS
application Android application and you
want to build this secure communication
right you need to have both applications
already you need
- great integrate Tammis in both of them
and then you need to check if it's
working and you can have bugs on every
step so to eliminate this problem we
made interactive simulator and point
that allows to connect and check the
session as a message connection the
users are still complaining user still
complaining user still and sorry asking
questions like hey but if I do these if
I do these what should I do
we do our best we really do our best
trying to explain not only how Amos
works but also what are the possible
attacks for this kind of crypto systems
how to make sure like what you need to
do with threads like how to make your
application threads thread safe what to
do how to handle memory then of course
we try to you know to collect all
projects that use temas and to say yes
your great projects because you handle
security and you like protect your data
you're really good and to mention all
all them just because people want to be
mentioned the next problem is as the
encryption regulator and regulations for
example if you use cryptography and you
want to submit application to the App
Store you need to feel you ask export
like regulation report
what kind of crypto you use and of
course as as vendors as providers of the
cryptographic library we kind of
responsible for people who that use it
and need to sort to submit this report
but as Lee is not legal entity we can't
provide them legal advice but again we
created a blog post and we described all
the steps they need to do and basically
this is a tricky question if your vendor
are you responsible on how people use
your tool or you are not I think it
depends three last slides just to sum up
Tammis is used in applications yeah in
applications that needs to handle
multi-platform so it's it's fine to use
like some single cryptographic library
if you have single application on single
language but then you have distributor
tab you probably want to have one
libraries it works in the same way
across all your infrastructure and
having these nice cryptographic API this
high level terrific API actually allows
developers not to waste their time on
making or preventing mistakes in
cryptography but rather to build the
real you know features in the apps and
one of these large cases recent large
cases is a bear applicational
note-taking app they decided to
implement and to encryption for user
note and we helped them to make it and
it totally based on temas and the
previous slides you can see that amount
of encryption like amount of lines
handled encryption it's much less than
amount of lines at handle of the scheme
management all these protocols
just because have a nice library let's
give this have a nice library means you
can spend your time kitten you can spend
your time doing like a real job instance
spending your time trying to eliminate
cryptographic bugs and like as a final
sort of my talk never ever agree to
support to the graphic lab room trust me
this might be fun but only like for a
year not the whole journey is not that
fun and they really really respect those
people that do support cryptographic
libraries they are doing a great job
ok thank you
[Applause]
I ran out of my time so for Q&A please
find me here and you can find me
tomorrow because tomorrow I will have a
workshop with jean-philippe and the
middle of the day cryptographic workshop
more cryptography less kittens always
say thank you imagine us dizzy thank you
[Applause]