okay yeah thanks for being here
I will tell you new tales of wireless
input devices well mostly because we did
some research back in 2016 and this is
an updated research on basically the
same topic and as it was kind enough to
introduce me I'm your close de Meyer I'm
basically a pen tester analyzing
products for security and as I'm in the
hardware department I'm really
interested in all the embedded stuff
radio security and all that comes with
it this is my dear colleague who cannot
be with me here for today unfortunately
but all these whenever I talk about we
and this is a group effort so he was he
did huge parts of the research with me
so I want to tell you about a little bit
of the introduction of and what we
analyzed and what devices we use to
analyze it and the previous work of
other researchers who had a look into
the same area and then I will give you
an overview of our our research what we
did the found security issues we we
detected during the research I will try
some live demos hopefully they work and
some conclusions and recommendations if
we have some time there two interesting
anecdotes to tell holy short ones and at
the end a Q&A session if you have any
questions so let's get started and when
I'm talking about wireless input devices
I basically mean the things you can see
on this slide so keyboards mice is the
most common one but also the presenters
like the keynote speaker used before me
it's one you can talk more freely and
use your clicker to switch to the next
slide they're also considered wireless
input devices and the devices we use for
analyzing them and attacking them are
basically software-defined radios or we
use them for at least parts of our
research like we have a hacker one for
those who don't know software-defined
radios this is just a
Eric will use B device I can plug in and
I can tell like the name says
software-defined radio I can tell in
software on my PC how this device should
act only RF spectrum how it should
decode signals how it should send
signals there are other devices like the
crazy radio this is just a really useful
tool because there is a chip on it that
is the same chip like in at least a lot
of keyboards we analyzed so it's easier
to use the same hardware like that is in
the keyboard because all the decoding is
already in the chip and you have to do
that manually and you even can use the
logitech unifying reciever because it
has the same chip as well and it's free
programmable over USB so previous work
of other researchers the interesting
ones are like the Hickory key project
interesting in that case for example was
the year it's 2010 so researching
wireless input devices is really really
old at that point like close to 10 years
and we have Nova 2019 and their devices
are still not really secure also to give
you a quick overview so this involves
the keyboard evolved the Hickory key
project was like for keyboards sometimes
working on the 27 megahertz nowadays
it's all 2.4 gigahertz spectrum and when
I talk mutates of wireless input devices
in 2016 we published some research about
secure keyboards well they weren't so
secure there and this is the follow-up
project to this and interesting enough
mark newland maybe you know him from the
mouse jack attack he did research in
2019 as well on presentation clickers as
well as we but on all the models so it's
interesting to see the differences and
Marcus Manx UMaine well saw his tweets
or something
he had a closer look at all the Logitech
products so in this project we
to answer the the open questions we had
from our last project and we want to
have a closer look and Wireless
presenters because we didn't had a
closer look there the first research
project was about mice and keyboards
just a recap from 2016 the the most
important question we want to answer is
D for the Fujitsu keyboard for the other
keyboards v1 we're able to replay attack
we can talk about this later what this
implies but interesting enough there
were keystroke injections on these
keyboards so even though you don't know
the key because this is all the
keyboards market themselves as being
secure and using AES encryption and
although we don't know the key we were
able to inject keys on the horse that is
using the keyboard without knowing the
actual key for most of the keyboard but
if a jitsu keyboard used a different
chip and we were not able to understand
it back then and for a new research
where that will work keyboards and a lot
of more wireless presenters because we
want to understand them as well so that
we get a better understanding of what we
do and there are basically three
approaches to do this first one is the
hardware analysis for such a researcher
because we don't have internal data
sheets on what they do so it's just
buying the hardware on Amazon or
something like this and what first step
is hardware analysis opening up the
keyboards the wireless presenters look
at the PCBs look at the chips maybe
there are markings on the chip if you're
lucky you'll find the datasheet for the
chip online you'll learn more about this
what about the chips there and in some
cases you can even sniff the
communication on the PCB and learn more
about the chips of course there's the
radio based approach to analyze the
device this is like I said before using
the hack RF and software like no radio
or in spectrum to understand what they
are actually sending over the air or it
can use crazy radio and the NRF research
firmware for NF based keyboards or
presenters or mises
it makes it a lot easier because the
decoding is already handled by touch
and for the former analysis what's the
third approach we didn't do that much in
this project just because we didn't had
the need to do it back in 2016 we
actually did that and it worked well on
most keyboards so most keyboards don't
have the eve chips that are on there I'm
not locked down so you can just connect
some wires the chip readout it's
remember and learn and understand how
the keyboard is working and in most
cases we were also able of course to
extract the AES encryption keys and then
you can decrypt the traffic or emulate
your own keyboard so for the hardware
analysis this is was a what a typical
presenter might look like what you take
a decent miss kit and most of the time
that's why they work on all operating
systems with most of the east of birth
for presentation because the dongle
adjust well emulates a USB keyboard and
when you press next slide or previous
slides
it's in most case it is a page up and
page down just what you're pressing so
this is why no additional driver is
needed for that and if you open the
devices up you can see a lot of
different well wisely the devices are
designed and they come in different form
factors as well so what you see here is
this device here it's like a ring shape
and I can use it my finger and can talk
more freely really easy in this case you
can maybe you can see it there chip
markings on that you can search for the
datasheet it might be easy completely
different
presenter completely different chip and
so having different chips means you're
basically starting the research again
because of what the different chip or
everything might be different for this
presenter another presenter as well the
friendship this one is even trickier as
you can see the chips are covered in an
epoxy and well you don't get any
markings and you don't know what chip is
underneath there for this chip we were
actually able to guess what chip is
under there because we saw that here
some some small wires between those
chips it's a two chip setup the first
tip is the microcontroller with all the
firmware for pressing the keys and
stuff on there and these second ship is
the transmitter the RF transmitter chip
and if you sniff the communication in
between you might learn how the chip
underneath the epoxy is working
same for the Fujitsu keyboard we had to
look at its did the same approach
because it was covered we try to read
data with soldering wires on there so
after the first research we could
determine the chips that were in there
and as you can see there are a lot of
different chips and so there was a lot
of work to do with them first of all you
try to find the datasheet and in most
cases actually we got lucky or the chips
for the NF 24 the datasheet for the NF
24 and for the cyprus chips they are
freely online available and used in some
of these products and you can learn a
lot about these devices in some other
cases like the bacon RF chip we got
lucky as well it is completely different
vendors but the chip is basically a
clone of the NRF 24 chip so you can use
a lot of the knowledge you again before
- yeah and you can apply it to the back
end chips and in some cases like the HS
304 chips
there was no datasheet online we don't
know a mark newland reverse engineer
part of the chips that helped us a lot
but otherwise no public information
available and for the radio based
analysis there are two lie tools like
the universal radio hacker for the
software-defined radios this is a tool
that really helps you getting started to
understand the peg packets that are uh
well somewhere out there and D on the
air and you can easily decode them and
you can actually use this tool as well
to resend package to you recovered or
craft your own package so this is really
helpful but it's not that easy when I'm
talking about Wireless analysis because
there are a lot of challenges the first
challenges and this is even one step is
already done there and we have nothing
so there's just some signals in the air
so you
need to guess I'll guess a lot of things
or look at a lot of things like what
frequency what modulation is it
frequency amplitude shift keying or
something like this this is a decoded
signal you might well you can see a
digital signal here but there's still a
lot of to do we're guessing this are
slow just ones and zeroes how do you get
from these ones in series to eventually
actually understand why a key a was
pressed on the keyboard for example so
the challenge ins are basically all this
we need to understand these signal
modulation the package format framing we
need to understand where packet lengths
fields are a byte or sometimes they're
reversed if there are check sums how
they check how the check sums works the
the payload feel of course the most
interesting we want to understand where
is the actual key a or key B that was
pressed on the keyboard and for some
other challenges you need to have in
mind is in the RF frequency hopping for
example some of the devices do frequency
hopping so they change rapidly the
frequency and you have to follow them if
you want to get the signal right or data
whitening and data scrambling we hadn't
had that before but in this research
some of the chips use data whitening in
data scrambling this is not encryption
but on on the air it's better for the
receiver to understand what this Center
was sending when there's a lot of
changes between ones and zeros it's just
easier to understand for them and for
that case some of the chips use data
scrambling and data scrambling is just X
oaring some more or less random string
it's hard coded somewhere in the chip X
or on the actual data to get a lot of
changes but we as a researchers need
that string otherwise X or in some
unknown string about some data is
basically encryption so we need to add
that string in order to get the reverse
the data scrambling the data structure
for these packets are most of the time
pretty similar like preamble
think worth there's that address of
course because if your neighbor buys the
same keyboard you don't want when you
press keys only operating the neighbor's
PC or the other way around there are
some control fields the actual payload
and it checks on this was true for most
of the receivers and if you looked at
the data sheets and the ones and zeros
in the air you eventually come to
something like this so you understand
what the preamble is you can dissect the
actual address that the chips are using
some more ya control fields payload
length fields and of course most
importantly the actual payload that is
sent by the devices and the CRC check
sum field so this is an example for one
of them but they are similar in most
cases so let's talk about the actual
actual attack a text we can do and
there's a really old one and really
obvious one at least for us it was
obvious because for all the keyboards
and that's why we have it here again for
all the presenters it was true as well
because they're our presenters out there
they have mouse emulation as well that
you can show what the mouse pointer when
you're presenting and we noticed that he
even was involved of the even of the
encrypted keyboard the mouse
communication is always unencrypted and
unauthenticated so if we understand the
protocol correctly we can just move a
mouse it's not that interesting but let
me quickly show you some some
demonstration this was in 2016 as well
we just brought a a proof of concept to
show people that maybe it's also
interesting - or maybe good to encrypt
your your mouse mouse as well because of
when we control the mouse well of course
with a mouse it's not that easy to
attack an PC but every PC at least on
Windows has an on-screen keyboard and
you can just search for the on-screen
keyboard of course well
maybe you will not find it by the first
try but maybe you'll find it by the
second or about fourth doesn't matter it
comes on on top and if you never use it
before it's always 100 pixel from the
top and 100 pixel from the left so
there's some some conclusions where we
can find it even without a back channel
and that makes it well more or less
reliable and well that's a it's a funny
way to to show this mic well of course
the the screen must be unlocked but it
actually worked and the it's not it's
actually also resolution independent
because most movements are resolution
independent so there are some things
that make this attack work better and
some make it harder this is why it's
really slow because the curve of mouse
acceleration is really hard to
understand but even when you do small
steps you can actually well this is just
the power show download and execute
payload of some ransomware or something
like this it takes the time but point
proven it it is possible
so apart form from spoofing mouse
movements what can we do else of course
their replay attacks this is most
basically just recording the signals we
have captured in the air for example
with a software-defined radio and just
replay the signal and for our research
we found out that all the presenters we
had were actually vulnerable for that so
if somebody's here presenting and
clicking next slide next slide next
slide and you record it with a device
you don't don't have a clue about the
actual the actual format that the
presenters using doesn't matter just
save the data into a file and send it
with the software-defined radio later
and it will go to the next slide or to
the previous slide just a side note this
was true for most of the keyboards as
well we analyzed so far so what what you
can do actually what the keyboard is
when you come into the office at the
morning and somebody is recording well
if you boot up your PC the first thing
you will enter is the the username and
the password and if you go to a coffee
break and lock the screen you can just
resend the signal out and it will unlock
the PC so this works there we have a
YouTube video showing this if you
interested in it pretty pretty simple
but for wireless presenters well it's
not that interesting of course I can
well mess up the person trying to
present in front of you but we can
actually take over the PC just with a
page up and page down button so more
interesting are the keystroke injection
attacks so what if we can enter some
some keystrokes here and as we found out
the data for the presenters are still
unencrypted and unauthenticated so by
understanding the whole packet format we
were able to understand where are the
actual page up and page down button and
if we can craft as the same package with
some other device and just switch out
the page up and page down button with
let's say the a key or the B key or the
C key we were interests
that will be emulated USB keyboard and
the dongle except these keys
although the presenter don't have that
keys in order to attack the PC what the
dongle is connected to and we found out
that two of them actually had some kind
of white listing not excepting the keys
that easily but most of them were were
just vulnerable for these keystroke
injection attacks and I will try this
life like every live demo I will hope it
works and the SSID devices in nowadays
use a 2.4 gigahertz signals and I think
they are oh the room here is pretty much
crowded with Wi-Fi and Bluetooth and
what on so pardon me if it does not work
so I will exploit this ring presenter
here yeah this is we shout on some other
logical presenters that it works but
this was part of the newer research and
he this device was vulnerable as well I
will use the crazy radio dongle for that
because it has a compatible chip to the
chip here and the receiver and there's a
special firmware on the that can lets me
send well whatever I want and this is
just an etiquette PC not really
interesting to see just a common eyeline
to what I can start here that will find
this device emulate the actual presenter
here and not just pressing page up atone
for what other keys and let's see if it
works and as you can see well it just
opened the command from and typed I'm
saying in just as a proof of concept of
course you can change it to whatever you
want download and execute again so this
this worked pretty easily of course it
was not encrypted it was not
authenticated but this is true for most
of the presenter so I guess it's it's
interesting if you present and if you
want to be secure this is why the
presenter from the conference is still
lying here at night out using it so you
can only because the tools are already
online so you can get them on github and
try it out at home maybe not at your
neighbor at least in Germany this is not
a large file or
for the keystroke injection attacks well
for the for the presenters was pretty
easy but what's about the the Fujitsu
keyboard he didn't understand back then
and back then when I talk about this we
analyzed the three other keyboards down
there and we found at that at that time
a cryptographic issue and the way they
use the is counter mode so they actually
use encryption they actually use IAS but
they will just don't use it right and
therefore we were able to inject keys
although we don't know the actual AES
encryption key but this did not work for
the fugitive keyboard there was a there
there's a different chip on that
keyboard and and what the way it was
programmed it was just not vulnerable
for this this kind of attack but as we
have a closer look so this difference
it's a keyboard as you can see there
it's a two chip set up as well you can
also sniff the communication again
between and if when we had a closer look
into the transmitter chip see the chips
are from Cyprus the keyboard is phone
from Fujitsu and and what most chip
manufacturers do - well some kind of
showcase their chip they providing you
example code or something like this and
Cyprus was I had some website up there
and you can search for it and there was
some some example or some software
development kit way can check that was
especially for that chip or for these
chip and serious and within it chip
Cedars there was example code for this
is how you can do a basic keyboard and
this basic keeper of course it's just
example codes and unencrypted keyboard
but you can use that and it turns out
that the Fujitsu people actually most
likely use that example code with the
unencrypted keyboard and added
encryption to it well you were not able
to decrypt it or to inject encrypted
packages but our Samson was maybe if
they use the unencrypted keyboard code
and edit encryption did they removed the
unencrypted keyboard code after adding
the encryption
and turns out they didn't so instead of
injecting encrypted packets we just
encrypt sent plaintext package to the
chip and he process the chip processes
the plaintext packages as well and we
were able to gain a keystroke injection
here as well so this trip uses data
whitening and this is rather hard so we
did the same like with the crazy radio
we bought a port that has the same chip
like used in the keyboard this is again
some eye from from some multicopter or
multicopter drone hobbyist remote
control chip but this has the same shape
we want to use and that's good enough
for us
and it also on the only back side and if
this ship here not sure if you can see
it back there
on the back side there's even a small
micro controller where I can program co2
so this is a standalone attack even if
you don't need something though we we
put the demo code on the controller here
on the other side there the transceiver
chips this device has four transceiver
chips but one of them as II for the
Fujitsu keyboard and reprogram it just
to send the unencrypted keystrokes let's
try this in a live demos well it worked
a lot of times but I was presenting this
light again at some point and did not
work let's see if it works this time
so just connecting a battery over here
so the board has some power to run
and as you can see well not doing
anything blinks a little bit here that's
everything you can even make it smaller
if you want to but works again so
keystroke injection on the keyboard that
supposedly should be secure is encrypted
but they just forget to remove the the
unencrypted keyboard code from there
after we had a closer look at the Alex
mmm 901 this is the one I just showed
you the keyboard and people asked us
about plx three nine Oh keyboard and
sure fair enough it advertised this
table as a secure 2.4 technology
keyboard but not mentioning AES
encryption somewhere so what's
interesting for us to have a closer look
and this R is the data feed ordered
product sheet before we had a close
closer look and other data sheet down
there see that Rashid after we had a
closer look and now the font is really
tiny but my spot the difference so of
course we when we find security
vulnerabilities we do a responsible
disclosure and tell the manufacturers
and they updated the keyboard actually
this keyboard is no longer you can no
longer buy it they have a better ones
now with better encryption let's quickly
have a closer look in that keyboard it
was a an interesting journey because it
was basically the lockdown chips and
just by sniffing the communication with
a logic analyzer you can get the
sequence what you want microcontrollers
telling the receiver chip and on the
receiver chip we we noticed a pattern be
known before and this is what when the
device boots up it configures the RF
chip like what data rate it should use
what channel it should use stuff like
this and from that we were able to
reconstruct what ship must be under
there and we found out it must be an LP
900 bass chips somewhere but when we
understand this and what the chip
actually is we can again build our own
first of all this is when we decoded the
packet now that we understand what they
talk about each other to each other and
how they configured we again can do the
radio based analysis capture the package
and decode the packages to understand
what is going on there
and of course again the important part
is something like the payload here and
the CRC check sum and it turns out the
again this chip uses data whitening soda
scrambling we have to understand how
this works and even though the plaintext
is always the same and so it has no
replay protection or something like this
the the actual CRC when we buy two
different keyboards you can see here the
last part is the CRC is different so we
found out that the CRC is initialized
with a well device specific bite but
first of all the data scrambling that
was more easy because the data
scrambling was the same on each on every
keyboard so by reverting the data
scrambling for one keyboard you can
apply to just all other keyboards you
have to make a look at table basically
and again this is just a basic CRC no
message authentication code no no real
security so we can again spoof the
keyboard just for the sake of
completeness you can prove force this
year see how all this work how it's
working and you can see down here and
there there's a device specific value in
this case we have to initialize the CRC
with this value and if you want to hack
the keyboard of your neighbour of course
you just sniff one packet and prove
first this years even if you're hitting
the right CRC you found you device
specific initialization value and it
will be used for all packets there so
again to recap it has no protection
against replay attack it has no
protection against it has no real and
corruptions or sensitive data is not
really protected there and there are no
data authenticity so we can just move
the device or replay a text keystroke
and keep sniffing attacks uh this time
possible and my colleague actually wrote
that we are not sure if it's already
public but it's just another proof of
concept that you can actually in this
case decode what the people typing on
the keyboard so if they type the
password in you arrive on this secure
keyboard to sniff the actual key strokes
that were pressed and recover the
keyboard and already clear the login
credentials or whatever the email the
people the person is typing so
conclusions unencrypted an
unauthenticated data communication of
course this allowed us all the
disproving and and injection attacks
missing code protection against replay
attacks what we can do replay this is
rather easy and the cryptographic issues
we saw we can bypass some cryptographic
things and inject keys and in some cases
we even are able to decode the actual
key strings here so from the presenters
we had a closer look the well most of
them are vulnerable to keystroke
injection some of them had some sort of
whitelist inium a little bit better and
for some of them most poofing worked and
this does not mean there's no more
spoofing this presenters just didn't
have a mouse pointer and as we were not
the only ones researching the wireless
presenters I want to show you this from
mark Neil earnest way as well he had
looked at at different presenters as
well and came to the same conclusion
it's basically possible all the time to
to inject keystrokes some time limited
some Logitech products that do not allow
sending a B C or D keys but in some of
the cases you can press the the Alt key
and the number lock keys and without a
new block you can type Unicode symbols
on at least on Windows and again you
have it
keyboard with that and updating our 2016
research with a viola with the Fujitsu
wireless input devices as we showed you
the keystroke injection we were able to
do this as well so some recommendations
choose your wireless presenter input
devices might be by looking at some
table or maybe we jump to the last point
maybe not at all if you really want to
be secure of course if you in
environments that demand high security I
would recommend not to use them at all
at some points you can consider
Bluetooth space input devices they are
in most of the cases they're more secure
when they paired and when the in during
the pairing process there are a lot of
vulnerabilities especially in the root
of low energy devices the old ones and
if the attacker is near you while you
are pairing the presenter with your
laptop using Bluetooth Low Energy 4.0
like most of the presenters with
Bluetooth or keywords and you are able
to extract the key as well and can
inject code again and for some of them
there are replacements or updates are
available you can have a look into that
especially for a Logitech products but
if in doubt just use a wired one and if
you're interested in trying this at home
the most of the software's online
available so mark Newlands wireless
presentation work is online and the
tools are on github
Markus Manx who did the research on the
Logitech products his tools are online
as well you can try them and our Fork of
Mark Newlands presentation clickers
repository where we edit our keyboards
and the yeah presenters we analyzed is
also available online you can have a
closer look and if we have no she's just
some short anecdote funny because the
the is encrypted keyboard by Cherry we
had 2016 a closer look you can no longer
buy it as be unlimited is but they built
a new one it's the be unlimited 3.0
really new and shiny
but it has still the same cryptographic
weakness we found in 2016 so they fixed
the security issue just by rebranding it
so before there was this is a secure
keyboard now when you buy it there's no
more secure printed on the keyboard and
keyboard without printing securing it
well there is no security issue if the
keyboard wasn't secured in the first
place and another interesting thing to
keep in mind when I say look at the
table and you say ok I by the August
presenter or something because this was
the best in this research this is the
Logitech our 400 we bought in from
Amazon like three different points of
time and clicking on different shops and
this is what we got three different
versions of the our 400 all completely
different completely different hardware
and I'm not sure if the first one we
analyzed in this is for sure attackable
but keystroke injection the other ones
we haven't had a closer look we contact
contact that Logitech if the others are
just cheap Chinese clones because the
logo was slightly different and the
presenter was lighter and something like
this and Logitech refused to answer
because well it's the parts on the
presenters are internally and are under
disclosure and a closure so you you they
won't tell us if they are real product
or not but if you search online a lot to
take is saying that if you have a
Logitech product the USP vendor ID for
USB product as a banner ID should be the
one from Logitech and for the first one
this is true for the other two there the
vendor ID is from some Chinese chip
manufacturer so not really largely not
sure maybe they change the production
just because it was cheaper but so even
if you buy the the most secure one maybe
you don't get a secure one because if
you don't open it up you you don't know
so this is what I said and translating
to something like the parts are
copyright protected information so won't
tell us as one more thing we're not
finished yet with that research there
are other devices out there like the
barcode scanners or so
you can get basically they're just
keyboards as well we having closer look
into them as well maybe devil more
attacks and wireless input devices and
the slides will be online you can have a
look at all the references and check out
all the stuff and with that I'm finished
thank you and if you have some questions
I'm ready to get them thank you for this
interesting talk and well German
precision the timing is spot on so we
have time for questions you know so for
the first keyboard you are saying that
it can process both encrypted and
unencrypted may say how does it make a
difference like when you receive the
message how I can tell that it's
actually we don't know this was one of
the chips that has the firmware locked
on the tip so we can't read out what
they actually programmed on the chip but
the data structure is just different
from an encrypted and encrypted packet
and I guess somewhere they're parsing it
different when the data structure is
different when coming in from the
transceiver down low okay thank you
there's no no flag like saying this is
encrypted or non interrupts it's just a
different data format some more
questions okay I do have a question yeah
it's more of a political question
actually because I'm looking at all
these it seems like a lot of work and it
must be time-consuming yeah and they
don't seem to be prototypes in any case
meaning that these are products that are
being sold in the market so who finances
this research so what is the I mean of
course it's fun and I understand the
motivation for that but do you guys like
approach the company is there for bounty
hunting or things like that or and in
some cases so it started if the first
research in 2016 started actually as a
customer project because a bank was want
to use encrypted keyboards wireless
keyboards and they asked us is one of
these three encrypted keyboards secure
and they say well you have like one or
two weeks to analyze them and
okay we give it a shot but in one or two
weeks we can't actually tell much but we
saw enough to say well this is pretty
interesting and we want to learn more
about it and at that point it was just
self investment basically 50% from the
company and well to be fair the other
50% of free time
doing it somewhere in the evening and
then again and again again and after a
while
why we had the first devices report the
first devices some of the actual
manufacturers of these devices
cooperated with us for newer products
and we tested the products and give them
some yeah some feedback on what they can
improve on the products okay thank you
very much are there any other questions
so for the presenters to you can you
actually see which presenter it is from
just sniffing or if you inject so
because if you are in the audience right
now someone could inject yeah right now
right okay I have removed the dongles
but I guess for the other presenters
everybody other people present here and
this might be true yes in most cases you
can so the data structures are that
different if you know them you can see
what chip must be at least if it's one
of the common ones and they most of the
time they're pretty common even and in
most of the cases you can just use this
device because the chip on here is
compatible with a lot of devices and
it's also compatible for the bacon chips
because the backend chips are just
clones you can just use this device also
for sniffing this device is capable of
sniffing drinks thanks to I think Travis
Goodspeed is here somewhere because
there are some tricks in the chip you
can use for sniffing and if you under
see what is there in the air you
probably can guess the rest from that if
the presenter is a presenter we had
never take a look before I'm not sure if
you can say it that way but if it's
known you can distinct them from each
other
did you try to use the FCC ID to find
other details about the device or not
yeah we did from time to time so the FCC
idea is an idea if you sell a product in
America every radio based product must
have an unique ID that must be printed
on the product and it was interesting
enough at least for the Logitech
presenters there was the same FCC ID on
all of them although there we get them
with different chips and another
interesting story was actually from the
Cherry keyboard we start for the FCC ID
and the FCC ID wasn't there they did a
typo and the FCC ID they printed on the
product so you're not able to find them
but for the first research it's fun time
to time it really helps but we buy them
anyway opening up anyway so we get the
internal pictures from the FCC our ID
report by ourselves possible as well so
we have time for more questions okay so
thank you very much again let me