so we're here to tell you about a
fictitious startups from the future may
be wondering about the watermark on the
slide yes that is an eat in our wall and
any good startup know that you need a
logo this point stuffing to the rights
represent bro
Oh
[Music]
without exception one example is / let's
be done with lush don't you hear you
json peak horrible hat and it needs to
go away and has been solved by coors
JSON kids definitely one of those things
like people wearing especially around a
cross-site scripting even with contents
pretty quality is something that needs
to be addressed in line of dollars
script it's ugly it's hard to manage
animate applying honking security policy
very difficult a Content security policy
to team with mechanisms for whitelisting
inline JavaScript particularly the nonce
and hash pitches particularly the non
can happen so I was never a fan of
constant security policy not because it
still allows dynamic JavaScript so you
still have the potential for a pod it's
necessary move it or second daily news
monetary policy passions do not allow
them to Eva whether on the front end or
the back ends in sort of cake as using
email as code that's never been reviewed
which meant previous point not allowed
Eve alex is not faster than gates on
cars and even it is I don't care it's
inherently dangerous we need to go away
again do not have the name in JavaScript
everything I've just mentioned in the
previous slide is detectable by a
regular expression no static thing else
is cooking here and I've often catch it
loudly holiday stay current this is your
frameworks your libraries the languages
you get behind you're gonna get stuck
periods I would actually say this is the
hardest thing to accomplish of
everything I've mentioned I only
actually seen it happen to one pumpkin
eco about fifteen engineers they
actually live on master not even just
for these persians we also have many
more pies and abuses which made it a
little easier the amount of older
versions of libraries need to count
leverage so then
of the new libraries features you know
past ap is scarier things you might have
engineers in 20 years of you would use
newer versions of the tax aight guys and
they you know make assumptions of the
state when you might not be you know a
lot of the security being built in the
framers these days you can't take
advantage of without significant back
forty think one example of this is Ruby
on Rails use a tool called sprockets
package all of his assets now the cube
sort of users automated system to
package your assets together it's really
easy configuration change and you get
sub resource integrity for free these
resources they read without writing a
single line of code is incredibly
powerful unsupported code greatly
increase with a chance that you security
engineering will stop back courting the
patch ruby-on-rails just recently got
support for per action see sort of push
that it a feature tokens week it can
only do that one thing you know if you
get delete repo x you cannot believe
people live with those things okay while
this is sort of seen as you know
potentially unnecessary this is the belt
and suspenders been to take advantage of
that you have had to use significant
backwards not only to be code and the
interface change the internals of change
to incredibly difficult to do on that
point i get if you're a really far
behind it could be a problem to switch
but the double-edge sword there is
there's an assumption that newer code is
secure and somebody could push the
library hasn't fully vetted it now we
interview security ball because not
everybody else subscribe to the state of
christmas and so being right on the
bleeding edge feels like going over the
cusp is actually a great about one
hundred percent valid but in my
experience that's not the case getting
stuff is still work
let me add the whole you should do that
oh no I think that if you get stuff two
three four birds in fact you can't move
so I get that I think it is a balancing
act and I just specifically quick
counter point of death we absolutely
it's absolute valid point newer code is
not always better period is because
people have sort of learning lessons for
example introducing a tightening
attacked at this point in development
lot more difficult it was a year ago
where the framework uses up twitter has
had this problem they decided to switch
brain works entirely jehannum is
starting to experience this problem and
starting to cause a lot of problems so
don't be stuff collecting defeated
slides just means to enforcement
students has not have time to hide or
fix bugs only has time to prevent them
I'm sure if you have a massive army of
Engineers a massive army of many
consultants that's different but we're
talking about scaling a small team of
individuals designers the chair by
default in mind this has to be because
everything you do make security opt-out
decisions that having to opt into
security it's incredibly powerful the
default assessment psychological thing
that we made make opting out of security
a very conscious decision made your
function something super crazy like I
have all authorization because I notice
the state the person typing out those
words is our to think about what they're
doing the person reviewing its own is
definitely going to think about what
they're doing so they might have context
and a thought you definitely attest
explain in simple luck but understand it
you're only you have moderate adoption
at this point again the sort of steam is
like tin foil hat II you know like the
card you sort of impress the benefits
upon everyone so it's just a realistic
there you sort of going back to secure
by default and during a rails 23
transition and rail to see the value for
not automatically HTML state and it was
a manual transmission a lot of people
have sort of moved to rails 38 sort of
taking for granted
develop on Rails to apps and a lot of
people would even say why do I have to
escape and number why do I have to
escape constant numbers and become
strangers top can become dynamic and
like I said everything has to be an HTML
page or else you're gonna run into the
problem I'd rather solve the problem
tightly linked by keeping roll out all
the security headers anyone to be no
leader knows this might be my favorite
part of security to browser vendors but
let me proceed and everyone involved is
some tremendous work over the past five
years to make the browsers actually safe
to use and through the website these
browsers render much much better that's
a whole talk on the phone I'm sure
something rotten egg nog of the problem
do your best to support fewer browsers I
love they did have Tony cares about
current users of Chrome that is about
eighty percent of our user base and I
made that number up but I can tell you
it's the vast majority of users share of
Eugene care about everyone else if
you're on ie6 get out of our website
will not be supporting period and some
people still have the support i use this
for these crazy feature films across the
season share0 security whatsoever we
gotta let me to argue deliver are
typically very technical and keep their
stuff okay watch above them I don't
think there's any debate about whether
or not bug bounties Harvard they are
they basically can show you all the
plate thing that you hadn't thought
about it's really really good and you
get a series of reports and something
that you thought maybe was secured or
maybe didn't even know about and now
someone else that told you in column in
your organization retired to be used to
take more kings and future that maybe
haven't been discovered because these
are your blinds boss and I call you mine
say you can't get the foot out of my
head the best indicator of the next club
it's the last book how do you think of
the horrible trade off personal
what people how's it is usually other
services stramonium from so I was
fortunate enough to where everyone I'm i
participated and started when we felt
comfortable starting it there's a lot of
people who will say don't start about
them just because you should have a bug
bounty because I can be disastrous which
we knighted be careful for the audience
I'd be be purposeful unless you do and
don't lie yourself about maturity so the
last big bullet point of this huge slide
is barely any rate stacking ounces
computer believe I want to sell sorry
about a project that happened Twitter a
bunch of years ago in some possibility
no sadly the static announces dashboard
the concept behind savvy was a developer
of a push code or running static
analysis dip it from a distance so we've
only showed the new vulnerabilities and
we send the developer emails and hey we
notice these nutrients they have the
option going call bullshit on us which
think only happened a few signs I don't
think people were comfortable to work
bullshit after you official our ability
get another continual saying it's been
fixed the really only show the distance
because can't expect anybody including
security engineer to review an entire
report at all times human brain when it
has too much information to process can
homie cause changes and that's exactly
what's going on here and I want to talk
about another cost github named Sentinel
so it's all sort of designed after sadly
but in a very specific way to did huh
tangail you create a pull request
pendulums and you've owner delete the
lab line comments the individuals being
in the pull request super helpful again
these are only warnings that we have
very very high confidence bones counts
can cannot stand ppl heater now after
the code is murders the second games
running and rebelled whistle turning on
all the fights all the fault a vehicle
or is the only consumer of this with the
aspect indiana t long haul that day
because be much more
quickly granted what's going on and
decide what is Virgil investigation here
or not so what will they accomplished
we've instantly failed the security team
because about John the program so now
he's on the chest at close in fact
refuting events like Dorothy men in
robot so dear dr products for the to
left tackle that draw contest again
faulty we have some control over what
they're targeting information gratis at
the very least what time especially to a
place with a plan for triaging an
immediate issues through discipline
burning program we also have beta we
don't need to protect after security
reasons for a very long time we've also
eliminated or monday or limited many
patents and luggage way out right after
that you can enter the cookies are
limited cross-site scripting Vieira
content security policy skirt short
directive that's pretty good pretty much
extracted personification set your
course to none to take me to the plastic
Java the label stutters purse integrity
which concerns that foot controller
content delivery network mastery
containment every value of RC Davis
compromising birth transdermal code
other preferably Latin Democrats in
multan we've eliminated browser Catholic
stepping over plain text we're on the HS
ESP littlest buttons https base into the
raffle for our website we will get
rather it and speak at man
I would say one even asking the only
describes we love you betta association
to be added on your complicated policy
and lastly they're perfect so don't
underestimate the importance of building
a happy healthy culture you want to
establish Poland or just clubs cultures
actually tree off our archives and has
been just like any other Club security
motion be grounds for shaving you don't
want to punish the person who those
vulnerable coat the only investigating a
pressure on this issue this person
Gloria after all everyone is written
okay again but Alberto I'm above
collapse question which I can we delete
with code framework meet our moon the
retirement place we could count for it
was actually to gain by default how can
we detected earlier and lastly copy
social issues with Serena where you also
shouldn't be making in terms that here
you should take the initiative to join
meeting committee provides some
engineering support for non security
related project and series should always
been full of people on shipping code
securing the grittiness involved in
almost 20 projects we never have to let
people daily enough you don't want to
follow this mindset that every new
project is just going to make your life
worth it hope you want to show you
there's something that's good for
everyone authorship
you also want me to google another cup
you doing anyhow hopefully the go here
to be something that people want to
include and not recognize and despite
public has the first cultural patrol
with engineering team of blends
two-factor authentication with a little
help them secure so that's for the
features related or computing but I mean
the scooty might have a better idea from
the tip alternate choices and so will
provide guidance but comes the culture
really that go are convened your culture
should be that security not if they know
we're going to a be careful but this at
this point Papa buffers well the company
the bridge with the unicorn and the
drunk bastard making banners I have this
one time to hire an actual security
those two content with contractor been
mentioned earlier help me of the
transition and office down the five
years or 20 times in flames letting in
security ops in the area I've said with
on its own entity and now we're older
more clearly defined and now what
someone has an issue people out there
isn't a better time to see that should
get up Cooper
so now what are we accomplished but this
point I'd genetic security that's how
hearing becomes a good customer and
provider communication can be better and
now we're out but if our sanity chronic
you're going to stay in scrum culture
will fail quality will drop bobsville
service it's important to illustrate 88
and quality as a cultural problem and
all the sudden is really hard are you
against it people don't fail processes
view that processes are a result of
abating culture any culture can be
addressed with better processes at this
point unfortunately conversations with
security are not happening it's been
community with life it's about meeting
the exclusion is intentional very often
we sort of perceived tribal knowledge
amongst the team and sort of did
confidence that they can make a good
risk assessment which unfortunately
might different grade me from of the
OPSEC team also as you start to grow
native code will enter your staff no
matter what you do I don't know anything
about me to code security needed with
anybody on our team we just have first
the shit out of effort what's gonna help
it happening you're going to have an
incident this is a picture of the tweet
that incident from few years ago Jim
immortalized the period is probably
exhausting every other incidents are
unfortunate but they're not always bad
and good things always come out of
influence I want to get one example and
I also teach in design check in here the
teeth I think students first thing
everyone says was why didn't this have
content security policy this would have
killed his body entirety well
unfortunately the toss the tree SEC
teams are stalled out we had a boss
deployed and sort of has put on the back
burner louder focusing on for important
things if I call directly the CST
product project restarted who need me
and it was implemented within a
reasonable amount of time
all right good I don't press my men make
some time so it's good to hear for every
event created a sheet that you can
follow along with have a chat room
perhaps dedicated to specific incident
itself open up the video conference do
not jump on you want title on an
assistant cannot actually help us stay
out of people's way to follow along if
you can during the investigation again
do not point fingers I want to talk
about a recent soon of github which
caused private repository of data from
other people at a time being requested
if you look at the pull request to cause
this bug and you say you saw coming I'll
say your fricking lager first of all the
person writing the code has more
understanding than anybody else about
that specific part of the framework and
if anybody in the world they did not see
it coming the people are viewing the
code lots of people are like yes is very
good idea it's applied for a canary
server and no problems detected as soon
as it went to production more exceptions
we never seeing their tire light the
gift of happiness and it's a matter of a
minute and immediately the roles of fact
what happens what was the problem the
canary process did not detect us it
should have we did a lot of
Investigation figure out why it did not
for every incident takes the problem
diagnosed in fact notify those affected
and make a public statement people
really appreciate transparency no
company is perfect everyone's gonna make
some space He willed it in a positive
manner
so now what are we accomplish even
reverses and we now know where the games
are planning to the post-mortem process
aliens were identified company had a
rude awakening and now attrition
procuring all the things that but
throughout the whole process the
basement is not to imagine security here
and here in two minutes to the absolute
bollocks I mean that makes a
contribution cubana security brother we
have a pastor will divide the console
will call the year content security and
now our internal and external app under
critical variables such as our scheme
government spy network engineering
development so they reached a new level
of maturity within the security program
we're no longer fighting fires for
fixing classes of problems at this point
framework carbon becomes a day-to-day
tasks but is huge returns you know like
we mentioned earlier since we chose most
a shark loading data have been
officially separated by some definition
of official in the sort of mythical
world we've also made us what the
browser's cannot make HTML via string
concatenation the amount of spin
concatenation built HTML amount of X the
class created one day one we've also
made it so it internally it's are equal
to Tripoli a user include would not run
in behind this today but they should
I've heard plz plz was pretty good at
separating code data but I don't know
enough about it you also get forward
with the standards bodies to help shape
specification but might benefit you
sounds sort of available today I just
want to go over a couple examples so
just bear with me while I ramble for a
little bit I have a martyr dinner did we
get how to implement its led resource
integrity we thought we were done and so
they got a bounding report about the
script that did not have an integrity
attribute in our mind we wanted on
everything why doesn't the browser stay
use of resource integrity have a modes
that you require sub resource identity
for everything so I don't recall if we
compose it or we push for it or whatever
but it eventually happened I believe
it's going to be in browsers without
flies soon another example that happen
well more quickly would be foraging and
cross large and refer policy github
takes meeting the existence of a private
repository very seriously it's a problem
we'll never solve but the finger sort of
still plugging holes with if you had a
link here evenings off and you click
link and went to an external host you
now delete the existence that revert to
the external host it's not good then I
can't remember exact options at the time
we tried it in clemente origin policy
such that for all cases the only value
for reverb would be give up calm a 60s
github com unfortunately that breaks a
very important feature at ruby on rails
moon's redirects for that such as you
mind my guest uses the refer to redirect
you to where you work so we couldn't use
that we thought it's okay to eat them
prefer being give up and give up this
model table you could refer to get on to
someone else so that's where origin
cross-origin came from and it does
exactly that and we implemented it and
it was great success another devil from
the twitter days was the content
security policy hash feature but it said
i do not like nonces for their inherent
dangerousness but you know trying to use
an onsen in a high-traffic website and
being very expensive we had they have in
mind javascript that was in fragmented
HTML it was cast because it would be on
the giving page once at the time we
didn't want to be generated every time
it could not get rid of that in mind
javascript think for political reasons
council member and an office does not
work attach the fragment cast it has
been monopolised a Schmeling on their
old internationals in your header by
definition so we thought well the
javascript never changes the same every
single time use we can compute the hash
of that javascript can meet LCS peaked
on me
especially matches the hash that's
exactly what happened this unfortunately
I think delayed content security policy
level 2 for a little while and
proportionately by the time that was
ready we had moved away from cashing
that fragment but I don't think it's
good on something I'm really pushing for
now is what's called like hashes for
external sources very similar is the
resource integrity where you sort of
know the value of your content ahead of
time you can compute the hash at the 45
why can't you just specify the hash of
those external sources inside your
content security halt so currently I
think the best thing that you can do is
sort of widely supported is to move all
your assets on to one key and your
script source becomes that p and you're
done with it I think the Holy Grail is
the list of every single 50 scores from
the hash of it because you never know
you might get a file lying around on
your CD and you'll know about you have a
constant injection both pulled down old
outdated version of the library and you
have that success me in theory has the
best conference to call so you could
have so at this level charity aspects of
integrated into every part of the work
club we're getting architecture of the
union's we're going code reviews as peer
reviews there's automated reviews for
sort of releasing features for bounty
hunters sort of having early release so
they can have on things before things
get the general public another great
thing at this point is that shared
responsibility 116 is very very clear
one mile of optimized for engineering
focus time distractions are terrible
they ruin everything not everyone has to
handle if everything all the time when I
first joined get up the bounty triage
was on the first come first serve basis
whoever had the inbox opened when the
report came in with handy this is bad
for a number of reasons for one which
geographically distributed I used to get
up pretty late that everyone was in time
zone the features so I think doing Donny
trios everything is already handled by
the time I was ready to work and that's
not fair but more importantly what
happens we're always stepping on each
other's toes you guys you guys
ok we have response to the conventional
reporter within seconds of each other
that's in two different people who might
be two different things that's not good
the other benefit is defining this role
in separating things it's like when it's
not my value to do today I don't check
my email period that level of focus is
amazing so hard that you trust your
peers sort of path under you know
without you I'm not looking at my peers
response to vouch for you made speak
that's actually okay it's a lot better
than me analyzing every single thing to
say dude or did you do best whether it's
for skills or your interests the
combination of shit is obviously better
and don't do the working load you don't
enjoy doing the work and doing gonna do
a bad job or at least not the best job
could be doing the best part is if
you're just honest about what you like
and you don't like not everybody's like
to do perhaps something you don't like
is something someone else love I hate
black box testin the people on our team
does liked it I don't do any more black
ops testing anymore another thing is
sort of talk about that after a few
years is that your blood bounty starts
to dwindling returns the number of
reports coming in is much lower than the
lowest quality of the record is terrible
and you haven't had a serious one I
really you can like a year it helps
decide to adjust this by launching our
bug bounty promotion to pay out before
for the month of January in February the
top three most severe reports will get a
bonus on top of what they're already
getting paid and then just sort of the
best report babies on a serious bone you
gave us prove the concept you gave gave
us network traffic these are the best
reports that we get and we want to
encourage this now again I already said
that I'm a huge fan of bug Donny I'm
more of a fan of gun promotions within
the first day we got a top tailbone and
we're not happened without it I don't
want to pay the rest of what has
happened so far the Nuggets public but
all I can tell you is an overwhelming
success and I'm very thankful for the
for the skittle board because we got
graphic designers on this we've got PR
people long as we even got it sweet
limited edition t-shirt so we're doing
office of researchers so spinach days in
your startup's life is you're going to
read for I feel this is when things
start to get a little nerve-wracking the
company is doubling in size
year-over-year security things growing
in a somewhat slower pace the security
role all tense we did a little more
compliancy there's absolutely nothing
wrong with doing compliance order I've
seen great things happen before
statement we all fear except for those
wonderful people who can manage it how
many times that implements he shines you
from cell have you started looking to
acquisitions I am not happy about this
but it is unnecessary you hungry
acquisition by definition is going to
ruin your culture I highly doubt any
company to require some sort sit right
in and without any resistance so what
can you do you can come up the diligence
plan or incoming acquisition so at least
you can get some idea of what's going to
happen do they have a security team do
they run above them how do they store
the password to them in response program
our credentials makers having this in
place for the acquisition to be very
useful if you can do a third-party
assessment of the depositions beforehand
that's even better but most importantly
you need to know resistant aqua higher
for an actual acquisition the akwa
hotter need that you're just going to
buy the company for the engineering
talent this is what you want because you
want to shut down and product you don't
want me to you what happens to
requisitions is that your development
staff starts to diversify all these
technologies that you haven't bless are
not a part of your staff and then you go
into a little corner and cry because
anything built up it's just been torn
down overnight but other results you can
consolidate your development study I
think we did a really good job here add
a vapor decomposing and monolithic
application
services and add lyric line companies
there was a common platform to build
upon I was blessed the security team had
a lot of involvement with this new web
favorite that was being built first of
all we learned lesson ruby on rails
which does everything was some crazy
thing that no one would ever actually
need to use my guarantee there are more
games in there the framework a dope did
nothing but the most basic stuff we
could possibly need there were no bells
and whistles paddle at this point was
our last chance to really really stick
to the secure by default we provide the
cops with all the security Heather's by
default with a very strict confidence
security policy you had to opt out and
guess what that mana look they
definitely had trouble applying aankhen
security policy we now dozens of
Greenfield apps which we need one or two
pages a default conscience cable to the
worst of all those really need you to
come up with how the kind of automation
Twitter you'll had sort of been very
happy with the way side we have
progressed but we didn't have an answer
for solver so instead we focus on
designing API and we're secured an adult
and would have to be opted out of and
then we just search for those strengths
so probably photo book move beyond basic
application security and mortgage not
affecting implement a most excellent
earlier and they're essentially ask you
to beta countries on the internet we
have get set for all efficient check in
there different role gratitude but not
income you going managers marketing or
PR employees I mean high risk base rate
in user account now we used to read only
mode so that's a complex phenomenon and
we'll and high-profile comfort both of
you elongated announcement to be
drastically to expose on earth will be
log correlation machine learning self
activity and then log alerts and
dashboards that one letter in how people
are keeping excited or where they are ok
and then remind not knowledge to
renounce it and you'll know where you
can prioritize your efforts and lastly
this one is for security
the bottom of the ideal happen I just
want to point out some further resources
that i think are useful writing again we
do the great series and starting up
security some still an active blog and
encourage everyone delete it whether or
not you're gonna start up more than an
fri situation another thing that started
working is going on is the CTO security
checklist and know how we feel about
checklist you're not great but i think
this one is really off to a good start i
hope to appropriate everything i've
talked about into that later very lastly
I'd like to throw the conference and
putting on in april of 2018 album Vlade
being seen via greater than that but i
might be a little 25 so if you'd like to
learn more don't go to our website at
work well we have a twitter handle so
you can go there and fits all questions
so HD was really so the challenge it
feel all does it start ups 2 billion
help enough manpower to do code reviews
of what do i do on ax me as much as you
possibly can except that you can't fix
everything I really try to emphasize a
lot that humans aren't doing a lot of
the code reviews result but you can ever
cover everything
so how do you reconcile that little
early started bawling and I don't
polymerase and you're rushing it would
have an MVP how do you so soon as I'll
shop is capable of Russian twisting
things out is also capable of pushing up
security fixes just as fast i think that
the agita are closing in fast break
things exactly the way it should be
you're not going to touch everything and
it could buggy down mana for a little
while and doesn't get exploited it's not
a bad thing when we explain a buzz of
that s we cannot know if that the pub
has been exploited but being cautious
and stopping the country will ruin the
relationship with engineering and
embracing that culture and leveraging it
just is amazing I think the plague
effect can get up as long take that
approval in a matter of minutes and it's
just a chat ops command everyone in the
company can do that too I won't you can
deploy it something that would make it
more secure too oh okay
I mean recommend react as a computer
from you I has your opinion is never
used it yes I do you use it yes yes and
it has a graph-based it has the
advantage of the graphical so integral
defaults this is great for the word
dangerous and so I trust you screaming
so now i am in the dsm impression