now part of why I wanted to talk about
machine learning to the following
typically when you hear about machine
learning you hear about it from one a
few places you hear about it from
vendors and you look at the vendor
whitepapers they claimed that machine
learning can solve world peace they can
cure cancer they can help with space
exploration and whole bunch of other
things that probably can't quite do on
the flip side if you learn about machine
learning from academic papers you'll get
maybe a more balanced view but typically
that view is restricted to what happened
inside of a very nice clean lab
environment it doesn't tell you what's
going to happen if you try to take those
same ideas and apply to the real world
so my goal was to prod a bit of a
balanced view now I call the talk cyber
security ruler boondoggle this is what
happens when technical folks spend too
much time with the marketing team
hopefully the title makes some sense but
the idea to provide a more balanced view
the goods are bad and the ugly of
machine learning so if you are thinking
about using machine learning whether
you're trying to implement it yourself
or you're evaluating a third party
vendor solution or capability the hope
is to give you some additional context
help you make an intelligent decision
about exactly what machine learning to
provide you with and whether or not it's
something that you actually want to use
within your own products and services so
with that let's get started I'll bring
the talk into three parts so I'll start
off by giving you a broad stroke
overview of machine learning this is for
me to put everyone on the same page look
at it as a 10 minute crash course in
various aspects of machine learning
designed to give you just enough
information so you can understand the
rest of the presentation the second
thing I'll do is I'll talk about how
machine learning can be applied within
cyber security now this won't be that
complicated once you understand what
machine learning can do then the third
part which is really raw spend the bulk
of my time is talking about best
practices and pitfalls and they kind of
go hand in hand if you find a pitfall in
the implementation that typically
suggests the corresponding best practice
well maybe what I call a better practice
because it's really hard to define
sometimes what best means is it's a
constantly evolving area
and with that let's go ahead and get
started and talk about machine learning
with the more detail now machine
learning according to arthur Samuelson
was an early pioneer in artificial
intelligence is a few of the study that
gets computers the ability to learn
without being explicitly programmed now
I think the most remarkable thing about
that definition is it was proposed in
1959 so machine learning with the field
has been around for more than half a
century even though it seems like it's
gotten very popular in the last couple
of years especially as you start to look
at what's going on in the vendor
community and beyond but the field
itself is very rich and has a broad
history more concretely in technical
terms but it involves developing
algorithms that can draw inferences from
and make predictions based on data so
the key word here is data it's really
about being able to find the right data
sources development it needs to extract
insights from of data sources
automatically then apply those insights
to move instances that you haven't
really encountered before machine
learning itself inside a rich history
it's evolved from other areas of
computer science so things like
computational learning theory pattern
recognition data science from so on and
so forth and over time we've seen subtle
differences in terminology and
nomenclature but ultimately i think the
ideas are now becoming much more
mainstream and the goals now for the
practitioners how do you actually take
some of these ideas from the lab
environment and make them growth in your
life and i'm going to focus a bit on
that now the reason people like machine
learning the reason it's been in a lot
of popular attention is it enables you
to get some degree of automation because
you can actually plan to learn
automatically from data but you're
learning in theory should be unbiased
because it's based directly on the data
source you're looking at you're not
introducing any human bias listen to
what the actual outcome is going to be
and I finally there's an element where
you can try to improve over time so as
you get new data coming into a system
the hope is that you can use machine
learning techniques to evolve
automatically based on you data which is
obviously very relevant in a security
context so for security specifically
machine learning is interesting because
it enables some level of automation so
can we come up with models automatically
for being able to identify malicious
activity and more importantly can we
enable those models to evolve over time
as you get new data about attack
behavior because too
we're not dealing with the typical
static adversary in cyber security we
deal with a century an adversary who's
going to try to modify what they do on a
regular basis that's the theory and
practice is actually a lot more
difficult to make some of the stuff work
and that's where they're going to be the
focus of the second act of the
presentation is received now is she
learning in general involves three parts
I'm labeling these things explicitly
because I think it helps us understand
some of the pitfalls and best practices
so the idea is not the kind of beat a
dead horse if you already know what
machine learning is but by talking about
machine learning in general you'll see
exactly how I'm thinking about it and
how you can start to apply it or where
you can avoid some of the mistakes that
I've seen happen in the past typically
there are three phases machine learning
you start off with data very important
to kind of call this out from that date
of the goal is to generate a model and
that model is something that's going to
basically be something that's more
compact and easy representation that's
adequately or well explained by the data
and the idea can we take that model and
apply to these instances can we draw
inferences can be existing data and use
that to reason about things we haven't
seen before now in fact the way it works
is your model typically has a set of
parameters so you can think of maybe the
model instead of equations and there's
some unknown and the goal of the machine
learning algorithm typically to figure
out the values for those unknowns that
optimize the behavior of that model with
respect to the data we started with with
the hope being a particular correctly
you'll be able to then apply that model
to you instances and so it becomes an
optimization problem can I fill in those
question marks with actual parameter
values now given that one of the
patenting is that there are different
aspects of machine learning I want to
point out one thing about what machine
learning is not because people often
confuse machine learning and artificial
intelligence that user terms
interchangeably through the artificial
intelligence is a broader field of which
machine learning is one subset a great
example of something that was artificial
intelligence but not rly machine
learning was the famous chess match
between Garry Kasparov and deep blue
deep blue with supercomputing chest
platform that was developed a number of
years ago in monogamy and was the first
computing platform that could beat a
World Chess Champion in a match and that
was a pretty profound moment I think in
the history of AI because it was the
first time than a world champion and
chat that actually lost in a match
six game much new computer the mantras
that should be pretty close it was tied
up into the last game of the match then
Casbah rock did a really simple mistake
in the early stages of the last game and
essentially I've been psychologically
somewhat crane bolt in the last game
which is something that computers don't
do they don't cave on a psychological
pressure but what's interesting about
deep blue is that it's not a machine
learning system the way it was developed
is that the team hired a group of grand
masters and strong players and those
players develop an evaluation function a
functional he could look at a chest
position and determine really he was
better who was worse and how much better
or worse they were so it could look at a
chess positions taking White's better
here by this much black is better here
by this much that the idea was that deep
blue itself would evaluate a number of
different positions would consider
possible that it could play from a given
position it would consider possible
responses but consider responses those
responses and so on and so forth would
end up with a series of positions that
would evaluate those positions and then
work its way backwards to find out what
the right initial move would be now
given that this is not really a machine
learning approach this is an approach
where a human team of Grand Master's
came up with an evaluation function and
the computer was just used to leverage
is computational power to apply that
evaluation function at many times in
each humanly could and for a long time
that's how chess evolved chess has
really gotten better on the computer
front not because there's been some
fundamental advance and the algorithm
it's because they can throw more
computing power to evaluate more
positions if on the other hand you are
trying to build a chess-playing program
using machine learning you do something
different if I start off with the
history of games that have been played
the winners of those games and let the
computer figure out the right set of
rules that could potentially be used to
improve over time Deepu does not do that
people literally had the team coming up
with the function and then in between
every game of the match the team was
adjusting that function based on what it
learned about his Faro's play so it was
much more of a combined human-computer
effort in the true effort to learn from
data on its own now the next thing I
want to talk about are two different
aspects of machine learning at a high
level so we tend to have supervised
learning and unsupervised learning and
there are other branches of machine
learning but most of the time you went
out at one of these two
supervised learning is about being able
to learn from labeled examples so for
example let's say you're trying to build
a machine learning system for
determining whether or not you should
give a loan applicant alone so what
you're really trying to do is build a
systems that can determine the
likelihood that person will default on
their loan so in that case your label
data might include historical loan
applications as well as information
about whether that candidate ultimately
ended up defaulting on their loan and if
you find that there's a certain set of
attributes that led to a higher likely
to default then you can click that into
your model and then the model can be
applied to you loan application to
determine whether or not that absolute
contribute proof that's kind of at a
high level what is it happening at a
slightly lower level and it's really
important because it's going to help us
understand again best practices except
typically we don't just try it with raw
data and develop a model there's
typically a step in between a be able to
extract good features from that model we
call that problem feature extraction
that typically involves a human expert
who says okay well if you're looking at
a loan application so if you think you
should look at carefully so for example
you might want to look at the size of
the loan you might want to look at the
number of years the person's been
employed you might want to look at their
marital status the idea is maybe each of
those attributes in isolation tells you
whether or not the loan should be given
so for example if somebody's worked for
many many years they're probably a
better candidate for avoiding a default
if they've got a high-income relative to
the loan size that probably a good
candidate if they're married and maybe a
better candidate because they have two
sources of things from potentially and
so on and so forth and when the goal of
a machine learning algorithm is
ultimately take all those attributes and
figure out the most intelligent way to
combine them within certain restrictions
to lead to a good outcome when it comes
to predicting whether or not a new
person will ultimately default on their
loans toasted that application makes
some sense I wanted to provide a generic
application and you can talk about
specific application to cybersecurity
but before I do that I want to talk
about one other aspect of machine
learning which is unsupervised learning
unsupervised learning is about being
able to learn from examples that may or
may not have labels associated with them
typically this is a field of machine
learning that involves find understand
structure in data so you can see a kind
of
created a dataset synthetic obviously a
bunch of teens math and two dimensional
space and what you can start to see is
those points have some kind of structure
associated with them they really fall
into three different clusters and that
kind of tells you something about the
data so for example at some point will
they appear on that data set outside of
those three clusters that might tell you
that hey that one point is somehow
anomalous it's really different from all
these typically seen or if you see a
point that falls into one of the
clusters you can start to infer that its
behavior something about that point is
similar enough to the other points that
the attributes of those other points
could then be transferred potentially to
that you point that you're looking at
and for the most part when we encounter
machine learning in a cyber security
context you'll typically hear about
either supervised learning applications
or unsupervised learning applications
and all other fuels a machine real
investors semi-supervised learning a
bunch of other things I was going to
that today because I think that's too
much detail but hopefully this gives you
a feel for what's going on when machine
learning is being applied so how do we
apply machine learning to cyber security
first of all you think about it most
security applications involve some form
of classification of behavior on a
transaction is that transaction good or
bad whatever that means so for example
if you're trying to do a spam filter you
might look at hunan that's it can say
hey that email message glitter spam and
you might look at certain attributes of
that email like some of the words that
are being used the fonts and maybe the
size of the message information about
the sender of the domain name etc you
could also apply this concept to online
fraud if I given transaction is that
transaction legitimate or the fraudulent
and by the way when you look at the
credit card I mean they have been
applying was she learning for decades to
solve this exact kind of problem by
looking at attributes of the transaction
such as what's being bought the time of
day the past behavior of that particular
individual whether or not that
transaction SML anomalous that for
example if you suddenly buy a plane
ticket to Africa and you never travel
before you might get a phone call your
credit card company that actually happen
to be one so long time ago so I remember
that vividly they may look for other
things like is there something
suspicious about the transaction
behavior like for example if you buy gas
at the same time as buying a dental
computer that actually also happen to be
a long time ago because my wife was
buying gas while I was like a computer
we both got a phone call
so they're looking for things of that
nature things that don't make a lot of
sense but that somehow would be
indicative of fraudulent behavior
malware hundred great examples we're
seeing a lot of companies now to talk
about next generation antivirus they're
applying was she learning to be able to
detect whether or not a file is
malicious and by the way it's kind of
funny because I don't think this is the
next generation that you actually all
the major antivirus comes into doing
this for about seven eight nine years of
production but I think what's happened
recently machine learning to become such
a popular concept that we're hearing
more about the how in terms of what's
happening rather than the why underwater
also being able to detect malicious urls
malicious IP addresses you can apply
machine learning that problem so you
might look at things like how long are
the main been around what do we know
about who is information what do we know
about the geography of the server on
which a particular website is hosted and
so on and so forth to understand whether
or not some piece of traffic might be
malicious so those are some of the
attributes you might look at in the goal
with machine learning is to take those
attributes make sense out of them and
then make predictions about future
instances simply that makes some sense
you can also apply unsupervised learning
to machine to to cyber security in that
case you might look at things like
whether or not you see abnormal behavior
you know do I see a user suddenly
engaging in traffic spike so we saw this
could shape they actually did a really
good job of being able to show that
we're seeing your traffic because all of
a sudden we're seeing a situation where
a user or a particular website is seeing
where traffic patterns that aren't
explained by typical behaviors you might
be able to look at things like an
increase in failed login attempts you
might want to look at whether or not a
user is accessing resources they
wouldn't typically access these are the
kind of things you might look for it
you're trying to find an attack now what
I want you to do for a moment's kind of
suspend judgment about whether these
approaches will work in real life I'm
going to get to what I think some of the
pitfalls and strengths are but this is
typically how we see machine learning
applied when you're doing it for cyber
security and specifically in this case
how we see unsupervised learning applied
in a cyber security context so given
that what are some of the challenges
pitfalls and what I call better
practices for machine learning this is
really where I think the most
interesting part of the talk is the rest
of the work was really there to give you
that I was audio or
okay perfect the rest of the talk was
really about giving you some of the
foundations this happens going to be
really about being able to understand
how to apply those foundations correctly
and what I see is some of the challenges
and being able to do that so this is
really the part where I start talking
about the boondoggle right what what
actually goes wrong when you try to make
these things work in real life I've been
by the way so just by way of background
I've had a chance to work on machine
learning now at a four or five different
companies that kind of lose track but it
started off at Symantec a number of
years ago and I see a whole wall with
yellow so it's kind of good to see some
old colleagues but for the cool thing
there is that you know over time we kind
of learned the hard way what would and
wouldn't work when you all of a sudden
take something that looks really great
on paper and produces a really beautiful
graph and you try to put it to 200
million users and you don't want to get
that wrong on day one so it's the first
thing and this is a really subtle point
is that it has to start with good data
it's amazing how many people forget this
right that's why I kind of talked about
the process of being data then features
and classifier because if you don't
start with good data nothing else
matters machine learning is garbage in
garbage out I've seen many cases where
people will come up with a training set
they'll develop a model based on the
training set then they'll try to apply
that model on real-world data that looks
nothing that training set that they
originally trained on and sometimes it's
very subtle I mean it may be like in
they may have at the best of intentions
but they may have been using like a
black box tool or an existing machine
learning library they weren't paying
attention to what was happening inside
the library and sometimes a libraries
are manipulating some of the training
data as part of training and you may end
up getting a different results and I've
seen this gotten catastrophic me wrong
in so many cases that it's I'm just
pointing it out even though it almost
seems somewhat obvious ultimately with
machine learning you have to write the
last questions just like you wouldn't
data science it's not about looking at
data and making inferences typically
there's a phase in which you look at
that data and you say what are the right
questions to ask what are the right
things to look at and then based on that
you come up with intelligent inferences
so I don't think of machine learning is
a panacea if it looks really beautiful
on paper you've still got to be very
careful to ensure that when you put it
in real life you're mimicking you saw on
paper earlier and that I think is one of
the grandest challenges with machine
learning in practice the second
challenge is people get obsessed
with the classifier I mean I've never
seen you put an engineer in front of a
good library and they'll start tweaking
every single aspect of the classifier
but to me that's the least important
part of machine learning if you're
talking to a vendor and they're talking
about how many layers in their neural
network or they're talking about the
latest techniques that they're using
that's all fine and good but again has
to start with data first then coming up
with the right features associated with
that data set and then and only then do
you care about the classifier now it
turns out that if you've got the right
data first and the right features here's
a secret it almost doesn't matter what
classifier you choose you all perform
within like a fraction of a percent of
each other and most academics who focus
on this topic if they're looking for
like one-tenth of one percent
improvement or maybe like a one percent
improvement to publish a paper in
practice there may be reasons to go with
a simpler classifier for debugging or
being able to deal with it in the field
and really focusing on make sure your
data is good and your features are good
so I see that mistake over and over
again you'll hire a cadre of you know
PhDs in machine learning and they never
have one domain expert on their team to
say these are the features that are most
relevant like here's a good example
let's say you're trying to develop a
machine learning system to try to
classify whether or not a given URL is
likely to be malicious okay if you do
also decreasing the URL you can
manipulate it ten ways till Sunday but
if you ask any analyst in a security
operations and what the first they do
when they see a URL they do a whois
lookup and they figure out how long that
domain name isn't around that's probably
one of the strongest indicators of
whether or not that domains malicious
but if you're not looking for that if
you don't know to look for that if you
only are thinking about the data science
part of it you may miss one of the most
simple features that gives you a huge
performance boost and that's why it's
really critical to focus on those three
layers in order start what good data
then focus on features and then worry
about your classifier and I'm really
laboring this point because most people
do with the opposite they really focus
on the classifier they tweak the hell
out of it but they never think about
what's happening at a higher level in
the stack the next thing is that
security has what I call a class
imbalance problem most things we see in
real life are not malicious most times
their credit card transactions made its
benign most files on your laptop are not
malware and this almost seems obvious
but it actually has a
huge implication for machine learning
systems because machine learning systems
have to sidestep all those legitimate
instances on their way to find that one
illegitimate instance which means that
the problem of false positives is huge
it is a tremendous I think it's the
number one thing if you've got to focus
on minimizing in an infield setting is
how do you minimize that false positive
rate how do you start to think about the
right metrics that matter and it turns
out that class and balance becomes a
really critical measure because if you
don't think about class and balance the
odds are that you're not going to be
able to interpret your metrics correctly
and know whether or not you're
performing well so let's talk about some
of those metrics typically in machine
learning there are two very high level
metrics that are applied in cyber
security the one metric is what i call
the crew positive or detection rate this
is the rate at which we detect malicious
stuff so for example if you have your
data set that you're trying to evaluate
you look at all the things that are
malicious met data set and you try to
find what percentage of those actually
malicious things were classified as
malicious by your machine learning
algorithm that's a detection rate on the
flip side there's a false positive rate
which is the rate at which you might
alarm accidentally how many times are
you taking something that's otherwise
legitimate and calling it bad
accidentally I mention these two metrics
together because you've got to look at
them in conjunction with each other a
lot of people will tout incredible true
positive rate so I'll tell you you know
what I'm getting a hundred percent
detection rate but they'll never tell
you what the false positive rate is
you've got to look at that together
because you know what I can build a
fantastic classifier with a hundred
percent detection rate all I'll say is
everything is bad that's got a hundred
percent detection rate it's also got a
really crappy false positive rate now I
know this sounds almost like brain-dead
but at some level if you take a step
back you'll see a lot of vendors never
talk about the other aspect of their
metric and oftentimes it may be very
very bad especially when you couple that
with class and balance and I'll give an
example of that in a moment to make that
point really really crystal clear and so
in general there's a trade-off between
the true positive rate and the false
positive rate as you get more aggressive
to detect things they're more likely to
get false positives so if you're
typically trying to measure isn't just a
true positive rate and false positive
rate on its own where you're trying to
understand what machine learning is a
trade-off that you get between them
a good machine learning algorithm will
give you a favorable trade off it will
give you a big bump potentially in the
true positive rate for a modest or maybe
small increase in the false positive
rate and the way we do that in practice
is we try to take the true positive and
false positive rates that we get from
our classifiers we could pick we graph
them we call that graph the ROC curve
the receiver operating characteristic
curve and we try to look at the area
under that curve as a measure of how
well that classifier is giving you a
trade-off between true positives and
false positives and that's very a better
metric to look at verses just an
individual through positive a false
positive rate because it could totally
depend on the application you're
concerned with so now let's look at a
more detailed example about why I think
false positives don't tell the whole
story why you've got to look at
everything together suppose you're
reading an academic paper and I've read
academic papers that say something like
this they go you know we develop a
system with one hundred percent
detection rate one hundred percent true
positive rate and a 0.1 percent false
positive rate that sounds pretty good
right those numbers sound pretty
compelling if I saw a paper like that I
didn't know any better I might say well
yeah that sounds like something I should
implement and by the way I've never seen
a paper with these good numbers so keep
in mind this is this is pretty much a
dream scenario in a lot of academic
papers what happens when we put that in
real life so imagine I've got a bunch of
instances if you're kind of yellow and
there's one malicious one in there
that's the one that's really really bad
the rest of them are otherwise benign
very typical scenario if you're looking
at credit card transactions most are
good one might be bad good looking at
files for every 10,000 may be legitimate
files on a laptop there might be one
piece of malware in fact about 10,000
ones a pretty good ratio that seems to
work pretty well across a number of
different domain in which machine
learning is applied it's not perfect but
it kind of works for this example to
imagine for every 10,000 things you see
there's maybe one malicious thing in
there now let's apply this perfect the
amazing classifier to this scenario if I
did then let's say out of all these ten
thousand transactions Cal catch the
legitimate the illegitimate one because
I've assisted with a hundred percent
detection rate however that system also
has a point one percent false positive
rate which means that one is up a
thousand times i'm going to call one of
those yellow dots
read that means if you're sitting inside
of an incident response center or a sock
or you're looking at alerts or whatever
it is you're going to get another ten
alerts to go with that one alert that
you started with what that means is it
for every 11 alerts you see only one was
actionable so ninety percent of your
time we're spent chasing false leads the
reason I'm really believer in this point
is that when you think about it for a
moment the numbers i started with i said
one hundred percent and point one
percent those numbers sound really
fantastic at a high level when you work
out what that means in practice it turns
out to be really dangerous it turns out
to be something that actually probably
is untenable if i told you i'm going to
tell you a technology where you going to
spend ninety percent your time chasing
false stuff you're kicking out of the
room in about five seconds right there
would be no hope of being able to get
that done and yet it's really about
phrasing i started out by talking about
metrics in a very positive light when
you work out with his metrics mean in
practice it turns out to be very
negative if you're not careful about how
you apply them so the moral of the story
is think about your metrics really
really carefully i give you just one
example and there are many others for
example not every false positive is
created equal if i had a false positive
on a popular file let's say svchost.exe
now that has ever happened in real life
some of you know that would be much
worse than a false positive on a file
that has never appeared anywhere maybe
on one system out there in the world if
i had a false positive on a critical
business application in organization
maybe not be a very popular file but if
it goes takes one system down and the
company can conduct business that's a
huge issue she's got to consider that
not every false positive means the same
thing and it totally depends on context
the second thing is that not every true
positive is created equal okay some
people may not mind certain things or
maybe they're okay with adware being on
systems but they really care about info
steelers for other reasons so you have
to be careful that when you look at
machine learning and try to translate
that to what it means for an
organization you've got to account for
some of these factors in terms of what
you're trying to achieve with your
machine learning solution the third
thing this is kind of funny
maliciousness is subjective you know I
talk to customers where they don't mind
and
toolbar I don't know why they don't mind
it but somehow they don't mind it maybe
they want to buy a dword maybe they want
to buy those fake Rolexes maybe they
want to get spam but the reality is that
this is not always a clear-cut answer
and it totally depends on the scenario
and you can play think of other
scenarios that are more pernicious and
then finally machine learning is not
something to use an isolation a lot of
vendors talk about it like it's the
be-all end-all typically when machine
learning is used in a system it's one
part of a number of different techniques
that are used to find malicious behavior
so if you're trying to evaluate whether
or not a machine learning system is
going to be good you have to look at the
additive value of that approach on top
of everything else you have so typically
you'll have some black list and some
white list which we know aren't perfect
but they do a pretty good job of all the
popular stuff and then what's left over
might be looked at by machine learning
system or by some other technique so the
real criteria is not how do you do on
the whole data set the real criteria is
how do you do on a data set that remains
one some of the other techniques have
been applied it's really critical to
look at that additive value and there
may be cases where you have a machine
learning system with a ten percent
detection rate which sounds awful but if
it detects a ten percent of things that
were missed by everything else it's
actually pretty good so you've got to
look at things in context and by the way
the opposite is true as well you may
have a tension system a machine learning
system that has a ninety percent
detection rate but if it's exactly the
same thing that all your other
techniques could detect it provides no
additive value so given that what else
is wrong with machine learning when you
apply it in your life the other thing is
that in real life when we talk about
cyber security we're not dealing with a
static threat actor we're dealing with
adversaries who adapt we're dealing with
people who literally are thinking about
how to get five the systems we create
and by the way the rate at which they
get by is almost a direct function of
how much it's right you are to them so
you're not seeing when I've been at big
vendors or give a lot of customers will
see it's white actors adapt within weeks
of any new technique we publish if they
figure it out they usually are very
quick to adapt and make the changes they
need the second thing is that typical
machine learning algorithms if you look
at all the academic literature they
don't assume that you're dealing with
the malicious scenario they typically
assume that everything is sort of hunky
dory you've got this data set
you're trying to learn from it they're
trying to apply it but in real life in
cyber security we're dealing with right
actors who are specifically trying to
circumvent the algorithms are being
created they're going to try to fight
just under the radar they know your
threshold is X they're going to try to
be at x over 2 and so on and so forth so
they are very very careful in what they
do now that doesn't mean all is lost
there are some ways of trying to address
that for example you can take your
machine learning techniques and try to
make them work with more weight on the
later data set so that you can try to
adapt more quickly you can find
introduced new data you can try to do
rapid retraining or relearning so
reiterating quickly and on what your
machine learning algorithm decadence at
which they're being applied you can also
potentially try to do something called
online learning where every time you see
a new example or a new instance you try
to retrain your classifier based on the
latest data you're seeing now again
that's not perfect either I'm sure we
can come up with 72 different ways to
break that and in fact this is an area
of active research there's in fact the
whole field of machine learning called
transfer learning or inductive learning
that tries to look at the problem of
what happens if you're trying to develop
a machine learning system it's applied
for one setting and then you're trying
to make a small change in the rules of
the game and apply to a different
setting so for example they've tried to
do this for games like go where they
might try to design a machine learning
system that works for go on a you know
15 by 15 board and then they'll try to
see what happens is they take that same
system and make it work on a larger
board that's something humans are pretty
good at we're pretty good at being able
to adapt to slightly different scenarios
with limited data but machines are not
good at doing that and to this day the
literature on this area of inductive
learning and transfer learning we've
shown some early promise but I think
there's a huge way to go before we can
make this stuff work in real life but
it's very very pertinent for our
industry supervised learning also has
pitfalls specific to it so for example
the training set in supervised learning
will typically capture what you know
about right it's all the stuff that
you're aware of in the past which means
the models that you generate from that
training set might draw some additional
instances but will relieve slightly
expand your state of knowledge and
often happens is people develop these
really cool looking models and once they
end up with at the end of the day is
kind of a glorified signature it's
basically maybe about your if-then
statements looks some byte code but
nothing much more beyond that it's not
careful at least it's really important
to realize that we're dealing oftentimes
not just with the things we know about
but what I like to call the unknown
unknowns like the things that we don't
yet know about which is really what
we're trying to apply but she and
learning in the first place so again it
may give you some mileage but may not be
as much as you think on the flip side
again Moses behavior subjective and
whether or not something is malicious is
less about what that tool is and more
about how it's being used what the
intent is so for example power show you
know we've seen powershell powershell as
good uses we see a lot of bad guys use
powershell as well you can't develop a
machine learning algorithm the classic
classifier powershell on its own which
you've got to look at maybe is how it's
being used and whether or not that used
is actually malicious and intent and
that's something that's really hard to
do there may be cases where somebody is
legitimately allowed to transfer a lot
of data out of your data center they're
allowed to they're doing it for specific
business purpose the intention is good
but you put somebody else in there who
maybe has a bad intention and is not
supposed to transfer that data out and
all of a sudden attention becomes bad if
you look at just the behaviors alone the
behaviors look identical at a high level
it's the intent that might be different
and intent is something that's very very
hard to measure computationally I don't
know that any computer can be a good
moral Iser in our lifetimes but you know
it's an open-ended research maybe that
something will come up with at some
point but for now that's a fundamental
limitation and machine learning now what
I want to point out is it machine
learning going to like that the reality
there's a lot of low-hanging fruit out
there that people have not been thinking
for a long time machine learning is
great at being able to identify some of
that expand our horizons a bit it
definitely moves the needle on being
able to do better job of threat
detection but it may not move the needle
as much as you might read about in a
vendor white paper so it's really
important to put some context around
that take it with a grain of salt now
finally I'm going to talk about a story
of happening me personally that I think
illustrates this point a number of years
ago I was working on a project involving
foul reputation so is what working on
how to do automatic
mutation using a lot of data that i was
looking at and what not and you know is
any good technology to engineer likes to
do i started working on a side project
we cut that would be kind of interesting
had all this data on file reputation I
wanted to see if I could apply that data
to certificate reputations and I figure
out something about the digital
certificates that were being used to
sign the binder is associated with the
files which ad reputation scores and the
idea was the following if I have a bunch
of files and they've got high reputation
then I can kind of infer that the
corresponding certificate that was used
in digitally signing those files should
also have high reputation which then
would lead me to believe in anything
else signed by that same certificate
should likely have high reputation as
well so it was a way to use something
about Sol reputation to determine
whether or not I could infer something
about certificate reputation and then in
turn use information about certificate
reputation to then infer something about
file reputation and machine learning was
at the core of the system so i started
doing some file replication when I had
to apply to certificate reputation I
started collecting a lot of data as I
would typically do and so I had a bunch
of data on certificates at a bunch of
that on files and I was trying to just
play with some ideas so I put my my data
on a spreadsheet i had made about thirty
or forty thousand rows at the time and I
kind of reduced it down to just a
handful of interesting certificates and
roughly speaking the certificates kind
of fell into one of two categories the
first set of certificates were only
being used to sign popular stuff really
high reputation files think of things
like Microsoft or Adobe or something of
that nature everything those
certificates were signing were really
popular really high reputation nothing
strange or weird on the other hand I
also saw some certificates that were
being used to sign a lot of low
reputation files so things like ad where
vendors very typically would sign their
binaries but you could tell that there
were a drove enders because the binary
is being signed were all kind of
one-offs not very popular and whatnot
but there was one mind on my spreadsheet
that was kind of throwing me off and it
was line 23 I vividly remember it and
its certificate it was being just find
some good things that were very popular
and high reputation I was also being
used to find some things that were very
very unpopular I had maybe one or two
instances in the world
and that struck me is kind of weird why
would a legitimate software company
signed something but only give it to
maybe one person but do that three
hundred times for 300 if ur intense side
of it at all I conclude it may be to
something wrong with my data at some
point i think i left the company forgot
about the project and you know kind of
moved on in my life and a few months
later i was sitting there and read a
report about aspect of your heart or
heard of hopefully Stuxnet now what's
interesting is Stuxnet was digitally
sign it were digitally signed by the
real tech certificate which was line 23
of my spreadsheet so here I was ok
nobody knew about Stuxnet when I first
looked at the spreadsheet ok and I was
staring at it in the face it was
literally in front of me I could see
tons of binary is being signed by it in
fact a bunch that never were talk about
publicly at the time and I missed it and
I head back on a malware analysis i was
in security for a while I thought I was
a domain expert I was very humbled by
the experience I realized hate for
everything I knew here are these Fred
actors who completely threw me through a
loop and I completely ignored it I
missed all the warning signs was months
later before I finally put all this
together and I bring this up because
this is really why machine learning is
hard to apply in their life you know
we're not dealing with a sweat actor
who's only going to sit there and make
one change and throw a piece of malware
out there and never change it again
they're specifically going to try to
mess with you and machine learning still
hasn't figured out how to deal with that
effectively now it's not that you can't
apply it and move the needle but you've
got to be cognizant of the fact that
there may be certain things that will be
for the foreseeable future beyond the
scope of what machine learning can
accomplish I want to share also with you
some pitfalls of unsupervised machine
learning these are somewhat obvious but
I think it's important to note the
reality is that people don't realize it
that when you look at unsupervised
learning it's really about being able to
find things that are out of the norm and
something being abnormal is not the same
thing as being malicious for example i'm
here today at the a number of beach
house i have never been here before in
my life i can assure you you know some
machine learning system might be
tripping up somewhere if it finds me
here because it's an anomaly for me
right so an almost behavior is not the
same thing as malicious behavior there
may be reasons why you behave an all
mostly maybe
traveling maybe you have a work deadline
so all of a sudden you're checking in
and out more code than you normally
would maybe there's a holiday sale at
the website that you're monitoring and
all of a sudden they see a spike in
traffic that's abnormal normally
abnormal but is actually perfectly
reasonable within the context of a sale
and so it's really tricky you better
take into account not just what you're
putting in but you've got to take into
account whether or not the context
suggest that that data should look at
the way it does then finally it's
actually not that easy to measure normal
behavior you can kind of look at logs
and whatnot so for example I've seen a
lot of companies try to look at
geolocation behavior and look for
geolocation and almost like hey why was
Julie in China than a second later in
California and a second later somewhere
else that's all fine and good but
geolocation baseline hard to measure I
could use a mifi device I could use a
VPN all those things will typically
throw off to your location based
solutions and so it turns out that if
you can't measure the data accurately
and it's hard to tell whether or not
something is truly malicious versus
abnormal it's very hard than to make
inferences beyond that not even a human
could potentially do it let alone a
machine learning algorithm so there are
some fundamental pitfalls in trying to
make machine learning work in the real
world and really the mole the story is
that actions themselves are not the same
thing as the intent behind those actions
we're trying to find out in our field is
the intent not the action and you've got
to town for that when we think about how
to build machine learning systems for
dealing with those problems now one or
talk about one final topic which is
you've worked on really great machine
learning system it looks great on paper
at some point you got to push it out to
a customer put it in the field we've got
to deploy models and people kind of
forget about this part right they think
that everything looks good but there's a
subtle aspect of DevOps its associated
machine learning and in fact this may be
a right area for this community to think
about is how do you actually think about
DevOps in a machine learning context
here's a great example okay machine
learning through these models that malls
got to be deployed so you need some way
to vet whether the model being deployed
is going to do a good job of course if
you had a way to tell whether the model
being deployed was going to do a good
job then it would be much easier to come
up with those models that's a challenge
coming up with a good model but it turns
out that there are situations in which
you can take a model that maybe
looks like an make sense and you start
with it but somehow you better figure
out whether that real model is going to
work in real life so for example let's
say that you're trying to find that you
I thought has happened in real life once
somebody I knew a friend to develop a
model for trying to detect malware and
they applied machine learning they use
the library and somehow the model picked
up on the fact that you could use to
compile time for the binaries to figure
out whether or not something is
malicious here's a hint that probably
won't work in real life that probably
work really well on this data set but
it's not that kind of thing that you
could apply in the real world now if you
just went ahead and blindly put that
actually actually did go ahead and blind
me for that model in real life that's a
different story but if you took a look
at the model and spend a moment looking
at it he would say well obviously the
compile time shouldn't be a critical
factor in determining what not something
is malware since I've got a model that's
really heavily dependent on the compile
time it's probably not the right model
it's a subtle point but you better find
a way to determine whether or not the
model makes sense is the model something
is going to do really well on your
training set which in that case it was
or do really poorly in real life and
more importantly let's say you do put
the model in the field at some point if
a customer support issue comes up the
person looking at that issue may not
have a PhD in machine learning they may
not understand the importance of maximum
margin separation or even oral networks
or any bad thing what they really care
about is hey how do I fix a customer
issue to do that they have to be able to
understand something about what was put
in place but if the model is so
complicated and hard to understand and
there's no context that's really really
hard to do so it's really important to
understand it from a support context
you've got to figure out how to deal
with machine learning and make things
work and by the way that thing I talked
about earlier about data then features
and model that's a good reason to pick a
simple model because you want something
that can be understood potentially by
someone who does not have machine
learning background in the field so
given all that I want to kind of quickly
summarize the key issues here we talked
about why I machine learning I think is
a very good tool for cyber security but
on the flip side does have a number of
caveats and pitfalls associated with it
and that there are some realities to
understand and you've got to be able to
figure out when the height fails to meet
the reality in terms of best practices
start off by making sure that you focus
on data first then features then
classifier
you're spending all your time looking at
the features and classifier to not the
data you're doing something wrong and
you're spending too much time creaking
parameters in your machine learning
library you're definitely doing
something wrong the second thing is you
have to know what success means it's not
just about having a high crew positive
and a low false positive you better
understand what that means in a specific
scenario to which it's being applied if
not all those metrics are created equal
and then we really dependent on the
scenario dealing with third don't set it
and forget it we're like Fred actors do
adapt right there trying to pay
attention to what you're doing
especially if you're big and they're
trying to figure out how to modify their
behaviors to get by them they're trying
to fly dress under the radar to
understand that you will and by the way
stuck that was a great example a lot of
antivirus vendors weren't calling things
that were digitally signed by class who
certificates malicious and so Fred
actors figure that out and they found a
way to compromise the class you
certificate and find something with it
they're trying to adapt their behaviors
you can't just set it and forget it then
finally you've got to think about how to
put those models in the field
successfully and realize that the person
putting it into the field may not be the
same person who developed it and
typically will not understand all the
nuances of what that model might mean
and so as you start to develop models in
machine learning you've got to think
about how to make the model may be
sufficiently simple or provide some of
the right context or explain ability so
someone can actually create an infield
issue so with that I think machine
learning has a lot of promise I don't
want to make it seem like it's all
negative but I want to make sure that we
provide a balance here because you can
go out to any vendor booth read a white
paper and get the positives of it
typical vendor won't tell you where it
might not work but at the same time
machine learning has been used for a
long time I guarantee that most of the
major cyber security vendors on the
planet have been doing it successfully
and moving the needle with it but I
think that you have to be careful with
the height versus the reality so with
that I want to try to get you guys back
on track for today's lunch and hope you
had a good time with the presentation
thank you all very much
[Applause]