hi Richard Greenberg here on the Old
West Los Angeles chapter president and
chair of the epic California 2017
conference i'm here with joy Stewart
from HP Enterprise fortify hello good
doing great to see we're sitting on the
veranda at the Annenberg beach house
Davies house and it is magnificent here
got the ocean on one side the mountains
on the other and a fantastic conference
behind us so we'd like to ask you a few
questions and see what he's got to say
Drake a lot of conferences now more and
more events popping up all over the
place what made you choose this one to
come and represent your company in order
to really converted all over the country
and if you want to get access to the
Southern California application security
community see is arrows practitioners
this is the place to be I mean we've
been coming to this conference for years
we have to justify it every year and
it's justified by the people that attend
the event by the attention you get on a
subject matter that is dear to us all
application security how do you like the
setup you get enough room on your table
is a convenient is it a nice atmosphere
down there it's a great atmosphere down
there I mean you get the standard table
which is great you can get a bigger
table if you want there's a few options
you guys make available to us but it's
great we get to have our our less space
you keep people in an area that they
have to come by and see us so we always
love that right they can't escape and in
our marketing people love it too because
we get a lot of leads you do a great job
of encouraging people to come around you
know whether it's getting a stamp
whether it's getting the giveaways
whether it's getting a chance to be in a
drawing I mean you guys do a great job
putting together a tight event that
doesn't have eight million people at it
where you're not even finding the people
you want right you notice a difference
in the the attitude of the people the
fact that they're at the beach for two
days it's definitely a friendly
environment right I mean look around you
how could you not have a better day
you'd rather be here than be at the
office or via the moscone center or
something like that this is a great
great great venue and last question you
find that your presence here in the past
is paid off with more leads and even
more business absolutely at the end of
the day in any business it's about
relationships it's about p
well knowing you and having the
confidence in working with you and we've
come this is at least our fourth or
fifth event over the last seven eight
years right it's in the last we've been
at two or three of them here at this
location and they're all great and when
you have that kind of repeatability you
know again people have that confidence
hey look you've got staying power those
people are still there they keep coming
back and support the same community I
mean it's been great good so we expect
to see here in 2018 we are going to be
back here in the Annenberg beach house
apset California 2018 is there going to
be the place for you to be so thank you
very much from sunny California
you