hi this is kaleb garnet abstract
California Hawass Southern California
annual event in santa monica we're here
with Scott Jensen and Google God how are
you fine thank you Scott you had another
presentation you're on the road a lot
you talk about a thing called the
physical web once you help our audience
learn a little bit about what that is if
they're not familiar yet the physical
web is a project on the chrome team to
allow the web to be used in the physical
world so we basically look for broadcast
URLs that you can see really easily on
your phone so you can kind of walk up
and use anything from a map to being
able to use a vending machine for
example and so I believe it one of the
strategies for your team is to help of
course along the way make sure that
everything is airtight as possible from
a security perspective and that was what
your presentation today was about yeah
exactly so it's all open source
everything that we do we have our own
github if you go to physical desk web
org you can get access to that and it
was part of why we came to this
conference we got a chance to present
what we're doing explain in detail what
we're trying to do and then have it
pressure tested have a lot of tough
questions and ways that we can improve
it so let's ask how that win did you get
those questions from the crowd that you
expected that tough ones I did get a lot
a lot of tough questions but they're all
good questions and i'm going to i'm
enjoying talking to people about it
afterwards and some good suggestions as
to how we can fix it so yeah it's really
worthwhile coming terrific so what do
you think is next for the physical web
what should people out there be looking
out for well the big thing that we're
doing right now is we're getting it into
chrome and Android both chrome and iOS
and chrome in physical and on Android
and Chrome on iOS but then the next step
is to we hope get other people involved
other scanners and so forth and that
will happen as the ecosystem slowly
grows so we're just trying to make that
happen as quickly as we can ok so I had
two quick questions for you Scott where
can people learn more about the physical
web go to our website physical desk web
org that explains everything it's our
github and get you started and my final
question for you is what your favorite
thing about apps at California and would
you recommend it oh I would absolutely
recommend it I think obviously it's a
beautiful location and I've really like
all good conferences they're only as
good as the people I just really enjoyed
the conversations I've had here
thank you Scott you're very welcome
you