hi everyone this is caleb squaring with
taps at california 2017 here in santa
monica i'm joined by neil matado Neil
how are you great fantastic though got
there who don't know Neil is one of the
founding fathers of apps at California
originally a maybe three or four years
ago here so it's great to have you back
you know you're at github security these
days and you came back to present tell
the audience if you don't mind a little
bit about your presentation my
presentation really just focuses on the
fact that securing a start-up is
fundamentally different in securing say
the enterprise really what you have to
focus on is prevention rather than
finding bugs or fixing bugs because
that's the only way you can scale a
small team as a company grows which way
it will grow faster than your security
team so there's a lot of very specific
technologies that you can put in place
early on there's a lot of specific
cultural things that you can emphasize
as people do their day-to-day work and
really you just shouldn't be doing
anything unless it can scale and so my
focus where my talk was about everything
I've learned over the past five years or
so working with two startups
specifically github and Twitter and
literally what worked and what didn't
work I did not try to come up with any
sort of comprehensive high level plan
that will work for everyone it was
specifically based on facts of what is
happened in the past right so you've
seen a lot of change in your startup
experience as well as here at ups at
California so have you seen this
conference change over time all right
well the first year was definitely a
little rough attendance was a little
light and I think there are fewer
conversations happening just because
there were less people but now I see a
good mix of all the familiar faces lots
of new faces certainly a more diverse
crowd which i think is the most
important part and because of that I
think more conversations are happening
what do you mean by more diverse what
wait well it's not a bunch of white
dudes anymore certainly we can do more
in that regard but the the amount of
women here the amount of people of color
has significantly grown from the first
year terrific okay so I know you always
have a lot of projects a lot of things
going on I understand you're working on
a conference a new
conference he tell us a little bit about
that sure when we first decided to do
apps at California we didn't really have
a coherent mission on what we all wanted
it to be and sort of the the interests
of the two groups might have split at
some point so the idea behind this
conference is to make it a single track
invite only so no CFP I'm sorry anyone
can attend what the speakers will be
invite only so I can get a very very
highly curated content sort of thing
unfortunately that means that a lot of
people might not get a chance to get
their feet wet and we understand that
this is a problem for a lot of people
and it's it's something that conferences
like this definitely give people a
chance to do but we wanted to get a
small number of people together who
really have a great chance of making
great changes for the Internet as a
whole in this short amount of time what
is that going to be you have a way
people can find out more and then I have
one more question for you after that yes
so it'll be April of 2018 you do not
have an exact date but we do have a
month in here it's going to be the loco
moco security conference which if anyone
is from if not familiar with the local
moco if it is a traditional Hawaiian
dish that is incredibly delicious we
have our twitter handle at loco loco sec
and loco moco sec calm is our website
it's barely just a place as at this
point but you can we sign up for our
twitter account in the newsletter to
keep updated grace last question for you
Neal is how would you suggest people
think about apps at cali is this like a
must do or is this like a great
conference for a season person newbie
work how would you put this on the
schedule for people who are thinking
about a conference to attend well I mean
honestly I feel like it's a conference
for everyone because Jessica absa Kali
is a great conference for everyone
because you're in silicon beach and
there are a lot of professionals in town
that are here just because of the
location you have a lot of professionals
who are here because it's on one of the
most beautiful beaches in the world and
a lot of the places around the country
right now are pretty cold there's
definitely talks that are beginner
friendly and there are talks that are
highly technical and perhaps very
high level but nobody's better than
anybody and you can see that in the
conversations that are happening between
the experts and the sort of newer people
or maybe even the people who are just
experts in other areas and are sort of
getting our feet wet so it's really a
conference for everyone thank very much
you