foreign
good afternoon everyone and uh
good evening if you're in the
Netherlands where I'm from Hello uh
thank you all for being here I'm excited
to get this talk going I realize it
might be a bit of a niche subject so
we'll start off a little bit different
with some trivia questions to see how
much you know about Google workspace or
if you even know what Google workspace
is
so the first thing is did you know that
Google workspace is not the same as
Google Cloud it's two different things
Google workspace is basically the SAS
offering of Google Cloud
it's a suite of productivity tools it's
basically like Microsoft 365 and Google
cloud is more like Azure so that's how
you should look at it
from a security perspective there's
actually some really interesting things
going on within Google workspace
um out of the book there's almost
time I counted 50 security rules that
you can
use to that are actually used to trigger
alerts and notifications about weird
stuff going on
but did you also know that most of this
security alerts do not generate an alert
even though they're really good so what
you can do is actually you can reroute
all your email your domain to a whole
different domain and won't trigger an
alert or you could simply make a user a
super admin and won't trigger an alert
the alerts are there but you have to
enable notification Etc
from an incident response and analyst
perspective there's something very nice
about Google workspace that you probably
heard yesterday in the Keynote you
cannot disable all that logging in
Google workspace it's there for you so
if you do IR as a consultant you can
just get into an environment and be like
can I have to go the audit log and it
won't be the story about Microsoft ready
like ah it wasn't enabled at the time so
you kind of stuck with that so that's
great that was Google workspace
introduction a little bit about myself
uh so my name is Christian Stone I'm
from the Netherlands as you may already
heard or not
um I started my career at nordway which
is a cyber security firm and then moved
to PWC did a lot of instant response
there I was lucky enough to lead an IR
team there which was great but at some
point I thought maybe I can do things a
little bit different or maybe even
better so then I started my own company
and it's called Invictus you might have
seen it because it's on every slide it's
on my shirt it's everywhere so that's my
company
I also really enjoy teaching
um and that's why I started teaching at
the University of applied sciences in
Amsterdam it's like a part-time job and
then I got the opportunity to work with
Sense on the cloud instant response
course so if you're doing five or nine
this week you might be seeing a lot more
of me
um so good luck and yeah this was enough
about me let's talk about the actual
research why I'm here and why we're
discussing this topic
so I mentioned I started at um I did a
lot of instant response at PWC and I
think because we were in accounting firm
we saw a lot of financial related
incidents and that's mostly business
email compromises so people getting into
an email environment doing all kinds of
shady stuff and then trying to get money
out of it so I don't know changing
invoices doing internal phishing Etc but
the ultimate goal was getting monetary
value out of your
attack so to say
um which is really cool for us and the
whole team at BWC and we created a lot
of Open Source projects which are
actually still around and super popular
uh so if you've ever do something with
Microsoft 365
um please check out the Microsoft 365
extractor it's basically gets all the
logs and if you have Splunk if you can
afford it I also created an app and it
will automatically analyze all the data
and together with the team we created
the BEC guide which is actually
that's something I'm really proud of
everyone that worked in it by the way
not just me because it's really good and
it helped a lot of
other instance responders around the
world responding to business email
compromises
oh this is all fine but there's nothing
to do with Google workspace uh the thing
is Google workspace is like the unknown
thingy there was not a lot of data
available in Google workspace who was
using it there was no research on
forensics nothing so I was like ah maybe
um I should write a little two or
something to get some to acquire for
instance all the audit logging which is
a nice start for your investigation of
course
um that was our original ID
and um I also work at the University of
Amsterdam and they're like do you have
some research IDs and yeah I did I was
like ah maybe we can do something with
Google workspace so but these students
need to uh prove that they're really
smart of course and need to prove a lot
of points so they were like ah can we
take it one step further and this is
sort of like the Holy Grail of I guess
doing instant responses can we maybe
automate analysis as well so we acquire
data and we also analyze it
automatically which is very dangerous I
know but we try to do it
um the reason is like analyst time and
instant respondus time is very valuable
and when you do instant response
um you need to get a lot of answers very
quick if you're in a case and there's a
lot of pressure so what can we do to
basically bring the analyst time down
that was the original ID so I worked
together with two very smart guys and I
want to give a proper shout out to them
betchaun on the left and Greg on the
right they would love to get some
followers or connection requests after
this uh talk so feel free to stalk them
at the really nice guys and they helped
a lot with this research and honestly
without them I probably wouldn't be here
with this talk so that's the background
so basically
what can we do on the Google workspace
and in terms of acquisition and also
automatic analysis
Google workspace I won't try to repeat
too much what the keynote was yesterday
so I only have a few slides on Google
workspace what it is and I guess the
forensic side of it
so as I mentioned is the commercial
Suite of products from Google so you
basically have Gmail meet calendar drive
but it's all like officially supported
you have more storage space etc etc and
if you have the right licenses you can
get a lot of security features as well
so that's what Google workspace is
there's no real recent data but
um
from what I've seen which is anecdotal
evidence
it's getting pretty popular of course
Microsoft 365 is by far the market
leader but after that I suspect Google
workspace is the number two but I don't
have that data because they don't
publish it
in Google workspace
um it's a SAS offering and as we've
learned yesterday in the keynote as well
if you have a sar Solution that's in the
cloud you basically rely on the cloud
provider to give you data
um and Google does that they have audit
logging available and audit logging is
separated into several What I Call Log
types so there's five main categories
such as admin group login o or SML
there's like the main categories of logs
and then there's server-specific events
so let's say you use the calendar to
make an appointment and someone accepts
that meeting that will be locked if you
have Google Drive and you change the
sharing settings or you send out an
external invite everything gets logged
um
it shouldn't come as a surprise but
Google is really good at logging and
they know so much so if you ever look at
these logs you'll be surprised at the
level of detail that's available in
these logs the good news is the
retention is six months at least so what
you can do which is a nice trick if you
also use Google Cloud you can forward a
log from Google workspace to Google
Cloud then you can configure the
retention period to go much longer which
is pretty nice with six months is
already really good I mean if you
haven't
I think I've most of the instance I did
were I think after six months they sort
of realized there was an incident so
yeah six months is pretty okay
so this is the thing I mentioned in
Google workspace the admin Center you
can simply say oh please send all my
logs also to Google Cloud which is if
you have both Google workspace and
Google Cloud I think it's it's pretty
good one I don't think it's very
expensive either so you should probably
do that
if you want to take a look at the logs
you can use the workspace admin Center
there's a little section in the
reporting that says auditing an
investigation and you have like a visual
interface where you can search for a
filter for admin events group events
everything that I just listed all the
record types you can simply
filter on those you can do some more
advanced filtering with Boolean
filtering and you can filter an IP you
can do all kinds of crazy stuff there
which is pretty okay for basic quick
investigation
and then you can export you can export
to Google Sheets and CSV nowadays so
that's pretty nice
um but not what we want this is an
example of the audit logging when we
export it out what we really want to do
is um build a tool give it to the world
and where everyone can just use the tool
to grab all the data from their client
or from their own environment and do the
magic with it so that's why we do not
just rely on the graphical interface of
Google and we go a step further
and now we come into the topic of Alpha
and what is alpha alpha stands for
automated ordered look forensic analysis
for Google workspace well Alpha has four
letters and I think there's a lot more
words there but we thought alpha sounds
a bit better so we stuck with Alpha
um what it is it's an open source tool
and it's available right now I think I
disabled or I cloned and made it
publicly available this morning so it
should be available for everyone to use
what it does it it can acquire all
Google workspace order logs and
the next step is of course the analysis
step is where the magic comes in it
leverages the my attack Cloud framework
to basically classify events so what it
does it grabs all the logs and then
tries to figure out based on a mapping
oh is this event related to I don't know
initial access to persistence or to
another phase of the Mitra framework and
then it
basically classifies that event
the next step is
using that classification you can
actually sort of automatically identify
interesting activity because you can as
a tool or as a as an analyst you can say
like oh there's a lot of interesting uh
or there's a lot of mapped events
because not every event can be mapped to
the miter framework of course but
there's a lot of mapped events with a
Mitra technique or ship technique in a
certain period of time so it might be
interesting
so let's let's start
we went a step further and we tried to
build something that identifies skill
chains I don't think guilt I think for
the purest Among Us kill changes maybe
the wrong word but what it basically
does it tries to identify a tech change
so where we based on the logging can we
identify and attack can we identify
multiple phases of an attack based on
the logging
um
and what I can also do is after it has
identified these interesting activities
or the kill chains it can export it out
so you end up with like all the logging
on one side so all the exported logging
which you can also
um use a separate file which is way
smaller with only the things that we
think as authors of alpha to be
interesting for you which is very
dangerous but I'm going to be
transparent about what it does so you
can make your own decisions uh on how to
use this
and use a super complex algorithms to
perform this magic this machine learning
AI now just kidding it's it's not very
complex uh I will explain everything in
this talk
um but it's it's good to know how it
works in the back end basically to do
this automated analysis
so
the first step is acquisition
um so how can we acquire this data
automatically and how can we get
everything this is
um how you set it all up
um
there's a specific API the reports API
that basically exposes this information
and there's two types of reports in the
API there's activity reports and users
reports as the name sort of suggests
activity
report is based on what kind of activity
did we record in a certain
category so in admin events or in Google
Drive events or in chat events whereas a
usage report is more like what did a
certain user do
um so made a decision to use the
activity API because within activity
report what I should say we use the
activity log from the report API because
you can still filter only use it there
so it's it's a no-brainer to go for this
one
um
if you want to use this in your client
environment or in your own environment
you need two things
you need something with Google workspace
you need basically a user that has the
um a custom row called reports
administrator or that basically you have
to attach a certain permission
um which falls on the repos
administrator and you can tie it to an
account or if you are going the easy
route you can just request the super
administrator account
um it's a bit more secure I would say
for an acquisition at your client to
just repressed I only need this so set
up a custom role for that
because we do something with um a
so-called oauth application to get the
logs and to authorize you also need
something in the Google Cloud
um
what you what you need to do is you need
to create a Google Cloud project
and within that project you need to
enable a certain API so the admin SDK
API basically and you need to register
an oauth application the oauth
application what it does is basically
it's you can give it a certain
set of you can give it a scope saying
basically oh this application can look
at this API and an oauth will try to
perform authentication and authorization
on your behalf and then you as a user as
someone with the role repos
administrator needs to approve that
action
um I made it visually so it's it's a bit
more clear maybe maybe yes maybe it's a
bit more clear in the next slide but
this is also how most of the clouds
nowadays work if you want to grab logs
from apis you need to use an oauth
application
um so yeah so we can interact with the
API to get the data and we'll use an
oauth application especially four steps
so you can create a new gcp project this
is optional but I suggest if you do
acquisition often or frequently and that
you always have a separate project at
the client side because it's easy to
track
course and permissions and you can
easily also shoot it down afterwards
within this project enable the API
and then register an oauth application
this is really straightforward it's just
critically click give it a name and in
the end you will end up with a
credentials file and this is really
important because the credentials fell
will be used in Alpha to perform the
right calls and to ask for the right
permissions
because this is very common like this
building an old application is is being
used on Microsoft Google probably also
in AWS
the instructions are very clear and very
well documented what I've done is I've
made a description on GitHub if you
click on this link you'll find it
um and there's also a whole YouTube
video where I just go through each of
the steps and I do it really slowly and
you should be able to just follow that
and then you're good to go so even
though this may sound a bit don't think
it's it's actually pretty
straightforward uh most important thing
you need to remember is at the end of
this phase you will have a Json fell
that you'll need to use with Alpha
so using Alpha it has three modes Alpha
acquire well it acquires all the loads
Alpha analyze it acquires and analyzes
the log so it tries to identify
interesting activity
and Alpha loads and you can use this if
you already have previously acquired the
logs and you just want to use the
analysis functionality of the tool
to use the two
simply download it from GitHub and then
you can run you can use pip to install
it so go to the folder in this command
and it will install it
then you need to initialize it and this
may might may be a bit different to
other open source projects but we
thought it was a good idea to use
initialization for each project because
let's say you are a consultant or you're
doing more projects
you may want to tune Alpha to a certain
environment so you might want to change
some variables and with initialization
what it does it is it automatically
creates a project folder and within the
project photo there will be a config
file that will be unique to the specific
project so you can do all your tuning
there without actually changing the main
product
so you need to run Alpha in it and then
a project name you can decide what the
project name is it automatically creates
a folder structure for the logs and for
the configuration in the configuration
directory you throw in your credentials
file that you have from the previous
steps and you're good to go
so what can you do in terms of
acquisition you can just be like oh give
me everything Alpha acquire you can say
oh I only want to have the admin related
activities or I only want to have the
user login activities or only the drive
activities and then you have to use dash
dash log type equals the thing you want
and as I mentioned you can also simply
filter on users so let's say you could
call it into an incident or you suspect
something is going on with a certain
user you can simply also just collect
that user's audit logs
last but not least you can also acquire
based on a time frame so let's say most
of the instance you have an ID on when
it happened so then you can simply
select a time frame
I think I made a video about this yeah I
did
um
as you can see I don't know yeah it's
pretty pretty good
um I'm now inside a project that I
created so I initialized a project
called sense project and automatically I
already added the credentials file so
now I can just ruin it
what will happen is if I run it it will
do the authorization with award
um so it will open up a browser and
it'll say please log in with an account
that has the right permissions
it's pretty quick but basically this was
successful
and now it shows you all the logs At the
quiet per log tile because I said grab
everything
and in the end you can still see it on
this as a screenshot you will have a
little bit of you have 9 9.5 K activity
saved to a data folder and this video
was not fast forward or something so
within I think 20-30 seconds we actually
managed to get almost 10K events so it's
really quick so yeah I should probably
use this over an API export like a GUI
export or something
just because it's really fast so what
happens next is
as I mentioned the initial
initialization of the project results in
an in a data folder and a data folder
contains the acquired logs and what
Alpha does it it automatically creates a
folder with the UTC date and time of the
acquisition so to automatically you can
always go back and be like ah when was
this acquisition you can just look at
the folder name and you also never end
up with duplicate entries or something
so here you'll see I think it's around
20 different log types that have been
acquired you will also see a few that
actually are really small and it
actually means that they are empty so
they're 18 kilobytes and the new version
that's actually released now it won't
acquire empty log so it will only grab
logs when there's data there so it's
pretty nice
so now
um
yeah you basically have a decision to
make you can either say well this is
nice
um I can use this tool to acquire all
the data and then I can run off to my
own seam or my own data nurse platform
or whatever you would like to use and
stop but I would love for everyone to
come along with the Journey of analysis
and this is the second mode of alpha
this is the analyze mode
the way it works is and this is
basically where I'm explaining the magic
it's not not that magical but it's
pretty cool we use the micro attack
Cloud framework it's a collection for
the people that don't know
it's a collection of techniques that
have been observed by threat actors
um to be abused basically so let's say
under
um the privilege escalation
phase there's a technique called valid
accounts and
basically what happened is is that
certain threat actors use this tactic or
this technique against a technology in
this case it's Google workspace to abuse
it
um so what we do
is
we take the original event that's on the
left hand side and I've made a little
red box around it so the original event
is around the creation of a user and
I've blurt out some details it's
probably my own home IP
um so this is the create user event so
this is the type of event what we do on
the right hand side is we've made a
mapping
and the mapping is made towards the
Mitra technique or ship technique
so what you see is on the right hand
side you'll see that this specific event
belongs to the persistence phase
and then to the create account technique
and into the shift technique cloud
account so that's basically the
structure of the event
and the link is there for the specific
one if you look a little bit further
down this download report this is a
Google event
and this belongs to what we think the
collection phase of Mitra and into the
technique data from information
repositories so this is how we have
defined what original Google workspace
order logs
um yeah basically are in terms of
activity so really important to remember
this fell as part of of course the tool
you can modify it you can update it but
this is what we have decided to be the
case
and you can make suggestions if you
don't agree by the way
um in the next step what we do is
we take it original event that's mapped
we give it a score based on the
associated miter phase so here you will
have the different phases from Mitra
um so this previous event was related to
persistency so that event will get the
score of one because it occurs in the
first phase according to us
and the next thing it will do is
it will create basically a running score
where it compares
the score of this event so the let's
take this example of a persistency so we
have a score of one
and then we'll compare it with the next
event and if the next event has a higher
score based on the micro Attack Phase
that occurs in
well oop the running score with one if
it doesn't follow the major attack flow
basically so from persistence towards
collection will subtract one so the
running score will be minus one
this allows us to generate what we call
a kill change statistic and this is
basically where we have a number of
events so at least five
that have occurred where we do this
comparison so we check event one or
event two is in a later phase in the
monitor framework so the running score
is updated event 3 is also updated so
let's say we have five events that
follow the Mitra attack chain the
running score will be five because every
time the next event
follows the mitral attack flow
okay and then we divide that number by
the number of events so we have five
events that follow the chain and we have
five total events now what happens if
you divide five by five we'll end up
with one so the kill change statistic is
one what does one mean it's the perfect
kill chain it will never happen only if
you have a fabricated data set of course
um but that means that each event
um yeah basically follows the miter
attack framework which never happens you
could also have minus one which is a
reverse skill chain where an event
basically goes backwards so you have
five events or ten events that each time
go back in the Mito attack
framework flow so you will have an event
electoral movement followed by an event
in Prudential access for instance and
Then followed by one in previous
escalation highly unlikely if you have a
score that's close to zero
that represents basically random events
so yeah that's
maybe more common because you will have
in a normal data set you expect there to
be normal user activity maybe better
maybe bad or suspicious activity
followed by normal activity so this is
what the tool tries to do it tries to
identify Blobs of data so to say that
that contain interesting activity
step seven
for each chain of events so
um
it will generate the kill chain
statistic and if it's higher than 0.6
it will be available for export so then
we what we can do is with one command
and I'll show you it automatically
exports all these ship chains to a
separate fell so in that separate file
you should only have
events in an ideal world that are
interesting and this is a very important
point that I want to make
we are not in the business of saying
something is malicious we are basically
pointing out based on audit logging
and our knowledge of incidents and what
we think is important we come up with a
bunch of interesting events but it's up
to you to the analyst to the instant
responder to actually determine is this
malicious because
if we follow the steps of Mitra it can
also be that a normal administrator
creates a user adds that you should do a
certain group
does some more legit activity which
actually follows all the miter steps so
what we do is we'll give you interesting
events but they're not necessarily
malicious events so that's where you are
coming to Define that that's why they
pay us
um the analyze function and the commands
you can use so what you do if you run
Alpha analyze it will drop you in a
shell and you can do all these things
that I just showed you what you can do
is you can run a.kcs which stands for
kill change statistic and you can run it
on the whole data set or a subset of the
data and it will calculate the kill
chain statistic so it'll give you the
number whatever that is
you can run the a DOT ship chains
command which will automatically show
you
all the identified chains with a value
higher than 0.6
and what you can do within the tool as
well is basically get a summary of the
events within a certain slice of the
data so let's say we have a ship chain
that consists of event one to eight we
can use the summary command with one
semicolon 8 and we get a summary of the
events
which is nice but I'll show you what it
looks like
last but not least you can export out
these activities for further analysis so
what does it look like
um so you have to separate anything
that's belonged to seven and eight so in
seven what we do is we call a DOT ship
chains and it tells us that it found
three strip chains in this data set
and one ship chain for instance has a
score of 0.9 which is very high and
there's not a shift chain that starts at
event 75 until 85 as a ship chain of
score of 0.65 so it might also be
interesting
with the summary command we can see what
type of data is in there and this will
give you basic information like what the
type of event it is so in this example
it says change user access changes ACL
and the end it's basically saying oh
let's configure emo forwarding
which is very interesting so using this
method
we hope to give you
some pointers as to what is interesting
in a data set of Google workspace audit
logs
you can also use load but it's uh you
know as I mentioned is the same which
you can just use previously acquired
data what I really want to show you is
actually
is this any useful or is this yeah is
this useful at all because we've created
this and we've tested this but the talk
was about detecting malicious actors so
what do malicious actors do well they
attack your Google workspace environment
how do they do it in a few ways that
I've chosen I've simulated in for this
test
I've did three attacks a business email
compromise attack
um so getting your email environment to
fishing or through League passwords set
up forwarding rules perform data
exfiltration change invoices for
instance
Attack 2 is a malicious application this
is more like a solarwinds type incident
where you set up an application and you
gave it a lot of permissions and then
you send
um what you can do in oauth you can
generate a URL that authorizes that
application to perform this activity so
let's say you create an application with
a lot of permissions you can then send a
link to a user and when the user clicks
on a link it shows you oh this
application wants to access your data
wants to access your email it wants to
send email your behalf etc etc so this
is the thing that threat actors also
abused in the past and they still do
attack three is what I call apt style so
do some reconing your environment and
then try to steal important data so I've
simulated all these attacks
and the good news is that the data set
that this is all is based on is also
publicly available and I'll I'll share
the link later where you can basically
do your own analysis based on this data
which is pretty cool I think
um
so Attack One the BEC one what I did is
basically four steps and then I uh below
each step I I added a Mitra Attack Phase
that it belongs to
so forwarding rule relates to
persistency
um performing email log searches relates
to the collection phase of maitra so
this is a very controlled experiment in
my environment in my Google workspace
test environment so what I did is I
performed all these steps and then went
away for a few hours because it might
take some time for all the logs to end
up in there and then I counted all the
events that are related to this attack
and then I run Alpha against it to see
if it could find it and if it would
generate a kill change statistic so in
this case it did
um so there are 47 events generated
because of this attack and the kill
change statistic associated with it was
0.9 so there's a very high probability
that if you were to use Alpha that you
would have seen this and that you would
have investigated it further this is
good news but I want to be honest the
next attack not so much the malicious
app is very difficult
um to detect I would say based on the
logging in in a Google workspace
environment for a few reasons so what
you do is you register an oauth
application but you do that outside of
Google workspace so there will be no
record in Google workspace audit logging
about this
when you send a link to an email or you
send an email with a link asking for
permissions there will be no record in
the audit log that there was an email
basically sent yeah there will be if you
go here search through everyone's emails
you will find that email but there will
be no audit record that a link was
received for instance what you will see
is if someone approves clicks on the
link and approves it then it will be
registered in the Google workspace audit
log because then it will say like this
application was given permissions by
user X and then what will also be
registered is if that application starts
doing stuff on behalf of you so that
will also be registered
this attack
um
as I mentioned it generated a few logs
14 in total but most of them being the
application requesting permission or
basically the application authorizing on
your behalf Alpha was not able to find
or at least to identify this with the
kill change statistic method so yeah
this wasn't successful for this specific
attack
um Attack 3 the APT style so we log in
and what we're going to do is we use
something in a Google workspace where
you can what you can do is pretty useful
you can get an export of all users and
their roles just in the environment you
can click export users and roles it'll
give you a CSV with everyone in there
pretty useful but it's also locked so
it's really good for us what you can
also then do is perform exfiltration
what I did was performing exfiltration
of emails so in Google you have
something called email log search where
you can simply search for emails based
on sender recipient Etc it's a bit like
e-discovery but not really the
full-fledged e-discovery Suite in Google
and I also did a Google takeout
um
for the people that don't know Google
takeout is pretty powerful where you
basically say give me everything Google
you have on this account
from a from a threat active perspective
it's pretty useful because you can then
basically inspect the data see if you
can either extort them blackmail them or
maybe use that data to perform a second
attack on other websites they are
registered to so pretty useful so I
perform these activities and luckily
this was detected by Alpha with a score
of 0.65 and even though there were only
seven events generated in the audit log
so I was pretty happy with that
this leads to the conclusion so
out of the three attacks
um two were detected I would say so it's
pretty good
um
still I think what's very important is
um what we do is we say in the tool
itself there's a config file where you
say oh we
an attack gets detected if it generates
at least five or seven events you can
change that value so if you set that to
really low you will have way more ship
chains but you might also get generate
way more noise in the other hand if you
want to say I only want it to
generate a kill change statistic if it
has at least 10 events you might miss a
lot of stuff so that's what I mean with
tuning
you might still need to tune it to your
environment in my environment as I
mentioned it's my environment so I have
it in the control it's okay with the
current settings
um but what it really needs and this is
the area of improvement is larger data
sets and environments so if you have
Google workspace uh please give it a try
or if you have a client that you've done
the investigation for and you still have
the logs please load them in and test
them more attacks there are definitely
more attacks against Google workspace
that can be tested
um and when I started I mentioned event
mapping so what I what we did was
basically grab all events from the order
log and try to map it to the miter
phases well what if my miter decides to
add more techniques we need to do redo
the mapping or what if Google adds
additional logging we need to add that
mapping in so these are areas of
improvement and I think it's continuous
the most important slide is coming up
right now
and this is the too long didn't listen
slide
um just for everyone that was doing
other stuff uh if you read this you
should be up to speed a little bit on
this presentation
um
so I think Google workspace is relevant
uh because it's an entry part just like
Microsoft 365 email is often an entry
point for serious attacks so it's and
Google workspace is going to grow
because Google is behind it they're
going to invest in it and it will be
around for years it might change the
name again and again but it will still
be there
um
audit logging is on super important
Alpha is a tool that we developed and
it's available for free and I hope you
want to try it
and I would really appreciate your
feedback uh because we've developed this
in our little uh Echo chamber where
there might be other environments that
this skills very well to or maybe not so
please let me know
so if you want to help as I mentioned
the tool is on yeah the top link so
that's on our GitHub and the second link
is to the data set so I did all these
attacks I performed them and then I made
an export there's some very weird data
in it like because yeah I just needed to
come up with stuff and made a little bit
of a yeah all kinds of weird stuff but
I'll leave you to it
um I think I removed all IPS belonging
to me or other people that worked on the
project but if you find a one IP from
someone in the Netherlands please don't
those it that's my address probably
um there's also a YouTube link and this
is if you want to set it up you can just
follow this link and then I will show
you exactly how to do it and actually I
think in two minutes or maybe right now
there will be a post upon medium
on this link that will give you sort of
what I talked about today in a more text
format where you can just simply follow
all the steps and I will show you how to
use this tool with examples
etc etc
so please go there and check it out
we're almost there I have a challenge
for you
um it's pretty difficult to see for the
people online but who in this room uses
LinkedIn
that's pretty good well I had a goal at
the beginning of the year to have
thousands followers on LinkedIn because
I post a lot of stuff there
um I think I'm at 990 or something so I
hope at least 10 people online are here
can just click follow and then yeah I'll
have that go across stuff for this year
so please go ahead if you use LinkedIn I
won't do any sales purchase there but
I'll just post hopefully cool content
there so this is what the what the site
looks like
um I think we're the only one with this
specific name so should be easy to find
um
and then I'll open up the floor for the
next part of the challenge
um if you like this shirt or the white
version of it
um you can win one if you have a
question for me and I like the question
the best question you get a t-shirt it
doesn't matter I have small medium large
extra large everyone can have a t-shirt
that has a good question for the people
online you can still ask the question
but if Phil says it and I really like it
Phil gets a t-shirt so or Heather so uh
yeah this was what I wanted to share
with you and foreign
[Music]