Léonard Salina
certifat ispart of Annecy
Annecy stansfort sculpman French
the National Agency for the Security of
Information Systems witches of French
national Cyber ​​Security Center
of some effect
timeline
to buy script or get the
modification that o curd in direct active
this virtual  stord machine in nuts to
call data store datastore
hypervisor in console management
hypervisor ais XI
eternal owner witches vienna code
kernel we don't own
in service call DC
whyut direct control direct console
Access
second reason isat offend
except I understand corn of nactif direct
Center  Mike Lee to the
hypervisor Center witch willso Lee to
the compromise of all the virtual
machine running on the hypervisor
ou investigate vicef du
développement
PowerShell module thatwin el pue
gazer some forestic artifax on vise sphere
this module use the power ciel i module
from the mware witches  the PowerShell
module this view manage viewer
infrastructure
it  composes everything works the
firstone is codes start vs investigation
function that wheel a general colleague
information related to the hyper bizarre
attache to the beastunters
pernician and mosting porteri itwill
collect and the vis Center what we got
the VIP the via Evans a the visfair
happy bizarre
[Music]
Linux distribution
of the module is the stars
information
the hypervisor ultarget en canalso
generate support bundles for hitch
hypervisor
the parameter lightvie Evans for example
not their off the works will alway
YouTube collect only event techsidy that
we Candy of interestive
loca loca Delta configuration  meaning
the different between the
configuration after the installation of
the hypervisor we say configure
[Music]
virtual machine at the stadium on the
hypervisor interesting because hardware
changis thatware
for example
the
possibilities
for example Louise plaque un because and
Jason Ford in Jason formats pretty
straight
[Music  ]  not
etwork fire house setup machine
SOS
actors it is noted noucing number
blockpost
classic scenario
inform attacker
[Music]
strike to there is this compromise
Windows admin machine and the windows 40
[Music]
joy
the virtual machine that resident and
the
[Music  ]
BM in order to remove the right is
setup on the virtual
at risk
[Music]
Windows Workstation
spot the sside
[Music]
virtual machine
data data
[Music]
console an order to connect to that
machine
experience in itwig generated Logan
concludede  in order to persist in
performes lateral movement
we don't Windows we will irmment an attacker
Ken do it compromising vicef in note
using a single My where running on the
windows operative
via remote access tool installode on
Linux Server remote access tool
astonelling capable it's and it's  is wise
all Agathe hypervisor Wister
virtual machine zata Austen Enzo
supervisor once again
Windows machine this at the stage here is
suspense
capability or analysis vmss in extract of
credenzahal from the moon
performe station operation of heaps of
life indicated from the virtual machine
in the other Pax Delta formicito
[Music]
succession and SSH connection with Odyssey
attackers
[Music]
[  Music]
tout finish I will
connect to the second hypervisor
an order to pote persistence witches in
fact the time ishel beacon to the
seconds
of sidection
tout conclude
à Olivier view some leats out ou secure
empirement
[Music]
peecenter
management network for vicef
administration this not normal to be
able to S7 on hypervisor from anywhere
union network
[Music]