Rob Lee:
Honestly, there was a discussion
last night about Eric Kristensen's in the back
back here and he was making fun of me because
he was telling a story not two nights ago, well
actually, yeah, it was two nights ago. Rob pretty
much called me and told me to get into a car to
drive down. And it wasn't like a telling thing, it
was like he ordered me to get into a car because
he didn't want me to drive at 4:00 AM to come down
to the summits because last night's going to be
a really late night. And the way he worded it
was almost just like how I told Phil to get into
this job, it's like, "Shut up and come over," to
where we were working at that point in time.
All right, let me see if I can get over to the
slides. Oh, there we are. So this talk kind
of morphed from a very similar, Rob, and I'm
looking a Viv here in the front row who also
didn't really ask me to do the talk, it was a,
"You will do this talk. You've never
spoken at your event in the 15 years that
you've run this summit and ever since we handed
it over to Heather and Phil." I always find
it weird to give a talk at the summit. So since
it's been Heather and Phil's event over the
past three years, Viv said, "Hey, what a better
opportunity to now have you talk since it's no
longer your event?" I was like, "Oh great." And I
really appreciate the invite and happy to be here.
This graphic, and again, the DFIR
Godfather, I have to admit a little bit of
a failure on my part over the years, I'm a big
movie buff, but I had not seen The Godfather
ever. I know. During COVID I had to rectify this
issue. One of my good friends, Kate Marshall,
made fun of me pretty hardcore because she did
this graphic, and I told her, I said, "Admittedly,
I'd never seen the godfather." I said, "I kind
of get the reference, but..." She said you need
to correct this right now. Within weeks I watched
it. I said, "Oh, this is a really good movie." She
said, "Don't watch Godfather II, watch Godfather
I and II and you're pretty much done." I'm like,
"All right." I did that. So Francis Ford Coppola,
amazing filmmaker. Also, which I later found out
watching this series on Disney+, Light & Magic,
how the close relationship between George Lucas
and Francis Ford Coppola, they developed their
own studio, they had a really close relationship,
and I say, how did I not know all these years
about this being the big Star Wars fan that I am?
So this presentation, everyone's really
wanting to know, especially if you're brand new
to digital forensics is like, how do you get your
start? A lot of people come up to me. They say,
"Rob, how do I beat you?" And I said,
well, first of all, you need to laugh.
And I said, that's really hard to replicate. I
need to trademark it. Jennifer Santiago, who's
one of the summit... She literally has this radar
thing, it's like, where's Rob? She texted me,
she said, "Where's Rob?" And I laughed and she
said, "Found you." She opens up at the door and
just points at me. But my laugh, you have to have
a laugh, but no, that's really not what this is
about. She's like, how to become someone to start
in forensics? How do I start in cybersecurity?
How do I get my first two steps into the field?
So instead of doing a 50 minute talk on this,
I'm going to start off with the answer
to this question. How do you do this?
How do you get your start? Everyone know
what the term BLUF is? This is the basic way,
your first letter of success in any email
exchange is, do the bottom line up front.
Instead of writing a very lengthy email, you
always do the bottom line up front. The three
secrets of success in DFIR. Everyone ready?
This is it. This is going to be the 10 minute
presentation, boom, right here.
So number one,
never stop learning. And again, for anyone who's
new here, anyone who's been doing this for 20
years, from Heather to Phil to anyone, from Brian
Carrier to anyone who is a NASA scientist planning
on the Mars missions, Elon Musk, I guarantee every
single individual who's out there that you think
that they're an expert in the field, I guarantee
that every day they wake up and they're listening
to podcasts, they're reading books, they
are consistently learning something new.
They're filling their lives with knowledge
constantly, not only in digital forensics,
not only in cyber security. It is constant
absorption of data in some form or another.
And I think a lot of you already know this, but
again for those who are new, you may not know
this. You've probably saying, "Hey, I didn't
really realize that those who are at the top
of their field are just like those who are new in
their field, because for me, I'm looking at things
that, I said I've always wanted to learn how to
play the piano. I'm currently renting a house
in the Denver area. I just moved to Denver a
year ago and I somehow landed this amazing home,
which is basically an Airbnb for a year. It's
not an Airbnb, but the owners left to Sweden and
basically left all their furniture in it, which is
great because I don't have to buy any furniture,
especially with the supply chain stuff that's
going on right now, and there's a piano in the
middle of it. I said, "No, maybe now's the time.
There's this piano sitting here. I should look up
some classes or maybe hire an instructor.
There's a bunch of electronic apps."
And of course, now that I say this, I guarantee
two to three of you who've learned in the past
couple years are going to come up and advise
me on this. And this is also something else
that when you learn, you find out there's
a community out there of also self learners
who have taught themselves or who have taken
classes on these things that was like, "Here's
how I learn." And this is one of the things that's
great about it is that, okay, I'm now a learner,
first-time individual going out there and learning
how to play the piano. So how do you do that?
But also the second piece of this is also
very important as you're learning, be curious,
not confident. Anyone who is an expert in their
field will tell you that the more that you learn,
the more that you learn what you don't
know. Any expert in the field will always be
aware of what they don't know
more of what they do know.
Sarah Edwards is good example of this, the Apple
architecture, the Apple devices, the Apple stuff
that she works on on a daily basis is so complex
that if you throw her anything that is a new
question at her, she will fully admit to you,
she's like, "Well, I honestly don't know that."
You would look at her, she's like, "Well, you're
the expert on this. How do you not know this?"
Where someone growing up in the field is like,
"Well, I'm supposed to be the expert." Just
you're going to throw down or say, "Well, this
is what's written in the book. This is of course
what you're supposed to know." And we draw this
line, but an expert in the field will always say,
"Well, even though the book is written this way,
it may be wrong," or, "I did this research before,
I might be wrong." Or maybe the standard has
changed. It's always be curious, not confident in
anything that you're doing.
Second thing to look at here,
again in the bottom line up front here,
is be kind in anything that you're doing.
It's just a general approach out there.
I've seen a lot of people in this field,
anyone who runs around with a big chip on their
shoulders and is not kind to others, I've never
seen them succeed in this field ever. It is just
a natural tendency that you could point these
individuals out and anyone who's out there who
is not kind to others while they're learning and
while they are trying to explore, and this is one
thing that I love about this community in general,
and you don't see it across all the other
communities that exist in cybersecurity
is that this community in particular has
a habit of welcoming those who are new.
And I'm not going to point out other communities
that I have an opinion of that they're much more,
they have a defensive wall around it that you
have to prove yourself to get into it and if you
don't prove yourself, they troll you a little
bit until you get to the point where you could
get in and then you're allowed in to hang
with those with leather jackets and the T-bird
motorcycle gang on the back.
In the forensics community, you could go
to Recess Arcade and someone says, "I'm brand new.
I don't know what the heck I'm doing." It's like,
"Oh, come on in. Let's go do Jenga together. I
don't know what I'm doing either, but I've been
doing it for 10 years." It's amazing and that's
the thing that across the board that I would love
to tear down those walls in the other communities
with this be kind message, which is, we're all new
and we're all new all the time. Be kind.
The third one, the best, and everyone you think
is the best, and you know who we are, because some
of you say, "Well, I think they're all clique-ish,
they're all hanging out together." You kind of
have this fanboy, fangirl approach to some of us.
The best are not as good as you think they are.
We're human. We're your peers. We are actually
your peers in most of this stuff. Come up to
us and if you actually treat us like your peer,
we actually will treat you as your peer too. Most
of us are 100% human beings in all of this stuff
and most of the things that, if you start doing
your research and you start asking questions,
we're sitting down having a drink with you and
all of a sudden a year from now you're like, "Wow,
I don't how it happened but I'm friends with
Brian Moran. I'm hanging out with this dude."
And all of a sudden, everyone's like, "What?"
This is why this community works, in forensics, in
cybersecurity is that as soon as you stop thinking
that the best are somehow segmented
off, the best are just human beings,
just gave a talk at some point. So everyone out
there thinks you can't be on the stage within a
year, you're wrong. You could come do a little
bit of research and all of a sudden you're up
on the stage thinking about things.
All right. So that's the BLUF,
that's the secret. How do you do what you do?
It's those three things. Now, I'm going to take a
step back in time and talk about how did I get to
those three things and take a little bit expanded
view in the TL;DR for this stuff as well.
So the TL;DR and a little bit about my origin
story, which is again, if you read the background
to who I am and how I got to be here a little bit
is, again, this conference, the summit in
general, 15 years, again now I feel really old,
15 years. I remember when I went to my 10 year
high school reunion and I was like, "Wow, I am
fricking old at my 10 year high school reunion."
And now I've been at this event for 15 years
in a row and I look at the pictures back
then. I was like, "Man, I was hot back then."
And now I'm like, what the hell happened? I
know, things go downhill quick, but do I feel
any smarter 15 years later? Absolutely not. Do
I feel that somehow I have some more technical
prowess than I did 15 years ago? No, things have
rapidly changed. I am still the same individual,
maybe in terms of what I'm doing, my passions
have changed, the people I'm hanging out with,
by and large in some cases, some of them
are the same group, some of them have
changed over the years, the group has expanded.
But some of the things that I'm going to tell you
here are some of the core truths that have hung
with me over the years. What I'm doing though
has changed and what I'm doing at SANS has changed
over the years too. So some of these core truths
in terms of what makes me an individual and
what I'm going to tie into some of the themes of
why I'm going to impart some of these lessons to
those who are new to the cybersecurity field here
also ring true because things are not as easy
as you think they are when you're just starting
out. I've had a couple conversations with my
son and my daughter and those who are also
just starting out. And one of these
conversations that I've had most recently,
a lot of people get on my case about this is,
should people go to college? This is one of those.
My son's like, "What should I major in college?"
I'm like, "Dude, you're 10." I'm like, "This is
not something you need to worry about right now."
My daughter has no interest in this. Right now,
she's just like, "Okay, I want to play Roblox."
I'm like, "Okay, cool." She's going to major in
Roblox and do very well at this. But my son
is like, "How do you know what you want to be
when you grow up?" And I said, "Honestly, you
don't. What you need to do right now is focus
in on the things that make you happy, the
things that you find your passion," this
is going to be a theme out there that you're
going to focus in on. But I also started to
tell them. I said, "But you also need to take a
look at things that you sign up for, you should
commit yourself to completing those things. If
you sign up for soccer, you should go to the
practices, you should go to the games, we should
complete the season. And at the end of the season,
you should make a decision at that point whether
or not you're going to do the next season."
And I know some of the times you're waking up in
the morning, it's hard. You're like, "Oh, it's
early morning game." Hockey practice, especially
if you're a hockey dad, you're getting up, some of
those games are really early in the morning. And
of course, trying to drag your son or daughter out
of bed at those times is not fun and they don't
want to do it. I said, "You made a commitment to
this." And this goes back to this thing here,
where, when I was in high school, there was
a lesson I learned, this ties in to where it's
going to be for you as well, one of the things I
am going to recommend here is that when you
commit to something, you have to carry it through.
And this is like, if you start to learn something,
at least get to a point of self mastery for this.
For my story is the heart side. For anyone who
started Boy Scouts, the Life Scout emblem is
the heart. Is anyone familiar with Boy Scouts?
It is the heart symbol is the Life Scout. And I
was two requirements away from becoming an Eagle
Scout, just two, and high school hit and life hit
and I basically stopped. A lot of reasons why I
looked back at it, but it was one of those things
that I went back and I looked, I have my book
still from the Boy Scouts and I thumbed through
it and I look at those two requirements and they
were super easy, maybe two weeks' worth of time.
That's it and then a board to get my Eagle Scout.
To this day, you sit there, everyone has this no
regrets thing in life, but this is
a regret of mine. And what's that?
Speaker 2:
[inaudible 00:16:17].
Rob Lee:
I don't think so. 18. I could do it mentally,
I've got my Eagle Scout, but you got to get it
done by 18. I got my Eagle Scout, but again,
it's like can't do it. It's like you have to do it
by 18. And so as a result of that, I sit there and
look at that, I was like, "Man, I should have
done it. Why didn't I do it?" Life gets in the
way of these things and I should have followed
through. It's that follow through that sometimes
is that lesson that we have to take a look at
when we're walking through life at this point.
So, around that point in time, and around the
point, 18 happened, I looked back and I said,
"Oh, I should have done it." That was
that regret that set in at that point.
And I made a decision at that point saying,
"Okay, that's not going to happen again.
When I commit to something, I'm going to try
and finish, at least get the follow through,
and then look back and make a decision." For
a lot of people that know me, this has become
either a curse or a blessing is that I will
stick with something to the end and then make
a decision whether or not I'm going to either cut
or continue. Cut or continue and whether or not...
And again, anything is hard in life, this is again
whether you're working out, a lot of people who've
been with me a while, I actually call this thing
when you're just starting to run and work out,
and for anyone who's known me for many years,
I used to be really big and when you're first
running, you have this thing that hits you
that says, "You should stop running now."
And your mind is telling stop, run, stop, run,
stop, run, stop, run, stop, run, until all of a
sudden you get through it and all of a sudden your
mind is like, "Okay, this is actually okay." And
now you could run for about 30, 40, 50 minutes and
then you could actually run even longer than that.
A lot of people call this the shit
shift, excuse my language, but
that's actually a term, you can Google it.
Getting through that shit shift
is a very interesting point in not just working
out and running, but that shit shift occurs in
many different locations in learning in your
jobs, in personal relationships across the board,
that there's an uncomfortable
hill and hump you need to get over
to where you get to comfort again. And that's
where a lot of people, where you get stuck,
ends up being. It's like, are you going
to quit or continue? And that's where
that comes in. It's like, are you
going to be able to get over that hump?
And so this is where, for me, I always tell
people who are just starting out saying,
"Don't forget how important it is to get through
that initial hump," because if you don't,
there's always going to be this look
back and saying, "Did I quit too early?
Or did I not have the follow through?" And that's
what I'm trying to tell my son and my kids. It's
like, if you sign up for something, you have to
commit to it through the end of the season, then
you can make a decision on whether you're going to
do it for next season or not. And I'm like, okay,
at that point we can make the call,
not until. Maybe I'm just a mean dad.
I don't know. But at that point we'll make a call.
Now school, that's not a question. It's like,
okay, end of third grade, well am I
going to go to fourth grade? Okay.
Some of these things, maybe the college
decision may be a part of that. I said,
"We may have some questions there," because
for a lot of us out there, do we need to have
college for a cybersecurity degree? Some
of the stuff is technical trade stuff.
This next thing that comes up is this
thing that you're not good enough.
When I was at the Air Force Academy, and this is
where when you're just starting out something new,
I was recruited into basically the first
cyber unit in doing information security
that didn't exist, no one knew what the heck
we were doing. There was a single book that
existed on the planet, James Bafford's Practical
Internet and [inaudible 00:20:17] Security Book.
This is a real throwback. Has anyone
even heard of this book? It's a yellow
O'Reilly book. It existed back in 1995. This thing
was the only book that I could find other than
TCP/IP Illustrated Volume II.
And I was scared beyond belief that I
was recruited into this unit because I apparently
knew how to spoof email and people knew it
and they were like, "Okay, because you knew how to
spoof email, we're recruiting you into this unit
who apparently they think you know what you're
doing on how to defend entire Air Force bases
from internet based attack and all these scary
hackers." My eyes go wide here. And of course
they knew no one knew what they were doing
at this point, but there was this aspect of
it that they thought I knew what I was
supposed to be doing. So I was scared.
So this false expectations, which is what
the acronym stands for, false expectations
appearing real, is this fear that sets in that
you are not good enough because you don't know
what you're doing. The key here is no one
knows what they're doing, that is around you.
We're all winging it. But again, you think
everyone else around you knows what they're doing.
No one knows what they're doing, not just in your
career, but in life. By the way, your boss doesn't
know what they're doing either. The executives
don't know what they're doing. Everyone's kind of
winging it. They have a little bit more knowledge
than you in certain areas, but it's true when you
end up taking a look at it, it's like a lot of the
things that are being done around you is a lot of
decent guesswork and in some cases it's a lot of
education and things around you, but a lot of this
stuff where the fear comes in and why I'm tying
this back into these stories is that when you
end up starting something new, especially in your
careers, is that it is okay to feel inadequate.
And this ties into the next phase of the story
because those two things in my origin tie in to
when I got recruited by SANS, I had, like many of
you, I met Ed Skoudis, I met Eric Cole. I had this
massive fanboy, "I am finally learning how to do
internet security and all this other stuff." And
I started taking SANS classes and then I started
teaching SANS classes and authoring SANS classes.
And when that happened, there's something
else that occurred, and this is where
the things I wish I actually
learned in the SANS class kicks in.
So here's, you take SANS classes, all
the technical stuff that's out there,
here's where we're going to start diving into
where the BLUF comes in, bottom line upfront,
but the actual things that, and this comes
from, if anyone's familiar with the book,
Everything You Need to Know in Life, They Taught
You in Kindergarten. It's a book by Robert Fulghum
that came out during the mid 90s. It's an amazing
book, by the way, it still resonates today,
but it's very similar to this,
that everything you actually
wish they taught you in a SANS class but
didn't, it's on the non-technical stuff.
So the first thing is that there needs to be,
in every SANS class, a section on the imposter
syndrome, which ties into that fear. The first
thing I'm going to mention to you is that you,
like everyone else out there, is constantly
challenged with the imposter syndrome,
which is everyone is worried and consistently
challenged that you are not good enough
to wear the shoes. And the shoes basically ties
into this theory that, why I use this shoe analogy
is for anyone who is going to be wearing, and
I use the shoe analogy like dance shoes. If
you're going to be out on the dance floor and
you're going to have dance shoes on, therefore
you know how to dance. But in order to learn
how to dance, you need to have dance shoes on.
This becomes a catch-22, because if you
put the shoes on, people assume you know
what you're doing, but you don't want to put
your shoes on because you don't want to have
the shoes on because then people assume
you see what's going on here now,
but you need to equip yourself in
order to be able to do it correctly.
So if you show up, let's assume you walk
out to, I'm going to go learn how to climb a
wall. In order to do that safely, you have to have
all of the equipment, safety equipment, ropes,
the clips, and everything else. So if
you walk out there with all that gear on
and you show up at that wall, I mean you're
going to look like pretty much of a badass
and anyone who doesn't know any differently,
and never climbed a wall before, guess what,
they're going to look at you and saying, "Hey,
you look like you've done this for a while."
Kind of like, "No, no serious. Don't talk to me."
This is the problem with the imposter syndrome is
you feel that someone's going to actually ask
you a question about it. And everyone has the
same issue is that everyone is sitting in this
bucket and it's okay. You almost got to relish in
the fact that no one knows what they're doing. And
ask questions, and you're in that learning stage.
Guaranteed doctors, lawyers, judges, I mean you
got to think people on the Supreme Court go on on
day one and they don't have the FMG status, Google
that if you don't, I'm not going to acronym that
for you. I mean you got to think, hey, your first
day on Supreme Court, you do not get that label,
I guarantee they do. That first day, it's like,
go, "First case?" "Yeah." "Nervous?" "Yep."
"Everyone does."
This is where that imposter
syndrome comes into play here. And it's amazing
when you end up thinking about it, equip yourself,
regardless if you think you deserve
the shoes or not. Go buy the equipment,
don't hold yourself back. Now the equipment
may be expensive or not, then rent it,
buy it from someone else. But again,
always equip yourself with the stuff,
even if you think someone's going to judge
you for it that you have not earned it yet.
Equip yourself with the right stuff in order to
learn the job properly in all instances. That's
a good recommendation in general, because if
you don't, how are you going to learn properly?
Arm yourself with the right equipment.
I can tell you, what does the equipment
list say you have, Rob? It depends on
what you really need to do for your job
at that point. But again, I see time and
time again, it's like, I have not earned...
It's like the movies have this
big dramatic thing about this, the
superhero earning this uniform and the Batarang
at the right point in the movie or the sword,
that's all BS. What you need to do is go right
out the door and say, "What do I need to be
able to do this now and how do I learn using the
equipment that I will be using in my day job?"
It's super important that you start using the
equipment now, not what you will be using later.
Even if you have to borrow it, borrow it from
a friend. It's like, "What are you using there?
Okay. Can I use that?" And go forward with that.
Breaking glass and rules. So,
this one's interesting because you have to take
a step back that in this field, this one comes up
quite frequently, and I'll give you an analogy
first before I dive into how messed up digital
forensics is in general about rules, because
we are layered with rules in general, but
not more than two nights ago. Again, a story
about my son. He watches, I'm paying a bill
and they bring out the card reader and stick the
card in and they hand it back to me and said,
"We need your signature." And I put my
signature in, we're walking down the street,
after I put my signature in, he asked me a
question, "Dad, how do I get a signature?"
And I said, "Well, you have a signature. Spell it,
C-O-N-N-O-R." He said, "Yes, I know, but how do I
get a signature?" I said, "You have a signature."
This is going back and forth several times here,
"You have a signature." He said, "No,
you don't understand. How do I obtain
a signature that you could use in the reader?"
So what he's thinking is going on is that there's
some universal signature checker somewhere up in
the cloud somewhere that is checking my signature
from what I put in. Now, everyone in here knows
I could do that as my signature and that counts.
He's wanting to know how he could get his
signature registered into the cloud so when
he signs something, it'll also check. And I said,
"It doesn't exist." And he's, "Why do we do it?
Why are we doing something called a signature?" I
had to stop there and I said, "Because we do it."
And then I had to explain, I said, "Okay." Let me
take my mobile device out and I said, when I take
a picture, and I turn the sound on, when I take a
picture, do you know why it makes that sound? No.
I had to explain the sound of the camera. I was
like there's no reason that sound exists other
than back in the 50s, this film thing existed.
We are sometimes sitting on the reason we do
something no longer makes sense other than it's
because of the way we used to do something.
Signatures, as we all know, are one of
those things. It's 100% security theater,
we all know it, and everyone in here makes
fun of it. The people at the party are like,
"Yeah, signatures." We all tell our backstory
on that and it was like, "It doesn't matter."
Chip and card readers, we have our
little thing we talk about it. But
the reason I talk about the break glass
stuff here, especially when you are new,
guess what, you have new eyes on things like no
one else. You are my son. You are like my son at
that point, you're asking why are you doing that?
You are asking the question, why do you do MD5
and [inaudible 00:31:10] sums for evidence
hashing? Why both? Why does that make sense?
Why do we... "Well, it's because we all..."
Why? That is amazing perception to be able to
ask at that point, to ask the why question.
Now, I also noticed out here during break,
everyone lined up to get the stickers. Why?
There was no... Was there a sign of rules out
there that said you have to form a line to go
get the stickers and the little key chains? Or
just there's some generic rule thing that someone
said, "Hey, this is a really nice way to do it?"
Or if you really wanted to, you could go up
there and stick your hand between the people,
grab some stickers and claw them
out like the claw from Toy Story.
I mean this is the kind of thing
when it comes into when you're new,
are we following a set of rules because there's
this default set of gentleman's, ladies' rules
in an environment? Or when we're in a career
field, we're told these are the rules you must
follow because someone else set the rules a
long time ago and we must follow the rules?
My advice for everyone in here, when you're
looking at rules in general, break glass
with an explanation point. Don't break
glass to the point where you get in trouble,
but break glass to the point where
you will be able to look at something
and saying, like my son, "Why are
we actually doing this signature?"
Because you're new you're going to have that new
perception that no one else has. Break the glass,
challenge the rules when you can, and you're going
to be able to be that new person to nudge things
into new directions. Those of us who have been
in the field for 20 years cannot perceive things
because we've been doing it, we're the old
school folks. It's one of the reasons they
make fun of the boomers, and now we make fun of
the millennials, and the Gen Z-ers that could be
made fun of here soon. Everyone who's the old
school folks is the old way of doing things.
I look at some of the Gen Z-ers these days who are
like, "Why do I need to get a driver's license?"
It is a serious question. Why get a
driver's license? It's like, "Well,
it's what you're supposed to do at 16." Why? I
don't need a driver's license. Anytime I need
to get somewhere, I could just Uber, whatever.
What's the point? It's a new way of thinking.
[inaudible 00:33:53] I hadn't considered
that. Some of the things of what we're
challenging society today is that breaking rules
needs to be adhered to, so break the rules,
especially if you're brand new. You are
sitting on top of something really special,
don't worry about it at that point, have that
perception no one else has. Break the rules.
Chad. So, taking a stop here for a
second, everyone needs to think about
my friend, Chad. I have to figure out
which one I drink out of here. So Chad
is my co-author FOR500 and 508. And back, I
would say 2007, I started talking to Chad Tilbury
about helping me co-author 508. And it took,
I think, two years of conversations with him
until he finally, and again, I don't even know
where Phil's in back here, Chad, unlike Phil,
Phil immediately said, "Yes, I'll come on board."
Chad was a very long... It took him a while until
he finally said, "Okay, I'll consider it."
And then he came on board and was my co-author
FOR508 and then eventually became my co-author
FOR500. And the reason I mention Chad
is that you can't do things in a vacuum. It's not
just about you. It's every time that I look back,
the one single piece of advice I always tell
people is figure out who your partners are,
who is your team, who are the ones that
you're going to be working closely with? And
I guarantee the team and the people that you
work with are going to be the same people
that are going to be surrounding
you for the next 15 to 20 years,
professionally, personally, they're going to
be in your orbit for a long period of time.
And you see these people, again, bounce around.
Sometimes they'll disappear for five years,
they'll come back. And a lot of these
folks that are out there end up primarily
being significant contributors, personal and
professionally inside, and being your greatest
supporters and helpers across the board. Chad's
one of those. Both of those courses would not be
what they are today without Chad's influence.
So to a certain extent, he is the was to those
products. And granted, a lot of people credit
me for 500 and 508 because I help essentially
substantiate and create them, but without Chad's
diligence and working on them, neither of those
products would be the success they are
today without Chad working with me on them.
And that's one of the significant portions, I
had to give a lot of credit to, who is your Chad
when you're going through this process of being
new and starting out out there? Who do you work
with? Who's going to be your partner? It's
not like all of a sudden I need to go find,
start now, but when you're looking out there
and you're starting to really figure out who
you're resonating with and who is your natural
partners, who do you call on a daily basis?
And it's not just Chad that has
ended up being a part of my team.
I have many others that are out there and
you see them across the board here inside
my circle of folks out there. And a lot of
the people are sitting in the audience here,
some my family, some are... Whoop, let me go back
one. So you can see the name. They all become
your team. And obviously there's actually about
50 people I could probably add to this slide,
but I intentionally added a lot of people I
knew would be here in this room and online.
But the reason I specifically mentioned Chad is
because he became for years directly attributable
to the SANS product that I worked on, FOR508
and 500, but then also directly associated
with the summit with Heather and Phil, Kate,
Viviana, Lee Woodfield, Dennis Scandrett, advice
from my sister, Melinda. She might be watching
online. A lot of these folks that I constantly
lean on for day to day what goes on in Rob's
head, it's not just what I do is attributable to
how I function is saying, Rob just
somehow does stuff. Honestly, it's
mostly them. I mean I hate to tell you that
half the things that I have an idea, and
that idea might be just like, "Well,
here's a stupid idea," and Phil might say,
"Percolate on that and then actually come up
with the actual idea." And then we end up doing
executing on it or Heather, the same thing, or
Kate, all of these things that come out of it.
Eric Christensen, who's sitting in the back back
there, he's another one that he sat in my class,
and his name's up on this chart too, I would
say 10 years ago, and he started talking to me
about the SIFT workstation and saying, "Rob,
you're doing it all wrong." It's literally,
you should do docker packages, you should do this,
you should do that. And I just looked at him and I
said, "Can I employ you to 99 you? I could use
some help on this thing." He said, "Sure. I would
do it for free." I'm like, "No, no, no. Let's just
figure out a way to have you start working." And
he became the engineer behind SIFT and was doing
it for many, many, many years. And again, Eric,
I don't know, everyone turn around and look at
Eric, so he is the man behind SIFT right there.
Eric now works at SANS, he's our chief engineer
of all ranges and basically is engineering the
entire scalable interface of how we're powering
SANS courseware in the cloud. And that's how some
of that stuff happens. A single conversation of
an individual coming up to you and saying, "Hey,
I have an idea about how to do
docker packages and a virtual machine
that I happen to do this in my other job." A
relationship that you form because of a single
conversation, because of an idea, forms
a relationship, forms a friendship, forms
a partnership, and forms a lifelong connection.
And Eric also loves Legos, loves Marvel, really
good dude. And now he is working with Phil and
I, and sit there and look at him, just sit there,
have a conversation with him, you'd just be
blown away about the amount of knowledge a guy
has him on that stuff. But each one of these
individuals has their own backstory with me
that I would be able to bring to the forefront.
And Chad also is, like I said, you have
a very similar story with Chad when there's
the contributions of 500 and 508 along the way.
So next one. Going to take a pause here for
a second. So find your team, but this one
is very important as well. And this one, I find
giving a lot of advice on to people mid-career,
not when you're new, but when you're kind
of 10 years in that you get this stuck mode.
You reach this point in your career
where you're saying, "I'm really not
doing what I thought I'd be doing. I'm kind of
meh." It's the old adage, and I'll have to say,
I was kind of torn on the way to describe this.
Is it stress? Is it kind of unhappy? But the
meme that a lot of us who describe this is the
dog with the coffee cup, the, "It's fine" meme.
You know what I'm talking about? It's like, "Yeah,
it's fine." You're just sipping coffee.
There's a fire burning around you. I'm good,
I think. And you're just content,
but you're realizing you're not okay.
Versus waking up every day and saying, "I
love my job. I love what I do. And I love
who I'm interacting with." So case in point
with what I'm now doing at SANS. I don't know
if a lot of you have realized this that SANS
right now, that I've moved away from teaching.
They asked me two years ago to move from the
DFIR curriculum lead position and I'm now
helping lead all of the curriculum in a
leadership position. So all the cloud,
digital forensics, office operations, all
the curriculum leads, curriculum directors,
all the content now roll under me. And it's a big
change for me and I was really worried that I was
going to lose my passion because I loved my job
running digital forensics in its response at SANS.
And you worry about, anytime you make a big
shift like that, it's like, am I going to lose
my passion? But another passion of mine has always
been leading teams and leading content in the SANS
dream of affecting cyber security in the right
way. And I also look at things, like I said, could
someone else do that job? Could they... I had
that ego thing in there a little bit, it's like,
well, what if someone else is doing it
not as good as what I could possibly do?
I said, "I don't know." I was like, "I think I
could do a good job maybe. I don't know. I think
I'd like to do that job. I'd like to be given
a shot at that job. I hope I'm doing it well."
But again, there's this passion of mine that
says, "I want to wake up every morning and not
just affect digital forensics, but affect all of
the content that SANS is delivering worldwide."
And that's my job right now and I love it. I
can't believe they pay me for this. Of course,
my boss might be watching on screen right now is
like, "Good to know, Rob," writes that down, but
I love what I do. And now every job out there
has its stresses and your eye roll moments and
the grass is greener on the other side but SANS
has a promise, the most trusted source
of information security certifications. I
believe in this mission of what we do. The
most trusted source, and I believe that.
We have this mission that we're trying to
accomplish. Now, if I didn't believe that mission
and I was in a, "Nah, it's fine." I'd wake up
every day, kind of stare at things, not really
sure what the mission is, not really sure what my
why of why I'm doing this. If you're in that role,
and this is where I advise people, I have people
call me out of the blue, have people that I work
with sometimes say, "I'm not really sure that I
see what I'm doing anymore." That's where I get
a little bit concerned, and have you lost your own
personal why of what you're trying to accomplish?
And that's if you're brand new and maybe you need
that new brand new moment to your own career field
of what you're trying to accomplish, your own
personal why that we're trying to accomplish. So
it's the it's fine versus your own passion. You
need to try and find your passion. And this is
something too. If you want to reach out to me,
you are in that situation, I'm glad to try and
talk to you about it. Find me in the hallway.
This is something that it's a personal thing
that sometimes people need that, let's talk about
it. It's hard to unbox that a little bit because
sometimes what's affecting you is actually
not your job, it's other things. But again,
that's where I'm like, "Hey, you need to go talk
to someone else when you find that out." If it's
your job, sometimes you need to redirect and find
out it's not the fact that you're doing the...
Well, let me refactor that. Sometimes people got
promoted and they're doing the wrong job suddenly,
and this is where a good friend of mine,
Laura Dawson, we keep on asking her, I said,
"Do you want to get promoted?" She's like,
"No. I'm perfectly fine in the job I'm in."
And we're shocked. She's like, "No, actually, this
is the job I like doing. I'm very passionate about
my job." And I said, "Well, don't you want
additional money? Do you not want additional
time? Authority? All these other things?" She
was like, "No, I actually don't." It's like,
"The money, I'm able to live comfortably." "Well,
what about cost of living?" And she's like, "Well,
that sounds like something that you need to
worry about to make sure that I'm going to
be happy at my job." I'm like, again, some
of this stuff comes from, there's a TikTok
that came out that actually had some of these
themes in it too, that we sent to her as like,
"This sounds just like you." And she's
like, "Oh yeah, that's definitely me."
And it ties into this theme that sometimes
you don't need to be promoted to be happy.
Sometimes you just need to realize that
happiness comes from understanding that
your own personal happiness doesn't come
from getting promoted and getting into,
"Hey, I'm going to be getting my
teeth kicked in at a new position."
But realizing, every time I work out, my
passion is actually working next to the
people I love on a daily basis, but it always
comes into this. You reach that certain age,
you're like, "I have 10 years to do it. If I don't
do it in the next 10 years, now what?" And this is
where that, what would Chad do? Because Chad
and I have these conversations all the time.
Chad is one of these individuals that honestly he
could have done a startup, he could have become a
CEO of all these other industries, but he has
had conversations with me and he says, "Rob,
we live comfortably. We get to
go on a couple vacations a year.
We get to talk on the phone. We look at some
of our peers that are out there in the field,
are they really that happy?" And I said, "You
have a very good point. What is happiness to you?
Does it need to be at the startup shooting
for the stock options and drilling yourself
into the force 12 to 16 hours a day? Or is it
really saying, hey, I want to work for a very
laid back organization in which I have my life
and I could go to concerts and mountain bike
on the weekends and take a vacation every
now and then and have a lower salary?"What
is your passion and what is going to
create the it's fine moment for you?
This is a very hard discussion and I think a
lot of us in our field are torn by this, "Go
to the startup. Get your options and your bonuses
and all this other stuff, because all my friends
are doing it." And then you get over there and
you're dying. And I see this happen all the time.
And on the other side, you see individuals in your
friends out there mountain biking on the weekend,
it's like, what are you doing differently?
It's like, I don't need that. I want my life.
I like having a different way of doing it. You're
still technical, but you're choosing a different
path, and this is where you have to make that
option there because the deduction of the other
side makes it sound like it's really cool, but are
you really going to be landing on that big payout?
And that's where, when we get into some of
these last assuage of this, we'll get that.
The next thing we had talked about
here is the up, down, left, and right,
is when you're in any organization, managing
relationships requires you to manage up, down,
left, and right in almost every single situation.
And what that means is that a lot of us, we
latch on to only those individuals that we like.
It's weird. We tend to only interact with
people that we like. In all organizations,
and this is where the hard part is, you have to
break out of your comfort zone and interact and
manage relationships and build relationships
with people that you sometimes don't like.
And that sometimes means I need to go out of my
way to manage a good relationship with my boss.
I need to manage relationships with those that
work underneath me, that maybe I don't like,
peers I don't like. You have to really spend
time, especially as technical individuals,
we're not sometimes the most
social individuals on the planet
and it's hard for us.
And I know I just totally
went down the trope of what technical people
are, we're not social, but we're all here,
but at the same time it's hard in many cases
across the board, whether we're social or not,
all human beings tend to flock to people that
resemble us in general, and sometimes we have
to break through and say, "I'm going to reach
out to someone across in my peer and just get
to know them and spend some time building a
relationship with someone we don't know. It
will pay off in spades in your relationships at
work. It pays, every single time I've done this,
and I say, "I'm going to go and spend time
with someone I don't know," it builds bridges.
And every single time I've done this in my
career, it has always, always, always paid off.
Sometimes it takes time, especially
[inaudible 00:52:33] like, okay, he and I
or she and I or they and I ended up having
some sort of a heated email exchange, something
happened there. So I will intentionally go out of
my way to, "Let's go to lunch," or I'll call them
on the phone and spend some time with them on the
phone and say, "We're not talking work, let's just
find out who you are." Do some backstory
discussions. Talk about families, vacations,
something else. Build the relationships in
your organizations as potentially necessary.
And also tied to the thing I was talking about
passion versus it's fine, is that your money,
everyone who knows the TikTok meme here,
this is a very short one to close this out is that
if you have your passion, the money will follow.
Don't chase money. If you do, it will
create that it's fine environment for you.
The money, as every single time that I've talked
to people out there, is that if you find your
passion, you will be paid, you're going to be in
a situation that's like, "I don't know. I'm paid
silly money for the job that I love." If you find
your passion, they're going to pay you for it.
It's just like, you're going to be waking
up, especially in your technical degrees,
especially in your technical field, everyone
in here is technical, you're on the right path,
you're going to be paid for your job if
you're going to stick with the cyber security,
cyber forensic side that you're doing in here.
Not all money is created equal. Just realize that,
but find your passion, if you find what you love,
you'll be paid for it. But don't always say,
"I am taking the job that pays the most money."
Just be really careful about that in general.
All right. In summary, I'm going to redefine
these as we're going through it. Number one,
don't be afraid to wear the dance shoes. Number
two, what are the rules? What is the obstacle?
And again, don't be afraid to break the
rules. Look at the obstacles and look
for the ways around them. Number three, and
we need a T-shirt for this, find your Chad.
We could get a T-shirt made by the end of
the summit, that'd be amazing. We need Chad's
face on it, by the way, just his face, just
straight up, "Find your Chad." Number four,
don't settle for its fine. Overall if you're
in that situation, you're probably in a,
you're in a pickle. I've found again and
again, if someone's in a it's fine situation,
you need to potentially look for a reboot.
Find your passion, it's tied directly to that.
Number six, build relationships with those you
normally don't build relationships with. If it's
a relationship feels like, "Wow, that was easy,"
that's not the relationships I'm talking about.
It's the relationships with the folks that it's
like, I actually need to think, I need to build
a relationship with that person. That's the
folks that I'm talking about. And number seven,
it's not about the money. The money's going to
follow you whenever you are following your own
passion. That ties directly into, for anyone
who's out there starting in your career,
all of these rules are going to be maintained.
This is what I wish they taught you in SANS
classes. This is what I routinely tell people
throughout the 20 years I've been teaching SANS,
these are the same rules again and
again and again that I've advised people
when you're working through your careers.
Now, at the end of this, one general rule
that I started with, always learn. As a part
of that, we have a brand new released guide,
the new DFIR manual written by Phil
Moore, Heather Mahalik, Kat Hedley,
Jason Jordan that has just been released at this
event, big round of applause for them right now.
And they have done an amazing job
and this is just recently released.
Now to close this off, what I'd like
everyone to do to close off this
segment is I want everyone to stand. I know
this is going to sound stupid, but stand up,
stand up, stand up, stand up, stand up. We're
going to take a breather here. What I want you to
do is to build a relationship right now, and are
we going on break after this? Okay, we're going
to go on break after this. What I'd like you to
do is I need you to build a relationship with two
people that you don't know next to you, you have
to shake their hand, introduce yourselves to them,
and say where you're from and then go
out in the hallway and eat and drink
with them. All right. Thanks everyone. My
name's Rob Lee. I appreciate your time.