today we we're gonna talk about the
discovery in cnc it's a good topic by
the way i like this talk about the moral
analysis and here my contact on a two
year and uh
here my contacts too and uh social
medias i have here my web page and uh
okay we will show you during this
conversation my twitter youtube i have
here in my guitar some project i'm i've
been working
about that probably hunting mower and
stuff like that and uh if the people
would like to send them a message
it would be pleasure right and let me
introduce myself again i'm now i'm a
principal security engineer at talk desk
this is a portuguese company now
portuguese from brazil parties from
portugal it's different and
this company is responsible to sell a
product the contact center as a service
it's a
i'm new employee there and i'm security
research at senate segura it's perfect
pronunciation it's a brazilian company
but they offering a pen solution it's a
privilege access management it's a
brazilian company but they appears in
many uh important report like a gardener
and uh you know foreign
it's a pretty cool solution but my job
here is to work with uh research right
and to see what happened with a new
threat
and the discovery and presenting
something related to our threats not
exactly related to solution
in my advocate of this awesome project
it's actually not a crime the name it's
pretty
obviously right because it's really not
a crime it's a mindset you have creative
mining it's how you can apply your
knowledgement in uh
you know in a technology and when you
see some applications when how you can
create these or how you can explore this
uh
of course but the thinking is the point
is it's a it's a lifestyle right and uh
for example if you if you are a lawyer
it's not a bad lawyer you know a
criminal lawyer or a a good lawyer
you know and uh this is the concept of
the hacking uh when you see something in
you using your creative mind and i'm
part of the staff staff a team of the
defcon group in sao paulo here and i'm
stroked of the hacker security by the
way we have here in courses in
portuguese and then structure of the
pentax magazine
one course that i am
teaching about the more analysis okay so
uh i would like to put every people in
the same page the simple definition
about what is threat uh
before to talk exactly about the
exploitation about the moral analysis
exploration actually and i would like to
explain more about what is athletic a
threat threat none of my definition it's
a defeat by this size all right so
straight it's a potential cause on an
incident and i mean it's related to
sovereign attacks and that intellectual
property or identity that or sabotage
all those things is related to a threat
if you think about the thread it's
usually it's related to the same
software right explored by something and
and of course you have a hardware
hacking or stuff like that but usually
it's related as some software so it this
is a thread not the flip definition is
definition by eizer okay and a simple
life cycle about the moral analysis so
what is exactly uh first of all we have
a simple right or artifact we don't know
if it's malicious not so we have a
identification step important and after
that you can choose what the best
strategy you apply the statistics and
dynamic analysis maybe you are asking
about the reversal engineer it's a part
of technique using in this
analysis or you can use in a statistical
analysis you can use a raster
engineering dynamic analysis of course
using tools to help you to see about the
information but the point is you need to
understand about those bases right
because you need to understand how the
important works in the memory how kind
of imports you have
called by some dlls and
many stuff like that right so but this
is the main point about the
what kind of strategy method you can
apply in your analysis okay and after
that you can create a report because you
need to present this to someone and your
company if you work about if you work
with a security
from my perspective importantly you
present some report to our your
coordinator or your manager and after
that you can improve your defense's
mechanism because if you if you do some
analysis in your job
you can improve your security defense
right because if you see what the the
path or
what exactly path the mower uh executing
your network you can improve your
defense mechanism or you can build some
uh thing with a good
beautiful name like the cyber threat
intelligence and you can you know
it's training in your environment this
uh cyber security resilience because the
threats are changing all the time right
so this is simple explanation what is
the statistical analysis is the first
step using number analysis because
describe the process of the program is
more deeply right so you can read about
the code you can understand about the
structure what kind of function it's
called by this program uh usually this
is the first step using the modern
studies or the research right because it
doesn't run at this time the demolition
you know it's the pain of course of the
program but usually it's more safe right
so this is a simple definition then
canals on the other hand using the
runtime
usually using some tools to help you
to it's a good something and you see the
report about that you know the report
you see the log but you need to
understand what this log are telling you
in the print right and because of this
you need to understand about those bases
okay or you can automate this process
using some the concept called said box
right sandbox is not a it's a simple
virtual machine uh
that you can use it to execute the mr
inside this controller environment and
to see the behavior of course it's not a
simple syn box because usually you need
to have some engines inside of the
sandbox to understand about the behavior
of this binary as a hidden inside of
this sandbox okay so this is a simple
definition um okay so now
before let's talk about the logical
structure about the pdf i would like to
share about something with you here in
my virtual machine so cross your thing
about the the lords of demo and let's
see what happened here okay so we have
here many uh mowers in my virtual
machine here to show you
so
first of all when the first remember
when you talk about the identification
is that the important step is um we need
to identify what is exactly this
artifact or this sample so first of all
we can use this file command to see what
is exactly the fire
right so let me check here for example
this invoice it's another a pdf okay we
have more than one mower here
is pizza mower in my case here i like to
work with them uh real modelers so let's
check here a sample
is a pe portable executable let me check
it here another it's a who is it's
another portable executable right but
the point is we need to see about those
bases that's my point here so what can
work exactly what is the correct
understanding about this file it's file
it's a tool that help you to identify
the five okay determiner the terminal
file type but the point is how exactly
work this tool and the point is here the
explanation how this
works here is this file have a what a
magic number what is stored in some
place what place is this information is
stored in particular place in here at
the beginning okay and of course when
you see in the unix platform as you can
see here in my my virtual machine is a
compilot right so you just set the file
command and you receive a return of the
this this command identifying based on
the magical number so all those files
has a machine number of course
measurement numbers can be manipulated
by the
the researcher the the the attacker it's
it's interesting so of course you need
to to trust in this comment but you need
to understand how this work is in the
background right so i have here for
example let me show you here i have here
yes i have here the file and mac
i think it's maggie maggie and magic
maggie okay i download here the database
of the file
sorry for that let me check here okay i
download here the
file command
the the database of the file how for you
unders
you need understand how this works in
the background of course this is all
those databases but not
pilot okay so if i uh read for example
whatever like javascript here
javascript
if i right here i can see
exactly how the file works in a database
so when you set the command of course
it's compiling in unix platform and
after that
the the file command the database has
some uh
rules that that that can use to identify
this file right so here as you can see
this is the information that you need to
have in the beginning of the file
remember when you read
uh when you read now about the file
command is a matching w it's storing the
in the beginning of the the file right
so if i copy here this information and
let me generate some file here
called malware.txt
and i will i just have this smile here
let me
okay let me put something here mower
and let me save here
and yes
okay
okay not have permission
okay no
[Music]
nano and malware talk text
it's proof it's okay
i will pass here
if not as this change from our
just to show how it's possible what
manipulate if i use here file
malware
text
it's another different it's on our
yeah malware
text
take a look this is a ascii if i read
this malware.txt
we have a mower okay this is our file
okay let me download it this is
it's another
pie
it's about just only text i have here
yes
okay just need to be confused so i have
here again
malware is a text okay it's um
we can read the correct
okay if i now if i manipulate the
beginning of the the match this magic
number started in the particular place
in the beginning as you can see
if i pass here
let me edit here i will save
and now take a look what happened if i
put file mower dot text
is not a ascii now is a node.js script
because i'm putting this in the
beginning of the file you know if i
manipulate again one more time and i put
here let me cut here and i will put this
uh
the book vote here three times and i use
save
so do you know what happened here
you can imagine so
what will happen now
take a look at this we have a fighting
script
because i'm manipulating so if you
understand about the python programming
language when you set this you can put
all those strings in the same uh
space right so i'm manipulating the file
here
and if i cut one more time and i put um
percent what percent pdf
like
whatever and i will save here
and take a look what happened now
but the extension is always the same
it's doctex take a look at this now i
have a pds so it's very important to
understand those bases so i you can see
how this works is this a file so that's
my point here so let's check another
interesting point here for example take
a look at this let me return here and uh
let me go to this folder and i have here
uh file who is yeah yeah so let me check
here strings dash a this should quiz
five less i will start in the beginning
okay so we just information about the
string it's not it's it's not a
completely no analysis it's not a
reverse engineer but it's a first step
the identification step right so you can
see here the uh session right so doctech
stock or data docs data and dot or ask
for
c so the session inside of the pe the
portal is executable okay so if you
check here we can
try and find many others information so
here you can see
uh some
functions called by what
by some dll so here we can send load
library and get process address usually
it's pretty cool inside of many mowers
okay and you can see here other
different so virtual a location in
memory space heap a lot so many
functions so here you can see the dlls
so
you can use
this uh information to help you but
let's see one important thing
interesting so as you can see here in
the beginning
we don't you you can't see the mz
signature here right so
for example if you using um
[Music]
let me check here x no x d n x x i think
use this
x d
next g next you know hd and uh
you know
uh any 32
and uh who is again and take a look this
in the beginning is mz
right
if i
check a different way here for example
and uh
so i have here more more bytes let me
check here more
let me put here okay
take a look at this uh we don't we can't
see here the mz
you can see the pe we just started when
you set the strings
uh
it started in this
moment if i check here take a look at
this uh the strings fighting less again
you see they started off they string
printed it started here in this moment
take a look at this
right so why my question why didn't
appears the mz
in the beginning because this is a
string right
so it's the simple question for a simple
answer right it's it's pretty simple if
you see here the strings is a tool that
can help you take a look what the
explanation here for each file given
strings printed the printable
characteristic sequences that are at
least four characters long
so you need to understand those bases
not only for fire for a string but you
need to understand about the structure
of the pde the pe the pdf the alpha and
so on and so on it's not just run on a
tool or run and then you know dynamic
analysis tool to help you it's pretty
important right but we didn't understand
how this work exactly because you need
to interpret this information or
understand the result of the log when
you set some command right so cool so
let's continue to talk about the
structure of the pdf in general we have
a four parts and a pdf the header it's
very common in all files the body then
cross reference table o x table and
trailer okay it's divided in four stack
four parts actually and we have a board
when you have a page images and whatever
and you have a um an x table or cross
reference table it's a it's specifically
part of the object it in the file for uh
access random from the
other object it's it's connected both of
them right and the tray is the same idea
it's location the certain object
ethernet
okay so this is the structure of the pdf
why i need understand because when you
set when you use some tools to help you
you can identificate
what is exactly or how is created or how
the attacker can use this in the pdf
okay so let's see now the demo about the
explanation we have here i think it's
more 20 minutes and i will explain these
uh analysis okay i have here the cv and
uh in the resume so let's suppose they
someone received this resume in the
company so first of all the
identification is steps okay i record
this to be more easily to explain you
okay first of all i would like i will
use the pdf id this tool provided from
dda steven right so
they created through as they put some
e-scan inside of the pdf and of course
when probably when dda stephen created
these tools probably they understand
about the structure of the pdf about the
how exactly is the cross reference table
the trailer and so on and so on and as
we can see here in this command we have
in this object 15 objects here okay we
have a two streams streaming what's that
mean streaming streaming usually is that
is the place when the many times the
attacker using to put some
thing malicious or maybe um
you know a job script or a selling url
or
many
things inside of this stream
of course
it's a it's a very interesting point
because when you instead about the
threads or security the people would you
like to
the young people actually like to study
about the uh or try to discover a new
exploit or zero days or you know but
we need to understand how the known
thread works
after i understand how the known thread
works i can
understand the techniques
i can't i can't understand
how is the
creative mind
used by the attacker in these attacks
and after that i can understand the
difference techniques and of course
after that i can develop in my
zero days excuse me it's not a zero-day
excuse okay but the point is we need to
understand about the known threats
for after that and understand how the
unknown threats works
it's from my perspective i don't know if
this is correct or not but just my
perspective you you if you have another
opinion it's no problem it's not it's
okay it's it's no words about that it's
we have a space for everyone and uh the
point is from a perspective we need to
understand about the known threads okay
so
when you understand the node threads you
can create the tools right if you have
if you have these good skills of the
programming language you can develop
that tools by the way i suggest you
okay so let's continue the analysis here
and
they have here some other
interesting informations here so this
command it's pretty cool because when
you execute a pdf id take a look this is
slashes here slash page is slash encrypt
slash javascript
slash aaa so here you can see
something inside of the pdf probably
when dda steven created this tool they
find some informations
related to open action so what does
what's that means of an action in this
case open access is basically is when
the user or the victim received the pdf
and executed download the action this
just only download the file inside the
their environment okay or or itself
download in the vitamin machine
the user don't need no need to click
again to execute the mower or execute
the pdf inside the the victor machine no
need is a good why because this open
action it's enough to execute itself the
fire just only download to the internet
okay so when you find the opening action
is that means that
when the file download the victor
machine
the user no need to click again okay so
that's the the point here so probably
when the tga stephen developed it i'm
supposed to okay
probably when the dds even create these
two probably they understand about this
behavior okay because probably they
analyze many times the many different
threads many different uh
different files and they probably is
understand about the known threads and
after that they create two
makes sense for me
and so when you have open action or a a
for example is that means that the user
don't need to click
you have not you but the malware has
action
automatically after the download okay so
that's the point here now cool so let's
continue to see so we have here five
javascript so it's totally suspicious we
have a five java script and you have an
open action in this file it's a pdf okay
i'm continuing to analyze after that i
execute the pdf parser it's another tool
from the gay steven uh
all those tools are inside of the
the unix platform as you can see so here
you some flags or comments or parameters
whatever name that you can set in your
analysis so i
set the javascript to see how many
javascript we have so as we can see here
in the object seven object
12 sorry and take a look at this
important
in the key that is something interesting
we have here in the beginning
take a look at this object one and type
catalog and referencing remember when i
talked about the cross reference table
and access a random and in the cross
reference table inside of the body so
as we can see here the object one
referring and object two three four six
seven ah six and seven but remember that
we have 15 object inside of this pdf
right and another interesting point here
is take a look at this we have an open
action remember that my explanation
about the open action so
the user just me just needs to click the
download the pdf and the pdf will
download in the environment
and the pdf is started automatically
something but we didn't know we don't
know at this moment
but as we can see here
we have that we have a javascript linked
linked with an open action i
mean after
the download
something happened automatically
with
a javascript
we can see here
but
the code is
not identical right we
it's we can see exactly the information
okay but
we need investigate more nice cool so
let's continue to do the analyze so we
we find we found the five javascript in
in the in this related to this string as
i i show you here so let's continue to
see so i'm set pdf parser and i would
like to see the ram data it's a
the completed data inside of the this
pdf okay so i will show you
here this command the important command
here to between find information the run
output for data and filters this is the
command that i am setting here okay to
see the the all run data inside of this
pdf to see more clear all those objects
so in this case i i just have only 15
objects
but sometimes we have a
60 objective it's many objects inside of
the pdf okay
so again you can see here
open action and javascript okay
and um
we can suppose is totally malicious
because it have an open action and have
and a javascript okay
and we have object 2 object 3 object 4
and again we have here one other
interesting point take a look at this
because remember we have an object one
at seven but we have a 15 okay and here
in object four take a look at this we
have another two difference or two news
reference and object eight in object
nine
so now
we can see more object
to investigate right because we don't
know exactly where is the place that we
find
the javascript and now we have a new
reference
right it's object 10
in in object 10 we have a javascript
here so maybe it's an object 10
let's see what happened inside object
10. object 9 is just a image
not important thing but we have another
object here object 11
it's more
close in object 10 we have the first
reference
another reference actually
object 12 and in this is the javascript
that we find
in here take a look in object
11 we have the first streaming remember
in the beginning we found
two streaming and take a look at this
in this object the left
is
it is more left the size inside of this
is streaming totally small
maybe we need to investigate because
we can put something
inside there object 12
reference object 13
and this object 13 take a look what i
found here another extreme
but here we have
the left
it's high it's bigger right and here we
have another important uh information to
tell you take a look at this we have a
big flat we have to have here flat
decode was that meaningfully
flat decode it means that i need to
decode something
it's it's cool
obviously but okay it's i need to decode
what i need to decode this streaming so
this is the
the action that i need to do i need to
decode this information inside of this
streaming
okay so probably this is the object more
suspicious for my perspective okay
because it's for makes sense for me
it's a big size and this is the okay
just that this i mean writing about that
this is the main object
and the wrote it wrong it's not mainly a
main object okay object 15 so just
not important information so now we need
to
read more about the object
15 this is the main object okay so if
you you're using now pdf tica it this is
another
platform that i use in this analysis
this two is not from dda steven right
okay so this is a pretty cool tool to
manipulate pdf and we have many
functions many flags to sat here like a
marriage pdf documents and whatever but
i would like i used this just only to
uncompress and hey compress in my case i
would like to uncompress because i found
many informations inside of this run
data
this i need to uncompress the all
informations inside of this pdf in main
in
mainly in your bj object 13.
so i sat here i i put the output because
i need to uh
copy all those information from this
dump.text
i execute the uncompressed comment and
now i have the
uncompressed data inside of this dump
okay and take a look at this i have
clear information inside of this
streaming this object 13.
and now we have the first technique used
by the attacker so here we have a
javascript also skated okay
okay for me now it makes sense because i
investigate more about that and i see
some other encodes inside of these
and
of course we don't have a time to
explain all those stuff but basically
it's a javascript obfuscated and if you
see here when i pass and i copy and
paste here this code in this file i
generate this file sample.txt
and you can see here the different
colors here so probably we can
see more about that and you see i see
here some evil parameters and i'm so i'm
thought when i made this investigation
if i'm talking about the javascript so
probably i need to print something in
the internet so if i were printing
something in the internet i can
manipulate these in html right and i
changed this paragraph by using this
evil parameter to write this information
in a browser okay so i set the document
right to write this in a web page to try
to suffocate this information because
the attacker using the javascript to
scale it so my age is if it was visual
for skate this information in a web
browser okay
using this evo parameter okay so i save
the file i change
this some parameters i create the sample
as you can see here i give the
permission to execute this
okay
now i can execute this in you know in
in in a browser right on in google
chrome or firefox i don't remember in
the firefox in this case
okay here when i execute this take a
look what happened
i received the print this information in
a web browser to take a look at this we
have now the pay load
in this case is a payload responsible
for what for executing the callback in
the vitamin machine to the attacker
right so inside of this javascript we
had what we have the payload responsible
to go back to them cnc so i now now i i
could
i could finish my investigation but i
continued to do i copped this all those
codes and i passed this in another file
because i see some standard in this code
and i generate another file called
payload
as we can see here right
and i see
i i saw actually the this standard um
number percent number percent
ladder
number percent the ladder i i saw this
is standard in this code so my date was
to cut this percent to understand about
as you can see here take a look at this
we have a number letters numbers slider
numbers but i had a percent here in this
case i used sad to cut this percent
because i would like to copy
this information here
this information here the attacker uses
another technique the encode
techniques based on an eu
a new to see you know a new
and
easy
use actually it's a old techniques but
basin on the now is you have 16
basically
now it's another uh it's evolution of
these techniques right so now utf-16 now
and this is e2c e a u 2
each is e u c u c i don't remember the
name correct now but it's the evolution
of this uh old techniques it was uh
now is uh
utf-16 okay and they're using these
techniques you see two
um
e you two seats
uh using unicode technique to encode
this uh information so now i change as
you can see the other um
environment because i would like to
explain the same exploration in the for
the perspective from the windows machine
so i copy here as you can see the same
code
and i you
cut this person take a look this
standard as i mentioned right so as you
can see here the ladder
percent number ladder percent and number
so i will use here another platforming
melissa mozilla sorry and uh and here we
can see the correct name
the old techniques as i mentioned
is here
ucs to sorry ucs this is the correct
name it's old right so the correct name
now is utf-16 sorry for that okay and i
cut here as you can see
and i execute this access to file i
generate a binary as you can see here i
called
uh cnc i remember correct the name yes
and i generated this uh
ucs2 encode i generate ixa binary as you
can see
right and after that i use short to
search some http
access inside of this binary that i
generate now and as you can see here i
found the what the
cnc from the attacker so
now we have all those informations of
the attackers so we have a javascript
encoded uh obfuscated sorry and inside
of the javascript we had
a payload inside of this payload we have
an encoded technique but based on ucs2
and inside of this cs2 we have
they made a request to this cnc so if
you have here this is the cnc in estonia
by the way right as i show you here it's
based on estonia right
it's based on estonia yeah yes it's
based on estonia
okay and if you see here in uh virustoto
is this is uh
ip malicious using to explore victim
machines
okay
and here's some recommendations about
some books that i the people usually ask
me about their some recommendations so
we have here demo analysis mastering
from back
packed and more analysis techniques and
freddie hunty and by the way i have if
you'd like to receive i have five free
ebooks to send you by email just send me
a message in uh
in the meet in the social media and
twitter for example felipe you heard
about your talk i was in uh an event i
would like to receive this free book and
if you like to buy this in amazon for
example i can
get you on a discount ticket right and i
can send you okay so now i finished my
presentation i think you i passed one
minute
okay and i don't know if the people have
some questions so if you have any
questions so please let me know
yeah thank you
for the talk thank you for great
presentation and now we are ready for q
a and i'm just checking everywhere if we
had any during the talk
okay
so
currently we still have none but
normally it takes people
a couple of minutes to
type them in if you are in zoom with us
and you want to ask your question out
loud remember that you have this option
you can do it you can raise your hand
and then
some we will get
send them a message
you seriously people have some shame
people can send me a message by social
media or worse
yeah thanks for being so such an open
person we will
publish this online and if anyone has
questions they will reach out certainly
but i am sure that we will have
questions right now
just uh yeah mind the gap between
what's going on in the real time and uh
what's going on on youtube because there
is always a delay of 20 to 30 seconds
yeah but
i was watching they do too but
not in english the problem is that i
don't understand i live in poland one
year but
it's totally different and yes the
latter it's different it's not that
different when you when you're polish
you know
because we can
speak
and they understand the accent mostly
yeah exactly exactly yeah i i have some
colleagues from the front from the kiavi
and at that time and the pronunciation
is some similar like a brazilian in
spanish
but the the
the ladders is totally different
yeah you know
we write differently of course
exactly
uh
okay
so it seems
there are no questions
okay i don't know this is i don't know
if i don't know if this is good or not
but
probably the people good or normally
it's good because it means that
everything is clear and everyone
followed it and uh yeah i think that it
should be a good sign but i have a
question
uh oh my goodness
no no this is very simple
being being such a um
being a guy such interested in finding
this kind of artifacts in documents do
you have some uh automation around
everything you get like via email or
download uh
from websites like i don't know i i'm i
was a web guy before becoming a manager
i was like
absec guys so i basically put all my
traffic through a setup of uh
http proxy zap and burp you know
just
so do you do yeah
similar
no no actually
in this in the moment no uh i didn't use
anything and uh when i for example when
i need to investigate something i open
my virtual machine and i use some tools
but probably um i'm
thinking in the future because now i'm
working with a singer segura it's a
brazilian company again i'm starting
this new research gene it's a volume
person for now but in the future we have
uh something like uh segura labs or
stuff like that but my idea is to create
some environment to
create this to receive some artifacts
you know uh or create some flow like i
have a
like antivirus at
uh you know antivirus.com to receive
this some simple suspicious from the
community and after that to pass from
the
past through this this uh like email
after that some sandbox or you know or
uninstall some honey pots to receive
attacks to see the behavior to
understand how this works and to see
something is strange and then after that
or to investigate more deeply right yeah
but of course the pain of the
infrastructure because when you use
order
yeah i was right twice so
uh
it looks like everyone followed and
everyone got everything but the only
question we have for now is could you
please repeat the names of the tools
that you used uh through the present
yeah yeah yeah of course
using the pdf id this is uh embedded on
the unix platform and pdf id pdf parser
i use in a pdf tca
but
you can search in google
putting their dda steven
and they have a pdf tools all those
tools is there okay and you can download
this package using the in the windows
platform if you want and but more than
this tools
is embedded on the in the unix platform
anyway we will we will have the
recording
online on youtube so if anyone is
interested just refer to the recordings
i think we'll be publishing them very
soon like in a week or something
okay any more questions maybe
okay then so let's wrap it up for
philippe thank you once again for the
great instructive
talk
uh and yeah i hope
i will have some time to put aside and
watch it once again on record
yeah thank you thank you like thank you
for this time and uh again if you if the
people
have some questions you can send me and
thank you again for this time this
opportunity yeah okay thank you very
much the contacts and social media
presence
of philippe will be published as well as
the
uh recording of the video thank you
again thank you bye