thank you thank you for the interaction
and thank you all for joining me today
really appreciate it thank you very much
the organizers as well it's a pleasure
to be here
I've never been to Luxembourg before and
absolutely loved it so far so thank you
today we'll be talking about the Verizon
data breach investigation report here's
a brief agenda for the day or the next
45 minutes at least
first we'll talk about briefly what the
VD BIR is I'll call it the full name VD
BIR the report kind of all of those
interchangeably let's talk about some of
the top trends that are focused on in
the report hot industries this is all
things that are these are all things
that Verizon defines then I'm going to
talk about some defensive techniques and
we'll open it up for some discussion
afterwards so what is the VG Br
this is the 11th year of the report just
a quick note
it's the 2018 report and so that's
focusing on 2017 s data I like to think
of it as kind of a pseudo-random meta
threat intelligence report the
pseudo-random nature of it is defining
where the data comes from there are
three main repositories that Verizon
calls the biggest one and the one that
has the most confidence in terms of the
rice and reporters when they're creating
the report is from their own third-party
investigations so this isn't to say
Verizon's breached every single year
that's kind of a misnomer I think
sometimes when the report comes out
Verizon has an enterprise security team
that does Incident Response in forensics
much like any other kind of mandiant
type of functionality if an organization
feels like they have an issue they can
bring in Verizon and they'll do a triage
and investigation so a Verizon uses the
various framework Varys is the
vocabulary for event reporting and
information sharing it's a great
framework I've used it in the past and
previously in the list positions outside
of I've never worked for a Verizon but I
didn't even know that they created it
until I came across that in the report
but it's a great way to classify and
categorize investigations and breaches
the second repository of data is
investigators that are not part of
Verizon's enterprise security teams that
submit their data to Verizon already in
the various framework so that kind of
has ii love
of confidence moving one down verizon
also has very good relationships with
independent researchers in the field
that don't use varus at all they'll go
and talk to them get kind of a sample of
different investigations that they've
been working on and Verizon will
integrate that into the Bears framework
so focusing on the meta nature of the
report we're not looking at specific
techniques in a single incident throw
over 53,000 incidents that Verizon
classifies in this report 2,000 of which
turned into actual breaches and the
distinction there is that an incident is
anything that affects the CIA triad
so confidentiality integrity and
availability of a system whereas a
breach is as I put it data walking out
the door so that's the kind of final and
Dalby all at RSA I've worked in our
Cirque and we talk about incidents
versus declared incidents so that's kind
of the divide or division between the
two threat intelligence is pretty
self-explanatory freising produces this
report in the hopes that we can all as
an industry learn from the incidents
that have happened in the past and
hopefully prevent them in the future why
does this matter why does this report
matter
well marketing material I mean that's
it's a joke but it is quoted pretty much
everywhere and so it's good to
understand the actual data because
different vendors including my employer
will twist the statistics in this report
to whatever need they they would like to
fill so it's very good to understand the
report as the data itself that being
said it is a great way to translate some
of what's going on in our industry to
lay people it's very palatable very easy
to read from a non security minded
expertise additionally and I think most
important to me is that it's very
difficult to get kind of impartial data
sets of breaches from wide range of
different verticals and industries and
so I look to Verizon and mandiant has
their m trends report every year as very
good sources for this I wish in our
industry we had more of those but I
think it's hard to monetize them that's
probably why
doctrines so there are a number of top
trends throughout the Verizon data
breach investigation report I'm only
going to focus on a few of the biggest
ones including social engineering
ransomware
we'll have a discussion discussion of
insider versus outsider threats then
we'll talk about dwell time and
cryptocurrency mining was pretty much
completely absent in the Verizon data
breach investigation report so we'll
have a brief discussion about why that
may be the case so social engineering I
think we can all agree that social
engineering is a pretty prevalent
problem in our industry especially
phishing basically at least two-thirds
of the incidents in the Verizon did
breach investigation report directly
come back to fishing and I think you
know it's it's pretty common knowledge
that it's much easier and oftentimes at
least to ask someone to hack a human as
opposed to hack an actual system so
that's very likely what's causing the
spike here using stolen credentials is
also the top of a list of data breaches
and again that goes back to the fact
that if you can you know get your way
into someone's head and get passwords
and information from them there's no
need to take a technical approach so
ransomware everyone's probably familiar
with the wanna cry attack if you're not
all you need to do is ask any one of
those companies and many more it did not
go well for them this was probably I
know as an industry we have a lot more
insight into the attacks but outside of
our industry this is probably one of the
biggest wake-up calls in recent years
which is often good for business for us
but it had some pretty damaging effects
not only did FedEx crawl to a halt but
the National Health Service of England
and Scotland were also heavily affected
as were some US hospitals so speaking of
the data that Verizon presented
regarding ransomware it was the number
one Avenue of malware or use of malware
across all the data set so represented
around 39 percent of attacks again
number one this year it rose from four
last year and it was all the way down to
22 in 2014 so ransom wares definitely
had a pretty fast increase in terms of
prevalence
we're also seeing more impact to
critical systems than ever before so it
looks like attackers are becoming a bit
more targeted and the ransomware
campaigns at least advanced and more
sophisticated attackers are doing some
recognizance and discovery to determine
what an organization's crown jewels are
and then infect those specifically
oftentimes that enables them to ask for
much higher payout as an organization
really you know relies on that data or
those systems in order to function
Rass as I call it ransomware as a
service is also another branch of
ransomware that's becoming increasingly
more prevalent there's an entire
industry being created around ransomware
this is more commodity based malware not
those targeted attacks that are
impacting business critical systems but
in these instances it's very easy to
access ransomware services and so they
traditionally have lower ransoms that
are asked of them but with the increase
in prevalence comes an increased costs
like we've never seen before email again
92% of ransomware was delivered via
email so I think it's clear at this
point that email isn't a infection
vector is incredibly popular for attack
campaigns so now let's move to a
discussion of internal versus external
threats this graph was pretty surprising
when I first saw it I don't know if I
was drinking too much of the kool-aid
when it comes to marketing but I think
we as an industry really overemphasize
insider attacks in truth only 27% of
attacks are insider the vast majority
are external threats there are a couple
of reasons I think this could be the
case there are definitely some popular
examples that we can all think of as
insider attacks whether that be Edward
Snowden
more recently reality winter in the
United States there's a lot of damage
that can be done by an insider insiders
often have privileged access to our
systems but as we spoke about previously
in social engineering it's very easy for
a an external actor to become an insider
through credential reuse and theft
something that I found remarkable was 4%
of users will click on any link that
they're presented with so even if it
says like danger danger this is bad
this will hack you please click they
will click before percent sounds
relatively small but that means in a
user base of 25 people someone's going
to be that individual that always clicks
on that link so this goes to a kind of
outside of the report but a different
mentality of designing systems secure by
default I think that's something that we
would really need to focus on in
security user training is great
awareness is amazing but it's it's not
solving the problem let's talk about
insider threats for a little bit the
vast majority of these are due to error
carelessness
so that rogue IT administrator really
doesn't happen that often it's
definitely a scary possibility and and
it does happen from time to time but the
vast majority of threats that we're
seeing are just kind of carelessness
I found it particularly interesting that
healthcare is the only industry that has
more prevalence of insider threats than
external and again the vast majority is
doing duty or carelessness and we'll
talk about that a bit more when I talk
about healthcare is one of the top
industries external threats vast
majority are financially motivated I was
surprised that only 50% were organized
crime syndicates I kind of expected that
to be a bit higher but the financial
motives are rife throughout any sort of
attack campaign and so you don't need to
be you know an organized crime syndicate
like you once did necessarily because
you can get a lot of these tools off the
internet now with very scripted type of
capabilities only 13% of the data set
was found incident incidents in the data
set were found to be a result of
espionage similarly only 12% of the
actors in the data set were advanced
persistent threats so I think much like
insider threats we focus a lot on our
industry on kind of apt apt apt
while that does happen and in public
administration as I'll talk about later
if you work for the government it is a
legitimate concern but in private
enterprise it's just not seen very much
this pretty much matches what I see in
the field when I'm doing Incident
Response and working on engagements it's
very rare that I'll see an incredibly
advanced sophisticated adversary
really maintaining that the persistence
I see a lot of persistent threats
through commodity malware but not many
advanced persistent threats 12-time this
is where we could all do a lot better
this is kind of an embarrassing slide
for us as an industry because 87% of
breaches happen or compromises rather
happened within minutes or seconds
whereas only 3% of the discovery happen
in a similar amount of time so in over
two-thirds of the cases the vast
majority it took months if not years for
incidences incidents to be discovered an
interesting corollary to this is working
for RSA no witness I often see
enterprises coming to me with a
requirement of 90 days of log retention
and so I think if we look at that number
most people quote about three months as
the typical dwell time but had actually
challenged that and say that we can only
see it for three months because you only
have those 90 days of logs it's very
likely that a attacker was inside of
your environment for much longer so it's
an interesting point I don't know what
that says about retention I think
instead of focusing on retention we need
to focus on visibility and getting out
in front of these issues much sooner
so cryptocurrency mining cryptocurrency
mining was mentioned in the Verizon data
breach report all the way 60 pages
through the report for the first time in
appendix D appendix D was their Year in
Review and so it kind of goes through
month by month the 2017 just mentioning
some of the most notable attacks eight
of those twelve months had
cryptocurrency mining so Verizon knows
that this is the thing it knows this is
an issue that we're facing in the field
but it wasn't mentioned at all in any of
the top trends really anywhere in the
report other than that one appendix so I
think something is a bit off here I
don't think it's any maliciousness or
kind of turning a blind eye what I think
really happened and in talking something
with some colleagues most of them agreed
that takes a little bit for us to react
to a threat as sake analysts it then
takes even long
for our industry analyst to write and
report on them so I think it's just a
bit of a lag time that we're seeing here
my guess is that in the 2019 Verizon
day-trip data breach investigation
report cryptocurrency mining is going to
be front and center probably not
dethroning ransomware but way up there
in terms of the top trends looking
outside of the report I think it's just
logical to see cryptocurrency mining
increasing in prevalence not only do you
get immediate return on your investment
you can siphon out funds much quicker
especially at scale but it's also
relatively non-destructive if you're
doing it right or wrong from a defender
standpoint because it can be very easy
to fly under the radar if you're doing a
low and slow type of campaign you can
persist in the environment for months if
not years without anyone really noticing
that anything is going wrong there's
also an interesting thought that I had
when it came to cryptocurrency mining
I'd be interested to know if anyone in
the crowd has any kind of thoughts
towards this but the rise of the crypto
currency markets himself in terms of
financial gain and my personal
experience also kind of correlated to
the rise that I saw cryptocurrency
mining in the field and so I'm
interested to see now that the
cryptocurrency markets have kind of
dropped off if cryptocurrency mining is
no longer as prevalent as it once before
something else that has been talked
about is that the former actors of
ransomware campaigns have pivoted to
cryptocurrency mining that's not
necessarily what I've seen and not what
my colleagues have seen we still see
ransomware pretty prevalent
cryptocurrency mining is just now
supplementing that so on
business-critical systems if you have a
very advanced attacker do a ransomware
campaign otherwise if you have a whole
bunch of hosts cryptocurrency mined in
them
and do that low and slow gain over time
so now let's focus on some hot
industries Verizon breaks up the report
into I believe 12 different industries
but we're just gonna focus on a couple
of the most important ones so healthcare
healthcare is the only industry where
again insider threats are more prevalent
than external threats however human
error is a major contributor again that
element of error and carelessness is
incredibly rife within healthcare
I think as an American at least I can't
speak for the European health care
system which tends to be much better but
when I go to the doctor between doctors
nurses administrators there are infinite
number of systems that they need to
touch on a daily basis just to get their
work done they're also not necessarily
the most technical technologically savvy
individuals nor should they necessarily
need to be but this is probably what's
causing a lot of the error and
carelessness here one thing to note with
an employee employee abuse though is
that around 40 to 50 percent of the
insider threats in healthcare are due to
employee abuse these are things like if
a celebrity was treated at one of your
health care institutions employees are
very likely going to go in and try and
find information not necessarily to
monetize it but just purely out of
interest thought that was relatively
interesting Chervin in terms of external
threats ransomware is huge in health
care I don't know if you heard but
Atlanta the city of Atlanta and Georgia
and New York or Georgia in the United
States suffered from a huge ransom or
attack it mostly focused on government
institutions such as health care police
critical infrastructure so you know
locking up patient records that it
comfort so that an organization can
treat patients is a huge concern public
administration so this is where apt
matters in public administration public
sector over 40% of the breaches were
caused by advanced persistent threat
actors relatively nation-state actors
and so whether it's critical
infrastructure such as voting industrial
control more and more in the future
we're looking at connected cities spies
are definitely inside of our
infrastructure in America we often focus
on the Russians but I would firmly hold
the American intelligence apparatus are
firmly in a lot of other foreign nations
infrastructure so it goes both ways and
it's something that we definitely need
to keep an eye on if you're in any
industry but Public Administration
advanced persistent threats again not a
big concern this is where you do need to
pay attention to them
so the financial industry I'm very proud
and that I have a lot of customers that
are financial enterprises and they are
doing quite well these days they're the
only organization over the past three
years to show a reduction in incidence
and in fact it's a pretty dramatic
reduction the current threats these days
are mainly physical whether it's ATM
card skimming you hear that a lot about
at gas stations or Bakke bank ATMs or
ATM jackpot Eng Barnaby jacked the
famous ATM jack potting at blackhat in
2010 still incredibly current today
education education is a interesting
industry when it comes to this report
because over ten percent of the attacks
in education listed fun as the primary
motive that kind of gave me like a warm
and fuzzy feeling inside because when I
was a student I was definitely doing
things I shouldn't be not a malice at
all but purely out of interest and
curiosity and so we still see that that
is ripe and alive in education these
days this is also a great graph because
it means absolutely nothing to me
if anyone in this in this audience can
determine a you know sensical trend out
of this I would love to hear it the one
nugget of gold that I kind of get from
this is you can make a lot of trends in
our industry as I'll talk about in the
defensive techniques section reports
such as these can be invaluable to your
organization but they're also certain
things that you can't make transitive so
if you're a defender in education you're
not gonna try and you know focus on
cyber espionage as your main attack
vector that you're protecting because
while that may matter one year it
clearly won't matter the next so you
need to take a very robust defensive
posture when you're in a field like this
so now going on to defensive techniques
visibility is one of the biggest things
that I wish I had more of when I was an
analyst in organizations when I talk
about visibility I'm not just talking
about logs I'm talking about network and
endpoint data as well logs are great for
getting that kind of knock at the door
kind of a little bit of information
about what's going on but it's really
the network and packet day
that our network and endpoint data that
I use in my investigations to do the
deep forensic look into what's going on
it's impossible to really get the entire
scope of the attack campaign surely from
logs so this is a great graph that
Verizon puts out in the data breach
investigation report if there's anything
that you see in the report if there's
only one thing you see I recommend you
take a look at this it's probably very
hard to see from here and so let's just
take a little look at a subset of that
so these are incidents of those four
industries that I talked about
previously and this just is going to say
that you really need to tailor your
defenses not only to your industry but
your specific environment so looking at
industry specific determine what threats
are most prevalent in your industry you
can do this using Verizon you can look
at you can take these kind of
overarching patterns and layer them on
top of something like miters attack
framework I'm a huge fan of that I
understand they're giving a training
upstairs I'm pretty jealous that I'm not
in that but it's incredibly valuable to
do this type of intelligence whether you
have a dedicated threat intelligence
team in your organization or if you're
just layering it on top of some of your
hunting X exercises so for example if
you're in public administration you're
not gonna try and defend point-of-sale
systems that's just not where the
attackers are looking right now they
mean this in the future you know things
like DMV point-of-sale or Department of
Motor Vehicle and other sort of
institutions that have point-of-sale
systems but currently that's not what
they're going after
far more interested again in that cyber
espionage and that I didn't want to say
it that will be my one cyber for the
talk I promise you that so you also need
to maintain a security posture relevant
to your own organization and the the
kind of capabilities of your
organization manual had a great talk
earlier today in the top of the morning
talked a lot about process people and
technologies it's very much true for
this as well if you're a junior
organization and you have one intern on
your security team you're not going to
ask them to hunt all day so
if you don't have a sim you shouldn't
invest in AI machine learning deep
dreaming technologies that aren't really
gonna do much for you the last point is
I also highly recommend that
organizations create a report like this
for themselves doesn't need to be
anything external not nearly as robust
as Verizon does but there are two main
things that you can do here the first
and probably the most important is
baselining the attacks that you see in
your environment this will help you
fine-tune graphs like this and you can
layer your own data on top of someone
like Verizon's additionally it will give
you some ammunition to go to your board
of directors your executive team and
show what you've done
oftentimes in security I think we're you
know often ignored if we're not heard
and so being heard from normally means
knocking on someone's door that you
don't want to and having an awkward
conversation about a breach this is a
great way to kind of get ahead of those
conversations and show what you're doing
and the value that you're bringing to
the organization without necessarily
need to do that in incident
investigation scenario so multi-factor
authentication I had to do a little RSA
throw up here but what we're really
talking about today is Hardware tokens
Google had an amazing report where Krebs
had an amazing report on Google that
found that since they rolled out
Hardware tokens and they do actually use
GB keys there they haven't had this was
an early 2017 they rolled them out and
since then about a couple months ago
they haven't had a single incidence of
phishing amongst their 85,000 plus
employees so that's incredibly
impressive and rolling out something
like multi multi factor authentication
is relatively low overhead and so if you
can do that one thing in your
organization it's a great way to get out
ahead of the threats that we're seeing
finally just going back to basics
talking about like sysadmin 101 you
don't need to have you know the battle
starship from day one you can just start
patching and backing up we talked about
patching a lot and I know it's not often
as easy as it is said patch where you
can try to have some political pressure
bring awareness to why patching matters
and backup is very very easy I've never
seen an organization that has much
friction when they try and roll out a
robust backup plan that's gonna help you
very much so with those ransomware
campaigns instead of being to you know
hoard Bitcoin and have a special bank
account where your company has Bitcoin
on reserve just backup every night and
if you get hit go back to a clean copy
next thing is kind of CISSP 101
permissions so privileged suite
permissions of least privilege only give
people what they need access to to do on
a daily basis review those privileges on
a quarterly or at least yearly basis and
make sure that people are still
accessing the assets that they have
access to Netflix has a great program I
believe it's freely available on github
forget the name of it right now but it
will automatically roll way permissions
I'm kind of a roving random basis so if
someone complains very easily scripts it
and turns the permission back on but if
no one notices that they lost their
permission they probably shouldn't have
had it in the first place so that is the
entirety of my presentation any
questions at all I do have some
discussion topics just spur debate and
comments everyone is so opinionated in
our industry I can't believe no one has
a question or so you are correctly
pointing out the importance of patching
and allowing for a patch where you can
strategy if you if you can't patch
everything you know you should patch the
Delta there turns out to be really
important so energy spent auditing your
patching strategies so that you know
what isn't patched is actually got a
bigger payoff than patching what you can
thank you I think
incredibly salient point once you do
know what's not patched in your
environment by increasing the visibility
that you have there and increasing the
monitoring that can be almost as good as
patching something in the first place so
if you have a high valued asset in your
environment that you can't patch whether
it's critical infrastructure or legacy
system at least monitor the heck out of
it because that's gonna give you a very
high fidelity or return since she's not
here to mention it himself Michi occult
sec in Slovenia has a very interesting
protic called Oh patch I don't know if
you've seen it it's basically a micro
patch where he patches one single
machine instruction where the
vulnerability is so install an agent on
a server or workstation he pushes out
and a micro patch and the vulnerability
is gone until the actual patch can be
released or for unpassable things this
one is harmless interesting that the
project is called a patch and I'll
definitely need to look into that thank
you it will soon be available also for
enterprises with a subscription where
you can say for these types of devices
and applications I want to be sure that
there will be opiates available for this
and this and that
no that's great I can see a whole bunch
of practical application yeah thank you
for that anything else
did what Verizon saw and reported on
does that make sense so there's the the
top threats that you guys are seeing in
your enterprises you just give like a
yea or nay i I just have a question ho
do you use this report and actually do
you use the information that you find
here in New Delhi job yep I absolutely
do use this report I've been using the
report since around the fifth version I
think in late 2000s when I was a soccer
analyst and so I would absolutely look
at my industry look at the compromises
that are prep
and relate that back to the security
posture that I was defining so it's a
great way to kind of find holes that you
potentially have oftentimes we need to
be so reactionary in our jobs that it's
very difficult to stand back and take a
look at the real landscape what we're
essentially facing and so this was a
great kind of level setter for me you
know it's pretty beefy report but it
only takes a you know weekend to turn
through maybe once or twice and really
get some actionable intelligence from so
that was the goal today was just to kind
of distill a bit of that to you guys
hopefully you can take this back to your
enterprise yeah so so I just fell in so
I hope this question was not erased what
I was thinking and I would like to have
your opinion because I was just like
wondering would it make sense and I
don't know if any of you ever did that
since the horizon data Beach report is
now a de facto thing and you've every
time it comes out people just jump on it
and claim that they read it but usually
didn't at least they looked at the fancy
charts and whatnot
have you for example I don't know maybe
you Walter but maybe someone in the in
the participants have you guys ever used
the things that they list out there all
the metrics to measure it in your
environment and then compare it what you
have as an average there and would this
make sense since we're looking at so it
did are probably not the best metrics
but at least we have historical
representation of I think the most
common one is the time to detect thing
that usually that's the most like
referred one have you guys measuring
that because still in a lot of cases in
IR teams they're not really looking in
that one but they do something stupid
like the number of tickets so what would
this make sense what do you think yet
that that was actually something that I
mentioned that was that was kind of a
little golden nugget is is I encourage
you know all the companies that I work
with all my friends that work at
companies to develop these reports
internally again don't need to be
external at all but I don't know
a single company that has taken me up on
this that does publish it and they don't
certainly need to be as robust it for
aizen's but it's a great way to again
layer your own data on top of horizons
to kind of make it sense a little bit
more for you and to baseline your own
environment and so compared to what you
have in and as an average like are they
blow under like what is your experience
that they're doing better than the
average worse than the average are they
even honest
doing yeah so to speak to the honesty
real quick a friend of mine a couple
years ago took a job with Verizon
enterprise security and that was my
first question I was like are they
actually listening to you guys or is it
like a marketing like a Gartner type of
thing where they figure out what they
want to say and then put some statistics
behind it and he said that no the the
report writers are heavily embedded with
the enterprise security division of
Verizon and all of this data comes
straight from the investigations that
they do so I was very glad to hear that
the first part of the question in terms
of really making this your own I
generally see a little bit of deviation
in some of the attack techniques that
are most used but the trends in terms of
the you know the top three or five
things that certain industries are
facing are generally dead-on you know
little standard deviation but I've been
pretty impressed not only with kind of
this year's report but historically how
well lay chart some of some of the kind
of trends in the industry and there's a
really good companion site to the
Verizon data breach investigation report
that Verizon puts out that has all sorts
of visualizations that you can interact
with and modify to kind of even make it
more your own I'm still waiting for them
I've been trying to work with them to
open-source some of the engines that
they used to create the report so that
it's easier for organizations to take it
at their own data and have a a private
version they of course want that to feed
back into their cloud repository but I
don't think they'd get much traction you
know if that was the case so I'd love to
see them have kind of a you know offline
version of this that you can modify for
your own
I have a command again if I may um on
the kpi's and of like say the most cited
breach statistic a date there's a new
book out that I is on my Christmas wish
is that I really hope it's called that
works I win
top old book which is called time-based
security which according to him and
several Rob several of the people who
recommend the book online and in an in
the book itself is a new security
strategy that risk-based security by
mots be aware but I'm looking forward to
reading about it yeah that's really
funny I was a dinner with when a couple
of months ago and I hadn't heard of his
new project and he was talking about it
and it sounds amazing it sounds like it
could be you know we have a few cannons
in our industry type of go-to resources
but a lot of them are relatively
outdated at this point and so I'm very
excited to see it I was kind of probing
him to get a sneak peek and he shared
some things but I think I'll need to
wait until I get my own copy but I
believe it's out now right yeah yeah I
think it was released about a month or
two ago and so um yeah I should have
read it um so I'm still just jumping
back a bit what you say so you said that
some of your friends and you as well
started generating these numbers and
seeing how well you're doing compared to
the average how long they've been doing
it or how long you've been doing it and
how do you improve you managed to
improve on those numbers or any and also
is it more something that you show to
management so something more that you
feed in as a more strategic thing or use
it more for your like tactical needs and
say that okay we're not doing well let's
improve on our processes and and try to
figure out better ways to detect
compromise yeah I think both are very
important I think from a tactical
perspective
of creating a report like this for your
own organization it's a great way again
to baseline you know you don't need a
machine learning algorithm to baseline
some of these simple statistics you can
just put them in an Excel spreadsheet
and see how it goes
year by year at the most simple basis
again it's also incredibly useful to
show to your management I spoke a little
bit previously about how security only
interfaces with the executive branch
during a breach oftentimes basically
when things go wrong so this is a great
way to get out ahead of that and show
the productiveness of your division
within an enterprise without needing to
kind of have a black eye in the process
in terms of the longevity and how long
I've seen people creating their own
versions I work with one customer who
didn't even need my recommendation
during an engagement I present my report
they gave me historical report believe I
went back around five years so they've
been doing this for for quite a long
time and what they've done now is
they've integrated it with their soar
platform their security orchestration
and automation response platform to
automate a lot of the collection of
these these statistics so things like
meantimes resolution they have a little
bash lit in the top corner of their sock
manager dashboard so they can always see
where they are in their SLA is the
analysts don't necessarily love that
because it's very easy to profile them
and see who's doing work and who's not
but it's it's a great way to help
improve even within a sock perspective
you know if analyst X deals with certain
incidents much better and analyst Y
deals with other incidents much better
it's a great way to kind of optimize
workflows so that's from a more tactical
soft perspective I do have organizations
I've started writing my Incident
Response reports in more of a framework
like this talking about trends TTP's and
then vertical specific intelligence that
I kind of layer on top of what I've seen
in their environment and then I
encourage them I leave portions blank
kind of a template for them things that
I didn't have the purview on but I
encourage them to fill out and then
maintain that year after year I think
proactive hunting has become a big thing
whether specific to an environment or if
you bring in a third party to do it was
kind of an incident response discovery I
would highly encourage folks to do that
I've been a part of a number of those
where companies have been going through
mergers and acquisitions before they
flip that switch and let the newly
acquired company into their network they
do not necessarily a pen test and not
really a vulnerability scan kind of a
mixture of the two or they do a
proactive defensive exercise to see
exactly what's going on in that that
property before they bring it into the
into the castle that answer yeah well
this is getting back in in terms of
improvement are they able to I'm not
saying that they should you know strive
for just moving the needle but they're
really able to because once you see
these data then you realize that your
might not doing as well as you thought
are they have in their program once they
started measuring these a point where
they try to improve on that and if they
were able to do that so for example in
one case like the the mean time to
detect dropped in the past few years a
lot of people tie that to the fact that
now ransomware was was a thing
so they take into teasing into account
as well but it so how did it improve on
it that would be interesting for me yeah
I've definitely seen improvement I think
the biggest way that I've seen
improvement is budgetary if you have a
report like this explaining exactly what
the trends are your environment you can
take that to leadership and say you know
this is the justification for this
technology yeah giving giving them
actual numbers yeah instead of just
saying that we need more money yeah
exactly but I have seen it improve with
training as well so if you're an
organization that's facing you know four
different threats and you see one of
them is affecting you a lot more that's
a good indication that your knowledge
base is lacking in that one area from a
defensive standpoint so whether you
bring someone in who's an expert in that
field or if you pollinate your own
existing analysts with training I've
seen that that work as well in one
particular example someone was getting
nailed with web application stuff
they had no idea was coming in through
that vector they thought it was a much
different type of attack and so they
schooled up one of their analysts
actually through sans training and that
didn't make a market decrease in that
attack vector it was also a very limited
actor so I think just recognizing it in
the first place was a big step forward
for them but then to have those
technical chops on your team prevents
those types of things from happening in
the future
so no other questions yeah sure it's a
good topic so a few years ago they
changed the way that they presented the
top vulnerabilities used to compromise
companies and the data that went into
the report was totally wrong every
single vulnerability in there was wrong
they messed it up somehow
I think they republished with the
correct vulnerabilities but then in the
last one they took this out entirely
which data which I found interesting and
relevant because I can also tie it to
the OS 10 which someone just analyzed in
the respect of which vulnerabilities
were actually used to compromise
companies again similar to what we rise
and wanted to do and stop doing what do
you think of Verizon taking out data
from this report that some of us
consider valuable yeah that to be
completely honest that was very
disappointing for me as well it is in
the report here and there and some of
the appendices the online companion tool
actually does the best way of kind of
getting to the granularity of the actual
tactics and techniques that are being
used I think so my perspective on that
and correct me if you have a different
one what I saw happening was a lot of
attribution being surrounded by those
certain tactics and techniques so if you
saw a certain you know rootkit let's say
being used there was such a media focus
now in our industry that
they'd initially oughta automatically
pretty much assign a specific
attribution to that you know this was
North Korea and I think you know we can
probably all agree that's incredibly
dangerous attribution is not a game that
I ever want to play due to a number of
factors but that's kind of where I
sensed it going in terms of Verizon no
longer wanted to put their name behind
this as this technique equals this
person they certainly weren't making
that jump in the report but I think a
lot of the media attention started going
there where they're saying Verizon
saying that you know fancy bear is using
this against these industries that's not
what they were doing but it was easier
and easier as more of these techniques
we're getting associated with actors to
make those leaps in popular media at
least that I do wish there was a good
resource for that
I think mitre has really kind of filled
that gap the attack framework does have
pretty good granularity sometimes too
much granularity when I show it to some
of my you know customers they're like
wow this is like a hundred and twenty
eight boxes like can we get like four
there's definitely value immense value I
think in the granularity that they they
take it but some middle ground at least
for you know director manager levels
would be appreciated
yeah I think that was the ohi's featured
that in the executive summary so not
only was it in the full report but even
if you had you know somewhat of a lay
person without really who doesn't live
and breathe security like we do they
could still easily digest those TTP's
yeah and you know question clouds no
yeah we still have fifteen minutes so
who are not vents on the break okay so
thank you Walter
thank you guys
[Applause]