yes hello everyone so my name is Daniele
and today I'm going to present on the
PDA which is a project that I've now
been pursuing for almost two years first
before we get into it let me take my
co-workers on this one so Martin had a
lot with the revelation framework and
statistics that we've used to present
some of the results that are later in
the store and Stefan basically program
most of the website and platform that's
basically used to deliver the data and
interact with with my PDF and my
supervisor and I'm always happy when I
can talk to him and exchange ideas so
the outline for the store is basically I
start with a summary so you get
directing to the topic and what's it all
about
then I go back about two years in time
motivating how we came to that idea and
what basically has happened unto them I
give a layout of the approach that we
have followed and then present my PDA
itself and the next step is basically
showing you what you can do with this
corpus so essentially what I'm
presenting here is a very clean corpus
of malware of unpacked nerve actually
and then going a bit in the future so
for the summary what's map idea so from
the intention is basically a free
independent put resource for
confidential labeled unpick reference
samples from other memories inversions
so everything in one sentence basically
means I try to have a good coverage of
many families then have the abortions
tracked as well trying to limit it to as
many as few symbols as possible so I
want to have a small corpus that's still
very representative and I'm very happy
to share this kind of data at the same
time along with the samples it makes
sense to track all the meta data because
right now if you think about it how are
you going to find blog posts on
something you're going Google and that's
a lot of effort otherwise we could
basically directly attach those
references to the samples so you have
everything in one place so it's one of
the ideas here and since we have a nice
corpus and we can also basically test
and develop our yaro rules against it so
that's the some of the ideas here
so looking about one week ago I had
roughly
two and a half thousand member samples
there for around 670 families and I'm
targeting multi-platforms not only
Windows malware but also embedded stuff
I at least of apks OSX
JavaScript's because that's a thing as
well and everything in that corpus so
the contributions of this work because
there's also paper to it ever we
released later on
first we define some requirements that
we think are useful thing to follow if
you're basically creating such a corpus
and then we provide our vision or our
take on this corpus and the platform as
well and the second part is basically we
do a comprehensive quantitative static
analysis so basically looking at the
structure across all of those families
and provide some results on that as well
so how did all of this begin so who was
at what come 2015 so some of you guys I
have to do it that way might remember
that there was distinct so quite a bunch
of TTA talks and yeah I'm one of those
guys so I basically presented on my
previous project which was DG archive so
basically a clean collection of Agra
from Berkeley generated domain names
however as much renting there was on
DJ's I still feel from the feedback I
received that's a good project because
um when you provide created systemize
data you can do really good stuff with
it and also since it was launched I had
more than one and a half million queries
to DG archive so it seemed League is
also used by some people in 2015 there
was another thing does anyone recall
this slide it's actually from a
lightning talk so there was this plug
watt plug X so basically when Crowder
gave his lightning talk on that we have
a synonym problem basically with malware
so everyone is preferring to stuff in a
different way and we cannot really come
to consensus and what he basically
proposed us let's let's try to do
something and fix it I didn't really
talk to him but I thought also it was a
good idea because when I basically came
back from kampf
I looked at all the data that I had so
I'm from several years I had basically
the idea I'm
sitting on a pile of Investigations that
I've done and debated I structured
amidst them normally probably by date I
have to sample I might have a dumb might
have unpacked samples might have an ID
be some some text and write up for it
and what is somewhat structured is still
mess and what came to me is basically it
might be a good idea to do this in a way
more structured fashion so I thought
having a code centric inventory that's
basically focusing on static analysis
would be like really really good because
we can basically resolve over our
synonym and naming problem with it
because it's it's like a rosetta stone
where you have pieces that you can refer
to and basically put just a lame label
on it because code is basically the
basis that we can find consensus on when
we try to name stuff I guess yeah and
another thing that I've learned from
ggrf is basically we as a mother
research community should definitely
start thinking about preservation
because when I tried to recover as many
ggs as possible I ran into stuff like a
Zener wall or TDS s that were active
around 2008 2011 or more and it's very
hard to find samples for those families
by today's standards so even if I'm very
sure that they are somewhere in the in
the deaths of virustotal and hidden
there it's hard to find those examples
that consist or basically contain the
DGA code especially if it's not like a
first stage drop or something but a
module that's being pulled it can be
hard to find the kind of stuff so
basically having this this archived
repository of mother families might be a
good idea
from the perspective as well so for
related work
um so Erica's not here this year but at
least I want to have him in my slides
he's been doing this but mess of our
project which is basically a wiki like
structure also trying to cover many
different malware families but in that
sense it's just metadata that's also the
zoo that was referenced yesterday
because um you were using it as a label
injection when you do we're doing
clustering I think there is basically
it's still mostly pecked malware and
it's only semi structure that's caught
that way because you sometimes have
folders that basically contain the same
family or you have one folder containing
more than one family and stuff like that
virus pay is a quite
new project it seems to follow some same
ideas that I've been doing with my PDA
but I think it's more focused on
knowledge exchanged and actually trying
to build this kind of archive that I'm
pursuing here and finally you have
projects like ID ransomware that's also
I guess keep their collection but it's
basically hidden and not accessible
directly so basically that's also only
metadata yeah so also the title is
basically inventor rising Netscape and
what do I mean by that
so it's basically a kind of a sling now
it sounds a bit like cartography and
that's basically what I basically my
vision for this project in the in the
long run is so cartography in a
historical sense is basically done with
baselines and the fun facts basically in
bond is one of the older ones of such
baselines
so in bond we have this distance of
round about two kilometers which has
been used to measure a very long stretch
of land afterwards so you basically have
this plate which basically tells you
what it was used for it's basically a
pillar somewhere involved and from a
theory you'd measure other points that
you can see in a distance and then by
the angle it's derived basically the
disband that's basically width between
those points that you're measuring
and in those times basically it has been
used to to cover the whole distance from
Athens uruk's so run about four
kilometers and that kind of started in
Bonn so it was just some fun fact that I
wanted to bring up here so apply to
malware we could do that as well I guess
so if we are trying to collect some
reference points for families and
versions we could measure code somehow
or at least do an indexation on it so
that's basically my vision for this
whole thing so I thought okay let's give
it a shot and that was basically run
about two years ago so for the approach
I thought it might make sense to go one
step back and try to do it's just
somatically from the start so what are
probably some goats that you would want
to pursue if you build another corpus so
I thought there's this work from 2007
2012 by Christian Russell and he defined
some prudent practices that's one people
people would should follow if you are
doing Mary experiments
and I thought okay that's reviewed and
try if you can find some things that we
can reapply and from that we basically
found our own requirements that are
basically more tailored to our special
case which is basically looking at
static analysis so some of the major
goals that you might have in mind there
is you want representative data I think
that's pretty obvious because you want
to have coverage in multiple angles at
the same time it has to be temporal in a
good sense so you can probably do some
historical analysis on malware it
doesn't make sense to them into a
platform because you still can out a
piece of the corpus afterwards if you
want to do that and if you want to do
some analysis on the evolution of
families you need to have different
abortions as well a second design goal
was basically to have everything and
then accessible format so it's it has to
be easy to work with so that's very
important and for me it was of utmost
impatience to have unpacked samples
because just putting labels on packed
samples doesn't really help
so unpack this cool and to some degree
it also makes sense to clean an app
because if you have process injection
you might have some fragments that are
not really related to the family but are
still present in memory done that you're
doing so you have to do some
post-processing to you have actually
really cool data and while we're on it
um let's not just up with levels but do
all of this just made our data think
directly in the same run basically yeah
and finally um I thought okay this
should not be academically isolated so
let's see if we can find some practical
use with it as well so first off it
probably has to be topical and
maintainer so it's not just today now
dump this the Soul corpus thing but I
will try to have this maintained and
basically that's the collaborative
aspect to it and I invite basically all
of you to contribute to this kind of
repository because I guess it benefits
all of us and finally it probably ought
to make sense to provide some tooling so
that you can basically work with it so
for me it was quite important and that's
still a lot of work to have good Yara
coverage of all of the covers because
that really helps us solve maybe this
identification problem now finally I'm
from of her that I'm working for
as nonprofit organizations so we can
step in to some degree as something
vendor-neutral and maybe we can reach
some consensual branch ophea okay let's
go back to to Christians work so like I
said it's basically a list of things to
consider when you're doing experiments
with malware and it's basically 18
different aspects that are organized
into four categories so first you want
to ensure that you have the correct data
set but that means you probably have to
divide between good wear and malware
that you want to keep balanced across
the families that you're using a new
experimentation that you separate
training data from a relation data that
you have to think about artifacts and a
lot that kind of stuff and there's
basically things to consider since we
are building a malware corpus the the
good path aspect and the experiment
aspect to it basically does not really
affect us but just there's some some
good ideas to put in secondly you want
to do transparency in how you publish
the results so that means that you
publish the data set that you explain
where the labels are coming from which
expert experiment setup we have been
using and that you also do very
scrutinized analysis of your results so
when you do for example the
classification method that you explain
how true positives and false positives
and false negatives basically constitute
themselves and then why are happening
then you want to do realism because you
can live in your ivory tower and do all
your isolated experiments that you want
and if you want other people to use it
you probably have to look at relevance
and that means that you have to look at
the real world and in that sense
basically that the experiments should be
designed in a way that's similar to come
over basically encountered in the wild
and finally safety is also something to
consider because if you're working with
malware you might potentially post harm
to outside parties so you have to think
about the deployment and containment
that you have to put in place so for us
um we basically came down to six things
that we thought would be good
requirements for the good novel corpus
and it's basically limited to static
analysis in that sense so I already said
that so
of content makes sense we want you to
cross-platform because only doing
Windows is kind of not no longer the
time now unpack examples accurate labels
do the documentation part because we
want to explain how we came to the data
and basically what the context of it and
finally um that's something probably
debatable but I think the creation
should be controlled in a sense because
I want to ensure that the format that
we've been using to set up this corpus
um still stays the same and stays intact
and also this dissemination should be
limited so it's not that you can just go
to the website and download everything
but we employ some basic vetting here so
that we can at least to some degree
ensure that the data is not flowing
wildly so for presentative content um we
want to look at relevant malware that
means if you do it that way is probably
also useful for for incident handlers or
for other instances in the real world
and that might be doing research
one thing is we favor quality over
quantity so it's it's not the goal
basically to roll the corpus as fast as
possible but rather look beyond what we
can now call something that you pick up
barrier so um if you look at how most
campaigns are operated you will find
polymorphism in in how packers are
basically applied to to certain versions
of malware but beyond this pickup area
it comes down to way less different
versions that you can actually observe
in the wild and that means we can
basically limit ourselves to only
representants of a version for one
family and that really is an aspect that
helps down boiling down this data set to
only DD necessary parts so just to give
you an example for that and we've been
doing another config data mining since
2012 as well and if you look at Citadel
for example which was a very popular
family at that time we had run about
100,000 unique cetera samples over time
if you run all of them do dynamic
analysis very similar to what we've seen
bye-bye syrup yesterday
you probably cannot identify many more
than like twenty one versions for all of
those samples so if you're only
interested in archiving the code and the
evolution of Citadella in that sense you
can probably achieve a data reduction
factor of maybe four and a half thousand
so in that sense we would not be
interested in in storing all of the
Citadelle samples but only one per
version and that's something that you
can also observe for for a bunch of
other families as well so there's
there's a huge amount of timber going
around s procs
but there's normally only some
mainstream versions because they are
maintained by some novel author and then
he has to basically publish that as well
and that basically ensures that there's
not that much flowing around so
basically this is called maintenance
aspect that you have on the side of a
normal malware developer basically
effects them as well so they probably
have to have some distribution channels
and are not as fast as pushing versions
or it is not if you look at trust all of
the MLB landscape yeah cross-platform
yes 2017 so let's be real we had some
major incidents over the last year that
basically affected monitor system so
just do it that way so be it Mirai Lukas
is basically twittering a lot about
recent mother on Android and stuff like
that so just incorporate all of that as
well
for unpacked samples um there's
basically essentially if you want to do
effective static analysis because you
don't want to worry about Packers you
just directly want to be sure that
you're working on the actual maverick
code and yet discuss discussable if you
want to do dumping or unpacking and my
opinion the dumping is actually a better
way to approach this because normally
some of the intermediates parts that may
be acquired during the unpacking process
of the Packer itself are not really of
interest unless you are doing analysis
of Packers and dumps usually also
contain some more runtime data and this
can be decrypted strings at times you
may may have some dynamic API usage so
basically you have saw more API coverage
then you would have any cleany disk
unpacked sample and do not have to vary
finding the routine that's basically
doing DD api imports and stuff like that
and there's also way easier to autumn
because like I said you can normally
just run it at a certain point decide
that you want to take it down now
furthermore I think dumps also can serve
as some kind of normalization because
there's certain other families that only
exist as share code so having them honor
this basically would mean that you have
to find that exact point where desert
share code is staged by some loader into
memory or whatever but if you say okay
I'm really just interested in dumping it
then basically I have the same
representation which is memory mapped
and initialized for the share code and
for every other program basically as
well yeah accurate neighbors and
metadata so basically this whole project
is somewhat centered around family
identification so that means we first
need to find some accurate labels for
the families in the first place but also
there should be for example plugins
checked if we are able to find those
plugins so say you are you have a
banking malware which is different
information stealer plugins and we're
also interested in to archiving those as
well
documentation yeah like I said so
looking at Christians proven practices
basically explaining how we got to the
dumps is something of importance or
basically where we are getting the
samples from so that basically allows to
ensure that we have accountability and
repository bility so when we are doing
experiments you can do them as well and
hopefully we end up with the same
results
tracking the origin of samples normally
means since I get most of the samples
from publications of AV companies thread
into companies and they like I probably
try to include a reference where
basically got aware of the hash in the
first place and explaining the dumping
method and environment stuff we we get
into debt in a couple of minutes yeah
controlled creation and dissemination so
the last point here like I said we want
to ensure that the structure of the
whole repository stays intact even over
the course of time with having more
users and having them contribute to the
data and limiting access is basically
needed to avoid harm to the general
public because if you just download the
stuff let it run that's probably not a
good idea or you might have some use
that are not really into familiar with
how you treat malware and they might
just download in a double-click it and I
don't want to be blamed for that kind of
stuff okay
so how are we going to put this now into
practice I will first explain some of
the terminology so basically what I mean
if I call something a family or
something is unpacked and stuff like
that then I explain the collection
approach again in some more detail and
are we produced or stamps and finally
how the course is organized so if you're
later on working with it so that's
probably of interest to you and also how
much data we already have in there right
now so what's another family it's from a
modern standpoint I guess it's not
really cleanly defined what a malware
family is and everyone probably has
their slight different fuzzy definition
of it so I'm just going to try and give
you my current definition where the meta
family is so basically all samples that
you can find that belong to the same
project from a developer's point of view
so basically the way we are tracking
families means that someone normally has
the responsibility has created the code
is maintaining the code and that's
basically what defines a family for me
what this allows you is that you can
basically also group those components to
this family that only work in context of
the family so be it some customized
loader some plugins that are interacting
with the the main module of the family
and stuff like that but it also allows
you to basically deal with stuff like
source code leaks so look at Zeus I'm
not going to call everything
Zeus that's basically derived from Zeus
so we can split off stuff like Citadel
isin and came over Peter peer-led later
stuff in the same way you can also look
at the same project that has been a
rewrite so there's a couple of families
in there like three or four I guess that
basically are the very same malware but
rewritten in another language so you
would have someone start off with Delfy
and suddenly he thinks it's cooler so he
rewrites this bar in the same way just
in in C for example what's an unpacked
sample
so for me that's a direct representative
of the family so there's no longer other
third party code involved that's usually
used to protect or obfuscate or whatever
you want it so I'm third party in that
sense basically I have another family or
maybe a sample that I've created with
the Builder and then apply the Packer to
it the amp example would be basically
again the sample without the background
stuff however this does not include for
example addressing deification so if the
obfuscation is part of the mother family
itself unpacking to me does not mean
that I have to remove this office Keshan
because it's basically a feature of the
family and for example can can help to
identify it and from a classic sense
because that's just basically how I when
I got into it but what we meant when
we're talking about unpack now where it
would be something that you are able to
run from disk again so basically the
probably unmapped version that's on this
you double-click it and NMFS running
directly opposed to that what's dump
sample well with the memory capture of
the malware and normally will then
include some initialized data and that's
an issue if you want to go back to the
the unpacked runnable sampler from from
a dump sample you normally or sometimes
after the point at this initial data
initialized data basically will
interfere with you in the sample will
just crash but dumping can also include
that you look at some oxidative modules
that amalgam I have or some of the other
memory that it has allocated weights for
example storing some of its imports or
some additional codes that it is jumping
to and that you also track that as well
so once more tests this quality over
quantity thing the philosophy that I've
been pursuing as I rather want to extend
the coverage as many families right now
as possible then going deep into a
single family so I could basically say I
want to have the best coverage of dried
eggs and trick bottom what but it would
probably take a lot of my time that I
can allocate to things and right now
still the ideas to get a good coverage
in in the white sense
so that's basically this dis quality
thing that you can use it to identify as
many different families as possible just
a stronger emphasis on verification then
by now I've been doing a lot of manual
work to ensure the basically this is a
very clean corpus so that's also a way
to push quality but a lot of effort let
me tell you that it can also mean that
we prioritize on families that are more
active or more impactful normally I'm
somewhat following my filter bubble and
look at the blog posted I would normally
encounter and probably prefer those as
well so by having more contributors
probably this basically will have the
impact of widening what we consider as
something should be prioritized in the
long run it is a really good idea to
write some means of quality assurance so
say you have a Yara rule for every of
the families you can also ensure that
your yards do not have false positives
on other families and in the same way
that they are still recently enough to
find new versions whenever you add them
to the corpus and we've got two data
origins
I prefer public sources where possible
and basically everything that similar
PDS also found a virustotal so it's like
97% so I really want to have stuff that
can be obtained in another fashion as
well okay I said we do multi-platform
stuff because it makes sense to track
that as as we are progressing but I'm
still having a strong focus on Windows
malware because there's at least where
the most families are still documented
where we have the most history so that's
basically what I've been focusing on
with the doms the method that I employ
there is basically to have very fixed VM
states that I used to derive the doms
from and what's the benefit of that well
I have very known and fixed system
parameters to it so for example even if
it's using a SLR most of the static
windows API function offsets will remain
the same in all of the different memory
segments that you will encounter them
and this allows you to apply some
techniques
to rapidly extract those windows API
functions on arbitrary dumps as long as
they have to be produced by this
basically environment so I'm using
mostly Windows XP and Windows 7 and no
one's gasping but it's so oh it why are
using like with operating systems that
are like more than 10 years old it's
pretty easy because it still feels like
most novice feeling most at home there
because you have fewer embedded
protection systems by the operating
system directly so my goal is basically
maximizing execution success so I want
to have the most vulnerable system
darris and that works kind of good as
well what can you do as well of course
you should install all the runtimes you
want to have all the dotnet runtimes
because you really have to give you
malware a place to feel home and it has
to run and has not a crash so I'm really
interested in producing dumps so I have
to make it for the memory as easy as
possible to run you have a three are two
dumping our methodologies is pretty
simple I guess you just run it wait if
the memory that has basically changed
during execution and then filter down to
what you think is the unpacked version
so basically the dump and then you
potentially repeat it because you missed
something or there's nothing to
basically extract or what frequently
happens you have to inject manually and
that's quite painful so um if I had to
guess I guess I've spent more than 600
hours of doing this unpacking and
dumping already so on the other hand I
think that's sadly the only way how to
get dumped for some of the families
because what you can observe there's
basically something it gets mapped is
fingerprinting your environment and will
unwrap itself if it's not happy and
that's totally something that most sand
boxes will not give you or even if they
gave it to you you might just drown in
the data so I've quite some experience I
guess with unpacking and stuff so in
many cases it was more natural to me to
just look quickly at something and then
try to cover it up that way in many
cases what you can dump there
already fine but sometimes like I said
you will have some overlay or for
example the packet sample and the amp
example in the beginning of the same
buffer or something so it makes sense to
basically cut off the tail and things
like that in order to to clean up the
malware because if you're later applying
static analysis methods to it you really
only want the coat of the extra mega
family and not the chef that's basically
on its tail
yeah for identification um yeah the
better your coverage is the faster you
can do it otherwise it's also manual
investigation has someone basically
blocked somewhere about those strings
that I've just found in this buffer that
I'm looking at so a lot of work so let's
of Michelle if you're interested in how
the data is stored basically it's it's
more or less this tree like structure so
on top level you would have platform dot
family name and for example let's take
you also on something that I'm very
familiar with because I have been
looking at it for a couple years
below the family folder you would have
ideally folders perversion
so that basically allows you a direct
grouping in those folders you would have
samples stored as 256 and along them we
would have the dumps with basically the
base address from where they have been
dumped as well as unpacked samples in
some cases not all cases and that's
basically the whole repository structure
for all of the data that's right right
now in there along with the data we have
a JSON file that gives you some meta
information like the block reference
that I've just mentioned the last time
it was updated aliases for the family
actors that have been observed using the
family and all that kind of stuff
for many of them there's also the Yarra
folder sorted by DLP with roots in there
so basically everything beyond TP whites
are already contributions by users of
the framework and you would have one
yarra file per Yarra rule because it
also eases
versioning and management of the stuff
so now the good thing about this kind of
file system like structure is this is
basically our git repository format so
if you want to have the data set it's as
easy as doing git clone and you have all
of the data at once and if you want to
do updates you do a pull request yet you
get pull and then
you have the most recent version of it
so it was our vision of having it in a
convenient way so that you can do the
same experiments or whatever you want to
like with the data set so this commit as
shown there is basically the route
commit and it's also the commit that
we've been using for our of the analysis
that I'm going to show in a few minutes
and this at that time was based on 17 or
almost 1,800 samples with run about 600
families if we look at the distribution
and of course we notice the majority
that's also probably the reason why I'm
because I'm feeling most at home with
Windows malware
I normally try to include Android
whenever I see someone talking about
Android malware and stuff like that and
and same for the other families and
everything was basically multi-platform
is written in Java or some JavaScript
like for example used by Tola and stuff
like that so basically Chrome extensions
are not we've got to unpacking and
dumping about 90% of the window stuff is
actually at least from a family
perspective dump with at least one dump
so sometimes our families we have
multiple samples but only one dump
because like I said quality or coverage
first in that sense I want at least one
representative for it and Jefferson are
just unpacked so also gathers probably
75% of the samples are definitely in
some unpacked state yeah so those 24
percent are missing right now okay so
how do we make this stuff accessible I
already ate said to you that this just
get repository that you can check out
but just also website because the title
was basically a collaborative approach
to it so first let me start with the
mission statement what I want to
basically achieve with this map edia
thing and then explain some of the the
trust mechanisms that we have
implemented in order to ensure basically
access limitation and also contribution
quality defects of it that's listed
there is already accessible so if I'm
just going to fast you can also I think
just go to on Google and or research
from a PDF it should show up in the top
five I guess so the the primary goal as
I said for this
project as a whole is basically to
provide a community driven independent
resource for this whole identification
stuff so basically if you have an
account on there you can propose changes
to the data set so if you know of a
family that's currently not in there you
can propose it if you have some samples
for a family that I don't have or
versions that you have identified and
just want to see them in the data set as
well you can do all of that so basically
what's then happening is there's a group
of peer reviewers that will basically
review your contribution and then
there's probably accepted or otherwise
rejected with a note what you should
improve in order to have it in there so
basically just how you would submit
stuff to a conference or similar we are
opting the traffic live protocol mock
just his personal experiences with that
and I hope it's the turning or better
and in this project so most for the
non-critical data is basically t.o.p
wide so you will inventory and that's
what you will see if you go to the
website is basically openly accessible
as well as the aggregated statistics
that I'm going to talk about any
references as well
everything else is ember so if you have
an excess or basically in account for
the platform the basically means you
have to keep it to yourself in your
institution there's some resources
within there that are designated
otherwise so you already saw this you
are think there might be teal pea green
so there's other ways to share some
components but the majority of the data
is really intended to stay on the yeah
and if you want to get an account there
we use some basic form of wetting
so basically existing community members
have to vouch for you so basically we
know who is accountable if you do stupid
stuff and this might fall back to them
so that's basically a system is very
established and stuff like opps trust
and such and we are basically just using
and orient ourselves on that yeah I
talked about this peer reviewer thing so
if you won't have data to contribute but
a good at math analysis and have a good
rest of the damaja landscape you can
also do reviews here so that's also a
way to contribute to this project and a
platform like I said normally two modes
are require
to either accept or reject a proposal so
you get some more sort of grounds to
base a decision on and what we're also
planning to do is doing some achievement
stuff so if you're frequently reviewing
things right now it's just fantasy
points and you can not do anything with
it
but in the long run I guess we might
provide some more services that
basically will have some quota because
they are more computationally intensive
and basically more contributions would
allow you to get a higher quota to that
kind of stuff so if you want to defend
the earthworm together with the freedom
fighters okay so in summary I'm the
baseline data set that I'm offering you
right here is run about 670 families
2,500 samples with very clean labels I
hope and already some contextual
enrichment but there's many many gaps
that want to be filled and it basically
would allow us to have this kind of
rosetta stone that basically tracks all
the aliases that different people are
referring to when they talk about my
other families or actors for that
instance and depending on how active
this thing is going it can also
basically become something like a
newsfeed because um if you keep the
references edit for families all the
time you see what's happening or it's
more on VOC at the time and get all of
the blog posts directly from one
resource so it's kind of an aggregator
switch might hopefully become that thing
so it would be really good because then
I don't have to crawl my Twitter feed
all the time we are using basically the
reference data of I miss for the Fred
Hector repository and whenever we are
not able to reflect something that we
want to do in my PDA we also contribute
a Mac and like adding an an actor into
their directory or merging some of the
areas and stuff like that so I'm miss
really good thing then again we also
want to cluster automation support so
basically everything that you can access
on the website also has a REST API so if
you want to do searches there's a Python
client ready for you where you can just
directly integrated to stuff that you
already have okay so now I've been
talking a lot about the project and the
data set and what
I want to do is basically do a bit of
showcasing what you can do with that
kind of data so I had this vision they
want to compare across many mother
families and find if there are some
similarities or what basically is some
of the trends of malware authors are so
the data they've been used in this thing
is basically the decommitted I just
referenced so around about 1200 dumped
files for almost or for for 6 families
and in this presentation I'm only going
to address three things so we have
compared PE headers across all of those
families we did some very cursory code
analysis because that's like a rabbit
hole and it totally would not fit the
time slot of this presentation if we had
already presented all of the results we
have there and on the other hand we know
API usage which is very interesting
because I guess that's one of the
cornerstones the vs analysts most rely
on when we are looking at now there so
that's the whole inventory of Emily's
right now it's probably still easy for
you to find something that's not in
there but that's basically also one of
the problems because if you're looking
at a lot of stuff in parallel you have
to aggregate to some degree so what I'm
now going to do is in most of the times
basically look at the aggregated samples
per family and then compare the results
on that level so let's do a very short
recap of what Pierre does look like so
that's your usual PA header for example
one of the more famous things here that
you normally look for is probably the MZ
magic the EPE magic so basically the
cornerstones that we used to to find
stuff in Dom's
then there's also this dust string thing
that might or might not be very common
there's a rich header that might contain
some interesting information
there's the Machine field that tells you
if it's either 32 or 64 bits then the
number of sections we have you also
heard earlier yesterday about that and a
timestamp and for example with the
timestamp normally he was nervous you
don't really know if you can trust the
timestamp but if we were able to compare
this across 400 50 families we might get
a trend how often these times
might be an actual value that's
basically realistic or not there's also
characteristics fears that defines how
the malware basically can be loaded on
the system you might have a linker info
that tells you some more about how this
thing was potentially compiled which
operate which system is required in
order to be able to run it the subsystem
in that case it's like value 3 so it
means a console application instead of a
UI application
dreg characteristics those contain a
bits information about the security that
this file is capable of ending on for
example if it supports a sauna or not
and then finally you also have those 11
data directories and that also contain
some interesting data so the above
diagram may or may not include some
Easter eggs and it's up to you to find
them so for your presentations it will
be in that kind of table so on the left
side I'm across all of the samples and
on the right side aggregated for
families
so let's first have a look at how often
you will normally encounter some kind of
MZ or PE magic at all and here the first
the good news is taking this as an
indicator for the availability of a peer
of PE headers in a good 95 percent of
the families you actually find this
stuff and you can extract information
from some kind of PE header so then what
you can see here is I have some more
that I can basically extract from that
are having MZ bad check so sometimes you
can see the mail rest basically just
deleting TMZ or just CPE but otherwise
the the header stays intact but only
basically just one part of the story
because there's more funky stuff
happening so some of the reasons why you
might not find a B era in that case so
for a good 30 families you would have 18
times position independent code that's
basically not in need of a header
seven times basically the segments that
executed with therapy stop with some
data and in five cases you would have
now a tea instead and for seven families
you can find that five of them basically
null the whole PE header so some more
effort you can basically extract it
before it's now
and for two families you can also
observe that it's xorg so one does it
with a one-bite pattern the other one
with a four bite pattern so it's a bit
inconsistent so up there you can see 27
verses 37 families the reason for that
is basically that only some versions of
some families are using those
destruction of PE headers
yeah drawstrings also available in like
90% of the cases in general you will
find three different variants for those
so basically the most prominent this
program cannot be run in DOS mode but
the other ones are basically tired
mostly tired to data feed so that's one
of the easy ways how to spot wall in
compiled stuff rich headers are a less a
bit less common so you will only find
them across all of the families in run
about 60 percent of the cases it's a
propriety staring at by the Microsoft
basically encodes how many times things
have been compiled with Microsoft Visual
Studio and also with the different
versions of widgets to do that may have
been present on the system over time and
there's a paper from Jim but this year
that goes in a bit more detail about
that it's really interesting the next
thing that we might have a look at so
say we have a PE header the vast
majority again is 30 but 32-bit images
one reason for that is that I've been
using 32-bit windows a lot to dump that
stuff but for about 15 families you
would find that they also have 64 bits
modules so for example some of the more
modern bankers like after a trip but
basically dynamically decide which of
the modules they want to use try decks
the same and things like that and at the
other hand what was a bit surprising to
me almost every 4th family basically has
their main module as a DLL opposed to an
exit file we forgot to those security
measures as expected
Marvis not really keen on basically
having those so for example if we talk
about relocatable mavar like SLR
might be a sense might make sense to
just deactivate it because it may ensure
that your members running a bit more
steadily say for an X I guess
so only in about half of the cases you
would find those security features
activated time stems like I said are
really interesting so for almost 90% we
have a non zero or not definite time
value definite time with you because def
before contained in the back that
basically always included the same
timestamp there and you can also read
about that and now let's have a look at
time times in a bit more detail because
that's basically what I just said so if
you want to look at the age of the
corpus we can for example check when
those files have appeared for the first
time on virustotal and if you don't have
data it looks some more like this so
about 90% of all the samples that I have
in there are basically 2013 and later
so going more in this preservation
direction if you have basically a lot of
samples that are identified and predates
basically this border I'm really happy
to take them and integrate them as well
just to increase the historical coverage
and the other sample right now is a
GoSee sample from 2006 so if you want to
estimate dpe timestamp accuracy what we
can do is basically use the field from
the PE header and the virustotal field
and do the difference of them so looking
at those 1200 times I have to start with
I can detect them that don't have a PE
header then those that have enough mud
field so they are not really useful in
doing this kind of analysis another 30
don't have a virustotal time stamp
because they are not on virustotal
you will find some time stamped and
there are certainly fakes because they
are in the future so basically they
would have been submitted to viruses
before they have been compiled so it
doesn't make sense and we can also
filter down to this this range like
earliest sample until now so I did this
late October so that's the the upper
border and this was with 949 Canada
timestamp pairs that we can look at and
see the distribution looks somehow like
this so mine again this is basically the
number of samples and what we can
observe here a good 10 percent are
basically so basically this black tie
and direct
to the left is a submitted to virustotal
on the very same day that you can find
the EDP time stamp a good 30% are within
the first week 50% within one month so
at least in many cases it's it's likely
that EP attempts them will be somewhat
correct so sometimes you have to
consider what's happening after the
compilation maybe the guy gives his
malware to someone else or it depends on
a Pacolet it's basically as an external
service it has to be delivered to spam
campaign so the basically explained
explains why you might have some some
gap there so altogether about 80% of the
time stamps live within one year of the
pre-computation term so 206 samples fall
out of this range a good third of them
has a PT background so that's something
that you can observe sometimes you get
an apt report published and some one to
three weeks earlier push those samples
referenced in there onto virustotal
and they have been withheld before
that's probably one of the reasons there
sometimes you have leak builders so if
you are now using Citadel builder it
will still contain the same stuff as for
four years ago or something so this
means why you might have fresh samples
with a very old time stamp for some
families I know that they've been using
forgery because some other fields also
faked and for the rest I have no idea
voids that
so probably also for Tory or some some
other results then again we had a look
at the compilation of those families so
using detected easy or similar methods
we can identify run about 500 data
points across those families and here
Microsoft which I see is by far the most
common compiler chain that's been used
to to create malware one data point
kinda sticks out there so we see six is
used almost as much as the more recent
ones which was a bit surprising then
again we see six also gives you
basically linking against the standard
runtime that's always on Windows so that
basically also ensures that your your
problems your program is not crashing if
it's basically not finding its
dependencies yeah we also have Richard
us for runner BOTS
760 different samples and basically in
all cases it's consistent with d-link
afield so you would have a matching a
product ID in the originator compared to
the compiler linker field data there
directly is are not touching here
because that's also way too much data
but there's going to be a paper so for
control flow graphs we did some very
fast or cursory disassembly on all those
families what you can find there your
average map is probably around 440
functions in size so most of the members
basically around dead size now what's
very interesting if you look at the
correlation between for example function
of basic log functions and instruction
and stuff like that they seem to have a
very high linear correlation so normally
you would have roundabout ish nine to
ten basic parts per function and fifty
to sixty instructions per function and
this was a bit surprising because that
basically means that there has to be
some connections in the code that are
probably worth looking deeper on and on
the other hand maybe personal coding
style is not as expressive as we hope
when we are using these kinds of codes
of fingerprinting authors but that's
basically research in the future okay
pdb information what you basically have
to speed up a bit can see there is
basically in at least 50 cases the PDB
string basically gave also one name of
the mellow family so if you're wondering
where all those names are coming from
PDB strings or at least one of those
sources yeah windows API usage so I
still want to cover that so I think I've
published a tool earlier this year which
is API scout and it's basically
something that helps you with API record
reconstruction for known environments so
we first want to look at the usage
styles of malware so basically are they
using an import table doing dynamic
loading
are they having association at that kind
of stuff and then the frequencies with
which if you
I used so the idea here is basically you
can brute force a memory buffer and find
ostatic offsets so if you're doing
dynamic analysis you are very familiar
probably with this import address table
format and the way that normal
basically unpack azure dampers work is
basically that they pass the structure
and reconstruct it but in many cases you
will also run into some issues basically
dumping and fixing them so what I
thought would be a good idea is
basically just looking at every D word
in a buffer and checking if it's
potentially one of those api's and
that's basically what if you I scared us
it's also having an Ida plugin so you
can directly use the database that you
have for your operating system get all
of those various resolved and can
directly apply them it seems to be a
very accurate approach as well because
I've been testing it on good wear and a
perform good currently it's not working
on either seven because the pipe in API
is totally broken usage styles so across
three hundred eighty families that are
not dotnet so I directly interacting
with the windows API it looks like this
so the majority of the families is using
standard imports so a good forty six
percent and on the other hand almost the
same fraction is doing dynamic imports
another fifty percent that's here so
those are very easily reconstructed with
API code which is very good news on the
other hand our fist occasion for API
usage seems not to be that common
actually so um they're some of the
methods listed but less than I think
twenty families right now but I still
have to go deeper and this statistics
will be updated over time so this is
this number of obfuscated families will
decrease potentially now little face
what's the most common a P I call a
cross off to semele s what what you
protect no sleep why sleep I guess
basically if you want to orchestrate
autonomous behavior sleep is like very
generic you can use it to delay C&C
communication you can use it to delay
execution and basically orchestrate how
a program is running
so many of the other ones probably also
beautiful specs for dll it's very much
the same but I was not really happy
because if you look at it that way and
you still end up with like three
thousand seven hundred different API is
used across all of those families and
the graph for those looks a bit like
that
however there's very good news the
pattern of this graph basically tells us
that the composition of the API set you
finds for a family is probably rather
unique so the API footprint has met that
Marva has might help you to identify it
and that's probably also a reason why
impatient in fuzzy and stuff like that
kind of performs quite well yeah I'm
gonna skip that so basically I've also
been doing API constic context groups so
I labeled another 3,000 offer IP I calls
into groups so we end up with like QR
execution string all the kind of stuff
because otherwise you run into this
issue that if you look at network you
have different ways to achieve the same
effect so it could do HTTP yourself
using sock or basic do the via 32 dll
you can use Windsor or use the HTTP hi
other videos and that basically this API
contact groups is a way to to merge them
to some degree and looking at it that
way um we can see that not every malware
seems to be using network if we think of
modern or some of you ran some of your
families they are just showing you an
email address but you have to contact
their order and stuff like that so that
might be a reason why they are not
calling out to the C&C servers same for
the other data as well but what I'm
doing right now is mostly showing you
data and the slides that will be
available directly not after the
presentation so you can read it up also
by yourself okay so what's the future
for this project of course we want to
maintain this data set an extended I
hope that you like it that much that you
want to have not an account for it and
want to interact with the data so that
would be like a really cool thing and
since it's focused on identification we
probably extend some of the aspects here
as well for for research I guess but I
showed to you today is basically only
scratching the surface and the next step
have already begun is basically looking
deeper into it
doing basically code indexation across
all of those families so the major goal
would be to identify unique code or
shared code across all of those
different families and ultimately
getting a better idea how functionality
is encoded into malware across all of
those different families okay so
basically the public launches today if
you want to have access to it come talk
to me so I run by the principle of no
mattress so if you talk to me you
already did no one met so that's a good
thing otherwise there's some existing
users who can now also invite further
users so that's the way how I want to
grow this thing organically with that
thank you for your attention
thanks Daniel for you're working for
your talk
are there any questions Tom there thank
you for your talk very interesting
project you you talked a lot about
executables and I think you just briefly
mentioned something about JavaScript or
Java archive like adwin grad families
how many of those do you have covered
also like PowerShell malware and all
kind of like non-executable malware
types that you have covered yet it kind
of depends on since I'm mostly looking
at public sources those are less likely
to encounter in public archives likelike
VT and stuff like that so if you have
pointers to them I'm very happy so I
think right now it's maybe like 30
families or something so it's not as
much certainly as the other ones okay I
think there is a question just right
there Anna thanks for the talk was seems
like a really great tool my question is
very simple can I get an axis so that's
basically what I just said so come talk
to me and we can arrange the kind of
stuff okay there is a last question over
there I don't know great research when
describing the mob our families are you
just focused on static parts or do you
also describe based on the behavior so
right now it's really focused on static
analysis because I want to have clean
dumps because that is something that we
can disassemble and then dive into so
that's the idea here I do not intend for
example to have like cocoa reports for
all of that stuff so that's probably
also not representative because you
always have to pecker in front because
there's no clean up example and you
don't know where basically to cut into
the the runtime behavior more or less
but it's basically is something that you
could do by just using the data for
example so if there's another one who
wants to pick up that stuff and
present those of runtimes happy to do so
okay thanks Daniel
[Music]