present some of our findings from
semantics perspective on wanna cry and
our investigation and this is actually
my first time up I'll come on first time
speaking so I am be kind and if I send a
bit weird I'm also suffering from a cold
so I'm don't worry about that if I sound
a bit odd and so the wanna cry
investigation and was something that was
kind of a big thing for us in terms of
we start seeing some massive increases
in kind of exploitation attempts for
maternal blue and it was one of those
things that was happening on a Friday it
was coming into the afternoon and when
we start seeing these red flags but
these amount of detection attempts we
knew that it was going to be something
that was massive and was our team that
were called in so a bit of background
for myself as well and I've been working
with Symantec for the last eight years
or so I'm initially I came in as a
reverse engineer and we kind of pull
apart malware kind of figure out what it
does and then we write and the text and
signatures for our different protection
technologies and later I joined a team
called the attack investigations team so
kind of our role is looking at high
profile attacks and we do a lot of
tracking of apt groups as well and we
kind of feed all our information that we
kind of get into other teams within
Symantec to help protect our customers a
little bit further so an overview of the
talk just to kind of give you a sense of
where you stand in it and it's short
enough I'll try to keep within the 30
minutes so to some time for questions as
well and so we have a bit of background
and about one a cry which most views
would be our familiar with so kind of an
a roundup of what we were able to find
out based on what was publicized and
we'll talk about our investigation so in
a lot of cases and people were
interested in trying to identify where
the attack was coming from and for us we
were able to identify an earlier variant
that was used that predated the May
attacks and enough kind of gave us the
most amount of insight into the
attackers and links to other groups and
other activities which we'll discuss
tonight
and allows to talk about those links
what we found some shared code and kind
of any the other relates activity that
we found as part of that as well and
then we'll just kind of wrap it up with
some lessons learned and some takeaways
so the background itself so before I
kind of talked about wanna cry I kind of
want to put things in to talk about kind
of context to put things into
perspective so when people talk about
Massive Attack's and that were and super
impactful some of the names are kind of
slope to the top are you gee blaster and
this is kind of a super old world back
from 2003 and and this is where we seen
like 16 million machines that were
infected in a single day which is a
massive number a similar wound uh kind
of flows the top was corn our conficker
so am configure had up to 15 million
machines that have been affected within
a 24 hour period and this was kind of
later on in November 2008 but then we
had one a cry in May um and the number
solana cry
were relatively small in comparison to
some of the other big attacks we only
seen around like 300,000 or maybe a
little bit more and machines ever have
been infected by wanna cry and this is
kind of bit odd and the reason why this
is is because of the impact are hot so
what happened was when people came into
work they were turning on machines they
started receiving are seeing this and
went to the machine on basically
requesting and payment of bitcoins work
to bid $300 and informing them that
their machine had been and held to
ransom and doctor files have been
encrypted and and this is obviously more
impactful than what you see well some of
the other and a big threat sure we had
mult are millions of machines affected
where those trucks was run in the
background and but this was more
impactful than that it was being
disruptive it was stopping productivity
and when I say impacts what I mean is
when we start seeing some of the reports
kind of floating around some social
media platforms people posting pictures
and some media outlets reporting on some
of those too
disruptions are actually incurred by
this and we start seeing attacks that
were on Billboard's whatever becoming
locked we've seen kiosks emergency
departments between train stations in
Germany and ATMs home TVs even the NHS
in the UK and even FedEx as well so this
was apparent that it was a massive issue
and this is was why our team was called
in on this to be able to kind of help
other teams it's smart to kind of figure
what was going on header were doing or
spreading and if there was any links to
other groups and you know in a tux and
what we could do to kind of help our
customers gonna protect themselves from
that and in terms of distribution when
we start looking at some of the
exploitation attempts from eternal blue
and we seen a massive surge which
occurred on May 12th and this is what
kind of set off red flags for us and we
knew it's going to be a long weekend at
this stage and this is kind of why I
kind of led into that makes me want to
cry because we knew was gonna be a
painful investigation from our side
particularly the fact that we're gonna
have to pull in resources and over the
weekend and what we seen was the initial
search moved around to so very detailed
machines are had been attempting to
spread what a cry but then we seen some
initial drop off as we entered the
weekend and followed by a resurgence
later on and it was likely that this
resurgence was caused by people coming
back in over the weekend on Monday and
then turning on their machines and then
finding that it was infected we also
took out the day they were able to
collect from our Kalama tree and just
kind of mapped it out over time across
the heat map and we found out some of
the countries that were impacted and
kind of early on I kind of had mass of
numbers in terms of infections and was
the likes of like Russia China Brazil
and these are kind of countries that
have really good internet access both
they for whatever reason have a lot of
on part systems and these were the
countries that we start seeing reports
come from in the early days when one
Akari start spreading in terms of
spreading itself and there's a couple of
message that it uses so em the first is
where is enumerates all the network
adapters
and detect IP information about their
system may have infected it'll generate
a list of IP addresses within those
subnets and then essentially try to
connect to all those machines and
connect a report four four five attempt
to make a successful connection if a
successful connection is actually made
it will then prepare and the eternal
blue exploit to be able to deploy want
to cry on to those remote machines and
it will also generate a random IP
address so it'll generate up to 128
random IP addresses it will attempt a
connection with them and if a connection
is successful again it'll prepare the
turnable you exploit and then it will
try to deploy I have one a cry on to
those machines for any time I had a
successful connection and it would then
scan and all the IPS from one to two to
five within that same I am subnet to be
able to seeker to connect any of those
ones so the kill switch itself so in the
code and there was basically a higher
Kota domain which was an unregistered
domain and this domain and basically
worked as a type of kill switch so if a
connection could be made to this domain
and a successful response was given back
and it would then essentially terminate
itself so it wouldn't continue spreading
and Marketo Marcus and how to identify
this and he registered a domain as part
of his botnet truckin so I think at the
time he even admitted that he wasn't
aware that it was actually kills which
he just seen an unregistered domain as
part of his analysis and then registered
after Lane and I think he had a story up
on his blog kind of detailing kind of
the circumstances on the events and it
kind of led to understanding why it
actually became a kill switch at a later
stage so it was theorized that this was
likely used to evade sound boxing so in
most sandbox environments and you'll
generally see people submit samples and
they'll want to be able to capture or
fake and I am c2 or command and control
and every social responses and basically
to extract see too quickly and usually
to kind of cluster malware in later
stages
and we started sinkhole domain which
stopped the spreading of wanna cry which
was a really good thing and but what we
kind of gave us tips to some of our
customers was instead of relying on an
external domain I ensure that you create
DNS entries for any of their local
machines so it resolves to machine
that's within your own network that you
control so your own private sink own as
such and the reason why we were doing
this was while people were relying on
this external domain they were adding
the unready domain to and their white
lists and which kind of presented a
couple of issues one there was reports
of attacks being performed so DDoS
attacks on and from the mayor botanist
against the domain de or the sink holder
and our tech was running and and if that
had succeeded then it would have allowed
what a quite a spread even further and
there was also kind of the ability
whereby if a later stages people had
forgotten that they had added this
domain into their other white into their
white lists and the domain became one
registered and then start being used for
malicious purposes later stage they've
effectively given a free pass so this
was something that we were kind of
suggesting is best practice for them and
in terms of payment and it seemed like
the guys who created one equai kind of
made a few mistakes or kind of hurried
and development of the tool itself so it
looked like and there was a point where
a decrypter or sorry a Bitcoin generator
so a Bitcoin address generator was
supposed to be dropped to disk and when
you were looking at the code itself it
looked like it was calling the Bitcoin
address generator before I was even
written to disk so this was kind of a
big thing whereby it wasn't able to
generate a unique address for each
infection and which meant that it
actually had to fall back to some
default values that have been hard coded
in and to the samples themselves well 13
hours later they also tried to release a
fix for this but at this point the
damage had been done and mitigation had
been kind of rolled out across different
organizations to kill switch had been
put in place so it kind of didn't have
much
and a fact lady so without a unique
Bitcoin address generator and a
defaulted to the tree kind of had
defiled addresses that were embedded
within the sample itself and the
attackers were demanding around $300 in
bitcoins and then saying that it might
double in price after three days if
there was no payment received and after
seven days and the attackers also
claimed that files would be lost or
modified and but there was actually no
evidence of this so even when we looked
at the code itself we couldn't see
anything in there that would actually
try to delete the files or even modify
them after this time period and last
time I checked there was around $90,000
in the Bitcoin address that I had been
paid and it may have changed since for
likely and even when it kind of came to
the dead line in terms of the render
time that the attackers had given people
to kind of pay up the ransom we've seen
that it kind of made a last-place so
they were sending out messages and which
is kind of funny because their start
referring to her as victims as customers
in this case so for our investigation
and identifying the vector of the attack
was kind of super difficult and this was
mainly down to a couple of reasons
so the first one was kind of larger
number of organizations were in practice
at the amount of organizations that were
impacted and by the stress and also a
large amount of traffic that had been
generated by the spreading and of won
acclaim and this made it difficult to
then dig through like your telemetry and
dick tree logs kind of identify that
first machine that had been affected
particularly when it was a likely gonna
be outside of your own customer base and
and it was a lot of it was a big thing
for a lot of groups that we were in
talking about this turn at the time they
wanted to find patient zero and they
thought that this would be kind of the
way to be able to identify how it
initially got on like did it for example
was it received by an email that then
start spreading and but this was kind of
some of the questions that the group's
wanted to answer and for us what we
actually ate was how to look off the
samples that we had collected ourselves
and we kind of tore it apart a bit and
then look for kind of some unique
markers and we created a somewhat loose
signature that we could then use to kind
of query or search across our big file
repository and we actually got a couple
of hits which is a bit odd because the
hits that we got were additional samples
that look like one a cry but they
weren't and even now had been reported
as part of the May attacks and what we
did was we took those samples and then
we found him against our Kalama tree to
see was there any customers that had and
been impacted by these samples and we
actually found with six organizations
and this predated the attacks that we
had in May all the way back to February
and so this obviously was a big thing
for us so we wanted to kind of jump in
on this I kind of figure out what was
going on was talking activities around
her and was this are essentially patient
zero and this what gave us the most
insight to these attacks I allow just
kind of create links to other groups and
other activity that we are later talked
about so when we first found these new
samples we kind of had a quick look to
see what similarities to water or what
differences there was and the first main
difference was it didn't contain the
aterna bloom exploit code at all and
this was something that was like oh
right this is a big thing this is
something that my pre days and when
internal blue was actually added to want
to cry so we dug this version one and
some of the similarities so these are
some of the similar or kind of
simplistic one so I did a cryptic
filename for example and Warner
decrypter products he used exclamations
instead of odd symbols and the component
files in the archives that was better
within the resources and followed
similar naming conventions and the
configuration format was identical
across the two samples and the passwords
used to encrypt the archive that was
embedded within it were somewhat similar
as well so the kind of reference while I
cry for the first victim that we
actually found and this was our February
victim and we weren't able to retrieve a
full timeline of the events that
happened on the machine but we started
looking at I need events around
we seem wanna cry version 1 on this and
within this organization and we found
some additional tools on some activity
there the first one was we've seen many
cuts have been deployed and had been
used dope credentials from the machine
that had been affected and those
credentials were then later stored into
a file called cgw ry and and then
another till watch which kind of looked
like a network scanner and called HP
tasks and was also deployed onto that
machine and it looks like the attackers
could provide a command line argument
which would allow it to assert our
search through an IP range and and
basically attempt to mount remote chairs
using the credentials from that cg w ry
file and if it was able to create a
successful connection it would then
essentially add this to a log file and
then it would copy some wanna cry
components and from version one across
onto these machines and the table that
I've listed here kind of gives you some
details of some of those components that
were copied across so we seen like an
the application for displaying the
messages which were stored in some
additional files we also had the one
acquire encryption component itself the
configuration details and then the
message files so most of your files are
encrypted or the instructions of how to
be able to pay and your Bitcoin ransom
and the February victim as well and we
also seen that this HP task till was
also the tool that was used to execute
the newly copied one account samples on
these remote machines and and we also
had identify some additional tools and
back doors that were on the infected
machines as well and we weren't able at
the time to kind of make any additional
links but when we started looking at
some of the victims from March and April
that kind of cleared up the picture
first so some of the tools that we did
find in this organization was a hawk
tail we caught desta over-involved mer
downloader and
we had some proxy tools as well so the
March and April victims so we had signs
of additional victims and we had at
least five organizations that we had
identified I have been impacted in
throughout this period and new samples
of one car I modified versions of one
acquired version one had been prepared
for each of these victims and they have
been delivered when we looked at the
victimology itself it kind of seemed a
bit odd and majority of all these
victims were actually located and within
Asia and but there was no real pattern
to the type of industries that were
being impacted so we had organizations
from government hospitality and chemical
industries but the only kind of pattern
that kind of emerged from that was they
were all organizations none of them were
individuals or consumers and we also
found some additional backdoors and this
is what kind of gave us the most amount
of information linking it back to
previous attacks and within these
organizations we had seen in some cases
a new backdoor that hadn't been
identified before called children of Alf
nack had been identified and we had
evidence of this to being used to deploy
one equai and we also had another
backdoor called Trojan of Bravo neck and
we also were able to find evidence of
this being used to deploy one occurring
in some of these victims so an alpha
knock itself had been used drop wanna
cry entry victims and it's a slightly
modified version that was deployed to
each of these are within each of these
environments and the backdoor itself um
I've been copied onto the machines and
then we've seen two minutes later many
cuts being deployed through that tool
and many carts were then executed
so essentially dumped the credentials
and then it would install WinRAR to be
able to collect those credentials and
move it off to some attacker control
every software and later we seen another
tool called G dot exe been deployed and
just performed UNESCO cops and this was
used basically to identify some machines
that were of value to the attacker
so and they used that to profile in
network research and the return and even
connected some additional information at
later stages we also found some
additional tools are also seen in the
February victim as well so again that
kind of network scanning tool that we
identified and that was used to deploy I
wanna cry and also being used to execute
the samples on those remote machines
Bravo knock yourself and was so much
different in the US and it actually used
a set of common passwords and to be able
to connect SMB shares and in order to
copy across wanna cry and we also found
other variants of Bravo NOC which
actually contain one acquire embedded
within itself so the links and related
activity so I'll try get to fit as
quickly only probably take a couple of
minutes because I want to open it up for
questions as well and we fair some
network are shared that were code
between and doozer and al-falaq and
doozer is a tool that was used by the
group Lazarus and previous attacks and
it had similar code for generating the
buffer that was used for command and
control communications and somewhat of a
fake SSL handshake and a generated
random number which was then used to
look up a table and to send some data to
the SI toos and this table was identical
across the two samples and which it was
a kind of strong indication that this
was a shared call between these two and
they also repented the same kind of
marker or a signature to the start of on
ec2 communications as well when we
decrypted some of the strings within the
two samples so alpha knock inducer we
found that the decrypted strings were
pretty much identical for the most part
and this again was a strong indicator
that there was overlap and we also film
an overlap with Bravo knock on user
again and in doctors
kind of shared cryptographic and number
of related routines and there was also
some additional share code that was
called out by Google so Neil had
actually posted two hashes and some
address and locations the first hash was
one acquired a second was a variant of
canta P and again kanta p has been used
by lazarus and this group which had been
used against several banks in the past
and we also had shared code which was
part of our course
sedimentation so generally in openness
le of around 300 plus ciphers that you
can choose from and this implementation
it was limited to about 75 and we'd only
seen that across these two samples and
there was also other chip-ins from other
people kind of identifying that this was
part of Lazarus and as you can see there
from cousins Yarra will and there's also
some temporal attribution as well so in
some of the victims we also found and
some additional Lazarus till so we had
asked over and involved mer and there's
been many links kind of already
documented between those two and we also
seen al sac and being used in another
sample which was a job inquiry resume
which kind of suggested maybe this
initially was impacting these
organizations through email so I'm gonna
shared infrastructure as well we also
had shared C and C's so we had Doozer
which connected to two IPS one of which
had been also a CNC for children of
Bravo knack and we also had alpha naki
which was also contacting a CT which was
found in the same file and that in turn
also AM contacted under I Peter would
share between dr. otaku pops another
Lazarus - so we are able to assign some
confidence value cities under links we
had network infrastructure overlap which
we had hard links on our kind of high
confidence same infiltration in terms of
the tools that were and found we also
had shared code which kind of range
between a kind of medium to weak but
when you kind of put them all together
it kind of suggested to us that this was
a high confidence and we all saw till
co-occurrence so and lazarus tools on
impacted victims that we had want to cry
and we also kind of had some techniques
which we considered weak so like the use
of hard coded SMB credentials and
password this to be able to spread over
SMB which was also seen in other tools
used by a la Souris in the past so since
Jonah so the lessons learned were pretty
bad Apache and the patch had being
released about a month previous and but
yes we still had and all these victims
that have been impacted by wanna cry and
either for reasons like OEM equipment
legal certificate
reasons or kind of rogue devices we're
still bad at performing backups and a
lot of people that I was talking to have
said oh it's cool I have really good
restoration plans in place but when you
ask them what happens when you're the
directory server is knocked offline or
your network is down how can you restore
them and they were pretty much kind of
plain that they were essentially dead in
the water at that stage and there's no
such thing as your perimeter so a lot of
other people were saying oh I've blocked
port for four or five on my firewall I'm
good
but that's not really the case why
you'll see a lot of kind of issues are
kind of public we need to use byline
let's say for example machines coming
into your network and linked to motor
vendors to your corporate network and
other things as well which kind of open
your perimeter so that line between your
perimeter and order other parameters can
kind of become more ambiguous and a bit
more blurred as such as security in
published and procedures and continuity
planning does work Friday the customers
that we talked that didn't get impacted
by this they had really good policies in
place they had really good procedures
and continuity planning there and they
were able for any ones that were
impacted they were able to quickly
restore services and get back to working
so the takeaways wanna cry is extremely
disruptive attack and the leak of
eternal blue was the reason why this
turned into a global threat and expected
losses and productivity and an efforts
to mitigate were significant because of
this attack and we found multiple strong
links to previous attacks conducted by
Lazarus and we had overlaps in some kind
of technical aspects like code sharing
and c2
communications and he also had previous
well documented and links to other
attacks such as the attacks on Sony with
test over and Bangladesh central bank
account EP and we also had despite the
links Lazarus it doesn't look like that
it was and paired kind of hallmarks of a
nation stays and kind of type of
campaign and for the fact that it was
looked like that the till was hurriedly
put together and while it might being
inducted by Lazarus it looks like it was
possibly financially motivated initially
but either Accardo or something happened
where and they basically have weaponized
way to turn a blue and I kind of spread
be under control and finally we're still
about a patching oh thank you thank you
Alan for the talk and sorry we cannot
take a questions at this time because we
have better over time but you can catch
probably Alan during the break and ask
him questions yeah I think not
[Applause]
[Music]