check-check
hey guys um I'm gonna start by
introducing ourselves
I'm Gabriel and I'm more of less more or
less a software guy and recently I
discovered that I'm good at breaking
things up so back in Romania I'm known
as the public transportation hacker I
hacked the public transportation system
in Bucharest a while back and after the
disclosure of the vulnerability and all
that
I moved my sites towards more fruitful
domains such as car hacking so myself
for him check check okay all right so as
for myself my name is Stefan I've been
doing security for a little bit more
than 10 years now I was mostly involved
in malware research and cybercrime and
the cyber espionage but now in the last
two years by the way doing malware
research people think it's an activity
that looks like this just like you're
sitting in front of your computer being
very bored but in reality it's something
that feels like this it feels like
you're in a period of fighting a bull
then I guess everyone here that's who's
interested insecure you're discovering
vulnerability vulnerabilities can can
feel the same thing we can feel the
adrenaline rush when you're discovering
the new exploit or something that wasn't
known before just a little bit of
shameless self-promotion so if you're on
Twitter make sure to follow us
especially Gabriel because he really
needs some some followers I'm not about
I'm for real
his account looks like it's a fake
account so we need to make it look more
more real but yeah Twitter is a great
thing for security people it's like a
big chat room where you choose who you
want to be in that chat room so yeah
we're going to talk about smart card
security today and the reason why we are
very interested in this is because we
live nowadays in a world that is
becoming
more and more connected and in which
essentially every car we drive nowadays
is a computer running on four wheels so
if computers can get hacked cars can
also get hacked and the reason why I
think this is very important is because
of the possible consequences so if your
computer gets hacked somebody infected
then maybe you don't care that much you
just reformat the operating system the
hard drive you reinstall the operating
system and your computer is liking you
but with cars then human lives can be at
stake because we're moving slowly into a
world in which cars would be fully
autonomous so these are the six levels
of a smart car of autonomous cars like
that level zero is there's no automation
and level five the last one is the world
in which you can just read your
newspaper and the cars operate fully by
themselves so right now we're somewhere
at level I think between two and three
so most of our cars already have some
automated functions but you still need a
driver in the back of the wheel and to
make sure that everything happens
correctly so in order to get to this
level five of full autonomy when talking
about cars engineers in the automotive
industry are essentially adding more and
more connections to the cars more and
more sensors more and more communication
protocols cars will have to communicate
with one another cars will have to
communicate with the streets with the
roads and so on and so forth and I don't
know about you but you know soon we're
gonna have you know real car botnets I
think so that's why we came interested
in in smart car security now of course
big incident that I'm sure all of you
know about from 2015 was when Charlie
Miller and mr. balisok when they hacked
a jeep that the journalist from Wired
was driving on a highway so this is this
was a very impressive hack because
essentially they managed to find
vulnerability that was remotely
exploitable through the 3G interface of
the of the car so each car had a SIM
card that was connected to the 3G so
they theoretically
they would scan the whole IP address
space of AT&T and identify each Jeep
that was connected to the network they
could have run their exploit on all of
the cars so of course after their stunt
Jeep had to recall 400,000 cars if I
remember right so that's that's a huge
impact I mean for an auto manufacturer
if you have to recall you know hundreds
of thousands of cars that means a big
loss and the big drop in your shares on
the on the stock exchange so yeah I'm
gonna pass the mic to Gabriel to tell
you how we started this project so
besides the fact that I couldn't travel
freely with the bus I like to tinker a
lot with all of the technology that
forms into my hands so as soon as I got
my car I just started trolling forums
and looking all around the internet for
ways to I don't know make it different
you know there are many like it but this
one is mine so I just need to change its
background or remove certain safety
features inside the cars I could play
with the touchscreen while driving and
all that and interestingly enough this
brought me to like this really hardcore
hobby forums in which people try to
reverse engineer debugging features that
the initial manufacturer left and
somebody managed to get SSH access onto
the car now what they were mostly using
was a script that would be run by
somebody in service and it would execute
a bash file that you would leave on that
USB stick and then you would have access
all around your system so after
basically using their work to get an SSH
shell inside the board I started digging
down and see what's going on inside my
car so again looking around it's got a
pretty known processor that's developed
for embedded application a random UNIX
distribution it's got the GPS module
soldered on
now for other cars they used to sell
that module separately but the new ones
only basically license your Maps the
maps that they want to sell to you and
leave the GPS soldered in order to
basically make the upgrade as seamless
as possible and this is gonna be useful
later when we go to the forensics part
one gig of ram a Wi-Fi module and the
USB thingy that i was telling you about
now coming from a dumb car this looks a
lot I mean for 2014 this was exactly the
same kind of power that you would have I
don't know when a meat core phone with
Android that was about I don't know one
or two years older or something like
that so we have a car
it's infotainment system SSH that we can
use to get into the car and that's when
we started the whole forensic sparked
now right off the bat you have access to
certain tools that were left by the
developers to display debug message and
stuff like that the same kind of tools
that were used to get SSH onto it
so we abuse the script we disabled
iptables because it looks like SSH
exercise was enabled across the board
initially so now you have to have a
hardware device in order to disable IP
tables and have have the ports open we
run the SSH daemon and we got him it had
the random default password really easy
I mean all of this was basically
information that was leaked from the
manufacturer to the guys to the
enthusiasts on the forum and running
around I found a few interesting files
that had the SQL extension which are
basically full dumps of the date above
my database of phone contacts of phone
numbers called history yeah I should be
calling my girlfriend less it's
and the most worrying part was that we
also found this binary blob for whoever
is not in Romania those were our street
addresses together with the numbers of
the street those were the most visited
locations that I inputted into the car's
GPS system so all that was there in
plain text and after digging a little
bit and correlating everything together
a bit more I even discovered that it
held a history of your mo of your
favourite routes in order to suggest
them while you are driving or selecting
a new destination from where you are so
that's a major information leak that you
can do it just in USB by the way I just
want to make this clear so this is the
first part of our project which was the
forensics part and this part we tried to
put ourselves in the skin of let's say
an attacker that once he gets full
access to the cars on our computer the
question is what kind of data can he
extract about ourselves and I think that
this is actually an area of the
forensics business that will be growing
more and more in the future because law
enforcement organizations around the
world they are already doing digital
forensics when they have suspects that
they arrest and they do the forensics on
their computers they do the forensics on
their phones and I'm sure that in the
future they will also do forensics on
smart cards or other smart devices
because there's real evidence that can
be extracted from from there and this
can even be exploited by a malicious
actor just think about getting a rental
car for example and you would basically
be able to pull all of the info of all
of the phones and the drivers that have
connected to those cars in the past and
there are some extra information on the
side that we didn't get the chance to
fully analyze it and we found stuff like
voice profile vehicle status info like
how hard you would brake and how fast
would you accelerate accelerate and even
a directory listing for your phone
and this isn't really that dangerous per
se but when you consider that if
somebody has puts a stick inside your
USB port of your car and can discover
that you use telegram
because telegram saves its attachments
in a folder and then folder gets indexed
because it has media on it by your car
even though you didn't actually request
that it gets kind of scary there's a lot
of metadata that you can gather just by
analyzing this kind of info now like you
think you're using an encrypted chat app
but then the file names of the
attachments that you received are just
available there and your car is seeing
it and then it's saving it forever in a
non secure way and it's not deleting the
information after you disconnect your
phone from the from the Bluetooth so
yeah the feeling that we got after doing
this forensics thing and on the on the
car's infotainment system was the fact
that this is probably made by very good
engineers but engineers that never had
to design a system that was connected
and if you think about it historically
or infotainment systems of cars there
were separate devices like you couldn't
connect what you could maybe connect the
radio and listen to the radio or put it
in a cassette or a CD to play it but not
actually have internet on it not have
bluetooth not have USB so at one point
probably someone in management you know
came to the engineering team and said
hey we need to connect our infotainment
systems we need to put them in the cloud
something like that so they quickly had
to find some solutions and to to
implement them and this is why we think
that that these things are so vulnerable
and basically what we're noticing is
that whenever auto industry develops a
new you know connected system they start
thinking about security but they only
think about security in the last phase
of the project just before the project
is shipped and we would like to live in
a world in which automakers would start
the project with security so security at
the bottom of the pyramid and then build
everything on top of an already secure
platform or framework with you know
secure development practices and it's
really interesting because security
comes
there at one point you can see it but
it's only physical security not actual
you're the not the actual safety of the
data about you that you store inside the
computer on four wheels so yeah moving
on to the the second part of our project
so the first part is try to understand
what can be done with that computer the
second part was to actually do something
with that computer to make it do
something which it shouldn't shouldn't
do something that the engineers didn't
think of so we essentially created a
proof-of-concept script it's a bash
script it's nothing very complicated but
it's a it's a script that takes
advantage that lives off the land it
takes advantage of binaries and tools
that were left there by the developers
so essentially we deploy it through the
same feature that granted us SSH access
in the in the beginning so a USB thumb
drive that it's inserted into the USB we
then use cron to keep the script alive
and what the script does is essentially
two things first of all it constantly
looks for open Wi-Fi networks that are
around around the car and it plots this
data on a on a log file together with
the GPS coordinates that we're taking
directly from the GPS module and we're
plotting all of this data inside a log
file and then whenever we find an open
Wi-Fi in the range of the car we just
connect to that Wi-Fi and upload the
data to a server that that we own
essentially creating a scenario you know
in which you Ward drive without a laptop
so you just drive your car around the
city and the car automatically plots
open Wi-Fi data so it looks kind of like
this so we had to explain the script to
our managers and they only understand
pictures but yeah you can see this is
the area where Gabriel lives in
Bucharest and those are the open Wi-Fi
networks around it so yeah this is a
security conference and I know that
security people they love to see demos
so our initial plan was to bring the car
here in front of you what we talked with
the organizers and they said that that
would be a little bit complicated to get
the car here
but that's why Gabriel before coming
here he I hope the video works he took
the car for drive around his block and
we added a little feature to our script
that would show a pop-up message display
a message on the screen every time the
car sees an open Wi-Fi network of course
we did it just for the demo but in a
real case scenario in which an attacker
would like to monitor all of your
movements around the city
essentially installing the GPS tracker
in your car of course you wouldn't see
anything anything on the screen
so really sorry for the bumpy roads we
don't have the best roads in Romania but
yeah this is our demo so time to
applause but anyway after this whole
ordeal we started to bumping ideas
around and thinking what would happen
next and while presenting the whole web
vehicle weaponization scenario and
installing a backdoor for GPS access and
so on and so forth
tour journalist he told me but could you
put ransomware on it and yes yes yeah
this might be at some point imagine that
you are investing about I don't know
20,000 40,000 euros into a vehicle that
you own well then paying a few hundred
bucks in order to use your infotainment
system isn't that far-fetched I mean for
your laptop you just to format
everything and call it a day maybe even
have some backups but you can't actually
do anything at least on the card that I
have if you have it bricked factory
reset isn't actually factory reset only
reverse certain files to a certain state
but if you install something like
something blocking the spawning of the
process because by the way we were
running as root so the GUI was running
at root there was no sandbox in between
processes nothing like that
no hardening no not user names for
different components
it was just it seemed to us like the
system was designed as a development
system not as a production system so the
engineers just assumed that nobody will
have access to the system because it's a
it's an air-gapped thing but then they
had to add all this connectivity to it
and it essentially opened it up to the
to the real world I think this is the
big problem with Internet of Things
nowadays because there's are usually
developers of embedded devices that
worked on devices that were never
connected to the Internet and now all of
a sudden were connecting them or and
more so the discussion with that
journalist got us thinking you know what
what scenarios can happen into the
future because maybe ransomware I mean
it's a good example for you know TV for
them to illustrate getting a virus on
your car but in reality maybe more
dangerous things will happen than your
car not starting up in the morning yeah
so we kind of invest started
investigating into how we can exploit
the infotainment system in its
communication with the other subsystems
around the car and we discovered the can
bus we started snooping around and the
car has a really neat feature with the
smart city brake assist or something
like that in which it breaks if it
detects something in front of you and we
wanted to basically spoof the messages
from the sensors that were going up on
the can but then a really neat idea came
into my mind what if we attack it from
the other side so what we decide to
actually Jam the set sensors and my car
has at least for this system has a
ultrasonic set of Rangers in its bumpers
in the back and a lidar in the front
just for evaluating the distance and I
starting again looking through forums
and I don't know just trying to find any
kind of opportunist Intel that I can I
can discover and it looks like people
were actually trying to jam these kinds
of radars in robot contests and were
actually discussing the legality of
doing something like it within the
context of that that contest so it's
completely doable that least the
ultrasonic ooh
jammers are completely doable and the
car doesn't really can't really provide
any meaningful information for about the
distance when it comes to its to the
nearest obstacle so this creates an
actual usability problem that can be
exploited from a certain distance and
some people in China decided to take
this one step further and to spoof the
radar signals that were coming from a
Tesla and they actually did it with a
piece of hardware from keysight a signal
generator after that a mixer and they
managed to go up to the 60 gigahertz a
range in which they could confuse the
same horse enough in order to not let
the start the car start from its
position because it had no telemetry and
by the way so this this read radio
equipment that they use the the keysight
device that generates radio waves it's a
pretty expensive piece of equipment so
it costs around $100,000 but the message
that we want to send here is that these
kind of devices like RF devices and you
probably know this better they are
becoming more and more cheap right I
mean you can probably do more or less
the same thing with a blade RF which is
just a couple of hundred dollars instead
of some tens of thousands even one
hundred thousand dollars and actually
this is one of the message that we're
trying to send to security researchers
when you go to conferences that you know
car hacking doesn't have to be something
very fancy it doesn't have to be
something very expensive with just a
couple of hundred dollars or Euros you
can just get an you know a Raspberry Pi
a hack RF or whatever radio board and
you can start messing around with all of
the sensors that the cars have like
reversing sensors or tire pressure
sensors like all of these things they
transmit data to the car's onboard
computer and most of these data is not
sanitized
so it'd be surprised in what kind of
features of modern cars you might be
able be able to find some remote
execution
and even for the whole radar hack before
even if right now it costs a couple of
hundred grand if you if you want to
actually build a set up for actively
spoofing radar that what that's what was
said about radio amateurs a couple of
years ago it would cost a lot just to
start mixing and sending radio waves by
yourself and with the advent of SDR
we've I don't know everybody has started
joining in and contributing and we have
new radio that is able to do a lot so
the entry level is going down as time
passes the entry barrier so yeah oh and
by the way this is a project of ours
it took essentially a weekend if you put
on all the hours that we work so I got a
couple of hours to be able to get access
and a few more hours to create a proof
of concept and then so it's not it's not
something you know terribly complicated
but it's something that the automotive
industry definitely is overlooking right
now so I guess we're quite okay with the
time I'm gonna talk a little bit about
the conclusions because we have three
main conclusions to draw from this
project and then we're gonna have a
little bit of time for for Q&A so the
first thing that we realized after this
whole story is that our privacy is
definitely threatened and of course this
is not necessarily new in the world of
you know computers and social networks
and mobile phones but when you're
thinking about a car you're not
necessarily thinking about the privacy
consequences that there are and the
reason why I'm I'm thinking this is very
important is because especially you know
in Europe and in North America smart car
sharing programs are becoming more and
more popular so instead of everybody
just owning a car there's some cars that
we own together and we share them
together also we're doing quite a lot of
travel for business so from time to time
we get to rent cars of course when you
rent a car and you have to drive 100
miles then you probably want to connect
your phone with the Bluetooth just to
listen to your favorite music and not
many people realize that when they
connect their phone to the car and the
car will get access to so much
personally for
that will never get deleted from that
system so I think that this is a big
problem that our modern world is is
facing at the same time there's the
thing that I was telling you about
connecting these devices more and more
so of course technology always evolves
but I like to look at this evolution as
a double-edged sword at the same time we
have all the good things the benefits
from living in a connected world but at
the same time we need to think of also
the new doors that we are opening for
attackers or malicious actors to profit
or to abuse our technology in some way
or another and of course the human
nature is in such a way that we will
always want smart things but I'm just
thinking that you know we should think
about security as well not just about
features and last but not least I just
want to end this on a positive note
because if you look at the history of
the automotive industry they have a very
good track record when it comes to
actually implementing security features
I think your physical security features
and this is of course it's a long
history it mostly happened because of
regulation and regulation mostly
happened because there were victims but
right now we live in a world in which
whenever you buy a new car that car will
come pre equipped by default with all of
the security features that you need like
abs for braking or ESP for stabilizing
the car or the basic seatbelt or airbags
that will protect you in case of a crash
and we have crash tests and we give
ratings to cars and depending on how
they perform in crash tests and I'm not
seeing any reason why the industry
wouldn't do the same thing with
cybersecurity so we need some official
tests some official organizations that
will test if the security of the cars
are good enough or not give them ratings
and then consumers should make an
educated decision based on all of this
data and I think I'm thinking that the
industry is ignoring cyber security
because so far there were no real
consequences there are now really
dangerous things because of a
cyberattack but I think that the day in
which you know human life would be lost
or threatened because of a cyber attack
in autonomous cars is it's coming so we
come it's all fun and games until
somebody loses an eye
so yeah so just before we end a little
bit more piece of bragging so to say
because we've been doing this
presentation at all sorts of conference
around the world mostly security
conferences so that we can meet
like-minded people that are also
interested in hardware and car hacking
and we were very you know pleasantly
surprised by the media coverage that our
little project got because you know
publications such as motherboard or
decipher or the register they wrote
about it and these are very good you
know info psycho publications but the
reason why we are even more proud was
when forbes contacted us to do an
exclusive interview about this thing so
that appeared on forbes.com and we were
happy because we saw this discussion is
moving out of the bubble of the security
people and more into the let's say
mainstream mainstream areas and then we
had a couple of interviews with two car
magazines car buzz and drive mag and
that was actually what made us really
happy because we realized that our
message is getting into the area of
automotive people or people passionate
about cars because in reality the
reality is that security people they
live in a bubble like we live in a
bubble and we all agree with each other
that everything can be hacked we all
agree with each other that there's no
such thing as 100% security but then
these messages they just stay inside the
security community so this is why we
think that events such as hardware that
eyewear security people can meet
hardware people and all sorts of
engineers can meet each other are very
important because I think security will
become more and more important part of
IT and the world that we live in so yeah
thank you very much for paying attention
and if there's any questions that's why
we're here for thanks
he just did some great hardware your
promotion thank you so who wants to
start with the first question
okay first in two GPP in the next
generation 5g a cellular networks they
are now in release 16 talking about
Victorian with tweaks standards there is
a lot of study on it and what is
appealing is that there is a lot of
attention that the autonomous cow most
of the in dense urban area it will be
not be done in the car because it's not
have enough computer ability and
resources and the cooling system and so
on it will be done
in data center that will be on the fifth
full generation that will be very low
latency connection to that area of
controlling and get back the driving
instruction and so on
first everybody can now go to this
standardization learning and so on and
give security vision and and change the
following release if you it will be
closed and change it this is the time so
everybody here can now change or get the
security reason were to put it in what
to do it's not a question right yeah
more of a call to action edition yeah
well I haven't seen that much action
when it comes to V 2 V and V 2 X to be
honest at security conferences I've seen
it at auto shows at stake shows and
stuff but nothing really I don't know
security people-oriented give them to
somebody by some guy at a hacking IOT
village or something like that so we
have to wait for that another question
means everything was clear I guess well
thank you very much thank you so much
[Applause]