all right hello just give a second to
kick on the recording here all right
hello welcome to hardware everyone it is
absolutely great to be here I am my
handle and my name is the same say there
one you'll get exactly the same
pronunciation it is absolutely wonderful
to be here in front of all of you let me
see if my mostly alright so welcome
everyone to Hardware dot IO welcome to
the keynote so I've been in the industry
for something like 10 years now I've
done a bunch of different kind of
presentations seen a lot of keynotes and
an opportunity to give a few my one of
the things I've always taken away from
these kind of addresses is that it is
always really good to start these kind
of conferences on an inspiring note
which you know I guess kind of shows
that I suck at keynotes so we are here
to talk about hardware specifically
about the state of hardware security
because if you look at hardware security
and kind of compare it to where software
security was 10 years ago you're gonna
start seeing some interesting parallels
right
we are just in that kind of early infant
stage of hardware security where people
kind of know that hardware security is a
kind of field they're gonna have to deal
with but they either have no idea that
they're annoyed ooh they actually have
to do this in order to release a product
or they're kind of aware of it and don't
really know how to secure their hardware
so other than the people in this room
most of the world is kind of sitting in
that state
exactly where we were when kind of
buffer overflow vulnerability started
becoming a really big thing in the 90s
and kind of sitting there going like
okay there are these people who can hack
hardware but what do we do about them
what does that mean for me a
manufacturer and you know for in worst
cases do I really have to do this is
this something that I really have to do
or can I put out another Internet of
Things light bulb you know I'm just
no one's gonna hack a light bulb right
what does it matter what's the value in
attacking those kind of targets but for
all the devices we have out there that
have been sitting there and kind of are
in an insecure state we have threats not
just to the devices themselves and maybe
doesn't really matter if someone happens
to own your ten dollar light bulb but we
have threats to the actual
infrastructure that comprises the
internet the mirror a worm a couple
years ago actually took advantage of
just the most stupid kind of security
mistakes right having open telnet with a
fixed password and use that to take down
the DNS backbone momentarily biting down
in DNS right so for you know a day or so
people couldn't get to github couldn't
do their work couldn't you know get on
Netflix those kind of things you know
how to actually a pretty broad impact
for something that came from taking
advantage of such a stupid security
mistake so we're still in a world where
you can take a piece of hardware off the
shelf look at it find out that it has an
open root shell sitting on a UART
console on a couple headers that are
exposed and worse if you look at a lot
of these devices they're running ancient
unpatched versions of Linux that have
been sitting there you know on the same
kind of embedded builds for longer than
the device itself exists we have for the
first time a device that has been you
know honestly contributing a lot in the
fact that it is the first unfuckable
device which is pretty inspiring know
right we actually have is InfoSec
charlatans who are coming around and
taking advantage of ignorance in the
field of hardware security in order to
make claims about hardware that they
cannot back up some of the speakers
you'll see have really you know that
have developed a lot of experience of
working with both
kind of charlatans in these kind of
devices so we're in this state where the
fact that people don't understand
hardware security allows people to make
these pretty grand claims with almost no
retribution almost no consequences for
their actions and we have devices that
have been hardened to hack devices that
have software that's been audited you
know literally to the point where there
is so little surface area on some of
these pieces that software techniques
are generally not yielding a lot that
are based off of a piece of hardware
that kind of gives you a much larger
attack surface so we have devices that
are really really really hardened in
software level but we're almost no
hardening has been done on the actual
pieces of hardware underneath so in this
case we have the Nintendo switch was a
Nintendo had for once actually put a
significant amount of effort into making
sure that the software stack was as
resistant to tampering as possible but
it turns out it kind of falls over on a
light breeze when you go and I should
attack the hardware and in terms of the
way the media handles all of us we have
fear uncertainty and doubt running
pretty rampant if you take a look at
this an article from The Daily Mail who
we all know are a very reputable source
of journalism especially for cyber
security and if you look at the way
they've actually reported this article
it is cyber criminals which I guess is
me who shorts are gonna wire to get the
most basic command level of the Nintendo
switch and in doing that they can run
any software code that they wish so this
is the kind of thing that has been
reported in a well I guess I'll call a
major news outlet and the United Kingdom
Britain and this for a lot of people the
view of cyber security the people who
are not InfoSec practitioners this kind
of thing is what they see
you can tell that this is fed gonna run
wild fear uncertainty and doubt run wild
because for this article the comment
section was actually the part that made
the most sense which never happens so
like when you have an article that is
this full of that kind of fear-mongering
and the comment section is gone again
whatever you know it's a local attack
why are you making such a big deal out
of this you know that we've kind of
gotten ourselves into an interesting
situation so how do we wind up here how
did we wind up in a state where we have
all of this knowledge that we've built
in you know going through the same
process in the software side of InfoSec
but we have such a dramatically bad
there's a dramatically lacking view of
the hardware security side so I'll start
off by telling you about my perspective
I can't tell you about everyone but I
can tell you how I'm kind of how I have
moved through hardware security so my
name is Katherine and I have kind of
made it a career over the past ten years
to try to be in places where I've been
able to enable people to learn things
about hardware and and later half of
that hardware security so I do a lot of
different things that are really less
hacking and more trying to figure out
how to make engineering accessible to
people and this started something like
2011 ish when I started working for
University started teaching a lot of
engineering concepts before I was really
in the InfoSec side of this I was
actually trying to teach young engineers
how to think about Hardware how to build
Hardware themselves and our university
had kind of two departments that were
involved in this level of engineering we
had the electrical Computer Engineering
Department I'm a computer science
department those were treated as two
thirdly separate disciplines they were
two separate groups the department's
frankly didn't really like each other
because why I haven't put the name of
the University on here and there is
always this kind of attitude from the
electrical and computer engineers
that they were the better ones while the
CS you know computer science majors
thought that they were the ones who
really were on top of things they also
felt that they had two completely
separate Magisterium
so even in Electrical and Computer
Engineering that was split between the
electrical engineers and the computer
engineers and each of those had such a
narrow view on what they thought was
their Magisterium what they thought was
their domain that we had students who
were electrical engineers sitting there
and going well I don't have to touch
code I'm an electrical engineer I can
design a circuit I can use a soldering
iron I don't have to do any of that code
stuff that's for my computer engineers
we had computer engineers who felt that
they didn't have to touch
pretty much anything other than digital
firmware right they didn't want a
soldering iron because that was for
their electrical engineer they didn't
necessarily have to touch anything that
ran an operating system they were so
narrowly into their niche that it they
kind of actually limited themselves
based on what they thought was their
walk in life what was their role and so
these students would kind of be under
the false impression when they were
working on a team with other engineers
that they were the ones doing the
firmware they didn't have to learn about
anything that sat underneath it
that was for implementation details we
had computer scientists who felt that
the hardware was just something that
they want up getting a driver interface
for they didn't have to worry about that
at all then we had the electrical
engineers who said ok I'm gonna make a
circuit that works how do i why should I
care about how it's used afterwards my
part of the job is complete no matter
what every one of these people every one
of these students kind of had the
impression somewhere that they were
somehow fundamentally different from the
people they look up to they looked at
their professors and looked at the
people they had seen inventing things in
the past and they thought there was a
fundamental difference between a student
who learned techniques in school and
applied them and the people who had
created these kinds of things and that
really contributed to the idea that once
you've got yourself a microcontroller
that was a black box not an instruction
set architecture had instructions for
using that black box but you would never
in your life actually get to look inside
that black box and see how the pieces
worked beyond what was necessary to
actually program
that microcontroller fast forward seven
years and a couple of jobs later I found
myself actually leaving the university
deciding to get myself a job that didn't
have as much of a contest between
teaching and research and so I moved on
to just doing kind of InfoSec research I
wanted founding my own company and in
finding my own company I kind of got the
opportunity to poke around with things
that were more enjoyable to myself as
well as the things that I was working on
for clients and so we were working on
but I started working on at the time is
actually hacking minute under switch and
in so this was really a neat target
because one the processor that was the
kind of a centerpiece for the switch was
a target that was familiar to me so I
had already previously done some work
for another company on the Tegra x1 I've
been actually responsible with building
a security hypervisor and the Android
instance is running on the tiger x1 and
so I thought you know I have familiarity
with this why don't I try taking to look
at the switch and see if it kind of has
some of the same security shortcomings
as other devices that use the x1 like
Google's pixels say and what I found
bringing within the people what we found
was that the Nintendo switch was
extremely difficult to attack on the
software front software vulnerabilities
existed especially in lower firmware
versions for the switch but they were
kind of far and few between and Nintendo
had a pretty decent setup where once the
vulnerability was found they could
release a new software version at that
point on the hardware level they could
make sure that once that device had been
upgraded it was no longer capable of
downgrading to previous versions of that
firmware stack so they were able to
effectively have a pretty decent
patching mechanism for these but all of
that software build you know is built
and sits on top of the hardware so all
the devices that sit here and execute
that software are centered around that
NVIDIA Tegra x1 processor which is a
kind of graphics oriented embedded
mobile phone style processor and that
hardware has its own second level of
complexity
and so in order to be able to kind of
take the same security that been applied
on the software side and know that that
was going to continue there's actually
gonna protect the device you had to know
that the same level of effort was placed
due to that device by Nvidia in their
Tiger processor and so what was
interesting is there this is not just a
hardware system right this system on a
chip starts and it started a code runs
free boot rom that is executed as
software on a small dedicated purpose
processor that is responsible for
ensuring the route of trust for this
device that boot ROM is firmware the
firmware was written by Nvidia and not
Nintendo and that is the piece that is
doing all of the signatory checks for
the system in order to ensure that the
start of day you are running trusted
code in a trusted environment and
locking out any peripherals they
shouldn't have access to before you move
to the next level pre moved to the next
stage of execution but instead of having
that boot rom be well documented and
accessible and Vidya chose to hide as
many details as they could from the
public view so security engineers who
are interested in auditing this device
could not see any details about how the
boot rom executed beyond that if you did
exactly these things it would put your
device
in fact they had not just made it so
that there was not information available
they actively put Hardware mechanisms in
the device to prevent the boot ROM from
being accessible once the boot rom was
running so so once the boot rom had
finished its job and it's about to pass
its control to the next stage it
actually engaged a lockout that
prevented any future software from being
able to access the code which is a
pretty standard practice but given the
boot ROM itself was pretty much a few
standard drivers drivers for an emmc
chip drivers that pulled boot code off
of an emmc or feet off of USB or off
many of the different boot devices there
was nothing really proprietary in that
code there wasn't really a good reason
to hide that as far as I can tell it
wasn't like they were protecting their
intellectual property by locking this
out rather they were just completing the
illusion that this boot ROM was part of
the hardware so they're able to say this
boot ROM is just an implementation
detail
I see part of the hardware I'm you know
kind of as a vendor I think the real
thing you're supposed to take away is
it's part of the hardware don't worry
about it it's not there for you it'll do
its job don't look at it don't bother
touching it
it's there for you know to get that
thing started and you don't have to
worry about what's in there that is
actually a pretty fundamentally broken
approach if you're looking for hardware
security because you're not gaining
anything by hiding this you're not
hiding some IP that you're not already
providing as example code for anyone who
wants to use your peripherals and you're
not actually really gaining any security
by hiding that from anyone because the
exploits that are there are still there
right hiding them masking over them just
means the people who find it are more
likely to be the people who are
malicious who are adversaries who are
trying to break into your device as
opposed to the people who are likely to
look at the stuff you know take a two
second glance and say oh hey there's a
really fatal problem with this device so
getting your hands on that boot ROM and
being able to audit that boot ROM it's
not something you can just ask Nvidia
for what happened instead in the actual
console hacking scene is that a variety
of people set up fault injection rigs
they took there's very domain-specific
knowledge and they got that boot ROM out
there anyway so by doing in this case
voltage fault injection they were
capable of bypassing that boot ROM
lockout and it's actually essentially
stealing a small binary that was they
comprised that boot ROM this was a good
thing in terms of securing the device
the fact that this could only happen
once this device was already in consumer
hands once the code of that ROM was
fixed that's a problem and in fact the
only people who could do this kind of
thing were people who are aware of
voltage glitching techniques and who had
you know hardware that ranges from
relatively inexpensive to you know
significantly expensive hardware that
kind of limitation of scope that
limitation of the ability for an
engineer to audit your boot ROM to the
kind of people who have knowledge of
that very specific
technique significantly narrows the
pools to who's gonna be looking at this
bootrom and who's gonna be finding
things this is definitely a problem with
Nvidia's approach it turns out you don't
actually need hardware fault injection
though we did use it originally to get
things out of there if you look in some
of the code they've contributed to open
source it turns out some of the boot
configuration table entries some of the
configuration that's used to specify how
the device behaves as it starts up
actually contains two flags one of them
is called boot ROM patch control and
their their boot ROM patch data and if
you're looking at this thing trying to
get a vulnerability idea of what
vulnerabilities are from the outside
you're scouring over this as soon as you
see something called boot ROM patch
you're going okay is this something that
I can use and it turns out it's actually
relatively easy to use these if you take
a device that does not have production
security set for example if you grab a
Nvidia dev board like the Jetson tx1 and
you cone you write your own boot
configuration table you can specify
these two flags and actually write to
pretty much arbitrary memory by
specifying the memory address in one and
the value that you want to write to that
memory in another and it actually gives
you the ability to live patch memory
during the boot rom and given this is a
tiny embedded device that doesn't really
have significant protections being able
to overwrite and give an address that
happens to be for example on the stack
gives you full control of the device
while it's boot ROM is operating and
before that boot ROM lockout takes place
so this is the kind of thing that would
typically be protected would be
prevented from executing a production
device but which is you're free to
control on a unsecured development board
for example that development board has
the same boot ROM so dumping the boot
ROM off that development board means
that you get the same boot rom is
running on every Nintendo switch that is
running on every one of these devices so
there's almost no point really to having
that AI romper tection the boot ROM
protection mechanism if they're also
gonna give you something that allows you
to basically overwrite any memory you
want to on the device at the same time
so this is kind of
this is definitely the kind of thing
that happens when you have lots of
engineers working together on a project
and not really understanding what each
other's goals are somebody said we have
to hide the bootrom from people we don't
want them to be able to easily access it
but then they give you a nice little
backdoor here that you can use to easily
access the bootrom meanwhile while we're
trying to well we were trying to get
that ROM out to audit it we also had a
lot of luck just doing basic USB fuzzing
in this case basically the idea of this
USB fuzzing was to send it as many
different standard requests as we could
and to see what happened if we just
tweak the details of those requests a
little so in this case we're sending it
a request that says hey give me two
bytes of status right it's a normal get
status request but one of the parameters
we get to specify is the maximum length
the device is allowed to respond with
and it turns out instead of sending back
two bytes no matter what instead of
using that as a maximum lane if we say
hey give me 4096 bytes of status the
device spews out 49 six bytes of
response of which the first two bytes
are your status in this case all zeros
and the rest is a huge chunk of data
that happened to be on the stack so I
have a view of the stack for the device
and everything that follows the stack
which is kind of a pretty interesting
info leak but maybe this is not directly
exploitable maybe you know if everything
is done correctly maybe there's no keys
maybe there's nothing vital in this
block but once you start seeing this
kind of thing looking at the device from
the outside you're saying if they can
make this kind of mistake what other
kind of mistakes did they make it turns
out that what was actually happening
here was not just a information leak but
there was actually a mem copy inside the
boot bomb whose length was controlled by
that user control request LAN so you can
actually do a mem copy that was of a
user controlled length and which luckily
they adapt so we got a big chunk of the
stack turns out a bunch of the data that
was both in that stack and following
that stack happened to be data that the
user could
manipulating control which means that we
actually had the capability to make a
user controlled copy that is of a given
land that happens to be before the stack
into a buffer us before the stack and
where we control the contents of most of
that copy I given this thing doesn't
have any a SLR or anything it's running
in a very limited context that's
basically game over we can put our
payload at the end of thing we can write
whatever code we want to if you that
malformed request issue that request
saying hey I want a really long status
byte from you please
and then it'll copy right over the stack
for this thing this is a really really
really simple vulnerability this is not
the kind of thing that should be
existing in consumer devices at this
point in time this vulnerability
eventually became a CVE sixty to forty
two before that I and someone else who
did independently discovered it wound up
giving it a whole bunch of cutesy names
I think at this point rather than have
72 different cutesy names it's better to
just call it 62 42 but this thing was
easy to apply locally note this is a
local exploit it requires you to be
talking to the boot ROM walls and USB
recovery mode so it's not a huge huge
deal it's any evil maid who gets access
to any tegra to do whatever they want
up until the tikar x2 which is not
vulnerable to this but this is a
powerful attack given physical access
it's incredibly easy to discover if you
run a USB fuzzing tool the fact that
that USB request was there falls out of
it and this this whole kind of exploit
is relatively simple and mechanism once
you actually get the bootloader code out
of there which you can do either by
taking advantage of their own
documentation or to figure out the
ability to patch the boot rom like we
had before or by taking the info leak
that you get from this and start saying
hey okay I recognize these these
pointers kind of move here what if I
start manipulating that in order to do a
more blind application of that attack
this attack completely compromises all
of the devices verdict trusts
protections because all those Hardware
rooted Trust's technologies everything
that's doing signature validation
everything is setting up the hardware
crypto coprocessors for this device all
of those things are run in firmware on
that boot ROM this pretends to be a
hardware solution
it's more of a firmware solution right
everything that they said don't worry
about it
it's an implementation detail is
actually an implementation detail that
is backed by firmware and if we take
control of that firmware the
implementation now becomes ours to
modify so here at this point what we can
do is take advantage of the boot ROM
vulnerability to completely control how
signature validation is done how key
generation is done we can read out they
supposedly write only key spots we can
actually access this device is kind of
all the seeds of that root of trust all
the things that are burned into the
hardware itself burned the fuses that
are not supposed to ever be accessible
to software running in the device
besides the security coprocessor those
are oral ours to just you know do
whatever we'd like with and so this is a
very expensive vulnerability that
compromises the entire verdict rust on
all the relevant processors and at this
point we can have to say ok well this
isn't the only tiger in its series what
are the relevant processors so we were
hiking on the Tegra x1 but it turns out
that everything from the x1 going
backwards was affected by the same
vulnerability so if you look at this
this is a vulnerability that has existed
in Nvidia processors for a decade every
one of these processors that has a USB
recovery mode which extends all the way
back to the first Tiger Class processor
has this or an equivalent implementation
vulnerability that mem copies there and
every one of these and so you really
have to start asking yourself how the
hell do we get here this is a
vulnerability that impacts a huge number
of processors it's a relatively simple
vulnerability it is the kind of thing
that really someone doing a basic
security audit should have seen even if
they were doing that security audit you
know from inside Nvidia and
hey maybe we should just check to make
sure that we never can have an unbounded
mem copy right if you got this you got a
binary from this and you identified a
mem copy function one of the first
things that I would do I think a lot of
you would do is go take a look at where
that mem copy function is used and just
kind of say okay there's seven or eight
instances that mem copy let me to make
sure that every one of those is used in
a way that seems to make sense that
didn't happen here no one in Nvidia did
this kind of auditing no one outside of
Nvidia did this kind of auditing before
this processor was used in the Nintendo
switch turns out that you have actually
two options when you want to get a
device penetration tested you can either
hire a red team add them to your
penetration testing or you can put it in
a game console and just let the public
do it but this this device here you know
finally when it was using the Nintendo
switch people cared enough to audit it
and find that vulnerability I do not
know that we were the first people to
find this vulnerability because given
that 10-year span it is entirely
possible that somebody else did the
basic fuzzing of us to figure out that
the vulnerability existed and just
decided it wasn't in their best interest
to tell anyone
it's possible that before we discovered
this someone else discovered it and then
gave it to their nation state or to the
zero day broker and so it's entirely
possible that before the CVA was
allocated somebody like the United
States NSA you know have this in their
ant catalog you know or what their
equivalent so this is a really
significant problem both because there's
early that asymmetry between the
attackers and defenders why are we happy
in a situation where people like Nvidia
are making that information asymmetry
worse by hiding their bootrom so we have
a situation where lots and lots and lots
of these individual pieces that we've
discussed kind of led to a really sucky
State for hardware security I'll argue
that this is not necessarily a problem
with the individual actions even the
Nvidia took I don't think this was a
this is not an isolated failure this is
a failure that happens all the time
on all different kinds of devices if you
take a look at equivalent qualcomm
devices when auditing the USB recovery
mode for those they found there are
actually a couple of USB commands that
were documented internally as peek and
poke those literally took a address and
a data value and wrote them for you
inside the recovery binary that was
sitting attached to the piece that give
you your whole route of trust we are not
in a place where we point a finger at
NVIDIA report a finger at Qualcomm and
say you made a mistake this was an
isolated mistake let's take a look at
how bad this particular failure is we're
gonna have to accept what we have is a
cultural problem as Hardware security
practitioners and as hardware designers
where people don't think about this or
they think no is actually gonna you know
go and hack a light bulb or a phone this
way we don't need to spend time and
money working on this kind of thing when
this is not really a threat model that's
ever been used or applied yet but the
reality is this kind of stuff is done
all the time
if you look at solutions that are
advertised to government's there are
plenty of software solutions that are
being sold to law enforcement across the
world that allowed them to take
advantage of vulnerabilities that have
been discovered in things like iPhone
bootloaders iPhone from our stacks it
allowed them to get the contents of that
from our circumventing the protection
mechanisms that are supposed to prevent
them from doing so we are in a state
where hardware security is very very
very much a problem we have so many
people who either don't realize it or
who are contributing to a that kind of
culture where that maybe is good for a
profit maybe is good for the timing to
worry about these kind of things are
getting devices out the door really
quickly but where they wind up kind of
damaging the overall hardware ecosystem
and putting people in a position of risk
I am happy to say that when we
discovered the CVE that on the tiger
that that was responsibly too
we gave nvidia a period of 90 days nerd
incentive take a look at that and figure
out what to do by the time we had
reached that point there was not that
much they can do about it beyond getting
information out there because that was
sitting in a boot rom that was not
catchable that boot rom could not be
rewritten on devices that had already
been produced so you have ten years of
devices sitting there in you know
people's cell phones and devices like
the surface Artie's the surface pro two
the non pro versions of service we had
phones like the Nexus or pebble to the
Nexus six that had used these processors
we had you know such high profile
targets as a Microsoft Zune which was
obviously in a lot of blood bearing
positions that you know we're affected
by this but more so we had the computer
vision systems Integra cars used a Tegra
x1 processor luckily not at a lot of
them and luckily getting physical access
to those is relatively a challenge but
there were Tegra processors in the media
centers of a variety of different cars
the did the various internal buses in
that car right by the can bus right so
those media centers potentially could
give you a pivot point to start either
compromising people's privacy of these
vehicles are actually potentially
compromising the vehicles themselves so
this really significant vulnerability
just when I was kind of dropped on
Nvidia slap and at that point there was
nothing they could do about it
we're still in a position where people
who are not so inclined to responsibly
disclose can be dropping vulnerabilities
like this without really you know giving
anyone an opportunity to to react to
these things and kind of at least do
damage control and in fact this this
vulnerability was so sought after by so
many people that are conditions to
Nvidia for responsible disclosure we are
well no matter what we're coming out to
the public because the public should
have the information to decide about
whether they want to use these devices
they should be able to kind of make
decisions themselves as to whether these
devices are worth using right we don't
want to create a situation where there's
information
benefits the attacker but we recognize
there's a possibility that other people
are gonna find this and releases first
right even while we're sitting here in
the disclosure window so our conditions
were we need to get this out to the
public as soon as we can
you have 90 days to fix this stuff if
anyone releases this any even a piece of
this any sooner we're gonna go and make
all the information fully available and
I think 60 something days into this
closure window somebody else did find
this and just without being at the
consequences posted the whole thing you
know and like a kind of crummy you know
six or seven sentence right up to the
internet so in response to that we
released her full tooling early in the
disclosure window and that kind of
situation was one where if not we had
not kind of given those vendors time to
prepare and said you know do your best
to do this urgently because people are
going to find this we could have been
sitting in a face for devices that were
being used for critical purposes were
completely unedited 1a0 day was
effectively dropped into the public so
this is a bad situation this is one bad
situation among a giant pool of bad
situations right the harbor community
needs to fix this so what do we do how
do we actually start addressing this I
call this a cultural problem and I think
it's gonna require a cultural solution I
think we're going to need to change the
way we approach hardware security in
order to start having environments where
these kind of things are not a problem a
great quote by Joe FETs who I don't
think is here this year but who really
is one of the people who is advocate or
who is advocating for hardware security
knowledge to be disseminated as this
kind of you have they don't call it easy
we're right we as hardware hackers
present all the stuff as deep wizardry
and it's easy to see why we want to do
that it's you know we can sit there and
go like hey this is the you know most
hardened system I've ever out of my
hands on but I knocked it over in 20
minutes using some USB you know it
sounds great it really is good for
building our egos but it has this really
nasty consequence because when we start
saying look at how cool we are look at
this deep magic we are doing we're also
telling people that hardware hacking in
so is something that is only done by
people who are in rooms like this one
only done by the quote-unquote elite of
hardware hackers so many people look at
this look at these techniques and say
well that's so far beyond me I could
never do that even if all they would
need is as understanding of some
protocols and even if all they would
need is a USB cable and some USB fuzzing
tools there to find critical
vulnerabilities like this one I have had
hacker friends who got to me and said
hey can you make me a u adapter for this
thing you know I'm you know I'm halfway
across the world but can you like make
me an overnight me you are an adapter
sitting in takács the thing I'm saying
like okay but it there like single
inline pins their point one's based you
could solder to that they're like solder
got no that's not Lansing my
capabilities I do not think I could
convince people that hardware is somehow
this magical mystical separate domain
than the domain we all work in software
developers work with a lot of different
technologies they work with web
technologies they work with C they
program kernels people were in the
computer science kind of domain are not
in such a separate domain that they
don't have to worry about the hardware
or understand the hardware we have to
stop treating this like this is special
or different even if it lets us you know
walk into rooms and say hey I'm a
hardware wizard look what I can do so
this idea that they don't call it easy
where the idea this is somehow separate
which is brought up my Toph it's always
in the the this kind of great maja the
love I'm gonna tell you how this stuff
is and I'm gonna tell you how to do it
I'm gonna show you that you can be the
kind of person who attacks hardware I
think that is I think that's both a
really great summation of kind of the
mindset that we need to get away from
and a great solution to these kind of
things we need to show that hardware
hacking is approachable and the kind of
thing that can be done by anyone
we need to fill in that artificial
divide between hardware and software
engineers we need to make it so that we
don't ever have another electrical
engineer going like oh let's see I don't
think I can touch it or another you know
software person say okay yeah I'm a soft
for a guy I don't have to touch this
which by the way one thing that is
really irritating in generalist there's
no equivalent to the phrase hardware guy
that's gender-neutral so like you can't
go and be like I'm a hardware girl
because I totally just that sounds
completely different there's complete
different connotations to that so maybe
someone fix that but the this device
shouldn't be there everyone who is
sitting here who can do firmware stuff
can delve deeper and maybe should delve
deeper when they have the opportunity to
learn there's not a magical wall sitting
here between hardware and software
people if you can learn multiple
software techniques you can start
learning Hardware techniques and we need
to build that into our culture instead
of saying that there are these rigid
groups of hardware people on software
people we also need to stop taking the
people who we view as these wizards and
lifting them up to the point where we're
saying like ok this is this person is an
elite hardware hacker look at all the
things they've knocked over look at how
they have you know jail breaks for these
five iPhones look at how they have you
know what our abilities allow you get
access to the Nintendo switch or
whatever stop worshipping these people
stop making that the thing that people
are kind of aspired to most the people
in the hardware hacking space all right
they're split into one of two camps the
people who are really approachable
really great educators who want to tell
you how to add Hardware I'm gonna make
it seem simple so you can get your hands
on it and then we have these people who
are kind of secretive about things you
hide the details to themselves who come
up with five or six exploits for you
know Playstations or Nintendo systems
and say okay I have these exploits I'm
not sharing details with there they go
and they set themselves up as people who
are kind of like yeah look at how great
I am with very little follow through or
little follow up to that we need more
teachers we need more people who are
willing to go out and describe the
hardware and show people how to hack
Hardware and we need less people who are
just saying look
the hardware that I've hacked we also
need to get rid of some of the barriers
to entry for hacking hardware there are
so many people who when you know
approach with the concept of hardware
hacking say I can't do that either I
don't have the equipment I don't have an
expensive oscilloscope that you need for
this I don't have you know the ten
thousand dollar fault injection board
that you need to do this kind of thing
and I don't have any of the knowledge
for this because no one ever taught me
hardware hacking as a thing and when I
go and look at hardware hacking someone
starts off with the word UART in their
article and by the you know the Tyler
six things in there saying how they
scheduled the DMA attack from point A to
point B and I didn't know what the
letters DMA stood for you know I mostly
write CI microcontrollers you know this
is kind of lack of entry-level
inexpensive tools and inexpensive you
know or open accessible entry level
tutorials and educational materials that
helps to build that divide between
people who consider themselves Hardware
hackers and people who don't you have
people who are afraid of getting into
hardware hacking and who have not been
given the opportunity or the things they
need in order to start analyzing and
getting in and learning in the hardware
hacking space I think Don is here aboard
ship whisperer light which actually is a
really extremely inexpensive hardware
hacking tool for fault injection this is
something I'd like to hold up as an
absolutely wonderful example of what can
be done in order to get rid of the
barriers to entry for these kind of
things building open source hardware
build the inexpensive hardware that
enables you to do something that is
commonly you know reserved for people
who can afford really expensive
equipment is a great way to get these
kind of techniques to a point where
people can start applying them right
where it's not hey you know build up
something in an uncontrolled environment
from transistors yourself or spend
$10,000 on a really expensive voltage
glitching board building tools like this
building trainings open sourcing those
trainings are all really incredible ways
to start empowering people to start
getting their hands on hardware and the
more people we have getting their hands
on hardware the bet
it's gonna be for everyone and the more
we're gonna start seeing these
high-profile vulnerabilities address
early because people will start getting
their hands on the these kind of
vulnerabilities and making you know kind
of a public splash the more people we
have participating the more we share the
load the better this is for everyone
we also have to not let our educational
spaces develop additional barriers this
is something that is really really
problematic in a lot of early hacker
communities where that rocks our culture
leads people to kind of say okay I'm
gonna yeah I'm one of the best of the
best and if you're not get out of here
right in our hardware hacking spaces we
need to make sure we are not ever
creating mindsets that get people to
stay away from those kind of spaces we
need to address toxicity before it
starts limiting the amount of people who
can focus on these things
mandatory call a lot do not under any
circumstances advocate for anyone's free
speech if that free speech if that
ability to express themselves is driving
other people away from the community
right if you have someone who feels safe
because they can express themselves and
they choose to use that dispel in a
racist or sexist views you are also
driving people out of that community by
making other people feel unsafe this is
a hugely rampant problem in a lot of the
hardware hacking spaces and a lot of the
console hiding spaces that doesn't
really reach conferences like this that
culture makes it made so many people I
know just turn away from this kind of
thing so we need to make sure that we're
not adding additional barriers beyond
the burdens to learn we need to make
sure that our culture actually is one
that lets people grow and thrive in
these spaces and for goodness sake do
not as a vendor start hiding away
implementation details if you have to
protect your IP that's one thing I can
understand that I can kind of say okay
that makes sense to me
I understand why you're doing this don't
hide your bootrom because you just don't
want people to see it
maybe you're embarrassed because you
didn't spend that much work on it it's
full of owner abilities but those
vulnerabilities are there whether you
hide them or not and don't think you're
gonna avoid the consequences
of your actions if you hide things
security via obscurity has not ever
worked especially once you have you know
once you happen to be the ones whose
processor gets picked up and put in a
major gaming system or a major financial
application as soon as that target has
value suddenly the hammer is gonna come
down all right so one more thing why am
i bringing this up now what's the point
of telling this to you people gathered
here at hardware i/o we've already heard
that the people in this room are kind of
the best of the best in this niche of
hardware and I have the beginning of the
speakers let's just kind of as a prop
here to kind of demonstrate that we have
people here who care about hardware we
have people who participate in the
community and have come here because
they're willing to share other people
have come here because they're willing
to learn and hopefully in learning start
to develop their own techniques in their
own media to share we have people who
are not even necessarily the best of the
best I want to avoid that idea that we
have rockstars in this field the people
who are coming here able and willing to
provide those kinds of pieces I said in
the beginning that I think a keynote
should be inspiring and then I
immediately told you hardware security
sucks hopefully to most of the people
who are in this room that is an
inspirational sentiment because
hopefully most people who are in this
room see an opportunity in that and
hopefully everyone who looks at the
state of hardware security says this is
something we can do better and by giving
a talk here or describing a technique
I've come here to try to help you get
you know started with this stuff I've
started trying to build you know things
that fill that gap that addressed that
need so the goal here and I think as you
spend your time here at hardware do the
goal for everyone should be to start
thinking how do I take the knowledge I'm
gaining and how do I disseminate as much
knowledge as I'm capable of giving and
how do I address those cultural gaps in
order to push us to a place where
hardware security is something we can be
proud of every one of us as
practitioners has work we can be proud
of behind us right or we'll have work
that we can be proud of in the future
and it's important that we take all
of that effort that we put in and extend
it to also improving the community I go
forth and take what you have and do good
with it all right thank you who would
like to start with the question so just
sharing a little experience because you
said resonated with my own experience so
when they was talking with the partners
I work for ArmA and I was talking to a
pattern about protecting memory and they
needed a device where memory was
encrypted and things like that so they
said oh yeah we understand them in if
the memory is in a socket okay yes but
you have to consider also the case where
the memory is soldered why can you
interpose of that so for some people
really the fact that you have to take a
solder in your hands is already magic
and you're right we need to fight this a
minute if I can solder and I can tell
you am a bad solder er anybody can it's
not magic right I definitely agree with
that I think there is there's always
some value in understanding the attacker
any of your threat model and what the
attackers level of effort is going to be
and it we have a limited amount of
resources right now we're not in a
position where we can say definitively
okay let's get everything perfect and so
it may be true that understanding the
guess us pieces of Ramnath soldered onto
a board may increase the attacker level
of effort to get that stuff
understanding that and being able to
factor that into your threat model is
something that's absolutely vital we
need to be able to have people
understand that there are these
techniques out there so you're right
it's not magic it is stuff that people
can actually get their hands on and do
and being able to make informed
decisions even if you're not someone
who's going to be doing that soldering
can
all done in order to be able to actually
let people who are developing these
things factor that into the threat model
and make the right decisions given the
resources they have do you think what's
the time frame that you should give
manufacturers to fix the vulnerabilities
at hardware is 90 days policy good
enough it depends on what you think the
solutions are as a practitioner so once
you've identified a vulnerability I've
seen some very interesting kind of
things where sometimes it seems like
it's gonna be a software effects you
know the firmware that needs to you know
needs to be patched when they need to
address that we can kind of treat that
to a degree like a more complex version
of software so 90 days has become the
standard for a lot of software based
vulnerabilities in the case of the
Nvidia bug we had something where there
really was no right course of action
besides telling people and letting them
know that their devices were
compromising and letting them decide
what to do next whether they want to
replace those devices get them out of
the field you know that 90-day window
was a good opportunity for them to
disseminate that that information as
much as they could but hardware is such
a such a subtle differences between
software and that once you've put out a
piece of hardware it may not be possible
to start manipulating that hardware it
may be a much more significant effort
than not a software system so really
what I would advise is talking to the
manufacturer as much as you can maybe
coming to the table with a baseline of
90 or you know 120 days and from there
saying you talk to us involve us in your
fix process you know ideally pay us
money and we'll help you fix this but
involve us in this whole disclosure
process let us know what you were going
to need because it's important that we
put pressure on you it's important that
we actually get you to fix these
problems but we understand that this is
something that is you know we don't
necessarily even know the hardware as
well as you do as the vendor work with
us and try to figure out what time frame
makes sense because I think up until we
have more experience and kind of see a
lot of a lot more case studies of how
these different kind of techniques work
we're not gonna be able to just carve
out like a 90-day rule like we have been
able to in software
I have a question thank you very much
for the talk
so hardware security is already a big
field and speaking about resources
assuming we have all the resources the
manpower the time the money where should
we focus these resources to make
hardware security hardened or more
secure that really is always going to
have to depend on what your individual
threat model is so if your threat model
is expensive is all of hardware security
I would suggest to look at the things
that are happening now the current
state-of-the-art breaches what you are
seeing and identify you know try to
identify what skills what lack of skills
led to these kind of situations when you
if you can identified that and you can
kind of reactively say you know for now
we don't necessarily know the whole
shape of the Fielder was lacking but we
can start making it so that you know
penetration testers are armed with the
right kind of techniques and so on
defense defensive engineers are armed
with the right kind of techniques to
deal with the threats of today and we
can kind of react and grow as expand as
we get more resources the you know if
you do have an individual threat model
that definitely informs what you're
going to look into with your individual
group thank you
it's time for one more question
thank you nice talk
so um hardware is kind of getting
cheaper nowadays maybe do you think are
we willing to pay some sort of
performance overhead for the security in
the sense that for instance there are
automatic methods and things that you
can deploy the compiler especially for
the case that you showed maybe you could
have some sort of Reds owning or other
techniques that are already using in
let's say your personal computer
software do you think we are at the
point where we can pay this overhead
cost to improve security I think we have
been for a while at this point where we
used to always think about especially in
software development this kind of time
space trade
and hardware we talk about space weight
and power right you have frequency as
one access you have power as another and
then you have the actual cost to develop
these things we're gonna have that
triangle that we've been balancing
between for a long times and I think
we're long overdue to have security be
one of the constraints in that because I
think it's very I think we're going to
need to start threat modeling or
hardware and using that to inform those
kind of trade-offs because being able to
have a you know an embedded system that
performs extremely well and is extremely
power efficient doesn't help you with
that embedded system is in a position
where it can have a pretty significant
compromise that makes it worthless or
that enables it to attack other things
sometimes sure you'll have a device
that's literally the microcontroller
that determines whether or not a
flashlight turns on when you press the
button right sermons the PWM for
modulating LED maybe those kind of
things don't require all that trade-off
but knowing what space we have what
threat models we have and what
trade-offs we can make is definitely
going to kind of allow us to inform that
because there are so many cases where
maybe we don't need our cell phone
battery life to be you know fully at a
hundred percent a level it could have
been maybe having a battery life of 95%
and not having that vulnerability you
know how many I don't have as much of a
vulnerability space is a trade-off
you know we're willing to make
especially as these Hardware attacks
come more delight so I think that's
definitely a space that we yes thank you
good thank you
[Applause]