hey everyone thank you for coming my
name is Ben and I'm Colin and today we
would like to talk to you about this new
site and check side channel attack that
we have called TL bleeds so we're gonna
use the TLB to leak some secrets and
cavae can introduce to you now through
the landscape of cache attacks cache
defenses and uh later on tell you about
how to bleed fits into that landscape
thanks man
so who are we you're part of food sack
so you might have heard of us you're the
security research group at full
university in Amsterdam so we do
research on software security but so and
then we do software hardening
exploitation but they also do hardware
attacks and side channels and this is
going to be what we're going to talk
about today and here you can see been
holding his pwnage plug and you will
soon see why all right so this is the
overview of the talk I'm gonna quickly
talk about cache attacks for those of
you who are not familiar with them and
then a little bit about defenses that we
are deploying these days against this
cache attacks and then Ben is going to
tell you why all of these defenses are
broken and then we're going to tell you
how effective this new attack is and
then you're also going to talk about a
little bit about the reception how
people basically reacted to the
discovery of the TL bleed attack all
right so what are cache attacks
so to understand cache attacks you first
need to understand what side channels
are and so if I want to basically
introduce it I would say like it is
basically something some mechanism that
allows you to leak some secret
information without you directly asking
for it and basically to make it more to
give a more real-life example we always
use this this teeth was trying to steal
something from this safe and this person
was basically wearing a stethoscope
trying to listen to how the the lock is
sounding whenever you try to basically
figure out the combination now if you
want to go through the real channel
right
you have to brute-force it right and it
would take maybe days if not years right
and then of course the burglar doesn't
have this much time so basically by just
listening through the the mechanism in
the lock the the burglar could figure
out what the combination is and there is
a share channel between the burglar and
this mechanism in which the the select
the secret is being leaked the secret
being this combination and this share
channel is the air right so it's a sound
right and then there is this air which
is shared and then this basically
through this air the sound basically
gets leaked and then suddenly you can
figure out what what the secret is so
this is in a real world but okay so what
happens inside the CPU and for that we
need to understand what is being shared
right so if you now go and buy an Intel
CPU or an AMD CPU well this one is
specifically an architecture of an Intel
CPU so if you buy one and you basically
try to understand to look at the
architecture diagram you you find out
that it basically is architected in such
a way that you have multiple cores right
and these CPUs these days or on are all
based on the one Neumann architecture
which means that you have memory which
is far away from the CPU but it is very
slow so to make it fast you start having
caches right it needs me and the faster
the closer to the CPU the faster you
want these caches to be which means that
they have to be smaller so this is like
basically the fundamental way in which
caches are designed if you want them to
be fast they have to be a small but as
you start like going further away from
from the the course you start to share
more and more so for example at the the
lowest level the the last level you have
a cache that is shared in between course
so basically a core could use some part
of the l3 which is also used by another
core in the system so this is being
shared between these cores and from my
previous examples now you immediately
can see that this could lead to some
problems right so and you might also
wonder like at the upper levels for
example if you look at this l2 what else
could be shared so if you look at the
core so this is not just a single
execution context oftentimes you have
now threads in Hardware
you have these things that are info
Kazem hyper threats right that are
basically sharing these upper level cash
is like l1 and l2 all right
so and you use these shared resources to
build side channel attacks so it is not
just the CPU caches that I just told you
about but also your memory is shared
between different execution contexts
your your TLD is also shared this is
which is a different cache which we will
get into soon and using all of these
shared resources basically you can leak
information but it's not always the case
that you want to leak something
sometimes you don't want to allow two
different processors for example to
communicate with each other directly but
by using this shared medium they could
indirectly communicate with each other
so if there is a shared medium and I
start to use it then the other entity
that wants to use this wouldn't be able
to use it as fast for example and this
could be this principle could be used to
build a communication channel so
whenever I want to send a 1-bit I start
using it and then the other the other
entity will know that I'm using it and
this means that I'm sending a one bit
right and so but sometimes so this is
fine it means that both of these
processes are cooperating with each
other but the more interesting case is
when one of these processes is just a
victim that doesn't know what is
happening and then the other process
tries to understand what this victim
process is doing and this is what is
known as the side channel attack so
basically allows the add one entity at
the attacker entity to spy on the other
entity so to basically make this a
little bit more concrete I will give you
an example a very famous example which
is called a flush and reload attack this
work has been published by you well and
Katrina and I explained how this works
so here on top we have an attacker
process and a victim process and then
the attacker is doing a bunch of
operations to figure out whether the
victim is doing a certain memory access
or not right and then later I will
basically show you why this detection of
whether the victim is doing a memory
access is good enough for the attacker
to figure out basically a cryptographic
key
so here is what the attacker will do so
the attacker will flush a certain part
of the cache right one part of the cache
and then the attacker waits for a while
right another attacker tries to access
that location in the cache again now
because the attacker has flushed this
location if the location is still
flushed the access is going to be a slow
and so in this case the victim is doing
something else is not doing access at
that memory location which would mean
that basically the access has not
happened right in the second case right
the attacker does the same thing it
flushes the cache but in the meantime
the victim doesn't memory access this
time now this would mean that this
location is now cached right and then
the attacker tries to check whether this
location is cached or not and this time
because this the the memory location is
now in the cache this operation happens
faster and now the attacker could detect
that basically the victim has performed
a memory access you can use this too as
I said attack eclipta graphic
implementation here for example assuming
an aes implementation that uses t-table
I'm using a lot of words that you may
not understand but the thing that you
you the only thing that you need to
understand is that the attacker just
tries to understand whether this table
has been accessed or not so here you
have a table and basically the the
location in which table which is getting
access every time you know this this AES
operation is happening depends on the
secret key and the input that the
attacker could provide so you give a
plaintext and then depending on the veto
of the key some location in this table
gets accessed and now using the
primitives that I just told you about
the attacker could figure out basically
visual occasion in this table is
accessed and since the attacker we
assumed that knows also the plaintext
it could basically figure out the secret
bit so the secrets are by this by the
virtue of these memory access the
secrets are being betrayed and by
controlling the plaintiff plaintext and
looking at the memory access you can
recover the key so you might wonder how
this looks like and he
for example the attacker could detect
these these bites this so like this
these are the latency measurements and
like if it is black it means that
basically it was quite a fast operation
and basically doing by doing these
measurements we can figure out basically
that given the plain text which cache
line was accessed and this allows you to
lick the the secret secret value and so
we have another example for you where we
visualize these so like accesses in the
cache so and this example uses the Lib G
crypt
ECC point multiplication which is
another cryptographic routine and
basically it works like that so don't
look at all these so like code that is
there the only thing that you need to
worry about is this basically routine
that gets basically execute execute
executed and it depends on this scalar
which comes from your cue to graphic key
and if this bit is set then basically
there is an addition operation that that
happens right so if we can detect
whether this addition operation is
happening it means that this this bit
location is 1 and otherwise is 0 so
let's look at basically when we give an
input to this function how does it look
like it looks like from the point of the
cache so this is how it looks like so
the blue one is if the key if the key
bit is 0 and the green one if it is 1
obviously you can see that whenever the
the bit is 0 the operation is shorter
but more importantly whenever the bit is
1 it also the type of access patterns
that happen is a little bit more
different and to actually understand
this a little bit better we have tried
to basically put them back to back to
see how they look like and they look
like this by the way the upper part is
data I think and the lower part is
caught so here for example you can see
that the blue part is basically when the
bit is 0 and the green part is when the
bit is 1 so operation takes longer now
it might not immediately be obvious for
you what the difference into this so so
you need to do some statistical analysis
and then gives an example of this
statistical analysis when he talks about
his TL delete attack the only thing that
you need to believe me on is that there
is a
friends between these two alright okay
so now let's look at so people of course
realize that this is a problem and let's
fix this right so they try to change the
cryptographic function to make it more
constant time and so when we execute the
one that is actually safe the accesses
all look like this right so it looks
like they're all the same and we would
not be able to actually see the signal
from this bit key that is one but
actually what they do is that they do
all this operation as if you know
regardless of the bit in the keyboard at
the very end they only commit the
results if the bit is one all right so
instead of using all this lock operation
all the time you see it at the very end
so if they keep the bit of the key is
one there is some little operation here
that happens that is a little bit
different and using this at the very end
instead of happening all the time we
could still figure out that the key bit
is 1 or 0 and so the the select the
result of this story is that the moral
of the story is that this is actually
not so easy to build constant time cash
implementations so we have realized this
and we have started like coming up with
more protections against this so forget
that like the software could not do this
in a safe way well if we could build
some protections in which if we run some
software some piece of code then it will
always be side-channel free so
regardless of what the software is doing
could we make it in a way that it will
be protected against this cash attacks
so that's what the defense is coming to
play well the defense is coming to play
and I'm going to tell you a bunch of
these examples of these cash defenses so
the first one is basically tries to
partition the cash here you can see the
first diagram that I showed you earlier
and here you can see that the l3 is is
shared within this course so assume that
I want to protect the first code from
the second code what I can do is I can
partition my cache in a way that core 0
does not have access for example to the
part of the cache that core 1 could
access so if I make this perfect
isolation between these two then I
cannot do a cache attack through l3 for
let's see how this is done in practice
this is by the way a technique that is
most commonly known as cash coloring and
the reason why they're called color is
so elect to make it easier to understand
what you want to figure out is how your
memory addresses are mapped to cache
locations and since there are a limited
number of cache locations you could
attach a tag to it and call it a color
so you could say like okay I have a
color blue and all these memory
addresses in the system would map to
color blue right and this is how it
would look like so if you can figure out
this mapping between your memory
addresses to cache locations you could
basically partition the system by giving
different processes different memory
addresses so they would map to different
parts of the cache and then if you do
this then say if one process only has
access to color blue then basically the
red process would not be able to
interact with the part of the cache that
is allocated to to process that is blue
and this basically prevents this sharing
of resources between these two processes
now this could stop cache attacks but
the problem is that now you have so like
some limitation in terms of how your
kernel or your operating system could
allocate memory to different processes
in the system and so this this
limitation basically makes it quite
complicated to write memory management
code I don't know how many of you have
tried to understand or fiddle with
memory management code if you have you
know that it is quite already as it is
it's quite complicated so if you want to
add more constraints to it it becomes
certainly much much more complicated so
people typically don't like to do this
just to give you a little bit more
information so that when when Ben starts
introducing TLB you would understand the
attack a little bit better I will try to
explain how these mapping between memory
locations to cache locations happen so
basically your caches are partitioned in
what we call sets so here we are
basically showing different sets as this
so like basically horizontal boxes so
here is one set here is the second set
and so on and each set will have some
spaces so
summer space it has a size in which
number of entries could go to this set
and if you access more memory locations
to that map this set you need to kick
out some other entries from this set to
make sure that there is a space for the
other one and this is known as ways so
if you're if you have say eight cache
sets with two ways it would mean that
your memory address address could go to
any of these cache eight cache sets but
not more than three of these memory
locations that map to the same cache
that could could basically remain in the
cache no more than two so if you have a
third one wanting to access the same guy
set you have to buy by construction
remove one of those previous elements
and this is something that is known as
cache eviction when we'll talk about
this a little bit more so this is how
cache coloring voids and yeah by the
virtue of this separation then the
process the different processes would
not be able to look at each other this
is not working so the other protection
so as I said like this is something that
is difficult to do you need to change
your the core of your operating system
which is not something easy so and
people have tried to solve this problem
right and they how do you solve this
problem you rely on your hardware to
basically provide you with the same same
support and so there is this technology
that is called cache allocation
technology that isn't an extension by
recent Intel processors and if your CPU
has this support you could use it to do
partitioning of your cache and so this
was originally introduced by Intel so
that we could provide quality of service
to your virtual machines in the cloud so
if you run virtual machines and s only
like one virtual machine could basically
occupy the entire cache get all the
performance and then the other virtual
machine would basically have very little
performance bad performance right you
don't want this to happen
Intel came up with this technology to
make sure that you a statically
partition your cache so that this
wouldn't happen and now basically what
you could you could do we could use this
technology to also provide some security
rather than basically just isolation so
it is basically a hardware feature that
you rely on so assuming that this is
your cache again
and you have your basically two
processes that you have in the system
what you could do is that you could
partition your system using cat
partition your cat using the number of
ways so here in this example we have two
ways which means that we could partition
only two processes in the system right
in reality the number of ways is a
little bit more it's for example if you
have a normal l3 system is often times
twelve or or sixteen so here now all
each process so it could access any
where in the memory but basically the
partitioning happening at the add
available but it could only host one of
these entries in the cache sets so now
using these not one process cannot
aspire other but this would mean that
now even though if there are so even
though you have like different number of
days you can only access a certain
limited number of phase right and since
you have a limited number of ways it
would mean that since you're
partitioning your cache in a very coarse
way your performance is also gonna be
bad and this is also something that you
may not want the other thing is that the
number of these ways in your system is
kind of limited right it's like 12 or 16
so it means that you could only have 12
security context in your system this may
also be a limitation that you may not
want so people have realized this and
they have come up with a second
technology that is called the tsx and
what is tsx is another extension by
intel that provides support for hardware
transactions so and how would this work
so typically you want to have support so
sometimes you want so you've written
some piece of code and you always want
this piece of code to execute it in its
entirety so if you're executing some
piece of code and at some point you
realize that something has gone wrong
you want to roll back all of this
computation to the point that you
started the transaction so those of you
who have written banking software for
example you know that this is something
that is very useful right you don't want
a transaction of a customer to abort at
some point and until you have deducted
the money without that person having
gotten the money from the ATM for
example right so we want this operation
to happen in
entirety either I withdraw the money or
I don't the value in my bank account
shouldn't change if I don't right and so
this is how Intel tries to provide
support for these kind of operations and
the idea is that the Select since this
whole thing happens inside the CPU you
want to make sure that all the writes
and reads that your transactions are
doing happen remain in the CPU cache and
this is what is called the transaction
working set and if this transaction
working set basically you all you go
over the amount of cash that you have
available automatically we will get an
abort because the processor can no
longer ensure that your code runs in a
transaction logic and you could also use
this principle to build your defense
right because the attacker remember
needs to basically flush parts of your
cache right and if you see that you're
getting an abort because of this then
you could so this signals that there may
be something fishy going on so you could
use this to detect that there is an
ongoing attack so we can use this as a
defense and yeah so people have done
this and so this is the the same figure
that I showed you earlier and if you
actually run it inside a tsx transaction
you can see that the signal gets diluted
quite heavily and then you can no longer
detect that there was a soul I can
access inside a certain location in your
tea table so know that I've basically
told you about this cache defenses so
this is where we started last year when
we start thinking about okay are we done
have you fixed all of these problems
with with cache attacks right and then
there so we were looking at the
instruction manual of Intel and then
there we realized that okay there is a
TLB right that is also shared between a
different execution context actually be
in different hyper tress which Ben is
going to talk about and the thing that
you immediately think about when you
want to think about this attacks is that
how many sets are there are there
actually sets in the TLD so this is the
first thing that we basically come to
your mind then looking at the
instruction manual it was it basically
was written there that there are
actually sets so we know that we are
onto something right
so if we started this journey that would
look that would lead to this discovery
of this new attack and during this
journey the thing that we discovered is
that actually the sets don't matter
right so so we had to do to the
limitations that we had we had to come
up with a new attack that would not
matter whether you had you have set in
your TLB or TLB or not and I know hand
over the presentation tube and to
explain the new attack that we had he
had to come up with to actually be able
to lead your stuff even though you have
only a single set that you could lead
your data from great thank you coming
all right so let's talk about this TLB
business so as Kavi explained there are
many shared resources in a system we
have the RAM with the cache and whenever
you ever shared resource there's this
risk of a signal leaking from one
protection domain to another which is
supposed to be impossible right there's
supposed to be this perfect abstractions
but because of all these shared
resources we realize these abstractions
are actually quite porous it would be
very nice if using these generic cache
defenses these cache side channels would
be gone but and and then to to a large
degree that is true for cache attacks
but turns out that if you use different
shared resources this problem returns
even with deployed cache defenses and we
can exploit the TLB to also leak secrets
okay so let's see how this works so by a
show of hands who here knows about how
page tables work great okay I can see
we're in a room of experts okay so let's
just go over quickly about this idea of
page tables so CPUs constantly handle
addresses executing from particular
address they're loading data from an
address that's throwing the internet
dress and all of these addresses are
what we call virtual addresses that's
the point of virtual address is to give
every process the pleasant illusion that
they have a 64-bit this huge 64-bit
address space completely private to them
alone no one else no one else's memory
is in there and your own memory unless
you want it to be is not anyone anyone
else's address space so you kind of have
this illusion of
the machine to yourself hence the idea
of virtual this abstraction is created
by the operating system which assembles
a data structure called page tables
which is this which is a mapping from
this huge sparse virtual address space
to the real physical address space which
is not sparse it's just you know on RAM
chips and it changed and mapping
whenever the process changes this
mapping changes also the operating
system takes care of this now this is a
beautiful mechanism it has very powerful
properties but it's also if you have to
look up this translation every single
time you handle an address which is all
the time it would be very very slow so
therefore all these translations are
constantly are cached very aggressively
in this caching structure called the TLB
Tilby is short for translation lookaside
buffer so the CPU is constantly
accessing the Tilby because it
constantly needs to translate from
virtual addresses to physical addresses
so what if the TLB were shared between
CPUs maybe between cores or between
hyper threads if that's true then the
activity of one thread would be visible
to another thread just because of the
fact that the Shankill be is in exactly
the same way as we can lick actively
through the cache so what we know is
that so let's try and find out about
this what we know is that Tilby has two
levels level one and that's in the
documentation right so we have just like
the caches have levels the tlbs levels
which is a faster level one split in
instructions and data translations of
course and level two which is much
larger and a little bit slower and
shares instructions in data and in
exactly the same way as caches have our
partitions in two sets which have a set
size called the number of ways the TLB
we expect is partitioned in a very
similar kind of way but we have no idea
what the structure is because it's not
documented by the structure we mean if I
take a particular look up into which set
or slot into which set is this going to
go into the into the TLB in other words
I want to be able to predict when I get
when I acts as a set of addresses which
can i cached at the same time and which
can I not
at the same time because the set that
they go into overflows that's what I
have to know to monitor Tilby activity
so let's look at the steal be as just
another cache and as Kara was saying
this is the representation of how a
cache might be structured so if you
imagine that all of these things are Ram
cache lines right there's this these Ram
blocks can go down for billions in the
downwards direction but there's only a
limited number of cache cells that these
items can be cached into they all have
to stay in the same column because this
is the first blue oops sorry
this is the first blue cache set this is
the first blue cache yet the second blue
cache at third blue cache it and you
can't go from here to here you have to
stay in your own column that's just
limitation of the hardware and any of
this column will ask Allah was saying
has 8 or 16 or so entries the way Innis
the number of ways that we have so as
you can see this structure so that what
do you mean by the structure is that
this column if I if I take any of these
blocks how do I - which set is it mapped
so let's try and find out about that so
let's just assume that the mapping is
linear just as we saw that just now like
the first column goes in the first set
second Congress and the second set and
so on and that and that the physical
addresses were laid out one two three
four five six eight nine just in this
linear mapping and that goes into these
sets in car this nice round robin
fashion doesn't have to be that way but
let's assume that's the case and see if
the curve that an experiment that we can
make bears out this hypothesis so let's
try and find for this for the l1 detail
be how many sets do we have and how many
ways to the what do we have under the
assumption that we have a linear mapping
so we try many possible combinations of
how many sets do we have from 0 to 80
how many ways do we have what is the set
size from 0 to 20 and we try and we
assemble eviction sets that would fit
perfectly into this TLB if it were that
size for all these combinations access
them over and over and over again and
using performance counters we
well do we get it he'll be hit or til be
miss and what we expect to see is that
when we have the exact right
configuration we see no misses but when
we go one over then we start to see
misses
so what we see is that the smallest set
size where we can see any misses
whatsoever is four that's here and the
smallest number of sets corresponding to
these misses is 16 so what we see here
is that our policies of they are one
detail be having linear mapping with 16
sets and 4 ways each is the one that
holds so using experiments like this
cream we can reverse-engineer the
structure of the a one detail bi kill B
and with slightly more complicated
experiments we can reverse engineer the
structure of the L to kill B as well
because sometimes it's not linear what
we find is that starting with the
Skydeck microarchitecture we have to we
take the page number because it's all
about pages right and we have to exhort
the lowest 7 bits of the page number
with the next upper 7 bits we ignore
them together to get a 7 bit number so 0
227 to get the slot number so it's not
linear but it's sort of a simple simple
approximation so this is if you were to
use modular 2 arithmetic and you
multiply the page number by this matrix
then you would get that output board
well does wear something very similar
but it then uses 8 bits instead of 7
base tubes or together and get the
result
so using these techniques we find lots
of different properties of the TLB what
we want to know in order to be able to
do anything at all is are these high
till be shared at all between hyper
threads but now that we know how to
reverse engineer the structure we do
this experiment where we where we access
completely access set zero on one hyper
thread and set zero on the other and see
if we get any evictions if you see any
misses and we try all combinations from
0 to 15 on one thread 0 to 1500
threat and what we expect if we see
sharing that where we see mrs. depends
on what the other threat is doing and we
find for the other one detail be yeah we
see exactly what we were hoping which is
that zero interferes with zero zero on
one threat interferes with zero on the
other thread and set fifteen and one
threat interferes with fifteen on the
other thread we tried exactly the same
thing on the eye TLB and we see no such
sherry so we don't not we do not see any
activity on one thread that depends on
activity and the other thread
unfortunately so you know on l1 duty
ITIL B we see no sharing for LT would
you see sharing but we see this a
interesting little shift so we find that
said zero on one thread does not
interfere with sincere on the other
thread but with said sixty-four so
there's this kind of apparently in the
hash function it seems like maybe we
include the hyper thread thread ID in
this hash function therefore slot zero
interferes on one thread interface with
slot 64 on the other thread I don't
exactly know why this happens but what
we think that might be the case is that
this evens out the TLB activity from one
in the other if it sort of might spread
it out more over the whole TLB
you might get more contention otherwise
that that seems to be the purpose of
these unusual hash functions okay so
using experiments like these we reverse
reverse engineered many properties of
the TLB so we have here a list of
microarchitectures and we find well how
many sets do we have how many ways we
have we find that for the detailed beam
it's always 16 sets and four ways hash
functions always linear and it's always
shares so that'll be we find that
associativity as we call has gone up so
we used to have a way a 4-way 16 set
cache and it's gone up to an eight way
eight set cash which is better we have
the same number of entries is both 64
but because the associativity is higher
we will see under the same workloads
fewer evictions because the partitioning
is the partition is larger and we find
that for the l2
TLB we have this weird Zor function that
started with a scar like
microarchitecture and before that was
linear as well okay
so that's interesting so we know we know
that we understand the structure we know
there is sharing to a degree what you
have to find out now is how can we do
how can we observe this signal without
performance counters because performance
counters we can't use because we need a
system call that they're too slow and
they're privileged so we assemble
eviction sets that exactly cover the l1d
Tilby and the altitude till B and miss
them all together so these three
versions and we want to see just by
timing the access agencies whether
whether we if we hit one or the other or
missed altogether which means we have to
do a page table walk and we Weatherly
measure the lenses can we distinguish
one from the other and what we find is
that yeah it seems like from the timing
latency we can tell the difference
between the hit enemies in the l1 detail
B so we can use that one D TLB as a
method to observe activity on the other
hypothet so that's interesting so let's
go back to this case study of the CCC
multiplication function when we can use
this as a case study to see if we can
leak the secret bits that were
purchasing the secret bit being in the
scalar function this is an on site proof
version but as we've talked about if
there were generic cache defense
deployed this would still be safe so
let's see if a generic cache defense is
deployed and you run this code can we
still leak this data to the till B or
not so let's see what that would look
like we can only use the data access as
the distinguisher so a simulation of how
this might look like is this so if we
look at the the background shade is if
the secret bit is 0 or 1 and the
activity is now instead of using the
cache we look at the TLB side activity
so what we see is that there you can see
some kind of difference but it seems
like that every set is active either all
the time all the way throughout green
and blue or neither nor a green nor blue
so there's no easy distinguishing
feature here that would let us see one
or the other so let's see a simulation
of that
let's see better simulation that yeah so
this is a cash trace similar to the one
Caudill was showing you but instead of
the cash trace it observe it shows you
the activity in teal be set so that
means there are fewer of them and the
granular the spatial granularity is much
lower because we're talking about in the
cache we have 64 byte cache lines but
these are 4 K pages so we have much less
information going for us
so I don't know about you but if I look
at this I can't really tell the
difference much in in blue or green yeah
I can tell green is longer of course but
we can't really use their information
because as an attacker we can't see
length we could only see patterns so
this is part tricky so we want to be
able to distinguish green from blue
using just a signal like this ok so
let's try and do this even though it
looks hard what we can see if now it
looks hard is that patterns like these
are different right they're a little bit
different in time so I see this axis
pattern when it's green always and this
access pattern which is you know fewer
dots together when it's blue so can we
maybe exploit this temporal signal in an
attack
so let's monitor a single teal be set
and use this temporal information we'll
try and use a simple information to
recognize are we in a groove sorry
are we in a blue area blue shady area or
in a green shed area which corresponds
to the secret key pit don't forget
so can we distinguish here from one
using this using this technique so this
is so this is a real attack scenario so
we have a spying process which monitors
one particular teal boosted over and
over and over again and the latency will
be low always unless the victim is doing
something there as soon as the victim
does something their lane see will go up
because it means our own Tilby entry is
gone
so this is what it looks like so we have
negative give the ping so this is the
victim does something nothing looking
for something nothing and so on so this
looks quite noisy so I can't read
tell the difference between blue and
green but if you take a moving average
just to make it kind of easier on our
human eyes then we can start to see some
regularity there is certainly for the
blue case and we can kind of tell that
the green case is at least different in
some way we seems like we could have a
chance to distinguish these signals as
long as we don't have to do it by hand
so let's try and train this using
machine learning so we take this SVM
classifier called the support vector
machine I was briefly show you how this
what this looks like so this SVM machine
learning classifier we can train by so
it tries to distinguish training samples
and this is the training face you showed
a bunch of green dots a bunch of blue
dots and features then it happened you
tell them ok I want you want you to tell
me in the future is this green or is it
red and the this this algorithm will try
and find the best separating line or
plane if there are multiple features or
a hyperplane if it's if it's even more
features this is an example with only
two features we're going to give it a
sample with hundreds of measurements
it's going to be a hundred dimensional
vector space doesn't matter the same
constant replies we're gonna try and
separate it linearly using this to be
found hyperplane given a training set so
can we do that
this is the output that we get so we see
this classifier is able to distinguish
extremely well given some training
examples start of blue start of blue
start of green start of blue so every
set of green which exactly corresponds
to the secret key bits so that looks
very very promising can you tell me how
well this thing works yes of course
all right so how well does it work so
this was like we went on and implemented
all these attacks and remember all those
defenses that that we talked about
software defenses and also hardware
defenses so we wanted to know whether
she'll bleed you know bypasses all these
defenses so the first experiment that we
rerun is basically just we picked a
bunch of CPUs with different
microarchitectures right and then we
generated a number of different
cryptogram
the keys and then we wanted to see if we
do that he'll be TL bleeped attack on
this lip decrypt function that we
earlier showed you how many out of how
many times could we actually leak leak
the key and so remember that this is
like a statistical analysis so sometimes
you don't exactly get it right so but
then most of times you have to like
either repeat or you have to boot poor
brute force a large number of potential
bits that you have actually
misclassified right but it turned out
that this attack is actually has a very
very high success rate so here for
example you can see that out of like you
know a thousand cases we could
successfully identify the key in the
bits of the key in like nine nine
hundred nineteen eight of the cases and
so this basically was quite quite a good
resource and sometimes of course the
keys we some bits of the key we
misclassify so the questions that can be
brute force for therefore the actual key
and here is basically on the right side
is like the median so like on average
how many of the bits is still required
brute forcing and you can see that it's
actually on average quite a low number
of bits that that we have to brute force
and so all of these only happens quite
quickly actually so one millisecond
right so if you can just get a capture
of one millisecond out of your operation
your cryptographic operation this is
enough for us to do about a 17 seconds
of analysis to actually figure out the
key so which means that this is quite a
practical attack right so most some of
the attacks that you see in the
literature I sometimes would take like
hours or days of analysis or we require
you to get a trace out of you know
fifteen thousand cryptographic
operations here we just need like one
millisecond of operation to be able to
actually identify the key and so the
number of brute force so this is the
median you might you might wonder like
how many attempts you may need so in
most cases as you can see and as this
number shows it's actually quite low
sometimes we need to like brute force
about four billion so when it is like
tell two bits out of like a large key
that we don't know we need to brute
force quite a bit but this is still
quite doable so it would take us maybe
like I don't know the largest the
longest case report what it would be in
a matter of minutes that would would
allow us to actually do the brute force
successfully now I I talked about like
hardware defenses that people have
deployed and here is one example the cat
remember cash allocation technology and
here it shows that it basically still
successfully covers the key we have more
experiments against these so like
protections both cash coloring and also
TSX if you want to know more please go
ahead and read our paper all the
experiment results are there alright so
how did people react to TL bleed so this
end is a file the advisory with Intel
saying hey look we found this new side
channel that would allow us to leaking
leak information so and it'll took like
two months or so to come back to us and
say this has the same power as a cash
attack and since they haven't solved
cache attacks it doesn't matter that you
could also do this with the TLB so this
was the response that Intel gave so but
some people who took maybe take
seriously a little bit more seriously
like open BSD like so we're in van was
in contact with Theo de Raadt so like
main commuter of open BSD and he decided
that basically Tillett has enough impact
for a for it to justify to disable hyper
trading by default on open BSD platform
and we were also talking with Red Hat
and also because of the discussions with
Red Hat they decided to provide this
option so that we could automatically
disable hyper trading if you like so we
thought that this is was a quite a good
academic exercise but yes so the media
thought that this is more than an
academic exercise I think especially
because open BSD disable hyper trading
so they start like you know getting in
touch with us and asking basically what
is the impact of this so there were lots
of communication to the media and so we
don't usually create logos for our
attacks but so the register was so this
was a communication with albums it was
nice enough to actually create a logo
for us so this is the logo of CL delete
just two hearts with some blood leaking
and and yeah somebody went through the
hassle of creating a wiki whoops
Wikipedia entry for us yeah so to
conclude we present it to you TL bleed
which is a practical reliable and
high resolution side channel attack more
than any that has been known before so
we could get quite a lot of samples
that's why Ben could do this like
temporal attack they bypass these t
elite attacks bypass all existing known
cache defenses and yeah so if you want
to know more about this attack and
generally discussed our channels you can
find us on Twitter this is our twitter
handle and if you want to reach the
wider group you could also use our group
handle and this is the website in which
we public may be publicly publish all
the attacks that we do so this is it
this is a talk this is a TL bleed so and
we're happy to take questions if there
are any thank you hello thank you very
much I think we have time for a quick
question and then we can move into the
panel anyone since a question yeah
that's a very good question
it's tricky because the teal B is so if
you allow this sharing its if you allow
the sharing unlimited dance then it's
basically impossible because if you were
to try to do isolation in software it
would restrict the virtual address space
of the person that's running too much so
that won't work so what you would have
to do is either play tricks to
scheduling so that you don't allow these
concurrent access by two mutually
distrusting process at the same time
maybe you could introduce a system level
a system call level facility that would
temporarily inhibit the scheduling of
other processes on the on assembling
hyper thread that something like that
would work and of course a very heavy
measured with disable hyper-threading
which has significant robux because
hyper threading does allow much higher
utilization of silicon ultimately then
then without
[Music]
what the most realistic attack scenario
is probably that of cloud provider so if
there if multiple VMs on the same
machine and that that that's the most
realistic scenario I think that will
allow two different parties on the same
CPU at the same time what what should
happen in that case is that they should
all be scheduled the same CPU at the
same time and I think that is the most
realistic balance to strike do you think
that's a complete answer yeah disable it
if you don't care about performance that
much or try to do your scheduling right
so I guess does that answer your
question it's it's one of these things I
think that you have to choose between
sharing performance or not sharing for
security and it depends on situation all
right thank you very much we talked and
we'll have a short break because we need
to set up the chairs for the panel so
you can sit here or breathe thank you
for questions please come to us sorry
yeah yeah thanks
[Applause]