see me remember to turn your wireless
card in back there before you go if you
have not already done so Cisco there is
the first of about 450 thank you the
cisco you guys have been wonderful thank
you for loaning cards and some of the
cars all from Europe times hit
you back there yeah haha time is this um
he's calm cool and collected we were
very fortunate to have enviarme all the
time you lead the fabulous see he's an
unusual you just put the great person
Duncan was of the person we communicated
his Beckett merits mostly preparing for
the meeting because Duncan had the
dubious pleasure of setting up our
router connection here at the hotel and
he just worked a lot for a long time
some of that was taken over by Phil
Harris asking the very end of the
process Leslie sort of the overseer she
provided incredible not support not only
to the cisco people but to Carol and
myself these other people were mainly
slaving throughout the night to put up a
network Elliot Karen Michael Phil
Brandon thank you go and John were
aboard also here waiting overnight John
helplessness and multicast support and I
just can't thank you enough
now was debating whose idea this was
from print I in my opinion it was three
people who thought of providing our ds3
and who did it Keeks Ted and Peter thank
you so much Greg and Jeff were involved
at the end of the process in getting it
installed big liar helps throughout the
entire process and I also want to give a
special thank you to Dave I don't know
where you are but for incredible levels
of support during the past few months to
me and planning a program I really
appreciate it our multitask guys are
packing up but they are still back there
here save because he works with them
luthien hon I'm not even sure if you're
here but they had to leave but it is
wonderful to have your support you can't
find anyone who does multitask better
than you
the Rings not only handled our food
cache this time but I'll say a lot of
other networking issues thank you rain I
could clap right into the mic that would
really decided that
redback provided our continental
breakfast shift today thank you very
much for that what clothes via 5 and so
on down and then say more people Carol
what word carries about eighty percent
of our meeting on her shoulders a lot of
you worked with her one-on-one before
the meetings Carol handles everything
having to do with the hotel she decides
what rooms were going to use and when
she decide what we're going to eat with
all our vendors to make sure that
sponsorships and they're in here go
feelings Carol and gone Thank You Betty
the running for the dog pictures study
is our infrastructure manager back at me
Garrett and she handle merits role in
building a hotel network helping me
Betty out today we're Jeff and Chris and
enjoy yer as always back at home
providing supports I want to thank all
of them so much days and fell are here
from the mission at engineering group
providing network support Bob Phil vol
working background for the past few
months helping us out Jason is our real
audios are he was unable to be with us
for the last feeding Scottsdale and JC
it's great to have you back jason is a
real pro thank you our next job is to
tear down the room you would like to get
to know us better please stay and help
otherwise we'll ask you to leave fairly
quickly and now right
yeah thanks the tear marks is done a
fair amount of extra work and providing
some subsidies we will be in Miami in
February help