okay well I I'll keep this kind of sweet
because I know I'm the one that's
getting in the way between your break so
this discussion is actually about
hierarchal services through a land back
though on a packet backbone which I call
a network service provider and what this
enables is why I talk about Ethernet
man's it doesn't necessarily have to be
an Ethernet it's for any upstream to
downstream kind of service where the
upstream provides a hierarchal kind of
scheme of mpls services to the
downstream end which allows the
downstream than to use that upstream for
both transit services as well as
hierarchal and fill up services and I
make the relationship to eat the demands
because biggest problem we have right
now in the ethernet in man's special
Ethernet is this ability to use a
backbone so I'll define so the problem
we got in in Ethernet services or
downstream is trying to get to multiple
cities is basically how you deliver
economical services between cities and
so the first problem you get is do you
operate your own land network global
network whatever you call any metro
network and try to make all I'd operate
and being a green feel that you've much
more tougher and so that's really
complex and costly the other alternative
there is to just go by traditional
private line services like lambdas ATM
sonnet and that is a possibility that
the problem is that there's still a lot
of complexity involved it's an overlay
model and as you'll see the problem with
any of the traditional telecom services
its distance sensitive so if I want to
operate and drop off cities all over
North America and then finding Europe
and Asia it's going to cost me a lot to
deploy this on any traditional telco
circuit so the next kind of thing you
want to do is you want look at this or
say well what can I do well the first
thing is that the IP backbone they're
great because their distance insensitive
so the first thing is if I can get an IP
fabric to do
the lots of capacity and gives me a good
kind of quality of service or service
and its distance insensitive i'm only
paying for the price of how i plug into
that backbone and use that backbone
which is kind of nice the other one is
if i can push the complexity of
operating a global land backbone to nsp
partners by using some schemes i'll talk
about it also reduces my cost of
operational costs also to to do this we
want to make sure that whatever services
we do within the city looks the same to
other cities and there's no real
restrictions of going within the city or
across the city and the last thing is we
won't make sure we can deliver some SLA
is between within the city to other
cities using the nsp backbone and long
lectures there's some certain SLA
characteristics that the service looks
the same whether it's in the city or
across two different cities so the first
question is we could certainly use an IP
backbone and use for example various
coloring techniques ipsec GRE also a
martini kind of tunnel we can also use a
3ds l2vpn kind of a solution and that
certainly will work which means we get
the access to the IP backbone and we get
VPNs on it but the problem we get then
is there's an operational costs that's
the old lens for a problem right now i
have three cities i bring in the fort
city and i have to provision the border
routers and every one of those i tell a
man's or ethernet man's like I prevents
provision them with Louis Freeh kind of
topology information so what happens is
I'm still running a virtual backbone and
so what I'm presenting in there is the
ability of doing something similar like
an get use the packet backbone but do it
through appearing model just like 2547
so what I'm really presenting is
appearing model 2547 kerikeri extensions
but I'm going to trick you late this
little better than section 9 of the drop
so in the other Lane model you can see
you get an 80
kind of problem of meshes that I have to
or the operators up this man has to kind
of worried about it every border which
is an issue when you're out when you run
from the 39 city and go to the 50th so
what we try to do is the peering model
2547 or vpr ends where it offers is
ability to do this disappearing concept
where the network the extreme networks
looks like a big gigantic router so in
this case we have three cities and
everything the port city the nsp just
kind of advertises that port city and
all the other cities get access to that
and that needs to be coming online and
there's no configuration changes so this
is very powerful that as I roll out new
cities and use the up streams backbone
it looks as an extension to my service
extension to my services and I don't
have to go modify any of these these
where the routers are between the demand
provider the downstream and upstream and
as other thing you can look at in the
presentation is that the LSP is going to
these lands I really managed and
operated by the upstream they're
actually as the city comes on why it
actually just shows up with all the
other cities as you can see it's not
something that the man provider has to
provision on Oliver's border routers so
how do we do this is the question so
what we get is this kind of model where
everything is just you know opaque to
the to the to the man provider and it
just superior relationship so the first
part is in the peering model what we get
is we get an MSP that runs his
traditional network as a packet based
network probably right you know learning
mpls and he offers this inner-city man
service or a downstream highly ethical
kind of service and then at every on
every city what I call the man running
man 2 we have a function of a border
router of a boundary router that's
purely with CPEs in the nsp also what's
really important as demands manual and
2i rental nigp but they're on the same
tana me so what the mall looks like is
this is that you get in the blue is the
nsp the blue LSP has its own traffic
engineer links which is the the bottom
blue kind of trap OMG LSP the LSP tlls p
then the next one above that is what we
call the inter CD LSP now this LSP is
really operated by the nsp and it's
delivered out to every city in the VPN
off this man provider so in this case
let's say Terry was a man provider and
we have city one and see two men one and
two the nsps responsibilities as I bring
up cities to deploy and deliver that
that intercity LSP to all the other
cities in automated fashion this means i
don't have a provision anything and
everything is automated and this is
highly important since because at the
alt functions i have all my phones going
to that for my transit services all my
other city in tricity traffic that any
operator mistakes can be devastating so
there's an operational issue on when I
can do this if I didn't have this kind
of model now once we like somehow we
automate this function where this
intercity LSP they FA like kinda LSP is
done then the land provider or
downstream can have free access to put
as many LSPs as you wants to put on it
or send IP traffic on it so what we get
now is the effects of a VPN and a
transit kind of service peering kind of
service for red traditional IP are in
the same interface and it's hierarchical
nature and the really important thing is
that second LSP there you call inner
city LSP SF they like it actually forms
the adjacency between c1 and c2 not at
p1 and p2 and that's very important
because all state information and all
adjacent seats for ldp mlsp state
information is not on the PE providers
box which means he can support you know
hundreds and thousands of down streams
and not having comes with scaling issues
so when I presented this presentation
about in July to the Metro Ethernet
forum i also had yak off work with me on
this and he helped me refine this and we
can
up with this idea of exactly how to do
this so one of the things I get to the
exact of details how to do this we also
important is to get the cost of service
mappings from all the higher service
LSPs down all the way through the inner
city LSP and also to the traffic
engineer LSP so that maintains the class
of service and we all know do this just
exp marketing's and toss them down so
the proposal is to join RFC 2547 this
which was well defined on a carrier to
enterprise relationship and very loosely
defined on how to do carry two carrier
relationships and I think 2547 is a
great model is for exactly this 24-carat
a carrier and the reason is the routing
tables from an enterprise you know
they're not what I call aggregated and
any kind of admission of any routes we
pointed back to the nsp to figure out
you know what's going on which means the
horrendous operational issue on a
carrier to carrier model the downstream
is really highly aggregated routes so it
fits in really well so what I'm
proposing yours you take RSC 3107 which
is bgp mpls and you mix it with 2547 you
get exactly what i just described above
so how it works is like this and I'll go
into actual details and again you have
the nsp in blue and the man providers in
yellow and that represents two different
cities so the first thing that happens
is you get is that the nsp would
probably create a traffic and engineered
link between p1 and p2 and this is very
important that easy does it through lvp
or RSVP he have to create a traffic
engineer link or some kind of tunnel or
between p1 and p2 part of the 2547
bispak and that allows a reach ability
from my GP point of view between p1 p2
so i won't get into that that's in this
back so basically the nsp just deployed
2547 on this network in the middle of
his network and the next thing that
happens after you created the adjacent
using the p1 and p2 the ce-1 asbr
announces prefix one so in this case a s
man one announces prefix one but instead
of
in just prefix one bgp he also announces
an MPLS label now instead of running
just giving any label you can use an
implicit label and put the no label and
that implicit no label then gets mapped
to with the prefix the p1 takes the the
prefix and the label and he attends to
it a route roughs distinguisher so that
it's now recognized as a VPN ipv4 route
and he assigns a route target which
gives it the vpm membership and the bgp
next hop becomes pu.1 and the label l
will no label is now assigned label l
which is used for egress targeted for it
on the way back which will see that
thing gets announced all the way through
his network all those other networks and
finally gets the PE to where City and
number two is and what happens then is
p2 announces that reachability
information to see e2 and says man a SB
ras one has come up prefix one and i'm
announcing it to see two and i'm going
to assign in this case label k because
it got swapped it's part of the function
so L got swapped ok and this time the
bgp next hop is p2 so when this is done
what you now get is the blue on the top
you've got an LSP that has been formed
that's being created by this interaction
of bgp mpls and 2547 and what this
happens now is you've got control
information flowing between the man
provider and appearing model to the
upstream back to a man provider and you
get a hierarchy on the top flow and then
you can put anything into this and what
happens is when you put like regular IP
traffic it into it you pop you push in
regular IP pushing label ke ke gets now
treemap 2l @ p you want a te too Elvin
looks and says okay I got it got a p1
from my beach p next top resolve to igp
push on label swap I just can't leave
swap gets the p1 p1 pops it again I pops
que el sorry and then finally he looks
the packet and there's an old label
packet and he pops it out to see one and
the packet flows so you just had a
regular IP packet for an LSP to go
across this is a cross between man 1 and
2 and LSP like an RSVP would be stand
for example a path message and this what
happens is it's very important that the
past message the the hop object gets
pushed with the IP address of ce2 as the
input of the tunnel so what has to
happen is this hierarchical LSP has to
behave like an fa like Ford adjacency
like characteristics it has to make sure
that the key hops is set correctly for
our SB to work and this could be used
for LD PRS routine what happens
eventually is you get an inverted tree
happening from all the multi points to
the point and the data flow that the
direction of the data flow which means
that you can pass hierarchal services or
just IP services over it and if you then
do it bidirectionally you get this kind
of multi-point to root a tree so you get
c 1 c 3 2 c 2 and so on and you and then
what you get is an inverted tree that's
bi-directional nature and it will
deliver you hierarchal services so the
issues involved is how do you get this
class of service model which I talked
about to give you n to n signaling for a
clap for call emission controls to get a
hard qsr model and to date no one to
speak and deliver a jitter service or
guarantees and jitters so these are the
two issues that still need to be worked
on this proposal is being submitted into
the IETF the next month for myself yeah
cough and it probably nine or ten other
authors which is still getting kind of
finalized so I hope they've really got
that's kind of a little complicated and
confusing but angles any questions
okay thanks