money was like two seasons in Miami on
Twitter I just one thing
so
security and you might expect but it's
not like to see it work
meanwhile energy demand for skills
training place increases and page is
pulling on down so we probably have it I
T generally Nations Security which is
great job is no coincidence no breach is
a little bit
getting something through the increase
training training done that means I'm
going to lose time everything else done
work for a while and we gotta think the
trading very very carefully to make sure
that we train more
engagement is really do this and we
don't have the engagement you probably
turn to that person that asked for
solution because you have the other half
but you can't get someone else to have
any interest to start thinking about it
you're not going to tell her how the
solution so we have to think about how
to drive engagement up to management to
our peers that's how we solve the
problem of not getting inside some of
the people we have to keep offering the
insides hurt to try to figure out a way
to take it did he understand the idea to
do we offered up a way that was
interesting to the audience because
communication applications not about
what happened on your side's what
happens on
side so how do we get that engagement so
these are all kind of the front and
adjust their standards huge pile of
stuff I'm doing and we're still stuck in
trying to solve your problem
second part of the problem there are
tremendous demands that kinda go with
the workload problem that kind of go
with the understanding that the little
different aspects I think of this is is
kind of something to keep turning
looking different sides of the ROI
analysis project
point of this what do you want me here
anytime or something tangible way to
return on investment analysis you don't
get asked this last person to do this
analysis framework if they don't have a
clear framework of the houses and you
ask them to go with you to financial
worries gonna do look at it and ask them
well as trying something that makes it
rather than building it yourself there
are cases where buildings kill you and
this is one of those things where you
get the idea from somewhere else
by the way if you can get the framework
that's a faster way to go because
apparently works decompile it but my
admission into it and hopefully they'll
get the job done as we do that we're now
having to turn to speak the language of
the business
when asked how can I be held in this
world doing the relevant business I have
had many conversations very very bright
people I come I still this conversation
we're trying to express how very
important thing is that need to be done
I was working on and he turns it will
ultimately the business + chickens
packages themselves well if you cannot
figure out what you're doing is relevant
to the business all figured that out
it's far too easy to turn that to really
great stuff into a hole that you become
less and less relevant and then the gap
between you and the people are asking
rose to shrink that you're on your own a
red team you doing interesting
very creative taxing you're coming up
with all sorts of polls they haven't
solved this but if you have not figured
out a way to talk to the blue team size
and meet you are so they can start
figuring out how to close that you read
TV is loud noise in this is no
disrespect to read to you it's good to
see you done it hard work it's drudgery
no less so than a lot of tasks you gotta
write reports and no one cares but if we
do how to make it relevant on the other
side people start to care
start to ask questions in the
conversation codes so why this team
found both of us
get some new tools new processes
around to trade that too low point was I
don't have time to learn this stuff and
the question is can you trade out this
new tool if there's something that's
going to be capable can we put that
cheesy decommission something else to
reduce the complexity of what we have to
deal with so that we can vote is here
and not continue to sputter cells like
butter toast so think about can we trade
rather than an event rather than just
keep piling on more sweet wish things
out we're ready to walk out
so this is these problems walked into a
third set of problems my beliefs about
their solutions here how we handle
business culture
every place I've gone to a founding
cultures either supporting or destroyed
success
really really careful what I do think
about what I just meant that I want to
do your that's gonna give security game
without undermining some other pieces
actually changed because he was positive
and everywhere I've gone to different
people
the Arthouse kind of it yeah we want to
just sometimes highly protected is so I
i mean a good touch culture but I think
about how
how we think about security in the
company matters and then concerns
whether we get in the way of their
support making changes how they get in
the way our support talking talking up
and change often do it can you just how
casual conversation to try 2008 allowed
to go talk across the whole how do you
go do that some companies it's really
easy to do
place talk to somebody one of the best
things I was just like the type of the
marketing department like they're going
to you and to think they are realizing
they're so good making pretty pictures
and i really come to like the marketing
department once I have no idea what I
want to do and strangely enough they
have a lot of influence public relations
and public relations has a certain
amount of power because public relations
double right story I'll talk about it
these people can't talk about it
ok so I've got friends of marketing and
public relations actually meet friends
of my compliance officer had great
conversations my way around and people
are raising issues to go so well have
the message by the time I actually get
to running my message to the message as
I said the culture counts people are
ready to help you on it so here I am sad
and kinda transitioning to the right and
if you if you've been there you've
experienced this we're about the time
working
we have to start learning because our
company like Apple esta so you really
like this
yeah okay so what are the three years of
12 capitalize it I don't care
ok years enterprise about 25
live with this for three years I
personally buy something to a new tool
capability to take about a year to
integrate it really living with it and I
don't like this can take your find
something else turns out that's the
issue
other companies don't like to capitalize
anything so don't kill them with three
year deal to save money investors
returned to me and talk business at
least understand your company approaches
it because it matters whether you buy a
three-year by Erwin whatever they want
to do that matters to them how they want
to structure finances supposed to be the
right color technology keeps changing
faster if you're not going to do
something is fairly complex learning
other partners is relevant in states
fast and other issues efficiency
don't mix of the two that this is how
good it is to do it may or may not be
the most efficient sometimes you make
the trade with the perception of the
world doesn't matter how valuable it
really is on the inside here's where do
we use in terms of people understand why
do we talk
financial limits to recognize those Dec
training opportunities music down time
planning its into something good will be
thrown out over and over again if i dont
prep people to receive the change
changes and you try to bring a really
good idea back up again this time no
doubt on the investment side if you are
asked to budget for something even if
you're not getting ready to do something
that is bringing in the new to buy
something today to meet its support to
those costs upfront usually they will
get accepted it the whole idea is worth
a shot by the way we will have to maybe
try next year they can add to the cost
and then finally believe it or not there
is internal competition also to
resources not just money but I'm
share gaining Europe top leadership
around something that is very long to
conversation and how long you've been
some of you may remember
still going on but large conference the
whole focus was always bittersweet calm
and they had a large interoperability
know there's an and it would be good
operate across the network stuff work
together most of just watching it very
easily today it's not that hard to get
things to do just that we're doing a lot
of connections but the base still going
on but the a probability is huge
just like an address the problem of
getting systems together the idea that I
want are putting forth is people how to
work together so it may look like this
and you can either call a problem but
the message that work or want to create
a lot more done if we work with others
their deadly 17 work going on this
picture so I also recognize the people
who aren't here on if we get everybody
to start working together
actually
or something
and few more years its program I'm gonna
take that approach 2012 warning warnings
and threats she talked about the to get
too well
10 bucks for a USB stick right now and
dropping the USB stick but I do have an
appt
yeah they cost yes I got that at the
technology to aid in the more recent
versions of their software anyway my
budget process equipment wasn't working
was but that wasn't trying to not sale
until I have to but yeah the
conversations
I just tried so in love with Heidi
responsibilities seventeen years ago it
was a great deal of time right now we're
going to get this going but warnings and
then go from there
just mentioned which is talking about
risks says thanks thing is
and more I think the messaging
is challenging because they talk about
things that such an abstract level
people talking in general means there
may be other conversations happening
around the company if you can't get the
concern you have about security Street
it but you can talk to other people
solutions are happening out there with
some of the things I have to be fixed
and other people start talking about
their chains someone talks about the
revenue side of the business about a
problem because it talk to you about it
he said we know there are solutions for
this gives them some ideas on his side
can usually get what they want as their
revenue so maybe that idea start to talk
with people because its topical now
around you get support for something
otherwise
this is what it is going to cost you
spend one week
hours you know people from each
department for X amount of dollars and
have one person commented this is what
we need from you to do to secure your
section and this is why and if you've
got an ROI says you'll spend this much
to train these people on a basic
security procedures and this is what
it's going to cost you a potential loss
and they've got that to look at just in
very very simplistic terms without any
big words or any long explanations
what are the things that are you talking
about potential loss what are the
potential losses in the business that we
talked about the rotational communities
on your business because no matter how
your business is everybody in the
community lives in you as a risk of rage
you know everybody's phone numbers go
out and I've got an 85 phone calls from
the telemarketer even something as
simple as that is going to go here
other over here to spend so startling
that reputation costs of the impact
could be less lower revenue couldn't be
more phone calls into your support line
saying what are you doing about this is
something that has happened with the
cost of that
lawsuits you know the interesting thing
about lawsuits that I've been trying out
as I keep looking at that they are
typically win the lawsuit settlement is
really expensive it's a lot less than
losing a lawsuit
find something relevant to your industry
is asking what is it costing to avoid
the loss of their numbers to put up
behind the arc and then try to figure
out if we have this conversation about
four hours a week for the organization
ok we can probably get to meet the cost
of that and we're gonna do so solution
that's that's a good idea i think is
rebuilding and rol
suggestion is launched and provide lunch
so make sure you have lunch in that cost
way time that they would be doing their
jobs you would have to include that
expensive your education program is
going to be pretty much no its not get
people engaged did you give them repeat
25 questions
so
there
love your suggestions and input in
conversation not how I get better
building bridges I just think it's
critical and just as much as compassion
about security we gonna meet their
passion realizes we thank you very much