wife is Gary Beck don't trust her that's
all you gotta watch out for more than 12
suits you all know that and suspend
yes I know who buys this is psychology
that's been studied a lot of people and
I have several videos to show you to
find some of the points that will be
talked about now a lot of times people
look at me go what the psychology have
to do with computers well everything
because we still have humans connected
to the computer for the time being
yes last week and so the problem is we
are the proud of what we've been looking
at places so I'm also so I think it's ok
it's what we do
also have about nine classified labs are
mine
company and so heavily involved
classified world I won't be giving you
that this way with counterintelligence
don't wanna know not what you say you
don't want to know so what we gonna do
this your brain is how your brain works
what does tricks does this helps us
making this all the hacker size you want
to know what those mistakes
the defensive side is really need to
know so that when you're developing
security you know how to correct and how
do procedures and protocols to help in
this situation so my question is does
your brain lied to you does it feel to
reality a hundred different way
implies failure that vaccinations or
something because you're doing ok we'll
talk about that little bit of research
to support she ate you will know or
everybody on this room who have facts
and statistics to prove that you're
wrong you won't believe so ingrained
into
volunteer one moment here to watch the
screen ok ok not the world
when the polls
six times for three times to times when
he tried this with human subjects Jason
averaged 12 times three times for 5-6
times a year on average about 325 people
give you reason why don't you completely
different team when you eat five times
more times three times when you have to
do a problem quickly you don't really
high
you through the first members you
multiply it by six and be like ed 2000
or so we need 1-2 times recently 600 or
so the first thing he asked me well we
should just not just need to be really
strong in the first problem even bigger
number from here just a different artist
to be harnessed to get with her
husband's phone numbers from 100
countries in the united nations
number was about 25 percent but he did
people bring out the last two digits he
wouldn't have $20 per 91 people in the
highest quintile
with so much for being willing to spend
$27 each particular reading how much
food prices are too high and then you
might expect
directions to people carry and/or
bounced between them and the first
experiment is replaced by someone else
talking to a different person was
replaced by someone else I know that's
how you get away with ricky is still a
friend of mine
so
what do you think that's perfectly fine
same thing happens in security you see
before they tried working right now and
dad coming days
medium-sized
we choose what we think will give us the
greatest emphasis but what movies they
seem trivial external contextual factors
to demonstrate one such factor we're
analyzing experiment were invited to
participate in the short to experiment
on decision making it to the carnival
style with a ball throwing desk
volunteers had to try it through a
jungle into a meter distance to the ice
them to participate we offer to children
to school
beholden to they couldn't find the store
was a dominant hand at 11 children or
thrown into your computers in economic
terms we presented our volunteers with a
choice between a low risk high risk high
reward but here's the twist we randomly
divided into two groups presented with a
low risk no reward options
high-risk high-reward destruction the
short field that participants before
entering this royal once the
participants had to become of wall with
their dominant
to take their toll
they were given the final trip D with
whatever the default option Wallace or
switch to these people would make their
decision based purely on risk and reward
or wavy options were presented were
framed would have a legacy
decided which is based purely on trade
off between risk and reward we would
expect that the honeymooners low-risk
auctions will be chosen 191 people
participated to talk 98 people walked in
with the ball in their dominance and did
not choose to switch
93 people who want to do with the ball
in there and the majority 62%
did not switch so what happened with
whatever the default this is known as
the status quo he said he'll take the
current position and you decide to throw
in their own internal no deterrent
instead they decided whether to give up
unity change from comida psychology
about people seeing losses and gains
different potential loss associated with
the default position was perceived as
greater than the potential gains tax and
insurance providers to their choices are
presented to people including the
options which are more decisions people
make a real world example bias is home
auctions concerning organ donation organ
donors presented as the default
influences
in social psychology
the car
happens many different situations in the
workplace relationships and even with
the shop
researchers and helps protect their
self-esteem
motions we can't control their role in
the evening use it to protect others
like we say it wasn't your fault there's
nothing you could have done have a great
impact on my life because we learn from
our mistakes and he just something for
years without getting there
she had asked me harder for you
so here are some point you started by
inserting yourself and notice when
you're doing it
to imagine how you know what happens if
you lose
the problems too much trying to solve
them when we dwell on the past our mind
excuses which starts to self-serving
bias
everybody but only the people who
understand