good to see ya oh alright I'm into you
grab at seventeen years I want to talk
about education in our program recently
was brought it to a washington D C to go
to the white house we actually want
number one in the world
target MIT
innovation system in 2011 were named
Computerworld laurette and occasional
school they came about two years ago
most kids go there and it's kind of
funny because the average kid that lives
there between 17 and $25 an hour nice
pretty good kids that are 19 to 21 years
of age
brilliant way to see a big into soccer
today justice works it works
don't just winging good
let me ask you guys were waiting how
many of you guys we can see here sale
and I want you to be honest no be
embarrassed by what other people would
you think that your computer is in your
own way in your own way and and here's
the kicker you got a black or a lot of
the other places that I and no one ever
considers herself an expert because
their computers are so diverse today
that you've got everything that's out
there so as an educator in 1999 when it
first started at the school they were
saying you know what to make computers I
love when is it was very very basis and
then if you go to the progression that
we've had over the last fifteen years
the biggest thing is now how do you
teach computers while the biggest thing
is a lot of him say good for your degree
how did you guys have a computer sized
okay and you know when you look at
degrees today what you're actually
looking at how much I trained myself and
how much they trained me and micro dirty
jobs actually were staying which case
I'm not here tonight universities and
community colleges what's happening in
technology day is when you're not seen
the value behind I T people in what they
want on their own
talk about the programming languages
that are out there you say it's ok I'm
going with
go back go to off just a backup moved it
over the years is our school to you
right way now our universities and
community colleges teaching right way
they are not so many more like MIT
Caltech got before him was from Georgia
Tech and I think dirty a better way to
learn computer science and explain their
homework computer history is an
important you know whenever you walk in
computer science class they start
talking about computer history and what
happened in 1960 1970 1980 and the next
thing you know you like your history
class are you can wait for some laughs
and hands-on most people are gonna be
hands on mars anyway so what do we need
to teach we need to focus on lecture
what's happening in an industry where we
need to be produced system
administrators programmers database post
09 yours and we need to focus on
hands-on I'm going to do about it
regions when I'm talking to my balls in
his place in those photos you know I
went to him and i said i want the
freshmen students to be familiar with
the same reason I want this to take
place as the senior students can educate
and when they do this it's going to
produce a round robin effect where they
see everything to me three times now you
know about Middle Tennessee State
University in this is all going to tie
you gonna make sense in just a minute I
went over to MTSU we didn't cash why do
we did it with the Department of
Homeland Security and when we did this
all these folks will come in handy and I
was going around us talking to people
that I was asking where you go to school
what do you do realize what people say
it's easy canceled
you know and I've been doing this for
twenty years whatever what we had
actually set up a bar bilities we're
sharing else works alone had no
passwords we had makes machines that
were sent over to the side of the head
and then we have some more hardened
servers that went with that and we
actually have flags needs one of you
guys
anybody here ok result in what I got
twins when I was younger because it's
all walked and I was waiting to hear
people say you know this is not a big
deal during the capture the flag and
you'll see the switches in the servers
in a way but the guys that had long time
of course I would connect to the network
and they started bringing this would
happen is of course it does it continue
so immediately you have people that
started with they minimize those windows
so the next thing you know if they open
up another terminal when they start to
see if they have connect to you might
start paying us which is being serviced
trying to see you look down there and
one guy literally has helped you like
but what he did was he started sixth
article bit servers and what to partner
with your IP address and when he started
playing it over and over again
IP addresses and he was dogs attacking
his body had asked I got next losing
connectivity and he started working and
then I got a hundred people with big
windows open they're just one another
and i'm looking at all what's going down
there are costs and their sales they
could walk past words once we arrange
that I want to have one of the people I
work with it does work for the Homeland
Security says I hope that will be ok
this sort of the bands for twenty three
core that simple
the server's name is this the flag is
under this folder so we had actually ok
USB Drive and it will educate and copied
off their you could have a flag true
stored true story anyway
there is my Cali Linux the YouTube
whenever they were this is what's
happening with education today I think
we actually want more from one another
and I'm just being sincere but I'm gonna
tell you how we have structured they
were right in just a minute
nobody even scare the network into a
total scam the network you may be able
to minors and then we were actually over
them with the tools anyway nobody even
used very same place to really going at
least I'm some anyway this is how we're
set up for hours waiting when you walk
into this game it's important to two
hours a day like I give you a break we
like sure you get to know the hours a
week and your help we talked to the all
the senior guys reopen the junior guys
and then as a senior guys great way they
get jobs in those guys become senior
guys they're helping each other so they
do this stuff over and over again they
have two hours of homework study time
and they have projects to the community
you know we've
reaction which was i've the steak
volunteer work with United Way and
police departments and sheriff's
department and just whatever nonprofits
hours things out we would save your work
or just labs you're not going to work
with layers receiving letters that are
in the plan work and go to school
network you know we've got 20 notes
downer but we also need help with those
forty students and 12 note you also have
this thing called student body was
student body that enjoys laptops
netbooks have people coming and they
look like some kind of futuristic being
whenever they open up their back you
don't know what's going to Best Buy's
exploding anyway so they take about five
thousand different note our school and
as they as they do this I just believe
every college community college where
they need to have that he's 19 1903
science and English next thing is that
we're not teaching people's computers
fast enough you know what's going to
happen when you get your four year
degree what did you learn your first
year outdated technology technology
that's dated so what you're really horny
in your junior and senior year is really
what you gonna be doing are you hope to
be doing that said they had to work or
school students so they want customer
service phone now there are starting to
hurt when we go out to these large
universities and that say you know we
got twenty times this really happening
is back in the dorms are actually doing
anyway and they need a two hour or even
six hours away is just not enough way so
we took off and we started to really
because we're doing these labs and we're
doing everything and then we started
having employers if we leaving atlanta
and we know where they're coming out
saying I want to be when strolling
across but this moves over to the
workplace to name one place you know
what they want they want the new guy
amount of money which one year's
experience
the thing that we've lost his mentors
yes we go into a place because how busy
it is now with mobile devices the
complexity to switch the complexity of
cloud computing and and the servers
things that we have because most of us
are understaffed even when they say the
new guys review becomes dad when should
really be made until everything and
there's a new you know and their new you
gotta remember we're trying to get yours
ITV the new guys assigned to you are
trying to order twenty years experience
for forty grand you're not going to do
it and we also try to tell the people
working at heights he was being patient
with the guys you know or you're doing
or when you're speeding up that we need
to stop in train those people anyway but
the other thing that we need to do
moving into the security side of
everything is focused on security now we
need to expose students to hacking tools
now 70 years ago and went to my boss and
i said im like shark in the network use
let students do that
really going to make it back alright
network control network logo and the
reason being is Wireshark not only exam
date and protocols and those kind of
things like passwords and yes my bosses
you know this sounds like a good deal
missus about some focus and say whatever
you want to do so
the reason we need to teach you about
how to break
more fun but it also means in 20
students experience just like all
through things like radio this mess with
you and that to one another we do it but
they need software and they need to
understand about things a security but
then I mean just some of the tools
they're great break I'll try to keep
control in one day we've got them
something to do whatever we're teaching
them now and they sign the form they do
everything from blocked a break into a
car and you know that she's so many
things that we do you know our
organization needs to spray were always
there is a lack of her out there why
there's such a need for security
well we better start meet or she owes
colleges and universities I'm not
talking about and have a little like
this you don't come out
how to run something that those things
are good and it's great to hear from
experts live mix black you know things
that happened throughout the United
States but we better start teaching as a
formalized as a nation because we're
gonna lose America's infrastructure and
some gonna happen where we have a power
trip or we have a water system that
becomes contaminated or have something
in manufacturing and you know if you've
got to be resource center here over the
summer
already gone this system shows in
America we look at a place of
complacency
you know we can complain about people
violating our rights but we can go to
Facebook and we can wipe out there click
on every four hours known to mankind
right right you know we've reached the
point that we care about security we
hear about not really do anything as far
as education to really try and consumers
you know everybody in this crowd
probably you know you need each time you
connect to any type of wire that's open
warrants and as I walk around people are
just walking into the hotel while I'm
over at Starbucks and you know I see
people just walking around why are you
following we but anyway so we we should
all these different things we show
students how do you say ok very
different types of scanners but we don't
do it just windows because we even
though Windows runs
share or Linux Enterprise Center in your
marketplace job insecurity or networking
so you know what we need to expose our
students to do that with our new
employees their department they did I'm
staying group policies morning software
switches spectrum analyzers for wireless
they need to understand those very basic
tools such as far shorter times dozen
times and they say I can get your
password easy it is easier on them and
send them where you want them to go and
that our school but if you look at it
colors that you see around it and say
students can be produced from work what
we need to do that every school and we
need to start early where you know the
law enforcement or walk students going
to be using something like this tumblr
using GPS mapping out wireless so that
they can see where the isotropic
radiator is so that they can have
understanding security want wpa2 AES is
not good enough to make sure that you
got a RADIUS server their IDs and IPS
systems that are employees but we're not
doing that go through my college career
and you go through it he says
job so you commit an entire you know two
semesters or three credit hours of the
morning just job that's good and you got
a job at ASB I mean you can just go
through those like a million miles now
but you know Java we've been a teacher I
was gonna teach dynamic SQL databases of
colleges this how to make a database
this would take place
you know these are bills these are the
individual side of the field in this
marks on pace to you on this is my
through what do we go through this I
hate this isn't the SQL injection this
is what you take place in this is how
they is one you know are we going to our
people who write applications and it
would you know we usually take this much
on an application security in this much
so you know one of the things that we
did this is as good this season so we
haven't tried to go exactly did you get
it going
so of course you example is this simplex
this we make it here but you know we
just teach own because the kids growing
up into space and then you say hey this
is so perfect that works and we can scan
is not addressed many scary movies MAC
address and MAC addresses when you say
what was wrong what is almost over and
you'll see its K device this touchscreen
is using manufacturing seasoned
healthcare the whole nine yards so once
they see that they begin to learn it go
over two minutes in the car
breakaway you know I want
operation of people were each charged
listen to me not just in education
directors but also these lapses in your
organization with your small business or
whether a medium-sized businesses that
so when we look at the upstairs we go
over and we find out basically support
for Windows so when you see the kids are
remote desktop uniquely try to login
because they win over their resources
passwords are and then find out it fails
to teach them you know but you also
there to see things like when I see you
have a sparkly system so the newseum try
to tell me and when they try to tell me
into it will take place isn't going to
fail and they will be looking starting
to change your number you can tell me
the IP use wrist and of course this this
shows that way I swear they find out
that it is and research and just like
yours and you can find out where you can
tell how people who put things in
infrastructure they skip something every
manufacturing or even in a hostile
environment if they're not the correct
equipment that's gonna be damaged so I
mean you can't see that but of course
they they learn
and they're going to skate into my eyes
and there you see the director and then
immediately just kill all the services
listed this motor which one is best
lighting system can be shut off every
homes is not just the imaginative she'll
text but you know everybody usually sees
this and I say we just tryna windows
because you guys are a small college no
we don't know details do more versus the
Linux but we also do Mex because in the
enterprise you all there and this is an
example when are we going using Linux to
do the exact same thing and we had to
wait for the hashes in there so they can
get all the passwords and we tell them
you know rwanda has gas so that we can
find your permission and is it goes
through that you find all the different
all the different users are advised and
then of course we allowed them to go
through the entire upload malware
you know we tell them i can text file
which they do it
senior students we make sure that they
can do we teach the bad side that if
they know the bad side of the good side
of it we take them over to the good side
so they can start locking things down
and you know I was just basic examples
because it does cover infrastructure
manufacturing healthcare business and it
also covers themselves to protect our
own identity
you know the thing about learning today
is with social media we're adding these
extra things in my life has found their
plans to you know now I've got like five
thousand friends over which two of them
will help me move I really needed a
friend right and so when we're teaching
students they gained 20 45 minutes to 1
hour lecture just behind there and then
they have a twenty-minute take home and
cuddle software back in my day we did
the whole hello world and we were so
happy to see if my whole world and it
was a programming language so primitive
today it's just unreal
back up in
I'm in with much of what we were doing
we are people that were very patient
there were so many of you guys actually
had to run against ok now you working
out what I'm going to do is keep the
blockage there I used to working in his
new skills used two men to wear them to
show them into be patient I how many
guys have been to a seminar in when you
get to the sooner you think I don't
waste money doing this I had more fun at
the last night right you can actually be
patient he trained people skills and
trying the UN Security as you do that
don't be intimidated today's world
recession in the way the job market is
what have you like I was saying earlier
micro dirty jobs education there's 3.2
million jobs are available today
we don't have the skills that can do it
so whenever trade in these folks going
to seminars make sure similar to provide
you with a chance to make sure that when
you do trading make sure you have that
soft fluffy stuff that you have to do
every year from sexual rest made to
avoiding phishing emails being safe on
the internet that kind of thing for the
office people but when you do trading
for your organization don't be scared
because most people are afraid to try
and people because they fear for their
jobs that's my one of you to join them
too much does this dog gone but what we
need to do is we do that because she saw
the people are standing up here now that
it to people because of complacency lack
of security
you know we had a retailer who actually
left your HVAC units or SCADA system
with Nepal passwords we've had a
retailer system that through wireless on
Friday afternoon that left it open
security network cases every case after
case education isn't just about how
colleges should begin to trying
education is also in the workplace and
of course with colleges or universities
if they don't train or excuse me they
don't change their methods of training
reorganize his skills gap in companies
are there are and you know I have my
students all the time ago what
programming languages do you know
they're going to start for trainer coble
and there's a really weird and I still
want to go out and get some small way
Ruby on Rails PhD and and then they'll
say hey teach me whatever and I'll take
the time to do that and if you want can
I see you guys if you're not a night see
you guys may come from businesses or you
may be associated with security and you
want to know a little bit about what's
happening it making you go around and
you see these kids next door to see
drones and lock picking him and all his
stuff
social media we need to teach people how
to analytically without remembering I
mean I don't know to do so happy
but training starts with ends in with
security you got what we are reasonably
decided that we would do is we reach
viruses into the network not our school
networks
loaded into control network and you
would think why are you introducing
viruses into the network now imagine
going to a four year university going to
get over a network and taking back what
do you think there was no school to make
a purchase requisition and going to
start over
you know that it works in your life when
you don't need it to other banks and
technology and it's going faster and
faster we had to turn out students like
I said that's one week and here's what
we tell our recruiters whenever they
call when they put those skills among
the resonators they've done their hands
and they are doing in control not just a
minute really really big when I simply
big you're talking about really big
school before school lab R you got over
200 computers with remains what we
introduce so they can go in and destroy
stuff so they can fix though so that you
know how to protect your right and when
these workers call we have to show or
tell me that they do not have a debate
and what i read your specialty is there
actually actually asked asked bones
you work with her ask yourself do I know
how to protect
got social networking the Brocade
switches range do you know how to
protect not just give up their whatever
do you know how do you know how to
predict that it's better to change the
way that we're thinking about education
and that's in the workplace and we
talked about security in the workplace
we better be changing the higher
education anyway guys that's all I've
got my job sounds like I'm feeling when
you go out
workplace help those in need and don't
expect the new guy have twenty to thirty
years experience