thanks for coming I'm Rick Sanders with
a little bopper my story in your
national and loving you
property you're in town but we made a
decision not to do not consciously do
any entertainment reviews of all my
server racks and so i i technology
clients 2011
run into and we are
marketers I was here I was invited two
years ago
2009 a great time
and was very questions and i got two
slides into my presentation we can start
talking just fine I know what he's done
by software answer questions during
answers to the questions which have
answers I don't listen and to accept
that there are likely sprained what the
issues are looking for a modern be cases
every day I get an email blast every day
and I'm always looking to copyright
questions so you know and ask questions
that's fine I didn't quite know how to
teach this when I was here last time
people are about how it works and
doesn't work with software so I do have
some introductory stuff just kinda
to wear software
intellectual property law and then more
about copyright that's the main thing
only thing for software and then we can
talk about the technology they meet
clients with it if I feel like I'm just
going every step you just start skipping
through about that software and IP
scheme very well
Congress
knew about software and some of the
problems that it would create back in
1978 this is very carefully and slowly
and seem to want to crash and the actual
content committee talked about software
recommendations bhosle accepted by
congress and software
used and and and and
and
first businesses and basically is a sign
that people like Bill Gates software
engineer a great businessman was going
to die
everybody can code whatever is going to
claim that becomes kind of a black box
and now I gotta tell you this is now in
case work
Alice has questioned the lot of the
patent software patents based on just
subject matter doesn't actually do
something that's an invention is in
retreat now but for what they're talking
to you guys
was it was really easy way to text
software but has a payment money and
about priorities and enforcing penalties
are just expensive you know if you're
starting a business is a great thing
because a lot of investors insist or
even a provisional patent application is
better than nothing but it's a start
it's like you know patent is a kind of
catch 22
it's a copy right in order to make
coffee you have to be awake but you were
not awake until you make the coffee
right you know you need money
application but nobody will give you
money until you have a pass just talked
about in detail trade secrets to the
extent you keep your processes
you keep your source code then it's it's
it's a secret that has a value that you
take reasonable steps to secret but it's
almost impossible software is open
source and that kind of it tends to
undercut secrecy investors never ever
ever there they believe that every time
every NBA is is is is just a track they
just fall into those are the copyright
his closest my striking a little bit
strange because of copyright is there to
protect not functions not idea is there
to protect
expression no expression for easy way we
understand novels movies talk about this
little bar or what is what is expressed
it was protected with the word we use
the original
has to be something that has some kind
of creative choices that comes out he
doesn't come up with the separate but so
far just has to come out of your head
has to have some creative choices so
even boring things can be doctors office
in UC campuses
protect the expression that if you were
to photocopy them but you would ya
yes yes I just signed a lot of people
you want to sign them are the ones he's
willing to just just a huge risk you
place your time your pitch into to
investors and there's like to see how
much do I show these people helped me so
much
we don't have any any any black magic
and adventure bit
right now
is keeping it secret keep your product
and and I think about doing anything
that I can hear my heart forever
free album did something somethings in a
public competition would not be able to
reverse engineer with him take them
longer than the Lifebook engineer or
more of us right I'm not sure until the
day they remind me of the flaming are
cool because they can't protect things
you can fax your fax to protect and
there's some stuff come upon a trade
secret but it still be legally protected
you know I am actually
structure
ok
of abstraction and
obviously
going to have burden of proof to show
that sensation similar at that point it
becomes the defense I'm yours forever
and there is such a thing as striking
similarity word-for-word it's like the
way you could have come up with us
so hard case where advertising
advertising agency hired so 3d render
but because the computer doesn't quite
render certain regions are introduced by
a straight scan in two or three weeks
even so even so hard work in the in the
equipment and a human being involved
help no copyright protection because
they all they had done replicated
something in the same idea here
backs in nature or not
take another couple examples
illustrations I guess is kind of protect
the ball this is I don't know very well
of it matter what the whole manual
itself has become the latest one
individual section in its own right but
not the well yes so we can say that's
actually comes a question because what
we're looking for is very important and
highly creative need less of it to
friends or less expressive might have to
call me a lot more
oil but also we do some filtering we
will filter out stuff and forced to get
to this way the structured might be
copyright information there in there in
there this is important for the Oracle
get to know the individual public domain
but election because you're exactly
right choice arrangement is a greater
choice is copyrightable then is the
waves were new york city already we give
proper protection to not just ground
level expression for the vids
points of color in a painting or design
but also to larger structures and just
the idea of those at some point you
start cracking up
you get to a point where you go into
orbit you're no longer
I would like a copy just this page I
would wonder if I don't know who's any
copyright protection here because
there's probably only this is probably
one of the very few concise ways trying
to create a concise easy-to-understand
way to park featuring the park features
itself has certain criteria that are
just fun changes we just part of it so I
think this is this is subject to the
idea of the park and expression one good
way to express this part of our future
accurately fully concisely pages and in
a way that's trying to give them those
criteria merges with the idea would you
never have to call them
system like the fact they came up with
their own cargo
I think not I'll tell you why that's a
good point I'll tell you why that's not
enough to me it's just two words in
quite enough creativity isn't quite
enough imagine so creative interesting
way instead of the office of the park
features plays a role and explains how
the car park ranger works that would be
very creative I'm still not have
copyright to our feature worse
downpouring way of doing I didn't know
about but I don't because I think that
is not meant to say to you right is only
too but we don't normally
tiny things you can buy stuff in your
face yeah yeah I wonder that would
create some sort some kind of but in
terms of pure infringement yeah I don't
think that would create a bear but I was
unfair but to me its rules of jeans a
lot of seems like there are other we go
I listen software tools like talking
about it
outside the context of software is only
one good way to code one function
around somewhere between ideas etc and
the story you don't know quite where
learning hand raised copyright jointable
its real estate in a way they took an
original piece of code completely
different doesn't exist but the original
code that the Internet is a completely
different mutation but automatically
generated ok you know if I were to
compare to what I find similarities
Cheryl Cole through your game and
there's not a virtual ghost less
dramatically changed at all since pilots
can you reverse
exactly could make a Dr appt at that
point it becomes a translation and
that's considered an adaptation and
translation of Harry Potter is as much
or some kind of some kind of
prescription and of course also you know
your source code is protected and so
many compiled version of that however
bear in mind that we make copies of the
software
cases where 5259 certainly tell us that
they are used because we now here we
have a table of contents phone died and
we see that the structure to do this
this and that structure might be
protected information first part about
89 protectable at that level that local
structure just doesn't matter what if I
put in there if I follow I can use my
own words but if I follow back precise
organization might be infringing
features it's just better no creativity
actually have Supreme Court case law on
the books where the ground is weird
creative way to organize ya gots some
categories that might be creative force
you have some images
the white pages or database of people's
just where they live just back to the
database we have different idea whatever
reason I that's that's a really good
point oh yes it certainly some databases
a schema
question can we separate the
functionality from the scheme and are
there more than there are ways to do it
but the schema is a structure that is
not a back questions is it purely
functional but is there more than one
way to do it and that would be a
difficult question but still sucking the
data of database just make a copy of the
whole database schema and all the code
and therefore
everything
me know about this case involving
Sherlock Holmes and we discovered that
most humane and leader of some major
stories and the extent that the oil
would we basically put some of it is in
the public domain
2010 Steamboat Willie
merger they didn't we don't use
copyright to give
we look at software is going to solve
where there are other limits your
software over the ideas functionality
come up with a way to solve he doesn't
like the author plus 70 years right to
that most elegantly and that you will
lose your copyright 2012 emergency money
is also something like every creator has
a kind of toy box of stuff in common to
everybody in that cost comes to play a
way to stop boastful soldier
young people these characters and
comment everybody baby to strike action
but there are two locks the same thing
with lots of basically big anybody any
any any technique that you're learning
today
coming up probably nobody has a right to
it
interoperability is actually very use
but it's important one if you have to
borrow in order to meet you won't
program with an operating system works
were holding back to be reviews hole
very quickly now into horrible Google
abstraction you'll be surprised what it
was horrible ended up winning
let me clear and get lost in there was a
platform-independent risking that for
devices and but generally by the virtual
machine allows it to be cross-platform
there's the language itself and then the
library because your computer can eat
and he's got his own library to work and
until 2007
all this License this and then at some
point they license everything but the
API library under the GNU General eases
some people do you get a license I like
to open source one day going to follow
try to make my job a big difference I
grew up there and is a little more
litigious and protect their organizing
the library
collected together two packages in the
packages into a library that has a
declaration
declaration tells the compelling
machine where to go the the path virtual
machine to the right and then the method
will and then the station is the code
that actually does
code the same that with religious thing
is that nineteen ninety-four percent of
the code is identical access no access
but nineteen ninety-four percent of the
covers the same tells you something you
like that in the first place
the same thing that means to me that I
was brushing merged with one way do not
copy the problem was he still sees the
structure the code
word-for-word codes but no copying the
appeal like a breakaway with structure
because of the structure people program
in Java
nowhere and turns out I don't know how
extensive organization helps everybody's
familiar with it binds to argue the
lower court was burned because everybody
knows that but we did it the way that I
am quite a few things does not read
because it was mostly a pack case went
to the jury and the jury found remove
your top you can't do better than jury
and almost all the money in the case
went to the tax on this point I got
Google was to set up its own
organization you probably can't at this
point back then right when they're just
starting a new organization might have
been killed
people could not easily program Google
now has come up their own organization
does not operate in part because I
mentioned we don't know we have very few
cases very few cases about this kind of
copy
are you mentioned it didn't copy the
simplicity of one that was used all over
to discuss the case cases is the
simplest method see his first
declaration urges
minds think the last person tells you
where to find it and how it's going to
be used the syntax
you just don't see how to work its
course the simple numbers you see max
but its numbers and returns the larger
we were very surprised I was my blog I
had two very excited by organizations
like but it makes sense to me and the
federal
we were looking at how they are not how
things were in 1995 1994 why it was an
issue about people needing to use job
that comes late ninety five were put
that whoever organized the job of
creating choices so what happens later
when when it comes along and back I
gotta tell you it was right you were
looking at it at the wrong time
organization they were talking about
I got this from from Oracle's brief this
is what we rejoice that are not clearly
driven by functional functionality
what about the fact that gather for
themselves how can I put together a
library that is easy to use their
organizing way that people will expect
those are not copyrightable features
fortunately Google argued that a trial
and you can try and make sure the jury
judge a monster of an argument to me in
Google just what with the simple
argument but there is made that big and
complex is this is this was entirely
driven by functional concerns ease of
use intuitive miss you baby get some
experts say back ninety-five we all had
basic understanding of how libraries
organizing this is just organized way
anybody would have done it if they could
have made that argument then they would
have succeeded in the murder but they
did we don't know the trial
now the question now is job having
become so common that library being so
common to have a very organization so
that their products are offered with job
that has been remanded and we're still
waiting for that that the trial December
day waiting on that in the air
they actually fired and