come into my talk names current wife
when I talk about adding web more along
the lines of sort of an introduction and
reason like this talk is sort of help
close the gap between developers who are
not quite sure how to secure their
absolute error code or anybody's
interested in getting into in person so
I'm basically give a high-level overview
as a security consultant what I do all
the way to airport delivery for an
assessment for an application web
application before he can start packing
or whether you're going to town on a
client's website is things that you have
to do for us we usually watch all this
is where we will discuss things such as
in the rules of engagement document
where this clarifies the scope so what
is the URL that we're actually looking
at what I peas is alleged the malicious
traffic so they know they have security
operations center something they're not
alerting everyone because they are
expecting us to be sending malicious
traffic at certain time and then when do
we start assessment when do we stop also
if we happens in October a service issue
on either end we have contacts we know
who we can call wake up at three in the
morning and
they're happy place that broke something
here in this assessment document as much
as you can because a report is expected
at the end of the USS so there have been
times as a new consulting where there
were more abilities that I found but I
was decided to keep going and so I
forgot to document this and when it came
time reporting to ask the client or more
access to the system because I forgot to
document something so just keep that in
mind and this document everything as you
go how do I got my choice as keynote in
this is available in Cali Linux it also
has installed for Mac OS or Windows and
it's just that it's an open source tool
that allows it to you but and codes free
shots or leagues are basically anything
and the cool thing about it is that a
client or another consultant once to see
sort of your break it down and put in
the report you can explore all of it as
basic HTML files so they can see
everything without having to install
he'd known as well as they don't have it
so that's pretty handy
so you can see how things down so if
there are a few different applications
on the same assessment then you can see
they haven't broken down by IP right
here or hostname and then all but
whenever I find or its just a handful or
one application the layout of what I
find and you'll find that the more that
he do this you're going to change the
way that the way they document things
this is probably the third or fourth
time that I changed how I do this and I
found that this is what works best for
me and is what helps me to move along
faster your reporting and just
referencing vulnerabilities so just play
around with the color-coding the green I
use that to say hey this is just some
quick go to information like what is the
scope of our forget a username or
password I can look at that and say I
didn't ignore everything that's green
dark red in the red would be serious
hi however your your company rates those
things and so on and for me that's just
a quick visual of you know how the
applications working so far so a lot of
times for everyone about tests are going
to have your HTTP request and response
was that way the client can see what it
is that you see and what the actual
response was this way when they go
through and they are trying to mediate
these things they can they can reproduce
the same results that you got you also
want to make sure you note any scheduled
downtime so you're trying here actress
in that location all sudden
that's gone and you can access that
anymore make sure you write down when
that happened that way if something did
go down if it was an accidental Dallas
service or something then you can say
okay this happened at 11:42 and this
will help their guys to be able to go
back and look at logs and try and track
it down so that makes it a lot easier
for the client as well and if they did
you test accounts and when you do change
the passwords make sure you let them
know what the passwords are some people
get upset to change it and don't let him
go and then again if you're working on a
bank website or e-commerce or something
and they don't give you a test credit
card you have to use you know something
from the company or something
make sure that you like that you know
give you your money back if you have a
really poor I see guys get in trouble
with us before you have a really high
and it's exciting especially this one of
the first ones do not share screenshot
about online if you do make sure you
saying that I that's so that you can
tell this is really where it came from
so keep that in mind there's some more
on evidence gathering when you're
putting your screenshots and your report
or something that you're going to send
to the required to the client make sure
that something they can actually read
just keep in mind if you have if you had
a really being resolution on your screen
and you do the entire screen shot in the
report is the normal page with you have
to squeeze that down they're not going
to be able to read a lot of stuff on
there so just make sure that you keep
that in mind here's an example data
based on from Season One Direction there
was a lot of information there are
several several rows of information
personally identifiable information and
things that I wanted to show but
obviously doing huge screenshot of that
as you can see him and squeeze it down
on a document like a printable documents
gonna be really hard to read that
especially with the black background
reading texts so did you know that and
pasted onto something that works many
more like this a lot more legible and
they're not trying to squint to see
what's important again with this example
you can see the highlighted area in the
username browner I call that out that
way in the report review or mediation
they can quickly see what it is that
they need to throw in that parameter to
get the same results to show that it's
possible to see the injection in this
would be you know for cross-site
scripting or whatever it is that you're
trying to call out whatever the
vulnerability is or what the payload
that she sent to trigger that make sure
you highlight those just to make it
easier for them then example the
injection for sure the username you also
want to make sure that s like the
password perimeter or any single
any parameter that is within that
application check it for Seymour
injection as well or whatever it is that
you're looking for and make sure to
document those have actually seen junior
investors where they just fine for
example the user name is vulnerable
task or what about the password grandeur
and say well I don't know I'm on user
name brand new and moved on so just make
sure you're checking every parameter
within the application
when you're doing tests are so many
things to look for
there's a lot of stuff to do and so
something that highly recommend it
highly recommend it is to have a
methodology to go by such as and this is
more of a checklist to help keep you in
line today she's not forgetting
something and I don't just many years
2002 that methodology is a check list in
case there something that is leaving out
but please use it just more of a
reminder for each you want to make sure
you're doing when you're looking at
whether you want to go and look out on
the internet to see what you can find
through open source intelligence figure
out if there's already been a breach of
this company or there have been so many
times where I've actually found a base
types of a scheme as he's passwords as
well as the email address of the
developers working on that occasion and
all of that stuff is still relevant
so you can find things like that but
around there so tip to developers if you
are posting something on a Help forum
and you know we're trying to get help
for anything any tour any any type of
programming make sure that you sanitize
your information to share with the world
so just change change the database name
change something slightly where someone
like me finds its not gonna be relevant
to that application and assessment if
you have someone that's helping you well
or not the end of the seventh but yes
someone that's helping you out on these
forums and you give them temporary
access
make sure that you count when they're
finished try to forget about it because
that has helped us to you
dumps and data bases
equipped all that I like to use in there
are so many of these out there for open
source intelligence is discover by
leaving here and I don't think that that
comes pre-installed you install it
yourself pretty easy you can see it does
quick recall on or you can get a domain
that you're assessing or persons name
for ourselves for us there are several
things that you can do that really
helped save time you're going to hear me
talk to you about and then you will
automatically launch 242 search against
just do a quick and it's the website or
no back-up files know what happened in
URLs or anything that would be
low-hanging fruit for an attacker
ok automated scanning automated tool was
supposed to be a happier well they're
huge time saver so when we run we
started this isn't really only have a
week maybe two weeks so it's pretty
quick so I mean it scatters itself it's
gonna spiders had to go through and look
at everything as quick as possible and
again it's going to help you find low
hanging fruit such as scripting or
potential sequel injection war you know
if it's found backup files or anything
that these games combined
it's just a nice nice tool the house
however vulnerabilities and is not a
Pinterest it's just a boner abilities
can so to those who say that once can is
appended
so well is just standing in billings
that's not going through and trying to
exploit those even further and you're
going to get false positives so you have
to go through and verify manually verify
all of the results from these automated
scanners and you're going to use those a
lot of times you can actually go
scanners will have a buddy or you can
actually attack see more in depth the
response and that will help you
determine right away if it's a false
positive or not so while you're here I
go again it helps you get out the things
that are false positives in the things
that are you can dig deeper into those
so if you find cross-site scripting and
the scanners just bringing back the
wrong that says access and you know that
can you do something or what can you do
to take that further automated scanners
and other so many out there but the ones
that I used personally Nessus this is a
good win that can get the host itself
and now you can specify credentials and
things to do authenticated scans but I
use this mostly just specifically look
at the host IBM a scan is another good
one that I like to use its pretty robust
really get it for authenticated scan
you have quite a bit of control over
that you're going to hear me mention
that several times while the store has
automated scanning built into it as well
as manual there's a lot of manual
testing that when you as well my
one-stop shop for testing and then as I
already mentioned 45 or abilities
vulnerable strips or and I use these
tools separately all the tools
separately as they're all going to have
slightly different results so it's it's
gonna get better results and not just
rely on a website that's open source
framework like WordPress or Drupal or
Joomla or something like that though
there are some cool cool tools like this
w me scan and it specifically for
WordPress and so will think about this
is a logo through and it will tell you
in person and if it's out of date so
that you're not having to Google and
reference to see bears the burden
because WordPress baby updated versions
were like every other week or something
so it's a good game for that it also
scans it will enumerate any plugins that
they're using so they are using that has
known vulnerabilities such as the old
and had basically
website that this trip will also
enumerate user names so this is cool
cares if you know the user names and
they don't have any sort of blocking on
the website you can do so again they
have tools like this for Drupal and
Joomla and other known in ColdFusion I
was getting hope you some sites because
they're so easy for automated scanning I
think I like to find more like to use
his or her buster and this is bad for
store that will go through and you can
do a pure brute force to find directory
names that exists in the other content
or you can get a list of very large list
that it comes with known directory and
file names and you can also look on the
bottom right on if you can see you back
here but you can also specify file
extensions that you want to look for so
here you and you alone the word lists
and unsavory books forum index PHP NID
SPX studies you know whatever extensions
you have here and still goes to sleep
for some good things it takes a long
time but it can pay off especially if
you're looking at a web app that seems
pretty secure
hitting a wall and what to do next let
this store on for a while and might find
something good
scares in Cali and this is different now
since telling too but television wine
and this was the path of fun more
scanners that are built in and then sync
and expose those or other popular ones
as well
ok tips or automated scanning
by the settings it's really bad it's a
bad idea just opened scanner but in the
URL and click Run several things can
happen you can let the host of potential
analysis because it's an old really old
server then cannot get over this
actually happened times for larger
clients that you hope aren't using old
legacy systems but in story comments 0
you know look at the number of
connections and it's going to make those
that a single time
and this is something to eat more that
you do this morning to figure out just
browsing at the website initially the
response time and looking at the code
will be able to tell if this is this is
something that you can hit really hard
to have the baby yet call something
that's very important to ask are there
any chance that you want to avoid the
assessment for example if they have a
contact for more or something that your
automated scanners just going to keep
hitting over and over again there's
gonna be some poor soul that's going to
get thousands of emails
vacations from Orem or its gonna jump up
a database or something so make sure to
ask those questions like what he wants
to avoid or on the other hand is there
something that you really want us to
focus on you have a page that's more
sensitive that you want to spend more
time on the other things and they'll
tell you they let you know another issue
is even if a web page at the site
doesn't exist I'm sorry page doesn't
exist in your doing scanners we're gonna
get 200 OK response from everything so I
can swing or something it's got
everything that you have in your
dictionary that you're looking for is
going to return everything that is an
actual page it's a pain in the butt to
clean up and takes forever to go through
so in these answers most use a page not
found where you can change it to 200 ok
and given the size and it will basically
take that as a 404 page not found
so if you do have credentials make sure
that test beforehand make sure they work
and then that way it's not like
Wednesday night or Thursday morning over
on Friday and you're just now asking the
client to check the credentials they
gave because they're not working that
looks bad so make sure you check that
helped to make sure here again that you
can login ok something I don't have on
here that want to make sure it to stress
you always do an application assessment
as an unauthenticated user and then as
user so they can call home and ask for
their admin level credentials and I also
need regular local user credentials that
way you can look for things such as
privilege escalation so are you able to
get into pages that the admin see as the
regular user or as an authenticated user
are you able to get two pages in the
functions that often he did you see so
always made sure to ask for all levels
of authentication counts then once you
have everything set up a new are
confident about your settings then you
can go ahead
and as mentioned earlier get past this
but as I mentioned earlier make sure
that you really manually verify the
automated scanners results gonna be mad
you just trust the scanner wrote in the
report declines looking at it and they
can't replicate the results because
there's nothing to replicate and ask you
about it and he can't give them an
answer other than sorry
so that's that's not a good situation
ok any questions so far and I'm moving
through the stuff we're all have
questions to you have any questions for
later
specific website ok so we'll go over
manual testing and this is something
that is so high level because the manual
testing there are so many different ways
to do this that if you get stuck on
something Google is going to be your
best friend there are so many free
videos out there that will teach you
exactly what it is you're wanting to do
so if you ever get stuff on on how to
explain how to eat a cross-site
scripting further or something lighter
remote file inclusion anything like that
make sure that you check out and it will
you will learn how to do it
to look at while you're really calling
the out the response what is the
surprise is that Apache IIS outdated
there's a lot of times legacy systems or
I'm hatch systems that are vulnerable to
things such as partly something that's
really there in several times where been
able to compromise the entire post
without getting into the web at the web
because I'm that so make sure you check
that out
you heard me talk about earlier any
primer you find things to do not sure
exactly what buzzing is or how to do it
again
Google will give you tools to do that
such as wooden cross site scripting or
sequel injection and things like that
here's just a quick reference popular
things to look forward that are pretty
easy to find out so without explains
these things
sweet bro cool thing I like about
virtually bro is that if you have any of
these lists from offer something that
are known as they're known payloads to
process scripting you can throw that
list in the air and specify what you
want to go I wanted to go to you and it
will automatically run through that list
same thing of yours went into early
quick and dirty check or sequel
injection or just general data
validation you can throw on some list
but first we grow and then you can
specify the brand and you can within a
minute or so depending on how large the
listed as you get your response to see
if these parameters of being filtered
properly or if not that's something you
should keep pursuing
things to look at how they passing
sensitive information through in the URL
3 get requests post requests for example
when you're and you could go and the URL
of do you see your username or password
or anything that says a lot for that
because it's not being cat or if there's
man-in-the-middle attack or is someone
gains control of the host later on then
they can see in the history they can
simply history you are all these
potential credentials are sensitive
information so you want to make sure
that anything sensitive is going through
a post requests and source code this is
a great one that seems like probably
eighty to ninety percent of us something
just three comments and source code or
someone pointing to that database name
or credentials or something that they
left us a comment to another developer
or you can see the only goal line a
comment for basically every line telling
you exactly what that code does well if
you look at that sometimes you can
engineer that and use that to your
advantage to figure out ok I know
exactly what this javascript is doing
and we're getting whatever from because
the developers just told me exactly what
it does so make sure that you're going
through in looking at those comments and
the source code really time consuming
sometimes but now
as I mentioned earlier occasion there's
a good reason again to test as an
unauthenticated user as well as
authenticated users is there something
that you can get to that you're not
supposed to see so many times people try
to use security by obscurity so whether
you're a regular user or you're an admin
mobile user may try to hide certain
leaks from you just from job as well if
you go look at the code you can see the
links in their admin / whatever I have
to do is copy and paste that and now
you're looking at adding pages that were
supposed to be hidden from the view so
go through the looking different URLs
especially because I know it sounds
silly but that's most of the time when
they're going to say is at an analyst
say if if you're not an admin hi this
it's it's really obvious and that led to
that developers don't want to you know
you don't want to rename everything we
have to try and have some reference to
go through just to stand what it is that
your code is best to do so you need to
check password requirements he said your
password is ABC 123 or just password if
so it's only password and its findings
document that I need to be at least
eight characters and they should require
special characters as well
let the host Knights stay out something
that's outdated again are there is
available 0 lifetime you're fine with
patches tom cat or something that is
accessible to the public which is that
should only be accessible by certain
IP's
widely available depending on his case
again if you're not quite sure what the
use cases but you think its ability I
was doing reported anyway and you can
always talk that through with a client
here they say well this has to be
available because this is how they
access whatever and it makes sense that
you can always drop but it's better to
be safe than sorry
you want to look for HTTP methods that
are dangerous such as a hobby to leave
and trace I've actually do you host
simply because they had but and so I put
a lot into strips that gave me a show
host and pretty much had my way with it
compromised it within maybe twenty
thirty minutes
assessment so look for those things and
they have any methods that you're not
sure about why they're using it again
report that and then talk later with
them
directory for things like directory
traversal
automated scanners things that just need
to automatically look for those for you
as well and this this particular example
is a great reason great example of
scares saving you a lot I don't know
about you but going up to the URL and
doing more / 04 / timing doesn't work
and trying it eight times and it's going
to be very time consuming so the
audience can really help with things
like that
is great as well what do they have
everything over the world they have a
remote desktop open to the public which
does happen or is it just worked for
three things as I sell things as you may
know a lot of our abilities as the cell
versions and then pls versions and weak
ciphers so there are several free tools
that will actually go and quickly hand
there there and let them know that you
have all the CDC's you know we signing
key or whatever it is make sure that
you're looking at the facility listings
as well or are they even using SSL and
you know certain websites that they have
authentication or something that's not
going over a secure connection that's a
boner ability to pay attention of those
things
mentioned earlier check out different
methodologies and is a popular one get
this helps keep you on track and just
getting into this we're not exactly sure
what to do what to look for work where
do I start and when things start looking
at these methodologies will help get you
on track and hope so make sure you
practice in a lab there's some
vulnerable p.m. so vulnerable web apps
that are far more on purpose for you to
practice all of these things and the
safety of your own lab peter is you
never want to go into a client-side and
run a tool that you've never used before
because if you don't know what it does
do it especially on client-side
reductions you break something and they
come in they say what you do and say I
dont know thats bad that's a bad day so
it just makes you practice and when
you're ready and websites
that's basically where slides but how do
I have to miss ok jerry has plenty of
time for Q&A and I know it was pretty
quick so many questions you guys have if
you have any specific tools you have the
top I cannot remove the name of Cali
like a Jew scanner June scam to send ya
a website isn't that a little rebuilding
itself yes it is and that's actually a
great one because we had clients that
have gotten so upset with that someone
like that infrastructure for that
website this died because it would send
out say for example contact we hand it
and it would send out a notification so
that would go to the email server and
then the attack would go in the net was
trying to send an email back to this to
let him know something was going on in
so so I guess high-level what happened
11 malicious attack that was sent you
know they had set up something
said they wanted to get mad at us from
flooding the system when all we did was
the basics and that $400 client wishes
and so that is a great point if you are
automated and that should be handled by
everything great something you have
you also want to make sure that you're
covered to say I'm not exactly sure who
worry but it's basically saying there is
a chance that were not want to find
everything so if your compromise from
something that we haven't overlooked we
are not responsible for that because
good reason for that is about to change
all time so they buy I would hear well
last month and you guys have a person
update or something or a new exploit
comes available that wasn't available
when we look at that I mean there's what
can you do about that unless you want us
to do an assessment every month or every
week and that gets pretty expensive so
you do have to have the image in there
basically covering the company and just
letting them know we will find what we
can find my overlook some things and if
we do we aren't responsible so
webcam to could crash on my website
yeah that's one of those things to that
practice thing that stuck in a while if
your lab environment handles it that's
cool you can go into an environment
where it's the system were they there
are variations on the server or you know
like the example i gave where the
service was sending so many instances
over and over so it's kinda hard to say
never happen in a quiet environment it's
kinda hard to say that so a way to sort
of things that I mean it does happen
sometimes unfortunately but all you can
do when it does happen is just be ready
cause the scanner don't have a scanner
and then leave brunch and something's
gone wrong however that's not going to
fly and yes laugh at that but that's
been insulting someone who is no longer
with the company he was because that was
an issue and so yeah that's another
don't hit a scanner and then leave make
sure there today he said it that way you
can give them hugs wherever they can
figure out what caused it
any links between the email server issue
that goes beyond just realities yeah we
we have that as you we have some people
were clients they're pretty sensitive
websites that leads to other things and
so this is where scope is very important
so that's where for example the
automated scanners you want to make sure
that you're specifying the scope and
where they say don't hit this submit
made because that actually goes out of
scope to you this other side and you
don't want to start hiring that just
because it was linked so that's where
you ask what do you want us to get food
and then you make sure to specify those
scare as well as any manual standing he
doesn't keep no thing that I found in my
scope on my scope age I will list the
things that we are not supposed to hit
and I'll make sure to reference that and
make sure that I'm not moving and
getting something that does happen
pretty regularly
pretty strong systems and their
production and then pretty much a mere
sight so with that all the rules of
engagement will specify from this date
to this day all manual and automated
scanning is 24 by seven and then we have
clients that say this is a production
site so there is a chance that anything
can be brought down only automated
scanning from 6 p.m. to 5 a.m. manual
testing can be 24 myself so that we do
have to specify those terms lot and we
do have some that only one has to do
Friday night to Sunday morning so that's
kind of important because your weekend
sometimes but you know it's not that bad
it doesn't happen as often but it does
happen
allocated to report anything that I
found that was not necessarily in scope
I think probably from the standpoint I
feel as though I am contractually I'm
not quite sure how late on this but
there have been a few instances where
the open source intelligence we're
actually found another web out on the
host that was given to us where I
uploaded a lot in the script and they
gave me tell you that and I probably
shouldn't have done that because it
wasn't necessarily the application that
but I felt like it was an extra services
that are provided to the client because
I knew right away when I saw that it was
really old and that it would be
vulnerable so I just wanted to check now
when I reported that I did it as a
separate email guys I found this I want
you to know that but I did not included
in their official report because it was
so I think as long as you do it that way
always ask you guys think I found this
phone call I just check it out just to
make sure what I think it is pretty
critical and pretty easy to exploit most
of the time let us know because we don't
you know we don't have
beach so I just kept on them and then
again if it sounds go just because he
made out of the report says it's not any
sense
thanks for not falling asleep on me and
please let me know if you have any
questions feel free to email me at any
time