enhance your enthusiasm for those who
don't know what that is is very cheesy
example of aids yard and all along
because I think true warnings need to be
made fun of like boilerplate language
included a trigger warning in this and
probably will in all future
presentations all this talk was designed
in the following the passwords user Andy
pulling selectors John users and
developers you have no other groups
while another year but there's more to
do with it
John River yes I actually enjoyed his
job development diet thing like the bill
so yeah we make fun of John it's like a
regular Joes on IRC me has dado tester
who are so doing this
doing the research that under this
presentation I actually found a couple
and and of the main developer whose life
here is Esther you're finding stuff we
should have found on her own
more idols and the problem I also really
torch relay and bridges if you were in
the XMPP talked earlier
team next year you already heard about
the plan not affiliated with the NSA oh
that's not some kind of weird double
plus I barely there were 48 miles
because I'm awesome director here and
the guys and they pretty much told him
he can't come because my handle is
safety in my email addresses room speed
up calling and in the same time your
program at the factory to let their
bowels provocation I told you so voters
spooks and their enablers and all of
that committee pretty hard and he
actually told me on Twitter that he
thinks I'm a troll
i dont trust anybody when I Dutra we're
going to do to get at Roland job let me
know this is the telephone talents lie
unspoiled the basics of what he would
bother doing this and generally how
about that because I really needs and
you can you can download the slides
later but more time to do some analysis
taking any questions
this is this is the scariest season ok
exploration to do battle field is
released in 2011 I actually did all my
testing all that feature at the time
that was like three years old
there's no chance he'll new password on
the bones I didn't so there is no bonus
lied on his dresser that done early last
year or early this year in January this
year actually and they were deviance and
store all their passes next year 2011
2014 top 10 classed as they mostly top
25 most common passwords and as a little
pastors lot of states this is terrified
I know but only about this is the
dumbest person like you have the you and
they don't like 23456 everyone else is
slightly more intelligent but that's
what president presentations
I was going to talk about why the hell
anyone would bother doing any of this
oh there's security research whether
it's for your company internally like
did later or externally like this
investigation or anything like that
oh there's a guy or are stable Nate
Anderson
article about my experience getting
hands that's how I became a password
cracker there are various cruelty
committed a lot of people would probably
without they didn't read this article
but he covers a lot of good drill and
then there's his password recovery which
is basically geared for law enforcement
asking for a show of hands or anything
you do not need any backdoor run tours
arranged this legal framework of that
just brute force everybody feels that's
just plain bad reason this is one of my
favorites lies checking mostly so send
me an email that they will first thing
else
in just 15 and yeah that that's a thing
and then my personal favorite earnings
which really just using striptease for
sure and public service this is the
first time around what is a password
basically it's 110 in this situation is
just organized words just heading plain
text structure idiots basically the
whole idea is that it could spread then
passes are reusable and advice for users
a little bit of time change your passes
unless you're really stupid knew
something like something william was
born just like straight
echo a string and again be five some of
those of you who are Linux users and
yeah that's just not good at all that
sort of behavior was acceptable back in
the seventies don't do it
salting started to become thing i dont
removal in the brain the tables were
designed basically just to preview the
budget passes and then
waiting CPU time 'cause nobody's video
tour of the files in their play text
equivalents in the problem being that I
am rainbow tables kind of God's Word by
salt which low-level standpoint you have
a string of texts that gets into the
word and then 2012 and generate a lot of
the better algorithms he's also just how
many times runs before you get the
correct as well just really worried as
true that there's nothing that's like he
did to the algorithm they don't use guns
some examples that are all color slide
ok but the light blue that's just so
bright green is salt and where I have
read zero day is actually just the
number of iterations now that is
actually an exponent that actually runs
256 times by three times so on and all
of these days of work out oh and in case
anyone is going ask later
standard for beetroot these days is a
workout
twill gotten all the news has cancer
password cracker
plain Jane SKU CPUs and I know you're
not going to use Facebook actually asked
that I just feel like telling it in case
you need you actually go download it and
you don't have to endure and made some
offer whatever oziel hands is the AMD
version for graphics cards desk and he's
the Nvidia version Indies implementation
of its terrible that's probably all
purpose because they're so there are
there to buy CD but still 140 so change
and anybody who likes you can build a
single cluster fuck 228 you can do so
doesn't care
title of the talks had better find
original slide the way it was presented
in eight by twenty five characters talk
about the GPU versions because only the
CD version which brings me to exploit
this is Joe Black Cat the movie the rest
of you you didn't miss
so you're going to sleep here that you
see director really has no basis in
reality this may have been in 1993 I can
probably as nicely as all of these five
and just basically to the mall and its
employees into longer than its alright
cool store that the real reason is GPUs
have lots of little dumb just see you
were more complicated functions really
can be broken out and that's where the
speaking real world example I don't have
no
alright I've got it and ended a
three-day do I tried to 400 million
tries per second with TV video card
that's really not advocate for the job
it's inadequate but it still vastly
better than my CPU hardware because i
dont really fantastic right 00 there's
also talk by evil dirty on he said this
hilarious had john is talking about
extending rigs on fire
Laureus
passwords dogs but it's it's definitely
worth watching I think it's about half
hour but I will touch on this is what we
call of reference design car that's
basically what you would find on the
website now these are actually the same
card when it's just that in this case I
think they took and $50 difference
I can't remember which doesn't belong
there is just corner cutting for gamers
will assume you're gonna be running 24 7
365 and you want to spend $50 on the
real thing
assembly otherwise you end up with fires
like brand new cars go with India and
Indians you remember about two years ago
when do you mind was thing before the
difficulty when everybody by in the body
of the TLDR version takes their
architectural deficiencies and at the
same time with the same cars in Newark
takes to that end to the power in half
over what agencies knew about the same
for its own use as much electricity
which means no burnout PCI slots no
fires
most of the baby is it the thing though
is there only like 3 beta testers for
video cards as last time I checked one
of the first one is a guy who made our
stay ago few years back for making
insurance IDP rig that forget how many
billions of has percent
and then there's me yeah it's kinda sad
state of affairs but these were slowly
story by ok this is this is my new free
means that I get the burden stairwell it
will meet this slide right here and what
I have to say
mining rig that is just collecting dust
and you use it for cracking passwords
you have to follow certain steps take
every person take everything out of the
military or parades take the train back
to the gas station from yes unless you
have another use for any separated into
two files takes your breath cards and
things that was not cheesy everything
else another bottle you build your
trading room that that fire because it's
burned anyways and you might slow down
or earlier
substance for the days when dinosaurs
roamed the earth he was given he was
fighting for and he got 87 percent they
were so everything every truncated
and was easily deceived you with John
River
for specific optimizations he got about
10,000 tries for second in and around
our forward-looking multiple blamed on
to something that really start to pay
attention to the last couple of years
alright for only benchmark funds are
used any invoice with the combined for
my car died Aug 16 PTI which is anyone
has heard about it is hilariously
inadequate for the job it was like 150
bucks two years ago its words and hiring
mentioned I would love that because
there were so many unique in these files
it says here idk but there's always like
there's like 423,000 which still it
wasn't this the Syrian electronic army
and didn't feel like I did you like you
like that was significant roles as
promised that I just used socks until
later when I see what I could create
I'm used to carrying which is really
popular it's kind of the go to work
until something else comes close
sites they're not publish it
human only guy his name is Taylor or me
he knows that 2010 could text passwords
passwords and I'll have the ties them
it's ok it's kind of like taking a
shotgun to inspire them but words and
they have certain restrictions and
guidelines and 2012 has done and I
forget the name of the other site this
really matter and greg did 2014 2010 and
hold them difference between the two is
hopeful about the original Holywell
competitions which turned out to be
noisy and you'll see I got brian
Sandoval percent higher by using the two
over probably talked about attack types
in general this is an area which
basically that the best way and said
is to take any passes for previous data
breaches
even when you do that kind of decision
your car still runs high temperature
still the justices just saying it won't
be a part of all it's it's pretty much
like space heater over but valid a
thousand words after I don't trust has
to find things correctly which I
actually heard that and that's the whole
reason I'm instead of beta tester
earlier and validate my style is pretty
much how I came to ask me later but
surely
condition that is adding changing
capitalization and truncating the last 2
characters and it was only like one in
every 10,000 passwords in with your
health and if I complete my forty
glasses sold for just a minute you're
into the dc-area tanks are going to be
betrayed me only way to even do anything
until his password cracking because once
a dictionary attacks against all the for
example the Ashley Madison featured as a
no lose our stories some functions
Elite eight decades just around the
rocky centuries to run iraq attacks than
that so many reasons future anyways
28 2012 and 35.7 he made his base in
progress since most people don't use
passwords for 600 even know what has
gotten way better we will actually get
28 told us it just takes place had a
similar problem I'm gonna talk about
commentators you must accept that it
tried every combo of words judiciary you
can also carries with something protest
hate utils
show of hands he's heard I swear
making the best workers ok two people
died in the year it's about a half hour
it's really comprehensive guide covers
it will and he also thinks its research
dot com which is just like a repository
of white neighbors passwords for those
who are into reading next big thing
commentators you can apply what has or
the other half
the dictionaries and then there's a rule
of thumb in a little higher than special
characters all in other fun stuff just
getting things together
testing and i think im just say taking
entirely too long the next lie detector
alot of fun by systems right now you're
like me and track their words basically
and simply won't do is change the
dictionary and something else then tries
that and you can find a lot more stuff
just doing that you can also combine
multiple leads to be a little more rules
than others similarly the rules as well
something else making wise but of course
the time grows exponentially as you do
that Adam is John river cruise news best
rules rules are John and passwords probe
has the same will I think john thinks I
think I have some examples at the bottom
just using the polish dries all over
these past modification I think you guys
to read i guess im trying to move won't
hear all of these passwords were from
the start you why do you use GPUs I
really have to explain this because I
had like five lbs
to NZ grass or terror group's name
sometimes it's more the rules and never
even bothered to do this and list their
names and doesn't care
alright a 64 is also a little over by
contrast you have done download the top
just under two hours before I guess it
will be up for download the whole
reversal for those who analyzed the day
he's a little bit of you calculate the
percentage was until all of the stuff
across town
26 tracks I got an 81 points to close to
meeting the challenge but a more money
says the first eighty percent of the
last twenty percent that's just as a
rule about this year they were wrong to
make sure I will talk to really
understand it just clueless preview
got hit on the head with a large last 20
years because we have such a rich body
of knowledge with how passes we can make
this strength that explained that detail
and the other day I will just be no one
else and said well as lower case and the
DS digit in mind about working
environment minimum required for
passwords
this is your gym right here that ok
uppercase lowercase simulator that but
mostly they're so you can change as hell
and you're good to go
increment and decrement the number of
cells century 24 cents you can also if
you feel like doing other languages you
can specify custom character sets for
your into they need maybe don't there so
I asked a comes with us in that sense by
the best buy the fall I landed the first
three because by the time like that and
I realized the other three would take me
forever and I actually read these and
this was done last year another movie
finished I start another way to go to
bed
starting back to the I determine the
proxy rules it was going to take
entirely too long
and I say let's run the numbers and then
challenged decided screw it I'm moving
north didn't you like less drama winner
starting electric bills
we'll get to that later
schedule he had to cancel out he is
doing this presentation and you're all I
will be a good addition he said
treasurer 87 is now that I've gotten
that out of the way I was kind of lost
her moans and I thought what can I do
next
so I don't know that both the holy wow
this too would and I generate custom
rules the first rule was first holy
wells the bites and Holywell to generate
I sorted by popularity and instruct me
to 48 gigs and will be respected and
then start for those few the uninitiated
as a lot of the UNIX that's pretty much
what kind of environment
yeah yeah yeah I can sleep I see this
sunset standing
terminal in my brain even with all of
that I still so you can really tell I
really really getting into the land of
diminishing returns and there are rules
bridge alright this is an entirely
different explanation
third column prime percentage is that's
before this is just using rock is the
leading unchanged was rules like the
least one person has died down rules the
same number of lines and i just want to
see if I can do
line-by-line what was designed to exceed
what has kept the 64 that was
hilariously terrible
64 was hydride optimized and competition
from the community so I didn't really
expect to see did just a few fractions
of a percent again
v2 is a lot smaller the better because
it doesn't have transformed
decisions and not understand you raised
the stories of love trust is all about
that I decided maybe I should do this
with Massachusetts too so I used the
script and i dont no less than a
thousand matches just don't just jump in
Norway's so really Lawrence says case
and I think I don't think twenty years
518 million combinations kind of tells
says on there and there's no power plant
it
33317 which is what it would take to try
all of those six Mons is no fault in
here
ok no more lasting love boat about these
numbers he was true he used a couple of
school 3 a.m. in the morning
I decided oh hey I'm just so
universe Holywell 125 right now what's
really funny is lots of intelligence
will lead to her less time and I say
that because the deal has overnight you
since 2001 was another reason I think
I'm glad you mentioned earlier or easily
chances of finding something really at
risk and that turned out to be true
doing something a little dated but then
they would take everything they found
the attacks again which might probably
in single-digit numbers just from my
personal experience when they do the
nineties and communities heading now and
use is also a test yet already in there
actually strips out there for doing just
that
generating dictionary with you more
losses they are rather glory selling
project were held which one that does ok
let's say you I don't know what's going
on
websites that was seriously I don't
bother but I'm sure there was a website
for the website it once treatable the
words for example battlefields you
remember all the top 10 slide that was
one of the top 10 passes and you do it
was any specific things has a common
thing that's related to the science that
they used that Abdullah with Ashley
Madison they used the report is coming
passes that was a grueling who cares
what is at stake here he comes from
Berlin of a person like that that's why
I didn't surprise her guiding this by
toxic is done
talks about it's basically just
inserting other words I kind of color
that so I don't have to explain it as
trends and then you guys ask me
questions and hopefully able to answer
them I just hope it and there's no
presentations kind of blamed as you can
see all of your passwords and my
personal experience
six character passwords
it just seems really involved well in
this case six to 10 because the users
were slightly dumber than your average
users just error since used lower than
something you can look at it from
getting pictures you have time to 3% is
kind of depressing this is one of my
favorites I love this so much so
birds just just didn't understand that
earlier that is just my personal
favorite is the bird is live in shoulder
service I guess so when can we explain
that this is just another way of going
on here this is like running past prime
pollen and just make you file I was
advised
talk somewhere else that I should do
some pollutants so here is the
obligatory if you're a developer used to
always tell your other managers and
developers til the end he doing
developers with users regularly generate
all major organs to text file this case
mainland you guys were given to so maybe
they talking about their other
undesirables nature something like that
would be good and in just a year
you guys know that sucks does 4096 round
shot by the fall on the password for the
container you can adjust that is kinda
scary is basically just screwed on the
Bible productions year ago I do I do I
test and then I did so in 2006 so I went
to show 1986
just because I did it in the shower
proof alright this is the one you told
inside I told about the basics passing
out then drops and begin a little has
changed in her bed so trashy more
business cards so they had they done
alice is a little bit of beauty here or
there are references to stop and get
into the very bottom easy sex lies and
lies about firing developers and others
before coming here but yeah all of this
stuff
year old be built in one way or another
away like someone watches you to take an
okay thanks guys
reach out to be a certain reason whether
it's your senior questions comments and
will you can find and there's also give
her a question
know that's all I'm craving is some
sites down in the past and take the job
I do not own
presentation and cultures but it's not
like they're really good enough just
like one-liners basically but but but
unlike an actual effort
doing something that's worth using
multiple people are not aware of this
but if you find something like that let
me know those guys rule as hell is my
favorite yes it is