user you should go in but Baucus to make
you anything really fast and this is not
about making fast things it's about
making things investment but if you like
talking about fast things than cars and
bishops so we should hang out at some
point this weekend so the song is
essentially a rambling about stuff that
myself and my friends have made in
various makers basis most notably
emergency Georgia Tech but I got a bunch
of friends there might even their
resources they're like miners and their
started I was interested in robotics and
high school when I got to college at
Texas as pure science major I started
hanging out
machine shop and realize that I like
making things with my hands a lot too so
they kind of got me involved in and
ballots past two years but I also do
some research and and most of my
researches and physically part of it
things so I'm gonna talk about how to
make really anything you want in an
efficient manner using tools are now
really accessible
and before I really get into it I have a
QR codes if you want to follow along you
can just download sites I got a bunch of
links and stuff
the format of the target is going to be
about some techniques of constructing
things that may be constructing things
that are three-dimensional are very
complicated a lot easier and how it's
you essentially resolved very difficult
to make things into very easy to make
things so like taking a complicated
three-dimensional art and then taking
that down to the point where you can use
the bands on three axis CNC Miller
things like that I meant to bring in one
of my free to bring home its so talk
about that a little bit we'll talk about
some softwares and resources for you
want to design something and and Chad or
want to design a circuit board or you
wanna get a circuit board made by
courthouse where do you go to do that
where to buy electronics parts where to
buy motor controllers a robot parts and
then talk a little bit about machines
like 3d printers and CNC routers and
soldering irons and get started and
making things where to go and what to
buy three get started and what are the
things that I really like to use things
but I don't really like to use my name's
child I'm CSI undergraduate course I'm
doing a victory lap right now it's year
round
text for a little while but it's been a
good time so far as a bunch of
internships because I like having some
experience and that's one of the reasons
why I like making things we learned
something last text books like actually
doing so making things is really the way
I complicated and I want to do something
with it
I like writing a lot it's really fun I
think he's an audit also music and
building things some of my research
interests so many I machine learning I'm
into nuclear engineering and breakfast
so before we get into you know how I
think you should make things I just
wanted to give you a little bit of
information before so you can get a
little perspective and how I think about
making things sort of first really big
project happen of high school and I was
really bored with what I was learning in
physics and chemistry and I had this
kind of quarter life crisis and I
decided I wanted to do something that no
one had really done before I wanted to
do a real science experiment something
that I never been published before and
at the time I was kind of into renewable
energy I still am now i think is really
really awesome and I found out popular
Science magazine that people were
building nuclear fusion reactors in
their garages and basements and I said
you know maybe I should try to do that
because as you know that you could build
a nuclear reactor in your basement that
sounds like a totally legitimate thing
that any person so I wouldn't worry
about anything these days is represented
by community on the internet and
building nuclear reactors in your garage
is no exception
there's this awesome website called user
dotnet
that's a bunch of physics and
engineering people who likes to build a
high-energy physics experiments and
their garages and so this whole system
ended up being a vacuum chamber vacuum
chamber with a system of a compromise
that sucks nearly all of the air out of
the chamber gets down to very near the
pressure outer space and then you
probably in some deuterium gas prices I
still provider trends just got a new
trial in the nucleus and then you have
like a glorified spark plug on the top
of the vacuum chamber that allows you to
put in voltage into the chamber and you
simply put 50,000 volts of electricity
into the chamber on a little bit and
Accenture negative potential and when
you do that you start by analyzing
nearly everything in the chamber you
attract everything that's positive one
stylized to the sensor and so you get
this little positive star easy for me in
the center of the chamber and everything
sort of get attracted into that and you
get enough energy on the things that are
trying to do that
putting off all the gym so you can
really create nuclear reactions in your
garage and it's a very very low amount
of radiation really laughable you have
to run these things for tens of
thousands of years and be standing
within you know actually start absorbing
enough energy in your tissues to make
things like cancers mean of course
there's a risk of cancer at any exposure
to radiation I mean we're all
radioactive banana for breakfast this
morning was certainly radioactive
everything's are you active this is a
very very low amount of radiation this
is like banana level radiation reaction
rate so I'm fifty percent of reactions
that happened in this you get killing
three and the other percent you get
tritium release and you're trying on the
other side you really support and you
can detect the neutrons and right now I
tore the whole thing apart and I'm
building a particle accelerator so
that's like my next project after you've
done it you kind of look back at the
vacuum chamber and exercise and how
resourceful you are and it is almost
certainly a very hard
engineering challenge as well but
billion particle accelerator makes it
look like us together so I'm trying to
build a cyclotron which involves making
an MRI strength magnetic field and
putting a vacuum chamber in between them
frequency switching essentials and if
your interested let me know but that's
not the stocks are moving on
I've done mechanical things too but
you're on the left is called atomic
puppy
unfortunately built this in about a week
I was interning at the time and the
place I wasn't any had this really nice
hackers based on campus that they would
let you use so I 18 hour days that work
for a week and worked for a lot of time
that I was supposed to work and then
spent 10 hours building robots and they
had this little CNC machine I was able
to make all of us are printed out of PBS
and then the main body frame is made out
of aluminum rods from MasterCard black
pieces I didn't see the Super impact
resistant material that's actually
really easy to work with such a great
candidate for the three pounds and it
was pretty funny thing on the rate is
electric go kart that I made their kind
of MIT bildt's
cards time and the column GE cards and
this is a southern pride because it's so
bright and this is some child
Atlanta Maker Faire that was writing it
was pretty fun so it's kind of a
brushless motors what is much smaller
scale and looking into all sorts of
really fun technologies that will be
used in large-scale electric vehicles on
a smaller scale and once you sort of get
familiar with this electric vehicle
workflow you kind of like an addiction
you want to put like a motor on
everything because you can go by 1.5
horsepower about a hundred bucks and
then you buy a controller for 50 bucks
and then some batteries for 60 bucks and
you know for about $300 altogether you
have like a really silly electric
scooter or something like that
the tour of these things have electric
longboard and originally was ruled ride
but the way the more store it would
target the board up so you could throw
yourself off the board with how much for
the murders had to turn around and
front-wheel drive down and said you
always go breaks into your electric
vehicle
things of that sort of develop the room
maybe like the last twenty or thirty
years as electronics mechanical motion
have become more ubiquitous and really
cheaper which have unveiled a new way of
using computers to make the entire for
typing process quicker since we have
smart machines now allows you to really
hard task to become super easy like 3d
printing something you can spend most of
your time focusing on designing the
actual park and then using the computer
smart tools do the rest this was a
totally new school coming from high
school where we would take plywood we
did this competition called best we
would get like a big box full of parts
and then we had to make a robot over six
weeks with it and we can't just shot
from the hip and we will take you
through a band saw no cut pieces off
until we had something that looked like
a robot I got to draw a lot people to
wear on their computer for like two
weeks designing a model in a cat
software which allows you to do
three-dimensional parametric drawing so
you can build your entire thing in the
computer in a mock up the bolts and
screws and see how everything is going
to fit together like your mothers your
stress analysis on how all the parts are
going to move around they would spend
nearly 80% of the time doing this on the
computer press a button have their
materials list generated for them to
master car and electronics Supply
Warehouse get all the packages back and
then build the robot and it gave because
all of the parts though the design was
done they would send it to a water jet
or laser cutter
and then you have a bunch of parts that
slot together and you have a robot and a
date of actual machine so this is a
valid way to make real things because
you can make things like what you're
just gonna have you know message to the
limits of what materials and electronics
can be used for you know stand the test
of going to competition a competition
even though they're built in like a day
or two so I was kind of obsessed with
how this can can have in how regular
people like you or I can use this to our
advantage than anything so I kind of
took the Wikipedia definition and and
change a little bit my lighting
technologies that we end up using either
like us to control things like CNC mills
lathes and routers CNC mill is like a
really fancy dress that can move in a
couple of different access ladies are
things that make parts that are
considering about so essentially like
cylinders and bolts and screws and stuff
like that may be used for
two-dimensional flat parts you can cut
out with a router is basically cutting
tool water jets opportunity as someone
like lets you know like this place has a
water you could work here this place has
a water you could use or you can go to
this university and have a large jet
that they let their students use
does which is awesome things you can use
their water coolers to lever and it will
spoil you my my parents speculate
sometimes
the reason why I have taken five years
to graduate from just because they have
twenty-four seven access and it's
essentially this machine that takes up
to six inches thick steel and then it
uses water cut out your parts take one
class so the deal I really really need
and we have this program after you've
demonstrated your ability to use all the
machines in space you can volunteer and
you give three hours of your time a week
to come in and help other students make
their parts and you get 20% about 90%
amazing crowd of interdisciplinary
people got a hackerspace wherever you
live it's getting involved in have that
in my Resources section atlanta has
freezing totally epic people involved in
you know sort of uncommon to come across
as being able to access them all the
time but there are tolls now like big
blue saw and you can see your files and
what meddling in like a week they'll
send you back water jet parts it's a
pretty cheap rate of actually getting
cut out and they handling all of the
rain the machine almost 30 starting
point where the laser cutters and 3d
printers are very very minimally priced
more than that actually constitute them
and you can make those yourself so often
times you know so low level makers
3d printers or or taking so the first
technique is called earlier with you
this is basically a way of taking my
wanting to make a box we take this box
divided into sheets and then generate a
pattern of slots that fit together like
your fingers together with each other
this is really need you can add
fasteners in a really region structure
this
the picture is kind of terrible
resolution but it's a small compared to
how you can see that makes any sense
whatsoever
there are there are buses on this frame
that's into this aluminum extrusions and
I'm using that take advantage of the
steel fasteners and into a really dirty
part out of wood are pretty common frame
technique and there are a lot of online
now that will generate this website
called me her case dot com and you can
eat size of the box you want and what
hardware you want to use SVG or a DXF
file for you which you can go and then
like Trey Songz wooden hand or send it
to your laser cutter and then cut your
box it all together and then you gotta
finish the project includes box 220
which again this usually cheap these
days one of my favorite techniques i
think is kind of underutilized right now
is actually I've mentioned this several
times like it is taking a break into
slices Lexus just recently published a
video where they hired this art studio
to make one of their cars out of
cardboard and they took a
three-dimensional design of the entire
car and then use the software called one
to make and it goes through you tell it
the size of materials that you want to
use and how you wanted to see what you
can do like these puzzles pieces and
then they're slotted together like
finger joints essentially but it can
also just lots that are slices just sit
next to each other so you can go
together or use a towel tired part so
with the Lexus car
so
technology competition
cardboard answer
stands for fused deposition modeling
which means that I didn't have time to
set up your printer running before let
me know and I like the way this whole
process works FDM printers and when it
goes through the belts and then you just
move around in the pattern that you want
so what you take any 3d model you want
to your layer thickness for instance
this prince in 100 micron thick layers
think about the thickness of a sheet of
paper you have a piece of software that
goes through that part divided into 100
micron layers and then each of those
parts it does that finds the path around
that and then a path through that to
make a film structure on the inside so
most parts from FDM printers are not
actually 100% solid you put them with an
infield so like honeycomb structure on
the inside that lends structural
integrity what does not require a whole
lot of time or filament actually built
is not solid throughout so it seems
material and so you do that and then
the next layer process works by doing
those layers one at a time and then in
between those layers the platform moves
down or the head moves up and have a sad
face here in addition is because over 20
countries have a nice way of saying as
printers have improved a lot over the
past five years five years ago they were
really have to deal with and for a while
as the 3d printer persons 3d printer
broke I was the one who six days and
Technology IIT folks in the crowd among
us who you might take something that you
love you have to fix it all the time
because someone else broken you're not
gonna let you know when they work though
they can be your greatest friends it's a
really cool experience to be able to
like need something have an idea in your
head design it and then press a button
and then have it printed lawyers
and if you have just some money that's
as far as good as one of the best things
that anyone who wants to make things for
themselves is packaged computer aided
drafting and get familiar with it and
start using it to design things working
with CAD really teaches you a lot about
the process of designing something
further real world and how things should
get together and we should go and your
size and weight constraints and things
like battle bots and spaceships and race
cars all start typically right here you
know after you decide that you want to
make it look like this is your block now
especially with digital manufacturing
technologies is pretty nice it's kind of
an industry standard at the moment but
it's expensive it can't be forced
through the internet for less than its
retail price so if that's your thing go
for it they're very big company and the
company that owns them Dassault
systèmes find a 3d printer company but
called Stratasys who owns MakerBot and
make a really terrible printers now so
if you go get their software don't feel
bad about it
there are companies like Autodesk
software is like and if you have a edu
email address the user three which is
awesome they also have many versions of
their products that are just yeah yes
there's also Solid Edge Pro Engineer /
creo this is what nasa uses for most of
their stuff it's also and Autodesk in
you can find trial versions of that are
used for non-commercial version of
things that you want to make it last
time I checked I think that was for you
yeah yeah yeah so open scatters great
I've seen it
widely adopted in the 3d printing is
here and there are really great
tutorials for that and if you've ever
gotten started to like about salt works
because I'm gonna have to figure out
what I'm gonna do when they graduate
they have a really nice suite of
tutorials that it actually published on
you know you get a salt works they have
tutorials that will take you from
nocache knowledge at all
making a really really complicated parts
and as for electrical design goes there
are suffers like a like at which run in
Linux is a free open-source cats are
resigning circuits also has a huge
community around you can basically go
from having nothing to fill the pool
circuit board and care
particular
process
construction technologies everything
you know if I'm a daddy and the air and
did that hundred times and something I
played around with very recently is
called clarifies learning image
recognition API that allows you to use
the binary classifiers trained to say
yes this is a hell and I built this
little light saber over the course of a
weekend with a lightsaber and Arduino
and I am you on the inside of a
lightsaber and we wanted to try and see
if we could you clarify its classified
time series data so there is actually
made for recognizing things and images
like you give it an image and it says
this is a cat these are a bunch of
people are sad people they were not
doing any time series recognition so I
was like I want to see if they can
classify this so what we did was we talk
later faded into a complimentary filters
so we took the x value the ex
accelerometer value-added them together
took the Y accelerometer gyro value out
of them together and then just use a
Python script and we noticed that we did
what we did swipes we did left right up
and down
down we are building a demo using swype
no way of the lights around and fight
back and forth images so we left right
up and down we made these plus each of
those whites are unique in their plots
every less weight this pattern where you
had like the blue line going up and down
on the red line going down in the
diamond shape it was a distinctly
different pattern so what we hope is
that we construct a set of binary
classifiers and then give it
data in real-time and then it tell us if
this is a separate over down and it's
actually able to do this and this is
like 20 lines of Python go from sensory
input from an Arduino doing like very
minimal
three and then training that end calling
their binary classifiers so it's like as
far as writing the code as we spent like
two hours trying to get a 266 module
never made it work but did work and we
were doing really really good
recognition rates we have like over an
80% recognition rate for all over large
so if you ever wanna play with her own
that's indeed learning for their eyes as
far as materials
everywhere i buy stuff from is and this
slide if you've never been to be
MasterCard dot com
like now it's you can get anything you
want master this weird alloys titanium
or stainless steel sheet extrusion form
fasteners deletions drill bits machines
motors everything it's a really really
awesome place in the ship super fast
sometimes they're more expensive than
other places but if you need a sheet of
6061 aluminum quarter of an inch thick
by foot by foot and you need tomorrow
master is where you go places for buying
like raw electronic 632 you know if you
want that on a date for that you can
like sticky USB stick into your USB cord
into in the program
holiness of you are aware he's already
but sell
nice development kits for both of those
actually have a good tutorial databases
sites they're really really great
resources we have a couple of scrap
yards
sometimes they're really fun things and
I would encourage you to find find one
around here you can get really great
things and good inspiration is amazing
what you can buy on Craigslist that the
last you are like my favorite to Chinese
websites they are they sell really cheap
like a three-phase brushless motors and
batteries and hobbyking actually sell
overseas but you like bikes is hilarious
website that sells like electric bike
components from China and their website
is pretty there is the translated
really funny but my friends and I have
order stuff from the site to its pretty
reliable I would say they are but I get
a couple of slides here
machinery and tools that I recommend any
specific questions asked me be happy to
give you my recommendations
these are things that I work with like
everyday stuff so I like to think that I
had over a period of time
experiences and information to make
suggestions about what you should just
interested in getting started in 3d
printing up me is like a fantastic 3d
printer $600 right now like crazy number
347 they must never break the same could
be said for this guy which is made by
the corporation was actually be thrown
away but he's still a pain sometimes you
can also other tools CNC routers there
are now almost entirely free printable
CNC routers and then you can use that to
make even more serious tools see make
three presence here out to make a wood
CNC router and
nice machine so there is a box
resins are really really nasty chemicals
sometimes and oftentimes those who agree
but looking for anything else going to
several places that have like the RXT X
in Houston Texas are used I don't know
if it was that cheap but all of the
drivers and software as far as the laser
itself goes I mean glass laser
technology if you exercise and it looks
like it has promoters and things like
that you can write your own drivers that
hasn't he later to buy it's probably the
free site guys have
$16
y GroES readers
they do you make the freemen of eighty
2020 it's really really really tired
myself who was 24 hours that's that's
that's magic once I get the cyclotron
bill so everyone for coming out of time
for you have it set out somewhere over
here and things or race cars and
spaceships