so
earlier this year
2012 actively targeting USD 14 and
financial impact is really high so we're
just making your consumer aware of this
car but didn't really give us all to go
on there how to write so you know more
or less familiar plain simple so it
actually has its own tax tax on its own
category and the scene and September
2013 no really knows how long
development cycle was no prior to that
words starting with the earliest
recorded infections of course this star
as many windows box is ann's
we're seeing with the way this press
been involving an advance in becoming
more complex I personally wouldn't be
surprised if
experience 2020
because you know
other part of the problem we're going
back to my place if this into this this
this pitches stories so
where we're seeing three million every
day the probability of getting infected
from tyson's twice as likely again so
again probably so it seems like this is
at least I should write but so companies
is that
they they have third party they're just
foxnews.com CNN MSNBC to see an ad
posted by third parties who also knows
as for yet another and we gotta get this
cat needing a waterfall advertisement
but your hands up on her agenda but
these advertisements have been done in
half and then screen and so now all of a
sudden you got wishes scripts on site
and so Google started getting a lot of
sites and you may have noticed liking
search results back to search results
perhaps I have a screenshot of this
actually do my presentation just added
but scripts right you're perfectly legit
but then all of a sudden this site maybe
they contain malicious
because there's some scripts there that
could cause so and so far only to 300
customers across the entire house movies
are passed down and asked him last fall
and then so in 2015 cedar keys alone and
help the health care industry comprises
about 36 percent of that don't be
so every industry is not you know the
findings industry manufacturing that's
being charged it thats why that is great
big money in this a single instance over
$250,000 and a million dollars has been
hey out
presentation and and I think that's just
in his room house peace to you know all
my drive over Knox was more has gotten
myself like Microsoft and something
about this you know why we continue to
allow consumers to be exposed to
something like this why we give them
better tools to try to have been to a
couple interesting lately what was right
here in Nashville but downtown
information system security national and
this year one of the key no said we need
to raise accountability of companies
around secure software development life
cycle low around
taking care of the consumer and this
kind of this kind of problem that to
that statement I think that a lot of
ways you know vendors can be doing more
to help the consumer brands so close
startup script a locker in September 13
when it is this whole family which
included Creek Bridge Rd
crowd he wishes you know otherwise and
you know it's this this week most of my
research and studying on this and has
been around for awhile but this week
Tuesday so this is changing rapidly and
it's continuing problem
here's a list of antivirus products that
you know pick up on this and most of
this detection takes place after the
Christian actions but done so you you
know that point and kind of you know as
well if you have it that so here's a
little chart you're asking about
millions and millions here so damaged is
a process you know handle the second to
your IP addresses four hundred thousand
times infections and thousand different
dollars so just looking at this guys
would wear some observations of these
observations about 3,000
polymorphic yeah so I took this to me
there were four thousand samples code so
yeah somewhat of a bus trip in that it
uses itself but that many different
versions had been previews right and so
that was wider and then going back five
addresses to be the elevators all the
actual physical so I think the number of
actors based on
so well
yeah the actual file types as well so is
based on you know the guys were doing
the moves on the ground and has been
from their observations been trying to
be just frustrating user so there's this
year then there's also this far down
here we are encouraging of the file
types then down your body to become part
of a large community dole so that when
the time came across as most recent
version has just been attributed to
frustrate these people as much as
possible so total jerk
so our communication and tour Swisher's
Torres it or not he addresses sandbox
where it is
browser variance covariance so is out
there now there's a walker that's out
there now and so it's just different
transmitter
desktop please tell me right so have we
talked about that there's there's a
magazine to you but basically a
ransomware as we can for open are you
know all the hardware itself we're
talking
so I don't get it you know they talked a
little bit about that earlier but the
number one factor
followed by explain their these
processes see screens this disguised
so you know how many people take resume
submissions by email because it's really
easy for someone just disguised there
there you know a lot to locker yet seen
as something else and by far he's
executables are screensavers that are
disguised as a dog or disguised and then
by default it was a it doesn't show you
file extensions right so you think
you're living in a file extension double
clicked on it you're running as local
admin now your user profile every locker
and then we'll get off get into some
were spreading from there here's a
little
no longer taking two populations and
smashing together yesterday somebody
down to one of the dogs like socks for a
dog to the point where they said will
hate me to pay us fix your problem
that's the point where users so they
could no longer so they see didn't
respond to the Remote Desktop Support
scam
so I'm sorry guys for ya no that's rude
over space this one so did that to ya
last three letters they have seen the
video file name would be like resume doc
docx and then but they're really
extension that's not a CER yeah yeah so
by default Windows doesn't show you the
file types
yes that's true
yeah i i process so even with checking
to see it this personalized
potentially infected machines with the
past like virtual box so that this might
be a part of that why I want to get you
to action
sometimes
what's the problem here
control your product key for the
encryption so this is for the ransomware
authors take some time now
and get you generous and send to be able
to you capture the products so and then
hijacked that try to do this so I'm
trying to go back and check he said he
is not transmitted clients or so
and try to pay that price tones so you
know log management confused attacks on
this activity and as well as relations
services anomaly detection can be used
to text you know where you can contact
just like the phone contacts we talk
about their
and interestingly enough the season
change so help your computer files help
your violence or something like that
which is another way of trying to throw
people were saying this and trying to
figure out how to text
against it and also away so we can all
learn on these files and then shut down
the system and network connection and
not exactly sure all of you can see the
source for a year or more specifically
skinnies and PowerShell scripts users
languages or directory
administration I personally like making
changes between Windows and Windows
administrator and what we can do our
show and some thats a result of things
like that and guys have heard me around
those tax and you're reading and then
because variance of 25 days and so you
know we're looking back and you know
cascade backup backup backup and that
you're right now we're so your your
go-to you were get my back is is is no
so scared because you don't want that
schools and he's a very high schools and
what I meant by that was more protection
complete right each case so not running
as local admin provide some protection
but only for others data because he
looks for a file path you can write to
the drive and he ever connected to the
registry and that's cool does expand and
then there's speculation about becoming
even more
so that running as local admin does
limit the scope or running as well and
it increases the scope infections all
the dayton was so we'll get back to a
date and does provide some protection to
talk about the invention is taking some
generation DGA to act against generated
johnny is right so it's ok this web
areas not something huge and then
locking that so that's
recommendations for some general stuff
over and write your own security
practices more specific stuff on the
right thing you've heard your security
guys you know you know you know things
like that you know I ever saw was
interesting because two weeks ago the
out behind came out and said just pay
the ransom because we don't really
really effective and we feel like you
have a good so yes we do
question I heard someone say yeah
alright so so don't want to fight the
man regular offline that we've always
always always trumps crash drive
reinstall
golden age and talk about what happens
if you don't and that is great service
you check out her home where I think
moves quickly so sorry
yeah so right here this is gold against
my opinion against this threat so check
out software restriction policies and
that stops and works as a first-line
defense here are great for his work that
out
us in this situation so that your
Dropbox Dropbox awesome
their customers affected by this day
actually into Dropbox says restore
previous because they didn't help that
they could restore its all enterprise
was backed up you know that was until
they went with that
and so would have to call to say that
this point I'm just click on their back
and several years synchronization closed
box so drop by for the keys from from
these websites like this fire I just
burst you interesting laid off last week
two moro crypto arranged for taking down
the new keys up there so if you happen
to save your encrypted data you can
potentially go upload the file to their
and discover that now so as a last
resort hang on to your date on like a
hard drive them off my hard drive or
something like that because you're
taking down
but black she is remote access to a
black she got was in the news about
three weeks ago he's not even 12 weeks
in prison twelve 12 weeks twelve years
in prison for spying on women's reserve
webcam using black she's road access to
those you got black shades got it
somehow got a bunch these women's
related emails or things like that and
he was fired on them through their left
hands and all she now and then got so
glad she's really really hard to remove
odors and black jeans and so late plate
say get your files off of their
can rebuild from gold as my
recommendation and these are going out
through the organizers so if you guys
look through these things
there but early reaction in his response
is essential that you can take an early
reaction disconnected from the network
to several clients hurricane season are
shut down your hard drive extremely rare
executables can be run user right locker
and then you can save your files and
that you know like I said law
enforcement officers and taking these
braids down all the time and so the
whole list of resources here with a
presentation and question is a real
quick love for the Knoxville area and
security LinkedIn Twitter and I'll take
you guys have now opened and certainly
huge fan of theirs in place since you
asked and reseller and it's not in their
personal use OpenDNS since they came out
they opened nasa's doing which is which
actually allows you to trace to their
architecture is gas has time to offer a
special on that the pay premiums so
check out open
this website