you
we said as
product today you may you might have
some kind of emblem on it but you have
like an Indian system mounted on on a
German car if you're driving a GM SUV
the four-wheel drive comes from us as a
company so you know I think we need to
sort of open these horizons a little
rather than you know everything at
compartmentalization because if we are
going to be silos in the industry I I
daimler and Ford are collaborating with
technologies or fuel cells you know they
actually have a company to get so
there's a lot which is happening which
is dismantling barriers so I just
challenge this point of view I'm not
talking about a new petition at least
and that was a question I have to think
about is how can we keep production and
at the end wealth in Europe am I in my
imagination when we think about I stay
with my battery example when we are when
we could make it and our suppliers and
manufacturers are trying to do so to be
maybe a little bit in front and if we
could make it to produce them somewhere
in Europe wherever there would be of
course that would be part of the
competition and of course it could be
also and should be also possible that
non-european manufacturers having ecards
with those batteries we are relying not
on borders I mean this industry is
completely globalized and i think it's
it's no way and it would not be a very
good idea to to draw that back somehow
mr. excellently I would like to support
my registered email
in this question because this is also a
question about the sources for batteries
for example where are the main sources
of lithium in the world my opinion I
think I heard that this Asia in South
Africa it means the source for a battery
production is not in here and one more
time we are in this point what is the
sustainability of the economics which
means the competitiveness of the
business has to be really sustainable
and has to continue to grow and this is
this fight against one more time this is
the question about the triad okay car is
the rigid global product you are right
then maybe some Indian products are in
in place placed in the cars ensure
public in Slovakia some Chinese products
are also placing these are real and
product which is contains some parts
from different regions but basis now we
are talking on about the European Union
competitiveness and this is the point
sometimes we say in Slovakia we are more
holy than Holly this famous regulations
when I to take into consideration the
whole co2 production around the world
and the big energy plants the energy
stations yeah they connect our cars in
the world is not the main one we know
about this all of us which means this is
a discussion about the competitiveness
and this is the thing about this and to
keep the European environment in very
healthy conditions on the other hand is
this a challenge which is good my Indian
friend Manjit Singh from DD he says
always there is no problem there is only
challenge and this is true nature and
therefore we have to start ready to make
some actions according to industry 4.0
but real this this is a big point for us
to be spoken about between associations
in the Indian Union one more time try to
protect not the market but protect the
brain sometimes a little bit that
basically
is the job of executives of German
automobile industry to protect their
business and to grow their business that
that's their job and if they are
challenged they need to figure out how
to deal with the challenge and is the
job of the government of Germany to mean
to make sure that how million people
don't lose the job so I don't view that
as a question about the borders our
political issue is just pragmatic issue
they have business which they have to
defend and grow and country has the
labor market which has two deafening
grow its it's simple like that I don't
view that political you're so right in
terms of the innovation if he saw it's
not the technology which is disruptive
it's the business model which is
integrating the technologies and putting
forth to the customer which is disrupted
I don't know how many of you guys know
this but I had the opportunity to visit
the assembly line of Tesla and the
battery size is that or double a size
it's that small which is building and
it's laid out seven thousand of them are
laid out on the base so that's that's
how he is thinking now it do you think a
block of battery or getting Elon Musk to
invest in in this geography of Europe is
is that a solution because neither the
capital has has today a color you know
dollar may be the one of the secure
currencies but to my mind the capital
will flow where there is a demand and
there is a business sense or a business
model which will produce an roi I mean
that's that's I am NOT talking the
political language you know there that's
totally different i am talking the
language of businesses which actually
contribute to value creation whether
it's even in the in the economy or to
the jobs
so if I may just do it on that also
regarding the legislation also to
country that would actually allow for
example self-driving car if I my own
more traditional note could have a big
competition what do you think about this
do you actually believe in no no car
accidents in the future i think in us
already they've been tested so maybe
your experience from us so you know you
know first of all nothing is perfect in
this world you know we spend ton of
money to make sure there are no plane
crashes and they are we spend billions
of dollars to protect nuclear weapon
nope no Clara basically power plants to
not have accident and they are so you
know expecting perfect technology is not
realistic and we have to set right
expectations you know while we have been
talking in last 30 more than 30 minutes
in conventional cars more than 10 times
size of these room people died why we
have been talking in the car accident
more than 2,000 people died during how
during the time what we have been
speaking that's the reality and you know
so driving cars has opportunity to
basically reduce that not have 1 million
fatalities per year maybe only 200,000
or hundred thousand days will be a huge
huge improvement it will save million
lives but the issue has to be addressed
very carefully because in American legal
system if you have holes at home
appliance which will cause 200,000
deaths per year will be not acceptable
so so basically society has to be ready
and an improperly under standard
phenomena and and government will need
to change the regulations to save these
million lives it should not be viewed as
this news are driving car cause 200,000
deaths no it's save a million lives and
current US legal system is not ready for
that European system is slightly
different and I don't know no much less
but you know this technology will not be
perfect and we need to deploy it we need
to save people lives and there will be
huge debates how to do it and you can
take two extremes you can be continuing
improving for example perceived safety
of this car by making them slower and
slower but at certain point it will be
inconvenient for people to use and all
the concepts utterly irrelevant because
it is inconvenient people will use other
conventional technology so because it's
coming in next five to ten years well as
I would say more of closer to five years
than ten years I think that this debate
has to be there and repair the society
ground and basically legislation ground
to successfully incorporated technology
because every new technology has the
resistance you know you know when car
started you know people has to be
running this flag up front of the car to
warn other people and society adopted so
I view that even bigger challenge on
society signed and the technological
challenge to accept that if I may jump
into this the concept of nobility is
changing and how a person gets from
point A to point B and back whether it's
a piece of work or play place of
residence in this obviously safety
becomes an issue and sustainability
where emissions etc become an issue so
India China is the mobility answer to
mobility is a hundred vehicles per
thousand in here but if we had that kind
of volumes
in India would be a totally different
challenge and probably totally not be
sustainable so the mobility concept
itself needs to be relooked for it is
going to be so the the master transport
systems need to be collaborative they're
also the industry four-point-oh pass
cards which are possibly going to about
75 million of them being produced as
hear that how many of them are going to
go to active safety systems passive
systems fewer them we saw that there was
we need active active safety systems so
at least the first step active system
where the vehicles start talking to each
other and maintain some some without
even the driver realizing another
another ECU or something takes over
twerking with with the commercial
vehicle the Daimler commercial vehicle
in India which is called Bharat bends
that trial is on for a for a safety
system and and the challenges in India
are totally different where you don't
even have the markers for Elaine so so
you have to adjust to the end of road
rather than the you know seeing the
divider in the lane so there are there
are these challenges maybe look at
mobility and not look at the auto set
auto set is one piece of mobility I
think and my friend who's just come from
Boston from MIT close to MIT this
disruption is already happening there
they have small pods I saw that in the
media lab they have small pods you can
sit in that pod go to a location and
keep that part there it sort of also
takes minimal space for parking and then
you can you can just keep doing this so
is that going to change how we look at
mobility is the mass system mass
transport system going to change the way
the mobility is seen so these are some
of the questions which are going to come
in mr. Cena may I ask lavaca is the
biggest car producer per capita I don't
have to tell you it is of course but do
you think we shall try to find a niche
maybe in with an automotive sector in
innovation for example by easing the
Delhi distillation with self-driving
cars besides spoken it before there is a
lot of layers of this question if we
talk about it say the production part
because matter dolly is really right now
then turn on my point of view the
biggest one till one supplier in
Slovakia thanks to the 43 car makers now
but fortunately the fourth one is coming
already which is a good message not only
for us but before all the economics the
neighborhood because really silica
silica stew a small country only 5.5
million inhabitants and this is a small
market baby do in the audience all of
you you know this may be the difference
between the third generation a
revolution because the digital factory
now we are talking about a 4.0 which is
the smart industries this is a
difference between those and main
difference in short to say is a to make
it more autonomous units which have been
had been managed in the past on one very
strong one tight structure we have a
good opportunity to be a developer of
such a autonomous units because we are
our core business is a stamping and
welding on asus it means that the welded
parts for a body invite cars we simply
build some parts of body of cars you
cannot see that there are structural
parts the skin pass they built the
producers OEMs by themselves because
there is hidden certain know how in
design
and for this we need to have a accept
the engineering design company also a
good tool makers good tool design
firstly than toolmakers optum a shin
then we do have also them some stamping
facilities with the latest sort of
technology for stamping transfer
stamping for example and so on also in
the meantime we are changing the
material from the steel for aluminium
very source of casting with aluminum now
the components are the compounds are
coming in place for a short future which
means and then we have to join somehow
the parts which we are used to stand
before and this all has to be done by
some unit which could work out to
animals but in the connection to the
previous operations let's say to the
standing Department to the logistics
intelligence and a next one after this
also to the store and to customer
because we are running just in time or
just in seconds in some some examples
which means we have a very good
opportunity to be in the process and to
be a developer of the real units by
ourselves and accept this standing and
welding is the biggest activity of
Matador we have a company in two min
surprised me I engineering which are the
guys this is a really start up this is a
question if the startups can do only the
guys from garage or if also the quite
big companies big means in the European
term small to employ more than 250
people which is also sometimes not
useful I think because if you have a
company you are successful then you grow
in the next two years you have you
employ more than 250 and boom you can
get cut because you are become a big
company this is the question but we
started with three guys checking the
system and now we have we employ about
60 guys there the turnover has grown
until 35 million euros in last 3 years
which is very good but basics is they
are young guys young people we take
every year from the universe
the best students here and it is in
Slovakia to be honest lack of good
people logoff and with those guys
redeveloped really the latest
technologies according to the automotive
industrial part we are not talking about
the human robots man half this is a
touch you should feel ya you should have
to see ya then you have to basically the
three abilities we do have touch because
is we are an integrator of cuca I've are
robots and last month we sent with salt
that the first implementation of the
Kookaburra robots to skoda which is
simply collaborative robots which has a
touch which fields and this is a part
that is more part of Industry 40 but
really robot is working in line with the
human with people and we are sure that
he cannot damage he cannot maybe makes
an accident to the colleagues to the
people one of the very very very few
implementations of such robots in this
region of 230 and the DC robots could on
it fear of commissioning I have played
with this robot HS because we put on
plays and digital camera it means the
robot is so he was a chance I almost in
a very few of a very few minutes yeah
but this is this is like a touch ok then
you see in this the naked me you can you
can start to think already right now and
out of this money but in the connection
to the other lines digitally the system
we should do that only so please please
feel free mr. dimma in the meantime I
would actually like to enable actually
devices and sends yours being able to
communicate with each other without
human intervention for example wow
that's that's a little question for me
being not a technician at all I don't
know maybe one more because that would
be also influential onus but of course
also other panels are more than welcome
to to comment on that I mean I mean in
general generally spoken of course
standards is always an issue
hmm you know a standard setter in our
industry in terms of industry 4.0 for
example when it comes to production we
have a vast number of working groups
really working on quality standards in
production on how can parts talk to
machines and how can be how can speed
this be safe and and and proper and I
yeah that's that's maybe my answer
actually that's yeah gentlemen's would
you like to comment on that as well yeah
I'm actually very fortunate my friend
his company called RTI called a little
diamond elation easier Schneider and is
in United States and basically Wall
Street Journal and Forbes they voted
this company number one influential
company for industrial Internet of
Things IOT and communication protocols
and meeting him once per month it is
interesting to observe that so what word
you can view that in too few layers you
know you have bottom layer which is the
hardware and it was highly diverse in
the past you had mips are and both pc
and so on but the cost is being reduced
by reducing number of the platform so
seems like two major platform Armin and
an Intel is emerging on the hardware
layer once you have father in place the
next thing is how it communicates the
protocols so the rest under decision
bodies were all big companies Cisco
int'l and son are participating Europe
is participating Europe try to create on
standardization body and but eventually
they merged with us one and this is the
communication layer that you have
standard ways of parts talking to each
other in predictable way and
already these standards are used across
the industries like GE general electrics
or you know US Army and and many others
components are using this
standardization software layer that's
the middleware and that the relatively
good standardized there was two
different competing platform but
you