market for example I have this small
paper good in bed my sides of it
slovakia the trading in currency euro
good news prospectors not required this
is actually all over european union and
it is it is obviously good news very
good support from the local authorities
friendly and that is also very necessary
prerequisite verbal confirmation enough
for our admission to the market
possibility of additional tab okay full
access of foreign investor o'problem you
with clearing through BOS euro click
funds investing bad news no possibility
over your bones like program in slovakia
if we take romania on good news prepare
again a prospect no problem with pension
funds investing bad news written
permission to the market necessary it
takes time and that depends on the
country from country to country
bureaucracy below specific parameters of
the one of issue need to be submitted
from the very outset a readiness of
placement participants to implement
additional filter training in euro
issues with access of other domestic
bonds rather than romanian government
bonds we tried bulgaria for example
there the situation is a little less
positive not so very good support from
the local authorities there is
information to the market necessary no
additional tab possible problems with
pension funds investing and also
unreadiness of placement participants to
implement initial and further trading in
in europe so obviously our
recommendation is to there is a need for
further unification of local
requirements for different groups
of issues corporate borrowers financial
institutions IFI obviously what probably
we see is a necessity is to make a
single list of available debt
instruments for raising funds on local
markets necessary to set up uniform
requirements for different group of
issues as well as for different types of
that instrument be bond program read
boards etc also there is probably very
strong need for unification of
documentary requirements for admission
to training because they all differ
requirements for authorization
translation into different languages it
all difference so let me stop right here
is actually administration it's a burden
also outside the US citizen to you and
Marcus wanted to touch something on this
one so please go ahead I mean I there's
two three things I wanted to underline
number one I mean I think we have and it
has been more or less echoed by our
colleagues we have a problem of
perception of capital so in so far I
think Lord Hill Jonathan hey liz is is a
blessing because he understands that I'm
in this market this single market is
European Union will not work without
improvement of the perception of capital
so this is a very good thing then and
has been said of course we and this link
state we have a problem in in the
politicians I mean in many countries you
talk to members of governments and
they're proud not holding stock because
sometimes it's easier and they don't
have problems that they don't have to
declare it prov course this is this is a
major problem because this will not
bring us where where where we should go
then we have a problem is risk of course
nobody and and and how to tackle risk of
course we're not saying we should not
manage the risk and nobody says we
should produce a subprime to of course I
mean I think everybody has had the
learnings but we have this problem of
the perception of risk we have it
as far as the capital market is
concerned we have it as far as
innovation is concerned we have it in
all aspects and if we don't overcome
this we will have big problem in Europe
because because we cannot exclude risk I
mean of course we have to manage risk we
have to assess risk we have the control
risk but if we want to exclude risks
exam time this is very much the thinking
of many policymakers in Europe I mean
this is the end of progress and and what
we will have to very clearly say as well
I mean this will be the end of wealth as
well and 11 other point I wanted to
touch upon is the financial transaction
tax because because has been raised by a
number of colleagues and just to
underline the dip in business could make
communities is heavily opposed to the
financial transaction takes it's a very
strange animal and because I mean of
course there is now only 11 countries
which for my taste is still way too much
supporting it but there are so many
question marks I mean first it's very
clear that it will before everything
raise the cost of Finance I hope that
the Google raise the cost of raising
finance is number one number two is
number two is it is totally unclear I
mean we had a situation for a long time
where at least the French were blocking
two derivatives now we have a very
strange situation where they in a
strange kind of package deal with the
climate change conference in Paris which
is something totally else they gave up
their opposition to this which which
made the topic move forward so at the
time being there is it clear and present
danger that this most forward but i
would i would totally agree with every
but everything which had been said I
mean this is a very dangerous instrument
because this is totally
counterproductive it can be very
distortive because it's totally unclear
if it is introduced how this would
affect those who are not participating
and it's it simply the totally wrong
message and will continue to fight
against it would you like widen it to
all the 28 countries or just get rid of
it completely Oh careful I mean I mean
the reasons the reason why it's not the
reason why it's not
proposal on behalf of the 28 instead I
mean all the others to not agree and
there's a clever countries around yeah i
can mention the right yeah but I mean it
oh it would only have I mean this is a
political thing this is a thing where
we're some kind of political punishment
to to to what is politically suspected
be happy happy financial crisis
apparently needs needed to be invented
but I mean if you look at it in
substance I mean this is very harmful
very dangerous and those goes absolutely
wrong glitch you mentioned risks I can
assure you skin in the game is the basic
principle for SDS securitization and
there will be a lively discussion also
on assets treatment and this kind of
digs and also on standardization so
because yeah it's a another subprime
eventually for many things please yes I
think I think it is right and it is
prudent to say if you are originating
business and if you're originating risk
and then you pass it on to somebody else
who does not have the primary access to
the custom and the business that you
keep skin in it yeah that you say you do
not sell off all of it but you have a
vital interest on the development of
this portfolio I think this is perfectly
right there is nothing bad in that the
brave hypothesis of this capital market
union is still the same as in many many
other aspects of the European idea you
just under commerce you just so to say
lift the barriers and then everything
which is in this proportionate disparity
will flow and will be all the same all
over Europe we have seen this in other
aspects of economic development that it
did not happen we did not see in
productivity we did not see it in wealth
development with we didn't see in
another aspect of you in this sense the
capital market union could be a bit
easier because money can move relatively
fast so as it was set rightfully by bama
hill if you have a saving mentality
versus an investment
tality the one will always keep sitting
on his on his savings book and the other
one will look for new investment
opportunities now especially an SME is
in a stagnating economic environment the
question is who is willing to give more
resources to allow growth now from a
bank perspective we have learned our
lessons still I'm fundamentally
convinced if you borrow money you have
duty to repay it yeah still there is
something like non-performing loans out
in the world and if you do your
financial modelling you have to assume
how much of your loans that you're
granting maybe will not come back and
this will give you the risk premium that
you should prudently charge that's the
one element the second element is how
much debt is good for a company relative
to its own risk bearing capacity being
defined by equity or any sub ordinated
instruments and here i will see a big
potential because many entrepreneurs are
stuck in a way they have invested the
money they have they make a moderate
profit but it is not enough really to
take the company further to the next
step and if your equity is good for a
loan of 100 it cannot be the solution to
try to grow by taking up alone for 200
simply because the correlation between
own funds and equity relative to solid
level of debt doesn't work and here I
believe that new instruments new
opportunities to give access also to
Central and Eastern European countries
to offer investment opportunities within
the EU to two areas and places where
there is more of an investment and
risk-taking appetite than on the savings
appetite is definitely worthwhile the
effort so I think still armed with all
the problems and hindrances I fully
agree with what you said it is a very
good and ambitious idea and intense
and it would be great to see it happen
before we move all anybody wants to ask
a question please the council will have
some decisions very soon banks
structural reform meaning that banks are
required to separate their investment
banking from their retail or commercial
banking proposals since this is such an
excellent battle I wondered whether
anybody has a view on that because you
could argue to some degree the same
things as what has been said about the
financial transaction tax so what does
this panel think about banks started
reform should trading activities be
entirely separated or say first of all
be forbidden and then if they are
executed a they're happened outside the
bank I mean if I may start from my
simple non-regulatory point of view and
then pass on to the really knowledgeable
colleague I take it as a valid political
desire to say if you have a banking
industry and you have people who take
their savings and give this to banks you
want to be sure that these savings are
protected and safe and nothing can
happen with it and you that you can be
sure that the bank at every time is in
the shape supervision and position that
that the deposits are safe now if we
look at the financial crisis of
2007-2010 twirl were moderately
capitalized so the risk bearing capacity
was relatively low and one of the
answers was to increase the
capitalization levels of all banks to
make them more robust second to that the
question was how transparent and how
predictable is a bank's balance sheet
and here I think it is a reality that
you say you have a part of the bank's
risk profile which is very predictable
because if you have a
portfolio of mortgage loans with an
average duration of 20 years there is
not much happening within the quarter or
a year and you can also see relatively
clear the activities in private lending
and in corporate lending but the element
which is very hard to follow also from a
supervisor's perspective is the whole
element of trading and investment
banking well within the limits that you
give yourself your risk profile can
change very much very fast so from this
perspective I have some understanding
that from a regulatory and protecting
intention you want to limit the
potential maximum risk a bank can have
in this component now and I think there
should be a must be an element for each
and every bank to have trading
opportunities because otherwise you
cannot fix your mismatch you must have
the possibility to trade currencies to
deal with your interest rate hedging and
so on so forth if you then say that can
go up to a specific level and this is
fine as a universal bank I think this is
a prudent way if you go so far that you
really say a bank that has on the one
hand the universal bank customer facing
with corporate and retail and on the
other hand a relatively big investment
arm that you really cut through and and
say this must be two banks I find a
relatively radical approach and and i
would rather expect that it goes through
the level of thresholds from the total
risk profile of a bank but that is my
view and happy to say that this
discussion for iphone is very
theoretical because each and every
thresholds which are under discussion
are way above our trading and investment
banking activities because we're really
in the down on earth real financial
needs and businesses of our customers so
it's it's no issue for us but the
academic discussion I find very
interesting
for this life not a banker but if i may
just quicker study i think it is
nonsense i mean mr. Lenk is very
Leverett very very polite and as we
talked about i think it is simple
nonsense because what what are we doing
today we're kind of regulating and
taxing down the banks to their almost
insolvency because we're taking all the
money that they might earn away we have
regulations to put in place more and
more and more that they cannot earn more
so what I what are we doing here if we
do the same thing now in splitting them
up into two different things it will be
even worse and then I mean you even use
the word forbidding trading okay right
right it's right but I mean this is a
crazy world we're living in sorry I mean
there's all the restrictions anymore I
mean this is going to bring the real
economy to an end as well and we should
we should always bear that in mind but
it's currently the politicians are
sitting there and say we are the saviors
of the world there has been this
incredible shift over the crisis from
the economy maybe sometimes dominating
too much I don't know the politicians I
don't think so but nevertheless and now
the politicians are very much kind of
driving back like the wagon by
dominating business in a way they say we
have been saving the bank we've been
saving the world because the world has
been would have been lost without us
stepping in helping the banks and buy
this perfect marketing what they're
doing here on the political side all
over Europe we we we simply are
forgetting and this is actually their
plan their forget we are forgetting that
actually the whole crisis comes across
because all of those governors all over
Europe have been spending far too way
money over the past decades then they
actually earned we have crisises mainly
now actually on the under debt credit
debt debt crisis were on honor honor
honor accountant levels I mean look at
Greece look at all the other countries
this is the main problem and we are
discussing
now having strong restrictions on banks
again please mark of God very briefly to
Kyle's question my first I think Peter
might be right that part of the ansible
on the thresholds but we'll see but two
karats question I mean of course the
question we are a business Europe asking
ourself is will display the fin aversive
banks help them to serve have the system
to serve the real economy better and our
answer is no so we don't think it's a
good idea because it will not lead to a
situation where we're real economy will
be supported bit and maybe just to suit
to you at this point BS are installed
and some people hope maybe it will be
drawn so let's see what BS are installed
now so Daniel negotiations going on no
yes on a council level no no definitely
not there is at least one issue I'll we
accommodate Vickers vice versa the rest
of the group for example and your
questions from the from the auditorium
ok it's not sure definitely may be
interesting to look at the united states
where for many decades we have the
glass-steagall act in place and then in
nineteen ninety nine which separated the
two functions that you've alluded to and
then in the late 90s 99 i believe that
act was effectively repealed so and how
post-financial crisis we went back to
the glass-steagall world so clearly in
the US i think people would be more
sympathetic to the idea of separating
the utility function of banking's or the
deposit kind of the the part that has to
be bailed out by the government if
necessary from the more speculative part
that is more involved in trading in
financial markets so i don't know i
wouldn't call it complete nonsense I at
least from the US perspective it
wouldn't be viewed that way but of
course Europe has its own specifics and
universal banks of a much richer history
here if I may touch on a couple of other
things that have been mentioned here in
the panel earlier
so one was that 2019 might actually be
too ambitious in terms of completing the
capital markets Union because we have to
harmonize all the laws insolvency laws
and the tax laws and the accounting laws
and I wonder whether we really need to
harmonize everything everybody talks
about harmonizing all these standards
but I think it would go a long way if
instead of harmonizing we simply
clarified which rules apply in which
situations so imagine a Slovakian buying
shares of a German company listed in
London okay they might be reluctant to
do this if they're uncertain about which
countries rule will apply to this
transactions a German laws is it British
laws is it slovakian laws if we could
remove this uncertainty this would have
to be done top down by simply specifying
okay we all agree it's going to be the
say the country of issuance or I mean if
that uncertainty is removed then I think
harmonization is not all that crucial
and from that perspective 2019 might be
perfectly achievable and one other point
that was mentioned here was about the
United States how the average American
talks about stocks after you spent five
minutes with them and that's absolutely
true and and the reason is pretty
obvious because for over three decades
Americans have had private pensions in
the early 80s private pensions were
introduced and now most people in the
United States myself included have a
have a pension and we we make our
decisions any any time at any point you
decide how much to invest in stocks
which stocks which bonds which mutual
funds you have to make your choices and
that is the best way to build literacy
in fact building up upon this I think
one one great thing we could do in
Europe after the development of capital
markets would be to develop portable
private pensions and this is something
that is mentioned in the in the plan
from the Commission it is the one point
I would highlight perhaps above above
others
because if you have first of all if you
have portable private pensions these are
vehicles in which people can save for
their own retirement wherever they move
within Europe they can take them with
them this would be helpful not only for
the development of capital markets
because this would boost the development
of pension funds which are key players
in capital markets this would also have
the benefit of enhancing labour mobility
in Europe which is absolutely essential
I mean we all know your Europe is not an
optimal currency area and having more
labour mobility would be desirable to
keep the countries in the euro and you
know having portable pensions would
would clearly go along your way and then
finally it would help with the
demographic problem which is as we all
know a very big problem in Europe so
this is this is this is one thing we
could do that would tackle at least
three major issues in Europe develop
capital markets support labour mobility
and and helps all the demographic
problem you all touch at some point the
the issue that you need to explain have
a plain or simple language or clear
language with people involved in the CMU
so maybe like to start it Carson how do
you educate investors retail investors
in our institutional investors about CMU
about the possibilities to make it
happen because this is one of the
crucial items on the on the shopping
list to make it to make it work or it
could have a very concrete and take this
example of this panel I mean I will not
let a follow-up to the bashing stories
who did what I've been serving for seven
years to the council and different
formation here a group a coffin
competitiveness Council and sometimes in
the year the european heads of state and
government Anna listen to you your
statement basically telling that their
self-perception of ministers is like we
are the saviors of the world I have to
say I've never attended a single meeting
where this was either explicitly or
implicitly expressed by any of the
ministers in no meeting whatsoever
but it's never telling what you are
basically telling us here how you look
at politicians what do you think about
politicians I think the story starts
with that it tells me that your
perception is completely different from
their reality I remember basically into
the four weeks in june july this year we
had 19 state secretaries meeting in four
weeks 19 state secretary meeting 10
ministerial meetings and four heads of
state and government meetings do you
honestly think these guys enjoy meeting
each and every day in Brussels or if
every second day and dealing with these
financial problems and then go out and
tell people oh we are the saviors of the
world I tell you starting with angle
America going down there basically the
vvv members list do the financial
financial media finance ministers and to
the States it is not a single person
enjoys this kind of exercise they do not
see themselves as savers of the world
but if the perception is like this and I
tell you from the beginning of the
crisis it was exactly the opposite side
of the minister side the perception was
this reckless bankers and from that kind
of attitude a couple of activities were
started that tells me there is something
wrong in the perception there is
something wrong in the mutual
understanding and it tells me people are
not talking enough and there they I have
seen many many sector since i'm dealing
with many sectors one of them and this
concerns me most is the financial sector
is extremely self referential they love
to meet with others because they can
communicate easily they understand this
but out to the outside world of
financial sectors they have serious
serious problems to communicate in a
proper way because they simply use the
same language the same methodology I
mean we can give an example financial
tax I'm a trained economist I share all
the concerns you have repressed when I
talk to people and visitor groups well
educated people they do not understand
the first argument that's how it
destroys capital market activities they
dispute this and not only them I
remember very vividly when we had a very
very long
debate in the echofon council where one
minister the formal swedish minister
unders book made the same points that
were put forward here and he was heavily
disputed by at least half of the
ministers in these meetings and well
you're basically wrong the perceptions
completely different our analysis is
different we come to different
conclusions so they are not the savers
of the world they have similar problems
and sometimes I wonder and this basic
you prove it perfectly how isolated you
are in your thinking when you talk about
the FTT itself the FTT is a price I
don't like it i would even share your
view don't you ever implement this but
the FTT was a price the FTT was a price
for some of the Parliament's approval of
the ESM you may say in the end okay DSM
is the european stability mechanism that
basically has programmed countries or
those who are not familiar with the
acronym so i have the same process
disease like many of us um this was the
approval basis the condition of the
approval in Parliament's to agree on the
ESN on the rescue mechanism so those who
are constantly against it should say
well the heads of states in government
the minister should have let fall in
portugal ireland and greece in order to
avoid the FTT I'm not sure whether you
all subscribe maybe you subscribe to it
and say well they have done too much
anyhow that's what i read from your
statement right now but this is a
political price you had to pay so that
tells me these things are not basically
isolated in each sector so the
instrument and then in the financial
sector it has a political component like
any political decision has an impact on
the financial sector and in my personal
view humble view is we do not have
enough bridges to communicate I know a
couple of ministers not the ones in now
in the council but the former ones they
are not experts they afraid of all the
terminology that people are using you
could have asked basically ministers
about secret ization what does it mean
and then the first connotation that
comes to the mind of ministers is this
was one of the troublemakers of the
financial crisis
and I've seen already responses we may
dispute I do not share this view this is
the perception so we have to start on
this talking on this in probably less
technical wave five ways it means i'm
not a linguist expert on this but we
have to talk more we have to explain
more we have to explain better and we
have to change the language technical
language does not translate into
understanding that's my my simple
conclusion and I see this even on our on
our side and I would not blame the
finance sector the political sector has
the same problem the same language
problem we are not investing enough in
this so it starts with language we
should invest much more and investing
language does not mean we translate
everything in 23 languages that's not
the translation issue there we invest a
lot of money by the way in Brussels but
you'll come from the council so how do
you change it actually you create like a
gazillion of papers like now just one of
the elements in this way i like the
in-form accounts looking forward to have
the informer council there in Slovakia
is we invite people to present their
views probably the a coffin is not
fairly progressed I think the
competiveness council does a little bit
better to have not let the technical
experts but experts from different
stakeholder groups to listen and to
exchange their views in these cutting
these luncheons this informal part this
part of exercise but it there should be
lets say much much larger larger scope
invite have dialogues have even more
dialogues don't restrict it only two
luncheons do this even informal meetings
in the informal a cough in Slovakia
could set an example I'm talking already
for instance with the Dutch presidency
as well the trio could set a new example
in this kind of dialogue and then the
other thing is basically encourage
ministers chair people of groups to go
out to reach out basically and not only
to communicate with in Brussels or the
indian national capital to reach our
your room dyson boom was here yesterday
i think gave a speech these kind of
thing we need much much more of these
activities from brussels out from the
institutions then go out reach out
communicate Talk listen to people try to
understand what they are asking what
they are telling and try to respond in
the language that they can understand
and not hide behind the Brussels
language war
basically where we have this well
trained phrases which is behind which we
can hide and say well we use them again
and again and again which nobody would
understand let's in thats my humble view
just on reaching out talking we need
more dialogue it does not suffice listen
to hide behind these let's say
individual silos and then say we are
right and the others are wrong to the
sectors respond just one sentence and
there's a lot of the same servant I
would agree with with with Carson I mean
on the FTT I mean you obviously know why
we have to fight against it I mean I'm
totally aware of the history we both
know that not all political prices which
have been given at a certain moment have
been paid in all directions so so
therefore i mean the debate will will
continue but on what you said about the
phrase a lot of phrasal phraseology and
the linguistic i would totally agree but
it does not only limit to the financial
sector i mean just to just do to bring
another sector you know the the the very
latest abbreviation in brussels very
much at the mode is the TC MV where
nobody knew what it was about two weeks
of no more five weeks ago but this is
the technical committee on motor
vehicles and now at the time being i
mean this is the abbreviation which is
maybe on the under on top of the hit
list and and and me myself in my in my
weekly discussions with my directors I'm
maybe seven six seven times asking what
the hell is this now so so of course
there's hundreds of these abbreviations
not all of them are avoidable but but
you're totally right them and we should
to great efforts in this way in this
directive because otherwise we will lose
the people but I still would like to
hear the answer because let's go back to
the bank to the capital markets Union
and investors future one because as you
just mentioned maybe there is a change
of culture moving curve from deposits to
investing so how do you do it we should
be in charge how do you do it how do you
teach and educate future investors how
do you talk to people let's say pension
in Slovakia or net
forever because you need these people
and to understand and also you said you
cannot expect a carpenter to be a
financial engineer so but you need these
people to understand this thing so how
do you do as a bank the reality is that
you have all kind of regulation on
various layers we have were active in 15
countries in Central and Eastern Europe
of course we have to make sure we always
observe the national regulation on top
of that we have to adhere to the
Austrian regulation since in Austria is
our head office and now we are under
direct ECB supervision so of course all
European regulation also has to be
adhered to this is a fact and all this
is fine as long as we first understand
the regulations and second they are not
contradicting and I think here is the
element where I fully agree with you we
need a clarity we need transparency and
we need the willingness to address the
contradictions because somebody is left
over at the end if I have a board member
who is personally responsible for
adhering to the local rules and I as his
supervisory board member tell him if you
do that I have a problem with my
European rules one of us we can both sit
there and look at each other and say
that we are said but we would expect
that one of the two regulators would be
ready to acknowledge and to start the
dialogue which rule now to change to
give the real economy in the group like
ours an environment where we don't have
to live in contradicting regulation in
this sense I personally perceive it as
positive now that for example the
guidance in steering and regulation for
the biggest banks in Europe came under
the regulation of the ECB yes it is a
hell of a work for us now to do very
fast the step from the Austrian
regulation to the ECB regulation but at
least I have one final boss and if they
say yes or no I know me out
no what I have to do and I know what I
cannot do and this helps very much and I
think in that sense it is on the one
hand important to bring this to the
surface it also needs on the other hand
effective power structures that bring
endless dialogues to an end and here I
think this is something where there is
also an area of improvement way too many
things end up in there we agreed to
disagree and we now have to find again
some pieces to trade and to balance
interests and to see how do we come to a
common denominator to move on into one
way or the other and I think this is in
my view what I will talk from the
capital market union that whenever in
doubt what should now be the direction
to take that this direction is
predominantly driven not by individual
political interests of member states
that it is driven by the intention of
the regulation what do we want to
achieve we want to give one unified
capital markets where people who offer
investments and people who look for
investments can meet each other in a
relatively simple format that would be
the perfect outcome and and I trust the
way you described it and you attitude it
that if this spirit is is realized then
finally the intermediaries as the banks
will have an environment in which we
know how we can function and finally the
real economy has a benefit because they
get easier access to to capital and end
to that so
you