dear ladies and gentlemen honored guests
it is my great pleasure to have the
opportunity to introduce the president
of the european investment bank mr. van
de hire enough braces have been set on
the EIB and the president and these
prices were well deserved vib has been
investing in Europe for more than 50
years and by volume it's the biggest
multilateral lander mr. who firmly leads
this institution even though that times
are challenging and it is exactly these
challenges I would like to highlight the
challenge is the DI be and by extend mr.
Hoyer will be facing in the near and
distant future it is hard to say that
with the implementation of the younger
plan the bank is facing an unprecedented
task the European fund for strategic
investments it's not business as usual
the long-term future of the EU rests on
the ability of the FSI to deliver on its
objective and that is to close the large
investment gap the work doesn't have to
stop there the FSI has a strong
potential to become what Europe is
liking and that is an instrument for
macroeconomic stabilization making the
FSI deliver is not an easy task to
handle but judging by the pace with
which the eib has been implementing the
FSI from setting up the necessary
processes to the pre-selection of
project i am happy to say we are in good
hands and with this thought I'm pleased
to give the floor to the eib s first man
ladies and gentlemen please well
come di be President mr. van a lawyer
thank you very much even Minister dia
vassal state secretaries ladies and
gentlemen excellencies it's a real
pleasure to be here at this very very
impressive conference and talk about
Europe's response to the investment
crisis this summit which takes place for
the fourth time has really become an
established platform to discuss the most
urgent political financial and economic
issues this year this year's event is
putting key emphasis on the assessment
of the used strategic agenda and its
implementation and this is just one year
after the well life began in you in
Brussels because we had an impressive
and different campaign for the european
parliament election and an unusual
procedure to get a new commission into
place and now one year is gone the
debate will focus primarily on
fundamental pillars of this agenda the
energy union the single digital market
the genuine economic and monetary union
the capital market union and the
investment plan for Europe but this
summit will also not fade out the
multiple challenges Europe is facing a
various fronts security crisis the
British of random and first and foremost
the migration and refugee crisis which
is which all took my belief will have a
great impact on the future of European
integration I say this in particular
with reference to the refugees crisis
where we see day in day out pictures of
refugees some of whom risks of their
lives and dramatic circumstances in
order to make their way to Europe but we
also see pictures of scenes showing how
people in Europe are reacting to this
challenge a challenge that many period
people perceive as a threat but which
also can be seen as a great opportunity
at the moment many questions arise
questions
which are present no answers is yet but
which urgently need to be answered and I
am sure that in this context and this is
still a little bit underestimated the
financial dimension will reach the
tables of the finance ministers very
very soon so we better prepare for that
in many cases this is already the case
but others seem to need more time in
order to recognize how deep the
challenge is going to be even this has
been already been said so often that it
has become common knowledge the fact
remains that we must first of all
eliminate or at least mitigate the
causes of migration in the countries of
origin and I know that this will take
more time but we must begin now wherever
possible people must get back hope and a
reliable perspective that the living
conditions will improve that there is an
economic perspectives in particular for
young people worse ensure that people in
their own interest feeling able to
pursue their way to prosperity and
freedom in their home countries in doing
so I believe that we must also
reconsider some fundamental pillars of
development policies I think it's time
for a paradigm change in development
policy needs to be pursued there but in
the activity is strong strategically
based or activity that is scared at
producing economic perspectives growth
innovation and jobs and in this case it
is true what we see in other context and
I will come back to this today again
it's quite obvious that however your
ring out public budgets on the national
on the International European level
public funds will never be enough to pay
for the challenges that will have to
cope with in the next year's also in the
question of migration but also the
question of climate change all's in the
question of the attainment of the
sustainable development goals to which
we just described a few weeks ago in in
New York we must also strengthen the
transit stage especially turkey in the
Western Balkan countries for example
within the Western Balkans conference in
the
with reverse important conference and
the European Youth Employment initiative
we have two instruments that can be
effectively combined in the Balkan
states I remember vividly the Western
Balkan summits roughly eight weeks ago
in Vienna when Chancellor Merkel
reminded herself and us that two years
ago when she started the Western Balkan
initiatives then called Boland
initiative at the same time she started
the youth unemployment initiative
together with president along did a few
others and by now we have made
experiences with that last year long eib
invested 14 billion euros in loans to
SMEs and mid-caps and into vocational
training facilities and similar
institutions in order to produce
perspectives for young people and this
is an instrument that could not be
married with the Western Balkan
initiative by offering similar
activities to the Western Balkan
countries as well whose leaders very
clearly said what is needed because one
of them put it in a picture and said
well I have the problem that my people
my young people without orientation have
three choices either be a resilient
seated out and wait for better times
takes a lot of patience the others are
tried to move north immediately to this
country to Austria to Hungary to freedom
to Germany in the third group he says is
turning to the Islamic state so there is
even a security and strategic dimension
in this question so we have to give more
attention to the situation in the
Western Balkans and we try to be helpful
there the situation varies currently
driving young people who have no
prospect of finding work either north to
Sweden Germany Austria and Luxembourg
for instance or it is driving them south
into the Islamic state and here only
determined action against the lack of
prospects will help and thirdly we must
overcome the challenges within the
European Union the first thing is the
countries of arrival and let's be honest
we have had a blind eye for too long on
the situation on the southern shores of
the European Union there we must create
an infrastructure
that is fit for human beings and can
cope with a humanitarian as well as
administrative tasks but the same
applies to realize what the job of
successfully integrating people who are
able to stay in those countries actually
implies for us the eib has approached
the eco-friendly finance ministers
council eight weeks ago on this issue
and will continue to make offers how we
believe we contribute to at least help
on the financial side of mitigating this
huge problem ladies and gentlemen the
Tetra summit is taking on also this
challenge and I welcome this very much
because I'm fairly sure that we will
never be able to cope with that
challenge without arriving at a European
solidarity based solution ladies and
gentlemen let me tend out turn to the
agenda point where i'm proud to kick off
the discussion europe's response to the
investment and innovation crisis i miss
admit that the organizers of the Tetra
summit last year had a very good hand
the main aim of the conference was to
address europe strategic growth a good
gender a challenge was which has not
lost in relevance the fact is that for
decades we have been living off our
capital the result is an enormous
investment backlog and need for
modernization since the beginning of the
financial and economic crisis a
pronounced lack of investment has led to
a further reduction in productivity
growth which was in any case already low
in all major sectors of the economy to
put this into figures last year in
preparation for the incoming new
commission we made a series of studies
addressing these issues because we
wanted to know how big the gap is
between what is really needed and it
what is out what's actually planned in
terms of investment in Europe let me
just by a few figures illustrate how
dramatically we in Europe are lagging
behind total investment is Europe Europe
is still currently
about fifteen percent under the level of
2007 it was not a surprise that in 2007
it dropped surprises that it said low
for so long now compared with the 2007
peak and I take out the bubble for
instance in in in real estate in Spain
before 2007 that of course contributed
to this high figure but there's only
very small part of the explanation but
compared with the 2007 peak the volume
of investment has followed by
approximately four hundred and thirty
billion euros in absolute terms and at
nineteen point three percent of GDP is
around two percent below the long-term
average of a little bit above twenty one
percent investment to GDP in the field
of energy and energy efficiency alone an
extra 100 billion euros or so per year
would be needed on top of what is
already envisaged and to fill the gaps
that still exists in Europe's transport
infrastructure another 50 billion or so
a year would be required this would
include investment in expanding
intermodal transport and environmentally
sustainable mobility in urban areas the
urgency the urgently needed expansion of
broadband networks and maybe even more
important of data centers the amount
required comes to 55 billion euros a
year and one issue that people tend to
neglect or overlooked to upgrade
Europe's water and sanitation systems
including flood protection to meet
demand it is estimated that a good
additional 90 billion euros a year will
be needed if you add this all up you end
up at the figure of more than 500
billion euros per year and the point of
reference for all this is not some dream
of environmentalists or people who love
trains or people who are just becoming
aware of the quality of the water pipes
in our countries the benchmark is the
decisions of the European Council the
target set by the European Council for
2016 or for 2020 respectively so it is
what we have agreed to pursue and not
something that we now begin to dream
about
to make things worse this investment gap
is complemented by an increasing
innovation gap that makes Europe's
position the globalised world even more
challenging it just two percent of GDP
expenditure on research in the EU is not
only one percent below the three percent
target laid down in the Lisbon agenda
but also more than one percentage point
below the levels achieved by other
competitors and if you take the top crop
of them the United States South Korea
Japan we can save that only for one and
a half decades we are trailing by one
point five to one point eight percent of
GDP behind their expenditures on the
knowledge economy in general if the you
wanted to achieve with three percent of
GDP target for research and development
which by international standard is by no
means excessively ambitious we would
have to invest another 130 billion a
year so I'm convinced that we have a
specific problem in the field of
digitalization Europe's strengthen the
future where we determined first and
foremost by our ability to make up for
lost ground in terms of digital
technologies and services but even when
sure to say that the lack of
competitiveness in many parts of Europe
has also been caused and then reinforced
by the fact that in the past we have
invested far too little in this field of
course structural weaknesses in Europe
play a crucial role in explaining the
low growth but lack of investment in
this highly competitive sector is also a
significant factor also he just a few
figures the data traffic within the EU
on for communication for the internet
for video has increased by the factor of
five since 2008 if we fail to make the
appropriate digital infrastructure
available to accommodate this rapid
growth we shall continue to fall even
further behind in terms of global
competition we must realize that in
addition to the issue of training and
human creativity the data issue will be
the key factor in the future to
successfully withstanding competition in
the field of digital infrastructure
alone we must invest 30 billion a year
more that we are currently investing and
this
includes not include yet the
consequences to be drawn of the ruling
of the European Court of Justice on the
question of digital safety digital
security and because there we will see
that another major challenge facing
Europe is the fact that it does not have
the necessary data center cape capacity
we are constantly reminded of this in
directive and data protection incidents
if I might call them that occur
ultimately they take place maybe outside
Europe and make it impossible for us
Europeans to exert any influence because
we ourselves are not in a position to
make appropriate capacity available
that's another 25 billion euros
incidentally here is not only a matter
of investment but also of creating the
necessary framework to complete the
digital internal market it's a little
bit absurd there is probably no sector
in the world which is by its nature more
transnational than the digital world but
when it comes to the reality in Europe
we find out we are far away from that
just think that only four percent of
digital services are of a cross-border
nature four percent in area where like
few others national borders can easily
be overcome provided that this is
accompanied by an appropriate regulatory
framework which we do not have because
we had 28 of them or the United States
of America is one and you're India has
one and the China has one so this is key
obstacle to Arkham return to
competitiveness excuse me ladies and
gentlemen my aim of enumerated all these
figures is not to draw a pessimistic
image of the future of our continent but
to draw attention to this development
and to show you some means of how this
development can be turned around leading
to a more optimistic scenario after all
these figures one effect this event is
if evident this huge investment
requirement cannot be met with public
funds alone when I met jean-claude
Juncker in the spring of 2014 when he
prepared for his bid for the presidency
of the European Commission he was
preparing his program
which would present to the European
Parliament but I told him what I've told
you today basically these figures were
just produce or found out at that time
he asked what needed to be done to get
other vicious circle of low investment
slow growth high public expenditures in
what role the EU bank could play in this
respect well we all know that eib is not
the panacea and shouldn't try to be and
the abbey activities cannot substitute
the fundamental precondition of having
the Member States implementer reforms
for achieving an investment friendly
regulatory framework but the Ewbank can
support economic development within this
framework and can identify barriers to
investment and we are trying to help
vice president of the Commission
Timmerman's on this crucial challenge
the Commission will have to meet in the
next year's we do this by also by
mobilizing private capital on a large
scale to in order to invest into good
and viable projects in the real economy
because the EU bank is the crowding in
bank that's our job we are sometimes
accused of crowding out the private
sector and whenever I hear that I go
after it and try to to remove the
problem because public bank is not there
to crowd out other banks public bank is
there to go into gaps which the market
doesn't fill because they're basically
market failure then it's justified the
public bank in my conviction always must
justify its intervention what makes ya
bees activities so crucial is the fact
that we can leverage scarce public
resources and hence maximize their
effect by blending them with private
capital and focus on loans which means
that we as a year as a bank actually
would like one day these loans will be
paid back this is why an experience
which really knocked me off when I came
to this Bank four years ago I had to
explain rail ministers even members of
the European Council that we are not a
grant organization we are a bank we lend
money and believe it or not we want to
have it back with interest so it's a
different model than being a development
agency I mean this is sometimes very
relevant when we do our business outside
the European Union because they're
sometimes the exit communication is we
come over them to programs
out of our huge pockets no no it's the
basic idea is to provide loans to be
paid back and the headline is lending
which is not unusual for the bank for a
bank blending that is the better use of
EU funds and advising that is closing
the gap like sometimes exists between
ambition and capabilities we have a
catalytic role through mobilizing
private cattle but this is not enough as
there is abundant liquidity on the
market anyway I mean the situation when
yeah we went to its shoulders four years
ago and asked for a couple increase was
completely different today liquidity is
not the problem Europe is drowning in
liquidity but what is needed is an
increased risk taking capacity of those
who must produce the projects that will
bring our economies forward it is about
mobilizing capital in order to invest
into projects that require an appetite
for taking risk that currently many
private investors do not seem to bring
along and this is not a criticism this
is a just a statement of facts because
what do we expect for instance when we
clean up the banking system which we
have done which the finance ministers
and the European Parliament in the other
they have done in the last year's
successful in my view but that also
meant to reduce the manoeuvre space of
the banks to come up with new loans and
this is produced problems in many areas
we do not have these problems only in
crisis countries take for instance the
effects of the banking regulation on the
SME loan activities in the Netherlands
one of the richest countries of the
European Union in the Netherlands you
have serious problem in getting alone as
an SME and therefore there is also a
challenge for us so when we talk about
crowding in private investors for
investments in Europe that due to market
failure will not take place with the
support of a public bank then it means
that we have to address the question of
risk and going on to risk is nothing new
for you
be risk-taking is an inherent part of a
bank's activity and we have started to
increase our risk taking capacity 15
years ago when introducing the bucket of
the so-called special activities at that
time there was 250 million euros this
amount has increased in recent years to
over five billion euros per annum and
will with the support of the FSI the
younger plan will reach some 20 billion
euros in the next year's this is the
basic difference the ability of the EU
public bank to increase its activities
in on the higher end of the risks scale
and since then we have introduced
several new blending instruments for
certain sectors but as a bee is not
lending taxpayers money but needs to
collect every single cent we lend by
collecting private capital from the
financial markets worldwide almost fifty
percent by the way from non-european
sources the writing of the bank is of
fundamental importance making the
ability to increase the risk taking
limited in quantitative terms the
volumes we are talking about are between
60 and 90 billion euros per year which
we need to borrow on the international
capital markets and that requires the
confidence in the trust of the investors
and the investors will fade away quickly
as soon as we produce the impression
that we support projects which are not
sound economically viable and
sustainable so this is the the tension
you always live in between being a
public institution based on the treaty
of rome or nowadays the Treaty of Lisbon
but on the other hand you're extremely
market and competition oriented because
you have to stand the competition with
other people who would like to get these
60 to 90 billion from the investors on
the international markets this is the
point to a rock Lanka and myself agreed
to enable eib to take risks on a much
larger scale and if you want this was
the birth of the investment plan for
Europe or better known as the the young
Kaplan and from the start jean-claude
juncker brightly put the lack of
investment and decreasing
competitiveness of the European unit on
the top of his political agenda
for the new commission term with the
investment plan for Europe we now have
an instrument in place to address these
issues and this is not limited to FC to
the European front for strategic
investment it's the best known part of
it which by the way despite its name
it's nothing else than a managed account
inside the bank backed by a 16 billion
euro guarantee of the EU budget and five
billion in cash from EA be in order to
increase the risk taking capacity of the
bank as just described so sometimes I
need to tell investors fund managers and
others need to disappoint you first
because the fund is not a fund and the
European Council in December 2015
explicitly changed the conclusions of
the European Council by making clear
that it is to be to be an integral part
of the EU bank and not a separate new
bureaucracy in Brussels what is new with
the investment plan for Europe is the
fact that now we can take more is on a
broader and larger scale furthermore the
provision of an EU budgetary guarantee
for this purpose remains represents and
that is my view the most important thing
in the medium and long term of the
development of the European integration
process the fundamental paradigm change
in the use of EU public funds away from
grants and subsidies in favor of loans
and guarantees now you can say we are
talking about 21 billion as a guarantee
buffer out of a and 16 of them out of
the EU budget for a period of seven
years where the EU budget is more than
1,000 billion euros but still it is a
very important first step away from
these subsidies thinking in Europe and
towards a more mobilizing activity
thinking via grants biovar guarantees
and loans I believe that every economic
experience shows that somebody who is
given a loan with expectation of paying
it back probably has a wiser idea for
the use of that money then if
he or she just gets a lost grant
although I see there are institutions
which depend upon grants so we have to
be very careful part of the money coming
from the EU budget comes from horizon
2020 this is in many cases very very
important research money that will need
also in the future so the trick for the
people in the commissioner and the
Parliament will be to get these
relatively limited front of 2.7 billion
euros out of pockets of the research
budget of 80 billion for seven years
where they do