good sir what does it
we're often ladies and gentlemen we are
following up on a discussion which was
related to industry 4.0 words part
industry which of course is very much
related to innovation our panel which
was called embracing innovation will be
actually chaired by by me and Peter
balik I'm from the ministry of economy
of the Slovak Republic and our panelist
in today's discussion related to
innovation policy and the role of the
government and of the whole ecosystem in
supporting innovation will be shall mr.
Frau shall friday from israel who is the
former deputy chief scientist of israel
and right now he actually completed work
for the world world bank as a consultant
in in poland we have Tony the coaster
from the European Commission working for
the director-general at DG connect he's
responsible for digital single market
and innovation policy in the European
Commission we have Adam class who is
from the US but originally he's from
Canada actually he's from Canada living
in the US he's working for a well-known
and globally renowned investment company
a private equity investment company KKR
and we have mr. radko mutapcic in in the
panel as well who is the director for
center in Eastern Europe cloud services
at Microsoft he is based in Croatia and
our distinguished guests will today
speak about the role of the government
and the role of the commission also in
supporting innovation Slovakia is
definitely perceiving the fact that
innovation is very important and we
started at the Ministry of Finance one
and a half year ago an initiative which
was focused on supporting startups and
startup ecosystem the strategy has been
approved by the government this year and
currently in the role of the Ministry of
Economy we are working on the
implementation of the strategy
at our Department of innovation and
business environment at the Ministry of
Economy we are focusing also on other
issues related to innovation and it is
the support of cluster policy and the
creation of innovation hubs creation of
connections between small and middle
sized enterprises between corporates and
universities we're also focusing on a a
supporting entrepreneurial education at
very early stages of education from
elementary schools in cooperation with
the Ministry of Education and we're also
focusing on smart industry or industry
4.0 which has been discussed in our
previous panel by our director general
miss Susanna and I ova the status quo in
Slovakia is that Slovakia is lagging
behind on innovation however we are on a
right track and the government has its
priority to support innovation and to
support innovation in the industrial
sector that Slovakia has been very much
focused on in the 90s and before as well
our role as the government is also to
cooperate as much as possible with the
private ecosystem and with universities
as well we created several platforms
where we are discussing our policies
that we are proposing together with the
members of the Slovak startup ecosystem
of the Slovak innovation ecosystem and
we are getting feedback and advices from
them on what should be done in order to
foster innovation in Slovakia this pppp
dialogue public-private dialogue has
proven to be very effective and we are
coming up with very interesting measures
to support innovation now I would like
to actually call up our distinguished
panelists to talk about the innovation
policy and their point of view on what
the government should do in order to
support innovation and what are the
police is that we should focus at in
order to boost innovation in our country
so first of all I would like to call mr.
shell fry right
to touch upon this point and talk about
his experiences from Israel thank you
very much I would like to begin with the
expression that has been mentioned
several times too many times in fact and
it's called innovation so we have to
dedicate to three minutes to this
expression saying what is it all about
first of all you should know that
innovation is an expression that can be
measured and in fact it is measured it
is measured as a result of several
factors that are together affecting
innovation if you are familiar with the
EIS European innovation scoreboard you
can see year after year we're all
European countries are in this range
there is a right hand range which is for
the leaders of innovation countries like
Switzerland and Finland and Sweden and
so on and on the other hand you have
countries that lagging behind and needs
a lot of improvement one of them for
instance is Peter mentioned is Slovakia
which is not doing so well on this scale
of innovation once we understand what
are the factors that can affect
innovation and how are they measured we
can speak more fluently and openly about
the innovation because if you want to
increase it we have to understand what
factors are composing this single word
innovation you have the World Forum in
Davos which issues yearly comparison
between 140 countries as far as
innovation is concerned and again you
will see where your country is Slovakia
well and us and so on and so on so when
we are discussing innovation we have to
remember that it is immeasurable a
factor that has to be improved here in
Slovakia I thought to myself what are
the reasons that Slovakia is in a
condition that it should take some
measures to improve innovation and we
can discuss it for the vol de but one
thing that can be seen immediately is a
R&D to GDP ratio which is a measure of
the generally speaking the amount of R&D
dedicated relative to the GDP you have
the target set by the EU for 2020 of
three percent it was a target set for
2010 and it wasn't achievable then
another set of values well put on
nevertheless in Slovakia it's less than
one percent to be more precisely for
2012 it was point 82 which is really a
remarkable low figure so at least you
have to do it quite relatively quickly
and at least to pass the one percent
barrier which may lead to higher figures
if not the three percent is not
achievable it's a dream but still you
have countries like Austria with two
point eight percent and you have other
countries that you can follow up and see
the figures that are much higher than
the one prevailing in Slovakia I would
like to conclude my introduction by
saying that as far as I understood from
yesterday discussion money for R&D I
speak is not in short it's available and
the question is how to use it in an
efficient way and we will
disqus on that issue little bit later
thank you for thank you concluding with
money we I would like to ask Adam to
touch upon what is maybe the role of the
government in your perspective as a
representative of private equity
investment fund what is the role of
corporates what is the role of the
government how should we enhance
innovation Thank You honor to be here by
the way as the token North American on
the stage so I'll try and be boisterous
and annoying and loud but I'll speak
actually more from my private experience
than my job so I I've had the privilege
to live and study and work in a few of
these you know hubs of innovation
kitchener-waterloo in canada where
blackberry came from which used to be
cool Silicon Valley now obvious reasons
gothenburg for for a year london went to
business school and sort of a financial
and and other types of innovation so
what I've seen work really well as far
as government fostering you know is is
providing the right infrastructure to
foster innovation the right environment
so you need to create the right climate
for an ecosystem to thrive right it was
looking recently at this trying to
educate myself a bit on on the situation
in Slovakia correctly right so it was a
KPMG report we looked at recently sort
of the state of of Slovak startups and
if one of the charts that stuck out of
my mind was you know what do we do
really well in Slovakia and and the the
number one thing would be really well is
technical experience and technical
know-how we have very strong
universities and a very strong workforce
on the technical side what do we do the
least well was sort of business
intuition which struck me and I don't
pretend to know the root causes I do
know a little bit of Slovakia I'm
married to Slovakia so I've spin
quite a bit of time of the last 10 years
in Slovakia so a great affinity for the
country but just based on some of the
things we've talked about the last the
last few days it would seem to me that
some sort of a you know a formal
fostering of linkages between your
strong technical schools and strong
business commerce institutions which
could be private or they could be there
could be educational institutions so one
of the questions would be you know does
the Slovakia have you know a strong
leading business education system in
place now both for youth as well as for
mature folks who want to go back to do
say executive education learn about new
venture development startup education
and and so one of the ideas would be to
foster on that standpoint strong
linkages between the technical schools
and and the business community and or
fostering a strong business education
environment most not all but most
successful startups have a strong
business person aligned with the strong
technical person right whether it's
apple or hewlett-packard or monocle and
strong sales marketing business mind and
that business intuition it's it's it's
actually interesting because if you look
at that chart again of what's lucky does
really well you've got that you've got
the technical side that's there but if
that business intuition side effect
charts true then you need to beef that
up so as far as a government policy
perspective which I don't pretend to be
an expert on but that would be at least
where my perception of where the focus
should be we actually mentioned a very
important point the education of
business or the business perception
among the youth here in Slovakia based
on our assessment that we were doing
last year before we came up with the
measures in the strategy to support
startups we came to the conclusion that
actually the entrepreneurial culture is
quite negatively perceived or
entrepreneurship as such is negatively
perceived here in Slovakia and of course
this is something that we cannot really
affect by
a quick win police's we are trying to
focus more on educating entrepreneurial
education in elementary schools as well
as well and we are in discussion with
the Ministry of Education do you think
this is the right direction for the
government to get involved in trying to
switch the perception of
entrepreneurship some of your great
young entrepreneurs and incubator
mentors over the last few days you've
got there out there right so it's it's a
sense of getting them in front of people
get them in front of the students get
them in front of the youth get them on
TV and I'll get get get some of your
strong potential and over leverage them
over expose them so that people get a
sense of you know the you know these
people are here you've got great people
that have come back to selected recently
from experience abroad and they want to
build their businesses here so they need
to get their stories out and and other
people need to look up to them as role
models just very information if you
mention the word entrepreneur in sand
exactly so we need a new word I can toss
out our chip Andrus in the Department
for innovation you know Kofi ilysm for
animal thank you Tony you are
representing the European Commission
here of course we are also in discussion
in our roles in the ministry of economy
with the european commission we are
working together on the digital single
market strategy that you are an expert
on in the european commission this is
definitely a regulation that has the the
the rationale for the European member
states to implement and to try to have
to take away the barriers between the
European member states so what should be
done by slovakia by the member states in
in in this regard and how should we
foster and help the european commission
to integrate the digital market in
Europe
a very many thanks for inviting me here
and I mean before we really kick off and
say what what Slovakia has to do and
what European Union has to do and so on
I think it's good to take a step back
and just simply stand still for a second
but why this all matt is wide as
innovation supporting startups R&D
entrepreneurship why does that matter
and why does that in particularly matter
for Europe for the moment and I think
because we always take it for granted
but it's important to to remind that
also that we're still in a very
complicated economic context there is
many member states with so high
unemployment levels in particular
amongst young people there's a risk that
a part of that generation may be facing
major difficulties in accessing the
labor market and that's why this is
really important I mean in the first
first and foremost it's about creating
possibilities for employment for youth
employment and of course it's also
better or industrial leadership and
that's why we're focusing a lot on that
I mean we're doing a lot in terms of
data to our R&D programs where there is
now much more focused and direct funding
to to the startup community and to
member states slovakia is is a candidate
for that even supporting them in setting
in setting up schemes for the national
start up for for creating the right
environment for the national startup
community but also as you rightly said
it's not just about supporting directly
through money it's also about creating
the right the right environment and
wired european levelled we need to talk
about a digital single market in the
first place one because yeah probably we
have now pretty well functioning
single market in the physical world so
we've done away since 1992 with most of
the barriers some keep on popping up but
then we try to eliminate those as well
but what we have we seen happening in
the digital world is that you know there
are new sort of technologies which
allowed to identify in the digital world
when normally the factor distance
doesn't play a role anymore but you can
sort of re identify where a customer
where a person is coming from geo
localization basically and so we see new
segmentations of the single market
happening in the digital sphere and that
is frankly it's not acceptable not just
because in the European treaties since
nineteen fifty-seven we have this
ambition that there should not be any
discrimination on the basis of
nationality but also because this
fragmentation of the single market is a
major handicap for our companies the
large companies maybe think they can
benefit from it sometimes but for
start-up cim which have to be globally
competitive this is a major challenge
there I i we want to contest that we
have a tendency to talk ourselves down
there is a very vibrant startup
community in Europe there are a lot of
places Berlin London Gothenburg they've
been already named but also Slovakia
there is and you quoted the figures from
from KPMG there is a vibrant startup
community forty percent of the more
active in the sphere in which I work
namely the the digital sphere so there
is no lack of that but still startups
because of this setup have a tendency to
only address a national market from the
outset which you know in the best case
is 80 million customers in the U which
is a single market of 510 million
customers of 20 million companies when
you talk about the b2b sphere and we're
not addressing it it's being segmented
so that we have to get rid of that's a
program which we have it yours and a lot
of that will come true also through the
to the for adoption during the Slovak
presidencies we count on your support in
that framework as well so there will be
legislation but there is as you said
there are also things which the Member
States need to do it at their level and
and we can we can consider I wanted to
ask you about how should Slovakia
position itself during its presidency in
the agent of digital single market how
can be collaborative with raping the
European digital market well as I
explained the Commission will propose a
series of legislative steps and notably
on banning geo-blocking on reforming
copyright in the European Union those
are important measures complicated
measures because of course behind that
there may be some vested interests and
therefore it will be very important that
we have to support both of the European
Parliament and from member states and as
a presidency you of course play you will
have a critical role to play in in
conducting those negotiations and always
they said maybe always reminding your
fellow your fellow member states in the
in the Council of Ministers at European
level yeah that there may be some vested
interest but there are maybe some
overarching economic and political
ambitions which we should have in Europe
namely that ultimately this is about
fostering as i explained growth and jobs
and investing in our future thanks radko
you are representing a corporate one of
the biggest companies in the world that
used to be maybe a start-up 40 or 50
years ago how are you cooperating with
with the innovation ecosystem in the
center and eastern european market and
where do you see the role of Microsoft
in collaborating with different
stakeholders of the of the innovation
ecosystem yeah thank you know
well I don't think Mike's which is
really different when you say how you
see the Roloff I think the companies are
now growing in the in a different way
that they used to like 20 30 40 years
ago right so they also need to build the
kind of ecosystems and platforms to try
one right so Microsoft spending I think
around ten billion dollars every year on
research in the development but still
they cannot grow only on that right so
on new venture second system today and
it's shifting toward the new ventures
right so when you look at the big ones
and how they grow from the open
innovation perspective for example
they're actively looking at the markets
and they're researching you know what
should be our net next step what should
be our next growth should we continue to
for example grow on windows and office
right or should we grow on something
else which is I'd around today cloud
computing and services related to this
one that's that's a huge step for for
the corporation it's hard to do that
only from the internal perspective and i
would say that a lot of them actually
are looking into the ways how they can
interact we do have a corporate programs
i think they have a bigger one every
corporation have something like you
heard about them Microsoft ventures or
google ventures so you're actively
sourcing you're looking for the deals
you know where you should invest and not
necessarily only in the field of your
expertise or what what your business
current business model is is looking for
so you can see that especially in
finance worlders but they're not really
men dating that the stuff which is
growing from there should we be used or
deployable the only now in my our core
business so they will look really openly
into you know what is the next because
they're building a bigger ecosystem than
this one what's missing from that
perspective is that you know we should
encourage more from the different
perspective including policy perspective
that bit organizations are spending more
time and money into something like this
so that we have you have this money
which is coming from the from the from
the government's from the European Union
which supports innovation and growing
the entrepreneurs you have
our venture capital which which is
currently I think the biggest driver
from that perspective even if you look
at the numbers it's not it's still still
public and then we should increase also
this spending which is coming from the
corporate ventures that's calling this
way so that people can have more options
you know how they can grow from there
how specific company look at this one
you know it's not that its massive it's
supported its policy helped through the
policy all through some regular
regulation it's it's things to do I
think you have to do something like that
and I think you know people should look
at every single option in from the equal
pay for equal perspective right
depending on where you are at your
growth stage for example I was you know
that everybody is using that example i
was in Estonia I was talking to their
tech Nepalis it's a bigger because the
kind of incubator technology incubator
over there and they have this huge
really nice chart of how we are
supporting people in the you know in
their development phase and I was
surprised at least that was the first
time when I was started to or the idea
itself right so they're investing into
primary schools or different incubators
trying to support the innovation
creation right they're not really
thinking like oh now I have the the idea
and now i'm going to you know invest
into idea or at any specific stage of
the startup so there's a lot of options
and I think the corporations are really
looking into this one not that actively
that much big ones for sure but there's
a huge potential especially in something
that because medium sized organizations
which could use area we have a press
conference with the minister and
representatives of the the spp this
lower gas corporate and a know about
hackathon so it's going is working
together with the government and other
private stakeholders of the ecosystem
where corporates are defining their
specific challenges that they would like
to resolve by very innovative and
creative ideas that they would like to
get from from the ecosystem does this
create actually value for corporates
radtke what do you think decide
to type of the approaches so I would say
it's so obvious you want to think like
this like hackathon but I in general I
think that a lot of them are really open
they don't even define their own
problems so we had a Microsoft we had a
lot of opportunities to basically use at
our different programs that basically
used something some generic worldwide
challenges like you know worldwide
issues that people have like I don't
know how do you how do we feed people in
30 years from now there will be like
forty percent more people on the on the
earth so how we support that with the
technology actually it's nothing nothing
really connected to a Microsoft for me
perspective okay what would be the next
you know business case for us but I
think it's a valid question and we can
help with the technology and money to do
that and just to you know to finalize
when you when you look look we're
currently we are contributing the most
from that perspective actually it's a
foundation it's billund and Bill Gates
malindo Foundation which is trying to
solve those issues so how you use that
money to really impact and solve some
some of the things for good you know
let's let's eliminate some of the
diseases that's a millennium challenge
right Megan Adam you wanted to comment
on muskrat or how does Microsoft
delineate between what internal so if
you're going to do a hackathon how do
you decide sort of what is a public need
that you're okay you know in a hackathon
environment versus things you want to
keep frankly closer to the chest yeah a
bunch of years ago when I when I first
time visited research in the development
that say arms inside the organization
right I was surprised they actually
they're they're they're actually
functioning the same way as you would
expect some external incubator or I'd in
a research center would would do some of
them from the open perspective some of
them just like died in a day they
research and they die and some of them
became like a global hit some of them
some of them are integrated with
specific knowledge for example Israel is
having great startups which we also like
from the perspective of are here are
algorithms and some startup elements we
can we can use and build on top of it
but
you know those things stay inside the
company because you pretty quickly you
see what will be the next growth but
some of them go outside people go
outside and then and they start their
own startups they continue to do work on
them or you know what because it doesn't
make sense so you just grow them right
and then you make some of the things
public and usually I'm I'm surprised you
can do that when you look at the
corporation's go and research keepers to
the outside world you know how many
people from Microsoft our research
division actually work with the
university's off you know and contribute
algorithms and so forth and you can see
there's a lot of developments over there
so I think it's a nice balance how do
you do that how you are coming from a
country which is a top-performing
country in terms of innovation and
innovative for many countries here in
Europe but also else in the world you
are actually a best practice in terms of
venture capital system yeah as a small
country such as Israel how to boost
investments how to boost venture capital
how to boost business angel activities
in the innovation ecosystem I'll put it
this way and to increase the involvement
of angels and VCs etc is a long process
and I am sure that at least part of the
audience here asking themselves okay
nice talking smart guys but what will we
do tomorrow morning and tomorrow morning
I mean in a half year time as I'm glad
it and I said what I saw yesterday and
understand that first of all the
Slovakian people generally are very
smart knowing all the tools available
say I have the money to perform what are
lacking is immediate actions that should
be taken and this immediate actions they
should be taken can start tomorrow
morning for instance if you take
countries like Finland and it takes
Sweden etc you see that they have
established and agencies
to this capable of direct support
industrial R&D on top of other missions
for instance teka see supporting if I am
not mistaken the university's their
project etc but I am concentrating on
industrial R&D and this is something
that probably your ministry should
exhibit solving all internal problems
that you have here with other formally
no way private entities like this
business association and then the other
ministries etc tever it's something that
can be solved and the politicians on the
higher level agreed that these steps
should be taken so why not to take this
opportunity and put it into practice by
saying that I mean that you have to put
an agency capable of doing the whole
inside outside that don't care but
putting it together putting the
decision-making process into practice
providing the assistance to good
projects according to the evaluation of
course and benefit from it for the
economy of the country
you