Thank You vice president for setting out
the European Commission's and your ideas
on what is the unfinished business in
the economic and monetary union I'm
pretty sure there's a few people on the
panel who maybe have a few things to add
and just before I start with the
questions I will very quickly point out
that you have the opportunities to send
the opportunity to send me questions
which I can then posed to the panelists
and you can of course at the end also
ask your questions in person and also i
have a question up here that would be
great if you could answer because i'm
very interested and also how people
beyond the brussels bubble and beyond
the sort of sphere when where these
things are discussed actually feel about
how to take our monetary union forward
and it looks at the level of risk
sharing and financial risk sharing that
we will need in the eurozone going
forward I'm very much looking forward to
your answers and to start out with I
would like to ask Peter Casimir because
I think we really need to get an idea of
what is the national perspective on this
because it's the Member States and
especially the finance ministers who are
feeling the impact of the crisis and in
Slovakia and for you as the minister
what has been the most annoying aspect
of monetary union in the most recent
years and what would be the best way of
fixing it as part of an overhaul of the
year of the monetary union expect but
the first of all I would like to touch
you up you know remarks beggin because
you you complain that nothing happened
were last that was the boring year
whereas you know that way you have been
redone it Dow colleague Greek colleagues
so that's that's the reason I but that
wasn't that was until August a fearsome
okay so so now we're in November so
talking about the so experienced you
know that we joined the eurozone and
first generate 2009 so and from the bomb
there's currency union has been
experienced the most severe economic
crisis in its history so which in and of
itself it's quite annoying you know so
it's it's froze from the beginning yeah
but we are lacking we are quite proudly
still we are proud member of the
eurozone and maybe somebody remember you
can remember that it was not so
difficult to become the part of this
club you know and especially special be
for crisis so so the crisis was really
wasn't something like eye opener you
know for instead showing that the
eurozone is is not so robust pillar of
economic stability as it's supposed to
be you know and so as a result of the
situation for country like Slovakia is
that it's a little bit unfair be the
country no like why is which is doing
which dude a fiscal and structural
homework at the national level but the
responsible policy choices are not
rewarded economically enough because
because the real situation the situation
into in the reason as a whole it's
translating on transporting this
troubles to the growth of GDP to the
problems with with labour market so not
reward but punishment sometimes you know
so and as it's also very difficult to
find that in such situation know so yes
I remember I remember times that we have
we have been the penalized for the
membership in this club you know so so
it happened but it's almost history I
hope so because the eurozone like like
well this mansion response to these
challenges
and this response was was very useful
but I think it was the crucial we have
to that that we the acting instead of
reacting i think this is this is our
thing it's very important to mention so
also what we should admit finally that
there is also the institutional problem
which is incorporated darkly in in in
this currency union and which is not
going to which requires a systemic
solution and talking about a systemic
solution so then we have to go back to
the economy to admissions and you know
the chemical literature has been saying
that it's quite easy and that the I've
just work what the currency union cannot
function effectively without the fiscal
Union you know this is just this is a
theory but this is all maybe this is a
reality so which kind of fiscal Union I
mean is I'm in the fiscal capacity to
cushion the Sharks symmetric and
asymmetric that's that it's also easy if
you want you because you call us to
irritate so I rotate it so thank you I
mean that's a very interesting idea this
embrace of fiscal Union from a country
that is usually one of the Hawks one of
the strict ones one of the ones
everybody needs to be responsible for
themselves so about his view does
Austria one fiscal Union and looking
back at the last few years what has been
the most annoying part of this euro zone
for you and your country and how can we
fix it thank you very much
because it sometime not easy to work
there you can see how this group your
group is working and we are all
interested point of use to develop
monetary them to a better design for
growth so if i look back for my period
for about 14 months being mr. violence
across yet but looking also back to the
history from the point of austria we can
say that for austria the membership
Union and in the Eurogroup success story
so it helped us very much in our
competitiveness all over Europe and it
helped us very much enlargement of the
European Union is the neighbors face
time so we can finally important files
so something is going very well and
something
better is empty hopefully so of course
we have to do some things in another way
we do it now that's true one of them is
as I always say in Austria that is also
for the Austrian government not only for
the European Union we have sometimes
problems is between the competences and
the responsibilities who has the
competence and who is responsible and
it's very necessary what what is
Dombrowski said that the five presidents
report should help us to solve this
problem in the future the second thing
is the monetary union had brought a
plenty of advantages it's a monetary
union is a good idea for a unified
Europe but it's true that the community
and the processes and the state of work
in the community can be optimized so the
second thing which is a problem for
developing and finishing not unfinished
finishing the EMU is the question of
speed so we are often discussing for
years about a problem but we cannot come
to a result so one of the problems is we
have too much announcement from two
layers result and we should change this
and the hope that the five presidents
report will help us also to load this
problem and if you look to special
problems we have done a good job and in
something we have done not so a very
good job so let us speak about short
well very quickly about Greece there we
have lessened learned the third program
has more front loading before paying the
money as the first and second problem
club program together we have lessons
learned and that's good to do it
we have of course the problem that we
have some some discussions about the
government's in between the institutions
so sometimes I'm really astonished if
the president of the Commission peeps
have some information about the media's
about for instance deposit scheme or
other things that should be discussed in
between the institutions and therefore
the governance of the institution has to
be a question for the future one thing
which we can explain which is a problem
for us remember probably out of my
colleagues on the panel while it's
dubrovsky spoke about a very important
thing that's the banking Union it's one
of the really success things with the
Union did but they're the first step is
that we have to implement the BR rd
regulative and it is hot has not been
implemented by all the member states
eight of the Member States are lagging
behind but we are discussing about
things like the next pillow-like Deposit
Guarantee Scheme which is the third step
before we have finished the first step
so in my opinion we should learn lessons
make the first step then the second and
then dessert and they did not desert
before the second and the worst that
could as so end the discussion about
this probably unfinished Union another
example is breech financing we discuss
about many many times about the bridge
financing for the single resolution fund
and we have not a clear decision up now
maybe we get in on monday or tuesday
that could be possible but there are the
problems we have also in the aspect of
the image of the european union of the
commission and of course of the member
state what is the result
we have done probably some good things
but maybe not not fast enough let us
point out one of the Commission's
working program is paps that's very
important for the developing the
European monetary union because there is
the connection to the fiscal question
which is very important and if you look
how the world is changing in online
business and other things in in special
problems we have in the fiscal system
it's a good that we do is but we have
probably 22 if all these issues more
speed and we should remember if you
build a house every brick is an
important break but first you need a
good fundament it's not necessary to
build the chimney before the fundament
and therefore I hope that we can be as
successful as we have been in the crisis
I don't know who say did I think it was
really loose ain't never waste a good
crisis so let us learn out of this
crisis but as the Member States the
European Union has probably the same
problem that we have not changed from
Ede from administrating in a very good
way the crisis to design the development
for the future and that's the question
if we want to be successful by deepening
the European monetary union by
transferring the files president report
we have to remember that that is
necessary that we are thinking about a
vision for the future and not only
administrating the status we have now
thank you I'm Edwards kick Luna what's
the view from from Malta your this small
island a little bit separate from the
rest but you've still been paying for
all these bailouts and over the last few
years what has really gotten your gold
what is the thing that you don't want to
deal with ever again and how can it be
resolved well first of all I thank the
minister and then the organizers for
inviting me over here it's very very
important conference and let's take them
one by one I think for Malta and for the
Eurogroup in general it was has been a
very positive experience we're learning
step by step and it took the it was a
very testing time I must say and just
like a boat and its crew will be tested
during a storm not when it's a you know
very calm seas and it was quite stormy
it's agreed I mean we have never seen
anything of this sort in our own
lifetime and because we recall before
the crisis thinks in the European were
becoming a bit boring talking about
thousand and ten giving lip service here
and there so actually the this
earthquake this storm really shook us up
and started going and thinking seriously
about the limitations of the hour our
structure how strong it is or how weak
it is to extend these types of crisis
and and and shocks I if I were to so
that you know that's that's the positive
side and we are still working progress
we we must admit there were times where
where embarrassing for us I mean they
could have been done better and which
experience doesn't have this resource of
incidents I'm in the Greek case really
almost got out of hand and it was
difficult because it was also
unprecedented but I think looking
overall if there were two areas where
you you could have done better and
sitting back now and the first one is
that you would expect that since we're
not going on our own we
bus a group and we're talking about
coordination then there should be
coordination so our response to the
crisis unto the death surprise the
deaths crisis was that everybody does
the same thing and this is what was not
needed it was needed from countries like
Greece and and other indebted countries
but it shouldn't have been overall for
everybody because this is the kind of
aggregation and economics they tell you
about if one thing is good if everybody
does it it's not it might not be good
and the fact that surplus countries
joined indebted and deficit countries
together and and and deflating so to
speak on on on a large scale put us
where we are now that that that we can't
just get out of this deflation we should
have had a more much more intelligent
and and because the experts were telling
up they were only we had our eyes open
and listened we you know the surplus
countries should have looked at their
own responsibility which would have been
different but what we did where we
looked at the most indebted and weak
countries and continued pressuring them
pressing them but there was nothing done
to those countries who could have
increased demand to compensate and we
must recall that especially the
Eurogroup we have a fixed exchange rate
we're all in with one currency so all
the models of the IMF which they've had
so many of them all the crisis since the
second world neo since the setting up of
the aisle I am f2 to date we're all
about countries who had a floating
exchange rate in the main and and so
while they were consolidating on inside
they had an external sector which
compensated and that we were fixed so
that is one area the other one it and
still with us is that the Eurogroup or
the European Union is not as good for
multitasking in other words its
concentrate on one issue with the
exclusion of the other and
you know this happened in our response
to the crisis but it's also about for
example the taxation methods they are
very important tax evasion tax avoidance
is the time and so on and we're all for
we know that it will improve the the
exchange of information would help also
the monetary union itself but not to the
exclusion of other things they should
have been in parallel and not you know
all the competitiveness issue where
we're paying lip service and we're off
our radar screen so most of our energy
and correctly was about banking
regulation and financial regulation and
then coming up and topping it with the
banking Union which I agree with my
colleagues that it was a success and and
we just hope as it has been done in our
country we've we've passed all the
legislation regarding the BIR d and the
IGA will be approved in a week's time so
I just wish my colleagues would join and
make sure that by the first of January
all the countries will have the
legislation in place because this is
very essential we've been successful and
therefore we want to at least complete a
very big but successful project and
bring it to its implementation but going
on Pitou the competitiveness issues are
now being discussed now I mean we're
about seven eight years you know after
the crisis and and this was our weakness
I mean the European Union and the end
and and the Eurogroup in the
international arena is is is is is
telling and and and it is now that we
reckon we will support you know
competitiveness Authority the fact that
if our own fiscal councils will be like
internal auditors with the fiscal board
being the external auditor then this is
something which is very very important
it will strengthen as a minister each
national ministers hand in controlling
expenditure and keeping to the focus of
deficit well overall there were a lot of
positive things the country specific
recommendations at least in our case
we're just on the dot these were the
kind of agenda any government should
have taken and it was very comforting to
see that the Commission was seeing the
same view of where our strengths and
weaknesses are so overall we've learned
few lessons where the worst is behind us
and we should now build on these on
these on these experiences and
concentrate on competitiveness you know
we cannot delay this such an important
topic because we're always repairing
repairing here and patching there but
overall are we in a good strong position
to race with other regions with other
blocks and come to the front as we
deserve well we've got a long track to
go there and control you're actually
German but you I think you've been in
Brussels for long enough to take sort of
the view from the top and tell us what
is the one thing that has really annoyed
you in the last few years and what is
the one that policymakers the people up
here in the panel who are taking
decisions on our monetary union what is
the one thing that they should really
focus on now and get done well thank you
very much first of all for for this
question I mean of course for for me as
a as an economist and the thing tanker
we are having a good crisis because
whenever there's crisis there's demand
for for expertise so so in that sense
I'm not unhappy about it but of course
of course I'm unhappy about let me say
really three things the first one is
that GDP performance of the euro area is
about as bad as it was during the Great
Depression and I think this is this is
not a very good benchmark against which
we are measuring ourselves so certainly
need
improvement I'm also not happy about
youth unemployment in the south of
Europe I think it is at in acceptable
high levels and let me also quite
frankly say when you go to to Asia and
you know that Asians are very polite and
you know if even Asian friends tells me
when will you Europeans finally get your
act together you sort of fear that also
the rest of the world sort of once the
eurozone ready to to move and to succeed
now my take is that the eurozone is not
an equilibrium we are unbalanced and you
know one of the things you learn when
when you go to graduate school it's
called by levis law you know so vilas
theoretician it's the foundation of new
classical economics I mean what he
basically says is if one market is not
in equilibrium then there must be
another market that is also not in
equilibrium and I think that's why we
should be extremely cautious thinking
that the disequilibrium that we
observing in the south of Europe just
concerns the south of Europe it does
concern also the north of Europe so I
think the imbalance in one part of the
eurozone is also an imbalance in the
other part of the of the eurozone
especially in the north and I think
you've talked about this advert I mean
that day is certainly the the issue of
adjustment in the south and there is the
issue of adjustment in the north and I
think we should not belittle belittle
that that problem it is about demand it
is about wage developments which
developments have been far out of line
compared to productivity in the south of
Europe in one direction but they have
been foul out of line in the north of
Europe in the other direction and I
think this is this is the fundamental
problem and that needs to be fixed and
it's not an easy thing to fix now let me
quickly quickly go go go on to other
points that that I think do you deserve
attention I mean one is of course this
whole discussion on banking Union
I think banking Union is of course a key
a key project via google have been
promoting and emphasizing the importance
of that project throughout the years as
early as aspect in 2007 some independent
economists even emphasize this before
the euro was founded now I think we
should be aware that at the moment it's
not finished yeah and that's why I think
it's a good thing that the European
Commission tries to to continue pushing
that agenda but of course that agenda is
an agenda that has to do not just about
risk sharing but also about risk
reduction and I think that's certainly
correct I mean we cannot have a banking
Union where you know basically the link
between banks and governments is only
cut through a sharing of risks on the
liability side I think we simultaneously
will you will have to make sure that
become the banks in their assets I'd
become more European meaning they should
have hold less over in debt of the
country in which they are located which
probably means introducing single
exposure rules and ensuring that banks
and other countries are actually ready
and allowed to buy sovereign debt from
from banks in in ephraim from
governments of other countries now last
point is still this this structure
structural reform discussion
competitiveness discussion I mean I
totally think that we need to we need to
take we need to take a global view on
this I mean we we are certainly not
performing as well as we want it is not
a reason to be happy if Greece improves
from number 72 number 60 on the global
rankings of competitiveness it's still
not enough I mean we need to if we want
to have our living standards we have to
become better in in what we are doing we
have to improve our education systems we
have to have better administration let's
go
option and so on and so I totally I'm on
the side of those demanding a very deep
deep structural reforms in the countries
that that perform the worst on those
corruption governance indicators and so
on this this is really an agenda for the
future thank you so not one easy quick
fix not surprising I guess and it seems
to me that in in these presentations and
also yesterday from the Eurogroup
president there were there was some
criticism of the European Commission
hence York shelling just mentioned that
actually maybe we're moving a little bit
too fast on the deposit guarantee scheme
maybe we need to implement the second
leg BRD which is which which allows the
investors in banks to two forces the
investors in banks rather to absorb
losses first before governments come in
and actually put money into these banks
that that needs to be completed first
then the your accrued president said
yesterday that the the European fiscal
board that the European Commission just
proposed a few weeks ago actually falls
quite a bit short from from what had
been in the five presidents report maybe
it should be given more power and more
more rights to assess national budgets
and then of course the multis finance
minister just pointed out that actually
maybe we need to be looking at the
economic policies of different member
states in the aggregate that not
everybody cut spending at the same time
which could be one of the things that
this fiscal board could do and so
vice-president Dombrovskis is the
European Commission may be moving too
fast without too much without enough
coordination with the Member States or
are you in fact doing what we've just
heard from from mr. shelling that in
fact we need to move fast and always
talking talking talking is actually just
holding us back well i would say on
those issues as regards economic
governance
it's extremely difficult to find a
consensus for some countries European
Commission is a ruthless enforcer of
austerity and we heard some views on
this for some other countries we are far
too generous in applying rules are not
strict enough we are not credible enough
in enforcing to build and respect same
with proposals on deepening of EMU some
countries are saying it's all too little
too late we must actually move right
away to stage two in five presidents
report and and and be much more
ambitious some are saying let's take a
break let's implement what we have
decided in recent years and we'll take a
look and so we're trying to find a
balance between those different opinions
and it's clearly that will not be
universally uploaded because they're
very divergent views among member states
so how quickly on which items we should
move but then on some specific elements
you raised for example on European
Deposit Insurance Scheme this is exactly
what I outlined also in the introductory
remarks that completing the banking
Union first means that we need to fire
finish what we have started including
full transposition of BRD including full
implementation of deposit guarantee
schemes directo including ensuring
bridge financing for a single ization
fund if we are to successfully move also
towards European Deposit Insurance seem
and of course all those issues are very
much linked and also European deposit
insurance scheme which is basically this
element of risk sharing also should be
accompanied with a further work in terms
of risk reducing in terms of market
potential
works on the risk exposures and and so
on and so forth so there we need to move
on parallel on in both those directions
so and you can use other examples in in
other areas that it's not so easy to
find a consensus because opinions vary
quite dramatically among a member state
so what has been outlined in fi
president's report that it has an
ambitious yet realistic approach and
that's more or less what we are falling
to through also in our proposals mr.
Casimir I think by calling for fiscal
Union you are maybe if you just look at
the stages and the five presidents
reports skipping ahead quite a bit and
just to draw in a few questions from the
audience what exactly do you have in
mind when you think of fiscal Union I
mean we've spoken in the past about
having their small incentives for
structural reforms we've spoken about a
full budget we've spoken about an
unemployment fund what do you have in
mind what kind of fiscal Union for the
eurozone definitely we are not talking
about the Minister of Finance because
you know sometimes we are just beginning
from the structure who will be sitting
where but but you you were surprised
with that that how can so hawkish
country with the hawkish Minister of
Finance be committed to the fiscal Union
just explain we are hawkish to the
virality to them to the rules you know
and honestly I do believe in in federal
future of the Europe that's all despite
of what what mr. vice president
described as how it's how is difficult
to communicate inside of Europe
sometimes we are Italian family that's
that's true so this is a this is a
reality and talking about the timing you
know it's also important I can imagine
and the difference in our
in August with with with grease that we
are in integration we are speedy
gonzales you know now so because this
this could be completely different
situation in different environment but
this is history now and the reality is
that we have to be cautious and we have
to really to focus on on the work which
has been already done I do agree with
hans-jürgen on this for example on this
bridge financing I mean breadfan passive
financing of resolution fund and and I'm
really angry with with certain
colleagues because you know you are in
the country where the BRD was a full
integrated in the legislation eage
ratified we be a country with ex ante
deposit scheme fund we are a country
with with real resolution national
resolution fathom it as a backstop I'm a
real money not just leverage in or
something virtual so so it's it's quite
difficult to explain to two people in
this country there are others you know
where where they don't have even this
excellent of fun so with with empty
pockets no so this is this is a
difficult so the first of all homework
do your homework and legend we can to
finish this this case on the deficit
scheme for example and talk about them
the fiscal Union so i really i don't
think that the jurong can reckon on in
its present form in the long term and BK
what we need it's the creation of
country country cyclical buffer which
would effectively administer temporary
fiscal transfers to cash in macro
economic shocks what it mean in such
instrument can take a form of common
european unemployment insurance scheme
for example
pyaar karle Padawan raised this issue
during the tongue presidency during the
informal a cofee this is a quite
realistic plan and could be
understandable to Europeans because this
is a really crucial because it's
sensitive issue the redistribution and
to transfer between between countries
but I think it could be quite visible
and and understandable to the people
this is a crucial so this is a this is
just a sample and talking about the
symmetric shocks so then it's we almost
have it so it's this this axon so it
could be the permanent FC so this is
just about the this could be the vision
you know and okay we need to be
pragmatic rome also was not built in a
day this timing I know that it's I think
it's it's right time to irritate us what
should do it's the role of the
Commission for example which is the role
is coming with the Commission is coming
with very enthusiastic plans so Alan
this is a good work has been done on
this issue mr. shelling coming from one
of the countries with the lowest
unemployment rates in in the eurozone do
you think your citizens understanding
we're very well what it means to pay
into a common unemployment fund would be
happy to do so and hence support a
country like Spain where unemployment is
above twenty percent or like Greece oh
no they don't will understand so it's
not explainable in a straight way you
have to give another way of explanation
if it is necessary the second thing is
there was no critics at the Commission I
think that the Commission makes a very
good job the problem is that most of the
member states don't understand that we
are Europe we are part of Europe and as
vice president of vodka say we have so
different meanings and positions where
we can find no consensus
it's always the same way the Member
States cannot find the consensus and and
the the Commission has made it in the
wrong way so that's always the same
discussion let make it clear it's not in
this way we are Europe we are member
states and we have to bring in our
positions and most of the content the
Commission brought in the last year
since the new commission is established
we are very very good look at the
banking Union look at the discussion
about the capital Union look about the
five presidents report that's the right
way where we can bring together a better
results than we have it now the second
thing what is probably have to be done
is how we can find a better economic
coordination for that would you say how
we can raise the GDP that's very
important for Europe because let me
point out just three figures Europe has
seven percent of all inhabitants of the
world of all people of the world of
seven percent from Europe going down
because other countries have a better
reproduction rate as it though the
second figure is twenty-five percent of
the worldwide GDP is run by Europe going
down but fifty percent of all spending
of the social systems are done by the
Europeans is that a model which we can
finance it for a long time or have you
think about other things so therefore
it's very important that if you have a
discussion about probably the GMG them
achieve 20 what is the role of Europe
not about is the role of a very strong
economic country like Germany what is
the role of Europe generating grows in
the euro area and in the world because
we need this to solve some problems so
the unemployment rate in Austria what
was your question it's going up one of
the problems is that Austria is a
growing country we have about 8.3
million
habitants and we are growing up to
probably nine million we are have a long
long tradition as a country for
immigration and the problem we have
solved is the same as as Peter said and
viola said this problem cannot also can
only be solved if you make structural
reform in all the systems and we have to
do this and we have to do our homework
in every member country not it's not
that not the responsibility of the
collision but what we also have to
discuss that didn't happen all-time high
of employees all-time high of aim please
so what we are doing now is we try to
find a way back to the growth we had
have 0.4 in the last in the year 2014 we
will have about 0.7 in the year 2015 and
we will double it in the next year
that's the good message we double it in
the next year just the Commission told
us 1.5 thank you well it's good message
for us but it's we have so many problems
in every member state solving
unemployment generating rose and so on
that it's not easy to explain to the
Austrian people why we should make a
deposit guarantee scheme why we should
make a european-wide unemployment
insurance because the people say we have
enough problems in our own country and
that's a very very big problem to find
the balance between the Solidarity of
Union Europe where we are a member and
the national point of view which is
political very difficult to explain not
so probably in the in the in the content
or about the issues but its political a
very big problem it's a problem in
between a coalition and its problem is
the opposition
pesty opposition mr. Skeel una so you
said earlier that we should there should
be more focused on the aggregate stands
of eurozone economic policies but that
also means for some governments to lose
some of their sovereignty what if you as
a as a country actually feel right now
is the right moment for you to cut
spending because you know that you
actually have some tension bills coming
up in the future or vice versa would you
be willing to give up this sovereignty
what and what does it mean does it mean
having a European fiscal council does it
mean having a European finance ministry
does it mean that your group president I
mean who gets to take the decision on
that but definitely a question of
sovereignty it's a political question it
belongs to the electorate is my
colleague was saying I mean they have to
decide what they are ready to give up in
order to obtain even in the country
itself when we give up you know when we
elect the government we give up certain
freedoms in order to obtain something in
return the same for taxation would pay
in order to get collective services so
however before I answer this question I
mean I I think I'd rather like to see
how are we going to be judged by our
children in the future would have we
made a good job I mean have we achieved
what we intended to achieve there are
going to lose themselves into this
legislation and the other one and how
many nights we've been kept awake in
order you know 22 and the media circus
and so on I mean we're going to be
judged where are we and and I definitely
agree with gone from here that finally
what would like would be that the
European Union especially the Eurogroup
will be at the top as far as the
competitiveness report whether the world
economic forum or the World Bank's Doing
Business one would like that the best
countries will be at the top and would
want to see our own Union being there
together and well at the moment we
not so these indices by the way whether
the taken by these institutions or by
Bruegel in the sense of advising have
been very sign
you