the debate and situation and at least in
my case I'm a member of the European
People's Party family which is the
biggest yeah Donald Tusk and jean-claude
Juncker sits at the same table and we
meet in Brussels next time in December
and I I shared with many with people
like Nicolas Sarkozy who is back at the
table from France that to start with
quota as the beginning of the answer or
the system was wrong was not not a good
beginning but to deal now with the
situation seriously and and really is a
must for all individually for countries
and also for for the community central
europe has different history i'm happy
you use durham central for decades I had
to oppose we are Eastern year we are
noticed Eastern Europe there is western
central eastern there is European mosaic
of a different countries different
regions different languages different
cultures Europe is very old nice and and
valued valued or precious diversity in
unity and Central Europe means something
in in the center something what was a
better field between big powers in the
past during the century of fears century
of fears it's it's it's a notion of
ilium that's an important now I come to
this it is something where these
countries were part of ethnic purchase
when more totalitarian time has has
flown than freedom very limited decades
of democratic experience now we have 25
years of freedom it's one generation one
university life mean
a new experience with freedom
responsibility common Europe and all
these are key and multicultural society
around but also my response was if not
compulsory quota but but functioning and
responsible solidarity because
solidarity is something which must be
based more on people-to-people
relationship than bureaucratic or
administrative relationship and this
response in my spectrum in my party is
is there I oppose my prime minister to
see European Union because of quarters
it's something dubious and this term was
used by the member of the government of
Slovakia I agree it's dubious for
domestic reasons there is a lot of
politics in in the situation there is
there is a lot of calculation today and
I am against the calculation because it
is about so in your own money but people
now they are dealing and and we are
ready to do to show and share solidarity
so you think that it's Slovakia should
accept in fact the mandatory quota even
though that was the wrong starting point
it was wrong starting point and Slovakia
should claim the rule of law is
important in Slovakia for slovakia in
europe for europe yeah if legal expert
says that rule of law is not good
because majority then i'm against some
taxation laws in slovakia which is which
were not reasonable and are against
economic growth in this country but i
have to observe majority and legislation
which is valid so is it in your eyes is
it acceptable for a member state of the
european union to limit their refugee
intake save to christians look as i am
white no no asylum procedure is based on
strict rules and and we are we are
country which observes international and
national legislation it's not based on
religion or race yeah so I oppose this
approach for future for long term for
integration of course there are
significant sensitivities but this is
not issue of asylum seeking an asylum
treatment no well but he will come to
that in the next round a final political
question and then we'll move on how do
you perceive the role of Angela Merkel
in this crisis has she been throwing her
weight around too much has she been
creating problems for others or has she
been showing moral leadership or all of
the above simple question but not so
simple situation and answer if I
mentioned constitutional crisis economic
and financial and I know what it was
inside and I both there when anger
miracle replaced garage shredder I was
in the Commission in crow this
commission and in burrows she brought a
lot of pro-european commitment balanced
approach reserved a smaller states it
was not kind of curatorial or or direct
aureum against the rest and I think she
helped significantly decisively to
address constitutional crisis economic
and financial nothing is perfect nobody
nobody is perfect and her role was
unreplaceable in those years and decayed
on on on this sort of situation I would
say the messages from largest European
EU country on readiness to absorb to
accept up to 800,000 refugees message is
spread very easily and swiftly
throughout an outside continent meant
for example that in Syria and Syria or
in
she comes most of people think and
believe that they are welcomed and
expected in Europe or in Germany and I
hope that in Germany now after sunday CD
and CSU and SPD miracle and they
affirmed and Gabrielle will be able to
keep on going and to address steps which
are necessary now otherwise without
Germany without consolidated approach we
shall not consolidate situation together
and I think that consolidation of the
situation is a base for credibility of
Europe at intra and add extra and it
will not go with our German government
led by or now led by Angela Merkel but
there may have been an error in
communication in the way angular Merkel
communicated to the Syrian refugees the
willingness to there is always there is
always a lot of simplification
propaganda misuse by for example illegal
traffickers yeah bari by organized crime
we got a question about organized crime
comes out in a second I wanted to ask
first Monica venome will the refugees
pay for our pensions and our welfare
systems yes for four-day parts but the
integration is the kind of her the key
word as I said already earlier and in
certain countries sir there are areas
where countries have difficulties to get
employees so in in certain countries in
certain areas it really can be of help
when more people come to the country but
but really what is important is that we
can't look at the immigrants or refugees
as one group because they have different
origins different skills different
backgrounds so and that actually makes
the integration process very challenging
because you need
tailored measures so for some of them
you need to improve the basic kills but
actually the amount of highly educated
immigrants and refugees have increased
during their years and we have to take
care add that there is not either brain
waste which is happening actually now so
if we invest in them now then in the
long run they will help to pay off yes
exactly works s we have to think of it
as an investment but bit when it comes
to this brain waste one interesting
figure is that when we look at the well
educated immigrants who have they
decrease from foreign universities so
forty-two percent of them work in a
lower skilled jobs than what education
so we're not taking enough advantage yes
and but when it comes to those
immigrants who have they decreased from
the domestic University they're only
twenty-two percent of them work in jobs
with where the requirements are lower
than what their education so they lot
lot to be done and in order also to look
at a kind of the transparency when it
comes to decrease of course in every
country have to be sure that a decree
which you have has the same level as say
you have in your country but I think the
system is not functioning properly when
you hear these figures that's certainly
something to bear in mind Kathy you want
to come in on that I just think there is
there is certainly scope for changing
the narrative into a lot more was it a
lot more positive one not only the OECD
research but a number of other studies
and research show that there is one area
we haven't talked about yet there is one
area of public policy that's the most
predictable of all and that's demography
and this is a continent where the labor
is shrinking which especially
in Central Europe as an would certainly
agree the demographic projections are
very dire and so you have you have a
pool you will have to look for a pool of
labor in the next 10 15 20 years in our
in this very country and in all the
countries around it and in many parts of
Europe so that's this one real sort of
driver that should that should push for
integration but the other the other
aspect is that the people who come here
and it doesn't matter whether they come
from a poor background in Africa or
whether they are fleeing Syria and you
know Aleppo they the one thing that
unifies them and I agree that they have
diverse backgrounds but the one thing
that unifies them is the day are
risk-takers they have drive and hence
they are much more likely to be
entrepreneurial right so is the is the
best and brightest that that you that go
and take the dangerous journey to make
it here so I think that they can if if
the policies are done well and if the if
the countries use the integration
capacity that they may have because it's
not the financial is not a logistical
challenge at these numbers it's
certainly not it's a mental challenge
and is an integration challenge and if
it's if it's done well they could
contribute to making the societies
diverse and hence more resilient in this
new era of exponential tea and global
developments that are hard to adapt to
and if you have a society that's more
diverse it's going to be more deductible
almost by definition bacuna so you say I
just wanted to say that there of course
we are not either saying that this is a
kind of a nice story everybody wins that
is not the case of course if the
integration doesn't kind of if we don't
succeed in that also certain groups in
those countries where a lot of
immigrants and also refugees come and
especially when it comes to low-skilled
jobs the native-born good
in lots worse position so I think
information delivering is kind of the
key and also we have to be able to
deliver all that information which is
not so nice yeah I was going to come to
that that there are losers of
immigration and that's the same whether
they're refugees or economic migrants or
whatever and those tend to be the people
at the bottom of the pile in our own
societies what used to be called the
white working class and they are the
people who are first of all losers from
globalization in general because they've
been priced out of jobs by imports but
also specifically competitors for public
spending on housing schooling health
care and social benefits with the new
arrivals and who I here in Germany to
some extent I no fair yura gasps misson
is still around or whether he's had to
leave us but one hear stories from
Germany that of German working-class
people saying you know all of this money
all is being spent on accommodating the
refugees what about us so I think that's
certainly something we need to think
about sorry there's you had point mate I
can also speak to that because I think
that's it that's something we're under
estimating at the moment hey I you know
welcome positive narrative swords
migration but I think we should be very
careful about too closely linking
economic benefits to refugee populations
as a driver for welcoming war there is
an international legal responsibility
yeah to protect those in need of
protection regardless of their economic
costs and benefits so you know we have
to keep that as that as the headline and
I think the second reason to sort of be
very careful about this is there's been
a lot of talk over the last few months
of you know there's the Syrian engineers
are Syrian doctors this is how
tastic we need these people and that's
great as long as you're Syrian
engineering qualification is recognized
in the country you arrived in right and
one of the major challenges for us over
the next decade and this is particularly
challenge for Germany which has a quite
a rigid labor market and recognition
system is how do you manage to recognize
that qualification and or create the
kind of bridging programs and skills
development programs that will
facilitate access to the labor market at
the right level and one of the ways to
think about this is not just investment
in recognition of qualifications but
also skills development programs that
look at coastal populations Native
communities as well as new refugee
communities and thinking about that sort
of investment for the whole community
and population and here i think that
there's completely an underserved role
for private sector actors get well
that's certainly a message that we would
want to to pass on to your gazz misson
who in his day job is deputy labor
minister and responsible for a lot of
those things we've had some questions
from the audience so I'd like to start
by taking one or two that have been sent
in anonymously and then ask some real
members of the audience to give us their
questions and comments but first of all
as peripheral EU states what role can
croatia Romania Bulgaria play as
positive influences for you desire z you
wishes in the Western Balkans region for
example on migration catty these are
you're not quite your your clients
because they're already member states
but you used to be client there near the
clients of duty clients well I would
echo my neighbor here on the panel yawn
and say that first and foremost uphold
the uphold the icky in their own
countries and and certainly should they
become or continue be transit states you
know not not not be inclined to to be
closing borders etc but
are all non Schengen countries so they
are they are outside outside of the
smaller Schengen space in the Western
Balkans I think that ironically we are
slightly better equipped in providing
concrete support than we are inside the
EU actually through D because there is a
there is an assistance mechanism in
place yeah we were able very quickly to
reorient and reprogram a lot of the
assistants towards migration management
border management work with the host
communities in addition to the
humanitarian aid in general so we are we
are ironically better equipped to react
quickly because a lot of the lot of the
mechanisms for example humanitarian
assistance is only for outside the EU
and this crisis has shown that
mechanisms for quick reaction inside the
you may need to be developed in the
future as well they don't exist yet so
we are able to react quicker and
certainly the help of Bulgaria Romania
Croatia to the Western Balkan countries
would be very welcome because logistical
help is needed expert help is needed
material support is needed but on our
side on the on the US side I'll just use
one one example we were able to
reprogram 10 million euros for for
Serbia and the former yugoslav republic
of macedonia with in between adoption in
the commission and contracting we spent
only three weeks which is like lightning
speed for for the EU so certainly helped
both in terms of personnel and and money
material would be would be most welcome
great well the couple of issues which we
haven't discussed yet which are there in
the public and therefore reflected in
our audience one is concerned about
terrorism the other is concerned about
organized crime and trafficking so one
question which i'm going to put two
young feegle but others are welcome to
come in how do we avoid the known
phenomenon with an already mostly
integrated Muslim population that we're
some in the second generation born in
Europe turned to terrorism that's a
whole panel subject in itself probably
and the other one what link is there
between migratory human trafficking and
other illicit forms of trafficking is
there any discussion of the nexus
between this crisis and other security
threats yeah it's yeah it's a huge topic
calm and maybe I would started with
mentioning one book from Israeli author
almost oz how to cure a fanatic this is
the title very short small book which
speaks about dividing line in our lives
and societies it is not between
civilizations it is not between cultures
between people basically but it goes
through our inner conscience either we
respect life with respect dignity of
everybody or not and the other side of
the line is fanaticism of any sort
ideological artistic political religious
you mean you may continue there are
different examples in human history and
European history especially of the
swords and waves of fanaticism and the
dough's and responses education
education education which means knowing
more and respecting more because we may
become happier in france in germany in
slovakia in relationship not isolated
not soul not
embraced by by our other DD walls or
hand offenses and I think that this is
phenomenon which speaks by itself that
integration is quite demanding process
integration is neither absorption nor
assimilation integration means
participation as equals taking part on
the same civic human base and for that
we need to bring understanding of
minorities and majorities together or
not not to nurture parallel societies as
we frequently see but really help
children to grow together to know the
culture of the neighbor and to build up
neighborhood in the neighborhood not
around Europe but not where people
really live integration even European
the relation starts at home in the
country it goes on by a neighborhood
with the neighbors I am happy that visa
grant is something we'll is quite known
and it's not imposed it is something
very European in living together and
even even working together in political
terms and this is example and
contribution also to European policies I
think we still need to learn the best
practices to put together quality and
access to education as a double
objective not only access and then you
have a gal Italian system without
quality or only or so low quality and
you have a logistic system so this is
more about education and living together
this terrorism and trafficking can I
something because I think yeah making
important very briefly I can see the
audience is getting edgy to ask
questions so sick I can draw on the
French example when it comes to
integration and I think identity is very
important there was some research a few
years ago in France where they asked a
lot of second-generation immigrants so
the children of immigrants yeah do you
feel French very high percentage said
yes I feel French the second question
said do you think others think you a
French the number dropped so people can
felt French we're aware that no one else
in France thought of them as French and
the body language of the state is
extraordinarily important if a state
says you are or you are not part of us
you are not part of our society you are
in you are out that has a strong effect
particularly on the second generation
about how they feel about participating
in a society and we've seen that in a
number of countries I think we should be
very aware of the narratives and the
identical identity issues that are
involved with yes and when it comes to
human trafficking and smuggling and
financing we haven't looked more closely
closely enough at financing I mean there
are investigative journalists making
links between Isis and smuggling I think
there are your huge crossovers between
different criminal networks this is a
very horizontal phenomenon many people
are migrants themselves facilitating the
next stage of their journey through
through helping co nationals across the
next stage of the smuggled journey so
they're not necessarily smugglers there
are organized crime networks involved in
this there's a huge diversity of
smuggling in travel logs is this but it
is a huge business with high profits an
extremely low risk and if you wanted to
be involved in other nefarious actors
that barriers to entry are extremely
though yeah I heard mark pierini the
other day say that it was a
billion-dollar business now this year in
Turkey if you reckon that each family
spent on average two thousand five
hundred euros to get from Syria to
Europe and most of that money was going
to intermediaries in Turkey worth worth
bearing in mind right it's your turn
ladies and gentlemen you've been very
patient gentleman over there I'll take
sort of perhaps two or three questions
at a time please
yourself tell us who your question or
comment is for and keep it short thank
you melanesia it's a method and a think
tank from Bratislava Slovakia the
question is to anybody who wishes to
answer that and I'd like to return with
no disrespect to the people who are no
longer here to the previous panel and
two things intrigued me very much one
was when state secretary Asmussen spoke
about the Constitution right to claim
asylum in Germany and he always makes a
very precise argument and today he also
made a very precise argument with one
caveat that was that he said that the
right is unlimited that means that
there's no ceiling which i think is
constitutionally and Aristocles
praiseworthy and from the point of human
rights also praiseworthy from the point
of policy it's very i would say
ambiguous because what I think it does
it encourages anybody abroad to kick out
as many people as you would like to from
your own country because it says well we
will receive as many as you can kick out
so that's first maybe some comment from
the panelist and second was when we are
dealing with the refugee crisis in
Europe I think that we are dealing with
it both domestically and externally and
domestically the debate is mostly I
would say not mostly but to a great
extent limited to snipping from one
prime minister to the other but what I'm
missing is that helping Germany while we
are watching Chancellor Merkel to take a
deep in the nasty water helping to
project an argument that there are 145
signatories to the UN Geneva Conventions
this is not solely a European problem
are we so weak in the European Union
that we can't talk that the countries of
the Gulf and we can only say
statistically that's well they haven't
taken in
buddy but we have to take in everybody
isn't it a time that we showed also not
only a big heart that we have for
everybody but also some brains and the
teeth because UN convention is not just
a piece of paper to which you sign and
then do nothing Thanks gotcha two
questions I think they mainly go to Liz
although you didn't say to whom
gentleman in the front row deputy tank
based here in Breslau two questions one
is about twinning mechanism of bilateral
arrangements which for instance this
country its country on one hand try to
turn down or sink down the quotas the
ear a location mechanism with some
numbers on the other hand offered
bilaterally to Austria to host
temporarily 500 asylum seekers from
Austria and I wonder what would be
comments from the Commission and from
expert pleased about this arrangement I
not Australian buses in the room and
he's listening a second Western Balkans
over the winter may become a waiting
room a huge giant waiting room for many
refugees it's partly by design because
what Germany needs to slow down the the
whole flow they cannot handle 10,000 new
migrants a day maybe they can handle
3000 so what the what is the capacity
there to House people to we know that in
Germany now people are intense what
about the Western Balkans and what can
countries like Slovakia that has a long
relationship friendship and support of
course the Balkan countries do in this
and attached to this for your figure we
will have a presidency of the you after
the touch and this migration crisis
might decide the success of failure one
presidency how we handle it I don't
think I don't see our Ministry of
Interior and other people involved
in preparation of the presidency
focusing entirely on this but are
already doing it so as a politician
former commissioner you negotiator what
would you do if you will be in charge
not but what would I get okay great
thank you very much is there a third
question in this round yes sir um can I
can I just say that women are allowed to
ask questions too as well as answering
thank you very much you forever all
there is autumn a winter is coming yeah
there is some project for really
decreasing all these problems of
migrants walking through several
countries project of the creation of
some let's say train bridge or plane
bridge this kind of support it was
discussed because really an airlift a
Berlin Airlift as it were okay thank you
sir that's plenty to ask to let me start
and try and allocate some of those
questions German constitution and
European teeth without with the Arab
world Liz would you like to take those
open-ended asylum I repeat slices and
dead I mean the thing about the Geneva
Convention international or is there are
some unfinished questions about it you
have the right to claim asylum but a
country also is the one that was those
protection so it's not necessarily
unlimited if countries find other means
to offer that protection and some of the
issues the concepts that are now being
discussed in many countries is can we
designate Turkey a safe third country
and in international law under certain
circumstances you can say you have
passed through a safe country where you
could and have received protection on
your way to us therefore we can send you
back to that so there are you know there
is an unlimited right to claim asylum
and the same would apply to Iran as a
safe country for Afghan
in theory you have to meet some very
very strict legal criteria and the UNHCR
is currently revising its guidelines on
this and it'll be interesting to see how
you might who and how countries might
fall under this rear it but it you know
there are the practical organization of
the right to claim asylum is something
that's deeply complex and could allow
for quite a lot of movement I mean the
entire Dublin system is premised on the
safe third country concept except if
you're returning people to Greece
obviously and when it comes to
internationalizing this issue you know
it's much easier to internationalize the
funding side of this issue and do
pledging conferences and there'll be
another pledging conference in the new
year it's notable that there will be a
world humanitarian summit held in
Istanbul in may of next year so there is
this moment now to really talk ok are we
going to bring the international
community together to discuss these
things together there are precedents
though there was a comprehensive plan of
action that was agreed in the 1980s to
deal with displacement from Vietnam now
while the political and contextual
situation in Vietnam was very very
different there are some lessons to be
learned about what it takes for an
international community to come together
and decide how to equitably just divided
up responsibility there is that
President and there's growing pressure
to talk about either a global
resettlement program or some form of
international congress that would have
be able to have this conversation and it
is notable that you know the US and
Canada have been increasingly asking
Europeans what can we do to help but
also countries that have never really
been involved in this before Brazil and
Argentina have been offering
humanitarian visas to Syrians and taking
several thousand each so far Mexico is
getting ready to launch a resettlement
program it's never done that before
there are new actors coming into the
field and when it comes to the Gulf
states I recognize the challenge of sort
of how do you ask Gulf states to take
refugees it's not it's not in this sort
of is philosophy what is interesting to
note the number of Syrian nationals
who've been given labor visas in the
Gulf region and that's something that
also happens in Europe if it's easier to
access
the labor market then claim asylum many
people will come and try and access
labor market in Poland for example
Ukrainians are using the labor migration
or rather than an asylum route because
it's a lot easier and it's been made a
lot easier so we should also look at
different ways in which people can
access protection which isn't
necessarily within the sort of legally
defined criteria but you think of it 11
sort of possible model that you're
pointing to there or sketching is that
we could put pressure on Saudi Arabia or
Qatar or wherever to pay for Syrian
refugees to go to Brazil or Argentina
rather than Munich interesting so there
are concepts of private sponsorship that
are emerging it's a long standing in
Canada which is the idea of offsetting
the costs of resettlement by getting
community at is involved it's a bit like
the American but if you're suggesting an
international trading of resettlement
places the American definition of a
Zionist is a Jew who pays for a second
jus so does the third you should go and
live in Israel I mean it may be worth
having a global conversation about what
an equitable division of responsibility
is when some of that responsibility is
financial and some of that is human and
there and what it would actually take
and I'm personally not convinced by the
idea of trading quotas for humans I
think that could go in a negative
direction Ferno some more innovative
creative responses to get a bigger
international response is definitely
necessary okay um the west bowl I'm
gonna ask you about the West Vulcan
waiting room but going if you want
waiting room in a second but just very
quickly on what Liz was saying let's not
forget we don't need to talk about
Bahrain and Syria is a Saudi Arabia
sorry and quite i think that the really
urgent international and much more
stepped up international response that's
needed is to help the two countries that
are completely overwhelmed and stranded
and not enough attention is being paid
to Jordan and Lebanon they are
middle-income countries that are
borrowing from the international
financial institutions at higher rates
then then otherwise and it's they have a
completely non selvam post-crisis the
systems are overwhelmed
nobody's paying attention so let's not
forget that there is a reservoir of two
and a half million people just in Syria
just in Lebanon and Jordan so before we
would we would venture into how to force
or cajole Saudi Arabia into taking
someone let's take off let's take care
of the host communities and I very much
agree that the investment needs to go
not only to the refugees but the host
communities as well and this is
something this is another crisis that is
very easy to foresee they are going to
get up and move within the next I don't
know whether month or weeks or years but
it's going to come unless we take the
resolution yes is a disaster waiting to
happen and not enough attention is being
paid we've got roughly 10 more minutes
no the Western emotional wait wait the
Western Balkans waiting room is exactly
what my humble part of the Commission is
trying to prevent an argue argue against
we are very concerned about attempts
that are actually vocalized bye bye bye
some member states of sort of desiring
to keep the the the refugees in the
Western Balkan countries I think that
particularly for me go Slav Republic of
Macedonia is in no no shape to to have
to be hosting huge numbers currently
Serbia is little better off the Prime
Minister himself spoke about you know
being able to accommodate a dozen
potentially up to 20,000 people but
these are really short term short-term
measures so I agreed there is a huge
danger that unless we do it carefully
there could be another bigger problem
arising in the in the Western Balkans so
that is something that is certainly not
in the interest of the EU and I think
that you mentioned very well you know
Slovakia and other countries in the
region are very interested in in the
Western Balkans and this could be
potentially a very concrete way of
helping them both in sending people
there as well as may be exploring the
model that we have in Austria I spoke
with the Austrian Ministry of
interior last Friday about the model and
it is a very interesting one big winning
model winning is a way of yes it's a way
of calling it it's a very interesting
model and also the lesson from it so
slovakia accommodated 500 asylum seekers
for austria temporarily in in a town
called gap Chico here and the residents
and the mayor were so worried about it
they actually organized the referendum
against it overwhelmingly against having
the the isilo secret stay there few
months down the line the mayor himself
said we were needlessly worried it
worked and so I think that that's a very
much a lesson when you look at the
eurobarometer the countries that have
very few migrants are the ones that tend
to be most anti-migrant and the ones
where you have experience with them are
most like we may get a chance if we're
very quick to ask Mary about her country
which is a country that has very few
migrants and is having a nervous
breakdown over them but first Yong the
Slovak presidency coming up what should
you be preparing for what would you be
preferring for if you were in government
if I may I would at minus three points
yeah first when I represented political
majority we passed in years 2003-2004 by
a migration office of Slovakia up to
10,000 refugees mostly from Pakistan and
Afghanistan no referenda no problem no
scare normally makes your way today
something I think Pete your electoral we
shall have elections my friends so as an
opposition politician is going to be
contesting those elections we do you
argue against
the prime minister or do basically
ignore the issue say it's a non-issue
we've done this in the past let's move
on to the real issues which in my mind
are x and y I'm sorry that this this
greynium doesn't speak too much or very
little about the roots on the problem
rather about the realities situation and
the complexities and if we don't heal
the wounds the roots we don't have
answers real answers credible answers
long-term answers to the situation on
the continent so I would respond to
Milan sure it's our own on German
response I'm happy the Germany now and
since I'd an hour is full of fast songs
Patriota smus something based on
Constitution and patriotism and European
and foreign policy which is linked to
European policy core of german foreign
policy european polish and that's it's
good for us that's good for Germany and
I think what what is needed to add to
this legalistic a constitutional
approach that everybody has right I
think they have right to have a country
which belong to people i mean they
refugees from Syria so let us let us
help Syrian people to get their country
back from jihadists from cali fault from
Isis Isis is the biggest international
and global global threat so let us deal
with that otherwise we are lost in in
this nitty-gritty debates so there is a
thread ultimate threat and either we do
something and eliminate such threat or
we shall have much more difficult
situations in Europe of next year
Slovakia's presidency Minister of
Interior has a lot to do and elections
is coming I think this debate should be
with people from interior ministry from
migration office and not only in
Slovakia but broadly more
internationally but it's up to them and
up to organizers to in
right what I would do differently I
think of course it's important to
prepare by action by doing not by sort
of planning but meh refugee crisis is
something a long term at least we may
expect and what we shall probably need
is kind of revitalization or boost of
Schengen and security policy more
coherent approach which means for in
security policy more together with other
policies humanitarian development maybe
Schengen group like we have your group
of ministers with permanent president
and some some mechanisms to deal with
highly sensitive issue and more
sensitive than ever and it will not be
diminished in next year's but even more
sensitive as I say and we didn't speak
too much about terrorism and and of
course we should also prepare prepare
for a credible Slovakia slow Slovak
input into into this preparation of
presidency so um i would i would go for
more active and responsive action if i
was quoted at the twitter i said
people-to-people people-to-people
solidarity is something important and
then there or something about why don't
do we have institutions here everything
and that's quote from either from a
normo name everything comes through
people & and remains via institutions if
we want to integrate in France or in
Germany or in Slovakia somebody to live
together it must be via people but
institutions ministers ministries
governments should facilitate should
create conditions which are safe
realistic for for people to people
living together integrating together if
not then we shall have a