thank you and good morning as you can
see a tide of our talk is apt attack
based purple teaming using attack you
might have noticed attack is in there
twice it's not an accident we are big
fans of attack as introduction and said
we are from mitre before we continue to
a formal introduction my name is Jamie
Williams I'm an adversarial engineer
mitre I do mostly research an adversary
emulation as well as behavior detection
and some of the work you might have seen
in public space that I work on mitre
attack as well as attack evaluations
I'll get a little okay that's a lot
better I can hear myself now and I'm
Daniel Weiss cyber security engineer at
mitre as well have been there for just
about three years I do both red and blue
spit split almost 50/50 right now and
I'm also on the attack evaluations team
so I said you might have noticed from
the title of our deck we are continuing
a conversation or presentation from last
year so if you recognize those gentlemen
as Cody and Chris good friends of ours
they were here last year briefing on the
same topic so basically in that shaped
our talk today is we're basically
picking up where that conversation left
off and giving a little more example and
depth into threat based purple teaming
using attack so before we continue or do
a quick recap of what they talked about
last year so you know I think what is
attack that's a great start the guys
from atomic threat coverage did a pretty
good job yesterday
describing attack but at a high level
attack is our knowledge base of
adversary behavior I basically the idea
is we have this idea called threat
inform defense basically if you
understand what threats are doing you
are better equipped to make good
decisions in terms of defense one of my
favorite things about attack is it's not
theoretical everything that is an attack
while the behavior is captured there are
documented real behavior so things
adversaries are actually doing in the
wild we're not selling attack it's free
global open so you can go to the website
and read everything for free there's no
subscription
there's no money in exchange as well as
you can check out our analysis as well
as we reference everything so you can
check out the sources that we read to
make these analysis and all these
judgments so you reference everything to
click it and go to the ground truth
intelligence there and final point here
is community driven so if you've never
noticed a lot of attack comes from what
we call contributions so we have our
contact information there it's a tacit
mitered org for email and our Twitter
account definitely we're always looking
for if you guys see things in the wild
that are missing from attack I think
there was a mention of that yesterday as
well as there's a talk later today about
you know cloud behaviors those type of
things we're always looking for a new
content so definitely reach out so to
kind of give you an overview of the
structure attack
normally you see attacked in what we
call the matrix view so I D composed
that to kind of make it make more sense
so starting with the tactics or what we
call the adversary goals so these are as
you see across the top we have the 12
what we call tactics what's special here
is this is not a kill chain so there's
no linear or like set order of these
these are just basically the different
that various different things an
adversary would do in an environment
once they're like post compromised so
things like gaining initial access
executing things moving laterally
exfilling and then on the end we
actually have as of last week our latest
tactic impacts so attacks against
availability and integrity coming down
from every tactic we have what we call
techniques so these are implementations
of how an adversary actually achieve
those goals so for example we look at
credit access you see things like brute
forcing passwords dumping passwords or
input capture which is basically key
logging so capturing keystrokes to gain
access to credentials with each
technique we have what we call
procedures so if you click if you go to
this page and website and click on
individual one you'll see a full
write-up and what we mean by that
technique as well as what we call
procedures which are actual malware or
groups that have done this specific
technique so in this case we're
highlighting accessibility features as
you see that technique spans multiple
tactics so it's profess and privileged
persistence so if you take a look at the
procedures it's kind of small so but
basically you see how different groups
have
and accessibility features for
persistence so in in the case of a PT
three they replace the SC binary with
their own payload so when you go to an
RTP desktop or a login page and hit
shift 5 times CMD will pop or the
payload launches as well as there's an
Empire module that can do something
similar it replaces the magnify binary
with scene D so you go to the like a
login page and you like open a little
like magnifying glass and instead of
seeing like a zoomed in thing you see
like a scene B pop and that's obviously
malicious so getting back to what Cody
and Chris talked about last year one of
the things that were really excited
about is what we call emulation plans
this is actually a new concept recently
well basically the idea is taking these
tactics from attack and mapping them
into a structure for how you would
emulate an adversary so in this case
what they released the last SIEF Khan
was a BT 3 so they basically did a lot
of research into the actual cadence of
apt 3 how they actually maneuver
starting with like the different phases
so getting their payloads ready and
delivering it to a victim what they do
when they compromise a host so you see
evading defenses discovery privilege
escalation so there's various techniques
within those tactics and then phase 3
you know collecting X fill and like
compressing and staging their data
another talk a big point they talked
about last year was using attack to
evaluate specific techniques so in the
case in this case we have like what we
call our Navigator this is basically
allows you to make filters or highlight
specific techniques and make your own
matrix so what they were talking about
was basically you know you select the
techniques you're interested in or even
just one and you use this purple teaming
model to evaluate that so basically the
idea is you start with emulating a
technique so figure out in this case
executions your API you figure out how
an adversary but actually execute that
and you'd run it in your environment and
on the blue perspective you detect that
or defend it however you choose but the
big point here is this transparency
between each and so the red team is
sharing with the blue exactly what
happened exactly when they did it and
completely telling you there's no
blackbox testing so telling you exactly
what happened and when where and how
blue team defends it based on all that
knowledge pushes their defense back to
red so basically the challenge there is
to up
okay now that I know you're defending it
this way can I do that same technique or
behavior and bypass your new defense so
that iterative process going back and
forth as you can probably tell like
seeing the level of like complexity and
like resiliency increases each time so I
know you're probably thinking right now
like am I gonna spend the entire time
talking about what happened last year No
so thankfully we do have some new
content here it's actually pretty
exciting for us where a guy she can take
a deeper dive into the science of what
we're talking about by emulation and
this purple teaming approach sort of
high-level just kind of give you an
overview what we're gonna talk about
today we're going to pick a specific
technique based on its specific scenario
and then we're going to walk you through
an example of the purple teaming
approach so emulating that behavior
defending against it emulating again
defending against it etc but the big
point here is transparency so we'll talk
about purple teaming the most important
thing is that each side is talking to
each other so hopefully through our
demonstration we'll show you the
importance of that and the value added
by doing that one assumption here is the
technique that we're testing we have
we're starting from scratch so we have
no like like something that we can apply
is defense so we're starting from
basically nothing for defending this
technique okay so yeah we're researchers
so we kind of heads in the clouds very
often so one more thing we got to cover
before we get like into the
demonstrations so it helps before you
start thinking about emulation it helps
to think about like your emulation
target in this case of a havior what we
talked about a behavior we're not
talking about things like static values
like hashes ip's domains strings things
like that when we want to do it what we
call it emulation we're emulating the
action or the behavior what the NAD
versary
actually does if you're familiar with
the pyramid of pain this is like more of
the high level things that are really
hard to capture so this is kind of like
a nebulous concept so a really
interesting way to help you like
understand what we talked mean by
behavior is thinking about it in terms
of attack so like I said before we have
the tactics techniques and procedures we
think behavior were more or less
thinking the techniques and procedures
excuse the pun but like we think that's
like more or less the
of a behavior it's the variation of the
house and what's this is really
important for emulation another way to
think about it behavior is in stages so
if you think about like anything in the
world there's like before during and
after so in terms of a behavior you can
think about this like apply that same
model for behavior and think about you
know the prerequisites so what happens
before a behavior happens the mechanics
so what happens during the behavior and
then the artifacts so what's left behind
after a behavior so mapping that to
system on events we can think about like
prerequisites like things like image or
driver loads mechanics being things like
you know process creates process
terminates remote like memory reads
threads being created things like that
so actually things happening and then
the artifacts being like more of the
forensic side so registry changes file
changes as well as if you're talking
about like beacons or rats network
connections that are left over that are
like established CT channels so you know
a lot of theory at this point but at
this point we try to get our hands dirty
we decided not to trust the demo gods so
we like pre-recorded all of our demos
but hopefully it's still kind of cool so
at this point I'm gonna hand over to Dan
sweet Thanks so now that we know what a
behavior is we're gonna actually jump in
into emulating one before we do I'm just
going to touch on how to do that there's
a bunch of open source frameworks out
there to actually do that the two I have
up there are up there for a reason one
is because we open sourced it and the
other is because they kind of represent
two sides of the emulation spectrum you
have the atomic red team side which is
on purposely made to be simple and easy
to execute a lot of the stuff that
atomic red team are one-liner so you can
copy and paste and run into your beat
and paste into your beacon or into a
command prompt or PowerShell for example
and just run and then do and then go
through that purple teaming process on
the other side you have a tool like
caldera which is completely automated
adversary emulation that does end to end
attacks and so as part of our demo we're
kind of going to devise a scenario where
we're gonna demo in direct command
execute
and indirect minute execution basically
says that we want to have a command line
style interface without invoking CMD at
that same time we're also are going to
avoid PowerShell so as you can see in
this example running CMD is also blocked
in this environment so jumping to the
atomic red team which is what we use for
this demo for the easy side if you go to
indirect command execution on the atomic
red team he actually had or they
actually have two different atomic tests
that you can run the first one is taking
advantage of the program compatibility
assistant and the second one is for
files on the first one the program
compatibility assistant allows you to
have that command line style interface
you just have to specify the - a flag
and for both demos we are going to do
the default value of just popping Kalki
on the second one the four files there's
three different command-line arguments
that we use the first one is /p which is
the search path the second one is /m
which is the search mask so that
basically says it's a for loop and says
our search path is system32 and the mask
our search mask is notepad.exe so for
every notepad.exe that you see inside of
system 32 i want you to run the command
after slash c which is kalki and since
there's only one notepad dot exe in
system 32 it's gonna pop one calc and so
just for the simple demo on the left is
the pca lua dot exe popping calc I'm
just doing it from the run window so it
pops through Explorer and then on the
second side you can see four files also
running through the run window and that
also pop pops calc so sweet simple demo
so now you see a pretty simple emulation
of a technique or a behavior two
different ways and so now we'll jump
into the blue side or the detection side
and so Before we jump into those two
instances of detection I just want to
jump back and talk about how you
actually come to a detection so if you
think of it from a pyramid style layer
the bottom layer is going to be your
data sources that's going to be the
source of your information so process
monitoring
it's dll's all those types of things the
second layer of that pyramid is gonna be
the sensors so what actually is pulling
or what's actually collecting the
information from those data sources and
then the third is going to be your
analysis on top of that's basically to
formulate the detection z' we have the
cyber analytic repository card or gets
not list up there but that is one open
source example of analysis on top of
those sensors and then just as a side
step I'll talk about detection lab real
quick we use that for all the demos it's
an awesome purple teaming environment
red teamers can use it blue teamers can
use it it's at a high level it's just
basically a Windows domain that you can
stand up comes with a Splunk server and
you can customize it however you want so
usually how I run it is I throw a system
on on there I open up system on to look
like proc Mon I enable a bunch of the
advanced audit policies so you get a
whole bunch of Windows Event log besides
the standard ones and then you can run a
detect a emulation of a behavior like we
just did in the previous slide and
you'll see literally everything that
goes on underneath the hood of Windows
operating system ok so jumping into that
first test which those which is the PCL
Lua XE on the right we have just a
pretty simple process for you so both of
these tests are pretty straightforward
Explorer is going to pop the indirect
command execution binary that we use and
that's actually going to pop the Cal so
going back to the data sources if you
want to detect the first test that we
ran the first data store the three data
sources that you need for this behavior
of t1 202 is obviously process
monitoring you're going to want to
monitor for process creations of the PC
at Lua binary the command line parameter
so you have to specify that flag that
the - a to run a process to start a
process or to run your payload and then
like Windows Event log 4 6 8 it
obviously process creation will give you
that also system money event ID 1 which
is process creation first this one and
then jumping to for files so same thing
pretty simple for files popped calc so
you want to monitor
the four files binary or executable and
then from the command line parameter
standpoint for files we use three in our
test so when you start doing this purple
teaming an iterative cycle you try to
kind of break the detection so in first
if we were looking for those three
process command line parameter flags the
red team actually could devise a way
that they can realize that they actually
don't need those first two flags
so /p the search path you don't need a
defaults to the current directory and
you also don't need the slash and the
search mask it just defaults to a
wild-card so star so if you're if you're
in a directory that has for example
three files it'll run your command three
times and you can also do it slash C or
dash D it doesn't matter and then
obviously the Windows Event log data
source so four six eight eight that
event or if you're using system on even
I did one will give you this information
so we take an opportunity to talk about
the product we mentioned earlier attack
evaluation so you've never seen this the
same kind of like red vs. blue scenario
we basically for attack evaluations we
ran that same scenario against EDR
products so the URL is in the bottom if
you check it out but basically we put
together a twenty step red team script
based on abt three ranted had our vendor
set up the product we ran that emulation
against those products and then provided
the output to those EDI products
specifically focusing on detection so if
you see as highlighted up there you see
on the right on the left you see the red
tide so transparency we're telling you
exactly what we did on the right we're
showing you what the EDR product
actually captured so like in terms of
every technique that we tested as well
as what was captured there so this is a
pretty good like vignette for you know
using this operationally or outside of
just testing techniques also going
forward like I said Dan showed you he
said he said exactly what we tested and
he took that to the detection side and
using those command-line arguments was
able to detect everything I'm actually a
huge fan of using like the red vs. blue
sparring analogy I think it's great a
big point here though is it's really
important sometimes to make blue miss
not just like for shaming or anything
like that but actually like it's a good
opportunity for leveling up so just
showing them something that they
ever seen to help them enable like
growth and like learning so big point
here though is you're not just showing
them things they've never seen but
scoping it to the realm of like real
behaviors so things they've seen that
real adversaries are actually doing so
the next step in this emulation process
is to emulate that same behavior but
better the first step in that process is
looking at the way the previous
detection works so like Dan just
highlighted everything basically bit on
the EPAct Lou and the four files
detection was process based so looking
at process creations as well as process
command-line arguments so immediately as
you start diving into the next level
emulation your first prerequisite is hey
I cannot live in that process land so
first thing comes to mind for me
avoiding processes is net for many
reasons firstly it says it's pretty
great in terms of like functionality as
access to the low level like win32 api
so you can do a lot of really creative
things in general a lot of the
detections for dotnet is immature
unfortunately it's really complex under
the hood so there's really not a lot of
great like automation and deep analysis
and logic based on the mechanics that's
going on in there as well as I mean
dotnet isn't like inherently malicious
its installed by default on I think
everything past Vista so there's a lot
of noise and opportunities for false
positives
so from an emulator a Red Team it's a
really great place to hide because
there's a lot of the normal activity
happening that realm we call that like
living off the land so taking something
that's already available and using it
for malicious purposes and finally while
this is a great emulation target is if
you've followed a lot of like recent red
team developments or frameworks they're
actually moving towards dotnet
specifically c-sharp to avoid like power
show which is also lives in that process
level detection realm and also like
thread actors have moved here so we've
seen Chinese as well as Iranian actors
leveraging dotnet vs c-sharp for their
malware kits so looking starting to do
research and how we're actually gonna
emulate this like in direct Kemetic you
ssin that avoids CMD we start taking a
look and we come across this blog post
about spoofing parent kids
so basically c-sharp net enables us to
start calling API functions one
interesting function is create
is an interesting characteristic of
create process obviously it creates a
process but one of the parameters allows
you to specify a particular parent pit
so that's super interesting so we like a
that's something that we could
potentially use to get past that CMD
requirement taking a deeper look into
this we come across the proof of concept
code so if you've ever seen this it's
called select my parent but basically I
think this was a Python script but
basically the idea is it implements that
parent pit spoofing so what it allows
you to do is even though the top you
give it a command and then you give it a
parent pit and it basically launches
that command as a sub process of that
pit so if you look at the the bottom
it's actually like proc Mon process
Explorer be able to see via this code
you were able to launch notepad from
Alsace which is really weird and
probably should never happen but it's a
really interesting like characteristic
of the way this API call works so taking
that tour emulation we're able to do is
we found another POC for this written in
C sharp and we're able to launch that
same cow payload but from Explorer so
for the sake of demonstration we left
the command-line arguments there as you
can see them but basically what's
happening is we're launching like calc
from the parent pit of Explorer and Dan
will take a look at this on the
detection side but this is like a really
cool moment when you're doing this like
iterative emulation because like you
finally found something that works and
like you think it's really hard to
detect that you like toss the ball back
over to the blue side okay good luck
with that and so we'll accept the
challenge of trying to detect this
what's really cool is C sharp and
PowerShell both used the same underlying
dotnet framework but C sharp doesn't
have all the from a defender side C
sharp doesn't have the same PowerShell
logging that is kind of why we want to
avoid that as well so basically what
Jamie just explained is it's the same
demo that we did before but our C sharp
payload is popping calc
but we're spoofing the parent page so
it's actually spawning from Explorer and
going back to the data sources the two
that we used in the first two demos
process monitoring and
command-line parameters are not as
useful in this case one you don't know
what the process is going to be called
what it's going to be called when it's
created I guess you could search for if
it's a if it's an unsigned process being
started or an untrusted process being
started but that from a malware
standpoint might not always be the case
and then as far as command-line
parameters those are arbitrary we could
have obviously obvious gated those we
could have put them in base64 and then
decoded them on the fly so from a
command line parameter perspective
there's not much there fortunately you
can go by some other data sources to
kind of have some insight into dotnet
being executed so I actually first I
think I saw these on Twitter first I'll
have it there the source in there after
but the two day or two system on event
IDs 7 and 11 so image load so the data
source is tied back to like loaded DLLs
and dll monitoring there's actually two
being loaded when you run a c-sharp or
net assembly so it's the common language
runtime DLL and run just-in-time
compiler DLL so those two are loaded in
when you run your dotnet assembly and
then when you run your dotnet assembly a
usage log file gets dropped into the
User Profile app data a common language
runtime usage log directory so just
interesting things that happen when you
run dotnet so if that's not enough to
convince you that dotnet was running you
can also jump into ET w which is event
tracing for Windows which is essentially
a kernel level function or facility that
enables you to log kernel and/or
application to find events to a log file
so there's three different providers
that will kind of dive into for this
purpose of detecting that demo the first
two obviously have to have to do with a
detection of dotnet and the third one
the kernel process is going to be more
as a bonus just
show that we can see the spoof
Parenthood and then simply to capture or
view these easy to W events there's a
bunch of different ways there's built-in
command line log man and tracer PT so
you can run those built-in from the
command line and there's also some open
source things to fire I released a PI
win trace which is essentially a Python
wrapper around etw and so for this demo
we actually are using another open
source Python script called dotnet
runtime e to W which is made by counter
cept and it is a Python script that uses
the dotnet runtime etw provider but it
also leverages the PI win trace wrapper
that fire I made and so when we ran that
to capture there's a common language
runtime events and all dotnet events
this is kind of a blow out of what it
looks like so you do get a lot of data
but it is indicative of dotnet running
so you can see the JIT events on the top
you can you can actually see like the
XIV con demo like the name space and the
class and also the function so main
function and they create process
function that were actually started you
can also see the module loads and stuff
related to the done net framework as
well as at the bottom you can Interop
services as well so all pretty
indicative of dotnet being run and then
as a bonus I also said that I talked
about how to spoof that parent pin how
to detect it so that third etw provider
which was the kernel process there's
another script it's essentially just a
wrapper it'll run this ECW provider for
you and then parse it out and show you
the process spawned the parent at spawn
from them and also the spoof parent so
if you use this etw provider at the
kernel process etw you can see
effectively what happens and it's in
there for a reason it's for UAC so if
you launch something from elevated
prompt and you click yes through the
consent that he actually this exists
the parent-child relationships match up
even though the elevated process is
spawned from an SVC host so this is
actually so there are false positives in
here but it's still cool that you can
see the spoofed parent and with that you
can do yourself a pedal look back that
was really cool but in reality like
scale that into an environment like take
that and deploy it to 50,000 hosts
probably a nightmare
so the next step in this is like looking
at that detection and actually detecting
better behaviors better so a big point
here is the realization that you know
maybe not every behavior is something
that you should detect in real time for
various reasons such as like you know
things like cost or noise like like Dan
was saying false positives for that type
of detection would be like horrific you
probably lose a lot of sock analysts
just quitting the dashboard would light
up immediately with all these like very
benign things happening in the system
because everything we're dealing with
here is built into the system and
natural they're also so you know you're
if you're not detecting things in real
time this may be an opportunity for you
to leverage other business processes so
things like hunt or IR so if you're not
gonna detect in real time maybe that's
something your hunt team or your IR team
will take responsibility for and say you
know I'll they'll pick up where like the
detections are missing another
opportunity here would be something like
protections so an example of that would
be if you looked at the most recent
release of dotnet they implemented a MSI
within the dotnet runtime so basically
if that means is Windows Defender and AV
products that are looking for signature
based malware and other heuristic
behaviors are actually communicating
with the dotnet runtime and can give it
like tips and hints on you know what's
bad what's good and kind of like maybe
prevent things that are super malicious
or super obvious so getting back to what
we talked about before that the stages
of behavior and mapping this like better
detection to this it actually will kind
of help us scope like what's a realistic
way to handle this so mapping everything
Dan just covered in the last last
session section to these stages so the
prerequisites the first thing you would
see like dan said those dll's associate
without net being loaded those would be
pre Rex
in the mechanics you would see things
like the process of being created as
well as the events from the etw and then
the artifacts being you know those log
files written by the just-in-time
compiler as well as that log file and
the user profile so individually all of
these might be not great candidates or
something to Alert on but if you map it
out like this you can kind of see a
potential like an and I'm calling it a
notional defensive approach but a way
you can actually build this into your
defenses so maybe a first step is you
know rather than firing on every time
one of these individual things happen
maybe you set an alert for any time a
process that is specifically unsigned is
loading dotnet dll's
so maybe that might be outside of the
scope of what real organic dotnet
execution looks like because obviously
everything the system is probably a
Microsoft signed a second step to that
would be every time you fire an alert
seeing an unsigned process loading the
dotnet dll's you have an analyst follow
up and take a look at those like very
grainy log files which would be a
nightmare to parse and scale but maybe
an analyst has time to go look at those
and actually do like an in-depth
analysis and for your hunters in the
room proactively look for the stuff so
inform your hunt team on all of this
behavior understand all these mechanics
and as they go around in the course of
their normal behavior and look for
things they can think of look for these
type of artifacts and do that kind of
analysis before in these behaviors
actually happen so kind of in conclusion
wrapping up what we talked about today
getting back to that attack matrix
basically what we did was it's kind of
nuanced and small but that one technique
that we're focused on we based on what
we did we're pretty sure we can take it
from what we call low confidence to like
medium so we're not 100% sure we can't
act that but based on this iterative
process we feel like pretty comfortable
that like we understand the behavior and
how to detect it or defend against it
whether it's hunt IR protections in our
environment so the next step would be
rinse and repeat
so scale this same like process and
activity out to all of the techniques
that you care about another way of doing
this is getting back to coding Chris
from last year chain them together into
a full campaign so rather than doing
each individual one you can actually
write like an email
plan that ties these together into like
a cohesive like flow that goes over a
you know a couple days or a week and
then run all of this detection against
the entire campaign based on those
specific techniques so this is our last
slide we'll leave this up there's some
good resources here the top one is a
link to attack so everything else you
could link from there but specific
things we want to call out is our medium
blog so we have blog posts there for
attack and attack evaluations as well as
like various use cases such as like blue
teaming hunting sock work automation etc
and the bottom two are our contact
information so our emo and our Twitter
if you want to reach out about
contributions or you got questions or
definitely tweet us with memes we love
memes if you didn't notice by our slide
deck or like eat sleep meme just
constantly trying to make each other
laugh so I think we have a couple
minutes for questions otherwise thank
you for your time and your attention
thank you
[Applause]
you