all right so hello everybody
I hope you enjoying your time in this
beautiful city thank you for
organization fermentation and everything
today we are going to present you our
project atomic threat coverage which
represents technical implementation and
operationalization of threat centric
methodology and my tri-attack framework
specifically at the same time we will
present you the reasons which stands
behind decision to develop this project
and expected and a few unexpected
benefits which we had when we starting
processing all information automatically
also everything I'm gonna present we
gonna present to you today is free in
open source available on github and
ready to be implemented in your
environment alright my name is Daniel I
work another threat detection team late
in theatre Salkin Czech Republic today
we will perform together is NIOSH with
her he is so constant responder in
theater sock in Krakow in Poland also
have two members who unfortunately
couldn't participate today
Mikhail action of his sock automation
team late in Moscow in Busan and Yakov
Wayans Ethel
he is threat detection specialist in
theater sock and Krakow in Poland as
well at the same time we all crack of 26
crimes meetings members these are our
home meetups like local meetups I would
say we used to present first proof of
concepts or interesting ideas updates
there first so if you guys feel being
Krakow come over say hi this meetings
takes place each first Friday of the
month
alright let me provide you some
historical background in 2014 when I
started when I moved from networking
security to general computer security
and started working with offensive
defensive stuff
I had only one question and also started
working with CM systems specifically I
had only one question where all of these
people get correlation rules and I
couldn't find the answer the thing is at
that time basically if you're looking
for like correlation rules detection
rules methodology anything you can only
find like information about brute force
and everybody was like you know by our
sim system for a couple of millions
dollars and you will be able to detect
brute force alright maybe something else
basically I'll started also doing some
hacking stuff offensive and I was able
to intrude into system move laterally
dump credentials and everything but I
couldn't find any information about
detection like literally you know empty
field silence no articles no methodology
nothing and for me it was clear that to
detect something or to define the system
from something you need to understand
this something right like how the
adversary's operates how it looks like
what kind of tools they use and what is
their motivation and I couldn't answer
like find the answer for these questions
like why nobody is doing that why it's
so obvious but not so popular and I was
digging into the topic like looking for
something which would reflect my own
understanding of this area and I found
one it's called
intelligent driven defense developed by
Lockheed Martin corporation in 2012 and
the main idea behind it is you supposed
to know your enemy it is basic for
military but not so popular at least it
wasn't that popular that time basically
just five years ago so I grabbed it
started digging into what interesting is
there what can I use and you know after
just one year in 2015 my tree released
their framework called my tri attack how
many of you guys use my tree
Dok framework in your daily job can you
please raise your hand right that's just
awesome thank you so I don't for those
who are not using or not familiar I will
provide a simple description it's just
basically adversary model description of
steps techniques procedures and Tuesday
advisories used during the intrusion and
post exploitation activities in other
environment probably most of you
familiar with concept of cyber kill
chain also known as cyber attack
lifecycle in mitre paradigm basically
what they did they just split it into
two pieces pre attack and Enterprise
attack which is about delivery
exploitation and all post exploitation
activities which ad versus D and
basically that's how it looks like it is
a table there are twelve columns which
represents tactics tactic is tactical
objective of an adversary during the
intrusion and there are more than two
hunger cells which represents techniques
which are like exact way how to achieve
this tactical objective for example
exfiltration over alternative protocol
it is a technique at the same time it is
a way how to achieve tactical goal which
is exfiltration there is a simple
description of what is it about
mitigation detection strategies example
of use in the wild and some references
so basically each technique has such
description so and with all of this
stuff like all the mindset we are first
decided to start implementing it and we
faced a few problems during the
operationalization first of all
description for my tree itself is the
high level it's not actionable which
means that you cannot just pick up this
advices about detection mitigations and
go and implemented in them your own
to actually implement it he need to be
more specific for yourself understand
what you are doing and why at the same
time it's not it's always a team work so
you need to understand your team members
other departments leadership what you
are doing why you're doing this and
everything else so it's needs to be like
detailed to be operationalized another
thing is which is falling from the first
topic is that mitre attack by itself
doesn't provide you with the ability to
explain what exactly do you need and
doesn't provide you with the arguments
like proofs what exactly why is actually
need this one the good example of such
thing is this one log source when you
are saying your CMC my hey guys I want
to have sis Mon there in our detection
engine because I heard that he can
detect what things do that and they're
asking you alright
how many data you like um what was B
increased like an hour
EPS what exactly needs to install there
and why do you don't you like the
default like you know Windows Event log
like application security and system
channels and it is relatively simple
question but to answer it tend to be
understood by everybody you have to do
like huge research like what exactly you
can detect with a small Y this batter
down Windows Event log how many data
like you will have after that and what
can you detect like many things so each
kind of each time somebody is asking you
for to prove something to explain
yourself you have to do lots of things
to provide these proofs and compelling
arguments and last thing well basically
there are lots of thing but these are
main for us reports and leadership
basically when you are starting starting
the implementation leadership want to
know how you progressing what is the
roadmap what is the current status and
where you will be like in two months of
or each and every customer because we
are MSS we supposed to do reporting per
customers so and it is also something
which supposed to be simple but anytime
you preparing the report you have to
collect lots of data for multiple
departments compile it together provide
in an understandable way for management
which is also kind of challenging and
that's why in 2016 summer 2016 we
decided to create our own tool or our
own framework based on my tree and she
basically operationalize this and it's
called not a total misreading which
cause it's code to use case framework
yeah so you may heard about it in some
conferences in Poland or in Luxembourg
in 2017 or 18 but if you haven't don't
worry today we will present you this
stack the same benefits and something
new and more actual so basically what
was it it was a confluence knowledge
base with the listed structure we were
using my track technique as a separate
use case and we were mapping multiple
entities to this use case like alerts
related data needed for which required
for this alerting and related slogging
policy and this way this way we were
expressing ourselves to CMT also your
mapping their response actions response
response playbooks and many other things
so Matthias will tell you more about it
just in a few minutes so basically we
solved the problems I have listed using
this tool but we got another set of
problems good example of it is the unit
test unit test is an entity which which
allow us to trigger some specific
detection rule and we are putting all
the stuff manually the confluence page
to basically adjust to execute it you
need to go there
copy paste it and to the
machine - you know trigger something and
everything was filled manually and
maintained manually another example is
the traction rule we were using our own
language to describe detection logic for
CMT we call it high level detection
logic well basically everything is
simple at the same time we were
supporting Cubana queries flying queries
and CMT were doing their own stuff and
everything was done manually so just
imagine if you want to add their new
service name for example we have to
update this logic we have to bake when a
query they have to update other things
which require quite a lot of time that's
the simple little bit let's say overview
or the stuff we had this one is a use
case there you can see like biggest
square is a use case with a lot of links
there are the needed logging policy
software and other stuff and everything
was tightly connected so just imagine
for example when we were creating data
needed entity there were no such thing
that we were doing we were putting in
these data into login policy and we
decided one day like well it makes sense
to separate these things and we started
working on you and it's a and they had
to rebuild basically everything change
our links add new links create new
articles for each data needed which took
like two three weeks for two specialists
and that's a lot and we're not counting
the general maintenance another problem
just following from that is that we were
duplicating some stuff but still there
are too many too many places where you
should update it we just you know for
missing some places and that's why in
some lists we were saying these
deprecated alerts or duplicated other
kind of entities so last fall religious
some
horrible number if you think it is small
how about that so you guys it's when are
you maintaining such amount of analytics
manually in web-based engine it became a
madness that's why I last fall we
decided to change and we were inspired
by two projects first there's elastic
comment schema we were contributing to
it at that time and we were really
inspired by the way how they handle
their stuff so you basically update one
configuration file or add something
there edited and execute make command
and after that it's generates
regenerates
all the documentation all the CSV files
all the index templates basically
everything for you in the background
like automatically which is just awesome
another project is Sigma we were using
Sigma in the beginning in the first
version of versions of use case
framework but then we decided to change
to our own logic due to some internal
reasons but last fall we saw huge
community support for this project at
the same time they've started mapping
their rules to miter attack techniques
and that's why we decided to try to use
them again and what's happened then
beautiful integrations automated
workflows big discoveries and also fun
and profit for us and for community and
mattie i'll tell you more about it so
we've a few requirements for ourselves
first of all we wanted to work with
plain text files because they are easier
to manage we could use version control
systems like gate and do some bulk
changes inside of those we decided to
not do any kind of maintenance in web
base editors because that amount of work
which we did in confluence was just
overwhelming and we decided to not do
that anymore
we wanted to MIMO manual job
to be able to focus on more meaningful
work like developing new rules or or
tests and we wanted to and we wanted to
automate everything which was able to be
automated so following that requirements
first of all we wanted something to work
for us as trigger entities and we
decided to use atomic reading for that
and if you are not familiar with this
project it uses Atomics which are tests
mapped to miters techniques and might be
used for testing detection capabilities
and mitigation systems which are
implemented
so those Atomics are stored in Yama
files and they contains actions which
might be executed by adversaries or red
team and what's really cool about this
project is that it also comes with
execution frameworks which basically
made makes all of those tests actionable
so you can prepare a list of tests which
you would like to execute and quickly
execute all of them on your in your test
environment using those frameworks so
once we had something to to test we
needed to detect such activities and for
that we decided to use the Sigma project
if you are not familiar with it it it is
the generic signature format for cm
systems and the real power of it comes
from its converter which is able to
translate rules which are stored in
Sigma format into queries for multiple
cm systems like Splunk elasticsearch
kibana Greylock ArcSight the list of
supported systems is quite huge so
that's only some examples and that's how
sample rule written in Sigma format
looks like as you can see inside the tax
we have mappings to miters techniques
and tactics there are some references
and the conditions which are necessarily
too met for
the rule to trigger on some specific
event so to make those rules works
correctly we have to collect proper data
and to keep track of it of what we have
to collect we've created data needed
entities so here we have the roll
example which you might want to pass to
see empty more data engineers to show
them what what they should expect the
list of the fields redundant ones here
are used for the analytic purposes also
the provider of that lock some
references and was most important it
also leads the logging policies which
are needed to be implemented to collect
some specific data and that's how sample
logging policy entity looks like so as I
said they describe what have to be
configured to collect some data and at
the same time they provide exact steps
which have to be followed to collect
such such to implement those policies
and recently we also created new entity
which is customer and this one allows
you to track which data you are
collecting which logging policy and
which detection rules are implemented
and it's not like this is useful only
for these service providers because for
internal security teams the customer
might be another department remote
office or even some specific assets like
some server or group of of the hosts
going further we've introduced
enrichment entities and those entities
describes how to enrich events with
additional information so here we have
the list of requirements list of events
which might be enriched and description
of the Gulf's on specific enrichment for
example this might be introduction of
new fields renaming or translation of
some of the existing ones and it also
contains the configuration which is
needed to achieve such enrichment
another thing our response actions and
we've created those for incident
response teams so they contains
workflows associated with specific
incident response phases and we are
using them to construct the response
playbooks and response playbooks
are used as incident response plan for
some specific threat and they are using
Xmas actions as building blocks and
since those were written in very
granular way it gives ability to use
same action in insight multiple
playbooks
so if you will update the response
action all of the playbook switch uses
that detection will be updated as well
quite new stuff or visualizations so
here we are aiming for ability of
creation visualization independently
from the system's currently we are
supporting only Cabana but our next goal
is to support this plank as well and in
future maybe other systems so as you can
see it's just the description of what
have to be visual visualize and we are
using them to create the dart boards so
it allows you to create dart board by
just listing the names of visualization
in which we are interested and they
supposed to be shareable and easy to
maintain
so a few words was going under the hood
we separated data logic and presentation
layers from each other
all of our entities are stored in that
TM files which I'll just show to you so
it's easy to do some changes inside of
them or create new stuff for example if
you have some custom logging for
application it shouldn't be a problem to
add them we wrote most of the code in
Python and we wrote few modules to
present that data in in different
formats and calculate some mappings
between them and what's also worth to
mention that we are using the ginger
templates
for human-readable wikis so it's kind of
easy to adjust how how you want to
present it and since it's ginger is also
asks you to create new export formats so
currently we are supporting only
markdown and the confluence but it
shouldn't be a problem to export that
data to other wiki system like media
wiki and small demo time so I would like
to show you step by step kind of
detailed tutorial how to implement
atomic fred coverage inside your
environment so it starts from execution
of Mike utility
and basically that's all that's all you
have to do so what just happened all of
these sub modules which are connected
we're updated in this case it was the
public version of Sigma project and
atomic read but this part is
configurable so if you have your own
private Forks of that projects you can
configure ATC to use those all of the
entities were exported to mark down to
the confluence and additional files with
analytics were created and Daniel will
show you right now how it looks like
after that export and what you can do
with the files which were exported thank
you
so guys I just want to ask you to follow
this QR code or better if you have a
laptop better use this short link to
open our demonstration is available
public but for mobile phones looks
horrible so better to use laptop
basically I'm gonna show you how it
looks like conference and again just to
refresh the what Mateo said everything
which we're gonna show you right now
based on open source Sigma detection
rules and triggers from atomic read
scene and some an open source analytics
from our side like Etta needed login
policies and related things like
response actions alright I hope you
manage to do it so basically that's how
conference looks like as you can see the
structure similar to use case framework
but a bit different so it was created
automatically just please keep it in
mind if you'll open detection rule you
will see this rendered table is all the
mappings clickable links to attack
tactics techniques automatically
calculated data needed entities and
links to them links link it so trigger
which is atomic read same test and also
here you can find the original Sigma
rule which was used to render this page
also if you automatically generated
queries and this list of queries could
be adjusted by units for example if you
need Splunk just add Splunk to
configuration and you will see that
automatically generated query for it so
if we will click two data needed we will
go to this article here you can see a
simple description of what is it and
again very important thing is logging
policies because data need just not
exist by itself you have to configure
something to have this data in
so basically how it works you just
provide CMC link it's the article or
list of links to articles and they just
click into link AHA so I need these data
to have this data need this logging
policy everything is kind of clear
transparent and detailed enough all
right also you see here
definition of tie provider Channel and
list of fields for analytics which I
will show you in a minute at the same
time there is a row log sample which is
required for CM team to explain them
what they should expect on receiver side
alright this running back to detection
rule there is a link to trigger which is
basically original atomic our HCM test
and here we have original article
created by automatically generated by
atomic reading project itself they have
the description from my tree list of
atomic tests and the tests themselves so
basically everything is here presented
in a human readable way also there are
multiple entities but I'm not going to
show you all of them basically you have
a link you can go there yourself and be
limited by time so I will show you only
one more which is response playbook and
again here you can see the same style of
page with links to my track framework
all the mappings from Yama file and if
you remember in Yama file you only had
this links to response actions which are
constructed following the six six steps
instant response lifecycle steps and
here we have description of workflow
again from the same Yama file but at the
same time in the body of this article we
have all the response actions rendered
automatically so basically in case of
phishing attack you just provide this
playbook to shock analysts or instance
responders they following their stuff
but the main power of this entity
ability to export it to the hive
platform you may heard about it but if
you haven't the hive is D I would say
the best or at least most popular free
open-source instant response platform so
atomic fat coverage translate this Yama
file not only to Conference markdown
it's also can create case templates for
the hive basically what you're going to
do we will go to case management or case
templates I don't click import going to
atomic for coverage folder picking up
automatically generated profile or case
template and here we see that this case
template was created and we can create
the case out of it so basically clicking
new case the case template putting there
some random name as you can see all the
mappings already there so that's how it
looks like description from Yama file
all the metrics from again from Yama
file and the response actions mapped as
tasks for this case template and if you
will open it you will see original
description from response actions here
in this task so basically you can assign
this task to some of instant responders
or do it yourself click start and like
you know just general your please follow
your procedure
next one and again here are caught and
again the same I just would like to ask
you to not use your phones for that
better use your laptops if you have such
opportunity because in the mobile
version is looks like really bad so we
will I will show you the analytics
dashboard based on open-source Sigma
rules and again with some our let's say
automatically calculated mappings
alright so here you see description it
says that there are 211 detection rules
or Sigma rules from open source project
we updated it yesterday so it is actual
we provided some extra calculation for
data needed logging policy and there are
test customer entities just to
demonstrate what customer entity was
built for so first row is distribution
of detection rules per my attack tactic
well basically everything is simple here
on this diagram we see that almost like
95 percent of our rules were not
implemented anywhere this way we can
track how many deduction rules we have
in some specific customer environment
implemented next thing is distribution
of data providers per detection rules
here you can see that most of open
source Sigma rules are based on three
providers Sigma sorry sis Mon and
Windows Event log security auditing
provider
next thing is that we can highlight
that's a system on is not just provides
to us majority of the detection rules
it's also providers most of critical
rules so this way you know we can is
explain why we need some specific data
source to leadership or other teams to
basically to anybody next thing is
distribution of development status /
detection rule here you can see that
almost 80 percent of open source signals
have experimental status which means
that you cannot just implement them in
your environment you need some extra
testing on production data or just in
the test lab and depends on your
requirements and only like three
percents stable kind of not defined for
the rest which is also can be used like
if you are saying I need some resources
from my detection lab you can show this
diagram you know kind of supporting also
a few tops like you can see most
detection rules were developed by
foreign Roth one of the authors for
Sigma and another one is says that
majority of like 90% of all rules were
built upon see events IDs six-month
event 81 and windows event ID 46 88 so
basically both are about process
execution this common line alrighty
yeah and the last demonstration for
today expert to attack navigator
if you don't familiar with that this is
a tool for exploration analysis like
mostly for gap analysis it was created
by white ray and before atc we were
developing a technology three profiles
per customer manually you know it's a
handy thing to show to your manager or
to customer like how you're progressing
what is the current coverage which is
kind of questionable but whatever so
what we did we just generate this
profile per customer and for all
existing analytics so basically
everything is already generated for just
picking it up yeah you have to click
like add new layer or new tab open
existing layer open under latex
generated pack navigator and choose what
profile you want later specific customer
just for all of them and here you go
that's the current coverage provided by
Sigma project so that's the that's handy
for again mostly for gap analysis but
not for like coverage analysis so that's
how it looks like
next thing we are not limited to
confluence at the same time regenerates
absolutely the same information we have
in conference in markdown format so you
can use if you don't like confluence and
don't want to pay money or I don't know
any other reasons you can use markdown
renders engines like get lab github or
any others he prefer and you will have
absolutely the same information there
each time execution make we have all the
entire knowledge base in markdown in one
of the folders and repository next thing
is analytics CSV so basically if you
don't like Cubana if you don't have
Cabana for some reason you can just use
analytics CSV it has absolutely the same
data you can answer absolutely the same
questions using filtering or maybe if
your fan of Bosh like cut pipes and
everything use this stuff so here is the
example of filtering for pass the hash
and you can see what data needed you
need for that also there is a mapping to
triggers again logging policy like
always that I need it always came with
working policies and everything else
next one which is also quite important
called pivoting CSV this file destined C
provide you with information where you
can get some specific data type like
hash for example what kind of data
source can provide you with this
information like you need hash for
example so you put there a hash and it
shows you the list of data needed or log
sources where you can find this hash
which is quite handy for triage and
initial response and basically you know
for understanding so as he remember we
created another entity called dashboards
with simple lists two links sorry for
two other visualizations and we
automatically converted to a JSON file
for Cubana of
you can automatically or manually upload
this JSON if you have this kind of
dashboard we also have it in our
demonstration version it's available
this using the same link or QR code and
we built this dashboard with mordor
project data tomorrow Roberta will
present this project and tell you more
about it but just it's worth to mention
that there is something to see to just
check how it works and why it is
important handy useful and everything
else alright
I think summarizes stuff first of all we
had if he expected process which are
working with text files not working with
web which is my end goal so basically we
now use our favorite IDE or do bulk
changes using bash or Python or anything
we want use git flow CI and everything
to you know just just for like for
general programming or development use
the merge requests push requests and
everything and to check new
contributions for other team members or
from other even teams like if cm guys
want to add some information no problems
use git flow will review your stuff and
merge it if it's ok or provide v's
information about you supposed to change
which is quite handy so basically it's
some sort of analytics as a code not
automation we don't do almost like
anything manually not nothing manually
we don't do mapping inside confluence we
don't do we don't support these three
girls in the conference we don't support
detection logic and the confluence
basically everything generated by itself
and everybody has all the time the
actual information so which is like just
great for now we work only on meaningful
data doing research doing development
and the rest is automated so it's just
fine
at the same time our data is compatible
with community projects like Sigma
atomic ransom so basically we can just
do git pull pull data from their project
and automatically natively integrated to
our environment which is also just great
I have to speed up see there are a few
expected pros first of all
visualizations of existing on Linux as I
said we started with generating of
analytic CSV files but then we realize
that why don't we generate elastic
search index analyze all the stuff
inside Cubana we just did and you saw
what was the result so for now cm team
has their own dashboard to track
implementation like they see how many
detection rules they can implement and
there is at least what kind of logging
policies the data in the date should
collect and everything at the same time
our leadership has their own dashboard
where they see how we're progressing
like how many detection rules will be
implemented how many how they were
changing this time and everything like
that at the same time it's all automated
automatically sorry such a horrible
thing updated automatically just we
updated something like new deduction
rules added something or updated conf
customer entity executed make and all
the information were pushed to all
kibana duck navigator everywhere
basically everywhere so each time
somebody opening this dashboard
everything is brand new updated and
actual alright I will skip this part
last point and just jump into goals and
plans first of all we want to simulate
of atomic red team and Sigma projects
format use it is obvious because more
contributors they have more interesting
and valuable
analysis we can do and provide back to
community at the same time we will have
more interesting ideas analytics
execution frameworks and converters
which is also great
another thing is utilization of my tree
attack
I believe we all community are as a
community need more projects with Maya
attacked Agins in first example of such
project is Metasploit just imagine what
will happen if we will attack all the
post exploitation modules of Metasploit
there are basically more than three
hundreds of them
we will dramatically increase our
simulation testing ability another thing
is that there is no project for
automated hardening these mapping Tamiya
attack there are lots of projects which
do hardening do using ansible or other
configuration management systems but
none of them use my to attack attacks so
we cannot implement it so if you guys
were seeking for a project to do like
next couple of months or maybe years
it's a good one so you can find us we
can discuss it may be provided with some
help or you know advices anything you're
welcome with that and last but not least
this week in Brussels on e mitotic
workshop we gonna present our definition
of coverage / completeness of coverage
for technique major attack technique we
will discuss it with community and based
on final let's say decision if I
probably will initiate a few coordinated
sprints working on some specific gaps we
will identify together with the experts
from the community all right thank you
for your attention if you guys have any
questions we would love to answer them
but I see that time is just no thanks
that new things but I was yeah we have
we have a few minutes for the questions
so if you have any question please raise
your hand and we will provide you a
microphone up there
so I know you used to mention using the
hive for your response framework
have you do you know if anyone's been
experimenting with using this with any
of the other security automation
platforms de misto phantom etc because
it seems I'm really curious about how
well we could get this in use by the
commercial products as well mm-hmm
we had the conversation in first TC in
Amsterdam last month with guys from Palo
Alto they just acquired the Mistah and
one of them was exactly from the mr and
they told me that they were also trying
to implement like new playbook format
but they were using JSON and there is
idea to invent or I don't know proposed
common format for play books which would
be like human and machine readable we
believe Yama is the best for that and
our format is kind of a cage so there is
an ongoing conversation about the common
format for instant response platforms
and maybe in the near future we will
have something like common format which
will be supported by most of at least
instant response platforms and I cannot
say anything more about other like EDRs
or anything like this
no information about it yeah guys you've
solved I'm here thank you
guys you've solved a lot of my questions
that I had when I was working in a sock
it's really impressive how do you handle
say customers that have their own
opinions how incidents should have been
handled I mean are there like
customizations for a given customer or
do you kind of erase this format
convincing enough for them to actually
do it the right way well basically
is a quite interesting question thank
you for us like as a project issues like
it flow and anything isn't a problem to
create like fork their customer and
basically that's how it works so we
don't like to share information between
customers and if they have some specific
requirements it's not a problem to
implement like response action
specifically for the customer for
customer environment and map them to
playbook so it's it's just highly like
very flexible no problems with that
[Applause]
you