thank you thank you all right all right
thank you very much yes so that's here I
came here to talk about a couple of
things about graphene and just analytics
but then you know when I came back I
started thinking about all the other
things that are beneficial before even
going forward for you know talking about
analytics is to understand your data so
today we're gonna be talking about data
and also it might attack framework so
you guys already heard from me
so if you go to that you know link at
the bottom it's pretty much my github if
you want to talk about a few projects
with me I would love to do that because
I like to talk about you know helping
all these things so and I'm also a
former capital once in your thread
hunter in Virginia and there is what I
started also working with a lot of I
would say data like more than you know
300,000 endpoints and you know then
including the cloud so I think that
wasn't like an awesome experience to
know exactly you know how it goes from
ten thousand two thousand endpoints all
the way to a massive amount of data
hi everyone my name is Jose I call by
cyber panda in Twitter I'm currently a
cybersecurity students are not the
Virginia Community College in the US I'd
like to contribute to open source
projects with my brother and also a
former senior business intelligence
analyst from UNICEF Peru oh and you can
follow me inside rewarded sorry I didn't
mention that okay so the agenda for
today we're going to be talking about a
little bit you know three hunting
programs with data all the way to start
you know coming up with a methodology to
start mapping your windows event logs or
your you know security in general
security event logs in general to the
attack framework for example and then
we're going to talk about a little bit
about more than at the end and you guys
are gonna know why in a little bit so
three hunting and data so I believe that
a lot of organizations are doing this
already right they're putting together
their programs they're doing all the way
from the pre hunt activities all the way
to defining their hypothesis analytics
hunting you know reporting all the way
to enhance and security controls
everybody's doing that already right the
problem that I see a lot every time I go
to a company is that they focus so much
on that you know but they don't focus at
all into this primer they have which is
there's a lot of
there's a lot of data that is being
generated that if you don't understand
exactly what that data is then it's hard
to implement all the other processes you
know you have in there some other
organizations are even skipping some of
the steps on their own programs and
they're just giving a console a search
bar to a security analyst and say go on
hunt and all they do is it just Google
they find a script or it find a specific
query they run it and they just call it
a day and they say this is a hunting
engagement so there's a lot of things
going on right all the way from a basic
program all the way to just giving a
search bar but I did know the day if you
don't care about your data it doesn't
matter what you're doing talent
technology it doesn't matter if you're
the best of hunting if you have a data
swamp rather than a data Lake is gonna
be very very hard to even do your job
and I have experienced that I actually
have performed IR and also hunting
engagements on that and it's not fun at
all it is very painful and a lot of
people just get frustrated because
that's one of the biggest problems out
there we talked about how to do you know
procedures how to put together your
program some nicest lights about how you
can link your different teams together
and all this stuff you know work
together with a red team it's amazing
right but in reality when you go to your
organization that's the problem at the
end and that's gonna force define if
you're gonna be successful or not so you
might be asking yourself okay so more
data there more problems yes I know so
if you have data it's gonna be great if
you wanna do an investigation if you're
going to use it to you know find
anomalies outliers and things like that
but at the same time you have to
understand what it is that you're
actually collecting and when I ask this
question
it actually has another question which
is do you know what you're collecting
and do you know what data you're
collecting two different questions
because when I said do you know what
you're collecting the answers are yes
I'm collecting process monitoring I use
my EDR I use this maaan I'm collecting
all this my question is no no but do you
really know what you're collecting what
is the data behind those data categories
or names that you have in an excel sheet
you know what's going on with those
events do you understand exactly what's
under that and most of the time the
answer is no so how you might be doing
it to start at least getting a little
bit closer to talking about data and
also your hunting engagements so a lot
of organizations that we go to right
my attack came last year to talk about
you know their emulation plans and
things like that and it's been for the
past year and I have a belief he's being
crazy the amount of people that I talked
to in the implement minor attack so that
should be pretty much everywhere in your
hunting program in some organizations
that I go to they say hey I have an idea
minor attack has these you know metadata
called data sources and I can start
mapping all my controls to those data
sources that are gonna map to a
technique so easy right and then before
we continue a data source for minor
attack is considered a you know
information collected by a sensor in
order to allow you you know to validate
a detection of an adversary technique so
if we take this concept right you can go
from a pilla technique to data sources
that will map to other things in might
attack which is awesome how you can just
you know have relationships in there and
you can just start doing this right and
a lot of companies have solved this
right they think that they have solved
this they say my taxes process
monitoring I have my Eevee are minor
attacks is Windows security event logs I
have my domain controller and that's it
they just you know check the box and I
already have my coverage well that's in
work like that right we have you know
windows security van locks we have more
than 400 events if you map a technique
to Windows Windows security events
you're mapping 400 more than 400 events
to just one your data source and there
is not a way to understand exactly what
it is that you need per technique if you
only say I need Windows Event data
sources so if you're doing this and you
feel you don't have to move forward
right you might be asking yourself why
are we here right the main goal is to
start sharing a little bit of the value
of it is to understand data and when you
start hunting at the same time we want
to define a methodology to allow
companies to start mapping their
security events all the way to to attack
data source and at the end of the day
also we want to make sure that at this
conference which I like the concept from
a blue and red team perspective if
you're a blue I want you to understand
exactly you know what data sources you
can use to validate a detection of
specific techniques and from our Red
Team perspective what actually you look
like in the environment every action
that you make
or take it's going to be locked
somewhere or somehow so we want to make
sure that we identify how you can start
mapping actions of an adversary to
specific events as well so we're
focusing on these you know right now so
we're gonna start defining the
methodology and it's gonna be very
simple
I mean we're gonna just start going
through attack data sources all the way
to start mapping specific events to
attack and we're gonna start doing some
validation to make sure that our
mappings of security events to certain
actions actually make sense when you
star you know put it in against in a
specific technique or variation of a
technique so we're gonna explore attack
first and how do we do that
oh but first before that you know people
also ask me why do you use attack to
start mapping data sources why you know
do I need attack I can do it myself just
without thinking about attack what
attack is a great I would say project or
framework to start and then you can
build on the top of that right cuz
nothing is perfect right you can build
on the top of that and if you feel that
something could be updated you know it's
an opportunity for collaboration don't
reinvent the wheel right if you're gonna
start creating your own categories
mapped to your own techniques that
sounds to me like miter attack already
so you should be able to at least use
something that's out there for the
community and start building on the top
of that the way how I access my tower
attack is by querying the data through
their public taxi server in sticks
content it might ask yourself what's
taxing the sticks so I have this slice
inside here so taxi would be just the
application a application protocol to
exchange cyber threat intelligence over
HTTP and we have his sticks it's pretty
much the language the format were the
data ax is you know presented in
serialized as well so for example on May
4th of last year miter attack pretty
much announced that they were pushing
all their information as well into this
public taxi server so when we talk about
sticks data that's an example how a
technique turns into an attack pattern
grouped an instruction set and so on so
you have to now understand what it means
when you query data directly from the
taxi server so because of that I build
my own library or I will call it more
like a wrapper on the top of
is to libraries Python sticks and
clients and taxi Kline and those two
allow me to play with that data query
the data and it starts serializing it
and transforming it in any way that I
want or filtering the data as well you
can install this it's pretty much a via
pip just pip install I updated yesterday
I like to update my tools before talking
it's pain in the ass because because
sometimes you're like this is gonna be
awesome then something breaks and then
you have to make sure that it's done
before that presentation and there is
also a couple of jupiter notebooks which
arches you know web documents that
allows you to you know run queries in a
specific programming language you can
save the output on that document and you
can share that document with anybody
else that's a beauty of that so there is
a folder for that any all the
instructions on how to do it so now you
have a way to use the library to query a
minor attack or you can use the jupiter
notebook where you can use use the
library and still map minor attack so
what does that look like right so you
just pretty much import the library you
initialize a specific class and then you
pretty much you know do dot and tap and
it was going to show you all these
specific methods that are available the
reason why I do this is because if you
are using the miter attack or just a
miter itself the miter sticks in
libraries you have to write a lot of
different lines of code in order just to
make a simple query like give me all the
techniques from your database with this
tool you can just do all techniques
equal to using the method get all
techniques and you get every single
technique in a Stix object format and
you can just play with that data and you
can use import it to another application
you can do you know whatever you want
with it if you want to do it through the
website good luck taking snapshot of
every technique and then put it in a
format that you want so this at least
allows you to have everything
programmatic whole way so if you want to
have attack in your applications this
would be a good way to do it keep in
mind there is 500 techniques apparently
for the whole all the matrices in might
attack there is this concept of you know
revoked techniques so minor attack
pretty much will save techniques as well
that have
disable or revoked or light a canal so
you have to make sure that if you work
with minor attack data through their
api's you take the revoked ones ow
there is a method that allows you to see
a specific technique just by the name
and as you can see there is a specific
field that says revoked so I did that
for you already you can use use another
method called remote you know remove
revoked and you can get pretty much all
the techniques that are available in the
minor attack framework you can play with
those and you know start understanding
the data sources behind each technique
which is my main goal so the minor
attack team distributed East 485
techniques in three matrices is the
enterprise the mobile and the pre attack
matrix these are the last the last
numbers we have after applying our
library now from a data source
perspective almost 50% of the techniques
have data sources the question here is
what's happening with the other half
part of techniques right so basically
the idea here is this could be the
reason this is this is happening is
because maybe some of these techniques
are not happening inside your
environment where your sensors where
were your sensors are collecting data
such as for example the pre attack
techniques or this is also an
opportunity to collaborate with the
attack team
if we split all the techniques with and
without data sources by matrices right
we can find that all the techniques that
do have data sources belongs to the
enterprise attack something very
interesting is that there are four
techniques from the enterprise attack
that do not have data sources so this is
a big opportunity for us to collaborate
with the attack team yep so there's
something you can do this weekend if you
don't have anything going on yeah you
can you can do this conference now
looking at information about all the
data sources that we have in the middle
attack framework the most relevant data
sources are process monitoring file
monitoring and process command-line and
this is because for example with process
monitoring you can start analyzing or
validating the detection of at least 169
techniques out of the 214
before we continue with our analysis of
the attack framework there is something
very interesting here is there are some
data sources names that are related to a
specific that for in this case windows
windows yep yeah they are related to the
Windows platform so only you can do you
know with these libraries you can get
all the techniques by a data source so
in this case if I want to know all the
techniques that are mapped to PowerShell
logs there is actually four of them and
if you go just do a basic loop please
you know don't judge my Python I'm
actually still learning Python you can
actually get a technique map to a
platform and as you can see two out of
the four are mapped to more platforms
beyond just windows so that's very
interesting cuz when you start playing
with this data you gotta be careful
because you cannot just say one data
source PowerShell locks is helping me in
you know three meters I'm sorry in three
platforms Mac OS and in Linux and
windows so you know keep that in mind
when you do this type of analysis yeah
so and if we apply the same concept for
all these data sources PowerShell WMI
windows are all reporting Windows
registry or windows even logs we need to
be careful if we have these data sources
we cannot consider that we are covering
all the made all the platform
right these data sources only works for
Windows so we need to be careful with
that now going back to our graph is we
we already said that the process
monitoring is that the most relevant
data source right because it's from a
coverage perspective you can answer
analyzing at least 169 techniques but
the question is can we only use one data
source right to analyze the variation of
a specific technique well the answer is
that we can only do that in 2121
techniques the other 219 techniques
requires at least two data sources so
for for us the number of data sources
that you require or the order that are
recommended to validate the detection of
a specific technique is related to how
much context you need from your data to
validate that the detection mm-hmm so
now we are not talking about just one
data source we're talking about groups
of data sources right so this is the top
15 groups of data sources that the
attack team recommends to work together
right all the techniques in this case
for example file moratorium process
command line and process monitoring if
you start collecting these three data
sources you can assign a list at least
42 techniques yeah it's like at least 42
that require the combination but of
course if you look up the first you know
you one two three at least it covers you
know combination of file monitoring and
process monitoring only so the idea with
this is that I have clients that say I'm
good with 169 techniques because I do
have process monitoring that's it you
know so we're just gonna go with it no
it doesn't work like that right that's
just part of the context that you need
to do analysis so now that we understand
at least attack data sources from their
perspective right that's something that
they're providing to us so we can at
least get some information we can start
documenting event locks that are might
be related to those data sources every
time we think about this technique for
example they recommend these three data
sources right away you think about 46 ad
a from a Windows security event logs and
that covers both of the you know data
sources
we actually have a recommendation that
process command lines should be inside
of the other one but that's something
that we can talk about later but this is
beyond just 460 a process monitoring
could mean process termination it could
mean process monitoring creation from
another data source or a process
accessing a process process right into a
process there's a lot of things that can
happen with a process monitoring
perspective so you need to define that
and document that otherwise it's not
gonna be valuable at the end so you can
start doing this by you know applying
this concept that I learned also from
from working at Capital One which is the
data dictionary concept which you have
to define and understand what it is that
you're getting for each event all the
way from the fuel level to the
description of the field you can talk
about data types as well so the way you
understand what it is that your aquarium
is this an integer and string and this
is very interesting for example if we
look at event ID 3 we have like source
port destination port those are
numerical values right those are
integers but what can I do with that we
can start doing something basic like if
we take for example one field we can
just do basic stat counting we can see
the most frequent least frequent you
know ports being used pretty much over
time we can do a lot of stuff like that
but when you start thinking about this
is a number this is a number so I can
actually do some type of descriptive
descriptive statistics average max
medium so can I do that yes you can but
at the end of the day if you do that to
a port I don't think that that's gonna
have any meaning to you you cannot
connect to app or you know 10.5 you know
point 5 6 7 because that's the average
of ports in my environment it doesn't
work like that right so when you talk
about that concept then you have to
understand the events themselves and the
types in a different way as well because
if we see this column of type of data
right is giving us more an idea of the
format of the data right but if we use
another perspective let's use a
mathematical perspective if we start
consider describing our data with type
of data it could be qualitative or
quantitative data qualitative data the
concepts really basic you can describe
your values using letter
numbers or or symbols and in
quantitative data you can use only
numbers to represent your values right
so the idea is for example Roberto
already talked about source port value
the source port value gets or poor value
so this value is a quantitative discrete
value what is the meaning of a discrete
value is like in a range of value you
can only have a specific values right so
using the descriptive analytics like the
mean or the average sorry the average or
maybe the standard deviation right so
most of the time the value is not going
to it's not going to mean anything but
for example if we apply the same concept
for a quantitative continuous data which
is in a range of of data you will have
infinite values right
like for example bytes in or out your
network you can find what is the mean
the standard deviation all these
descriptive statistics in if you put
these information in a graph that you
supports plot graph you can start
identifying what values are outliers or
a typic in your environment so that's
the way you can use these maths approach
to prioritize your actions or yeah so
for example yesterday I was talking
about a little bit for example someone
asked about and someone asked me about
machine learning and all the stuff out
there and to me saying well if we're
gonna talk about machine learning and
all these concepts that are crazy out
there that everybody uses for marketing
from our perspective we need to
understand this the data to be described
like this if I don't understand my data
described that way I cannot come up with
a use case for any specific data source
so we're gonna be doing is actually
creating data dictionaries that gives me
a basic data type for a format but then
also give you a little bit of the
mathematical type for that feel and
that's what if you talk to a data
scientist they love that because they
want to know exactly what are the values
are gonna be working with so they know
what they can apply to that specific
data so that's you know very very useful
another reason why you should be doing
this especially from the red team you
know perspective so our colleagues well
my colleague Mac raver and you know Lee
Christensen does their presentation in
black cat last year they
about documenting sis Mon for example
what a specific feels there's gonna be
the attack influence rating it's gonna
be higher what are the fields that they
can actually manipulate in one of the
fields that you know they can easily
just touch and then change well they
have to do data dictionaries in order to
understand that so if a red teamer is
doing it why isn't a blue team we're
doing it as well so in general we all
need to be doing data dictionaries for
the data that we collect and the data
that we generate as well so it goes for
both sides next step we're going to
develop a data model in a data model now
that we understand our data from an
attack perspective now that we
understand our data also that were
collecting from specific field levels
descriptions we can install now defining
the structure or understanding the
structure of our data miner has their
own data model that's the link over
there and they also use once again
sticks definitions or specifications to
map specific objects that they can
identify on the data sources when you
think about a data model some of you
guys understand these concepts might be
thinking about a database well it's you
know a similar concept how you can start
structuring your data so that it makes
sense to be store in a database right
this apply this gets applied also to for
example CDI right when you can use a
basic graph knowledge for example to
start mapping specific entities each
entity can have a specific properties
inside and you keep a relationship
across all of them why can't we start
doing that with you know fear you know
security event logs for example we have
every event log that we have we're gonna
identify a user a potential process an
IP a file well there's kind of peer
relationships across these entities that
we find in our event logs all those
events have you know properties and they
also have relationships that we can
identify across those events at the end
of the day if you're doing sis Mon you
can actually have this type of basic
data model which allows you to
understand what it is that you can do
with system on this is very helpful for
an instant response perspective for
example if somebody finds an IP or a
process you can pretty much think about
the other possibilities that might be
attached to that specific you know
entity for example or from a hunting
perspective or from a Red Team
perspective if I'm making a specific
action that's what it will look like on
sis Mon you can apply this on enterprise
tool like carbon black and as you can
see this
a similar way if you start reading one
by one you can pretty much see also
carbon black giving you certain
relationships in the data so that's very
important because that's how you can
actually start telling somebody I do
need simple sis Mon I don't need this
man I need an easier solution or I don't
need an easier solution you have to be
able to define that if you can do that
if you say that you want to use an EDR
because I have some cool shirts in a
nice calendar you know good luck with
that it needs to be defined this way you
know from our perspective so going back
to our technique from attack from a data
source perspective now that we
understand what are the different events
that might provide specific sub data
sources for the attack data source in
there we can apply our data model and
it's star mapping what are the
relationships that we find in each sub
data source that then will be related
back to an attack data source this is
very interesting because then I'm going
deeper into what does attack data source
actually mean to me so when we talk
about now process monitoring then I
understand now that this means something
like this now not just a data source
name that I just mapped to a tool
directly now there is a process in
between I can do the same thing with
registry for example right I can find
relationships inside of my data sources
that provide those sub data sources map
to attack data source but this is very
interesting because I'm identifying
relationships about a process in the
registry but what if I want to do a user
point to a registry if you're using
system on system does not give you that
right system does not give you the user
name so if you're running an analytic
saying username blob and this is
monumentally twelve thirteen or fourteen
you're not gonna get anything and you
might think it's a high-fidelity rule
right if you want to do some type of
registry map to a user you might need a
cycle right a cycle pretty much is a
system access control list you can use
this cycle map to a you know system on
in for example registry if I map if I
create a cycle on the system registry
every time I adversary wants to query or
access information about system own
through the registry I'll be able to get
this event which is gonna give me the
specific user is
give me the registry map to a process so
that's very interesting to me because
from a red team's perspective this is
what you will look like if you query
this Mon and I have a cycle in it and
from a you know from a detection
perspective I want to know that I have
some use cases that I can work with I
have process to a registry and user to a
registry as well so you know today you
might be asking yourself okay it still
does not make sense right yeah this is
probably a little you know like I don't
understand how this could be helpful
when I execute a hundred stuff like that
let's say we're using WMI to spawn a new
agent to move laterally right so you can
just do that with Empires module from a
detection perspective it looks like this
to me there is an authentication going
on specific port every time you do an
execution through WMI on the destination
it's going to be hosted by WMI prvs see
as a parent process and then the parent
execute whatever you wanted to execute
and if you are doing it to launch an
asian it's going to then make a network
connection i can map that with my data
model and say i have event to be one and
three they both can be joined by a
specific field the process good and I
can actually say I have W my prvc as a
parent I don't care about a child if the
adversary uses PowerShell Cmdr any other
process that they want to use or names
or anything I don't care about that I
want I care about the specific behavior
going on in here W am i executing
something and then making a network
connection that could be translated to a
query for example a basic sequel query
which can be used by any other tools
that support sequel right so you can
pretty much have this and I did another
day you'll be able to find that type of
behavior which these slides are gonna be
available so the query pretty much was
put on the top do this in your
environment try to find every single
parent process that is W my that is
executing something that that makes a
network connection that does not happen
that often so now that we understand our
data which occupant it all the way to
the fuel level we understand the
specific data types we understand
destruction of our data relationship
that we can find we're gonna start then
now mapping it all the way to attack in
a way that will make more sense to me
where I could say I have
data I have a specific event IDs map to
an a specific relation that I can find
all my data sources all the way back to
an attack data source for example that
to me is so valuable because I will be
able now to understand that I have
certain possibilities just by one
specific attack data source and I can
also create built on the top of attack
and say every time we say process
monitoring those are the possibilities
that we have and of course those will
change depending on the variant if the
variant of the technique calls for a
process accessing a process or writing
to you know to a specific thread in the
process then now you can pretty much say
this technique requires process
monitoring and requires process right
into another process pretty much so you
know the data idea is to have this
documented in a way that will make sense
I have this link in a project called
awesome that is going to allow you to
see exactly what certain actions mean
back to an event ID I show these sort of
red teamers they loved it because now
they say if I go to this list I can just
type if I want to look at relationship
between a process to a user or a user to
an ad object I just filter all this and
I can find all the event IDs that will
give me that relationship and then they
can pretty much go on and do whatever
they want with it it's in this project
right here you have dictionaries data
model the mapping to attack and also a
common information model it's a it's a
project that we're building to start
documenting all this so we're doing a
lot of the heavy work already we will
have to uh you know love some
contributors and you know see where this
actually takes us and we have
conversations with attack to update
their attack data sources to sub data
sources so you know so that will be
interesting to you know see that
happening as well so how does that look
like from a hunting perspective now that
we understand the methodology well you
have to understand that if you have a
program like this you have to understand
where data actually fits data will fit
before you even try to build your
analytic because otherwise you will not
understand the analytic itself or the
possibilities that you can use with the
data to build potential analytics
analytics by the way goes all the way
from the basic query all the way to a
put
no statistical model the loser was
talking about possibly sorry I call in
which all the tankers how we talk to
each other and then data also fits
before you even execute the hunt and
that will define if you're gonna be
successful or not if you have this crazy
technology people with so much talent
dream team right dream team in there
going on hunt and you're not collecting
the data that you were defining or
analytic good luck with that so the data
quality assessments which are also part
of other presentations that we talked
about are very important as well but we
just want to talk about how data really
will define how successful you could be
for an engagement so we're gonna just do
a quick validation in here we're gonna
talk about overpass the hash in this
case we have this technique pass the
hash first right which is the basic
concept is to use you know to
authenticate to a box you know without
using the explicit credentials or clear
text from a user that's just basis of
pass a hash it is a variation of penser
hash right there is an overpass de hash
which is gonna use Kerberos
authentication right you can pretty much
get that ticket or that hash and you can
pretty much you know use it to request a
ticket so what does that look like just
in case the basics of you know Kerberos
right you have your password gets you
know go through a you know one-way
function depends on the functionality of
your domain controller you have a
specific keys you can use that key then
to request a ticket get the ticket back
use that ticket to request all our
service tickets and then you can pretty
much access other services in the
network there's the basics of Kerberos
overpass the hash
basically just gets the key or the hash
that was just stolen and you can use
that to pretty much start the whole
Kerberos process as well this is a
question for red teamers and blue
teamers which one is mimic ads in which
one is Rubeus
and we will talk about rubio's in a
little bit but at least which one is
mimic as anybody left or right okay time
is up well your mimikatz is the left and
Ruby's is the right we have sacrificial
logon sessions being done by mimikatz
when it does the overpass a hash the
reason they do that is because they
don't want to deal with the current
logon session so they
create a sacrificial Allen session they
inject the hash into else's point into
that session and then that pretty much
kicks in the whole Kerberos
authentication process with Rubeus you
have a similar concept but Rubeus does
not touch else s does not want to deal
with that and crafts the whole packets
to request a ticket gets a ticket back
parses it in them and then imports it to
the sacrificial logon session so it
hasn't led else as doing it Rubeus is a
tool built by harm joy or a wielder from
inspector ops and it uses you know
c-sharp to start also providing most of
the functionalities of kikyo a project
also by Benjamin Delpy and I'm gonna do
a quick demo into how exactly that works
and so the way we have some time still
cool so if I just execute this what can
I just do an hour pass the hash we're
gonna use Pedro is my dog like I'm gonna
make him famous and then we have the the
commands that we're gonna use with
Rovio's we have our victim it's an admin
we do have our domain controller and
then what I do with my victim is a try
to understand if it's possible to query
you know do a directory listing on the
domain controller of course access the
nine pedro has access to that and i only
have two hash so let's just use Rufus
for that and it creates a new process
which is gonna be the one with the
sacrificial logon session and then
reviews already imported a ticket on
that session so I should be able then to
query write the domain controller
nothing crazy
I mean this has been done but you may
because for years but the process you
can see where ruby is is going to create
a process with net only it's gonna do a
lot on type nine new credentials using
the hash that wasn't stolen and it's
going to of course you know create a
requests or crafted it's gonna receive
the ticket before it's connecting to the
domain controller over pour eight eight
it's gonna request a ticket get to take
it back and then each is imports the
ticket so that's very interesting it's
actually pretty cool
you're pretty cool attack so let's just
go back to this from current slide yep
okay so it's pretty cool right because
now we have this behavior that we
identify them from from Rubeus we can
start mapping reviews to specific
actions going on in here
where we can see successful
authentication locally we logon type 9
with new credentials we can see also
reviews creating a process but then at
the same time we can see also reviews
connecting to the domain controller and
then at the end it's gonna be the one
handle in the hole Kerberos indication I
can start mapping all that for example
to specific events so I can at least say
this is what I would like to use from a
relevant data source perspective to
start approaching you don't move this a
little bit one interesting piece in here
is that you can see I have system event
ID 3 and you know five one five six from
security I've seen clients saying I
don't need system or some other people
say I don't need security locks because
this one is doing it well you have to
understand that system for example gives
you the username and the destination
host and how do we know this because
we're doing data dictionaries right
there's no other way to know what fields
are available when you do it with five
one five six you don't get that
information so if you're looking for
stacking the values of users five one
five six will not be your friend right
this one will be your friend you can do
this still find the user if you link it
with another event that will match for
example in a specific behavior or you
can do like a time-based type of
analysis but it gets a little
complicated so you have to know which
events will give you what when we talk
about authentication also here with
reviews and mimic ads for example you
can see the mimic ads right it's going
to patch Alsace and then let's Alsace do
the whole process Rubeus is not going to
bother Alsace so at the end of the day
you have this process that is not Alsace
it's not a system user and it doesn't
have the signatures or anything from
Alsace and it's just talking to port 88
for example so from a system perspective
you get more information right you get
the system user you have a regular user
probably you know the
it needs to be of course and that mean
administrator can account and then at
the end you get information about how it
connects to the domain controller
through poor 8a
so the other day if I can throw this to
my either lab environment or to my to my
environment in production I can see that
if I look for destination port 88 I will
be able to find that most of them will
be else as doing all that do this when
you go back to your organization please
because I've done it in a couple of
organizations and you will be surprised
that there is only a few applications
performing these connections to a domain
controller through port 8080 and so it's
very interesting to start using that
data and to start probably finding
potential rubyists like type of behavior
right because we cannot just say you're
gonna find Rufio stat Exe right
but at least you're gonna find the
behavior itself is very very interesting
from a sacrificial logon session which
one is mimic as in which one is Rubeus
which means mimikatz left or right all
right
there's a quiz for infra red teamers and
blue teamers somebody said right I heard
somebody said right but mimikatz is the
left and rubio's is the right and
probably have more information in here
that's because when you do a sacrificial
law one session you're just doing random
dummy username domain and passwords to
create that process with the sacrificial
logon session mimikatz takes the you
know parameters that you use for you
know for user for in domain and then at
the end you can pretty much have that in
the log so me Macca's who actually
improve my perspective right now it
would be boo blend in a little bit more
than Rubeus as you can see because
review has a random strings that's
because there is a specific function
they're being used that applies the you
know random strings for the values of
the username domain and password so you
know that's what rules does it so very
interesting also you know thing to look
at and at the end of the day you can
find more sacrificial organizations
across your network if you're collecting
the right data we have mimic ants
we have reviews and we have also you
know bypass you otoki manipulation for
example so that's the one from toka
manipulation of course that could be
adjusted but if somebody's using this
type of behavior at least you know that
that data set would allow you to you
know get to that specific type of
behavior you might be asking yourself
okay that's awesome how do I learn about
these things also from a data
perspective like I don't have the
expertise to do all these executions of
of all these techniques there is a
project that will release a couple weeks
ago called Mordor has you know pre
security you know events generated by
specific techniques and you might be
asking yourself why do we know this or
you don't need this and this is of
course a you know map to the might
attack framework as well that's because
if you want to do something like this is
sync and you say I want to learn about
this sync you know like the abuse of AD
replication services because I know that
my domain admins have this permission so
they can do it so if somebody if there
is replication in my environment
happening from a non domain computer
from a known domain controller account
and it's happening from somebody else
that doesn't have the dollar sign at the
end that is part of my domain controller
name you're gonna start doing this and
crazy you know building your detection
lab and then stand in all these boxes
and trying to do all these things then
you're gonna find specific ways to do it
through PowerShell Python through pure
that net just can do whatever the data
is gonna be similar the relevant data
associated with that behavior is gonna
be a similar data set okay I can do it
through impact it cool I can do this
I'm not touching or not my users I'm
just doing a whole relay as well if I
could date is going to be the same the
data is going to still generate this
event which is going to tell me there is
a some type of access you know request
to a domain object with the you know
replication also you know permissions as
well so the goal of Mordor is to allow
you to for us to share those data sets
because we're ready to care of the whole
execution if you want to learn about
execution due for example the atomic
read team project if you want to focus
on the data directly you can use model
and how does that work you can consume
the data
the Kafka cat which is a tool that would
allow me to grab the JSON files push
into a Kafka broker and then you can
pretty much you know you say with else
tax to Paterno books any other
application that can consume that data
as well this is how easy is Kafka CAD
pointing to a Kafka broker the help
comes actually with a broker itself so
you can use point it to the to the port
a specific port specific topic and then
it's gonna be in what is called producer
mode point it to the specific JSON file
that we share and you're gonna have data
in two seconds you can pretty much run a
query on that data and you'll be able to
find whatever it was a DC sync type of
attack so this is very interesting
because now you can do your analysis on
data set that has been already created
in an environment that was similar to
also a minor attack uses for the evils
with three computers domain controller a
specific collector and inside that so
we're doing all the stuff and it's
already documented what's next for
Mordor and I only have a few seconds we
want to release today we're gonna
announce the apt three the data set
because last year the attack team came
with apt three emulation talk and that
was also from a Red Team perspective I
got the inspiration from that talk from
here and now I'm bringing the data set
which you can watch the other
presentation about how they did it I can
show you the data set as well so you
know the day you can pretty much point
it to the apt three data set and you
will be able to have the data as well
and before I leave to the last my last
thing here it's already there at least
the definition of the apt three data set
I do have this specific I would say
resource files that are used for Empire
and at the end of the day you can pretty
much start playing with this I'm
releasing the data set at the end of the
week because I want to make sure that
everything loose it was good in there
but at least all the things that are
used are in there and you can actually
also access the specific file that was
used as the playbook
because miter attack shared their
playbook but they only share Metasploit
and the other one is well Kabul strike I
actually was able to map that all the
way to PowerShell Empire so I have every
single every single command mapped to a
technique mapped on a specific step on
the eval for mitre attack and now you
have the data set as well and that would
be it let me just go back here thank you
very much everybody and I hope that you
guys enjoyed the presentation and these
are some links for you also to go back
with thank you guys
you