I have the unique pleasure of
introducing another longtime friend of
mine and a longtime friend of all of
ours here at tour started the day with a
longtime friend and closing out the day
with a longtime friends so it makes a
wonderful set of bookends makes me
really happy
we've got metrics here talking about
data security how to avoid an
embarrassing breach so please welcome
him to the final talk of the day all
right so I have basically worked in
information security for over 15 years
I've done quite a few interesting things
in regard to Incident Response I
basically have presented a torque on and
torque on Seattle and derbycon
and layer1 all the good ones so
essentially I'm glad to have been
selected to be the alternate this talk
is eventually going to go ahead and
cover data and a lot of people don't
actually think about data as far as how
we handle it how expansive it is and
things like that so we're going to cover
the history of data security the way we
used to do things and why we used to do
them the way that we used to do them a
data security lifecycle data
classification and types of data that
actually exist so questions are usually
brought up I actually get paid quite a
lot to go ahead and solve these issues
and how do I solve it there are elements
of data security they're elements in
actually all of information security
which would be people process and
technology so I will also cover the
industry standards we will do some
threat modeling the tabletop
exercises and talk about architecture so
why would we need data security
essentially a lot of people have now
started thinking about data security due
to privacy laws gdpr
if you guys haven't been paying
attention those are all the emails that
you've been spammed the thing is is it
actually does have some meat behind it
and the fact that it wants certain data
types actually categorized cataloged and
able to be essentially dealt with so if
I'm a European citizen if I want my data
deleted I can go ahead and have that
data deleted if I am a European citizen
and you gave my data to a third party
I can ask who you gave my data to so in
general knowing what type of data you
have and how to catalogue it is pretty
good but this is not that talk so it's
kind of bad because we all use acronyms
and nobody knows what the hell is going
on as far as these things here's some
real fun ones
Dhar dim DLP UBA pH I PII IP
you're gonna know more Darr data rest
dim Dayton motion DLP data loss
prevention UVA this UVA is actually
supposedly the new hotness when you go
ahead and implement it it's user
behavioral analysis which uses AI and
machine learning which we know doesn't
really work that well but essentially
what it's supposed to do is it's
supposed to work in tandem with user
intent so if I'm stealing all your
documents essentially if it's a part of
my normal business process and it's a
business process that's broken it will
attempt to go ahead and if I stick a USB
in there and I'm starting to take the
secret formula for Coke that should
never happen so it's going to actually
say what is this document what is this
easier doing with this document are they
actually supposed to have access to it
and if not it's going to go ahead and
kick off flags and somebody should be
able to respond to it
thi is protected health information PII
is personally identifiable information
and then we have intellectual property
IP so if we go way way way way back the
internet ARPANET essentially it was only
a concept in 1969 nobody thought that we
were going to have the clewd the
Internet's and now what and all that
stuff ARPANET changed the DARPA net and
back again so we could actually go ahead
and spread data with inner connectivity
to increase research we kind of also
shot ourselves in the foot with that
because now everything as far as data
moves around when we ended World War two
we
actually had a Cold War which was a lot
of research and development and since we
could actually transfer this data back
and forth we needed to go ahead and
figure out how to prevent the leakage of
the secret to our missiles our space
program and everything else if you are
ACS cissp and you passed the exam you
actually should know what I'm gonna go
ahead and show if you got it and you
still don't get it
I feel sorry because then it is really a
mill so there are two types of models
that existed so the Biba model was
developed in 1975 specifically to go
ahead and prevent corruption of data
corruption of data is essentially the
integrity of it and it is in a read up
and write down manner
so essentially you can only create
content at or below the integrity level
so think about it as you have the
hierarchy of monks and only the the top
priests can go ahead and write the
scriptures and the interns can only read
it they can't write it so you're
protecting the integrity of data by
making sure only the highest authority
writes the data the next methodology is
basically the Bela padula model in 1972
and these actually go back and forth and
contradict one another so this one is
called write up read down so you take
your average ordinary office worker and
they're going to go ahead and build
something
and what it is is I have office clerks
who get news feeds
they basically write it and essentially
the way that the data is protected is
it's only at your level so think of it
as you're a scientist creating something
for the space program you can create the
top-secret files but you can't create
the public files in the sense of you
wrote it
a person who has higher clearance than
you can go ahead and read down a general
can definitely go ahead and read them so
that they actually have these specifics
as to the data but if I am NOT in a
classified area or have the clearance to
go ahead and access that data I cannot
actually access the data so we built
machines back in the 80s specifically to
have MLS which is multi-level security
we don't actually have machines capable
of doing that with this built in so what
that means is my particular box a
mainframe or an as400 or something that
was built during the Cold War
essentially have different security
levels so the IBM as/400 which is now
the iSeries essentially still has as
Cold War controls in it a lot of people
don't turn them on unfortunately so if I
turn a iSeries as400 platform into a
level 4 it is going to strictly enforce
the database so that if you do not have
the proper clearance you actually cannot
access the data
so it follows that that model the ward
the write up and read down so whatever
level you are you basically write it you
have access to it and people higher than
your level can read it so the thing of
it is is these were designed back in the
day once again during the Cold War and
essentially memory is protected memory
space is protected databases were
segmented you could have multi-tenant
things on there and be assured that
unless you have the proper clearance
level it wasn't going to happen and
specter and meltdown would not be a
thing in this environment so it's kind
of funny because seadragon awesome guy
awesome friend it's like his twitter has
given up on sanity and have decided i'm
going to retire too nice a s400
somewhere in new zealand when it's time
to unplug so in other words he's saying
i want to go to a very very very secure
environment and i want to be segmented
and only people who need to have access
to me can have that access so also we
had things back in the day as far as
data custodian roles we have gone ahead
and pretty much gotten rid of that
because it's a cost center so who here
remembers a large green bar paper yeah
that was the way he used to get things
he didn't get an actual database extract
you didn't get anything if you were
lucky and it was approved a data
custodian would print out all your data
and then you would get a big big green
bar sheet and that's a way that it was
and gee there were no breaches
[Laughter]
so the other thing is is backups were a
part of this role so specter and
meltdown or ransomware rather ransomware
if you lost all your stuff this was the
guys job he basically protects the data
so he validates that backups are done
he validates that people with the proper
access levels to the backups get the
data back and essentially ensured that
any of the data that was stored never
went bad and it's correct we don't do
this anymore we have fast business let's
throw it in the clewd let's give it to
everyone let's set up Hadoop to throw
our data everywhere even though it's
unsanitized we have no idea what that
data is so given the fact that we've
moved to the fast business model it
requires that we have all the things
let's have all the data all the time
everywhere we don't care what it is and
that's why I said the GDP our thing
that's kind of gonna have to change
things for people because you can't put
that type of data anywhere and not know
where it is
so hey why don't we go ahead and give an
API rights to the entire database yeah
that's happened that's a breach let's
take a mainframe environment or in a
s400 environment which is pretty locked
down and you don't actually get access
to it and just throw it everywhere or
even worse that public bucket that's
three it's just data let's move it
better that's happened
we now interrupt this talk to ask why
the hell would you do that why is this
wood flailed his arms so we brought
virtual viz yeah I think you're cutting
out alright so what changed why did we
go ahead and have the advent of breeches
yeah we got Internet
we got email let's go ahead and take the
formula to Coke and email it to the
marketing team great
we got cloud instances like the s3
buckets
we've got laptop computers that could
actually be encrypted but I find it very
very very highly unlikely because most
people don't have the maturity to even
have a proper image on a laptop computer
we've got people who store them on their
phone and then that goes to iCloud we
then we got Dropbox mass storage the
size of your fingernail your smallest
fingernail and of course internet a
alright so going back to the way that
data should be protected and for all the
CIS ESPYs you already know that they
changed it to the AIC triad it's more
politically correct so you have this
triad and it's a triangle and what you
should be thinking about as far as your
data is one availability is it always
accessible to me as a business or an
individual because I need that data I
need confidentiality when I have this
data are the right people accessing it
am i giving it away is it in the public
cloud and then you need to
have the last triad of integrity is my
data correct so going back to the two
models that I had previously talked
about you have the confidentiality part
which is the read up write down and then
you have the Biba model for integrity so
essentially what is the attack vector
for confidentiality exfiltration
and other people who should not be
accessing that data what is the
integrity well we can't go ahead and
change your FICO score just because we
want to and what is the availability I
got to be able to access my data every
time all the time so this is a data
security lifecycle there are a couple
things that I feel are missing as far as
it so when you work with data
essentially it starts at the create area
and then it's stored then it's used and
it needs to be shared and then archived
and most importantly destroyed so when I
go into a client the first thing I
usually ask them is ok I need to see
what your standards and policies are and
they usually go these and they're so
poorly written that they don't really
have a chance in hell and actually going
ahead and fixing it so the first thing I
want to go ahead and do is look at what
I can destroy and that's going to be
retention so once again you can't exfil
what ain't around if you delete it yeah
I can't take it the thing of it is
we need to go ahead and destroy data and
not be afraid to go ahead and delete it
there are regulatory things like if
you're in a bank you have to keep data
for seven years I'm kind of stuck on
that seven years it's not changeable
whatsoever if I'm in certain government
places I have to keep data for up to
fourteen years but you should make sure
that when you have this talk you make
sure that you do have a retention policy
that will go ahead and ensure that you
don't have any issues with retention I
would say your most dangerous person in
your organization our data hoarders ask
Sony how those unencrypted PST files
help them a lot or embarrass them a lot
that was really really really bad and it
had nothing to even do with actual
business things personal emails leaked
so data hoarders are dangerous and
people can't steal what's deleted so
essentially let's say I'm an Rd house or
I'm designing things and I have
intellectual property I need these old
designs to design things better I can't
actually go ahead and destroy them so
this is where we talk about the actual
archive area and essentially what do we
see people making mistakes on every time
they archive them they don't know what
they actually were backing up to begin
with so it is important that you
reconsider things as far as
basically making it harder for your
attacker so you can go ahead and solve
this one of two ways you can encrypt all
the archives or backups or you can use
rights management and essentially even
if that data is exfilled it's pretty
useless
so backups aren't even a part of that
that little circle thing that I actually
showed you and now even more than ever
now it's going to be much more important
because the whole city the city of
Atlanta essentially lost their whole
infrastructure and didn't have any
backups and the backups that they did
have were about five years to old so I
was pretty much disastrous so once again
we need to ensure that backups actually
work and if they go missing on a truck
that went to the something Mountain
place they should be encrypted or all
the good stuff should have rights
management so once again even if I'm hit
with ransomware I still am operational
at least I can come back within a day or
48 hours worth I don't know any of too
many organizations who have actually not
lost more than two weeks worth of work
so that's something you want to actually
look at in your organization on average
when I've done Incident Response and
we've had to take machines offline it's
usually about a month's worth the data
that was behind because we can't
actually go ahead and take something off
production so things you can go ahead
and do to make sure is that you run
systems in parallel to do high
availability and at least have those
warm transfers databases are the
absolute horriblest ones to try and do
because there's just too many
transactions and the only thing I
suggest and those things are to actually
run two databases in hot swappable h.a
and all the databases are correct and
you encrypt the hell out of it and
essentially monitor the actual tables
that you actually understand to be very
sensitive so data classification we go
back to that little circle thing and
it's the actual create mode so which
came first chicken or the egg
well you created the file what are you
going to go ahead and do as far as deal
with it
I suggest that by the time you create a
file you should actually go ahead and
classify the data reasons are you don't
have the excusive I didn't know what
data is dealing with so I didn't know I
wasn't supposed to sending the stuff out
other technologies actually rely on this
so I was talking about UVA which is the
user behavioral analysis as well as data
loss prevention they suck you cannot
actually get any of the data loss
prevention or UVA things to actually
work it's not going to happen
once again magical AI and machine
learning it just doesn't do it the other
thing is is I can't turn on DLP to
actually be an active block mode because
there's too much critical things that
may go out so if I block an executive
from doing a sales guy from actually
doing the million dollar deal because he
actually had to send out stuff that we
approved yeah I'm probably going to be
fired if I block that
but if we actually go ahead and have
classification with meta tags that
actual AI and machine learning can
actually take the real meta tag and go
this is classified at this person's
level once again the read up write down
they are authorized to send it to XYZ
this is a normal part of their business
process I don't care it's three o'clock
in the morning it's an email it's going
out they're cleared to do this type of
thing that's proper way to actual have a
monitor mode and actually have awed it
it's better to actually go ahead and
block than it is to actually attempt to
just do monitor mode your sock will
never catch it all that data will be
exhaled we've done all kinds of
interesting things to solve these
solutions we've done hey if you see 500
credit cards block it credit cards are
super easy to go ahead and do because we
have a loon on the rythm what about all
the states different states driver's
license a New York drivers license
cannot be done via loon it doesn't have
a pattern it's all over the damn place
so if I have a thousand New York
driver's license go out they will go out
and I'm gonna let it go out but or I'm
gonna be blocking everything it's just
not very elegant so I highly recommend
that you look into some type of data
classification to actually tag and use
metadata for the actual document upon
creation there are very very very good
ones so somebody asked me wants to go
ahead and explain how this all works so
data classification we have a single
file that little drop single file not a
problem
petabytes of the I can't even sew
from drop to flood where the hell does
it go so I walk into a organization they
have MCS and have everything they have
petabytes hundreds of terabytes of data
they ask me hey I need you to find all
the PII can you tell me why the PII is
I'm like ah no so you have to start
somewhere so to solve these problems
what I actually go ahead and do is I
usually implement data classification
start meta tagging things and since I
know data is like water the drops are
gonna actually follow the rest of the
flood
so once I've actually gone ahead and
tagged it I start looking for what I
tagged and if I found some good stuff
I'm guaranteed to go ahead and find
where the rest of it is instead of
actually trying to actually scan the
entire petabyte because I can't do
enough distributed computing and
especially if it's a database to go scan
a database that would take it down I
can't do that because they're gonna say
well you need to scan the database you
can only do it every window but that
will affect my backups and then you
can't do it so what I like to do is as I
said make sure you tag it and then just
start following it and you're definitely
guaranteed to go ahead and find it so
the benefits of actually doing data
classification as an exercise
implementing in technology are one I
know what to go ahead and back up I know
how recent these things are so if I
actually start doing the metadata tags I
can go ahead and say show me all the
things that were tagged that have
confidential information
and start backing that up I know I need
to back that up it also shows me date
that it was last accessed and last
touched once again that discovery thing
I was talking about find me all my data
I just follow the rest of the data you
can then go ahead and consider smarter
security architecture in the fact that
nobody does defense in depth right
because they're trying to defend all
things as I was talking about to help
along the machine learning and III I
have to rely on those meta tags if I
want to do rights management correctly
and make sure that I properly locked
down particular files that contain
things that I need hey I can prove that
it was done because of data
classification and I get a general
situational awareness now I will say if
you do choose a vendor who does data
classification you need to have a vendor
that will actually go ahead and watch
the state of the file from cradle to
grave so I create a document and maybe
an Excel spreadsheet I may have first
names and last names nobody cares about
that that's cool but then I give it to
jail he had telephone numbers in there
and then I give it to another guy oh we
have their social security numbers in
that excel spreadsheet now your
particular data classification software
should actually start noticing that this
document has been changed
it wasn't sensitive it wasn't
confidential and oh crap now we have
SSNs first names last names it needs to
retag that as actually a sensitive
classification
all right so we have types of data
there's structured data this is the
easiest to deal with structured data is
essentially all your databases all your
asked 400 systems run databases and
actually control the tables a lot of
customers asked me to do the wrong thing
all my good stuff is in the database I
need to go ahead and protect this yes we
know you need to go ahead and protect
this but databases were inherently built
to be pretty secure
in most situations as they've been
around forever and most designs came
from the earlier designs that I was
talking about unless people actually run
ese so the one that's the hardest
unstructured data anything that you can
create on one of these personal machines
so we've got Hadoop databases we've got
pictures we've got source code source
code is damn near impossible to deduct
and I would never ever try and even do
any data loss prevention at all without
using tagging because when you use data
loss prevention and you actually try and
use the algorithm for source code which
is crap it usually is done on an end
point and essentially it causes your
developers too much grief and they can't
get their work done but if I have a tag
that I can look more on the network the
the classified tag I can actually find
that source code real quick
so how do I solve this I talked about
the people the processes and technology
first thing I usually have to do when I
go to a customer is figure out who's in
charge of all this stuff usually it's
been some IT security manager who has
been tasked with well they told me I
have to do this stuff and I usually go
alright so who's cutting the check for
me to be here ok let's go ahead and talk
to those people all right so your boss
wanted you to do this we're gonna need
more than your boss we need legal we
need HR we need everybody so we start
with how much of a budget do you
actually have to do this with and I'm
gonna have to figure out how to go ahead
and phase this usually it's going to be
you are not mature enough to even
monitor things in the sock yeah let's
try data classification it actually
usually works pretty well and then the
organization in itself becomes aware of
the fact that we have more data that was
sensitive than we think
then I've got legal and HR to go ahead
and talk about policies and the
standards and then of course enforcement
if you actually are stealing from the
company so once again it's all people in
an organization that use any of these
data protection products data
classification you have to get them to
actively participate if you get your
people who are creating these things to
actually tag these things really
accurate my actual classification
software can actually start noticing the
patterns of what is truly classified and
actually start auto correcting and auto
tagging based on the cons
that you're actually putting in
processes well I've got to educate all
the users as far as data classification
I've also introduced a brand new tool
into their environment to go ahead and
tag this so the effective ones as far as
products use plugins and when you're
creating a document it literally makes
you the first thing I do before I can
even save is what type of document is
this how do I classify this I would
recommend highly that that product that
you get force the person to actually
think about what it is so when you save
the document and won't actually save you
then have to go ahead and match all the
technology with your processes so any of
these processes the processes or
controls when I was talking about
standards and policies those should be
published on your company intranet
everybody should actually know about
that and there is no excuse to not know
what they are if there is then they need
to be referred to it and taught and one
of the other things is the actual
enforcement which is I need HR and legal
to actually if somebody's purposely
sticking things on USBs and I have proof
that they are and they're not supposed
to handle that data you need to go can't
work for me anymore so Brian Krebs is
not a DLP solution don't use him unless
you just essentially use things in
monitor so for technology there are
things in the stack that you can go
ahead and throw in there for data
classification and metadata tagging
there's a discovery tools data loss
prevention
Cosby rights management public key
infrastructure encryption and database
access monitoring and firewall I am not
actually going to go ahead and name
vendors because I'm not pitching anybody
and I really don't care to do this in a
talk but no matter what I buy none of
this is going to work if you leave
these tools in monitor mode and you
don't invest the time to actually tune
them so don't waste your money don't
waste your time don't buy any of this
crap if you're not gonna actually invest
time to actually make this work all
right so if you actually wanted to go
ahead and research this more there is
something called the CMM I data maturity
model I do not remember or ghen ization
z-- because you have to be able to crawl
before you can walk
but supposedly this data maturity model
is what good looks like if you want to
see what it looks like it's definitely a
thing to aspire to do I don't know
anybody who hasn't been like PCI qsa not
actually go through the correct controls
they just check box it's sad and it
doesn't work but it is it looks nice
it's pretty so what could go wrong let's
go ahead and switch to other things I've
gotta love the new stuff
I'm 38 this happened the last
presentation PowerPoint essentially
changed itself to - no focus and I'm
using PDFs for other things
all right so I had to do this exercise
with a place that actually had an
intellectual property and they didn't
actually understand how data security
works and they didn't understand why it
would be of any value to them in fact
some of them were developers and
absolutely wanted me to do this in a
waterfall thing and I'm like what the
hell are you talking about
so I did a waterfall diagram in any case
what I had to go ahead and do is break
it down to stupid things so we were
doing the data maturity model so I had
to cover each thing so you look at the
top it's risk what most of us care about
being the people that we are in InfoSec
just go straight to threat model and
vector so the threat model for cloud
risk reduction is I'm unable to go ahead
and provide legal hold materials because
I don't know what what date I have so
guess what if I don't know where the
data is and somebody puts the legal hold
on me they can say that whole server is
on legal hold I'm so screwed if I have
things there that shouldn't be there I'm
also unable to comply with regulatory
requirements such as gdpr which is what
did you do with my data did you delete
it where did it go so to go ahead and
actually tell the people why this is an
important thing how I'm going to go
ahead and reduce risk other than use the
data maturity model essentially if I put
in some type of ediscovery based on what
I had put together on data
classification I should be able to have
an accurate data inventory of what it is
that is on that machine I will know
whether it is in scope and can talk to
my legal department and say absolutely
not you may not put this on legal hold
because it has nothing to do
with what we were doing data
exfiltration once again what I don't
have on my server can't be sniffling but
gdpr
is absolutely funny because they want us
to tell you exactly what was done in 72
hours in a event of a breach
I can't they're they're they're no
companies that I know that even know
what assets were hit in 72 hours let
alone can tell you oh this this this
over here it contained SS ends and
pictures and IP addresses and and yeah
it was breached I've never ever seen
anybody who could do that
ever so once again a threat model
backups that have not been verified how
do I reduce the risk and why do I want
to reduce risk well if I have good
backups essentially I can reduce risk by
making sure that ransomware hits I'm not
affected for 48 hours of loss RM minus
RF somebody deleted everything by
accident yeah we're good that's happened
where people just accidentally deleted
everything that they were supposed to to
actually have left all right so let's go
back to the slideshow
so those were the few tabletop exercises
you should be thinking about this in
ways that you can explain to when you
threat model you should have in mind
three different audiences they're going
to be the exact so I need to get my
crayons out for they're going to be the
technical people who will go ahead and
implement this but to have no reason why
they're going to implement this and how
that it should be implemented so if
you're doing a good job you should
actually have the controls and then you
put technology in place to actually
abide by those controls so hackers want
crown jewels how did I protect them well
I need to know where they are you need
to go ahead and essentially have
perimeters so if I know that my
databases have all the good stuff and I
know that if you file servers have what
it is that I want I need to define my
defenses around it back when I was
talking about the way that computers
were designed earlier there was a thing
called Mac mandatory access control
essentially that data never ever left
ever and you can actually go ahead and
download or do some more research about
mandatory access control those
particular computers are still around
and when SELinux was actually put
together a long time ago you could
actually turn that on that hadn't been
around in quite some time
another thing that you can go ahead and
do is I would say anybody holding
sensitive data you could actually go
ahead and risk model the user if this
guy has access to my sensitive data all
the time
and if he's failing the fishing internal
attacks yes straight to VDI to you you
don't get to go ahead and even access
anything with important data but once
again that goes back to the
classification I need to know where my
good stuff is don't be afraid to go
ahead and find leaks by using honey
docks I purposely want to know where
things are being egress to the honey
dock essentially gives me a call back
and gives me an IP address another
company is out there and they were very
controversial because not only did they
do the beacon they actually did a net
count a call back you can buy those
things but I'm not gonna go into that
encrypt your data use PKI
make sure all of the things that you put
in your stack are not in monitor mode
and essentially if I have to go ahead
and transport data from one country to
another I need to ensure that I know
what type of risk that data has with it
and essentially if I have to have my day
to leave the environment and essentially
move from one place to another I need
that stuff classified and I need that
stuff under rights management or
encrypted so going back to the sensitive
data people yeah you fail the phishing
attempt you get to use VDI and that's
all you use that's basically it and
there is no bar here but if you have
questions go ahead yes
your creation of data
have I worked with any companies on
limiting their creation of data no I
have not in most cases it's going to be
a retention issue that I actually have
to start deleting things I would like to
do that but once again that's just not
how things work well I would love to say
if you don't need to make it don't make
it but we also run things in that fast
business pace where it's like first to
market and stupidity and yeah I'm going
to save everything or hoard everything
so pretty much so so once again data
hoarders are my most dangerous adversary
to my my client or company or things
like that yes
but now that
so that's another thing that I actually
blew by and supposedly the only pure way
to go ahead and deal with this so we
were talking he asked the question of
how do I deal with data that now has
become sensitive and could go ahead and
reveal something let's just say a health
thing that I don't want revealed got
into that spreadsheet and I can't
actually divulge that how do I make that
anonymous that's through a the only
proper way to do it is using a
technology called tokenization so you
have to go ahead and find some type of
the technology that will actually assign
some other value that cannot be
associated with the first value and
that's tokenization which a lot of
things are being done for GDP or right
now but you have to be very careful
because once again keys are created and
a legend is created for that
tokenization so if you have the actual
master list of all that stuff even
though I've pseudo anonymized it by
tokenization
it's not anonymous so people make that
mistake too all right I think I'm out of
time and yeah come and see me if you
want to any time and just to be clear
there are actually at least one bar and
a speakeasy sitting somewhere on camp
but metrics can take questions where he
wants thank you for filling in for us
again the talk that we had here
originally will be Saturday at 3 on the
maker stage so if you want to catch that
it's been moved it should be already
updated in the schedules that are on the
monitor and if you know someone there as
an icebreaker tonight introduce yourself
and say hey do you own a subaru from
oregon or a gray BMW from washington
they're in the long term parking we need
them moved don't don't set things on
fire if you have cigarettes be
respectful and put them out in a proper
place the ground the oh we have the the
but buckets sitting around put them in
there and no amplified music after 10
p.m. and have a great time tonight
everyone thank you for showing up for
the first day that's the end of the
first day's worth the talks thank you