and I guess without further ado let's
welcome Justin here to talk about threat
modeling thank you very much my name is
Justin Goodheart I'm from Olympia
Washington part of the only mega group
here hanging out helping out and I'm
here to talk about threat modeling and
try not to do feedback so if I lean
forward I started out with doing
development work for about 13 years and
then at one point they shifted and
pulled me over into the security team
and so I got a chance to start trying to
help developers write more secure code
better quality code and over the years
I've been able to help out with threat
modeling able to help out with scare
code static code analysis different
talks and pretty much just trying to be
a good member of the community how many
folks have done threat modeling before
show hands nice those who didn't raise
their hand
I could probably guarantee that you have
done some former threat modeling a good
example is with traffic driving around
obeying the speed limit signs doing
maintenance on your car being able to
keep an eye out for the drivers around
you especially those who are driving
erratically or who are on their phone
while shaving and putting on makeup so
what you're doing is you're putting in
different controls to try to reduce the
threats that could go against you
so obeying the speed limit science
keeping your distance from the car in
front of you making sure your vehicle
has been properly maintained so it
doesn't break down on the side of the
road those kind of things is what we are
trying to encourage the developers in
doing when they're building applications
and when they're taking a look at
implementing new systems we want them to
see what kind of threats are there see
what kind of things to avoid see what
they can put in place in order to try to
reduce the risk to the application
I missed the slide there it is so
certain out I was going to talk about
application threat modeling and then I
have a couple slides on network threat
modeling as well kind of a new area I'm
diving into threat modeling is where
have most my experience though so
application threat modeling is approach
for analyzing the security of
application or system so a good
opportunity in order to be able to take
a look at how it's documented how it's
built how you have put in the different
uh negations in place and it also helps
with the developers to get a chance to
work with the security team in order to
learn more and do cross collaboration
because there's things developers have
figured out to make things better they
could help security and then there's
areas where security gets a chance to
collaborate with developers to help
their code and their systems be more
secure so the process threat modeling
process is pretty much breaking down the
system then we do is you determine what
the threats are and then you go through
and you identify the countermeasures so
mitigations or controls you can put in
place to reduce the risk potentially
also eliminating risk usually that means
get rid of the feature but most what we
do with application threat modeling is
we start with the data flow diagram a
good conceptual diagram of the system
using some simple shapes the different
shapes are external entity so a
different system or potentially like
some one another company systems or
another internal system that you're
using or interfacing with maybe even a
third-party service you have a process
this is where the work is actually done
in the system so a function could be a
web service you can look at like the
application itself as its own process
the data flow so where the data is going
back and forth and that's what you're
trying to focus on and then data store
where the data it lands where the file
shares are or your data stores like your
database may be a flat file that you're
storing somewhere or some data and then
trust boundaries is something a little
bit different from
traditional data flow diagrams that
threat models use and that shows going
from one security context to another so
like a good example on a web server you
have different rights that you're
running as than you would if you're
connecting from a browser or the
settings that you have on a database is
going to be different than your web
server so you have different contexts
that you're transferring from and so we
want to show those lines in order to
show when you're going from one context
to another a good example of a dad one
of the diagrams for a threat model is
just one of the canned ones I found
online from Microsoft and this one shows
a user browser the users coming in
through a user interface service goes
over to user profile service that has
its own data store and it also
incorporates in a newsfeed service that
it also has its own back-end data store
but also can push out RSS feeds to the
Internet what we do is we start out with
the diagram here and we sit down and we
label each and every interaction going
from one process to the data flow or
from the data flow across the trust
boundary or going into another data
store and we want to make sure stuff
that we could actually reference that
one pinpoint and this was kind of a
sloppy normally the numbers are much
better and you break it down more detail
but this is kind of overlaying then once
you have your interactions on the
diagram you go ahead and you sit down
any show at each one of those steps
where it crosses over from across trust
boundaries across processes and you
should identify the stride stride is a
different threat categories but each one
has each of the different processes
external interactors data stores etc
have a different potential threat area
let me go into that a little bit so
stride is spoofing tampering repudiation
information disclosure denial service
and elevation privilege and we see if we
go back one
probably should shift these slides
around so that I go through stride
before talking about the matrix so
old-school what we do is we sit down
with this matrix and we break down after
you've identified all the different
elements on the diagram and we figure
out what threats were there and so we
sit down and we go okay we're going from
this point to that point and we'd sit
down and go okay they're spoofing and
there is repudiation and then we move on
to the next one
and so it's kind of a manual process
using this matrix later on I'll show you
a tool that Microsoft provides for free
that helps determine the threats
automatically make it a little bit
easier so spoofing is trying to pretend
that you're someone or that you're
something that you're not so a good
example is if I was to go up and say
that I'm Bill Gates
I'd have to prove it and usually we do
that through some sort of factor
authentication sometimes multi factors
sometimes single factor and you're
trying to prove that entity well
sometimes you're interfacing with
another service some third party that
third party you want to be able to prove
that that really is who you're talking
to and so you're trying to reduce the
potential of an attacker or someone or
maybe in a mistake configuration and
talking to someone that you're not
supposed to be talking to or gonna be
someone that they're not tampering this
is where you've changed in the data
either across the wire or at rest
or you're editing it when you're not
authorized to do so so being able to
capture it across the wire inject
something also potentially compromised
into files on the network share some
like that repudiation is basically a
legal term for being able to prove that
something happened usually we do this
through a lot mitigated through logs and
our to prove usually also the third
party good example what you're buying
stock and you go in there and you say
okay the stocks coming down it's about
fifteen dollars a share and you go ahead
and you buy a hundred shares but then
you see it drop another five dollars
so you call up the company you say hey I
didn't buy it at $15 I really bought it
at 10 well in order to be able to reduce
the someone trying to pull scam or
something over they have a trusted third
party that timestamps the interaction
how much it cost the time and you could
prove that when you bought it you really
bought it at $15 a share that's a good
example - also the checks in the mail so
you call it the collectors call you and
you're talking to on the phone you say
well the checks in the mail
well way for them to prove that the
check was in the mail on that particular
day the post office will stamp the
envelopes are going through the post
office with their own time stamp and
they're a third party that doesn't care
if you pay your bill on time or not and
so that works for non-repudiation not
the good kind of fun example information
disclosure is very similar to tampering
except this time is unauthorized viewing
of the data so you've been able to gain
access to a file you've been able to see
what's going across the wire than when
you're a supposed to now this has also a
lot when you're getting into
confidential data that a lot of folks
are not authorized to see denial service
is always fun this is where be able to
prevent something from running beyond to
prevent someone from getting to your
service be able to prevent it from
sowing into your website
denial service also has fun stuff with
the distributed DDoS attacks or what
happened last night I guess with the
wireless were conveniently went down for
a little while
elevation privilege and this is where
you can inject something in in order to
be able to get more rights than you were
authorized in half so some folks do this
through probably sequel injection
cross-site scripting to be able to gain
access to different areas or be able to
change something they're supposed to be
able to change or to try to change the
context that they're running ass in
order to be able to have more rights
admin rights other rights back about
2003 I think it was the trustworthy
computing initiative that Bill Gates put
out with a simple memo they started
working on being able to show
different ways of identifying a scale
for the risk of the system and they use
an acronym called dread and it stands
for damaged repudiate read
reproducibility I could say it exploit
ability affected users and
discoverability and the whole goal was
as you sit there with the big room of
folks and you go down each one of these
giving it to a scale of 1 to 5 and so
you could sit there and you could debate
over is it really a three is it a four
who wins and what ends up happening is
you end up going through and identifying
what the risk score is for that
particular threat and lessons learned
they ended up shift in it because there
was too many folks fighting over the
different scales to be able to go for a
high medium low so if you sit down in
the group and someone goes well I think
this is gonna be really bad because it
will impact us it will affect 10,000
users we're gonna set it as high and
it's a lot easier to sell a high medium
low than it is to go through each of
these and have a D of five and a R of
one an eighth a of three and what does
that mean kind of thing so high medium
low works much better when you're going
through threat models then you go in and
you start addressing each as well kind
of bring it back make sure that what's
going on my head you guys are actually
understanding too so you've gone through
you've documented a system you created a
conceptual diagram you've now marked
each of the interactions you've gone
through and you determine what kind of
threats are happening in each of those
interactions and you've gone through and
you've identified the risk of that
particular threat now it's time to
mitigate it so there's four main ways of
mitigating threats and it kind of it's
very similar to dealing with risk and
you can mitigate the threat by adding in
a control some way of you know to reduce
the potential of that threat being
exploited you can eliminate the threat
which usually means you're getting rid
of that feature you getting rid of that
system sometimes program folks will come
up to you and say we really need to have
this system in order to track this
and then they just want to be able to
put it into a Microsoft Access file put
it on the network share and think that
it's gonna be safe or even better
someone in the office admin assistant
knows how to build access forms and they
lock it down with a password but they
keep forgetting that you just hold on
the shift key open up the Access file
and bypass everything so a little the
risk is there so sometimes the better
bet is to either get rid of that
particular data store and say maybe
there's a better way or be able to
transfer it over like the next one where
you shift it over to another system or
you had extra insurance in order to be
able to deal with the risk or you deal
with a third party tool trying to
transfer that particular threat over
somewhere else and then there's always
accepting the risk and accepting the
risk could be very dangerous
folks are usually quicker to accept the
risk of assist a threat or of a bad
system than they are to actually address
it because I think it's going to take
more time more energy a lot more
fighting just to do it right and so
managers usually will just blindly
accept the trick there is to make sure
you document it make sure they
understand what the risk is and make
sure that they understand what could
happen if it goes wrong and even better
is when you could get the development
team to come back later and note out how
they would fix it if they were told to
go fix it in event of a breach or some
sort of incident but another kind of
thing I picked up in one of my studies
sometimes worry is a sign that the risk
hasn't been fully accepted or that risk
acceptance was inappropriate so you
start going down the path they've
already said we're going to accept the
risk and then now the manager is a
little worried about it or the dev team
manager or someone else release manager
and they start to question whether or
not that risk is worth it you should
probably try to circle back around and
reevaluate to see if there should be
some other control in place or what you
could do in order to bill to reduce that
risk so if you decide to go ahead and
mitigate there's two main ways and stuff
that
you can mitigate a threat design the
security control that will protect it
and that's where you go through the
different common mitigations like sequel
injection threats sequel injection
threat you use parameters queries your
threats gone you make sure you could use
third-party tools like candy the NAD
framework which does parameterize
queries behind the scenes you can in
some cases when you're doing more
dynamic script incorporates something
like sanitization and also input
validation but the best bet is to use
like parameters queries and you put it
in that control of using parameters
queries that threat goes away identify
that we are then accepting the risk and
this is the second option and this one I
also kind of note it's really good to
document it and also what you would do
if it was exploited because that having
that list there it helps you reduce the
time after you've identified that
there's been an incident before you
could have a fix in place or a hotfix in
place another good thing when you're
going through a threat modeling with a
team is to sit down with them and say
what are some of the common ones that we
have and as you start going through the
threat models start making a list of the
different threats and how you would how
you mitigated in that particular project
this list eventually builds up into a
nice library a reference library you
could refer back to how do we fix it in
the other project what do we do last
project or last year and you can start
seeing okay we saw this again how do we
fix it before this is a real quick easy
way or how can we make it better and
circle back and fix the application from
last year and so you get a chance to nor
to uses reference library but it also
builds up the team because as you go
through it more often they have a point
of reference they can study up on it we
have lessons learned and then another
good thing to do is look out at the
different articles and blogs and
different feeds that come in talk about
security related issues because that
Brent builds an awareness with your dev
team a security team as well being able
to know what's out there what kind of
events are happening
what kind of threats are on the horizon
what are folks finding what the new
technology is coming out and when it
does is it helps build that team up with
their understanding and the better the
understanding the more they collaborate
when they come across a particular
threat in the system that they have
dealt with before so an iterative
approach so just when you think it's
over you get to go through it again and
my organization a lot of the developers
they'll build the threat model and then
they walk away from it and they go build
something else that doesn't exactly
follow the threat model that's a very
bad approach so I'm constantly trying to
get them back in the room when things
are changing to reevaluate how they have
addressed that threat what the system
looks like maybe you even recreate the
threat model after the fact in order to
make sure it's more accurate and then
help identify if there any of there any
threats that we did not mitigate or we
didn't know we're there and so practice
makes perfect
and it really pays off and so as you get
a chance to go through a few it also
builds up more confidence with your dev
team because they've gone through it a
few times they're more familiar with it
they get faster going through the
threats and this is a diagram I pulled
for more of an agile process but the
idea is that you have that requirement
that vision that you want to build comes
in you model it create the conceptual
diagram you go ahead and you figure I
didn't identify the threats you figure
out the controls you're going to put in
and that's where you enumerate through
the threats and then you go ahead and
you build out your mitigations and then
you do a validation step and you could
use different tools for the validation
step like static code analysis peer
review so really good you also have the
Chancellor to pull the security team if
you have one in order to take a look at
the code at the system helping them with
the validation Quality Assurance testers
are really good allies to have when
you're dealing with the validation step
two because they could find functional
bugs that would also resolve in a
security bug because if it's not working
right maybe it could be exploited and so
some essential questions that we want to
ask while we're going through the threat
mam
process what are you building what does
it look like
what is it using what kind of platforms
what could go wrong with it once it's
built how are we going to deploy it out
to the wallet and just let it go or do
we have a plan to maintain it what do
you do about those things that can go
wrong so if you know that there's gonna
be the potential that your internal
server that's underneath someone's desk
could go down maybe you should move it
to one of the servers in the data center
or go to the cloud which is a fun
buzzword and then you go ahead and ask
the question of did we do a decent job
of the analysis when we're going through
this threat modeling process have that
retro Frank retrospection of how it went
how do we communicate as a team how did
we address the issues where the want
areas that we need to improve in do we
need better models do we need to do a
better job of working together across
the different teams I can get a chance
to figure out how to make it smoother
quicker and easier when we're going
through that I kind of explained the
more of a manual process of doing the
diagramming Microsoft I mentioned
earlier and a few other companies have
some tools that make it a lot easier so
that you could just do the diagramming
and then it helps you with identifying
the threats and then also documenting
how you're mitigating the Microsoft
threat modeling tool 2016 which they
also now have a prototype a preview for
their Azure version of a threat modeling
tool to help out when you're doing Azure
type systems this one is free and it it
works a lot like a Visio stencils you
just do the drawing of the year system
and then it determines the threats for
you and you just go down and you show
how you're going to address those
there's another one called threat
modeler threat modeler has a cost to it
but they have three different editions
to use you have standard Edition where
you get a chance to draw everything out
more of a single use on a single machine
license you have a dev ops Edition which
is supposed to help with the devs get a
chance to connect they do their role
security folks connect and do their role
and you get a chance to kind of track it
through your lifecycle
and then the Enterprise Edition is for
more of the distributed keeping track of
multiple systems multiple different
projects and then some other possible
threat modeling tools that you can look
up the secure CAD iris risk which some
folks say is really I haven't got a
chance to dive into but I've heard good
things about SD elements biosecurity
compass so that was the application side
I also want to note on the website for
tour camp I also have two other
resources a guide that talks about the
different types of threats for the
stride threats and then a list of their
mitigations the common ones she uses a
guide in order to help with the
conversation and then also I have a
networking resource guide in order to
help with some of the questions that you
want to ask to that so it kind of shift
gears a little bit from the application
side and you're going to see my novice
work on the network threat modeling side
so a lot of research into trying to find
someone else's work because plagiarism
is cool and so I found a really good
presentation that talked about
documenting segmenting and then
restricting is the kind of the road map
for how do you address network threat
modeling the concept is keeping your
documentation up-to-date on your network
map how the systems are configured so
you can use it as a reference guide in
order to make sure that things are right
because that helps with the validation
step when you can circle back later a
segmentation in order to be able to make
it so that it's not one big flat network
that everyone can't talk to everyone
unless you have other controls in place
like the certificates and there's some
new stuff that's going on now where you
don't even have to worry about firewalls
and I don't know I saw some stuff at the
RSA conference that was pretty out there
but with the segmentation you don't want
to be able to have something that has
like confidential systems or if you have
secret or top secret type stuff being
able to be on the same network with all
the public information you want to be
able to separate those out so that
someone who gains access to the public
systems can necessarily gain access to
your more sensitive networks and then
restrict and said I've gone with the
defaults for your routers and switches
and so I've gone with the defaults for
your servers be able to configure and
lock them down so that folks only have
access to what theirs they D to to get
the job done and only to the areas and
stuff that they're supposed to be able
to get access to some additional
considerations so how many different
devices are you talking about a home
network or you're talking about an
enterprise with 19,000 plus employees
with different servers and devices
across the whole how many different
versions the firmware you havin to deal
with if you have five different router
types but they're all dispersed across
and they all have different firmware is
there maybe a chance there in order to
get them all on the same firmware are
using the recommended versions in some
cases folks in different organizations
personal experience forgot to get the
routers up to date on the latest
firmware and so a couple years goes by
and you find this and it's a firestorm
in or to go through and try to get
everyone up to speed get it all the
phone we're at the right level and then
do you have a good change management
process in place you know to keep track
of the different versions the changes
where they're at and then also you don't
want any hidden surprises so one day all
of a sudden everything is available
through showdown and you're scrambling
to figure out why and there's been no
changes at least nothing in your logs
and then all of a sudden you call the
one the group that works on it and we're
actually there now off the internet
again so it's kind of weird when that
happens magically without any logs or
any change or any record that they made
any changes in the network or firewalls
and so it's kind of scary because you
never know when something might just pop
up another option I've seen some
examples where the folks have taken a
network diagram for their network threat
modeling and they just converted it over
to a data flow diagram and then you use
the existing tools of that in place but
they use it more with the strides in the
dread
and some folks say that that is
challenging because application
processes aren't exactly the same is the
network so so questions good please very
good question the question was how long
how much time do a developer spend when
they're on threat modeling when they're
building to a feature and depends on how
hostile they are some groups haven't
done or haven't been forced to do a lot
of threat modeling before and so they'll
drag their feet and they'll make it seem
like it's the worst idea in the world
just to convince management that they
shouldn't do threat modeling in the
first place it does happen but I've have
worked with multiple teams now stuff
where we could get a new threat model
knocked out in about an hour
and sitting down and just get a room
together make it a team sport pull in
the folks that are working like the BA
so they can answer some questions
pull in if you're dealing with like
databases operations stuff the servers
configurations pull the operations folks
into the room sit down and you just
spend that hour going through and knock
out the threats
make sure it's diagrammed accurately and
then run with it
and he'll make him own that very good
there are the question was between
application diagrams and network
diagrams the difference is is that right
yeah so with the application diagram
you're permanently are focusing on the
data where is it going in the system
with the network you're looking at the
different IP ranges your different
firewall rules where things get diverse
back and forth what kind of traffic
you're looking at do you have quality of
service configured so maybe streaming a
video goes different than someone trying
to send an email but usually what you
end up with is there's the logical
network diagrams or you could show the
IP address has gone from one router to a
switch or traversing the whole network
and then you also have some folks that
will do their whiteboard network
diagrams which look like clouds with
lines and some little brick walls and so
it kind of varies there on the network
side but usually what you want to do is
you want to have something that's
accurate so make sure that they validate
the diagram and then you just sit down
and say okay do we have the right
versions of the firmware do we have a
lock down properly do we have the right
firewall rules in place have we worked
with the firewall team and our to make
sure that the configurations are there
or is it set to any any which some folks
still do but yeah you remember
the question was about how we see the
threat modeling impacting the cyber
insurance world and the cyber insurance
world is dealing more with the risk
management than the threat management of
the applications but it still comes into
play because some folks will say that
they'll just go ahead and pay a little
bit more for the insurance or
third-party through an SLA will insist
that they have their insurance a high
enough not bill to cover the expenses of
the system or potential damages or how
it would take nor to get it up in them
in a natural natural emergency or some
sort of attack yeah please
the first part again real quick Auto
compliance of so kind of breaking that
so the difference I think the question
was right
so kind of the different what I
understand and correct me if I'm wrong
yeah so when you're dealing with how
much time do you put towards auditing
and compliance how much time did you put
towards training and best practices how
much time do you put towards doing a
threat modeling is that kind of a
summary good so when you're dealing
having those learning opportunities
where you're saying that we're just not
making you do this because we hate you
we're doing this because we love you and
we want you to grow which threat
modeling sometimes gets that way so most
of the time making sure to reiterate
making sure to be open when they are
hostile so you go into a dev team and
their first thing you want to let them
know when you're the first time they
have to go through a threat model is say
that you're here to help you here in
order to make it easier that is gonna be
a team sport but then you want to make
sure and stuff that kind of try to carry
them at the beginning go to extra mile
be there for questions be there for
walking them through it but then also be
able to point them to some good
resources they can find on their own so
the best practice is in training site
and then at the same time being able to
just actually tell them you're gonna be
audited later at some point you're going
to be audited and this will help make it
so those are easier so you don't have to
worry about that as much that helps with
the app dev managers too because
epitaphs managers don't like dealing
with audits the downside though when
you're talking about threat modeling
sometimes they don't see the importance
of it sometimes they're hostile towards
it or they're resistant and so again a
chance in order to try to make sure that
their managers are involved and that
they understand that there's a value
added to the team and that's where it
also helps with documenting the systems
because if they create a threat model in
the data flow diagram and you say that
that's good enough for their application
diagram it helps them go wait I don't
have to create more documents I could
just create that and then check it in
with the code and I'm done
that's a very good point so sooner the
development lifecycle to better a good
example we had a privacy office come
down with their own system and so the
developers were scurrying and our to
look good to the privacy officer and
they sat down and they finally listened
to me I'm like do it at the very
beginning before you write up the system
because that far too often they start
coding they'd have something in in QA
they possibly have something in
production and then they go wait a
minute we're supposed to do the threat
model on this weren't we it happens and
so as soon as they know what their kind
of a concept of what they want to build
do the threat model right there at the
very beginning and it's gonna be much
easier on them it's gonna be much easier
on everyone because it's no longer now a
stopgap it's no longer a hurdle that
they have to jump through it's now just
part of its like a guide it helps them
get a better picture of what they're
going to be building how they're gonna
be coding it and so usually they
actually like the threat model at that
stage opposed to being resistant to it
so yeah
the way I explained didn't work you have
your conceptual diagram of your system
and then different features can be added
on without actually changing the
exceptional diagram but if there is a
feature change that does change that's
when you want to circle back and revisit
the threat model during the third model
conversation we don't usually go all the
way down into the weeds usually we're
talking more conceptual a high-level but
by having the data flow diagram they
actually know a little bit better what
their process is going to be like and so
we could talk about them when we're
addressing the high-level stuff so it's
a chance to be more familiar with like
how is that function going to happen how
are we going to authenticate how are we
going to log what events are we going to
log so those things that already been
talked about in the meeting and
alongside in there the developers always
have my phone number so they usually
reach out but that's a good point yeah
[Music]
if you're dealing with an external and I
started the the question was this for
every process do you have to necessarily
have done a thermal or you can go higher
lab if there's an external interactor so
you're dealing with it someone else's
API you want to make sure that's
captured because every time your system
talks to someone else's if you want to
make sure it's on the diagram is a
external entity but when you're dealing
with the system itself you should wait
to tell folks is to aim the beneful
diagram world somewhere between a level
0 and level 1 I keep a high enough level
to where it's not 5,000 threats it's
usually more like a hundred threats that
you have to go through what ends up
happening is you could go all the way
down into the weeds and talk about each
and every function and you could diagram
it and you can put it into like the
third modeling tools or you can sit down
with the matrix and identify all of them
and it becomes bigger than the project
itself and so you end up having to go
through a lot more paperwork lot more
medications and you have to document so
much that the whole team kind of gets
bogged down but by bringing it back up
to like a level zero level one right in
there and enough
no kind of the main functional areas
like this is our web front-end our web
server area we're going to have our web
services here and then we're going to
have our data store in the back and so
you understand how the system flows and
you can talk about how you're going to
deal with authentication with your
authorization with something like you're
logging with also redundancy resilient
systems like load balancing different
ways of handling the potential of denial
service attacks how those configurations
are going to be
yes it's very good point so I'm not as
familiar with the ratings as much but by
having it done you could actually check
that off you could document it you could
show it in an audit or a review and so
that helps when you're dealing with
trying to show like auditors or trying
to get ratings on how secure the systems
are yeah because going through the steps
you know show that you've gone through
those steps and especially when it comes
to an audit but most importantly being
able to talk through that with the
development team be able to work with
them and on how they need to improve
their controls to make the systems more
secure yeah it's a team sport you learn
from the developers just as much as they
learn from you and you get a chance to
figure out how they approach to the
different issues any more questions
so I have some additional resources
again the slide deck is already posted
on the Tor site I have some threat
modeling tool download Microsoft's
secure development lifecycle resources
and then also a book reference this is a
pretty good book on threat modeling that
I found before so thank you very much
for your time and have a good tour can
[Applause]