i don't know i don't often do this on a
saturday night you know
this
um
all right we have our lunch keynote here
from v
armor i'd like to introduce mark
woolward who's the cso and cto
at v armor and he'll be speaking on
addressing application resilience in
today's complex
dynamic environments thank you for
joining us today
mark you're welcome
hey everybody um can can you hear me
john
hear you just great awesome okay well
hi there from the united kingdom it's uh
6 p.m on a saturday evening and we're in
the middle of our first
really big storm of the season so uh in
the middle of storm alex
so it's an interesting time to be doing
this talk um i'm gonna
try and start my slides now um
and john if you could let me know if
you're seeing the right
in uh i can't even find oh screen
here we go
okay um
all right that looks great okay you see
the slide
just the slide not not the sort or
anything like that
that's correct everything sounds good
looks good awesome
okay well anyway thank you for inviting
me i believe i'm speaking to people
around the iowa
and illinois part of the world so i
think about
4 000 miles away um yeah it's good to be
good to be talking to you
my name is mark warwood uh i'm cto and
ciso
for vrma um but actually
um most of my career i've been a
practitioner like most people here
so just before the armor i spent
16 to 17 years at goldman sachs where i
was a
chief technology officer for networking
and telecommunications
um part of the cloud architecture team
and a technology fellow um so
during that time i led the network
security function for several years
led network architecture was a cto and
actually my final
um in my final
few years i also owned an application
resilience function
um for the european region and it was
actually during that
time that i really realized that
anything that you want to automate um
and
make precise needs accurate information
um the need for accurate information
that has context
underpins almost anything that you want
to automate and
in highly dynamic cloud-based worlds
that's a given so i'm going to talk a
little bit about that
and i'm also going to talk about one of
the other lessons i learned in my time
at goldman
was about trust and reputation
particularly in finance
and also obviously in places like
healthcare trust
and reputation are incredibly important
and for us
as information security and cyber
practitioners
that means you know keeping control of
data protecting data protecting our
customers information
um and as we always used to say goldman
sachs staying off of the front cover of
the wall street journal
so john i know if you're if you're still
not muted did the slide move on okay i i
just have had some bad experience with
zoom lately
yeah i can see the uh uh
charts on the left and the right cool
okay so we're gonna before we kind of
get into
some of the some of the meat here i'm
going to
put this into a business kind of context
um
and where we are today certainly with
most of the customers that
i deal with um between the service
provider
um finance and and healthcare space
there's a conflict and attention going
on um
and the bottom left-hand chart kind of
kind of describes that
in every competitive business now in
every marketplace
there is a requirement to innovate and
get new products to market as quickly as
possible
and that's enabled by apis and by data
and you hear terms digital
transformation using clouds
to you know to spin up infrastructure
very quickly and deliver new products to
the market
um and data obviously
is an incredibly important part of this
and it's a double-edged sword because
data allows you to understand
what your customers require um can begin
to understand
you know what would be a a successful
new product
but clearly managing data
in our um
in a in a sensible fashion not just
protecting it but managing its life
cycle effectively is something that's
you know very very important and that
comes back to the trust and reputation
thing so i've been talking about
innovation over on the right-hand side
of that
of that bottom left graph but actually
then we have to balance that
up with all of the requirements to
retain the trust and the reputation of
our of our companies
um at the very least we need to remain
compliant to the you know to the
regulations within our industry
um better yet if you take a risk-based
approach
that will also that should also address
the regulatory requirements
and put you in a much um in a much
better posture
um what we're finding is that poorly
implemented regulatory controls
act against the business priorities they
they get in the way um
those controls can be static and manual
and these days they're ineffective
because what we see is that often
the application teams will work around
them um and
over the course of my career um
i i could i could name a number of
occasions where poorly thought out
sets of controls that have been designed
to meet regulatory requirements
have been worked around and have been
proven to be utterly ineffective
um but what i'm trying to show with this
graph here is you know over on the far
left you've kind of got the regulatory
compliance the old world of things
if you begin to take a more proactive
approach
which is around resiliency and building
resiliency into not just your
applications and your infrastructure but
into your controls
um they become an enabler and what we're
seeing from some of the regular
regulatory bodies
for instance the ffiec in the states
and the bank of england in europe is
that they're beginning to recognize that
actually
resiliency is that is the sweet spot um
as opposed to focusing on recovery
making
systems and applications resilient is is
really is really the most effective
approach
and when this is well implemented these
these kind of controls they provide
value to the application owners so they
don't
choose to work around them and they act
like the brakes on a sports car
you know with with a a resilient
infrastructure
and with good visibility you can go
faster
i did just mention now that actually
this kind of like this tension and this
move to digital transformation and move
to dynamic environments is now being
recognized
um is now being recognized by by the
regulators
the ffiec the bank of england they talk
a lot about now about resilience
continuous controls
prioritizing them controls around
business functions and we'll talk a
little bit about that
in a in in in a moment
the second half of this slide is
designed to show that actually what's
happening
is um the rate of change in many
organizations
driven by cloud and ci cd pipelines and
you know continuous delivery of software
um has has outpaced
the way in which we were doing our
mapping
and our analysis in a manual fashion so
things like business impact analysis
um and and and the cyber controls
are now being outpaced by the rate of
change so we need to do something
differently
so we've ended up with these very
complex environments
where not even the owners of the
applications and functions really
understand dependencies in a
in a in a clear and accurate fashion and
what we need if we're going to actually
protect the applications and the data is
a better way of understanding
you know the scope of the applications
throughout their entire life cycle which
includes an understanding of
relationships and the risks associated
with those
relationships we need to be able to ask
questions
about the posture of our systems and our
critical functions
and be updated when risks to those
critical business functions and
dependencies change
or something changes within the
environment to violate my policies
okay so this talks a little bit about
this slide talks a little bit about
what's changing
um and the old world versus the new
world
firstly as a kind of a an
information security and a cyber um
practice we become very very focused on
events
you know we have our sims um we have
you know systems and cloud and cloud
systems that generate
massive amounts of logs loads and loads
of events you know
millions or billions a day um
and those events don't have any context
it's very very difficult to action them
and we end up in a situation where we
are today where we're overwhelmed
with data um and that actually becomes
one of the problems
the second thing that's changing is in
the old world
we had numerous static controls
that didn't really understand changes
within the environment
so things like you know the static
firewall policy
that broke as soon as the application
changed um
and really what we now need is something
that understands
when the environment changes what that
actually means and provides it context
so you know for instance when a workload
is spun up
and it becomes part of an application
treat it as part of that application
immediately and understand whether or
not the
posture and the controls are are
appropriate
so the graph over on the right hand side
here talks a little about the different
sorts of
um systems and controls that we have in
place um
and it shows that you know things like
the cmdb
and grc tools have been very much
based in the old world where they're
they're based upon a static
uh view of the world um you know with
grc it's often
around periodic um reviews of the
environment
not having a real understanding of when
things change within the environment
and we believe that the answer to this
um lies with
technology that we call application
relationship management
and there's a there's a bunch of um you
know there's a bunch of
solutions and a bunch of um technologies
and products in this space
so let's take a little look at
application relationship management
and what it does using knowledge theory
um so if you're familiar with knowledge
theory it's often called the dikw
pyramid data information knowledge
and wisdom and it's a way of describing
different classes of information
so what this diagram shows is two things
at the starting point
first of all we have lots of data
so at the bottom of this graph we have
the machines
that generate logs in the billions a day
either from the cloud providers or from
our security systems
or from applications which are actually
now way better
you know instrumented than they were a
decade ago they generate an
awful lot of data and one of the
challenges there
is relating that data to something
that's actionable that allows you to
secure your environment
the second thing we also have is we have
at the top we have wisdom
we have the requirements we have our
control requirements
we have our regulations
um you know we have our regulatory
frameworks
that provide us with guidance around how
we should
secure and protect certain business
functions
and also you'll have things like your
internal security policies
which are generally written in word
documents which are very
difficult to turn into something that's
actionable and extremely difficult to
relate to the data coming from the
machines at the bottom
so what we've kind of got here there's a
gap
and that gap in the old world before we
got to automation and cloud
used to be filled by humans and weeks of
work
so you know the example is the firewall
change request
the firewall change request comes in
and the human being used to go away and
find out
what the systems that make up an
application
what do they do you know what do they
communicate with is this appropriate
does it conform to the corporate
security standards
and then a decision would be made and
the appropriate
controls to be put in place now
in the modern world of ci cd and cloud
that's broken
because the human being apart from being
you know
not 100 accurate is too slow
so this gap is a problem and application
relationship management
it it addresses that gap so
what does what does application
relationship management do
well first of all it consumes data it
consumes the telemetry from the
environment
and also consumes metadata
from cmdbs and inventories
and control planes to provide some
context
the first thing it does as we move up
from data to information
is it structures it it describes the
behavior and relationship of things
in in our in in our example it takes
that data
and it creates a graph which shows how
systems communicate
um and the nature of those
communications
um and it allows you to understand
information about how applications
clients and users
communicate with each other so we've
moved from data and from billions of
events
up to information represented in a in a
kind of a graph
context in a graph format the next step
is moving from information to knowledge
and knowledge is something
that begins to relate back to your
business and what you're trying to
achieve
your control requirements and
what you need to do to achieve that is
you need context
so application relationship management
contextualizes
this information with metadata what is
this system
is it part of a business function what
part of organize
of the organization is it a part of and
what are the cyber risks associated with
it so you know the telemetry fee
coming from your vulnerability scanners
and from your sim and everything like
that
that labeled information can also be
associated with those with those systems
so once you get to that kind of
contextualized
rich view of what your applications are
doing you then end up with something
you end up with a model that could be
addressed by the wisdom
or the control requirements as it's
normally expressed so for instance
the pci dss requirements for
segmentation
can easily be mapped to a contextualized
graph of your environment you know what
the cat1a assets are the cap1b
et cetera et cetera so you know
for the pci example it allows us to
determine the category of systems
label them compute the policies that are
required to protect them
apply those policies and monitor
another example would be for business
continuity management
this model allows you to identify the
dependencies of the critical business
function
compare their recovery time objective
capabilities which have been pulled from
a grc or from an enemy
an inventory report on the violations
and continue to do so forever more so
when something changes to say an rto
um capability changes or a dependency
changes
it will report immediately that that you
know that violation has occurred
i know a third example of how this can
work is a software vulnerability example
so what application relationship
management lets you do
is it lets you identify your critical
apps because they're labeled
pull the cvss status from the
vulnerability scanner
detect when critical functions have
dependencies or relationships
with significant vulnerabilities so you
set a threshold you know high or
critical
produce an alert that's actionable and
it's actionable against
a critical function so it's actually it
allows you to prioritize
your your response and it lets you do
that continuously once again
so you know what application
relationship management lets you do
is it lets you gather business context
and join it with the relationships of
the systems within your environment
and it's super powerful it gives you so
many different use cases particularly
from a cyber
on operational resilience standpoint
okay so i'm going to talk quickly about
how um
how regulation is changing um and in
particular
um what we've seen over the last year or
two from the ffiec and the bank of
england
um they're now talking about resilience
as opposed to recovery
um which is a big change in focus
and that is a response to the increase
in dynamism
of our it environments in our apps and
what we would expect to see
is over the course of the next few years
the other regulators and certainly other
sectors apart from the financial
services sector will catch up with this
as well
so you know point one is that resilience
and and and cyber resilience needs to be
continuous the old days of the two-year
periodic bcp test in isolation is not
sufficient
things change too fast and those you
know periodic tests are just not
realistic
the second point here is protecting and
prioritizing your critical business
functions
you cannot protect everything to the
same level
of um to to to the same depth
and there's now a recognition that we
need to prioritize the protection of the
most critical business functions
and obviously apply the appropriate
controls elsewhere but there is a
requirement to prioritize
number three the identification of
interdependencies
so time and time again what we found is
that businesses focus on securing their
you know the critical function of the
critical application
and the inter and their interdependences
their downstream dependencies
have ended up being the thing that has
been breached or has failed
so actually having a system that can
show your dependencies
is incredibly important point four
is is about risk identification you know
resilience
um resilience is about having the
capability to withstand events
rather than responding to them and
recovering from them manually
so you know we've
we've previously spent a lot of time on
detection and response and you know
the cyber industry has spent a lot of
time on threat detection and
and the response tools but actually what
we're seeing now there is once again a
swing back
to uh prevention and to putting
proactive controls in place
and in order to do that you need to have
a
mature kind of risk identification
process that you understand how to apply
those proactive controls
and then finally number five is you know
to build resilience you need to change
when the environment changes so when the
app changes
when your infrastructure changes when
the threat changes
your controls need to be dynamic and
again you know
application resilience uh application
um relationship management is designed
to
to address that that challenge
okay so now i'm going to talk quickly
about what we do at vr i didn't want to
spend too long this isn't a product
pitch
but this gives you an idea of how a
modern system
in this category would help you secure
your environment
so first of all this technology is
designed to protect
diverse environments you know the
multi-cloud where you have some legacy
you know physical mainframes where you
have some public cloud
where you have probably some containers
some kubernetes services
maybe functions as a function as a
service on-premise you've got sdn and
agents
so what you need is you need a system
that can sit across all of those
and plug in to each of those
environments and give you a single pane
of glass and a single pane of control
so what we do is we plug in to each of
these different environments
via you know edge um they
in in in computer science they're called
edge compute functions
basically edge processors plug into the
apis of each of your different
environments
um they can um
they will ingest the telemetry from
these environments
provide them with context you know kind
of get rid of some of the temporal
issues that you get with
with telemetry from from different
clouds and then normalize them
into a centralized relationship graph
which gives you a picture of your
complete
environment from end to end um so this
isn't
deploying you know new agents or new
infrastructure
we're plugging into the native controls
you might have
the endpoint agents you might have the
sdns you may have in your environment
and it allows you to deal with the
challenge of all of this data
it turns it into information and
knowledge
and then it provides you with a bunch of
capabilities across the top in terms of
visualization reporting policy
management
which allows you to to to implement the
security controls required
so a couple of use cases or three very
very common use cases
um you know first of all
operational and cyber risk management so
that's assessing the attack surface of
your of your critical applications or
all of your applications
and looking at connected risk through
dependency chains
the second one is isolation and
segmentation
providing accurate and tested policy
based around the dependencies of your
applications
and also the control requirements of
your organization
and assuring that they're managed and
effective through the life cycle and
then finally
secure migration effectively taking
cloud migration and adoption projects as
an
opportunity to put in place controls for
instance zero trust
controls around your applications and
then monitor those
controls and those policies across the
life cycle of the application
so they're three very very common use
cases our customers have
so i'm going to now quickly and i'm
conscious of the time i think i've got
another
another couple of minutes before we can
go to q a um
i'm going to talk a little bit about
some of our our customer use cases to
kind of um
to to illustrate this for you
cheers so the first one here is a
a financial services institution um in
in asia
uh a very digital bank highly digitized
they have a diverse multi-cloud
um in you know multiple cloud service
providers
they're heavy users of kubernetes and
containers
um but also they have like many
financial organizations they have many
traditional legacy applications
particularly on the
um you know on the on the on the
settlements
and on the reporting side of the
business um
and what they have is you know they have
infrastructure as a service platform as
a service
legacy sdns and the vr application
controller
plugs into each of these environments
into the apis within those environments
to provide a central consistent view
across the entire organization
so we act as an agnostic controller
management plan
for risk assessments and policy
management
and this promotes agility and it reduces
the complexity
because you know you're looking at your
environment and your applications
through a single pane of glass
and your people don't need to understand
the intricacies of the differences
between security groups in aws
nsgs and azure how network policy works
in kubernetes
there's a single policy model that sits
above um
sits above them all so that's a very
very powerful
approach to simplify and extremely
complex i mean extremely challenging
environment
so next this is a this is a bank in uh
in in my in my part of the world
and the requirement here really
initially was for application visibility
and assurance
so this organization has coarse-grained
segmentation
so they have segmentation between
different realms of the environment and
different
major business units but they had no
visibility into the effectiveness of
those policies and controls they
couldn't tell that they were working
and that's very common if you have sdns
you know you'll have the ability to
implement group based policy
but actually all you get back are you
know billions of logs
and nothing that really um describes to
you the effectiveness of the policy and
whether or not they're working and
that's important particularly regulated
environments where you
you know where you have to undergo
audits
so the application controller the armor
product
measures policy efficacy it reports and
it optimizes policies
and it manages the life cycle of
security policy in a very very simple
fashion
um it also provides the understanding
of application dependencies to
facilitate things like effective
business impact analysis and manage the
kind of the granular zero trust policies
that are required here
and again we're plugging into sdns into
firewalls and into public cloud
so it's a very very diverse environment
and then finally we're going to talk
about um one of the largest
um one of the largest service providers
in the world
based in north america um and you know
they're already one of the most advanced
software defined data center kind of
infrastructure adopters on the planet
um they have a high degree of security
and zero trust segmentation within their
private cloud but they have an
aggressive plan or they had an
aggressive plan which we've worked with
them on
to move to public cloud in a secure
manner
and improve their security posture as
part of that project so the role of the
application controller here
was to model dependencies compute
policies
test those policies stage them deploy
them and monitor them and ensure that
they're working
all the way through the application life
cycle
now you've heard me say the word life
cycle over and over again in this talk
um and that's one of the challenges for
security these days
applications do not stand still and what
application relationship management is
designed to do is it allows you
to keep your controls concurrent with
the the needs of your app of your of
your applications
so finally you know application
relationship management helps you deal
with
application and cloud complexity risk
and it allows you to address cyber
resilience and operational risk
requirements
in environments where change is constant
it takes the capabilities
of modern cloud and api driven
infrastructure and the data we can
can collect in this environment to drive
accurate decisions
about security policy and risk and then
continue to do so
throughout the life cycle so
i guess i'm going to conclude with a
question here
this technology began as a solution to
complex
cyber policy management challenges
um and also the requirement to
understand application dependencies
what we've since seen from our customers
they take this enriched set of knowledge
to solve other problems
um you know things like business impact
analysis automation
understanding environmental dependencies
you know so you know what's my
dependency on a concentration risk on a
given cloud provider
and to produce state flow diagrams for
audits and compliance requirements
what's incredibly valuable to us is
hearing from practitioners with
real world challenges that this data set
and approach can be
applied to so i'd love to have your
feedback and your questions so either
now
in in this q a or feel free to drop me a
name uh
an email my email address is mark with c
vr.com so thanks for your time i think
we have a little time for questions
in fact i've actually finished dead on
time which makes a change
okay john do we have any questions
hello
okay well michelle sorry i didn't
realize it was montana
greetings montana from the uk
is john johnson there because i don't
hear anybody
well i'm guessing
okay i'm guessing as there are no
questions then there are no questions
well
thank you all very much for your time um
and like i say if you if any
questions do come up um i'm mark of the
armor.com please feel free to drop me a
line
and thanks for your time
you