and i'm starting
all right good afternoon i'd like to
introduce richard marshall
check out richard's bio for more details
uh i've known rich for geez
probably 12 years and uh
of an amazing background and a real
great perspective on the industry
so let me
allow richard to start his presentation
if you think kobit was bad
let me share the slides here and we'll
get going thank you
thank you thank you john
all right i guess i'm in control on my
slides and i'll start my presentation
uh at the onset i need i need to thank
uh should i start talking now john um
you may need to request control but if
you have control then you're all set
all right i'm requesting control now
and just tell me when to start talking
yup go right ahead all right uh john
thank you very much for inviting me and
giving me the opportunity to make a
presentation
at corncon
as far as i'm concerned corncocon is
probably the
the best security conference in the
country
uh especially now but i've been involved
with you guys
for at least three or four years i was
there a couple of years ago and i'll
tell you
a hospitality and the opportunity to
meet with
fine folk out there is just absolutely
astounding
um i know those of you in the audience
are thinking it's kind of odd to
hear a presentation about modern day
cyber security from a guy who's
been in the business over 25 years uh
but i've
been speaking a lot at black hat and
defcon that's where john and i first met
and then we further submitted our
relationship at uh
the rsa conferences and uh
so we've been had a close working
relationship all of these years
but uh probably the
the best experience we've had together
was at corncon a couple of years ago
a great group of people it was wonderful
to be live with everyone
and i certainly look forward to being
able to do that again next year
there's just something about the
camaraderie of everyone
being together and sharing ideas all
right for those of you in the audience i
don't know whether you can
respond to any of my questions but i'll
just assume that you can
i want you to take a very close look at
this first slide
and tell me what's wrong with it tell me
what's missing
tell me what needs to be corrected
well i'm not going to wait forever for
an answer so i'll help you with this
most analysts when they're looking at a
screen trying to find
attacks look at tremendo look at details
which is very very important but it's
also very important that you note the
obvious
and so this slide was prepared with a
defect
initially to help point out the fact
that you need to look for the obvious if
you look down here at
my name you'll see that there's a dot
missing from the l
most people don't see that hardly anyone
will see that
but i use that to illustrate the point
that uh don't overlook the obvious
that's it's very critical uh to make
sure you catch everything
slide
all right
all right trying to move to the next
slide
i know it's going to take a little bit
of time here we are here's today's
objective
uh you know we're dealing with a
completely new situation with
uh the situation uh associated with
everyone having to stay home
and so we're accustomed to working in
islands of security you know offices
where everything is
nailed down we're very comfortable with
the security arrangement that we're
working with
and we think we have that under control
at least we have it
uh under control a lot better than now
so we
are in a position where we're moving
from islands of security as i like to
refer to them
to lily pads of vulnerability now what
do i mean by lily pads of
vulnerability everyone or a
large number of people
are working from home now
and it's creating
quite a few problems together but
they're also involved in shareware
everybody's using the same wi-fi system
and when they're all using
the same wi-fi system they're not all
paying attention to security
considerations children don't have any
choice they need to be on the internet
to do their homework
uh to attend class as it were
and those that are working from home
don't have the same
security procedures built into their
home system that they do in the office
while when they're in the office they
realize that the security
that's built into their system is going
to help protect them
but when they're at home and they don't
have that built-in protection
then that opens a lot of doors for
nefarious activity
and quite a bit of nefarious activities
ongoing
so what i'm going to try to provide
today is
what i've stated in the objective
and uh let's work together
to try to reach that objective
now the next objective is i'm working
from home so it's a little slow
uh let's see we jumped ahead
oh this is going too fast
let's go back a few slides
well it looks like everything's going to
happen at one time
and i'm going to ask you to take over uh
this thing is
beyond my control
that's going to relinquish control of
this
we'll make this work all right
shall i give up remote control now
yeah i have i have control would you
like me to okay
yeah go back to uh the second slide
all right i'm giving up remote control
to you
i don't know why i jumped ahead
we got this one yeah keep going back no
uh the actual second slide in the deck
keep going back
here okay keep going back
this one background okay yeah that's
this one yeah
yes all right a little bit of background
on this old guy i formerly was the
associate general counsel through
promotion system security or information
insurance at nsa
why is that important it was there that
i learned to be a hacker
i i was trained by nsa to be a hacker i
was halfway decent then i'm worthless
now
of course that was 40 years ago and 40
pounds ago
when i had a ponytail and as you can see
i don't have that much hair left
uh but i still am familiar with the
concepts that
was in my job at nsa was i was a legal
architect for the nation's first
information warfare exercise called
eligible receiver 97.
you can look it up on the internet there
have been several books that have been
written about
our participation in that but basically
we took a group of about
uh 15 15 to 24
pretty seasoned hackers
and we were designed to attack a dod
system
and my job was to make sure we could do
it legally without having to go to jail
because if you violate title 18 it's uh
it's usually a felony
and going to jail is not a very good
career move for most people but we did
not use
anything special and that's the point i
want to emphasize here
we did not use anything that was unique
to nsa
in terms of hacking all of the hacking
techniques that we used we downloaded
from the internet
now this was back in 1997
probably before many of you were born
but you can still download very very
from the internet today and that's a
point to remember
the adversaries are many they're all
over
the world they're dedicated they're
focused
they share information attack profiles
very generously so the
the threshold the attack surface
is very very large uh after i left that
i worked at the white house developing
some policies on
how to protect the critical
infrastructure and
cyber security initiatives and i
mentioned this point because
had those policies been implemented as
they were originally drafted
i think we could have avoided a lot of
the problems that we're experiencing
today
but unfortunately they were over
coordinated
everybody in the government wanted to
have their piece of the pie
and so things were diluted in terms of
strength
and so we lost an opportunity maybe
someday that'll come back and i
i think we're starting to get a better
hand on it now both with the department
of homeland security and
and the national security agency and it
was at at the
department of homeland security that i
was a director of global cyber security
management
which is an absolutely fascinating
opportunity i worked with
25 to 30 young individuals
they were young enough to be my children
actually
every one of them had a master's degree
in computer security
and i think i learned as much from them
as as anyone possibly could
i am an advisor to a number of boards
and national and international
corporations i thoroughly enjoy that
i also serve on a number of boards of
startups
that i do gratuitously
pro bono just to help these young folks
get started
let's go to the next slide john and
sorry i can't do this a little smoother
all right the focus here is how to keep
hackers out of your system
and uh you know the previous
presentation
which i thought was very very good about
malware
uh focuses on the persistent threat that
continues
day in and day out and of course it's
more critical now that we are working
from home
so one of the first things you need to
do is to identify
and correct your vulnerabilities and
that means you've got to look very
closely
at who you're connected to how you're
connected with them
because there are a number of ways that
the attacker can come in and take
advantage of you
one of the best things you can do in
terms of time
effort energy is to keep
your system patched we call it patch
tuesday when microsoft
comes out with their latest list of
patches
and all too often most
experts are a little late in installing
those patches
so while we may call it patch tuesday
the adversary calls it hacker wednesday
they get this same list of patches and
they take advantage of it
right away because they know we don't
always
patch our systems and this is
particularly true
when you're dealing with the financial
services sector
uh banks and other complex entities
have so many systems operating that is
before they install a patch they want to
review
the patch to make sure it doesn't have
any adverse impact on the operating
system
that's also true with the islands of
security not necessarily true with the
pattern
with what i call the lily pads of
vulnerability so
when you're at home you're your own
system administrator
when you're operating from home so it's
important
to you it's incumbent on you to make
sure you
patch your systems as soon as the patch
comes out that'll certainly help things
okay john ready for the next slide
all right this is a depiction of the
attack origins the
tax types et cetera and you'll see that
they're coming from all over the world
areas that you don't necessarily think
are going to be
that aggressive in attacking the united
states
now this depicts attacks on the united
states they're also attacking
europe et cetera but it's amazing to see
where all of these attacks are coming
from
uh you'll notice most of them are coming
from uh
china uh a few from russia
uh we also have some attacks coming from
uh western europe but just because the
attacks are
shown to be coming from western europe
doesn't necessarily mean that's where
they originated
all too often they originate in russia
or china
and then they're spoofed is coming from
western europe or indeed
from south america okay let's move along
to the next slide john
thank you for your help all right
i love this slide uh this is a
modification
of a thing called night lights it shows
where electricity is in the world
and the point to remember here is that
where there's light
there's an opportunity for a hacker and
you'll notice there's a tremendous
amount of light in the united states and
of course northern europe
and western europe but also look at
the activity in india and in china
it's amazing and then of course this is
24 hours a day do not make the mistake
of underestimating your adversary
they're intelligent
they're smart they're aggressive they
focus on attacks
over and over again they don't have that
much else to do
they don't have jobs so the easiest way
for them to make money
is to attack you and take advantage of
those systems
so they're highly motivated to do that
all right next one we're moving right
along here john
all right i know this is a busy looking
slide uh but this is the atomy of a
target data breach
and if you follow along you know numbers
one two three four and five i'll give
you an opportunity to
to read the notes as these take place
and you can see that these are
very sophisticated attacks um and again
these come from areas where you would
not ordinarily expect them to be that
skillful
and that technically qualified but
obviously they definitely are
one of the easiest ways is to come in
through a third party contractor we've
seen that over and over again
one of the more egregious examples was
when they
uh came in through an air conditioning
system
and then i was able to get in and
take over the system they do it
gradually they do it slowly
they don't want to be called they don't
want to be detected
they want to do a complete internal
survey of your system
take what they want take what they need
and normally when they exfiltrate it
it's done
in the middle of the night when you're
least expected uh it's done low and slow
and it's encrypted so it's very
difficult for you to catch it
as they're going out moral of the story
catch them coming in catch them when
they're inside
stop them from taking your data next
please
all right exploits unfold in stages as
we illustrated in the previous slide
on the right screen you'll see activity
actually taking place
one of the things they first do is is
reconnaissance and they take their time
doing that they're looking at system
weaknesses
and i also want to exploit personnel
and here's where it gets become
important both
in the island of security and on the
[Music]
uh
rich i think you're uh your video and
audio uh
froze up there
all right i will uh we'll get
we'll get rich back in here
you can watch the animation let me
get him added back in looks like he just
dropped
okay there we go rich you're back
and once they get in then they start you
taking advantage of
user privileges they continue the
reconnaissance the target data is
filtrated they may remain in retained
control
systems and keep visiting
so it's incumbent upon you to keep
monitoring and making sure you can keep
them from coming in sometime
all right you want the next slide
uh yes please yes
yeah and this is not a site that you
want to see
on your screen that shows that you've
been hacked and
uh
you don't always see this but when you
do see this your heart stops next slide
please
all right be alert to it as as the
previous presenter
said you know the the ones that are
doing the attacks
are still using their old technical
systems
to come and attack you they're look
in the past they look for an unwitting
executive they don't have to do that now
again because you're on the islands of
vulnerability anyone that is using their
system from home
can be subject to an inviting uh
email to open it up and once you open up
a bad email
then you get malicious traffic coming in
and they're very skilled
at using remote administrative tools um
and they can take care of
take advantage of your systems in
multiple ways
and open you to buffer overflows and
other infectionary
infections very dangerous situation
next slide please
all right many attacks are tailored
tailored specifically to attack your
particular system
now remember they cut their teeth on
going after very sophisticated systems
in the islands of security the office
environment
but now that they're taking advantage of
the lily pads of vulnerability
they still use their polished techniques
but it's much easier for them to
come in and take advantage of the home
system
and then from the home system then they
can hop
into the more sophisticated systems
at the office so you you'd be very
careful
system administrators need to be very
careful particularly with traffic coming
from home
systems to make sure that a bad guy or a
bad gal
is not coming in to take advantage of
your situation
uh on the left
under the caption of many attacks are
tailored there are important notes to
take advantage of once
again we notice that hvac systems
often provide unexpected pathways
hackers do not need to rely on back
doors or see road days
that they can attack they've polished
they've practiced they know how to get
in
and it's much easier to attack the home
user than it is
the office user but remember once they
get into the home user it makes it a lot
easier for them to get into the office
next slide please
all right this is okay here we go
here it's important to understand
everything about your system
because the bad guys and gals don't need
anything major
they they're very happy to look for
something small and exploit that
something that's overlooked and so there
they'll use hard-coded passwords they
look for clear
text to take advantage of again
[Music]
using legacy protocols they're
very dangerous to be exploited looking
for temporary cracks
and here's the other one to be alert
it's called byod
bring your own disaster people like to
say bring your own device but it's
really bring your own disaster
and we see that more and more not just
from the home user
uh using their home computer but
they're also using their ipads to
connect
and particularly their iphones which are
well their mobile devices
which are extremely vulnerable okay
next slide please
next slide john
yeah it's it's up okay yeah okay yeah uh
they're a little slow okay
limit your access privileges uh
to those that really need it don't give
it across the board just to be nice to
people
if they don't need access to a certain
line and don't let them have it
and i'm going to beat the drama on
patching your systems
that 99 of the vulnerabilities
i've read complete many times on surveys
if you have your system properly patched
you reduce the opportunity significantly
for someone to come in and
take advantage of the situation
and it's also very important for the
system administrator and it puts
a lot of pressure on the system
administrator
to actually read the logs so many things
are automated now that we have a
tendency to say
well when the alarm goes off i'll pay
attention
uh but they're not full proof
so the system administrator really has a
tough job to read the logs to know
what's going on to know what to do
and that's increasingly important now
that the home systems are now connected
to the office systems next slide please
all right i love this depiction and this
is the last slide
but here you see what is viewed as a
firewall
and people have very interesting ways to
get through
that firewall some of them are very
sophisticated
but some of them are very plain just
kind of walking around it
as we've seen in this depiction so
i just caution you to be extra special
careful out there
especially those that are working from
home especially those that are working
in an office and are monitoring the
activities of people who are working
from home
realize that because of covert 19
we're at home but the adversaries at
home too
they're working from home but they're
very sophisticated in their developed
attack techniques and certainly are
having a field day
coming in not only with ransomware
but also attacks to disable the 911
systems for a while we've had that
problem
and and more importantly we've had some
shutdowns
uh associated with power systems here in
the united states
so the world is becoming increasingly
vulnerable
uh particularly because of kobe 19 and
it just behooves all of us to work
together to help protect each other
to prevent a bigger cyber disaster that
may happen
john i thank you very much for letting
me have the opportunity to
share the opportunity to uh
converse with these fine folk and i know
we're
pretty close on time but i'm available
to
answer questions that i that you think i
might be able to answer don't
don't embarrass me by asking something
too hard
uh but i'm happy to try to answer
questions as they come up
uh you know please put any questions you
might have into the
q a window
maybe i'll be lucky like the last guy
and not good questions
well i i'm sure there will be lots of
questions and it's too bad we're not in
person so that people could sit down and
share a drink and talk to you right that
was that was what was so much fun
i think when you were here last oh gosh
being able to sit down with the whole
audience the whole crowd afterwards
and uh and chat and have a drink and
get to meet their families oh that was
great and
you know one of the things that i
enjoyed uh
the last time i was there i
talked to because there were a lot of
parent children combos in the audience
and i was very encouraged to see the
parents being there
with their children and encouraging them
to go into the i.t arena
it's a growth industry i mean uh all of
the presenters will agree with that
it's a growth industry and i commented
on the fact that
i took my son uh who was
a young teenager at the time with me
when i went to
black hat and defcon and put him to work
uh he was basically serving as a
a guide to take speakers to the
particular
forum where they would give
presentations
he got really excited about i.t and now
he's an i.t
wizard and i'm very proud of the fact of
what he's done
and i should give him a as they say in
young people's language a shout out
to the fact that he helped put together
the technical aspects
of this presentation so parents of the
audience
encourage your children to go into i.t
it's a growing field
it's a safe field you'll always have a
job thank you john
well rich we thank your staff one
question here from jake
he says once you're in cyber security
what is the best way to succeed
and move up through the ranks in your
opinion
well that's a great question regardless
of the field that you're in
number one do the very best job that you
can possibly do
be recognized for being successful and
competent
and responsive those are two critical
things
to be recognized and once you are
recognized
as being competent and responsive
then you have an opportunity to meet
more and more challenging environments
um i've
spoken a lot to senior managers about
this particular issue
and to a person they will say we're
always
on the lookout for talent
there never seems to be enough talent
there are a lot of people that can do
something but we need
people to do something special so
the point is to become very competent at
what you're doing
very responsive in what you're doing and
management will notice that
if they don't then you need to help them
understand what you're doing
do it in a polite and respectful way
initially if you have to be obnoxious
later then do it what do you have to
lose
but believe me managers that are doing
their jobs
are very sensitive to identifying people
who are competent
and responsive and they want to put them
in more challenging positions
managers want to keep their own job
and the only way they can keep their job
is to have
a performance
team that does well i hope that answers
your question satisfactorily
um we had another quick question here uh
i i say quick
kind of tongue-in-cheek the question is
where do you see
where do you see cryptography going in
the future
oh gosh um you know that
john if if i were there in iowa with you
this would be a topic for what we both
would refer to as a three-drink subject
uh we would talk about it long into the
night
there are so many advances in
cryptography now
uh i think one of the ones that's safest
to talk about
from my perspective uh is quantum
uh we're seeing great advances in that
not just from the united states but also
from china
uh if you were to press me on the point
which you obviously are doing i would
uh opine that i think cha probably has
the lead on that now
or at least they're are giving better
press about the fact that they think
they have the lead on that now
i am not a cryptographer cryptologist
uh but i'm very sensitive to the fact
that we need to
devote more resources
to advancing that technology so if
you're an
expert in that field or if you have an
interest in that field
there's a tremendous opportunity for you
to make great contributions
and i encourage you to do that all right
well
i think we need to uh cut this short
because
uh we're using zoom and i don't want
china to get offended rich
but uh we don't have we don't have
anything else in the in the q
a window for right now so let me just
thank you for coming this is really
super special that
that you would uh take the time to come
here and present
and uh just share with our audience um
obviously the
a lot of the people who are on have been
at corncon in the past
and uh remember uh meeting you in person
and having conversations and
so it's uh it's great to do this in a
virtual sense
so thanks again and uh you know we
let me make one other
a tommy bahama hawaiian shirt
just for the occasion because john as
you know whenever i give a cyber
preservation
presentation i always wear a tommy
bahama shirt
not that i'm advertising tommy bahama
but it's just part of my
uh uh
part of my trademark i guess
it's your genre
yes all right uh thank thank you
everyone we will be starting up here
uh in about uh seven or eight minutes
with our next presentation uh with bob
west
and mike coogan uh on
identity in the covid 19 era
all right thanks rich yes sir thank you