good afternoon
welcome to corncon 6.
wow it's 2020 and i was told today that
it's october already
um our next speaker is uh dr gene
spafford
professor at purdue university i've
known spaff for a long time
um he's his talk has no title
uh but it's going to be a great talk we
have we have a good audience here
and uh we're recording this for
posterity it'll be up on our youtube
here
in the next day or two um
let's see i think that's about itspaf
i'll let you
take over here all right well hello
everyone i'm going to try and share my
screen
and see how this works
so i've got
a screen shared
do you see my
i i see the screen i also see the
previews on the left
all right well that's not quite right
you have the right screen now i i do see
it it's a little bit small but
it's it's very legible okay so
uh you don't have two slides up on the
screen just one
i just see one excellent
well we have a comment earlier we had a
speaker the slides were a little bit
small
and the answer was if you go up to the
top
there's a change screen
is there an option for that i'm looking
left side upper above a timer
as i recall um
oh well i'm using keynote so
okay power well this is i think this is
fine
all right i can see the slide it's just
only a little bit small so go right
ahead sorry
all right well so hi everyone
um this talk doesn't have a title and
that is the title there's ambiguity
there and that's actually part of what
i'm talking about
is ambiguity and the purpose of this
talk
um so i'll just start off by saying
this is also interspersed with the
number of quotes that i find appropriate
and i think some of you may as well
sometimes i wonder if i'm in my right
mind and then it passes off
and i'm as intelligent as ever and
that's basically what this is about
um what i want to do is start off and
say in computing
software engineering which you've and
well i won't say undoubtedly but perhaps
i've heard about
is a building systems that do what you
want them to do
safety engineering is another area of
computing
and that's building systems that don't
do things you don't want them to do
like fail catastrophically security
engineering
is building systems that only do what
you want them to do
that's the hardest of the three
because you not only have to make them
do what you want to do
but you want to make sure they don't do
things you don't want them to do
so it has to be correct and safe
part of what we do in cyber security is
try to think in ways that
system designers have not anticipated if
we're not the system
designers that is and
try to apply some out of the box
thinking to get some new insights
into science and engineering both in how
to build systems
and if our job is to look for flaws in
them
find out how they're misconfigured also
to do that
and so uh by trying to think outside the
box think in ways that the designers
didn't intend
we may be able to find some flaws or
misconfigurations
so what follows are some examples i use
in classes
some of my classes at the university to
illustrate
some ways of thinking to help you sort
of get in this mindset
and along with some lessons that may or
may not be
useful to you
i would say try to solve these if you
have some
paper and pencils or pens or crayons
an inkwell with a feather whatever it
may be
you can try to solve some of these as we
go along
otherwise try to work them out in your
head
so when you get a solution don't
post it on it on the chat if you've got
video if you've got
if you've got audio on yours don't don't
yell it out
give others an opportunity to try to
think through the solution and i'll give
the solution to these
as we go along i'm just not going to
give you a very long time for each of
them
okay so let's start
with a diagram and we're going to have
four questions related to this diagram
with this square
and it's actually seven
squares if you look at it in that way
where a b
c and d are each a square and then each
of the little black sections inside is
also a square
so let's get that out of the way they're
actually squares
so i'm going to ask you four questions
related to this
and let's see how you do so the first
question
is divide the white area in square a
that is the upper right quadrant into
two equal pieces
now this should be pretty easy you can
do this in your head you don't have to
write this down
dividing the white area into two equal
pieces
equal equivalent same that's going to be
the meaning in each of the following
problems
how do you do it there's the answer it's
fairly straightforward
each of those diagonals as each of the
parts separated by the diagonal
is a mirror image of the other one
okay let's move on to one that's a
little harder
that's in b divided into three equal
pieces
this is a little bit more difficult
still it's not too difficult and again
if you think about it for a moment you
should be able to get this
visualized in your in your mind or if
you scratch it out
very quickly on on paper or canvas or
the desk or
somebody sitting next to you you'll be
able to come up with a solution
and there it is basically just extending
to the sides of that inner
square and now we have three squares
in the white area in area b
okay so this gives you the idea now
let's move
to a harder one
divide the area c into
four equal pieces
this is difficult this is not simple
i've had people get it you can think
about it
and what i'll do is i'll give you i'll
give you a little bit of time here to
think about this and
maybe sketch it out if you've got
something that you can work on to get an
idea
of what it would look like but remember
they have to be the same shape
same volume or same area in the solution
by drawing lines there
so a couple of you may have the answer
but because this one's hard i'm guessing
that probably
most of you don't but when you see the
solution you'll go oh yeah that works
each of those if you look at it same
shape
and same area
that was a little tough but people have
a good
understanding of geometry tend to get
that
okay so now that you've loosened up on
this we're going to ask the hardest one
okay we went two three
four and now we're gonna jump to seven
okay this is really tough although
people have a really good understanding
of geometry
and unusual shapes may get this
so i'm going to let you go for a couple
seconds and think about how you
do that
it's tough isn't it although i bet a few
of you have gotten it
i mean i don't know how many there are
out there watching this
but there's probably a couple who
thought about the answer
there you go it's really not that
difficult
but what's happened is that the way i
primed you with the questions for the
other three
and their solutions you probably weren't
thinking along these lines
so if you didn't get the answer don't
feel badly about that
that's actually what very often happens
when you get stuck in a rut thinking
about things
if you get in a mode where you think
the answer must look like a certain kind
of solution
then you may not find the actual answer
so conditioning is one of the things
that we have to overcome when we work in
security
let's do another one instead of geometry
we're going to move to something to see
what your mastery is
of english language
here's a line of letters and what you
need to do is cross out six letters so
the remaining letters
without altering their sequence will
spell a familiar
english word so what i want to do
is i'll give you a whole minute
to look through this and try to think of
how you cross out six letters so the
remaining letters
will spell it from their english word
okay got 30 more seconds
i wish i had some way of knowing how
many of you
actually solved this or not i see
there's 35 people watching
all right we got 10 more seconds
there we go did you get the answer
you see there crossed out six letters
s i x l e t t e r s
and you get the word banana
here's another thing that's important
when we're working in security or
computing in general and that's being
alert to ambiguity
where something may have multiple
meanings
and i sort of like that quote by
sigmund freud there but ambiguity
pops up all the time in language because
words can have multiple meanings
just as they did in that problem and so
when we are reading a manual
or specifications or comments or user
instructions or even code
we should be alert to the fact that
there may be more than one meaning
in whatever it is we're reading or
watching
all right so we're going to go from
language to roman numerals
let's see how you do here
so the roman numeral x i
and i'm assuming most people know what
that means
x i is eleven that's ten plus one
so add a single line to that
to change it to twelve
and that's pretty straightforward you
just add another one
or another i is basically what that is
so that's how roman numerals work and i
think most people
can figure that out
so change xx to represent 19.
and i usually find that younger people
who've been exposed to this in school
um more recently tend to get this pretty
quickly
and you just put an i in between so it's
x
i x and that's 19.
so here's another one change i i to
represent nine
so it's basically changing two to
represent nine by adding a single line
now on this i'm limited somewhat by the
display the way that i
that i showed this but basically you put
a line through the second one to turn it
into an
x so you have i x and there's nine
if you got that congratulate yourself
and then we'll do one last simple one
to show how this works change
ix to represent six
single line
again this is one usually where younger
members of the audience often get this
before
older members of the audience
and i'm sure you've gotten it by now
you draw that single line and there you
have six
the lesson from this is don't assume
context
so the fact that we were talking roman
numerals
for the first three didn't mean that
they were all roman numerals
because all i did is say uh add one line
and it could be a curved line to get six
and that's what we did groucho marx one
of uh
the great philosophers of all time uh
has a quote for nearly everything and
particularly for this
so again don't assume context or don't
let previous examples constrain your
thinking for the current problem
here's one you may have seen before but
not everybody has seen it or remembers
it
we put nine dots down in a regular
pattern
and the goal is for you to draw five
straight lines without lifting your
pencil or pen or crayon or whatever it
is
from the paper so to go through each dot
exactly once
now this is a little harder to do if you
have to imagine it
and so if you don't have something to
draw with in front of you that's a
little harder
but try and imagine this
how you might do that for five lines and
nine dots
there's one
there's two
if you think about it you might be able
to come up with three more
that will take you through all the dots
and there's
actually several solutions this one
there's a third line
fourth line fifth line so you can draw
that all without taking
your your writing instrument up from
your surface
and you get five lines going through all
nine dots okay
a harder one is do the same thing with
four lines
and again i'm going to give you maybe 45
seconds here
if i was doing this in person i'd have a
better idea i'd be able to see you with
i uh paper pencil other kinds of things
to see how many of you got the solution
but we'll go for about another 30
seconds and let you
try this out if you've got some paper in
front of you
it's the same kind of problem it's just
one fewer line
which would seem easier
but it's not
all right so some of you may have the
solution
one two three
four see
four lines we never have to lift your
pencil or crayon or whatever it is from
the paper
the lesson from this is be sure you
understand the boundaries
when someone gives you a problem what's
part of it
what are the lines if you always have to
color within the lines
that may not give you all of the uh
solutions
that you might be able to uh actually
solve the problem or find this
find the solution and again
my favorite philosopher groucho marx
i've actually found that this problem is
solved again
more often by younger people
because they are less likely to feel
that they have to
follow the same within the lines
constrained solutions
how about a word problem
we'll start off with one here uh which
i'll read to you
nancy's parents were a very eccentric
physicist and a wacky electrical
engineer
we don't have any of those here right
john
um anyhow nancy's parents got married
uh in grad school so they they were both
in grad school learning things
and they had five children now because
they were eccentric
but they were very orderly i mean
physicists and other electrical
engineers tend to like order
so they named their children
the first children was nana the second
child was nay nay
third child was nini fourth child was no
no
what did they name their fifth child
if any of you said nunu
now what was nancy because nancy's
parents
were really she was the fifth child out
of five
patterns aren't rules and sometimes the
solution is given to you but because you
see the patterns
you assume that the solution or the next
in a sequence
must follow what came before it's really
important
that you don't lose track of what you've
already heard
and that you don't get into the belief
that simply because there's a pattern
that everything must match it
here's another one of those kind of word
puzzles
there's a terrible plane crash in the
andes mountains
that's in south america by the way news
reports from the scene stated
definitively that every single person
had died tragedy
authorities verified these reports a
week later 22 survivors met at a
memorial service
how can that be every single person died
and it was verified how could they meet
how's it possible and it's not simply
because it was in south america
it's because every single person had
died
all the married couples survived
again words matter
if there are adjectives or adverbs in
place
or case or other things in a description
in a requirement statement in a manual
entry
they matter and if you're doing security
you should read these carefully
make sure you understand what they mean
and how they apply
of course john von neumann great
computer scientist
was also a philosopher but part of what
he did
no use being precise about something
when you don't even know what you're
talking about
talking about the single people there no
single person
or no every single person died that's
being precise
it's just being precise in a way that
you may be uh ignoring
here's a little computer program
and this is written in well c c plus
plus
um and um
i realize not everybody in the audience
is familiar with that language
but it's just a little short section of
code
and when i say what is wrong
let me just say that
there is something wrong with this
program
and the question is what is it and so
i'll let you look at this
i'll give you i'll give you again a
little bit of time
give you and give you a minute to look
at it
and
some of the old-timey programmers or
people who've done an awful lot of
systems work
have uh spotted this one i've given it
but
many many programmers look at this and
don't realize what's wrong with it
so i'll give you another 10 seconds to
look at it
okay
now on a 32-bit machine
i give the numbers here the same would
be true for a 64-bit or 128-bit
when you put in numbers that are near
the extremes
of the capacity of the numbers and add
them together
they overflow into a negative number
and so the program will print the sum of
two positive integers as always a
positive integer
and then it will print a negative
integer
the arithmetic that is done
on a computer system does not
always mirror what happens in the
outside world
because the values in a computer system
whether they're integral or floating
precision
are limited as to what they can
represent
they lose precision they lose values and
so if you're going to write code you
should always
check to make sure that you haven't hit
those limits
douglas adams uh not exactly a
philosopher
but a great thinker whose works i can
recommend highly
uh observe that in cases of major
discrepancy it's always reality that's
got it wrong
because reality is frequently inaccurate
which we know all too well
so remember what i started with
security or software engineering is
building system to do what you want them
to do
safety engineering is building systems
that don't do things you don't want them
to do
and security engineering is building
systems that only do what you want
them to do if you aren't clear what a
system should do
or what a system might do then you can't
constrain what it should do
or i should say will do that slide i got
it wrong
you can't constrain what it will do
the problem is if you don't really
understand if you don't understand the
requirements
if you don't understand the context if
you don't understand the limitations of
the programming language or the system
you're working with
if you don't understand the eventual
goals
no you can't build it correctly
and you're not going to be able to make
it secure
so that brings me to the end of the
slides
other than this one where i want to say
thank you for listening to me
and i will open this up
if anybody has any questions or comments
that you want to ask i'd be happy to
respond
all right folks if you have anything
please type it in the chat or the q
a
yeah i don't have the chat showing i
just have the q a
so please use that if you uh oh there's
the there's the chat
win says hi hey win
well we have some real positive feedback
we have plenty of time if anybody has a
thought-provoking question
all right lots of kudos um good to see
you spath
here i'll come on shad and i are here
he's kind of hiding there in the shadows
isn't he yeah yeah
his invisibility cloak has got a short
it's uh yeah it's uh he got it from boba
fett
and it was uh secondhand but uh we did
take the
death star down earlier so we're really
excited about that
excellent excellent we've we've hit some
of our deliverables for this conference
so yeah well you can see i'm giving the
talk from my control room and all my
minions have taken the afternoon off yes
yes i can see that
um i'm going to have to zoom in and see
if i can see any passwords on the
screens there
all right well hey it's it's great to
see you say hi to patty and uh
i'll i'll end the recording and thank
the audience we're going to be starting
up
at 3 30 central in about nine minutes
with our next speaker our final speaker
is ira winkler uh talking about you can
stop stupid
so great presentation and that would be
great i would love to get him uh
to apply that to at least my university
administration
there you go there you go i'm sure we
all have some executives we'd include in
that list
yes there are well i hope everybody
enjoys the rest of corncon
and the weekend uh it's a pleasure as
always
uh john and uh thank you all for
listening
so all right thanks beth have a great
weekend