back to that next year and whatnot and
back to some sort of normalcy
uh but today's talk uh understanding
offense um
is one of my favorites because it's
something that i commonly run into
when we're testing organizations day in
and day out and we test
you know some of the largest
organizations in the world always small
to medium-sized businesses and
you know there's a there's a struggle
that that is consistently across the
board for
for pretty much every organization that
we go in and
and identify and it's usually having an
understanding around what their
priorities should be
around how you best defend your
organization and and how do you actually
implement that based on the amount of
resources and time and everything else
that you have
and and really i think a lot of a lot of
companies focus very heavily on
technology implementation versus
understanding visibility and
understanding what attackers do from a
post exploitation perspective
and and it's it's a very different mind
mindset um to have when you're going
into
and looking at how you should best
secure your organization
so today we'll be talking about how do
we start you know looking at at
understanding our threat models what
adversaries are doing
um how do we um best prioritize those
and how do we build our security
programs to be
be successful i'll also be going through
some uh you know specific ways of
getting around
certain detection criteria and what
attackers do and things of that effect i
have a couple demos here i'll go through
as well from a technical perspective
um but i really appreciate you joining
today
just a brief introduction myself my name
is dave kennedy um i've been in the
security industry now for gosh over 20
years so
means i'm getting old um but uh you know
i started my career off working for
um the united states marine corps i was
in the intelligence community
um focusing more on cyber warfare
activities um and so i worked a lot
um with the nsa doing you know a lot of
different things a lot of fun times i
had two tours in iraq
um i've been a chief security officer
for a fortune 1000 company for a number
of years
and i started my own two companies uh
trusted second binary defense
uh we have over 300 folks uh worldwide
every everybody from the uk
norway you know pretty much consistently
all across the board and uh just really
trying to
have the best the best folks working
with our customers
making them better from a security
standpoint uh day in and day out
um i also co-authored the book
metasploit the penetration testers guide
uh which was a lot of fun writing uh
from the rears i think it's actually
back here somewhere
um but i was it was written in 11
different languages so we had
chinese in a number of you know
different different languages that it
was uh converted into
so that was a lot of fun and um i write
a lot of open source
uh tools so i wrote magic unicorn the
social engineer toolkit
pentesters framework a number of other
tools as well um focusing on either
defense or exploitation or expert
research
uh in a lot of cases i'm on the news
quite often
uh and i also helped out with the the tv
show mr robot
i also just recently uh got a delorean
so i'm really excited about that um
i've always wanted to learn as a kid um
and so over the past uh
over the next few months i'm going to be
uh working on kind of converting it to
the uh the back to the future
one two and three i wanna be able to do
all three of them uh so be modding it
out obviously giving it a
capacitor
and everything else but i just got that
last week so i wanted to put that in
there that i'm now the proud owner of
the
1982 dmc uh delorean which you know
it's actually a really cool car a lot of
weird things um quirks about it because
you know it was
designed kind of from the ground up um
but the engine itself is like so
underpowered so it's like a
1980s you know uh car when you're
driving it so it's really
really underpowered uh so that's always
fun i might do a new engine swapping
or something like that down the road
we'll see that's not what we're here to
talk today
um why we're here to talk today is you
know
organizations regardless if you're small
or large struggle with different things
um whether that's you know hey we're
predominantly moving to the cloud and
understanding cloud technology
whether that's a hybrid model whether
that's understanding what our perimeter
looks like
what understanding and educating our
users you know information security
tackles a lot of different areas and
it's an extremely complex
program to implement because you have to
essentially interface with a lot of
different businesses
and when you look at um a lot of
different organizations
you know one of the most complex
programs within a security program
is by far and hands down vulnerable
management volume management to me is is
one of the hardest
programs to actually accomplish with an
organization because one you're never
done
i mean i've never seen a company that
didn't have any vulnerabilities that
just doesn't happen
but the second part about it is you know
when you start looking at you know hey
maybe we have our operating systems down
okay and maybe we you know we're getting
to third-party um applications okay
we start getting into like the web
application databases middleware tier
things that affect ownership really
starts to kind of go out the window
on who's actually you know in charge of
maintaining and supporting
um that as we go along and so you know
when you look at vulnerable management
as an organization you know it we know
that that
we're not going to be a perfect system
that you know there are going to be
systems out there that we didn't know
existed there's going gonna be systems
out there that are legacy there's gonna
be systems out there
that we can't patch because it'll impact
the business too much there are systems
out there that
we just haven't identified the exposures
out there whether it's a custom map
third-party app
software that we have in place
regardless you know there's a lot of a
lot of complexities
running technology within an
organization and technology is just
expanding and increasing right we have a
technology that that gets added all the
time i'm sure
i'm sure everybody here knows of every
single piece of technology that is
implemented in every one of your
organizations and continues to know that
every single day
day in and day out um usually doesn't
happen that way right
and so with technology progression with
our attack surfaces expanding
you know the mindset of of ten years ago
was hey let's build a castle let's build
this heavily fortified
castle that you know is he's got these
um you know he's got a drawbridge he's
got archers
we got all this stuff that we can
protect the inside of our castle with
then you know what we started realizing
is hey now we have things like work from
home we have
different architecture designs where our
users are more mobile and and remote in
in many cases and we were leveraging
more cloud infrastructure so
our our castles are no longer there and
our attack surfaces have have absolutely
changed
as technology has changed as well and so
when you start looking at kind of the
current state of security
most organizations struggle to
understand complex techniques
and and when we talk about techniques um
the you know the term the tactics
techniques and procedures
is commonly used all across the board so
ttps right um
you know most organizations are solely
focusing on just the techniques and not
understanding the tactics that
adversaries
um go through and the procedures that
they operate by and
this is kind of a um a shift that the
industry continues to need
to need to do which is hey we know that
vulnerability management isn't going to
be perfect we know that we're going to
have some issues
um you know that we're not going to be
able to address or that we didn't know
existed
and that an attacker could potentially
exploit those specific weaknesses
and so if we know that that's the case
you know traditionally
let's let's fly back 10 years ago
whenever an organization would get a
penetration test done
and they'd focus you know on on
identifying what exposures they have so
they can patch them
there would be less of a focus on what
happened afterwards so for example let's
just say
you know i popped a a web application
had sql injection on it gave me
you know command execution and then from
command execution i was able to get real
code execution and from
remote code execution i was able to you
know um do defense evasion and from
there move laterally across the network
until i got access to
you know a system that was a server that
had a local admin on it that a weak
password then from there i was able to
move to another server and then from
there you know i got domain admin and
from there i was able to get access to
maintenance okay
let's just take that as an example you
know just a standard penetration test
a lot of the focus would have been the
weak password
from the admin account would have been
the sql injection on the web application
and that probably would have been it uh
from an attack surface perspective of
what
it would actually focus on now the the
problem with that is that
while you're addressing those specific
actual holes that you have which are
things that you should do because
they're risks right you need to
prioritize those with personnel timing
everything else
and address those and fix those there
was less of a focus on
the actual attack patterns that occurred
when that sql injection attack was
successful
so what happens when an attack is
actually successful within an
organization so you compromise
you have access now what happens okay
now we start looking at
you know defense evasion persistence
lateral movement all these post
exploitation scenarios all the way to
exfiltration
and and we start to look at those when
we break those down in our environments
and are those things that we can um
either a prevent you know within our
environment you know disallow certain
things from running uh consistently
across our enterprise
um or two are the things that we can
easily detect so that we can identify
when an attacker is in our environment
earlier on
and so you know you see something like
the miter attack framer come out
um and and you know what's interesting
about miter attack is that
um i have rarely seen an organization
actually implement
the miter attack framework um they want
to do it but then they look at the
techniques and sub techniques and like
well there's thousands of techniques
here i don't even know where to start so
i'm not gonna even bother
and and there's a there's a there's a
problem with that because
when you look at what security operation
centers um today are designed to do
they're still
very traditional a sense of you know
information comes in from a log
that log shorter is an alarm they look
at that alarm is that alarm a false
positive or not
close that alarm move on to the next one
or escalate it to tier two tier three
stock analyst
so you know we we still have the
traditional methods of security
operation centers
when we should really be looking at
unusual behavior or things that are
that are exhibiting behavior within our
environment that we should be
investigating from an attack surface
perspective
it's what we consider threat hunting um
in in many cases
so we're still very much a signature
driven industry and i'll talk about that
here in a second
um even even if you have an edr
you know endpoint detection response
tool deployed in your environment it's
still very signature driven
they have what they've built from known
techniques into their tools
hopefully detecting stuff that you've
seen a great example
is i just made a post on twitter
recently about it and we had a customer
that
was running one of the one of the brand
names and edr products
um and had both the endpoint detection
and endpoint protection on
and uh we had a red team engaging with
them and everybody wants a red team
engagement uh
it's it's because it's like the most
amazing thing everybody thinks it sounds
amazing so we got to do it
because we can't do a traditional pen
test because we're well above
a penetration test right we got to do a
red team i would say
probably 80 to 90 percent of people that
we test from a red teaming perspective
are not able to handle
what an actual red team entails um and
and we have varying levels of
sophistication like we can
simulate you know whatever specific
adversary that are in their
uh individual industry verticals all the
way to extremely mature
zero-day routes you know undocumented
features completely custom attack
surface
attack uh chains you know across their
environment to to some of the ones that
can actually handle those
but what's interesting with this
customer um and this is not a knock on
the customer i mean
a great customer they're they're amazing
uh folks
is that they relied though very heavily
off of technology
and when you rely heavily just off your
technology you're not improving
your environment you know understanding
what that detection means in your
environment or what the detections are
within the edr products that can be
circumvented
you don't have a good monitoring
detection program by slapping an edr
does not make
you secure in any way shape or form it
means you might have some more
visibility
you might have some predefined things
that maybe your antivirus didn't pick up
but you're still far far far far away
from being able to withstand even
an average level of sophistication
towards your organization from a
hacker's perspective
and look at what the ransomware authors
are doing we'll talk about this as we go
along
but the ransomware authors have have
gained a substantial amount of
sophistication
that are designed to get around your edr
products that are designed to get around
your antivirus products and they're
designed to inflict as much damage as
possible
and so if you don't continuously focus
on enhancing your monitoring detection
capabilities
you're going to fail when it comes to
protecting against specific attacks and
i'll show you some examples of this here
in a little bit and we also talk about
threat intelligence in a sense where
you know threat intelligence um is is
still to a lot of organizations
domain names of already compromised
infrastructure not actual techniques
broken down based off of industry
vertical based off of adversaries in
your threat models that you can use
actionably
to build better detection criteria in
your environment so again we have a lot
of maturing to do here and this isn't
a blanket segment across the board there
are some organizations that are doing
phenomenal
um at a lot of this but most are still
at a very basic level which again
we're talking about but to my back to my
story really quick around the
penetration test
you know the the the company would only
focus on sql injection and that password
not on all the different steps um that
that happened during that you know
how did i get those credentials in the
first place how did i move laterally
from one workstation to the next
workstation or one from one server to
the next server
you know one of those those those
specific types of techniques that i
would leverage
in an environment and there's there's
common ones across the board you know
whether i'm doing
you know local link multicast name
resolution protocol or netbell's name
services or whether i'm doing printer
spool attacks um
you know abusing unconstrained
delegation um
you know common techniques that we'll
see very much applied
consistently across a lot of attacks you
know those are things that you can
quickly
identify and work work through your
program without without a lot of effort
a lot of
a lot of change and so if you look at
our adversaries
you know 95 of of companies are not in
the nation-state category um
when it comes to to who their threat
models are
so understanding your threat models is
number one in any any program that you
want to
build because you need to understand
what your your offense is doing in order
to get a better defense
um so first and foremost having um and
understanding who your adversaries are
in play
uh and what their sophistication level
and capabilities are is number one and
starting to map those right so building
out your threat models
overall now i talked about this earlier
but what's interesting
about ransomware is that you know i was
completely wrong
a couple of years ago you know when i
saw what happened with the carter market
and the carter market got tough uh for a
lot of these these
that that soon became the ransomware
authors the the ransomware as a service
type models
um you know i thought ransomware was
going to kind of die off and the reason
why i thought it would die off is
because they were they were at such a
low sophistication level
um that i really didn't see them
progressing much and i thought yeah they
would get
you know people with with you know
fishing campaigns and small companies
that didn't do any security whatsoever
um but i thought that would eventually
increase and raise
um as time went on and so what ended up
happening though
is is is ransomware got a little bit
more
crazy um as things go um
sorry one second okay sorry about that
um
so i you know as ransomware
started impacting very immature users
and their sophistication levels were low
what the ransomware authors did which
was fairly unique was invest more in
their infrastructure the development and
getting more people
so it's kind of like a full-fledged
business
that was kind of happening and when that
started occurring they started getting
more and more sophisticated and going
after small to medium-sized businesses
and now we just started seeing recently
over the past year and a half them
targeting large
large organizations and going with with
very different types of attacks and i'll
talk about tech customizations here in
just a second
but i mean they're they're using living
off the land they're using powershell
exploitation they're developing their
own code
they're weaponizing their own tooling
they're leveraging open source resources
and
in open uh open source tools um
offensive security tools
um and so they're they're they're mixing
together all of these different areas to
have a recipe for success
and we just saw a couple days ago you
know universal uh health systems i just
had a massive day debris or not data
breach but ransomware attack
shut down their hospitals they're
turning people away allegedly for deaths
apparently again not confirmed on that
one so i don't want to
start rumors there just what was been
reported we saw uh garmin recently 15
million dollar ransom
they're getting bigger and bolder with
what they're doing and their
sophistication levels are not just hey
we're going to send out this executable
and this this document you know to free
to go and download is going to go and
download a binary wrapper then from
there execute
it's changing quite a bit um as things
have gone along so
you know and what's what's also
interesting about this is that they're
focusing less on the automation aspects
of things and they're doing more
targeted attacks
you know doing open source intelligence
gathering uh looking for
um you know specific patterns then go
after starting to target your
organization infrastructure in a very
customized approach and once they have
access to a system
you know they start focusing on other
ways that we can do
post-exploitation scenarios and lateral
movement across your environment
um and and continuously focus on that so
again ways that they are getting better
overall and those are things that we
don't typically look at in our specific
threat models and what we're building
from a detection standpoint
so in today's industry if you customize
and attack in any way shape or form you
can pretty much get around most
detections today
um that one customer that we was talking
about we did the red team engagement
with
you know they had a a one of the the top
you know
edr products out there both in
protection in texas and they didn't see
us for over a month
we had nothing that flagged not once in
their entire infrastructure environment
and they were shocked because they're
like well our edr products should have
picked this specific thing up and we're
like
yeah well i mean if we customize our
attacks your edr's not going to see it
you have to focus on your environment
and and look for unusual behavior in
your environment to get better at
actual detections so let's take an
example of of
getting around detections today and
obviously this is
uh windows defender it could be with any
product itself they're all very similar
nature
um to how they work even if it's an edr
product or or things of that effect and
in this case
we're going to call registry r32 now
register 32 is one of the most abused
um living off the land binders and
scripts that's out there a lot of
ransomware use it
um you know as a downloader and execute
a way to execute scriptlet objects
um but if you're not familiar with
living off the lan just just a really
quick um history lesson
on some of this um so primarily you know
the the method for exploitation was
still executables and binaries which are
still heavily used today because a lot
of people don't have good control
over unsigned code being executed in
their systems and then things kind of
migrated um to powershell
um and and powershell has been a a major
attack surface for
for the longest time and then you look
at what's what's called living on the
land and this isn't specific to windows
this is also this also very much applies
to osx
and linux as well and these are
applications
that are built in by the operating
system or third parties
they're code signed um and you know the
by the the specific
producer of that code you know to verify
the integrity of the code itself
and they have additional functionality
in them that allow for certain things
that happen like remote code execution
or things of that effect
in this specific case on registrar 32
you can go and download a document or
anything you want to it just
contains whatever it wants but inside of
it if you have it what's called a script
object which is you know a scripting
language that you can use for
um you know essentially compromising the
system if you want to um
you can call that specific script object
dll and have it parse that and
automatically execute
now since this attack this is since this
is actively used quite frequently
and microsoft instead of reducing its
attack surface and removing that
functionality out
they decided to write you know a windows
defender signature now
windows defender is straight up a
signature based antivirus product there
is no machine learning
artificial intelligence i don't care
what their marketing says um about it it
is straight up a signature based
antivirus product there is no behavior
in it whatsoever
um and and it's extremely trivial to get
around again signature-based detectors
even with things like with the
antimatter scanner face or amsi which
was incorporated in windows 10
amsi is dead it is not a security
boundary
um it is not a way to protect you in any
way shape or form it is a commodity
uh way of scanning scripted uh uh
scripting languages
um it is so far broken uh from a a
preventative standpoint
um that's not even funny so
you know from from that side don't even
worry about amsi from an attacker
standpoint we can we can
we can disable it um you know we can
tell it not to scan
you know there's two function types amsi
scan string and as i scan buffer
there's a million of different ways to
get around amsi so it doesn't even touch
your code in the first place you don't
have to worry about obfuscating your
code
you can just shut off amsi in the first
place and windows defender will never
scan in the first place so it is
it is broke um you know 10 ways to
sunday because it runs in
under the context of the user land aim
has said a dll gets injected into a
process space that you control as that
regular user can shut it down on any way
shape or form but anyways
in this specific case we see here that
that windows defender is
um blocking the specific command from
executing
um so it's going up to this website
downloading this this text document
and then what it's trying to accomplish
is just running calculate exe as an
example
so as an attacker is there a way for us
to manipulate or modify this code in
some way shape or form
to gain remote code execution so the
answer that is yes
if we remove what the signature is uh
for windows defender and instead of of
going out to the website and downloading
we can just use another application
within windows to go and download our
text file
uh that test.txt in this case you can
use bits admin you can use excel
new versions of windows have curl um
there's a million different ways to
go and download a file um off of you
know from the command line
inside the house and in this case you
know bits admin goes out to the internet
is downloading test.txt and then from
there we call registrar 32 without going
out to the internet
um and then running our script logic
which completely circumvents the
defender
signature for this specific case here
again very very broke very easy
to get around as an attacker's
perspective and that's very much how edr
products work as well
they're looking for very specific um
types of attacks because they have to
write signatures
for entire enterprises and organizations
that when you don't turn their product
on you don't have 600
000 you know false positives in your
environment so they're very tuned pruned
um type of of detections in those
environments and so
you know modifying it and changing it in
some way shape or form completely blocks
that um
completely evades those detection
criteria they have in place
here's another example i'll show you
here with uh with uh
using magic unicorn and so you magic
unicorn's a powershell exploitation
framework that i wrote
um and what it does is it um creates a
one-liner
essentially for you to go and download
or to execute um shellcode directly into
memory through powershell
and uh windows defender loves my tool
they love writing signatures for it
um you know i'll come up with a new
version they'll write signatures it's
the most ridiculous thing ever because
a funny story with this i didn't mean to
do that but a really quick funny story
um about this one is um i i wrote two
tools uh one was called trevor c2
uh which is a command control framework
that does the exact same thing
it has a c sharp module a powershell
module um
a c-plus plus module
that's cross-compatible to linux osx and
windows
and um when i wrote unicorn they'll
write new signatures all the time but
they still haven't written anything for
for trevor so you can just download
trevor
execute that have it load you know
whatever you want to show code into
memory
and it doesn't get detected because you
know they they only focus on unicorn so
if your tools popular
uh and and you know they decide they
want to write tools for they assign
essentially resources to write
signatures when new versions are out but
they don't focus on anything else so
it's it's ridiculous it's a cat and
mouse game but in this specific case
it's it's so easy to get around so
we're gonna i'm gonna go and open this
this generated code that we just did
this is our obfuscated code it's just
base64 encoded
so we get around execution restriction
policies and then we're going to decode
it so that we can take a look
at the code through windows windows 10.
now what we're going to see here is
we're going to see
amsi the antimatter scan interface
actually
scan my code now really quick here
what's going to happen
uh just behind the scenes within windows
internals is that we're going to copy
this code we're going to move it over to
the powershell interpreter
the powershell ise and when we hit play
what's going to happen is there's
there's a hook point in my in my in when
my code's about to execute
where amsi dot dll is is injected and
there's going to be an msi scan string
or msi scan buffer in this specific case
it's going to be amsa scan string
it's going to scan that code to look for
any predefined signatures that has been
written through what's called an amsi
provider an enable site provider is
going to be in this case specifically
windows defender
so amsi is going to submit to the amsi
provider
the string that i am trying to execute
on that system itself
um and so it's going to come back saying
hey antivirus detected this because they
wrote a
signature but we'll see how easy it is
to get around
that signature in the first place here
so we'll go ahead and copy this
and we'll move it over to the other side
and then we're going to hit play we're
going to create a um
a listener first so we can catch the the
shell when we hit it but we hit play
notice here it says uh the script
contains
um malicious content has been blocked so
we're gonna do is i'm gonna try to chunk
this up a little bit to figure out what
parts actually getting detected so i'm
just gonna delete this last line here
gonna cut it out hit play and notice we
don't get that that same error message
before which means that there's
a signature right in this specific line
here that's getting caught so what we're
gonna do instead is we're just gonna
chunk this line up to say a equals
and we're gonna take the second part of
the the code uh which is
invoke expression and we're just going
to substitute it in for a for a variable
a and then we're going to play again
and we completely get around um d
detection for that specific area so
he's got to kind of play with it right
um i have an automated tool that
automatically goes through and submits
on behalf of amsi scan
scan string um to tell whether or not my
code is actually being detected
um by a specific piece and it chunks it
up into places it knows the interpretive
language of powershell
and it chunks it up into a place to find
exactly where that signature is being
flagged at
and then it'll it'll either a if it
knows how to it automatically rewrite it
for me with obfuscation just and then
submit it again to see if it gets past
it
um or b um it'll tell me exactly where i
need to uh go in order to rewrite my
code to get around it so it just takes a
couple of seconds
to get around whenever they release a
new signature for the code
itself so you know trivial to get around
from a
attack service perspective so most
organizations rely heavily
off of their products and tooling
whether it's an edr whether it's a
next-gen firewall whether it's their
monitoring detection from from an
um from a sim perspective but most
organizations
don't enhance their security products as
they implement i'm not saying having an
edr is bad or having a sim is bad those
are all great things you want visibility
into your infrastructure
but relying upon them to be your sole
front of the detection is a really
critical area that most organizations
fail at because it's so easy to get
around
these specific products and so you look
at things like like edr products right
we as attackers going into
infrastructure know you know what your
edr product flags and doesn't flag on
we're not stupid we test this out well
ahead of time
and um i think it was um it was hexa um
adam
um just recently um uh hexagon um
sorry if i butchered the the name um but
uh he recently said you know if
if any of those products were public in
nature where you could download free
trials
um they would be completely destroyed
within you know two or three weeks just
just based on
how how big the gaps are within their
environment and um that that's a hundred
percent true
i mean uh you you couldn't you couldn't
have said it any better
these products are you know the reason
why they are they have been somewhat
effective
um and what hexachord was saying you
know on that specific area is that you
know it's because they're not widely
public to security researchers or
attackers
so you have to figure out a way of
getting them to test them out but that's
the only thing is just kind of tripping
on landmines and figuring things out
versus actually building
detection criteria um in your overall
environment so
again most organizations are still at a
very much a basic level
and you know some are further along than
others which is a great thing
those are folks that that focus on
understanding
what attackers are doing and i'll get
into that in just a second
so that's that's the main problem right
the problem is is that we don't look
at what our adversaries are doing we
don't look at what our threat models are
and we don't prioritize our security
program to to
to incorporate those specific input
items to build our security program in
the first place
our strategies are all focused on the
wrong areas our strategies are focused
on
all of the things that that we
hypothetically want to do
from a strategic roadmap perspective
over the next three years we want to
implement uh you know network access
control we want to resegment our network
those are all great things to aspire to
100 you shouldn't
not do that but it's going to take time
and effort so how do you keep
your security program that's at a basic
level in a way that you can minimize the
damage towards your organization until
you can get
all those things in place and so it's
that balancing act of having the
visibility and detection and making sure
that you can focus on your strategy at
the same time
and that really comes down to to
leveraging red when we talk about
leveraging red
when we talk about that specific
component there it's
it's understanding what red is doing
understanding what your adversaries are
doing right and i said that a lot
but most people don't look at that they
don't look at specific apt groups or you
know
insect specific type type you know
groups that are focusing on their
specific industry vertical
we looked very specifically off of well
hey we just got this new feed in we're
going to throw this feed into our tool
automatically and hopefully it detects
you know a specific hash or
you know a specific command and control
that's out there today we're going to
try to automate as much as possible so
that
you know we don't have to worry about it
unfortunately it takes a lot of hard
work and effort
and miter attack is a great example of a
good starting point because
with miter attack you don't have to do
all of the thousands of techniques
you can focus on the specific adversary
groups that are
in your industry vertical break down
those tactics and procedures
and start to build good detections now
let's just go back a second really quick
to
before is a good detection
for this specific attack looking for
regis qr32 with a slash i
and an hdp in it i.e what windows
defender is doing
the answer to that is no that is not a
good detection because we can get around
that
but what would be a good detection for
regis sphere 32 how about looking at
your entire environment
and seeing if you ever have seen a
process creation
for a regis vr 32 in your environment
from a regular user
i guarantee you the answer to that is no
so instead of focusing on a command line
um argument why not focus on registry
r32
ever being executed in the first place
or registry r32
ever going out to the internet in the
first place registrar 32 with network
communications
that is a good detection a bad detection
is what we see here because we have to
baseline
environments and again edr products and
antivirus products
focus very heavily on multitude of
organizations and corporations as they
go through
we don't have a good detection if we
just focus um solely on that
and and the way that you can you can
definitely approach this and start to
build it down is is by leveraging purple
teams
um or or just having somebody that
understands offense and working on
building the detections based off of
that and if you look at something they
might attack
um there's a blog that we did recently
on the top 10 most used miter attacks
that are
attack techniques that are out there
today that's a great starting point also
going through ones that you know that
you've heard of before because it's
probably relevant to your environment
and then start taking adversaries and
start prioritizing them hey these are
the
top 50 that we want to implement in our
organization that's a great step
of the top 50 attack techniques that are
out there
and ways that we can detect them in our
environment and getting better with
those detections right
um starting to whittle away that way
makes a big difference
in what you're trying to accomplish in
your mind detection program
and it really comes down to we we have a
a lack of detection in organizations i
can't tell you
how many times you know i go into an
organization as long as i don't trip
trigger their their signature base
detection i'm usually fine or even if i
do there's a
i did a talk last year um at wild west
hacking fest where
i started um messing with with security
analysts uh sock analysts
and knowing that that my my attack was
going to be detected how do i tell a
different story
um to the security operations center
that i'm going after
and the way that it did that was i would
take my malicious code that would get
picked up by
an edr product or antivirus or whatever
ends up being not antivirus specifically
um but their monitor detection program
and would definitely send an alarm
to a sock analyst and i'd wrap it in a
huge
massive script so like for example let's
just say i was using magic unicorn that
does shell coat injection
directly into memory through the
powershell process obviously malicious
if you saw obfuscated code coming across
your screen
what i did is i took a large microsoft
script uh powershell script and i tucked
my powershell
malicious powershell code halfway
through that script and guess what
happened
yep that flag does a false positive
right because they're not going to go
through thousands of lines of powershell
code they're like well this is a
this looks like a good script and a lot
of times what i'll even do from an
attacker's perspective
is i'll do osint on linkedin and find
like server admins or people within
their own organization
and i'll put like comment code in there
from that specific person that actually
works at that company
saying hey this is you know a script
that i'm using for blah blah blah if you
need any help just email me and i'll put
the email address in there
so for stock analysts it's like oh this
is this is bob
you know i know bob i work with bob
every day he's just using the script to
do some stuff cool we're all set i'm
just gonna
mark this as a false positive so we have
even larger challenges there i'm not
gonna go into
that part because that's that's the
human piece of it um
but you know the the piece that we're
lacking is that the priority and the
strategy around that
and really having a good understanding
um around
offense um and what your offense is
doing makes a good defense now i put the
cleveland browns in here because i'm
from cleveland
uh it's been an interesting season ever
each and every year but hey we're up uh
2-1 right now so that's a good that's a
good thing uh we've actually had we
actually have more victories
i think it's the first time we've had
two consecutive victories since like
seven years ago or something like that
which is
which has never happened uh we had a
perfect season one year we lost every
single game the whole the whole season
so we
you know maybe using this as a reference
isn't a good understanding because they
they can't figure out offense or defense
um but sports aside um
you know having a good understanding
around what your offense is doing helps
you build that better defense and
and that collaboration approach of
really working back and forth
um definitely makes it makes a big
difference overall
when we talk about um threat models
right and i've mentioned this
a number of different times but if
you're not prioritizing your detections
in how you're looking at maturing your
sock what what has happened is is that
we
what should be happening from a cyclical
effect from a security operation center
perspective
is that you have your sock analysts and
those sake analysts should be
less focused on the day in and day out
alarms
and i don't think you should remove the
ability for that but they should be
focusing on more of that
what we call the long tail if you're
familiar with the long tail concept
where
you have your your high volume stuff
that's up here and then as you start to
get down more and look at the unusual
things that are happening in the tail of
an attack
those are the the uh unusual indicators
that
are things that we should definitely
focus in there so
all of those things are our pieces that
we need to focus on from an attack
service perspective and start to build
um our detections around there now at
the same time you should have proactive
people
looking through your data looking
through your logs trying to understand
what's actually happening
uh to build all of those out and the
cyclical effect starts to occur
as you start to build those in and start
testing it from a purple teaming
perspective or more of an
offensive capabilities perspective and
enhancing your detection so again
continual
improvement of your security operation
center as you go along
um when you talk about prioritization
you know we have two
strategies right you want to have your
your long-term strategy
of of building out um your
your security program your strategic you
know portions whether that's network
segmentation
patch management volume management etc
you also want to have that stop gap of
things that are coming out new new
attacks that are coming out
things that are being actively exploited
in the environment being able to have
that stop gap to reduce that dwell time
that an attacker has
in your environment um some basics that
work
uh well in the preventative side you
know disallowing unsigned executables
within user profile directories
uh things like constrained language mode
within powershell
you know going to powershell version six
and disallowing powershell version two
um cismod i'm a huge fan of um using
kernel level event log tracing for
windows which is a free tool from mark
rusenovich's team over at microsoft
um great configurable option and olaf
hardong has um
has added a sysmon modular uh which
allows you to get a pretty extensive
amount of coverage with the miter attack
framework
um just enabling your windows firewall
um will stop lateral movement internally
especially if those firewalls can't
communicate with one another
you can't move from one system to the
next that's a great thing
uh you have to have endpoint logs today
that that's that's a must if you're not
doing that you're really far behind
um not just north to south traffic but
also east the west
improving on your visibility um and
focusing on on threat hunting and what
uh specific attackers are doing and i
just want to repeat one more time
before i close it off and open up to
some questions here but
you know you have to baseline your
environment and detect off of that right
understanding behavior in your
environment and that's going to show up
false positives a good example is
a good detection of a powershell isn't
looking for encoded command or kernel
32.dll or invoke expression
that's that's going to get you some high
commodity stuff but looking for whatever
powershell is communicating out to the
internet
that's going to be a false positive
nightmare at first because you're going
to have to baseline
and look for deviations those baselines
as you go along um
but as you start to whittle those
through you start to see less and less
and less of those and
now you can start to actually look for
unusual activity in your environment
originating in the first
place uh here's a blog post that we did
um if you just go
look up trusted tech top ten minor
techniques um you can find uh the
specific top tens there
um for you happy to you know share the
link or the the presentation afterwards
i think i linked them all in the section
um in the the latter stages of the
presentation um but closing up here i
want to thank everybody uh for for
corncon from having me um and uh for
putting on this this awesome conference
you know when it comes to
what we deal with today we still cannot
rely off of technology to automate us we
have to focus on people first
educating people educating our
environment so that we can look for
unusual behavior
um as things going on that comes from
understanding what attackers are doing
helping prioritize that in working
through that uh within your own
environment
um i have some other resources here um
you know you can go download just some
some good reading material um down down
the road i'll be happy to send these
slides out to anybody that wants it hit
me up on twitter or whatnot
but thank you again very much for having
me and uh happy to answer any questions
that you have
dave thank you so much uh looks like we
do have one question let me just pull it
up here at least
um it comes from nate would you estimate
that all the major offensive innovations
come from the nation state orgs and if
so would a cyber geneva convention
make the cyber world a safer place
i think i think i don't think a lot of
the innovation comes from
um a lot of the nation states you know
you look at some of the attacks um that
are coming out from from ransomware
groups um you know they're they're
highly sophisticated a lot of innovation
coming from there there was one recently
where um
it was emoted that um would
automatically scan your wireless
infrastructure
um to try to piggyback in and expand its
network communications and services too
so
you know a lot of the re i see a lot of
innovation comes from the
research industry as far as new you know
techniques that are happening out there
to try to
enhance and improve uh security overall
for a lot of them
um but you know nation states definitely
um are
a major concern because as soon as those
get discovered there's usually some
pretty awesome
secret sauce in there that's actually
happening um as it's going along so
you know i think um you know it's it's
all over the place where a lot of this
is coming off from it's it's you know
there's there's nation states there's
you know organized crime groups there's
researchers there
you know that this whole industry is is
exploding because technology is
exploding so fast so
i'm not sure if something like that
would help or not but i think um
you know a consortium of understanding
um the implications around attack
surfaces and being able to build your
defenses makes a big deal
great and then there is one more will
you be in the concord discord answering
questions later
uh unfortunately i don't have time to uh
to hang out in the discord but
maybe i can drop by a little bit later
tonight and my kids have uh basketball
practice here a little bit later so
apologize for that uh
but won't be able to make that but thank
you so much yeah norris thank you dave
that was all
thanks everybody take care bye
oh
sorry dramaal you uh came in before
and you win the chat all right
we're gonna be back at 11 115
with uh sean anderson executive security
advisor at microsoft
doing what should we trust should we
trust but verify or trust nothing and
verify everything
all right see you guys soon
you