[Music]
next talk is going to be
shut up and take my money by vincent
halpert
vincent is a research associate at the
security research group
of the department of computer science at
friedrich alexander universitate in
erlangen
nuremberg germany typical very long
german word
his main research interests are
authentication system security
and software protection of mobile
devices there's actually vincent's
second time speaking of the congress
last year his talk discussed conceptual
insecurity
of app generated passwords in online
banking
this year he will discuss the practical
aspects
and some successful hacks
that if i recall correctly took over
entire bank accounts
from users mobile apps with that vincent
over to you
yeah hello again thanks for the warm
welcome
and let's dive right into it because we
have a tough program
okay first of all online banking is
something that affects us all
because virtually everybody uses it um
in traditional online banking we use two
devices one
to initiate our payments and to log in
with username and password
and another device to confirm
transactions
with the rise of mobile devices
app-based confirmation procedures became
popular
like um like this app there
in in the recent past what i have been
talking about
last year um yeah it became popular
to implement those two devices in two
apps that means you only have
one single device and have two apps now
to authenticate transactions
yeah last year i showed that this has
severe conceptional drawbacks
but this is not the end of it
there the latest evolution in the um
in online banking are now one app
authentication models
i already said this last year actually
it doesn't make so much difference
so banks are no longer faking to have
real two
on two-factor authentication it's now
clear that it's just
one so you do the transaction
transaction initialization
inside the app and the confirmation is
just another dialogue inside the app
this time i want to talk about n26
yeah the shining star on the german
fintechs guy
and yeah actually
this time i only going to be talking
about
technical issues um and yet it's
clear that we have similar conceptual
problems like with two app
authentication
but i will focus on technical issues
because we have enough of this
there briefly about n26
um n26 is a berlin-based mobile first
fintech and it plans
yeah to establish your smartphone as
your financial hub for everything
yeah so that you can do little literally
everything
from inside the app actually it's only
founded
in 2013 it started in 2015 with their
app and it already has over 200 000
customers
which is astonishing actually
it now also has its own european banking
license
it's only i think half a year ago and
it announced not not even one month ago
that it's now available in 17 european
countries
and they also claim that you can open a
bank account in just 8 minutes
as it turns out you can lose it even
[Music]
faster
okay all right just like so let's talk
briefly about transaction security in
the number 26 app if you want to do a
transaction you at first need to log in
this works with your user username in
this case it's just your email address
and your password this is pretty
standard afterwards you're good
to initiate and transaction after you
entered all the details you also have to
supply a transfer code this is just a
four digit
number um you use this also to withdraw
cash
probably you would call this pin um the
last
last factor in this authentic
authentication scheme is your paired
phone this is actually the most
important
security feature um of the n26 account
and you can only pair one smartphone
with your n26 account
that means um from a technical
perspective
the n26 app the first time the very
first time you started
generates an rsa key pair and sets the
public key to the n26 back end and
whenever you initiate a transaction
they are going to send an encrypted
challenge to
your smartphone and that you send it
back decrypted
that's how it works actually repairing
that means pairing another phone is a
pretty well secured
um process but we will talk about this
later
just uh to talk about like the
infrastructure of n26
basically they have two apps one for ios
one for android
and they communicate over a json-based
protocol
tls encrypted the backend is at
api.tech26.de
how do i know actually that this is a
json-based protocol because i
used atls mitten attack and then in the
middle attack
to learn the protocol um i actually
suspect that i only needed to install a
certificate emitted proxy certificate on
the client
but actually i was surprised that they
didn't need to touch the client
because they didn't implement any
certificate pinning
so
[Applause]
so that means it's
that the first thing that comes into
mind is like let's do real-time
transaction manipulation that means we
manipulate a transaction that the user
does
um but we will change the recipient and
the user won't see nothing about this
so if you look at this graphic again
what if an attacker could get the dns
record of api.tech26de under his control
this would would mean that all traffic
is rooted over the man in the middle
attacker server and as there is no
certificate pinning we could just issue
a let's encrypt tls certificate
and the app is going to trust the
certificate
how does this work let's take an example
here
let's imagine i want to transfer two
euro to my friend dominic
after i entered all the transaction
details i have to enter my transfer code
too
when i did this i get like the second
factor where you need the
um the paired device and i need to
confirm it this is just like the next
dialogue inside
the app after i confirmed it that
transaction went through everything
looks good
and two euro less on my account pretty
good
in the next step you you can see in your
transaction overview 2 that there are
2 euro less but after the attack when
n26
realized that something wrong was going
on and they fixed it
you will realize that we actually
transferred 20 euros
not two but this was completely
transparent for the user even after the
attack
okay this is nice and we can we can
manipulate a transaction real time
but wouldn't it be even better
and more interesting to take over entire
accounts to do our own transactions
and for this we need the login
credentials the transfer code and the
paired phone
so we need to obtain all of them
let's start with the login credentials
actually i want to assume to him partly
or mostly that the login
credentials are already compromised but
there are some weak points in the
n26 transaction or in the security
system of them that
um yeah make it an easier task to obtain
those login credentials
there are two things i want to talk
about yes the first thing is the
recovery from loss procedure when you
forgot your password
n2x n26 just sends an email to your
email account
there's a link inside you click it and
you can just reset the password
and this yeah breaks the n26 password
policy
which is actually pretty solid because
if you have access to the email account
you can
have automatically access to the n26
account too and
the access to the email account could be
as bad as password or one two three four
five six
another idea is spear fishing think of
spear fishing like
a more targeted version of fishing what
you always need for phishing is a
similar
domain something the user can relate to
and
um if you want to make spear efficient
you want to have it more targeted that
means
you want to expose n26 customers to only
send out mails to them
and you need to have a valid reason to
contact them
for about the domain usually n26 uses
number 26.de
to and for password resets for example
i think number26.tag sounds pretty valid
in my eyes only by chance i happen to
own that domain
the next and next thing is exposing n26
customers
n26 offers peer-to-peer transactions
that means
if you have if your recipient also has
an n26
account those transactions are instant
to show the n26 customers
who of his contacts actually have an n26
account
they upload all of the email addresses
all of their and phone numbers
in your address book to the n26 backend
unhatched yeah
but how can we use but we actually want
to use this to identify
customers of a given data set we can
actually abuse this api for that
do you remember the recent dropbox leak
that
revealed 68 million accounts we
evaluated all of those 68 email accounts
against this api
and n26 took no notice of this there
were no
limits applied they just think i'm
really popular
listen
[Applause]
yeah in the end we revealed um 33 000
and 26 customers and could now send out
um
emails to them actually this also
provides a valid reason
to contact them for example um the usual
email of n26 looks somehow like this
yeah
so we could say to them hey you're
affected by the dropbox leak
um please change your password for your
own security
actually and then like here click this
link to change your password yeah
now i can already see the grow the n26
management board
um yeah nervous but don't worry we
didn't do this
my professor had legal concerns
[Music]
this okay now that
that we have the login credentials um i
we have to wonder can we actually
already do something with those login
credentials
and this brings me to siri transactions
with ios 10 n26 now supports
transactions using siri
that means now you can just say send
five years to dominic meyer using n26
then the transaction pops up and you can
say
send it and afterwards it's gone the app
doesn't even open
yeah so this already sounds wrong but
but you can only do this with the paired
device if you
if you use another phone and just log in
and try to use siri with this
and this dialog appears and you really
have to open
the app and you have to confirm it with
the paired phone
as it turns out this is just a client
feature
yeah so they uh so what they do
this is actually the entire payload you
need you just it's like five euros it's
totally meyer that's the phone number
and look at look at this api endpoint
transactions unverified
uh yeah okay so it turns out
you don't need the paired phone to do
this type of transactions
yet another thing that's interesting is
that n26 claims that they have some
intelligent algorithms to immediately
detect
irregularities and to prevent fraud
before it even occurs
so we thought challenge accepted
[Applause]
so and what we actually did and i think
this is pretty irregular
we sent 2 000 series transactions worth
one cent
within 30 minutes
so try to speak that fast
okay and so what happened like we waited
the next day
the day after nobody actually
made contact with us and we thought they
would never actually
make contact but over three weeks later
n26
required dominic to explain the unusual
amount of transactions
okay and they even threatened to cancel
his account i mean this is actually um
yeah
it's reasonable because it's yeah it's a
clear misuse of their account
and um violence the terms of service of
them but
dominic didn't send those transactions
he received them
so they contacted the wrong person
yeah this is kind of like if you if
gmail cancels your account because you
received spam
[Applause]
okay let's let's get back to the account
hijacking
and the next thing we need to obtain is
the transfer code and get to control
over the paired phone
what we will do with the transfer code
is we will try to reset it
and the paired phone we have to unpair
actually those
processes are not as independent as it
seems so
i will right start with the paired phone
as i told in the beginning unpairing is
actually a highly secured process and i
mean
this really this is my serious opinion
so let's look at the process at first
when you want to pair a new phone like i
said you need to unpair
the existing one therefore you open the
app then you click at unpair
and afterwards and they send a link to
your
email account then in the email you need
to follow
the unpairing email at the unpairing
link in the next step
the real unpre unpairing process starts
where you have to
enter your transfer code first then your
mastercard id this is something that's
kind of special for and 26 like every
n26 account comes
with a mastercard and they have printed
a 10 digit numerical token below your
name
and i don't know what this actually is
it's not the pen it's not the credit
card number but some
other sort of token so you need to have
um the mastercard actually
and in the last step they are going to
send an sms to you
with a token and you have to enter it
and only after this process the
unpairing is done
so that means we need to have access to
the email account
we need to know the transfer code we
need to have the mastercard
and we need to own the sim card in order
to reach the receive the
token you can screw up each of those
[Music]
okay let's go into it so the first thing
when you actually click on that on that
item in your app where it says
start unpairing it sends this is
basically http
get request but you wouldn't believe
that they sent the link as a response
yeah so that it's not displayed but
it it's there so you don't need to have
access to the email account because it's
in the response
yep okay next thing the transfer code
and i actually will skip this for the
moment and we'll get right back to this
but the next thing is actually the
master card id and
yeah this id is printed on the card and
we don't have access to the into that
card
so what will we do um
in the transaction overview n26 shows a
lot of properties for example like the
amount the beneficiary
whatever yeah so and it turns out that
this that they used
this mastercard id they thought oh this
is actually a nice id
let's use it as a prefix yeah so again
this is not displayed to the user inside
the app but it's clearly there in the
api it's way too verbose
[Applause]
so
okay so whenever um
the let the the step that i just skipped
was this transfer code
and the transfer code is unknown yeah so
but
you can reset the transfer code and it
is as it turns out
what you need to reset the transfer code
is the mastercard id
so you you need to enter those
this mastercard id that we just that i
just told how we will get it
and then we just will confirm our new
transfer
code think of one i don't know any code
and therefore we don't know and we don't
need to know the transfer code not even
the old one because it's not required
the mastercard id is sufficient
then um the last step sms
the sim card is inaccessible we don't
have access to that phone
um but this is a five digit token that
they send out
and it's only numbers i mean this is 100
000 possibilities yeah
and even full the login procedure
the login form has a brute force
protection
this doesn't have any brute force
so the maximum that i could get out of
the back end was 160
requests per second
so this means
so that means that it takes on average
um
yeah approximately five minutes to get
uh this token
yeah so in the end we will just brute
force it and that's it
okay let's
let's look if this really works yeah so
at first we will log into the app just
to see that it's paired
and if it wouldn't be paired we would
now
like see a dialogue that we should pair
our phone
so now so it opens great
and now we will start our
script and n26 claimed
that this attack doesn't scale just
don't
don't blink
so loud those are the logging
credentials now we do
do all the fun and actually everything
already happened it's just the brute
forcing that now takes place
and i have to admit that i have been
really lucky this time
because we are done now yeah
so um like there are this is the
response now the sms numeric token is
valid and the phone has been
successfully unpaired
so okay now let's verify in the app if
this worked
really yeah so let's open it again
okay touch id expired so this is
actually good that means that
and something happened let's log in with
our password
and there it prompts us for pairing the
phone so it worked
[Applause]
[Music]
this this uh even though i said that
this attacks
really scales very well it has a
drawback because
um three males are sent out to the user
the first one when you actually start
the unpairing the second one when you
reset the transfer pin and the third one
when the unpairing is successful
and the user also receives an sms but
it i i mean fraud is perfectly possible
but is there a possibility to avoid this
so let's try to call the customer
support yeah
the customer support is actually the
most powerful entity in the n26 security
model
because they can even change things you
can't change inside the app
for example your email address or name
you cannot change
yeah but they can so let's talk with
them
they can it turns out that they can also
unpair phones yeah
so now the question arises of course you
cannot just call there and say hey my
name is vincent please unpair my phone
of course they going to authenticate you
and what
[Music]
and what what will they ask they will
ask for the mastercard id
that we know that the current account
balance is always available if you have
the login credentials
okay there's one thing that's still
missing place of birth
it's always the same
[Music]
it's it's again you can't see this
information inside the app
yet it's just a displayed it but it's
there there's so much information you
can't think of
really they know more about me than i do
okay so now that means we have all
information available and we can change
any data and the user won't receive any
notice of that yeah so no email nothing
so we can just unpair the phone and
later we can
pair our own one or like this is
perfectly stealth
now actually i heard already ah
i only got 50 euros on my account why
should i care
this is actually a valid argument
because yeah many
n26 accounts are opened out of curiosity
and many are inactive or not
using it seriously that means you only
use it for traveling or
paying things online because of the
conditions but you don't use it as a
salary account so there's
frequently not so much money um in it
but as this wants to be the financial
hub for all
services you of course can also you
apply for an overdraft yeah and this is
an instant overdraft that is granted
during
two minutes and it's between
if you have guaranteed 50 euro and up to
and this requires the paired device what
did we just do
uh we have the pad device we have the
entire account
so what do we do we will just um hijack
the account
then we apply for an overdraft and and
then we will take
all the money he has as a balance and as
an overdraft
so even if you don't have money on your
account and think you're safe
you are not
okay this was was quite a bit something
i want to talk briefly about the
exclosure before
i will draw my conclusion
um i reported all these issues to n26 on
september 25
i didn't establish the contact this was
the ccc
thank you for that and i did this
because i didn't know how n26 would
react to
this kind of vulnerabilities but
actually there was no reason to think so
because
they acted really professional and yeah
they were actually
thankful that i revealed these
vulnerabilities
yeah then afterwards um they started to
incrementally fix the issues i don't
know when they
fixed the first thing i didn't monitor
the process
but the last fix i know of happened on
december 13 when they implemented
certificate pinning
on ios and apparently i have to say that
i didn't check
everything but apparently all issues are
resolved
but what what are the consequences out
of this
it is obvious that n26 needs to put more
emphasize on security
it's important to notice that this
wasn't
a coincidence it simply wasn't
and n26 needs to understand that it's
not enough to release videos with
caption mobile first meet safety first
and to claim that securities of
paramount importance of him of them
so pr shouldn't do your security
and it's funny if you if you visit the
n26 homepage
you will find out that they currently
have 44
open positions not even one is dedicated
to security
furthermore with such a strategy fintech
squandered the trust in financial
institutions that banks established
um yeah over years actually today you
usually trust
in your bank that they will deal with
your money responsibly
and in the end you also need to question
authorities i mean
it was baffin that that granted a
banking license to n26 only six months
ago
and really those vulnerabilities are
inside
for longer time
okay i think like
a resume for this is they you shouldn't
say works for me when it's about
security yeah so
so thank you
thank you vin thank you vincent that was
awesome and also kind of scary
i we only have a short time for
questions
is there anybody who has a question for
vincent
you know i guess everybody is out
deleting banking apps
oh number six
so quick question is microphone on okay
um do you know whether they have
disallowed those apps that have not yet
been updated
to still manage their bank account so
for example if someone has a mobile
app that has not yet been updated to the
version that includes certificate
pinning
would that person still be vulnerable to
men in the middle attacks
yes
so they actually they they don't have so
much of an idea
which device you are using they don't
even know which is the pad device this
is only a client value
do two more i think i'll hear number one
yeah hi thanks for the talk did they
actually invite you to
help them or give your talk at number 26
have they been in contact with you yeah
we have been in contact and i
also visited them and gave a workshop so
yeah we
did they
[Music]
you're serious i'm serious yes
and we'll do one last one here from
number five please so
during your talk you name dropped let's
encrypt and you kind of glossed over
that bit
about getting them to issue a
certificate for their api host name
do you know something i don't
[Music]
uh like the question i get i don't so
you you mentioned
getting a let's encrypt certificate to
impersonate their api hosting because
they weren't using certificate
pinning how about how did you go about
doing that but i didn't do this like was
a
scenario this yeah
that's an attack scenario okay i didn't
i didn't hijack the dns record oh
okay sorry
thank you all right thanks everybody for
joining
we get a big round of applause here for
[Applause]
[Music]
vincent
you