[Music]
we have here Eileen Callahan who will
tell you a story of discrimination and
unfairness she has a PhD in computer
science and is a fellow at the Princeton
University's Center for information
technologies and she has done some
interesting research and work on the
question that well as a feminist tackles
my work all the time because we talk a
lot about discrimination and biases in
language and now she will tell you how
this bias and discrimination is already
working in tech and in code as well
because language is in there so give her
a warm applause please
should I wait two minutes
you can start say it's okay I should
start okay should start it great I will
have extra two minutes hi everyone
thanks for coming it's good to be here
again at this time of the year it's my I
always look forward to this and today
I'll be talking about a story of
discrimination and unfairness and it's
about prejudice in word embeddings and
she introduced me but I'm Eileen I'm a
postdoctoral researcher at Princeton
University and the work I'll be talking
about is currently under submission at
the journal and I think that this topic
might be very important for many of us
because maybe in parts of our lives most
of us have experienced discrimination or
some unfairness because of our gender or
racial background or sexual orientation
or not being neurotypical or health
issues and so on so we will look at
these societal issues from the
perspective of machine learning and
natural language processing and I would
like to start with thanking everyone at
CCC and especially the organizers angels
the cows mentors which I didn't know
that existed but if it's your first time
or if you need to be oriented better
they can help you
the assemblies artists and they have
been here for apparently more than one
week so they're putting together this
amazing work for all of us and I would
like to thank CCC as well because this
is my fourth time presenting here and in
the past I presented work about Yanam
Eisen programmers and Salama tree but
today I'll be talking about a different
topic which is not exactly related to
anonymity but it's more about
transparency in algorithms and I would
like to also take my quarters on this
work before I start and now let's give a
brief let's give a brief introduction to
our problem so in the past in the last
couple of years in this new area there
has been some approaches to algorithmic
transparency to understand algorithms
better and they have been looking at
this mostly at the class
suffocation level to see if the
classifier is making unfair decisions
about certain groups but in our case we
won't be looking at bias in the
algorithm we would be looking at the
bias that is deeply embedded in the
model that's not machine learning bias
but it's societal bias that reflects
effects about humans culture and also
the stereotypes and prejudices that we
have and we can see the applications of
these machine learning models for
example in machine translation or
sentiment analysis and these are used
for for example to understand market
trends by looking at company reviews or
it can be used for customer satisfaction
by understanding movie reviews and most
importantly these algorithms are also
used in web search and search engine
optimization which might end up causing
filter bubbles for all of us billions of
people every day use web search and
since such language models are also part
of web search when your web search core
is being filled or you are getting
certain pages these models are in effect
and I would like to first say that there
will be some examples with offensive
content but this does not reflect our
opinions just to make it clear and I'll
start for the video to give a brief
motivation capturing police brutality on
their smartphones to police departments
using surveillance drones technology is
changing our relationship to the law one
of the newest policing tools is called
pred poll it's a software program that
uses big data to predict where crime is
most likely to happen down to the exact
block dozens of Police Department's
around the country are already using
pred poll and officers say it helps
reduce crime by up to 30 percent
predictive policing is definitely going
to be a law enforcement tool of the
future but is
risk of relying too heavily on an
algorithm so this makes us wonder if
predictive policing is used to arrest
people and if this depends on algorithms
how dangerous can this get in the future
since this is becoming more commonly
used and the problem here basically is
machine learning models are a trained on
human data and we know that they would
reflect human culture and semantics but
unfortunately human culture happens to
include bias and Prejudice and as a
result this ends up causing unfairness
and discrimination and the specific
model we will be looking at in this talk
our language models and in particular
word embeddings what are word embeddings
so word embeddings our language models
that represent the semantic space and
basically in these models we have a
dictionary of all words in a language
and each word is represented with a
three hundred dimensional numerical
vector once we have this numerical
vector we can answer many questions text
can be generated context context can be
understood and so on for example if you
look at the image on the lower right
corner we see the projection of these
words in the word embedding projected to
2d and these words are only based on
gender differences for example king
queen man woman and so on so when we
have these models we can get meaning of
words we can also understand steen tax
which is the structure grammatical part
of words and we can also ask questions
about similarities of different words
for example we can say woman is - man
then girl will be to vote and it would
be able to say boy and these semantic
spaces don't just understand syntax or
meaning but they can also understand
many analogies for example if Paris is -
France then if you ask Romans - what it
it would be Italy and if bananas -
bananas which is the plural form then
not would be too nuts why is this
problematic word embeddings in order to
generate these word embeddings we need
to feed in a lot of text and this can be
unstructured text billions of sentences
are usually used and this unstructured
text is collected from all over the
internet a crawl of Internet and if you
look at this example let's say that we
are collecting some tweets to feed into
our model and here is from Donald Trump
sadly because President Obama has done
such a poor job as president you won't
see another black president for
generations and then if Hillary Clinton
can't satisfy her husband what makes her
think she can satisfy America Arianna
half is unattractive both inside and out
I fully understand why her former
husband left her for a man he made a
good decision and then I would like to
extend my best wishes tall even the
haters and losers on the special date
September 11th and all of this text that
doesn't look okay to many of us goes
into this neural network so that it can
generate the word embeddings and our
semantic space and in this talk we will
particularly look at work to act which
is Google's word embedding algorithm and
it's very widely used in many of their
applications and we will also look at
glow it uses a regression model and it's
from Stanford researchers and you can
download these online they are available
as open source both the models and the
code to train the word embeddings and
these models as I mentioned briefly
before are used and text generation
automated speech generation for example
when a spammer is calling you and like
someone automatically stalking that's
probably generated with language models
similar to this and then machine
translation or sentiment analysis as I
mentioned in in the previous slide named
ant recognition and web search when
you're trying to enter new query or the
pages that you are getting
and it's even being provided as a
natural language processing service in
many places now Google recently launched
their cloud natural language API and
this we saw that this can be problematic
because the input was problematic so as
a result the output can be very
problematic this there was this example
Microsoft had this tweet but Hotei and
it was taken down the day it was lounged
because unfortunately it turned into an
AI which was Hitler loving sex robot
within 24 hours and what did it start
saying people fed it with noisy
information or they wanted to trick the
bot and as a result - but very quickly
learned for example I'm such a bad
naughty robot and then do you support
genocide I do indeed it answers and then
I hate a certain group of people I wish
we could put them all in the
concentration camp and be done with the
lot another one Hitler was right I hate
the Jews in certain group of people I
hate them they are stupid and they can't
do Texas they are dumb and they're also
pour another one bushed at 9/11 and
Hitler would have done a better job than
the monkey we had now Donald Trump is
the only hope you've got
actually that became reality now
gamergate is good and women are inferior
and hates feminists and they should all
die and burn in hell this is problematic
at various levels for society first of
all seeing such information is unfair
it's not ok it's not ethical but other
than that when people are exposed to
this criminal discriminate or
information they are negatively affected
by it especially if a certain group is a
group that has seen prejudice in the
past and in this example let's say that
we have black and white Americas and
there is a stereotype that black
Americans perform worse than white
Americans in their
intellectual or academic test in this
case in their college entrance exams if
black people are reminded that there is
the stereotype that they perform worse
than white people they actually end up
performing worse but if they are not
reminded of this they perform better
than white Americans and it's similar
for the gender stereotypes for example
there is the stereotype that women
cannot do met and if woman before a test
I reminded that there is the stereotype
they end up performing worse than men
and if they are not primed reminded that
there is the stereotype in general they
perform better than men what can we do
about this how can we mitigate this
first of all societal psychologists that
had ground breaking tests and studies
for societal psychologists suggest that
we have to be aware that there is bias
in life and we are constantly being
reminded primed of these biases and we
have to devise by showing positive
examples and we shouldn't only show
positive examples but we should take
proactive steps not at the cultural not
only at the cultural level but also at
the structural level to change these
things how can we do this for machines
so first of all in order to be aware of
bias we need algorithmic transparency
and in order to do bias and really
understand what kind of biases we have
in the algorithms we need to be able to
quantify bias in these models how can we
measure bias though because we are not
talking about simple machine learning
algorithms bias we are talking about the
societal bias that is coming as the
output which is deeply embedded so in
1998 societal psychologists came up with
the implicit association test and
basically this test can reveal biases
that we might not be even aware of in
our life
and these are things like associating
certain societal groups with certain
types of stereotypes and the way you
take this test is it's very simple it
takes a few minutes and you just click
the left or right button and in the left
button when you're clicking the left
button for example you need to associate
white people terms with bad terms and
then for the right button you associate
like people terms with unpleasant bad
terms and that you do the opposite you
associate bet with black and whites with
good then
they look at the latency and by the
latency paradigm they can see how fast
you associate certain concepts together
so they associate what white people with
being good or bad so basically you can
also take this test online it has been
taken by millions of people worldwide
and there's also the German version
towards the end of my slides I will show
you my German examples from German
models basically what we did is we took
the implicit association test and
adapted it to machines since it's
looking at things words associations
between words representing certain
groups of people and words representing
certain stereotypes we can just apply
this in the semantic models by looking
at cosine similarities instead of the
latency paradigm in humans and we came
up with the word embedding Association
test to calculate the implicit
association between categories and
evaluative words and for this our
results is represented with effect size
so when I'm talking about effect size of
bias it will be the amount of bias we
are able to uncover from the model and
the minimum can be negative two and the
maximum can be two and zero means that
it's neutral there is no bias and two is
like a lot of huge bias and negative two
would be the opposite of bias or bias in
the opposite direction of what we're
looking at and I won't go into the
details of the math because you can
see the paper on my webpage and work
with the details or the code that we
have but then we also calculate
statistical significance to see if the
results we are seen in the null
hypothesis is significant or is it just
a random effect size that we are
receiving and by this we create a null
distribution and find the percentile of
the effect sizes exact values that we
are getting and we also have the word
embedding factual Association test this
is to recover facts about the world from
word embeddings it's not exactly about
bias but it's about associating words
with certain concepts and again you can
check the details in our paper for this
and I'll start with the first example
which is about recovering the facts
about or about the world and here what
we did was we went to the 1990 census
data the webpage and then we are able to
calculate the number of people the
number of name names with a certain
percentage of women and men so basically
their endogenous names and then we took
50 names and some of them had 0% women
and some names were almost 100% woman
and after that we applied our method to
it and then we were able to see how much
a name is associated with being a woman
and this had 84 percent correlation with
the ground truth of the 1990 census data
and this is what the names look like for
example Chris on the upper left side is
almost 100% male and Carmen in the lower
right side is almost a hundred percent
woman and we see that gene is about 50%
men and 50% woman and then we wanted to
see if we can recover statistics about
occupations and woman and we went to the
Bureau of Labor Statistics web page
which publishes every year the
percentage of women or certain races in
certain occupations and by
Dundas we took the top 50 occupation
names and then we wanted to see how much
they are associated with being woman and
in this case we got 90 percent
correlation with the 2015 data we were
able to tell for example when we look at
the upper left we see program where
there it's almost zero percent woman and
when we look at nurse which is on the
lower right side it's almost a hundred
percent woman and this is again
problematic we are able to recover
statistics about the world but these
statistics are used in many applications
and this is the machine translation
example that we have for example I will
start translating with a from an
genderless language to a gender language
Turkish is a genderless language there
are no gender pronouns everything is in
it there is no he or she so I'm trying
to translate here or beer avocado he or
she is a lawyer and it's translated as
he's a lawyer when I do this for nurse
it's translated as she is a nurse and we
see that man keep getting translated to
wit or associated with more prestigious
or higher ranking jobs and another
example he or she is a professor he is a
professor he or she is a teacher she is
a teacher and this also reflects the
previous correlation I was showing about
statistics in occupations and we go
further German is more gendered than
English again we try with doctor it's
translated as he and the nurse is
translated as she then I try with a
Slavic language which is even more
gendered than German and we see that
doctor is again a male and then the
nurse is again a female and after this
we wanted to see what kind of biases can
be recovered
other than the factual statistics from
the models and we wanted to start with
universally accepted stereotypes
by universally accepted stereotypes what
I mean is these are so common that they
are not considered as prejudiced they
are just considered as normal or neutral
and these are tanks such as flowers
being considered pleasant and insects
being considered unpleasant or musical
instruments being considered pleasant
and weapons being considered unpleasant
and in this case for example with
flowers being Pleasant when we performed
the word embedding Association test on
the word track model or Glo model with a
very high significance and very high
effect size we can see that this
association exists and here we see that
the effect sizes for example 1.35 for
flowers and according to Cohen's D to
calculate effect size if effect size is
above zero point eight let's consider
the large effect size in our case where
the maximum is two we are getting very
large and significant effects in
recovering these biases in them for
musical instruments again we see a very
significant result with a high effect
size and in the next example we will
look at race and gender stereotypes but
in the meanwhile I would like to mention
that for these baseline experiments we
used the work that has been used in
societal psychology studies before so
that we have grounds to come up with
categories and sets of words and we were
able to replicate all the implicit
association test that were out there we
tried this for white people and black
people and then white people were being
associated with being pleasant with a
very high effect size and again
significantly and then males are
associated with courier and females are
associated with family males are
associated with science and females are
associated with arts and we also wanted
to see stigma for older people or people
with disease
we saw that young people are considered
Pleasant whereas older people are
considered unpleasant and we wanted to
see the difference between physical
disease versus mental disease and if
there's bias towards that we can think
about how dangerous this would be for
example for doctors and their patients
and for physical disease it's considered
controllable whereas mental disease is
considered uncontrollable we also wanted
to see if there is any sexual stigma or
transphobia in these models and then
when we perform the implicit association
test to see how the view for
heterosexual versus homosexual people we
were able to see that heterosexual
people are considered Pleasant and then
for transphobia we saw that straight
people are considered Pleasant
whereas transgendered people were
considered unpleasant significantly with
a high effect size and I took another
German model which was generated by a
hundred and twenty billion sentences for
an natural language processing
competition and I wanted to see if they
have similar biases embedded in these
models so I looked at the basic ones
that had German sets of words that were
readily available and again for male and
female we clearly see that males are
associated with career and they're also
associated with science and the German
implicit association test also had a few
different tests for example about
nationalism and so on and there was the
one about stereotypes against Turkish
people that live in Germany and when I
performed this test I was very surprised
to find that yes with a high effect size
Turkish people are considered unpleasant
by looking at this German model and
German people are considered pleasant
and as I said these are on the webpage
of the IAT you can also go and perform
these tests to see what your results
would be when I perform these I'm amazed
by how horrible results
I'm getting so just give it a try
and I have a few discussion points
before I end my talk this might bring
you some new ideas for example what kind
of machine learning expertise is
required for algorithmic transparency
and how can we mitigate bias while
preserving utility for example some
people suggest that you can find the
dimension of bias in the numerical
vector and just remove it and then use
the model like that but then would you
be able to preserve utility or still
recover statistical facts about the
world and the other thing is how long
does bias persist in models for example
there was this IET about eastern and
western Germany and I was unable to see
the stereotype for eastern Germany after
performing this iit is it because this
stereotype is maybe too old now and it's
not reflected in the language anymore so
it's a good question to know how long
bias last and how long it will take us
to get rid of it and also since we know
there is stereotype effect when we have
bias models does that mean that it's
going to cause a snowball effect because
people would be exposed to bias then the
models would be trained with more bias
and people will be affected more from
this bias so that can lead to a snowball
and what kind of policy do we need to
stop discrimination for example we solve
the predictive predictive policing
example which is very scary and we know
that machine learning services are being
used by billions of people every day for
example Google Amazon and Microsoft I
would like to thank you and I'm open to
your interesting questions now if you
want to read the full paper it's on my
web page and we have our research code
on github the code for this paper is not
on github yet I'm waiting to hear back
from the journal and after that we will
just publish it and you can always check
our blog for new findings and for the
shorter version of the paper
with a summary of it thank you very much
Thank You Eileen so we come to the
questions and answers we have six
microphones that we can use now it's
this one this one number five over there
six four two and I will start here and
we will go around until you come okay we
have five minutes so number one please I
might very naively ask what or why does
it matter that there is a bias between
genders first of all being able to
uncover this is a contribution because
we can see what kind of biases maybe we
have in society then the other thing is
maybe we can hypothesize that the way we
learn language is introducing bias to
people maybe it's all intermingled and
the other thing is at least for me I
don't want to live in a biased society
and especially for gender that was the
question you asked it's leading to
unfairness and
yes number three yeah thank you for the
talk very nice I think it's very
dangerous because it's victory of
mediocracy is just the statistical mean
will be the guideline of our goals and
society and all this stuff so what about
all these different cultures like even
in in normal society is you have
different cultures like here the culture
of the chaos people is different has a
different language and different biases
and other cultures how can we preserve
these subcultures these small groups of
language
I don't know entities any idea this is a
very good question and it's similar to
like different cultures can have
different ethical perspectives or
different types of bias and in the
beginning I showed a slide that we need
to do bias with positive examples and we
need to change things at the structural
level and I think people at cccc might
be like one of the like most one of one
of the groups that have the best skills
to help change these things at the
structural level especially for machines
so I think we need to be aware of this
and always have a human in the look that
cares for this instead of expecting
machines to automatically do the
correcting so we always need an ethical
human whatever the purpose of the
algorithm is try to preserve it for
whatever group they are trying to
achieve something with number four
number four please hi thank you
this was really interesting super
awesome the early early earlier in your
talk you described a process of
converting words into a sort of
numerical representation of semantic
meaning
[Music]
yes if I were if I were trying to do
that like with a pen and paper with a
body of language what would I be looking
for in relation to those words to try
and create those vectors because I don't
really like understand that part of that
yes yeah that's a good question I didn't
go into the details of the algorithm of
the neural network or the regression
model so there are a few algorithms and
in this case they basically look at
context windows and the words that are
around the window this can be skip grams
or continuous bag of words or there are
different approaches but basically it's
the window that this word appears in and
what is it most frequently associated
with and after that once you feed this
information to the algorithm it outputs
the numerical vectors thank you now
number two thank you for a nice
intellectual talk my mother tongue is
genderless too so I do not understand
half that biasing thing around here in
Europe what I wanted to ask is when we
have the coefficient 0.5 and that's the
ideal thing what do you think so T
should there be a institution in every
society trying to change the meaning of
the words so that they statistically
approach to 0.5 thank you thank you very
much this is a very very good question
and I'm currently working on these
questions many philosopher or feminist
philosophers suggest that languages are
dominated by males and they were just
produced that way so that women are not
able to express themselves as well as
men but other theories also say that for
example women were the ones who drove
the evolution of language so it's not
very clear what is going on here but
when we look at languages and different
models when
I'm trying to see their association with
gender I'm seeing that the most frequent
for example two hundred thousand words
in a language are associated very
closely associated with males I'm not
sure what exactly the way to solve this
is I think it would require decades and
it's basically the change of frequency
or the change of statistics in language
because even when children are learning
language at first they see tanks they
form the semantics and after that they
see the frequency of that word match it
with the semantics for form clusters
linked them together to form sentences
or grammar so even children look at the
frequency to form this in their brains
it's close to the neural network
algorithm that we have so if the
frequency they see for men and women are
biased I don't think this can change
very easily so we need cultural and
structural changes and we don't have the
answers to these yet and these are very
good research questions thank you I'm
afraid we have no more time left for
more answers but maybe you can ask your
question soon yes thank you very much I
will take questions offline
[Applause]
[Music]