[Music]
Jesse himself is a hardcore mower
searcher reverse engineer and he also
likes to break code and my voice is
breaking to him sorry for that
so stage is open to Jesse let's visit
the Durban
thank you very much so yes I'm always
social walking at eastside montreal and
during the past two years we have been
monitoring ago called cygnets with my
two colleagues drawn tomorrow it can be
here it can be with me here today sadly
and this talk is based on a technical
white paper publicly available on our
blog if you want to read it so as I said
this week all these groups in it but
depending on the researchers they have
other names like a p28 offensive LC and
this is a group of radical doing
targeted attack since at least 2004 and
their interest is mainly about Joe
politics as you might have seen in the
news they are very famous at the moment
they are supposedly behind the hack of
the democratic national committee and
also the world anti-doping agency and in
this presentation I will start by giving
you some context around this group after
that i will describe a textbook case of
their current operations during which
will dig into their tool set and i
thought i will present the different and
strange operation also run by the Senate
go up during the last few years and
finally I will conclude with some
lessons around and open questions so
let's start with some context around the
Senate hope so what kind of people
people are they after
and for once we know very precisely some
of the targets because they made a
mistake during one of the fishing
campaigns the operators use the bitly
service to shut down there are you
fishing your arms but forward to say to
be profiled privates so we had access to
around 4,000 shot on your arms during 6
months in two thousand Justin here's an
example of failure all that was chaton
in cut it contains the email address of
the target and also his real name
so at this point identifying the target
was pretty in this list their our
embassies in ministries of more than 40
countries there is NATO and EU
institutions and finally there is a lot
of individuals involved in Eastern
Europe politics to inspect those targets
they pulled out your days here you can
see a timeline with us and enjoy this
exploit for 2016 only and all these
vulnerabilities I've been reported since
and i'm not even talking here about the
revamped exploit they use there is many
of them also and we are going to see
that later
the story doesn't end in 2016
just as an example the google but
analysis go disclosed vulnerabilities in
flash and in the windows channel like a
month ago I think and the exploits was
using the pleasurable to gain control on
the remote computer and the window we
know when 32k vulnerability to escalate
privileges and bypass the Sun box i want
to describe the expert here and there a
reason of information internets but this
shows this envelope is quite resourceful
also this is the kind of group that
deployed many custom softwares of over
the past ten yells from the pass-through
encryption proxy tools including
different types of backdoors ensure they
give up quite a lot and before going
father i want to mention a few
disclaimers first even if retract
descended go pretty closely during the
last wheels we might be missing part of
the pictures and as my results shells we
call it a group based on the torque it
even they might be divided in step teams
and finally we are not competent to do
any sort of attribution but our research
might provide you instead maybe use for
that so let's start our journey in the
Senate toolkit with self
that is actually a good name for
fictional Senate target he works for the
government and has access to sensitive
information the chain of events and the
timing that i am going to describe are
in line with several rape cases with
investigating the last videos and we
just say such as a textbook case to
present part of the Senate toolkit
somewhere recently it's monday 930am and
searched rob arrives at work and he
opens an email this email supposedly
came from that for which provides
regular reports enjoy politics except
that if you look closely at the URL will
notice that the diamond mix the
regiment's father mean but also the UI
is the same as not to call on the
legitimate for website
except that an idea was in certain
inserted in the middle party to identify
the target but let's say sound clicks on
the URL and this is when cells mid-set
kit which is the Senate exploited and it
is only used for targeted attacks as we
just saw its entry point is usually your
home's mimicking legitimate websites and
the exploit infection usually start from
target phishing emails but we've also
seen I from your direction from separate
from hacked websites we found that in
September 2014 for the first time and it
is 2 News
so as a classic exploit kit when you
visited you receive your landing page
that will build a recognizance report in
the mansion the set landing page
contains around 200 lines of JavaScript
and the code stayed the same about the
last year you can see here you defied
expect of this landing page first will
retrieve the time zone and then it will
enumerate the properties of JavaScript
object called Navitar in screens and
finally it will emulate the plugin
installed in the browser as you can see
there is a special case for internet
explorer we're java and flush are
detected by special methods by the way
the comments here are from the
developers to give you an idea here is
report from cells computer its existing
file and you can see it contains a lot
of information such that the server can
select it's the targets were precisely
not only based on the configuration but
also based on the language they speak in
the time zones are there are in however
we don't know precisely what their
operators are looking for we crawled
expected with various configuration and
different IP addresses sometimes it
works sometimes it doesn't works and so
far we don't really know why but let's
say that cell is selected to be
exploited and this is one sells visit
the Senate exploit factory so here's the
list of exploit that we saw from set
since its beginning and as you can see
from the malls or they exploit at the
time they were used also interestingly
there was an exploit for my keeper which
is a cleaning tool for is then made by
the company from Ukraine and it is
probably mainly used by people from
Eastern Europe and the other exploits
our event exploits and i am going to
describe one of them right now so it's
exploit target the city 2014 632 and
it's been abilities in together floor in
the entire to explore vbscript engine
that allows arbitrary write operations
we sorta delivering the expert for this
city in october two thousand interesting
and in this case it was only using your
pc to disable the safe mode and to
download or build with partial but at
the beginning of the year we found a
very different version of this exploit a
more complex one that was used in
February 2016 this exploit didn't
disable the safe mode but directly
executed a rope chain the code is pretty
big around four hundred lines of
JavaScript and interestingly it's custom
don't try to read everything but here's
the beautiful coat of the function
building the rope chain and just to give
you an example we can see here function
to return the cut section arrest of a
dll on windows 7 as you can see that's a
lot of default turns out that part of
this code is actually based or inspired
by a present
Shin made at blackhat USA 2014 and once
again the single are not afraid of
digging into complete exploit two
mixtures of them in real life examples
back to search days now let's say that
exploit downloads the pillow and this is
this is one salesman selling powder to
set up lies usually downloaded by set it
like in such case and this component
actually includes two binary a dropper
and it's embedded payload it is
generally the first component by the
victim and related the operation of
selling product in March 2015 so let's
start with the doorbell now you can see
here is very simple workflow but it
contains some interesting vigils the
first one is aware and general district
so held the snippet extract from x-rays
so fast it will allocate the allocate at
my before and it said the last night to
the value 42 and then it will create a
file with a very specific name it will
then write 1 million time in this file
and then rid 1,000,000 time in the same
file after that it will check if the
last bite of the ten bite before still
contains the body 42 if it doesn't sell
the predominate its execution so this
code scanner strange but we believe this
is naming intimidation trade because
they replaced it with a more common one
in the most recent simple and also it
might create intensive harddrive
operation that may delay the execution
of the software also it may take
emulators wrong really implementing the
memory management so the next step is to
create the payload into the compressive
this operation are implemented in c++
class named uploaded by the developers
you can see it here on the screen after
that the power may use a local privilege
escalation exploit depending on the
simple one of these two cities may be
used the first one was your day at the
time they used it and the second one is
another gift from the hacking techniques
and finally the rubbermaid the Bill of
persistent in the system
interestingly with so many different
techniques use the father past month
some of them only used when the doorbell
rings with system privileges you can see
here just show them right the windows
comp object hijacking and the JavaScript
code executed with the run deal 42 those
techniques were first seen in other my
wells and seeking inspiration prime Y is
something very common for the citigroup
at this moment the villages running in
such computer and the ability is
actually a brokenness and smile while
and you can see here a simplified what
program establishing the network
connection with the census I would be
the first step
it changed the role times in the last
few months but the first it will try to
reach google.com and if it works it
moves on
however if it doesn't work it will
Richard the particular tools for
instance for firefox the books for the
profile and it will pass it if it
succeeds it will contact the senses
about job the proxy using those
principles and then if all the previous
technique didn't work it will wait for
the user to launch a browser in order to
inject into it
the next step is to send the first stage
reporting this to the census other this
report begins with an idea generated to
identify the computer and also it will
send the process list some information
on disk build number which is located in
the binary and then its end this
encrypted for the networking that was
previously established it is rather
small report but it is probably in order
to fill their own security researchers
and automated sandboxes the final step
is retrieving a configuration fire from
the census over here are different
values handled by the last version of
setup other people i will not go through
them they're quite explicit but the main
purpose is to download another binary
and to execute it as an executable or
jello now let's go back to alternate
events
we're still day one and sells computer
is infected with setup program same day
30 minutes later the parts are are not
sure that's
was not tomorrow Scioscia said Rico is
downloaded on such comfort up by set of
prada so this is a classic back door
with numerous common and interestingly
has the ability to extend its behavior
by loading external plugins it is
usually deployed after successful
infection like in such case and while
this component may be old we know for a
fact that it is still in use today so
Rico arrived on a stem and drop our
which usually installed the payload and
its configuration it will drop the
configuration at two places on the disk
the first place will be in the filename
msg and it will also copy the exact same
data in the windows registry and of
course since the configuration is
installed by the payload issue only have
the payload you won't be able to
determine the configuration used with
its now let's talk about the
configuration can see here the encrypted
version it come with a small header and
the data is dissolved with a
six-by-eight key located at the
beginning of the header and it is
randomly generated by the dropper along
the key you have 20 bytes each bite
representing the size of a field in the
data everything else is the encrypted
data now we have the content once
decrypted and here is the better
representation of the extracted fields
so those values are just values time
outside all I don't find them really
interesting here is self computer name
here you have a flag to space where
there on that the killer should be
enabled
here are the three since he sells the
first one is the main one that will
others are fallbacks here is what
ability to be an operation name we have
fun server founder all them during the
investigation some of them are shown on
the screen and as I mentioned before
Sirico has the ability to load external
plugins when loading one plug-in it will
store the path of this plug-in at the
end of the configuration the there is
room for ten plugins and in the initial
perfect configuration of those fields
are empty because
the villages dropped without any plugins
that out now let's have a look at this
people it comes with 26 comments and
it's coming as identified by a unique
number was coming to register register
during the run time using an export
function name registered you command and
you can see here the registration of the
few commands like for example Sirico can
read write anything on the disk can also
lists are running processes it can
manipulate the registry also it can
update itself its configuration or load
or unload external plugin
speaking of plugins they come as jello
and they will be loaded in the same
address space than the payload and
thanks to that they can use any function
of the main pale so as shown in the
picture here is what happens when the
pillows initialize a plug in it cause
the plane in its export I think some
function addresses as argument in
particular it provides the addresses of
the function handing the output
formatting and also the common
registration so the plane can register
any additional communicated and here's
an example of a plug-in used in parallel
with Cedric oh this murder was just
registering a new command this time
opening in HTTP channel those chances
our and also while silicosis terminating
it will unload every plug-in by calling
the Ennead export in this case the
expert on Angeles the previously
registered comment
let's go back to alternative and now
we're still day one and silica was
deployed 30 minutes after the initial
infection same day for house later
judgments ex-agent which was denoted by
satellite Sirico ex-agent is my backdoor
written in c++ as for which there is at
least a windows linux and iOS and
Android version exigent is the flagship
bag of the Senate go
they used in most of their operation
over the studios and usually after the
Wrekin instance phase light in such case
related decisions abortion around about
November 2012 and it is to lose so this
point at this point you might expect
some surplus reverse-engineering on
extension banner is right except that
just a mistake from the operators we
recently got access to the source code
of ethics agent and here's the next part
of this expect of the source files we
found it is a fully working c++ project
corresponding to the linux version of
this agent and it was combining july
2015 which we know because there is a
bin folder with a binary in it which was
created at this date and the source code
contains around 18k lines of code among
christening dresses so it is pretty big
we believe this lead source code derives
from the windows version fixation
because I several places they the lapels
just counted out some win32 api calls to
replace them to replace them by linux
API calls like in this case but with
determination and they're also volvo
ocean of exigent the source code is
major version 2 and the challenges
binaries are Russian three but it still
matches the illogic of the victory
binaries as you would expect in such a
big project the source code is heavily
committed the crime and sour mix of a
badly written english with some Russian
sometimes some ask you out to describe
the structures but with that being said
let's look at the communication workflow
so here we got a simplified view of the
communication will throw an exception to
give you an idea at the center on the
exigent infected computer the color run
method is an infinite loop which fetches
the messages from the module not just
that the kennel is its itself a job
those messages are encrypted c++ objects
which are see realized and encrypted by
the canal and then given to the channel
controller the channel controller is the
NFI interface to contact the census
silver and it forwards the messages to
this in silver
in the other direction the channel
control particularly asks the census of
foreign encrypted messages message for
each module and the message is then
given to the channel which and say lies
and decrypts it and then gives it to the
internet module one of the beauty behind
this simple design is that the channel
controller is unaware of the current
actual implementation of the network
channel which can be based on HTTP or
emails and in fact the channel will push
a controllable switch automatically to a
different channel if the currently used
one is not working and now let's dig a
little bit into the email channel
how is it working so the work with the
workforce quite simple
when the channel control i just
described has a message for the census
our emotional sends an email with the
message as an attachment to an inbox
depending on the simple the inbox can be
a free email address the Senate address
or hacked email address and the senses
about then retrieve the email from the
inbox and processes the attachment in
the other direction if this is our has a
message for one occasion module it sends
a message as an attachment in an email
to a different inbox from which exchange
on my channel Richards the email so it
sends the right but the thing is when
you use emails to implement a command
control channel fast you need to have a
way to distinguish your email from and
related emails like spam all legitimate
emails in the inbox and second you need
to bypass punctured girls on your way to
the inbox and for those reasons the
Senate developers implemented with a
call to scheme which they describe I as
a little too protocol this protocol
defines how acceptance emails are built
and here's an example of an email
following the protocol so protocol
defines the subject of the email as the
best 64 encoding of a value following
this format which stuffed with
random key then value God called
obstruction result with the key and
finally the agent agent ID shot with the
same key
the second is known by both the senses
are on the estate agent and that's how
they can distinguish their emails from
and related emails they got the subject
and check if the second is here in
practice in many extension samples
substitution is a 7 x values that
potentially contains the stream China
the protocol also defines the body of
the emails and the attachment name
remember that the attachment contain the
actual message so those are simply the
basic functioning of some random values
so that's the protocol but actually in
all in xcode the developers replaced the
protocol with some hard-coded values we
call it the judge and particle because
those values values are 1 in the
Georgian language they for example the
email subject is set to appear in Mary
which refers to a national ID numbers in
Georgia and nobody said to get
manageable which means hello and the
attachment name begins with that you're
right
which mean detail in John followed by a
times time for this wipe this was
probably done in order to not attract
attention in the georgian and structures
or maybe in a hack George and inbox and
to complete an excision now and has a
penis i just want to see if there was an
exception since infrastructure's because
once again we got access to some source
code and the source code this time was
left in an open directory understand
it's our and it was indexed by Google
such that we found it by some queries
for the protocol previously described
the source code is actually a process of
our for back and since our and you can
see from the source files here that it
is developed in brighton and was used
between aprons room 2015 which we know
because there are some like file with
that with
x times in it it contains around 12 k
lines of code because this is actually
more than a simple really
what it does is it will translate the
email protocol from excision infected
computers into request of our HP for the
call for the back and since other HTTP
request for a specific format called the
t3 protocol level 3 protocol and by the
way we believe they use the same kind of
setup for the HB channel rather than the
email channel even if this particular
process is just for the mail channel so
enough with excision now let's come back
to the charity event we are still they
want after the initial infection silica
was deployed exception was deployed and
at this point said it got to spying back
doors on the target at the same time
such that if one of them is detected
they don't lose access to the computer
and the next days are going to be the
time for information exploration and
lateral movements during the next three
three days and it is going to drop and
sells computers some password extractive
tools they often use a set of tools
called security exploited that are
freely available on the internet and the
store can extract password from a
variety of software and such like
browser or email clients
the problem is there are of their
well-known and they are often detected
by antivirus so senator up their own
password destructive tools in particular
there is one for Windows Live mount that
is dropped on such popular it has been
compiled specifically for him as it
searches the for the passport in a
hard-coded paths that only exists on
such computer of course the birthright
to reach with the windows password and
such computer for that they got some
custom tools to them windows passwords
from registry hives and without
surprised they just mutates maybe gets a
lot and the output is often stored in a
file named by that log all this all
these tools maybe the probably LP
exploits depending on the target
configuration cells may also meet this
controller which is a small custom tool
they made
screenshots when it is executed it
explicit instructions in rapid
succession when the most moves and it
does that 15 times in a row and finally
cells with external which is a crystal
network prostitute to contact capitals
that not normal average of four from
internet using the infected computer as
a pot this component appeared inmate
with us on the Dalton and it is still in
use so how does support exactly here the
initial situation the senate since our
is on internet such computer is in its
organization at work and is infected
with external computer laboratory are in
the same network but they are not
reachable from internet and they are not
another Senate control but the original
from such computer external begins and
encryption a handshake with the census
hour and the purpose of this contract is
to share also 42 anchored the
communications between the two of them
to saw external understand Cesare both
have a copy of a big table filled with
random looking bites
let's call this table to an external
randomly picks enough set all in the
table 2 and the 32 byte road starting at
this offset all is the key that extra
wants to share with it since the server
but external does not send the key of
course it sends the offset all plus a
proof that XML really know that TT this
book is another growth to located at the
fixed upset this time and encrypted with
the presently the census several checks
the proof and if it's correct that is if
it gives the expected value once the
Krypton and sells ok and said it's also
fourth key to the little bite row
starting at the upset or so at this
point all that data exchange between the
senses are an external will be also for
aggravated with the chosen key notice
that ending the upset of the key prevent
the description of the traffic by his
rap on sources 2014 is this encrypted
link is encapsulated into
less which is not a bad idea except that
external doesn't verify the certificate
of the census over and now the next step
once the encrypted link has been
established the sense of can authorize
not to open it now with the target
computer using an IP address or domain
name and participant number external
then open the specific connection with
the target computer here computer a and
start filling data between computers and
the census however in both direction
that is that the link between external
and consider it is not encrypted so that
any kind of specific data can be
forwarded to the target computer we
don't know exactly what kind of traffic
they are the parents are usually sent
through the external but it has been
reported to be used with PS exactly
tools that all of the execution of
common on a remote computer without
having an agent running on this computer
finaly externals identified by an ID
search that excellent management several
of them and so for example another to
know can be open with the computer and
it's not we'll take care of the wording
of the traffic in the correct not to
summarize the Senate census of volcano
rich computer a computer be a
participial using cells computer as
accurate and if we fixin on let's go
back to watch an accident
we just had three days of information
exploration and lateral movement the
rest action from the operator during
this first week will be to set up an
additional passed since method on such
computer for long-term monitoring so
friday around 11am the long-term
persistence method consists in a special
exception binary compound in Microsoft
Office folder under the name
msi the jailer this copy operation is
done by another binary locked on the
mission
you can see it here and to write in the
office fall down this is where it needs
to have a mystery rights and followed it
felt executive the local privilege
escalation exploit and then it could be
the oxygen binary name beside the gel in
the office folder
to understand what will happen next
first we need to know that there is a
legitimate windows dealer named msi
jello stored in the system32 folder just
this yellow is usually used by office
application in particular and also need
to know that the decision binary exports
the exact same function names then this
legitimate dealer so this at this point
you've certainly just what happened next
each time self-taught office extension
msi the general is loaded and that the
legitimate msi the dealer because it is
in the local for the office and this
this phone before the system32 file
extension then lost the real emicida
jello from the system32 folder and it
feels its own exportable with the
addresses of the function of the digital
media are such that it's called to
extension export will actually go to the
legitimate jello and the application one
crash
finally it's not it's malicious logic
another one it's so simple such other
hydrogen based on the fact that they can
write into the office order and by the
way we have also seen recently is social
the hydrating technique with our Lincoln
for the dr dot into the windows folder
so that concludes the story of cells
this textbook case of what happened to
the city targets during the first day of
infection and now we have a pretty good
idea of what the significance them look
like this happen
get the world case we found last year
someday inside the mall 2016 will
receive the unusual sample it was a dog
park with the latest reviews by Senate
and it was showing this document as a
decoy
as you can see it is a legitimate
invitation for Joe politics conference
and this document is actually publicly
available intern it suddenly the bloated
just the lowdown and even was it is
written in doubtful and since we are
good at naming things we need down the
WorkFirst simple though it don't know
the configuration file and based on this
configuration it will download and
execute another pillow the best method
was just the registry so nothing really
exciting so far except that we found
another done of deployment in two
thousand thoughts in this time and this
graph describes the deployment of the
time you can see we had gone down and
bettered the same copper and this time
with a small help our and the book it in
style
so even if this with you don't infect
MBR based system this instead I will in
fact multiple version of windows running
on the x86 processor so here are the
first set over just after the successful
infection the first sector will is the
new malicious MBR the second sector is
the origin MBR code resort with a
one-bite key and starting at the third
sector we have the core of the rigid
code also also exalt at last we have a
also for encrypted driver and the
install so high together in the registry
but I will come to that later
so let's describe a very simplified
version of this workflow fast the
measures MBR is executed in a very
classic wait we'll hook the
interrogatories Thornton which handles
on low-level it and write operations and
by doing the work it is able to
intercept every bite read from the disk
during the loading
thanks to that which such as the memory
for some specific bytes in order to
match them those bites belong to put MGR
which is the next step into the book
chain as explained before so this point
with enjoy is past and then the day's
control again this and this time it will
match the function or sell are
transferred to Colonel located in with
low THC which is the next type in the
kitchen like the night like the name
suggests this function will call the
camera entry point so one is now patched
and with today's control the execution
before the camera is executed at this
point the candle and all its basic
drivers are mapped into the virtual
memory and the integrated checks are
already performed so what this but it
does now it is it will look at the
function and map is space and it will
set the Russell section of the acpi
drive out to executable before hiding
some coding it it will also hold the
acpi drivers entry point to execute this
code the wicket need to save all those
important the rest somewhere because the
wicked physical address won't be
accessible after the kind of
initialization so it will save
everything in the counter head out you
can see hit it here we have the
briquette base arrest the address of the
function and map is space and also the
original bites of the acpi entry point
and how the device patched and when the
driver is loaded the hook will be
executed so fast the code hidden in the
results section will write back the
original entry point instructions to
avoid being detected by the kennel much
protection and this is where the widget
will map it's a physical address into
the virtual address space by calling the
function mm a pyro space and after that
it will be able to decrypt the hidden
driver so there's three components
involved at this moment the with the
driver will decrypt Affeldt dealer named
the usermod' component by the developer
tools and it will manually map it into
explore that exit then this user mode
component will decorate and lowdown
itself hidden in the register
as well but this was kind of odd because
the driver could have loaded down there
directly and looking at the usermod'
components we have fun evidences that
under frozen the internet pero used with
this book at first
more precisely when interacting dumbbell
it set this specific exported vibe too
true but the viable doesn't exist in any
known samples of dundalk so therefore
sporting the original pale we believe
that the budget or at least the driver
is connected to the black energy model
well because we have fun some several
several sharing features between the two
families user-mode component is manually
mapped into the Explorers memory and all
this code is shared between themselves
and Somali samples of like energy and to
do so there's three exports used in the
driver love you so much component
respectively entry fee data and then
those exports are also present in black
energy and used in the exact same way so
this might indicate that the lapels have
access to black energy source code all
however we are not aware of any brick
coming with black energy toolkit
anyway enough with it
let's go back to down there looking at
some other samples of downtown we have
found another department in 2014 and
this time don't have came with a cannon
much bullshit
so the rooted purpose is to ensure that
persistence understand by injecting it
into explore that sexy and also to hide
everything related to dump valve to the
user into this system so you can see
anything on the disk
thanks for the dropout they just left
all kinds of debug information in the
samples so here's the exact debugging
output during the driver loading we can
see the father and the registry to hide
the drive out the road and the dll to
inject we have two violent of this
wicket the first version the root it was
targeting windows XP computers and was
doing some simple SSD Hawking and the
other option is a minute filter driver
it was targeting more
seduction of windows and it is based on
an open-source example made by microsoft
also we have found 60 for example in the
wild but we are missing the dropout so
we don't really know how it managed to
bypass the driver signing policy and
interestingly it looks like some drivers
are made for specific configuration like
in this like this one probably targeting
a computer running kaspersky internet
security so to summarize we only found a
few samples of Dunder use during the
past three years which is not a lot
they were very careful with it maybe
they only used it for some specific
targets the senses about those samples
were reporting on was active during to
Yale's it went sour and other rather for
quite a long time and they just do it
get working on XP and more with some
version of windows they made a multiple
root for the same operating system
versions in short they worked very hard
on the bestest methods which is unusual
in such cases and finally we know that
was used to download the RICO external
an ex-agent mentioned only also this is
definitely connected to send it so it is
now time to conclude with some
speculative membranes because after
looking at so many Senate binary the
temptation is big draw some general
conclusions and i am not talking about
the software then not talking about a
traditional more about the software in
particular there is a question we were
often arguing between us as we try to
show in this presentation the diversity
of the Senate software is quite
impressive you should think about it
there is a doctor on water come between
those but get emotional c++ back door
and there's an expert infrastructure
with lot of JavaScript and system
exploits and the list goes on
so this diversity is good for them as it
makes tracking and detection harder but
the question is how did they come up
with this best of an ecosystem
they develop themselves or do they also
development and we have a few hints
regarding that question first
the Senate binaries are often compiled
specifically for a target and after it
has been infected the basic example that
is this occasion sample containing the
login and password of employees in the
ministry of internal affairs of Georgia
and they were used in the mail channel
this sample was made specifically to be
run inside this ministry network and
marginally Senate malware in constant
evolution in particular external the
plotter and excision changed a lot since
that first version you know the world
the repairs are part of a team that
outside of paid for one-time job also
among the variety of the Senate software
there are some share techniques like
building a also for key as the
concatenation of a hard coded value and
a random value are using hard-coded
tokens network messages these are two
just are just two examples of techniques
present in source and its software
developed in different languages so this
is not a couple pasted code but more
like a implementation of the same idea
so this may indicate that the same
developers are behind all these soft
wells another remark on the development
process is that there are some basic
programming mistakes in the sense
software for example here in linux
ex-agent a thread and all named handle
get packet is terminated with Petra exit
but it should be handled send packet as
you can see from the condition before
and the commented windows code so
probably run copy paste in the linux
version also there is a here in external
there is a report message was built for
the census ever wanted to know how to
open with the target computer the IP
address and the port number of the
target are written in a 6 bite but for
except that the memory pointer is not
implemented between the two rights and
thus the port of all right the pot
overwrite the IP address
and we can ask them the sense that does
not even check the report so mistake as
gone unnoticed and these are just two
quick example of mistakes you can find
in the Senate code so that the robot not
have a creative process and overall
Senate code often feels really harsh
following this idea this is it wasn't
sometimes inspired by classic crime
crime well for example setup will reduce
persistence methods from kind well and
shells some code with carbon wild on
dell which is called bears some
similarities with like some earliest
sample of black energy we may be tempted
to conclude that the developer are
connected in some way with some classic
crime our communities and finally the
experts to develop values funny names
like photo and love for HTML tags are
missing that you know with is which is a
soccer player for the battery to
download from exploits so if they are
able to use those named in production we
can get that they are not working a very
formal environment to see the list so to
summarize the speculation we believe
that Senate has some in-house killed the
lapels working with little supervision
and those guys have ties with primarily
underground which is not so common for
this kind of hope and if you don't
really I would be glad to discuss about
that speculation I'm it's time to
compute Senate activity increase the lot
during the last three years they are
doing targeted attacks on the lot of
different targets now and after kid is
in constant evolution so there is
definitely definitely more fun to come
for Marcel Charles so thank you very
much for your attention now
alright there's a lot of time for talks
we don't have unfortunately microphone
state can pass around in the audience
please go to the micro found microphone
stands over there or here
ok let's start with the internets do we
have questions from the internet
one question is this Russian state
malware I want to answer this question I
can discuss about that we don't do any
sort of a tradition because this is very
difficult to do another question from
the internet
no more serious questions from the
internet just now please when you exit
please be quiet respect that there's
some people in here who just wanna know
a little bit more
there's one question over there to the
right guy for question in the inside the
mall where period that you found a lot
of allegedly us more aware or as a
mother was found
do you see any development in codes that
is based upon the idea that they get
from these more where analysis that have
been made in those periods i would say
yes I didn't talk about it in this
presentation but expect for example
external was intoxicated before at some
points and then they started to
obfuscate some more recent samples so i
would say yes
okay thanks more questions yeah there is
one question over there it will have
like maybe obvious question may be
speculative do you think this group has
some nice to like Russian government or
Russian secret services there's
something I already told you I want as I
won't answer this question because like
where they can use Russian language but
that doesn't mean anything right
sorry I didn't understand the we didn't
get it okay so sorry sorry I need I need
to repeat the question was your question
was was there any reaction of your
research on their site that right okay
like I said before a when we started to
analyze external all with which since
some application techniques are
implemented in the intercept wells also
the resources quite strong its republic
with published it like a few months ago
so i would wait until 2i wait all to see
they are actively switching things up
and but they are definitely reading the
papers over so i think so
just one question that back over there
have you found any parents and the
targets they attacked sorry i didn't
have you found any patterns in the
targets they attacked at the reactor to
some of the one when the targets
probably be that was the first question
the second is have they reacted to to
any of the reactions of the target with
you mean well have they had did they
have follow-up hacks on mon different
targets because they found some some
information on the first ones
well like yeah because the second stage
back dolls are usually dropped before
the recognitions face if the target
isn't interesting you want to see them
on the computer so this is what you
wanted to do know now I mean they have
targeted to add that some attacks on one
specific targets you told us and so
you've probably talked to the target
I don't know why not because while some
targets us against it's like ms is so
that's not a very specific people so we
can try to reach them but they don't
obviously and so up us every time
sometimes people try to reach us and
they are doing like you
the mind madam Eliza but I never hear
about anything from the targets like
when I give that in the report all there
is one question over there back I one
more i'm doing the work you're doing are
you concerned about your personal safety
I mean I started this work like one year
ago so we'll see
more questions
internet so one more from the internet
what do you think the crime strike
report to people are asking which one
they made multiple reports the one about
the Democratic National Committee PAC I
have no further information right now is
they made quite a few we still got
enough time for questions so
oh yeah here we go i want i did you find
any little bit with our abilities when
when you investigated the code i think
my colleagues did formed some like also
when the google but no system release
the stories about flash and the window
which case i found the samples right
after that they want the one that public
but some other some other companies do
something about that so sometimes you
can find r0 days it's rare but you can
find them and follow-up did you find
anyone or abilities in the in the
communication to the command and control
server always something else we don't
look about about like stuff like this
I mean they made some mistakes in their
client side of the subscales but they
don't know about the census others and
everything
more questions yeah one from the
internet
are there any patterns to the fun names
that are used
I don't think so that's an interesting
question anything more from the internet
could you could be used to move the
microphone place or it will be great
thanks
do you believe that the US agencies that
have done some sort of attribution that
they have more information than you than
me more information than me
well more than you presented today yeah
probably later said at the beginning we
all might be missing part of the picture
on this is why some other companies
operation very good reports so
definition
but there's question over there against
a microphone
this might be a dumb question but you
said the targets don't usually contact
you
so how do you know about the targets
well we have no imagery system this very
different accounts like identified
targets like I know we have hits we have
BIOS we have samples we are analyzing
them and we have one finds some
similarities we one is told me about
targets I was thinking about the bitly
list we found this is why we didn't
compact any emails and like i said if
you think you are targeted you can come
to me and i will look into the this list
if there is like some tea old is that
may interest you
you're welcome more questions
internet yeah please have there been any
mass deployment of this type of malware
or is it only very individual tax
yeah it's very targeted there is not
like a widespread infections on anything
anything more internet we serve a clue
certification on the previous question
was specifically interested in the
report that attributes Russia to the DNC
and then there's another related
question asking are there differences
between quite strikes reports and yours
I don't believe while talking about the
same things because when we when we see
something published by like the exploits
about the recent exploits we are not
like adding this to the to our people
since it's already on the internet so
well
all white paper is the technical
breakdown and of their toolkit like
excision external and
I don't think they talked about this one
didn't work questions internets audience
we still got time
alright internet your internet go have a
internet is asking if the the targets
are any better protected night if they
are a bit but like more protected while
we are detecting the simple so if they
are running small security maybe but the
the goal of the white paper is to
provide is also for those that means all
people that are managing
infrastructure's so if you are looking
for that you can download the white
paper on the blog there is a pretty
pretty extensive list if you want to
protect your infrastructure also
incident response of course because we
are doing that
okay i don't see questions in here still
internet something there
no it's getting quiet
well then there's one more question over
there
I don't it seem that a lot of the text
of focused on Windows machines
yeah is that make or like I said they
have a second stage backdoor for is then
iOS android linux and like the source
code of exigent is an expression and we
also have seen several samples for less
than I think if i recall correctly so
they have like a big-ass known welcome
okay yeah we have a question over there
if there are no further questions
this is my first visit to CC does anyone
have a good tip for a good bar in guys
[Applause]
think social life we're going we can
discuss a little bit later so once again
met super cool
[Applause]
[Music]