[Music]
hello thanks for the nice introduction
so a lot was already said after this
semester so three years ago many of us
were shocked to learn it
we're not the paranoid conspiracy
theorists but that many of the things we
expected was actually true
our entire digital world is under total
civilians famous person Edward Snowden
said that he quote sitting at his desk
could wiretap anyone and it's like not
just like about the serious things it's
about really anyone and everyone it's
about games and porns it's about the
wailing people who ya playing angry
birds it's about the wedding people
watching porn to have an opportunity to
discredit them afterwards and yes
everyone even includes Chancellor's of
countries and we will show you a short
video now with terrorists reaction you
have to do we needed for screen of the
full typically yep maybe solving these
people speaking people here don't know
it yet because it i think it wasn't
translated into English so much so you
can read the subtitles and you now here
for off their permanent position to tell
us beyond in Dodge stunt is snapped in a
garden the NSA this politician deeds to
control zone and instead from tish let's
keep in Dodge land can
million for her going to asheville its
own prison
yep and then just a few months later
things came out and our Chancellor
Merkel said something slightly different
community about fish and bring this kind
of what fallen off the ball time inside
the only one of my our spin the point
that gun is in community of slavery and
rumors can love but one of the all-time
against i holding up my our spin the
friend Johnny let's get garnished that's
a no-go
that's a no-go but we all know like the
narrative of Germany and the u.s. being
very close partners and it's not about
being close partners only in a
diplomatic way it's also about being a
close partner in the spy agency way and
every Snowden said fairly at the
beginning of the revelations that NSA
and I was German Foreign Secret Service
bnd would be in bed together now to the
political elections what came like after
all those nodes revelations were like
yeah was written about in Germany as
narrow as already mentioned there was
this inquiry committee established and
it's the only inquiry committee that
yeah involved after the Snowden
revelations so there's kind of something
special about it in Germany
yeah so the German Federal bunda stark
the Federal Parliament is investigating
this buying accusations of the five eyes
and the involvement of the German spy
agencies so how much mass surveillance
is actually being done and when this
inquiry reformed the PG&E and this is a
quote from an internal document if
they're simply the pnd had great concern
that such an inquiry committee would
focus on the activities of the BND
SIGINT division of looking what the hell
BND is actually doing and not only the
NSA to GCHQ and the five eyes so that's
what we try to do is journalist and
that's what the committee was also
trying to focus on like the work of the
committee is kind of complicated because
like the primary source of information
for them are documents that the public
shouldn't see and it's like a lot of a
lot of documents by now it's almost
2,400 folders of documents of paper
which might some up to millions of pages
and those millions of pages are not
easily readable from time to time
because there's a lot of black on the
pages so
this also the people trying to kind of
vague get to know what the be indeed us
together with the NSA and the other five
eyes
yeah they can't see it because it's too
secret for them to see it so one aspect
of the work that the inquiry is doing is
stare asking government ministers and
chancelleries and the B&E gives your
documents so we can read what you've
been doing and in addition to reading
the documents which we are not a part of
their public hearings of witnesses and
experts in the bonus knock rooms where
we go to get to watch those hearings
officially streams are forbidden
recordings are illegal you could get
kicked out of parliament and never be
let in again but they say maybe you've
seen the theater representation last
night at the very beginning because the
public can come into the building the
yeah the hearing somehow public even
there's no even even if there is no
recording or transcription so what we do
is we go there we live transcribed by
ourselves we go to the hearings and we
transcribe everything all the apartment
Arians the government and witnesses are
saying and that's some cumbersome word
we have printed out the internet of what
we've done and we have about three
folders of what we wrote in the last one
if you're standing right here right now
and after the talk if you're interested
in a printout of the internet just come
by and we can give us a copy of your
favorite witness hearing but it's not
just about like your writing
what's happening there it's like you
can't go there and if you didn't see the
situation that's really difficult to get
an impression on which people are
sitting there like what other people
working at those by agencies and
surveilling the world and happy to sway
the word and therefore like still at it
starts to draw those people who testify
in front of the committee and because
drawing you have drawing like the
witnesses like two or three times
doesn't make so much sense
she began to form the witnesses out of
modeling clay and you can see those
witnesses in the exhibition next to the
boardroom I think for the next day's so
are those witnesses in the inquiry
hearing a bonus track well witness
number one it's called Edward Trey
Snowden because the it doesn't take a
lot of brainpower to discover that he is
an important person that could reveal
information that is relevant to the
committee's cost of investigating what
their secret services are actually doing
but as you probably heard there's a huge
fried political fide he hasn't been
equal inquiry hearing yet and there are
only four more hearings in
january-february and unfortunately as of
now it is pretty much
yeah there's a very low chance if even
that he will actually be heard by the
committee and that makes like people not
believe in the seriousness anymore and
clear all to like write about many of
the documents told the Germans
politicians as they invited him that
they care for more about not upsetting
the US and not destroying like their
partnership then they do about
conducting a serious investigation so in
solidarity with had Glen also didn't
come so what do we actually learned from
all those documents the press releases
the statements and the witness hearings
well first of all be any rienda German
spy disease we are in bed together with
the five ice with the other spy agencies
from the US UK New Zealand Australia and
Canada they are doing similar things
they're doing massive veins in the
digital world and also in terms of my
agencies like the others are extremely
bending or sometimes plainly outright
breaking the law
we have a few of those funny theories
they make up and for example there's
satellite reception and to select
interceptions eres like yeah basically a
limit set by the law and the B&E didn't
like this so they thought about how
could we circumvent this limit and they
invented the space theory so they said
like all the satellites they aren't in
Germany they are in space and if we
intercept the satellites and it's not a
germany so we don't have to comply to
the law and
you i think the first thing on this is
said they made up the Serie after
Snowden so they did this for a really
long time and then as they have noticed
like it's really getting your
uncomfortable in here they started about
like how could he explain this so the
theory is in Bavaria and by boiling
where the station with the red elvises
we're surveying satellite communication
somehow German law does not apply
because they're gathering information
from satellites in space but it gets
even weirder because they're extending
that to the so called virtual foreign
countries this is one of the many
buildings that the frankfurt internet
exchange takes his house did and the BND
is saying yeah well we're surveying
fiber-optic cables on German soil from
the German isp but it's a virtual
foreign country because technically
we're trying to get international data
transfers from those streams fiber-optic
lights again so German law doesn't apply
there and it gets even funnier you can
translate it to the functionary theory
and it says that if you are in a
function of your German and you are in
the front country and working for maybe
you and your right emails then you don't
have any protection of the fundamental
rise like here's privacy because you are
in a function and you are not a German
and fundamental rights don't apply to
you
so what other face it we learn from the
inquiry committee besides weird legal
theories that don't really stand up to a
little test
well we learned about a few operations
that the German spy agencies were doing
in the past the first operation that has
been most widely reported and talked
about a so-called operation icon which
ran from 2003-2008 there was a joined
operation of the German be in deep and
the NSA and was happening in frankfurt
germany and they were tapping and
internet exchange of the German telecom
and the weirdest part is they always
said yeah we always surveying foreigners
we're only surviving terrorists
so you might say okay Frank for an
exchange that's maybe not so foreign
but then on this internet exchange
there's many cat cables from carriers
coming together to her for doing peering
for making the internet work and we
found out the disability was tapping
cables running from Vienna to answer
them and cables running from Luxembourg
to break now they always keep telling us
it's only about the terrorists in
Afghanistan or Somalia but I think
that's not really terrorists and there
are other operations there's one
operation you are not even allowed to
say the name of its like bowtie and it
says that last three letters like a IC r
if you reverse them at CIA and so its
cooperation between the BND and the CIA
and they used like a journalist writer
mci worldcom which is now known as
horizon horizon and there they tapped
let's leave phone and fax your
communications so another operation that
we learned about in the inquiry
committee although we always expect did
was when closed landfill came to the
inquiry committee and told yet
well after operation economic
and tapping the internet exchange in
Frankfort from deutsche telekom being he
came again and said ok now we want to
tap basics to make frankford internet
exchange because was in the inquiry
committee he said well being the game
and basically they demanded a full take
they wanted everything
of all the things that could possibly
have all the traffic that could possibly
be routed by Disick's now after some
legal back and forth it was clamped down
a little bit because of legal by because
of the restrictions back then but still
power surveillance the there's german
foreign spy agency did inside of Germany
was of six German nice piece so instead
of going to the German internet operator
and saying well we want to check your
cables they went to districts to the
internet exchanges that we want all
traffic that comes to you from this
German provider and there is the other
operation which is called monkey
shoulder and their says inspection that
it's called after whiskey and it's a
operation between the GCHQ the NSA and
they wanted to go to the torture telecom
and get the transit communication and
transfer the raw data to the foreign
secret services and one special thing
about this operation is that allegedly
the Chancellery was not informed so even
those who should watch like the sailors
didn't know about it or at least they
say they didn't know about it and this
operation started in 2012 and it was
stopped after the Snowden revelations
came out because they said like okay
it's getting a bit too hot in here so
and then it gets murky the inquiry
committee was able to investigate the
ancient operations I canal and gloat
hike without being able to say the name
glow tight they always have to say hello
but from the other operations we somehow
know that there's another operation
called warp drive which would be indeed
us together which with the NSA and
another partner but we don't know which
one we don't know where it went
we don't know what provider was targeted
and when we don't even know if it's
already ended we just know the name and
we would be interested in more
information on that and there's a lot of
other interception operations and we see
like a table here but one thing about
this table is that it's only operations
that ended and they're not running
because we don't get to know anything
about operations that are still taking
place today it's just about like things
in the past so we don't really know
what's going on right now and it's also
that in the inquiry committee they can
only talk about operations of the five
eyes that means like the Canadians of
people from New Zealand Australia
Britain and the u.s. but we don't know
anything about operations of other
countries and yeah they might be many
many more
so what's a black card was here we were
little revealed this list of the
operations that the German spy gb and he
is doing but the blackout's even members
of the enquiry committee are not allowed
to find out what the hell that actually
is that the Secret Service are doing
their supposed to look into this ancient
& by now i'm bored of operation icon and
low tide and more interesting stuff of
what is going on now at in this very
moment that's not for them to
investigate this is one of the favorite
slides of one of the members in the
inquiry committee i don't know if you
remember remember that it's about an
operation called rampart aid and
and it looks as if the NSA is using
local partners in other countries to do
tapping for him and then gather all the
data so we had the running fury
I think it's almost confirmed now I said
operation icon was such a thing where
the beanie went to internet exchange in
Germany did a little filtering out of
Germans surveying the fiber-optic cables
and then giving that data pretty much in
raw shape to the NSA now whether to be
and he knows that is giving the data to
the NSA or not that is an open question
the inquiry committee has not yet found
out but this slide shows that the NSA
definitely has operations where the
local partner does not know that the NSA
is getting way more than they said
publicly another thing is excuse
gorgeous color is a tool and it has kind
of the nickname and it's a schoolgirl
because it's like to search through a
massive amount of data and it's used by
the German secret services it's used in
but I playing by the be indecent 2009
and had a producer that round since 2007
and it's also deployed and other I was
post but we have like your kind of a
murky testimonials about this and
they're running at least in test mode
and this kind of thing of test mode is
also running in our domestic Secret
Service and there was like the contract
published that how they got this thing
from the NSA and they got it for free so
they didn't pay anything for it at least
not money so there was kind of the deal
we give you all the equipment and you
give us the data that you get out of
there so when during the Snowden
revelations when the name xkeyscore came
up everyone was pretty freaked out
because there was one of the first and
one of the big revelations and our
German government's 000 those Americans
they're doing really fancy stuff there
but
would never do that but the enquiry
funding committee find out that for
years and years to be indeed has been
using the exact same tool in the exact
same way another tool that even goes
beyond what the NSA is doing is a tool
called veras that's at all that the B&E
developed together with determine armed
forces the Bundeswehr and it gathers
metadata communication metadata of who
communicates when with whom I classic
data retention stuff and special thing
about this tool viruses that it captures
all the metadata of all traffic on a
communication line like a fiber optic
cable so it's not being selected at all
only a little time for a part of
obviously German communications are
thrown away but we learned that the NSA
is apparently retaining 4345 hops of
metadata communication will look to be
India's gathering all hops and one of
the first hearings being evenness said
oh yeah we're retaining like six tops of
metadata we're like six hops there is an
experiment it's called a small world
experiment it's also known in
english-speaking world as the so called
six degrees of separation that every
human understand it knows every other
human / 6 hops of the people in between
so when the beanie is actually
collecting what they say recently oh
yeah the system wouldn't stop you if you
were to look into 9 10 12 hops like a
slower but it gets the system gets
Lauria so this was one of the things
that was pretty interesting for us that
the BND is not limiting metadata
at all so now this being a hacker con we
wouldn't have gotten our talk accepted
if we didn't drop some formerly
non-public information so we have some
ok for here now used to be classified
secret we have like amount of metadata
collected and retention periods of
metadata for the different outposts of
the BND so we have shooting in here and
it's two million metadata a day and
retention time of 10 years like 10 years
but I boiling one of the most famous
outposts of the B&E in Germany is
collecting five million metadata every
single day and is retaining that for
three months right housing another
outpost is collecting 15 million points
of metadata every single day and is
retaining it for six months
gobbling in we already know a lot about
that but that's an outpost collect a
hundred 118 million points of metadata
every single day and is retaining them
for an entire year and pull out being is
central Europeans HQ as of now is
collecting an additional 20 million
points of metadata every single day and
research training them for 10 years and
this is unique because as opposed to the
other outposts before this is collecting
the data that is coming from tapping
points of fiber-optic cables light on
the front for internet exchange and if
you do the math and you sum up all this
you
yeah come to the number of 220 million
metadata per day and then you might ask
yourself like what has been doing with
this meta data doesn't be in the keep
this metadata no it doesn't you should
do but never get better
then there's a number and that's the
metadata per month pushed directly to
the NSA it's like 1.3 billion metadata
monthly so it's not as sitting on a B&E
server in the NSA can query it deep
being together since theta and pushes it
onto a server directly to the NSA
hardware so metadata is taking by every
single communication on communication
line that the German spy agencies topic
but apparently content of communications
like the contents of emails or phone
calls are only selected which means like
you proud a big fishing net with some of
those communication types identifier
like browser ideas and most difficult
ones are IP addresses email addresses of
like that phone numbers but there they
get way more detail can be credit card
numbers they can be cookie identifier
there's many types of selectors and if a
communication is hit by selector then
it's stored away somewhere for further
processing
how many selectors do we have the BB has
14 million selectors that comes directly
from the NSA NSA is giving the PNG 14
million selectors that the beanies
running and assistance in its systems
and trawling the communication lines it
taps for enough these 40,000 were found
to be against so-called German or EU
interests after the BND looked into what
the hell is are these things that the
NSA is giving us who are the targets of
the communication that the NSA wants us
to surveil for them and they started to
investigate like what is against those
German and you interest after Snowden so
and under strange circumstances because
they like started investigating this in
different outposts kind of independently
and they didn't know about each other
allegedly and that's weird because they
knew about like critical selectors way
before is already in 2005
a B&E found out that it had selectors
about European companies vs and
eurocopter and that the NSA wanted the
pnd to spy on those companies now
they're not the most likable companies
exporting arms and military gear to the
entire world but they are party German
companies and Europe and European
companies so the BND is legally not
really able to spy on them but they did
40 and say but the committee members are
not allowed to see those selectors like
they should investigate what the B&E was
doing wrong and taught could make better
but they are not allowed to really look
into what they used to spy for the NSA
against German and you interest so there
was a special commissioner there was a
special commissioner was called like a
person of trust but he was not a person
of trust for the committee was a person
of trust elected by the Chancellery like
those who are kind of responsible for
all the wrongdoings also be Andy and he
wrote kind of report where he said like
yeah they had this isn't there was only
like a public version which that nothing
concrete no concrete selectors we got to
know and he adapted like the BND
theories and white parts of this report
so only because of the inquiry committee
we look to be itself found out that it
has 40,000 selectors of the NSA against
Germany European interest so the
committee said ok now that you
discovered this because of us we want to
see them right but the Chancellor
Chancellor your office said no the
inquiry committee but also other control
committees
pretty much no one except the translated
bendy itself and special person were
allowed to see them so the opposition in
parliament and the so-called g10
Commission suing the federal government
to be allowed to have a look at those
40,000 selectors that are known to be
against German and European interests
but unfortunately both of those court
cases were struck down one on yet
former reasons one of formal reasons and
one because they didn't really have
standing
unfortunately so no one is able we're
going to be able to see them until
someone leave something but there's not
only NSA selectors that have been using
the Viennese also using selectors on his
own interests and sometimes they even
take like the NSA selectors see that
they are kind of interesting and just
put them into their own list of
selectors it's three sounds 300 and you
could suspect that it's being the user
selectors they are in the German
interest but even those the BND is
losing himself our against German and
you interest and it's these sweets
thousand three hundred that are against
those interest there are many more but
we can only see those who have been
deactivated after those like
investigations what's wrong
so what does it mean this is also a
theoretical but we do have a few example
of those selectors the beanie is
actively spying on the French ministers
of Foreign Affairs and the bee india
spying on EU institutions the
Commission's of member states and for
example like we said before our
Commissioner grant writing up the BND is
spying on NATO and our fellow NATO
members and on the international
monetary fund the beam is spying on the
internet about National Criminal Court
aka The Hague and its buying on the
world health organization its spying on
OPEC the Organization of Petroleum
Exporting Countries spying on the United
Nations Children's Fund
Lisa for Christ's sakes and should be
any spying on the united nations office
on drugs and crime unodc and those are
just the selectors for someone that you
want to
that you want to surveil and then in
your system on your hard drives end of
all the communication then there's also
this concept called bycatch that someone
communicates with someone you're
surveying that communication is also
stored and we have some fun examples of
bycatch to the beanie was spying on john
kerry and on hillary clinton st was like
the Minister of Foreign Affairs and
being he was spying on a German
journalist that was communicating with
an Afghan minister and that's especially
illegal since the German spy Chiefs
opposed to not be allowed to spy on
Germans unless it has explicit reason
and legal justification for it
yeah and windy always says like the
filter out all the German communications
they have a filter system that they
called the office which is short for
data filter system but this photo system
has some problems because it does not
work well enough because it's kind of
fear and the first stage is a bit
primitive it sorts out all the phone
numbers which begin with plus 49 so if
you are German and you have yet another
phone because you may be living in a
foreign country then
yep bad for you they also sort out like
domains like wat de so if you have like
a googlemail.com address
yeah that's a pity and they try out to
filter German IPS which is kind of
strange because it's really difficult to
say like from ya an IP if it's really in
Germany especially if you use like tools
that are kind of what try to hide your
IP address and they say they filter out
stuff when they take toe is spoken in
German we got something we got like this
bike edges in German so we throw it away
but that's only possible like if they
already got hit on you so that's already
kind of BB gun then they say this right
away so they always say this filter
works then I went to a member of
governing coalition and said look we
have a dark domain communicate in
english and i use a VPN and tour so I'm
not in the film so I'm not filtered out
right but I'm a German i have German
rights and I said well you should out of
luck but for the cases like this with
next project or there's another level of
a blacklist but unfortunately we only
found out about 20 or so domains that
were on them and one of them was the
firefighters in gold stud which we
didn't really understand why but maybe
it's time to read the illuminatus
trilogy
that filter is not only as not really an
invention of to be indeed they always
say Oh works the filter works for
filtering on all germans and we even
have a certification we gave it to the
Federal Office of Information Security
to be as I and they certified it as it
works but when asked Friday inquiry
committee the guy who actually did that
yesterday that certification said well
yeah they gave me a machine but I didn't
really know what to do with it so i just
read some freakin manual and decided
that it sounds okay what they did in
there in the end it was revealed that
the difference itself said well what the
Machine does only really be Indian God
know what whatever he does that count
certification then we asked ourselves
like how good or how bad of the fittest
working like what are the numbers we're
looking for what are the percentages of
people being filtered out if they are
Germans and their numbers like
ninety-five percent then almost like
ninety-nine percent and that sounds like
quite a lot
that sounds like quite good but if you
look at the numbers then you have like
terabytes and terabytes and terabytes of
data and you have millions of
connections and if you take those
millions and terabytes and then you have
the ninety-nine percent then it's a mass
of fundamental rights violations per day
and then the question is what happens
with all this data and metadata that the
B&E collects and gives to the NSA
there's really serious consequences for
example there are drawn strikes and you
can't go too much into detail but yep
you can watch the talk this was given
yesterday the global assassination
brilliance and you can see what the
Americans can do with the metadata they
got from Germany partly connected to
drugs there was also like the base
Rammstein and we had like a witness in
the inquiries which was grand Brian
former drone operator and he said I'm
Stein's absolutely essential to the US
drone program all the information and
data goes through i'm staying for the
whole world so they couldn't do with the
drone operations without they're
stationed in Germany so mrs. and say
general I sent her pain and you know
probably a famous quote we kill people
best on metadata maybe see some metadata
that the B&E gives the NSA there's this
thing called signature strikes where ya
the u.s. institutions don't even
necessarily know the names of people
that they're killing with drone strike
they're just analyzing metadata of
people that look like a Taliban member a
communicator NSA general counsel Stewart
Baker said metadata absolutely tells you
anything about somebody's life you have
enough metadata you don't really need
content
well turns out that sometimes you don't
really need a trial in the eyes of the
NSA in the US before you get shut that
there's another thing later not only the
metadata but the BND also uses humans as
an information source and give those
information to the US where they can
like facilitate this for the drone wars
for example they used refugees as an
information source and it was this happy
which is called like the central
institution for inquiries and this was a
corporation liberty and say it was
cooperation with the defense
intelligence agency so the military spy
agency of the US and there they got the
information from the BND but not only
this they had those people from the DA
directly sitting in the inquiries of the
refugees and at the end as it didn't
have enough personal in the BND anymore
they also inquired the refugees alone so
no control over what's happening with
this data and they asked for example
like phone numbers and places another
investigation was thrown into the B&E
was not understand the inquiry committee
but by the federal commissioner for data
protection she went about eyeblink she
only visited a single outpost of the BND
and she commissioned a report a 60 days
report which is pretty damning but it
was classified highly secret so no one
knows a lot
read it until we publish it in fall and
that's politique org and in there
and in that report she found out 18
serious violations of laws and
constitutions that the B&E was doing
only imbibing these legal violations
word and these are quotes from her of
outstanding significance and therein
correr areas of the be in these actions
it doesn't get any more damning the net
especially since she's a member of the
Conservative Party and from that she
issued 12 complaints like a complaint
yeah doesn't sound like much but it's
the strongest weapon of the Data
Protection Officer of Germany and she
said like the BND severely is restricted
to write to oversight repeatedly and
unlawfully she said like that's seven
databases but I bring alone if out and
establishing order so that's a B&E would
be allowed to run it and that's the
store data of this must be deleted
immediately and must not be reused to be
any meat needs to immediately delete
seven databases including xkeyscore is
what Commissioner Sir now is that
actually happening
no because then there's other
politicians like this friendship and ski
sheep and ski of also the inquiry
committee who said oh yeah that report
from the Commissioner that was secret
but also it's her individual opinion and
we have a different opinion and the
government will just keep on doing what
it did so there's all those things we
found out and what does result from this
like that's a question we have to ask
ourselves and one thing we see that like
every scandal around spying agency
resulted in more powers for this agency
and what are the other consequences like
there was a transparency initiative
because like all the cover names of the
outpost of the BND were standing on
wikipedia and so the BND set like yeah
ok then we can put a metal plate on
those buildings which are already
standing in the internet another not
really that deming result was the
exchange of being these president and
CEO president
schindler which was replaced by a new
one Bruno car but their most serious
results are like more now staying
results like the B&E law so they
implemented a new law which has many
Falls like for example the foreign spy
agency inside of Germany's now really
officially allowed to be tapping stuff
inside of Germany and they are not only
allowed like before to your request
communication lines to be tapped they
are now allowed to just request home
networks instead of one fiber optic
cable and technically they were
illegally only allowed to tap twenty
percent of that they cannot have a
hundred percent of an entire network
which means a beanie can legally now
finally obtain the full take that it
wanted from the dates internet exchange
and frame for many many years ago so
when I asked politicians about that
doesn't that seem like a pretty drastic
expansion of to be in these powers and
basically they can do whatever they want
to say don't worry they don't have
enough hardware and money to do what
they're legally allowed now but whatever
you like official targets of the BND
odyssey like supposed to do we always
have this argument of like he's fighting
against terror or his investigating
terror or war proliferation but there's
drew's yeah if he's trying to spy on
Germans but there's other things there's
like for example counter fighting money
money laundering and trucks and there's
the big indie can survey Germans expect
some of illegal migration help into the
EU like our friends from see which were
saving lives in the Mediterranean and
being need this was from a law change
one half years ago that we're seeing now
against it's not only looking for
terrorists but for Mel where the beanies
getting the tix internet exchange for
d-does and news a B&E law so it's now
officially possible that he targets the
world
to retain Jones ability to explore to
Cain inside of importance to foreign and
security policy which means like a few
translated into one single word he's
allowed to do anything so it's not just
about terrorism
it's about political power is about
miracles sitting at the g20 meeting
wanting to know what the Chinese and
other partners are thinking and how to
prepare for a meeting
that's one secret services for what the
spider disease are really four but those
limits that we said now we're only for
so-called for the content of
communication for metadata there's now
officially no limited all the BND can
take for dump of metadata like it has
been doing and it's legally allowed to
give it two partners like the NSA we
don't only have a nubian dilo we also
have kind of a new oversight law which
is kind of insufficient like one
argument for this is they established a
new independent committee but this is
independent committee is appointed by
the government so like those who we
learned about that they are not really
controlling the undeveloped they don't
have any yet not much interested in
controlling the BND very well so they
are like the ones to point their
committee to control the BND better the
oversight committees have other problems
like a push-pull problem there when the
directors of these spiders you sit
there's the party members of parliament
can ask any question but they don't we
know what to ask about what the current
scandal is what theyre hidden things are
so it's not like this is as you go there
and tell everything that's going on
we had exhales have to be and you say
well I always had a list of things i
could have talked about but they didn't
ask the right questions that somehow the
time was up there but it's not just
about us saying like those
yeah reforms are kind of wrong but it's
also what experts said in the parliament
hearing and many many more people so we
have like a short one minute clip like
the best of what the experts in the
parliamentarian hearing it has a decent
quantity is after their answer and more
food for five contests we can often and
forth into an exam time for fastens
feeling I'm said to cliff we hadn't gets
indictment hours and hours and topping
our first these invitations because this
anger that fast easy Darden is Evan
meter by two RBI double bond distances
of up title it's really do it for money
investors only time she finally contours
being did that into shaha fit to your
father's day does that being the invite
him and I agreement food on filled with
hatred and implementation strategies
from flu shot and potassium currents the
matter eno to find safety controls
stands arts in flies to get seen and he
plays happy Saint from stealing
systematic in Duke leash he wriggled his
hand calculation is brutally good passes
in mind our fastest ports one sweet
those laws were passed and they're
entering into the forest next week with
the change of the year but other
consequences for to be in dr it's
getting more money and more resources we
were real just last year after Snowden
after the inquiry committee that the BND
is getting 300 million euros more for
his new project called strategic
initiative technology where it's getting
new fiber optic cable tips music and
capabilities new tools for mass data
analysis and you tools for hacking
there's other funny operations of
India's getting money for like 150
million for crabbing prophecy under the
name of this key and messengers because
they noticed like oh we can only like
break 10 out of 70 messengers and we
want to break everything and everywhere
person and they don't use just like your
technology they also use human
intelligence operations to get access to
keys and certificates and once again
like
every spying scandal lady saw results in
more powers for the agency at least
until now that's pretty unsatisfying now
what do we do is that so we need to get
active i learned in school and
university that democracies informed
consent of the government
well if I'm not informed i can't really
consent to what is happening the Snowden
revelations and the enquiry committee
have showed that the spy agencies are in
direct opposition to the principle of
democracy their operating in secret and
they're not controllable they're
breaking laws and breaking laws left and
right and with any other institutions it
would have been found the legal and
closed down and eliminated already why
is not happening with spy agencies but
since that is unfortunately not
happening we need to get active in
different ways
one example is to litigate to sue people
I want two more people we have some
people some examples of that tube
there's the opposition suing like at the
federal court of justice because they
want to hear Snowden the frankfurter and
exchange takes is suing the government
for its orders that the internet
exchange has to hand over data to be
indeed now I only learned yesterday that
once the new larger force and they're
getting a new order to hand over data
that they're suing on the basis of this
new law which is really really good and
important our friends from reporters
without borders together with lawyer
friends are suing the government for
surveying journalists and other people
of importance for violating fundamental
rights still out
outstanding m stands the society for
civil liberties are suing the government
for the article 10 law and the society
facilities is also suing the government
for the new B&E law but there's other
things to do like besides litigation so
we're trying to do our little part and
inform the public that's called
journalism
now not everyone was happy with our work
so far we got into a little trouble with
the authorities here but will create
continuing your work because you are
have to find out what's being done in
your names with your taxes
and it's also about like being creative
like looking what can I do best and how
can i use this like capabilities to do
something against the spy agencies and
it's also about like crack the spy
agencies to light like show what they
are doing is like about to understand
and interpret and I think like in this
room and spilling of many many people of
technical skills that are like the ideal
people to understand what they are doing
in a technical way and to look into that
and then it's about just informing
friends family and politicians like for
example if you something and like people
don't know about it just tell them and
you make clear to them what's really
happening with their mountain with the
Texas now we're at a hacker conference
obviously we acknowledge and technology
technology for self-defense
now we need to build those tools we need
to use those tools that is really
important but it doesn't stop there
we need to also change to need to change
the legal basis and societies that we
don't have to defend our fundamental
right of technology tools
we've been doing that for a few years
now I mean at cicis entire point of
existence but somehow we don't always
get where we are the world should be
there is also a concept of tyrant action
which I've heard that ever after certain
recent election results are probably
only going to increase now we've seen
people we've seen people hack the NSA
the beanies running servers on German
territory that speak IP we can't really
advocate for illegal things here but we
really would like to see more documents
send them to us
so much for us thank you very much but
now we have a QR code with our open bgp
fingerprints and will hand over to
questions
hey please stay seated and i will tell
the box sorry we're taking five minutes
over the time to come up here
shit right here in the middle like the
cross
instead of now asking questions from the
audience because we have to last time
who would you like to ask a question we
have like this one problem we have this
witness who didn't come to the committee
and we would like to be able to ask him
questions because we have to ask
questions because he's of number one
witness who started all this and so we
have to ask like what do you think about
what happened in Germany after like all
those like committee things for coming
out and like
[Applause]
[Music]
instead of human relations
thank you thank you very much guys thank
you so much but I gotta say this is cece
you know we're always killed for time so
let's let's talk about this quickly and
again thank you so much
that's probably the warmest welcome i
remember gotten the main question people
ask is first why was I not invited to
Germany to speak about this and I think
that's because the truth is sometimes
inconvenient and when we look at what
you talked about what we're seeing is a
response to this a lot of things become
clear that actually are never spoken but
never a sort of state and clearly out
loud to read in the newspaper you seen
the magazine's I instead actions are
speaking more loudly more clearly than
anyone's words really are and that's
what we've seen a story that's been told
since 2013 in country after country
right this isn't about nationalism
forget your flag and think about what's
happening to everybody everywhere even
in the United States even in Germany
even in the united kingdom on being
generous here we're talking about very
liberal what we would like to think of
open societies we see evidence again
again that this kind of mass
surveillance right indiscriminate
surveillance that's just collecting
everything off the wires that's hitting
sites like d6 internet exchanges uh you
know telecommunications providers all
over the world is they're actually not
effective in stopping terrorism and yet
despite that we see more political
support
I not only to continue these programs to
expand them as you say to fund them to
even greater levels
why is that and I think the answer there
is clear
put yourself in the position of these
politicians why would they be afraid of
upsetting the united kingdom of the
United States these sort of
international relations where everybody
is trading baseball cards trading sort
of dossiers about all of their citizens
private activities or
maybe they're saying well we won't share
Germans information with you but will
show the information of everybody else
whose lives connects to Germany or
transistor germany and this this is the
fundamental basis behind not just mass
surveillance targets surveillance it was
never about terrorism because it's not
effective in stopping terrorism
it's not about security all it's not
about safety it's about power
surveillance is about control
it's about being able to see moments of
vulnerability in any life whether that
person is a criminal whether they're an
ordinary person and we want governments
to be able to investigate serious crimes
early some of us do this is cece so I
get can speak for everybody in the
audience
ah but you know if there's a bad guy out
there we get a court order with this
guy's name on and said let's go after
them
let's tap their line let's go after
their modem let's go with the alligator
clips outside the house let's go in the
house when they're not there we've got a
warrant from a court
let's look at this person's life very
few people object to that but this for
watching everyone everywhere all the
time is an extremely dangerous thing and
i want to point out here
the journey is standing on the stage of
history in a real way because they are
the only country that has a real inquiry
going on and unfortunately we see their
operating from a position of either fear
ah where they're afraid that they'll
lose popularity in this sort of
international intelligence ring or
favour where they're afraid to upset a
friend right which is understandable
nobody wants to piss off their friends
but at the same time there are greater
consequences at risk here
china just passed and extremely harsh
new surveillance in December 2015 when
they were asked why they did this how
they can get away with this how they
could justify this
we're compelled technology companies to
help them decrypt communications that
we're going through their servers and
they said well this is what every other
western country is doing why should we
do the same Russia just passed their
yard ipad
which is even worse it's one of the most
blisteringly terrible surveillance laws
on the planet Russians called the Big
Brother law and this is something that
should never be passed anywhere in any
country and yet the same kind of thing
happens to go we're just keeping up
they're not they were probably doing
this anyway but the fact is we are now
seeing the moral high ground we are now
saying it's okay we're not saying we're
not worried about individual rights
we're not worried about human rights up
we're only barely concerned with the
rights of people within our borders
within our countries with our passports
right but your life is not this sort of
team sports where we go what color
jersey or people wearing human rights
are universal even in the United States
people go all well you know this person
is not protected by the Fourth Amendment
or something like that
I've got news for you we saw in the
Universal Declaration of Human Rights we
signed the international covenant on
civil and political rights things are
international agreements treaty
agreements in the united states and even
read our Constitution we have something
called the supremacy clause which means
our treaty obligations are equivalent to
constitutional obligations so yes in
fact foreign citizens people around the
world also have constitutional
protections you don't have to look to
the fourth many we have a mesh of other
frameworks and my final thing here just
because i know i've gone long
I is that this isn't just happening in
China and Russia right we were always
suspicious of them we always knew things
were going to happen there they were
August gonna play games on the internet
but it's happening in Germany is
happening in the UK it's happening in
the u.s. is also happening in places
like Canada I'm not old news not 2013
happening now this is from the very end
of october of this year right and
continue to the very beginning of
november or a journalist I and in fact
many other journalists in Montreal were
found to be up being monitored
specifically their phones were being
tracked via their GPS the other tower
positions they were being tracked
not because they were suspected of any
criminal activity but
because the police department was
embarrassed by the stories that were put
out the resource to people within the
police department so I said well we
tracked the journalists we can find
their sources and then suddenly their
intelligence agency said people are
responding really badly about this maybe
we should say that we kind of do the
same thing and the Canadian intelligence
service said hey we are going to do a
report about this to tell you when it
happened and why and how I justify it
but the unfortunate news here is just a
few days ago in this month in December
they said duh
we're actually gonna take that back we
can tell you that because this is a
state secret and if we get into that
paradigm of confirming what's happening
who's being spied on when and how we
won't be able to keep secrets anymore
well the problem with this ladies and
gentlemen is secret government is
necessarily bad government you can't
substitute the judgment of a few
officials behind closed doors for the
judgment of everyone in the country
everyone a nation not in a democracy and
we can try that we can even try to work
around the boundaries of that we can
create Inquiry Commission like we have
in germany right now but the problem is
we will see fundamentally again and
again that that paralysis that's
injected into our democratic process
processes by those natural human
inflammations of those sort of the
buffeting wins that we feel on either
side of us of fear or favour that the
Commission is suffering under right now
where they go
look what's gonna happen if we say we
broke the law
well we might lose power we might lose
reach we might lose procedure we might
become less powerful we might lose our
careers we might lose our popularity and
ultimately in democracy whether we like
it or not particularly in recent days it
seems that a lot of our governments are
dissolving into simple popularity
contests i think in the point is this
more clear than in the United States
where we just had the most public on
popularity contest in our history but
it's not enough to talk about the
problems is not enough to talk about the
family that's not enough to talk about
where the inquiry committee is going
look we can't talk to these people
because the United States might be
pissed off if we do that what we're
saying is that our principles don't
matter our rights don't matter the
structure of our governments don't
matter our beliefs our values don't
matter and if that's the case why are we
playing this game at all and if that's
the case all of the restrictions that
are put on us in this social contract
between the governing and the government
where we play nice in exchange for this
vote that increasingly means less unless
means we need to start thinking about
what we can do directly again everybody
in this room is here for a reason
everybody has things they believe in
everybody has things that they want to
learn and we learned a lot in the last
few years but perhaps the most important
thing and what I think we need to all be
considering with is what can we do
we're hackers we see a problem mass
surveillance is out there right
we can't get the target surveillance yet
we've got a really smart guy who's going
to be on stage next I think krista
Gorean talking about the targeted
hacking but mass surveillance was what I
set out to let people know about how we
can contested but the thing is all i
could do is tell you what's going on if
we're going to make the internet safer
if we're going to make our society is
more free more open it the generations
that come after us are going to enjoy
the same rights that we ourselves
inherited that people died for you don't
have to do something about it
maybe that's right code maybe that's
creating a tool maybe that's starting a
new service or maybe that's recognizing
that sometimes you have to say no vote a
different way but you have to take some
action it's not enough to believe in
something ladies and gentlemen if we
want things to get better you're gonna
have to stand for something
thank you
this one is political unit
[Applause]
[Music]
that's so awesome how you work so i know
what to do want to say something to you
at the end
yeah one last thing because we didn't
have time for questions now which is a
pity and we want to give you the
opportunity to ask questions and to get
in touch into like yeah exchange
opportunities and though you can get
like to the thing is called section 9 up
there at h p.m. and we will be there and
happy to share be rats are on the top
floor all the way over there
thank you very much if the War Powers
honor
[Applause]
[Music]