[Music]
our next presentation comes from a man
who is from Great Britain but now lives
in Greece now I don't know if he just
tried to escape the bad weather and
Britain or the brexit but we're sure
happy he made all the way here to
Hamburg today thanks now the latest
elections in the US and the referendum
on the breakfast have shown us that with
all the collected data and technology
that we use to break the outcome of such
elections we can do it we cannot really
know everything or predict everything a
new Dark Age is an exploration of what
we cannot no longer know about this
world and what we can do about this our
speaker James here as an artist a
publisher and a writer and his writings
have appeared in magazines and
newspapers all around the world such as
wired the observer and the Guardian he's
also a very experienced lecturer in
conferences in universities and
different events so we're very happy
he's here today so please welcome him
and give him a warm round of applause
James bridle
hello thank you very much for that
introduction
thank you very much having me thank you
all very much for coming here this is
huge and amazing and I'm very grateful
and I was yeah I just put hello there
rather new Dark Age because I didn't
want it sound quite so frightening at
the outset and I'm not like it's a thing
I'm working on at the moment and I was
also asked today to still talk a bit
broadly about some of the work that I do
so a lot of this is going to be like a
bit mimimi and that I'm gonna show some
things I've made as a way of explaining
the way that I think through technology
and society and various stuff around
that and hopefully there'll be
connections through that and I'll stalk
quite a lot about one particular project
I did this year and then some kind of
extrapolations from that to kind of
where I think I and perhaps we need to
be thinking next and I actually my
background is as a computer scientist
but I'm a seriously lapsed one I managed
to graduate with a master's degree
without actually learning to program
which tells you everything you need to
know about CS education in the UK and
has since been trying to teach myself
desperately ever since and really badly
but I've also been a literary publisher
and a journalist and number of other
things but it was my kind of background
in publishing and my interest in the web
that sort of got me slowly moving
towards the place I'm in now which is
increasingly in the art world but always
always crossing over and this is a good
example of the kind of way I put things
together which is a few years old now
but there's one of his work he's a
publisher but wanted to start to talk to
people about how technology and the
Internet in particular changed the way
in which we were putting knowledge
together and so what I did was I took
the complete history of a single
Wikipedia article I took the entire
changelog of it which was the article on
the Iraq war which at the time I made
this book was it was about seven years
of data on a single Wikipedia article
and because I was working a publisher at
the time I learned how to make books
properly so I typeset it all it's all in
like neat little three columns quite
small tight
but when I had that all print and bound
that single Wikipedia article changelog
took a 12 volume size so that the scale
of an a powerful old-style encyclopedia
and what I was thinking through this
work is the fact that the way in which
we build stuff with technology doesn't
really necessarily change the world's
often but the way we understand how that
technology functions changes the way in
which we can interact with the world and
so this is still an old-school
encyclopedia Wikipedia is still an
old-style encyclopedia but the
technology we've built that underlies it
allows us to put that together in a way
that allows us to see all the changes we
made to it we can see the fact that
encyclopedias are not final statements
of fact
but processes of argument overtime with
many many many voices contributing to
them it's a machine for historiography
rather than for history and that for me
captures something quite fundamentally
different about the way we're capable of
building stuff today and so my projects
go back and forth between like things
that exist as big solid objects which
are kind of quite easy to understand and
more kind of immaterial software things
this was a project that I ran for three
and a half years on various social media
tracking reports of drone strikes so I
was working with journalists from place
like the Bureau of invested
don't strikes in undeclared theatres of
war so these were the covert ones in
Pakistan and the Yemen in Somalia these
reports were being posted and those who
are kind of interested in them could
find out slightly more about them but it
struck me as deeply strange that this
entire war was going on
without images which is deeply strange
in our current times I mean and for a
long time for more than a century we've
they used to send illustrators to
battlefields right with pencils and
papers and an age of mass media was
saturated with images there was this
whole war going on without them and yet
at the same time we spent the last 10 20
years photographing the entire Earth
from space you can pull out your phone
and look into any spots on the Earth's
surface and I wanted to pull those kind
of infrastructures together to close
those
loop's so every time there was one of
these covert drone strikes reported I
went to a digital mapping service used
various ones to find as close as I could
the actual landscape in which that
occurred it's kind of resupply some of
these images back to this ongoing fight
and I'd post those to Instagram to
Twitter to tumblr as these long
sequences and trying to create a kind of
a visual record of what was occurring
one of the good things that happened is
that in these images started to then be
used in other places so media when
discussing drone strikes instead of just
running like a photo of a predator drone
supplied to them by the US military
would actually show images of the places
where these things were kering the
actual landscapes in that we're kind of
talking about here and that attempt to
make these kind of hard to see I don't
want to say invisible because you can
always see thanks Ingrid and I don't
want to say that but these hard to see
things kind of more visible I take that
kind of out into the real world as well
so for several years I've been doing
these drone shadow works which are
one-to-one realizations and that came of
me just wanting to know more about these
big machines a thing which I'm very
unlikely to ever see in the real world
but I have you know the tools to find
out just the size of it right just a
simple thing like that and go and put
that out in the street where people can
actually see and kind of measure oneself
physically against the thing it really
changes the way people see and
understand these things and I've painted
these all over the world and is totally
open sourced it so there's a guide
online to drawing your own and people
have then subsequently taken that and
done it both has art installations and
protests in all these kind of and I just
get like people sending me pictures
occasionally when these things have
appeared around the world which is
amazing it's very simple to just set out
to draw a thing in order to understand
it and then realize a whole bunch of
stuff by doing that physical action what
the drone shadows really emphasize is
actually the the intentional
invisibility of these things the fact
that they're designed not to be seen not
to be seen you know physically because
they fly so high they're invisible but
not to be seen politically as well
because because they automate systems
that would otherwise
lead to body bags and all the reasons
you know the military's like drones and
and that got me into the habit of doing
other things in the street as well and
this is a rainbow plane that I drew in
Ukraine a couple of years ago if you've
spent half as much time as I have on
Google Maps you might have seen the
rainbow planes that kind of I find them
deeply beautiful I find them if you're
scouting around airports or whatever you
might spot these things in Google Maps
and what they are are they're artifacts
of satellite mapping so the satellite is
passing very fast overhead taking images
as the ground the planes are flying very
fast below them and the thing is that
satellites don't see like human see and
this is the point at which I become
fascinated because I'm interested in
seeing how technology sees the world in
fundamentally different ways than we do
and satellites see using a variety of
sensors both visible spectrum red green
blue and in a high-definition black and
white in this case and deepens the
infrared in the ultraviolet so they see
things that we're not capable of seeing
and this these little glitches are very
interesting because they allow us to
glimpse inside that system and see the
way in which the machine is seeing the
world and attempt to kind of reflect
that back by by making them visible and
addressable and kind of pointing these
things out in this way it makes us
possible to to think about them for me
in slightly different ways and a couple
of years ago I did this project in South
London and this was called the right to
flight and this is on top of a
multi-story car park in South London
where we built these silos one of which
is a hangar for this blimp the blimps
kind of amazing it's a thing called
helicase which is a hybrid of a balloon
and a kite invented by a slightly mad
British guy who I had to spend several
days in the pub with and the helico it's
amazing because it's better than both
balloon and kite it has helium to lift
and but also a kite to fight the wind so
it doesn't get blown down like a normal
balloon but it has much more lift than a
regular kite and I was flying it off
this rooftop to kind of investigate
what it was like to be able to have that
view from above that kind of classic
surveillant God's eye view of the world
how would it feel for me to be able to
make kind of aerial images like this to
to become to to access this airspace
above London that was otherwise kind of
heavily restricted and and it was a
beautiful project it ran for several
months but it also waded me out quite a
large extent and because obviously the
first thing I did was whack a camera on
this thing because aerial photos are
beautiful and I want to see all this
stuff from above and very quickly I
started to become really uncomfortable
with that because I was doing
surveillance essentially and I was while
I try to inform people what I was doing
and I I looked at various ways doing I
kind of released the footage openly so
everyone see the probe the products of
what I was doing and this kind of stuff
no one actually cared okay
this is in part London is not really
giving a about anything but also I
whether it's just a and lack of
awareness of the thing or whether it's
just the fact that London is so subject
to surveillance all the time anyway and
this is kind of off people's minds but I
was the responsibility was entirely on
me to stop doing this essentially that I
suddenly got to a point what I couldn't
make any more images like this and I
realized that in many ways it's quite
hard to make artworks about surveillance
that don't essentially do more
surveillance and that's a really bad
pattern to get into because I don't
think it helps I think it just kind of
reinforces the logics of surveillance
and normalizes it for people and so I
stopped myself I took the cameras off
and end up putting like a kind of pirate
box on there so people could share that
felt like a more useful kind of
relationship to have with it and so I
started looking at more kind of
pedagogical ways to talk about these
things like this project which is called
citizen X which is a browser extension
very simply anyone can download it
tracks your browsing but entirely
privately data doesn't leave it I don't
share it with anyone including myself
but as you're browsing the web you can
hit the button and it will pull down
will show you very simply stuff that's
very simple for most people in this
I'm sure where the internet thinks you
are and where the Internet thinks the
website you're visiting is so it shows
you this relationship of the the
physical infrastructure of the internet
and like many artists I've been kind of
investigating the physical
infrastructure of the internet for a
while and thinking it's important to
sort of point at this stuff and go you
know this magic cloud place you hear
about isn't some faraway strange place
it's like it's a real thing it's here
it's large buildings filled with
computers in legal jurisdictions subject
to certain laws and but but there's
there's weirdest stuff going on under
that as well so with this project I
didn't just want to highlight that
physical Internet I wanted to highlight
what that physical Internet does to your
rights which is in this case based on
NSA documents showing how the NSA
assigned citizenship and what the NSA
does is it and when it's pulling in all
that data it looks at your browsing
habits and it says well based on where
this person is going on the Internet and
the sort of behavior they have there's
this percentage likelihood they're
American because that's an important
determinant for the NSA because they're
supposed to not track Americans so they
have to have some mechanism for making
this distinction so moment by moment
online your citizenship which used to be
this really solid thing that used to be
a thing determined by your passport by
your place of birth that you could prove
those of us who are lucky to hold stable
citizenships you could prove with a
document that's no longer the case your
right to privacy is being determined
algorithmically all the time by tracking
of your behavior and so what's it's an X
does is it looks at your your very
simple behaviors online and it builds
you one of these algorithm exists and
chips to say this is what actually your
web browsing behavior would look like if
someone more nefarious was looking at it
and how that might kind of come to
affect your rights and I was looking at
the sky a while back because I was
looking for these planes which are
covert Metropolitan Police surveillance
planes and hang out in fields quite a
lot looking for weird stuff like this
and what I found instead was was these
flights this is an example of where I
got into fields and stare at the sky
and find myself stood next to a bunch of
kind of weird interesting people because
you end up in the fields around airports
with the plane spotters the chem
trailers and activists working on
various subjects and working with a
bunch of activists on tracking
deportations from the UK this is a the
system the British government uses to
deport people which is basically where
they hire private planes because it got
embarrassing to do it on on a general
general usual aircraft and in the middle
of the night they put people onto these
planes and they fly them out the country
and this is a very hard system to see
because it happens in the middle of the
night at private terminals airports it
happens within closed courtrooms and
within privatized detention centers and
so working with some friends of mine who
are architects and architectural
modelers we used planning commissioners
went to the council we got the files on
these kind of places we did these kind
of classic invert vesti of journalism
practices of finding eyewitness accounts
finding council documents visiting and
sketching places where we could where we
weren't allowed to photograph in order
to visualize them so this is a courtroom
in the centre of London in the UK it's
illegal to photograph courtrooms so
there's no photographs exist of this
space but there are very very shiny
architectural visualizations that we
made of it this is an interesting
courtroom because it's a courtroom in
which special laws apply the UK passed a
special law for immigrants appeals
commissions where there's suspicion of
terrorist activity or some kind of
security risk where they can present
secret evidence which is evidence that
the defendant and their legal team are
not allowed to know about it makes a
complete mockery of the idea of a fair
trial and what's interesting is the way
in that the way in which that appears as
architecture in spaces like this because
you can actually point to it the divider
on the left here is what separates the
public viewing gallery from the spooks
viewing gallery and the closed witness
box over there is so that members of the
security personnel can scoot service can
appear without giving away their
identities and this culminated in a
eight minute film you can watch online
called seamless transitions which
documents these these various spaces
that the courtroom which you just saw a
detention center near Heathrow Airport
and the final airport through which
people are deported which is Stansted if
anyone goes to the UK on holiday and and
what what again I was trying to do in
this these this film was not necessarily
paint like just the what you would
traditionally do with photojournalism so
this was commissioned by the
photographers gallery in London and and
it was when it first went on show there
it was alongside a huge amazing deep
dives to the archive of something called
the black star archive which is an
archive of human rights photography from
the 20th century it's extraordinary
but it's very much what you think of
when you think of of 20th century
photojournalism
which is the kind of sharp
black-and-white photo a face in a crowd
this frozen moment this moment from
which we can supposedly draw like this
particular story this one signal thing
which will explain everything else and
it's and it's a fantastic way of working
but in this site I kind of realized I
was doing the opposite which is I was
using the architecture of these spaces
and also the way in which work like this
is put together which is hugely based on
research assemblage cooperating with
other artists visualizers and also
cooperating with the software
architectural software that makes this
is the same software that generates a
huge amount of the built environment
around us and yet we still kind of
assume there's one master architect at
the heart of one of these things rather
than several thousand people working on
code or AutoCAD or whoever it is who now
have a huge stake in our built
environment so all of these different
pressures come into play on trying to
depict not a particular place but the
entire legal and infrastructural system
that goes into creating the situation
that results which is horrific
deportation system so that's a very
brief and swift run-through of some of
the sort of things I do
I wanted to talk a little bit more about
about this project the cloud index which
requires a little bit of history which I
hope will be interesting this is this is
one of my favorite people Lewis fry
Richardson and in 1912 13 Richardson was
a meteorologist who was working the
Eskimo Deer Observatory in Scotland
doing a very very early kind of weather
calculation mostly just recording the
weather and trying to like think about
what it might mean to start to have this
kind of huge body of weather data and
then in 1914 he was called up for the
First World War and he was a Quaker so
he's a pacifist so he joined the
ambulance division and spent the war and
running around with stretchers the other
thing he spent the war doing was that
he'd taken a bunch of data a bunch of
readings from the observatory and from
other observatories around Europe that
had been gathering before the war and
over the course of two to three years
during the war while in trenches well
under fire he performed the very first
mathematical calculation were 24-hour
weather forecasts just over the area of
northern Europe just over the area that
you see here but he figured out what the
mass was to take a bunch of historical
weather data and advance that 24 hours
right to push that prediction forward
into the future which is an incredible
achievement and I say it took him
several years to do this with pencils
and paper and when he analyzed the
results because obviously the day he was
doing was by that stage almost a decade
into the past he turned out to be
broadly correct some things were bit
more exaggerated whatever but it but his
his kind of an his thesis worked and
because of course this was a time before
what we now think of as computers he
didn't he thought this was a kind of
achievement but thought realizing its
full potential was a very long way off
and he in the in this book the one that
showed before he goes on this kind of
beautiful little fantasy where he
describes what it would take for his
weather forecasting to actually achieve
some kind of industrial scale and be
economically useful this is a painting
of that fantasy
by Steven Conlan from 1986 where he hung
Richardson described this vast globe on
the inside of which will be painted a
huge grid covering the entire Earth
which weather forecasters could kind of
point to read data off calculate it have
it replaced you can see there be teams
of mathematicians then still called
computers working in the middle and then
this kind of amazing infrastructure of
information Telegraph's and all the kind
of communications infrastructure of the
age pouring information into this place
and pouring it back out again
and so this was he knew it was possible
but he thought you know mankind would
never actually get to the point that it
would possible and mankind did get to
that point in in 1950 when the very
first mechanical calculation of a
24-hour weather forecast was performed
and which was done on the ENIAC which is
a computer that some of you have
probably heard of which is my personally
favorite computer and the first stored
first mechanical stored program computer
built in the 1940s the University of
Pennsylvania and this is the process for
doing it and they brought together a
team of meteorologists in in kind of
from 1948 onwards and in 1950 they ran
this very very first calculation or the
very first successful calculation of a
single day's weather forecasting over
the northern United States and when they
did it it took about three weeks to run
right which doesn't sound so great but
you have to remember that the ENIAC
broke down a lot of the time and what
they realized was that actually if they
subtracted all the time when the machine
hadn't been running from the process
they got it down to 23 hours and 30
minutes so they had very for the very
first successfully time calculated the
weather faster than the weather itself
was happening right this is a incredibly
significant moment and john von neumann
who worked on this project wrote in the
in the project log that we have achieved
the dreams of Lewis fry Richardson
computation now advances faster than the
weather itself and I like the fact that
it happened on the
yak which as I say is my favorite
computer for those who aren't familiar
with it and here it is it was a you know
an early mainframe so occupied two huge
rooms first at the University of
Pennsylvania and later at the Plymouth
proving grounds aberdeen proving grounds
where it's moved after the war and it
was you know it required a lot of
fiddling and plugging in and if you've
read chewings cathedral which is a great
book about the kind of history of the
early kind of computational programs
there's a beautiful quote in that from a
guy called Harry Reid who was a engineer
who worked on this computer in which he
says that um I always thought of the
ENIAC is a very personal computer now we
think of a personal computer as
something we kind of carry around with
us but the ENIAC was a computer that you
lived inside right it completely
surrounded you and actually for me like
that that division of personal computer
is obviously and I think increasingly
not true because we all live inside this
kind of shell of computation now we know
that these are mostly terminals to other
other connections whoever owns them
whether we build these things outwards
or not whether we're talking to
satellites or not the ENIAC hasn't
contracted into these things has
actually expanded out into a kind of
vast shell around us and the other thing
that I really like about the ENIAC is
you know it's one of these computers
this generation of computers were the
last ones that were kind of truly
physically legible so computation now is
legible to those of us probably not me
who are really smart enough to kind of
follow logically step by step what kind
of process is happening within machines
with the ENIAC you could do that
physically with your eyes by looking at
the blinking lights so that you could
watch a computation kind of unfold on
you across the walls you could actually
see that as it went from different parts
of the machines through the through the
architecture you could kind of follow
that and that kind of legibility also
seems to me something quite crucial to
kind of go back to and reflect on as I
mentioned one of the people who worked
on that was a john von neumann who i'm
sure you're most familiar with is the
kind of invent of the von neumann
architecture works on a lot of these
early projects and obviously was working
on both
the weather project but also on the
Manhattan Project because this is here
with with Oppenheimer who run the
Manhattan Project and the same computer
the ENIAC was used for both the weather
forecasting programs and for the
development of nuclear bombs these are
the kind of two grand computational arms
races that really kind of got computing
going in the 1940s and 50s and von
Neumann had this line which which he
divert which he wrote first in the
commentary on on the atomic on the
weather project but later recycled to
talk about the Manhattan Project which
was kind of his view of what computation
could do and particularly computational
prediction and he said that all the
stable processes we shall predict and
all under stable processes we shall
control and that was his view of what
you could do with computation you could
model and control the world's a
sufficient degree that you could predict
the outcomes so I wanted to to take some
of those ideas of the weather and our
computational predictive abilities and
bring them somewhat up to date and I was
I got particularly fascinated with them
what's currently happening in neural
networks because I studied and you know
studies see us awhile back I studied AI
in the like early noughties but
basically the AI of the 90s that was
dying so we were taught neural networks
as a kind of historical anomaly like a
nice idea some interesting theory but
basically a dead end and the field kind
of went quiet for 10 years and it's just
starting to go kind of massive again
right the last 5 years newer networks
have become as AI starting to kind of
become inside everything essentially in
rather interesting ways and so I thought
was important to kind of really eight
them and explore them again and this is
from a paper from the beginning of this
year things move fast in this world of
Facebook research paper about DC ganz
deep conversation deep convolutional
generational adversarial networks which
is something that they've been they've
been pushing and using and this is from
a newer network generation from that
paper where they took
thousands and thousands of thousands of
bedrooms pictures of bedrooms and they
asked this network to simulate new
bedrooms so each of the images you see
here is not a bedroom that exists in the
world it's a bedroom that's been dreamed
up by a neural network that's seen many
many pictures of bedrooms and it's
fascinating to me what we decided to
train these things on and and the more
public image of newer networks which is
kind of everyone's a lot of people have
seen is is the deep dream stuff from
Google and so what deep dream is is an
attempt to see back through these
networks and try and understand how they
think about and make images so it's kind
of instead of asking the the network to
look at an image and tell you what it
sees it's asking it basically gives it
blank or or fixed images and I'll sit to
kind of reverse them back through that
network to kind of imagine and visualize
what it can see in the world and it
turns out those things are terrifying
and I think I think this should be
acknowledged more and when deep the the
guys on the machine learning team at
Google first came up with deep dream
apparently they showed it to Google PR
and we're like look what we made
and PR was like never release that and
in fact they weren't allowed to they did
the dream leaked first of all and I
don't know how but it's interesting and
and then they had to come out and say
okay this is what this thing is and
everyone went war man computer tripping
balls and didn't and didn't you know
there hasn't been a huge amount and I
know I don't think like you know the
people behind there that are quite
annoyed that there hasn't actually been
a bit more thinking about what this kind
of stuff entails because it's what
neural networks are doing in the world
is kind of interesting and you can do
weird stuff with neural networks and
visual new interaction DC games a
particular list from the same paper so
you can do addition and subtraction you
can take a bunch of images associated
with certain concepts you can then
produce new images that combine elements
of those things so this is a network
that's never seen a picture of a smiling
man but is seen
these other distinct stages and you can
do other take on that to produce new
kinds of image outcomes as I thought
well if a computer can dream of bedrooms
and it can dream of smiling men it can
dream of all things and it can possibly
also dream of the weather so I took you
might have noticed from the other works
I'm quite obsessed with satellite
imagery so I took 8 years of satellite
data of weather over the UK this is from
the EU space programs meteo sat which
sits up there well above null Island
watching the earth every day several
images a day of weather systems over the
Western Hemisphere and chop that down
into images over the UK which came to
about 16,000 images which I stressed is
really not enough for doing this kind of
work but I only had 8 years of data on
the other input which was polling data
from the UK on their voting intentions
in the EU referendum and I'm sorry about
brexit I'm not going to speak of that
again except I am because this is what
this project is about and this is this
is a short snapshot I actually had eight
years of polling data it's a bit sparse
at the end but it was enough to
extrapolator eight years of information
and so I built one of these networks
with the assistance of Jean Cogan who
might be around here somewhere and who's
brilliant and fed it eight years of
weather images from space eight years of
images of cloud formations and eight
years of this polling data about the EU
referendum and my newer Network dreamed
new weather formations it dreamed new
kind of cloud patterns and once it has
started to make these kind of
associations
it was then possible to say to it well
you've seen what the weather looks like
on these certain occasions when the
voting is trending in these particular
directions so just as we did the
addition with the smiling man etc let's
do some addition on the voting and say
well what should the weather look like
if the entire country was to vote in one
particular directional or in the other
direction to generate weather potential
weathers that we could simulate if we
wish the Democratic outcomes to be
different and and the ones that the
extremes are what they
are actually kind of enjoyed more the
outcomes that played around with
undecided voters this seemed to me
actually something that really required
more attention in in the aftermath of
you know very divisive elections of the
kind of various kinds that we've seen
this year to try and put a little bit
more emphasis on not on hard brexit or
trumpism or whatever it is but on the
huge space within that of indecision and
unknowingness that actually guides and
hugely influences a lot of our elections
and the reason that I thought that this
would be in part a worthwhile thing to
do is because we can change the weather
now okay if we if we want to and this is
Vincent Schaefer in his laboratory at
General Electric in the mid-1950s
Vincent Schafer's the man who invented
cloud seeding which is the realization
you can place into into early forming
clouds crystals are silver iodide that
will cause those clouds to precipitate
you can you can you can raise smog
levels you can burn off fog you can
enact quite large-scale changes to the
atmosphere when Schafer's work started
to appear in the 1950s there was a huge
public debate in the US and elsewhere
about what the possibilities of weather
modification might be there was a huge
belief there's a huge military belief
that that weather would be the weapon of
the future and the u.s. used weather
modification extensively in Vietnam it
had a two-year program of seeding with
silver iodide clouds over the Vietnam
and in order to basically obliterate the
Ho Chi Minh Trail
they reckoned they extended the maan
seen soon period by an average of six
weeks each year making it rain more and
more and more and when that leaked again
leaking they stopped it immediately and
there's been little willingness in the
West to continue cloud seeding exponents
ever since then but it doesn't stop
other people these are Chinese weather
making rockets the Chinese government
has a weather Department of some 50,000
employees whose job it is to make the
weather and they active very much in
agricultural locations either making it
rain on the crops or preventing it
hailing on crops but they also do a lot
of work clearing the air for official
parades for the opening of the Olympics
for these kinds of events so the weather
is is a tool that we could be deploying
should we wish to and one that we might
increasingly want to think about
deploying in the in the not-too-distant
future when we have to ask ourselves
quite serious questions about what we
want to do with the environment how
we're willing to use the things that we
know how we wish to use those things
whether we have the strength of our
beliefs in our ability to act in the
world and and why do I do this and and
and it's because I'm no longer convinced
actually that it's possible to
understand the world just through
processing kind of vast amount of
information that I don't think this is
any longer proactive useful way of
dealing with the world but I realized
that I kind of wanted to retain the
cloud not as a kind of bad metaphor of
kind of lost the engineering or
corporate control and not as that kind
of materialist look I found a data cable
kind of like materialization of the
world but but as a way of thinking the
world as recognizing that the cloud is
cloudy that what it reveals to us is
often actually a kind of difference and
differentiation around the world and
that is not a purely kind of fixed
channel for information that's there to
tell us how the world is but asks us to
question it and thinking think about it
more and this is increasingly necessary
because this informational view of the
world this view that by gathering
information we kind of make more
knowledge and more sense is increasingly
at risk and I'm sure again Moore's Law
is familiar to most of people in this
room the rule that the number of
transistors doubles every couple years
in Sun space you get more more power
more more processing power this is its
inverse this is something that's been
named eroom's law by people who work in
the pharmacological sciences this is the
graph of
money spent on medical research against
drug discovery and it's going the other
way the more money that's put into this
the less and less we're learning and
there's various proposals that have been
put forward two obvious analyses of this
which is a long-running and
long-standing problem in pharmacology
and and one of the most prevalent
theories is is essentially too much
information and if you know how drug
discovery has done now it's not
basically people in white coats in a lab
and it basically looks like a server
farm it looks like large machines it
looks like robots and it looks like very
very large datasets of information being
automatically run through these
high-throughput screening machines in
order to test new drug reactions against
one another and this this problem seems
to be continuing and one of the ways in
which science labs are dealing with it
is increasingly putting people back into
the process not as some kind of like
airy-fairy you know computers are bad
people a magical kind of way but simply
that there seems to be some other way of
thinking the world that doesn't rely on
vast vast datasets but I'm plotting
slightly distinct in non machine equate
them the example I like of that is is
the story of advanced chess so this is
the famous game in 1997 between Kasparov
and deep blue when IBM spent a decade
building a computer to built beat this
one poor guy at the only game he'd ever
loved and yeah it was you know as this
it was this insane moment because we
basically our idea of intelligence is
always like the one thing we're still
holding out and you'll notice in any
discussion of AI that what constitutes
intelligence has kind of receded for
decades as the machines have got better
and we've got oh no not that this no you
kind of continually moved the barriers
but at this point chess was the thing
right and it was a really shocking
moment when possibly the greatest chess
player ever tire of all time was beaten
by this machine and you know deep blue
was it was a brute force
that's what it did it basically was
capable of doing such vast search
through the kind of development process
space of the gamers involved that it
could out think any human by a pure kind
of brute-force approach of thinking
ahead and that that ultimately seemed to
be right we finally built enough
processors to be too human and and what
was interesting is that while lots of
people were kind of like oh god and
that's it the machines take over
Kasparov came back just one year later
with a thing he called advanced chess
which was a new kind of chess which was
not humans versus machines but humans
and machines versus humans and machines
because it turns out that today in it
you know and this has become very
successful and a you know not even a
supercomputer today advanced computer
will wipe the floor with any human alive
but a human using quite a relatively
weak computer assisted by it will wipe
the floor with even the biggest
supercomputer there's a some kind of
interesting complementary nurse to the
way in which this thought happens and
that seems to me one model of how we can
think about our relationship technology
not as this kind of completely
oppositional thing but as a form of
cooperation and kind of thinking through
problems together but at the same time
there's something also that's that's
coming out of that at the same time
because this is where we next put
intelligence right this is into this is
the alphago game from earlier this year
when google's deepmind again just a
massive spoilsport machine played Lisa
doll one of the greatest go players in
the world and despite a heroic fourth
game third game for them deep mind one
and so go is now again one of these
things that we held up as being such a
important move intelligence and is now
kind of you know has again been taken by
the machines and while I really look
forward to advanced go and all the kind
of interesting things that will come out
of new ways to play it there's something
fundamentally different between deep
mind and deep blue
and that is we don't understand how deep
blue I'll forego so it does what it does
we don't understand how the newer
network and actually beat these dog
there's theories and there's kind of
ways of watching the game and picking
them apart but essentially this was a
machine that was trained first by a team
of humans and then trained against
instances of itself and it's learning
ability while it played against other
instances itself was kind of exponential
and it's thought processes because it's
in the annual network and the weights
and train that your network is
unintelligible to us at some kind of
deep fundamental level we can maybe
produce the kind of weird deep dream
mind state images for alphago but they
weren't tell us what the the process is
that allows this this to happen every
what we heard this is the example of the
strangeness of neural networks I've
checked this story and it doesn't appear
to be true but it's the classical story
of how strange neural networks are and
why they do things that we can't quite
understand which is em that the US Army
commissioned a neural network to
recognize tanks they get a team of
researchers a tank a bunch of soldiers
and they said go and hide in the woods
take loads of photos feed them into a
neural network and we wanted neural
network that can see tanks in the trees
that can see camouflaged artillery and
so and so forth so they went out they
took those these photos they were back
to lab they built in and annual Network
they ran all the images through it and
and it worked perfectly on this kind of
X thousand images that they had the the
newer network every time classified yes
there's a tank in this image no there's
not even when the tank was like hidden
deep in the trees and invisible as they
went back to the Army together neural
network and well like he go we've done
it all and the army put its new pictures
in and it completely failed I didn't
work at all and the way they went back
because they were working with a
relatively small dataset they looked at
the images again and they realized that
the tank had only been there in the
morning and so what the images were the
tank in had been shot in the morning and
all the images without tanks have been
certainly afternoon and the neural
network was really really good
I work out whether it's morning or
afternoon and but it completely had
utterly failed to see tanks
and these are the kind of strange misses
that occur when using technologies where
we don't quite see the way the machine
sees the world and we're building neural
networks into all of our things now this
is Nvidia's program to to train cars to
drive well they basically just put the
newer network in the car connected to
all the computers and driven it around
for a while so it learns to recognize
the world around it without any external
cues it doesn't know the rules of the
world rules of the road it doesn't know
what anything else looks like it's just
watched humans drive for so long it
figures it out for itself these things
are becoming inside the things around us
all the time and we're actively building
the tools of our own mystification this
I find particularly strange this is for
a Google brain experiment just a couple
of months old where they are trained to
neural networks to hide their
communications from a third party so
they Alice and Bob in this arrangement
evolved their own
cryptographic system to protect their
communications from Eve and I myself
think it's a really great idea that we
should train the machines to be able to
talk in secret behind our backs I think
this is a struggling to see and see why
we would want to do this this this idea
though of course of being able to gather
all the more data about the world making
it to collect everything in order to
make better decisions is of course one
that we see across across across domains
this is the this is the approach of
surveillance agencies this belief that
by gathering all of the information they
will be able to make better decisions
they will be able to pull out and they
will build a model of the world that's
so complete that they'll have a full
understanding of it on which they will
be able to act and it strikes me that
this this is not actually all too
different from the way in which we also
oppose this belief that actually the
belief in information itself being
somehow sufficient to
change opinions to to sort of enact some
greater good naturally on its own behalf
is also the approach of of transparency
of kind of full information release that
that the the you know NSA and WikiLeaks
essentially believe the same thing which
there is some smoking gun information at
the heart of the world that if we only
bring it to light everything will kind
of magically be made better and that
that that seems to me to be an
increasingly insufficient way of viewing
the world this is an as is a small
example of Facebook's analysis of hot
topics for November 2016 with WikiLeaks
right up there in the old men quadrant
of most discussed topics from the time
of the election I'm a big fan of Julian
Assange's original network analysis
secrecy that posed the kind of leaking
as this kind of like grit in
authoritarian regimes that were kind of
make them grind to a halt but it does
appear to me at the moment that right
now it's kind of merely oiling a machine
that none of us want to keep running
that we're locked in a kind of deadlock
of an information war that we're both
playing against each other in ways that
are not going to break us out of this
this opacity transparency dialectic
anytime soon and all around us this it
seems to me that it's becoming harder
for these predictive mathematical
information based systems to work and we
need to ask very specific questions
about what that's doing to us and to our
societies there's a huge fuss around
polling and and the poor performance of
polls both in the referendum and Trump
and everything else and but but most of
that seem to focus on the fact that like
the mathematical models were were wrong
and they'd have to be revised and we
kind of built better ones rather than
saying these things are things that
actually poison the discourse as part of
the process that when you are running
polls running metrics running forty
models like this all of the time
alongside everything you're actually
shaping the outcomes
so when polls are done during a campaign
they don't just say what people are
going to do at the end they change
people's behavior during the campaign
and they also change what is politically
possible because people run polls and
they say or people don't like that we're
not even going to put this out into
public discourse modeling and predicting
in this way restricts the kind of actual
possibility of discourse around us the
debate around fake news is a kind of
startlingly interesting one but one that
is not all so historically new or novel
or should not be and also it needs to be
I think very specifically historically
situated as something that as an idea of
so this suddenly that we can't know this
stuff or that it doesn't emerge from
quite specific ways of seeing the world
I was particularly struck and by some of
the reporting in recent weeks that and
went on and on about and the fake a lot
of this fake news stuff emerging from
the former Yugoslavia public of
Macedonia that's cited it particularly
in this place without any particular
context around the political situation
in that place is possibly being related
so the story if you don't know it is
that lots of kids in Macedonia and
particularly apparently in this one town
of village set up those of these
websites which were getting more hits on
Facebook the New York Times only kind of
additional media by completely making up
stories and so getting tons and tons of
ad revenue and it strikes me that this
is a place in which they have a
government in Macedonia which for the
last 10 years has pursued a policy of
fake news as government policy this is
part of Skopje 2014 part of the
Macedonians government project to build
an entirely fake history for Macedonia
by erecting statues of Alexander the
Great and Philip of Macedon and
classicizing buildings with kind of
Hellenic columns and this kind of stuff
in a completely kind a historical move
that's been opposed by lots of people in
the country but as a result of a kind of
huge resurgent nationalism and
nationalism that actually depends on
feeding a kind of fake stories and we
seem to be optimizing a lot of other
stuff for this as well and we seems kind
of desire this inability to fully and to
see and understand the world
these are images that AI researcher
Robert Elliott Smith discovered in his
own photo stream when he he posted
originally the two pictures on the left
and Google's I think it's called like
auto magical algorithm or something
produced the image on the right which is
an image that combines them both to have
both people smiling but it's an image of
a moment that didn't happen right now
ever it's a memory of something that
never actually occurred and likewise
Adobe is pushing a thing you might sing
called voco which is a way of editing
sound as you would edit text so
basically a tool for a kind of public
tool the kind of Photoshop for audio
essentially that allows anyone to kind
of create these kind of things our
entire a lot of our technological
advances seem to be in order to kind of
create and change and mold the fabric of
reality in ways they're not always
visible and transparent to to the
visitor and the outcome of that is a
world in which people don't believe
anything when when complete authority of
any kind of trust in institutions no I'm
no one for blind trust in institutions
either but the fact that when in the UK
you had a referendum and something like
more than 25% of views of participants
believe that was going to be rigged by
the security services is a very worrying
situation to be in and that is a result
of a kind of a crisis of literacy an
inability to deal with these
increasingly complex narratives that are
supplied by our technologies more
information as we saw in the
pharmacological research we've seen the
neural networks doesn't necessarily lead
to better decisions and in fact often
kind of hardens people against them the
sociologists fredric jameson in his work
cognitive mapping described this as
described conspiracy theory in
particular as this attempt cognitively
to map landscapes of information which
is simply too vast for people to grasp
the no one person can hold this entire
system of information inside their head
it's the same problem as big date
it's also the same problem we encounter
every day on the internet because we are
continually faced with stuff that
doesn't map into our model of the world
and that is existentially terrifying
because we're quite weak you know
lizard brained creatures and that we
have not equipped ourselves with
literacy for dealing with complicated
and often paradoxical information and as
a child of the kind of hippie internet
right this is deeply worrying because
for me the internet has always been a
place of incredible emancipatory
possibility a place in which you have
access to all of this information and it
makes the world more comprehensible to
you it gives you grant greater agency
and that allows you to make more social
better ordered whatever your decision
very naive you it turns out okay but a
really important one to get across
because we're living in a world where
information has been increasingly
available for a long time now and is
increasingly riven by fundamentalisms
and deeply entrenched differing points
of view so we need to think very
carefully about what our and what our
responses are what are the new
literacies that we need to build not to
understand more information but to
understand these these differences
between information there was a I took
the title of this talk from a piece in
the New York Times from a few weeks ago
by the director the global weather 4k
global weather foundation a big weather
forecasting agency huge computational
weather forecasting data the full deal
and what he was saying was that
alongside these growth of information
available to us is also huge in
cataclysmic change climate change is now
progressing to such an extent the
atmosphere is warming to such an extent
that the models that we've built based
on the hundreds plus years of weather
data we've been gathering no longer
apply the weather models are actually
getting worse because the underlying
models that generate them no longer work
so well in Inked in a rapidly changing
climate and we're actually moving
towards a place where we're going to
know
less about the world than we did
previously we're going to be able to
predict less and that's going to affect
our ability to prepare for it this no
not that this and I'm running out of
time and I want to take a couple of
questions when I was got them and here's
what I think I don't think the internet
and so much the stuff that we've built
on top of it is a tool for understanding
the world as some kind of abstract
entity that we can regard as a static
and stable rather it's a tool for
understanding our own ability to
understand interact with the world and
it's the most extraordinary complex and
advanced such tool we've built as a
species so me it's a it's a it's a
cultural tool it's something that
emerges like language and writing
emerged and and what's extraordinary bad
is that no person or no single set of
intentions created this thing or
imagined what we might do with it
foresaw its uses it's an unconsciously
generated tool for unconscious
generation and it's this model of
complexity it's kind of cloudy cloud and
if we are to take our kind of
technological understanding of the world
seriously and I feel that we must
recognize that it's teaching us to
expect and understand differences in the
world to understand cloudiness and
complexity and not conformity and
similarity thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you so much James we now have a
couple more minutes to take questions
please use the microphones or show up at
the microphone so I can see you Oh a
bear after anyone it's alright it's not
or beer later is also good okay are you
sure you don't have any questions this
is your chance I think we're good all
right then
thank you very much thank you
[Applause]
[Music]