[Music]
do we need to talk eyes would expand
Frank up short on this activist in a
foreign land kernan when you're talking
to stem max me it i'm surprised me she
also misses Pompeii on SEO traditional
water and trees in the house on one of
them and provide an offer because I
teach your was putting on shoes yeah
damn you see my opinion this happen
against american dollars fun of me other
than would finish with an organ been my
inspiration configurations occurrence is
honorable and decent brushed up from
Miami here once had seats and not since
Pam's ama genius
this is signings yeah activia yogurt and
activists of the Titans East are 0 and
cyclic taboo us to end on went just wide
us in this global science missing
nothing right
welcome to the english translation of
this talk compose freebooters and radio
lockdown and marks me has been an
activist in this field for a long time
is here to tell us about what that is
and what activists can learn he is a
politics political scientist and works
with the Free Software Foundation Europe
and is and lives in the German of
minister for the moment at the moment
and the translators are sebastiaan and
your blast
okay thanks for the introduction and
your attention as I said Apple talking
about the capacity Reuters and radio
lockdown and how you can get politically
active politically active we are in a
sort of paradise of net activism here
one could say the history of the case
Computer Club is the history of of
people that were technical notes and
hackers but went into the political
sphere and tried to change politics with
their technological background and the
that is exactly what the Free Software
Foundation Europe who I work for
does
we are here to make people let people to
be able to control their technology
because in too many cases technology
controls us and we have a lot to do is
politics in that regard of course and i
will be talking about to political well
problems that have accompanied might me
for a long time and are still there and
I will talk about tell you that it's not
that hard to get active politically of
course these are big topics one of them
even in EU topic but there's so many
political problems that exist you just
have to look to us the next community
municipalities that use so much
proprietary software problems that we as
half knowledgeable technology people
notice immediately and i would like to
encourage you to get active yourself and
in the second half of my talk after I've
talked about the rotor the commercial
route Israel out to get us all on the
same level as it were i'd like to talk
about what I took away from this i am
not an absolute political professional
now haven't had decades of it experience
but i have taken quite a lot of things
away things that I think could be used
for any kind of activism and containing
this is about who how to prepare best if
you've identified a topic how do i form
alliances how to find allies and how do
I communicate my issue to the public
what can be done we only have 30 minutes
so it will not go into so much depth but
I hope you'll take something away anyway
and now at the end i will talk about a
few obstacles that you might encounter
that I heard was that could bring the
whole thing down but with a few simple
tricks and the right attitude i think
it's easy to get around this
I'll begin with competitive Reuters who
of you has heard something about
capacitors ok we can skip that slide
I just very very briefly for the one or
two people that put one of two people
that haven't it's about the fact that
losses are forced upon you turn modems
are the kind of pic the guards the door
guides for all the traffic that comes
from me into the world and everything
that goes out until into the internet
maybe TV streams and things like that as
well and until roughly august this year
almost 2016 these devices did not belong
to us in many cases particularly for
cable providers these people to say that
our network includes the rotor and the
rotor is the network termination point
only once I've connected that ethernet
cable to my laptop that smart where the
consumer network begin so everything
from the root or the first murder of the
first device at the wall into the
network was said to belong to the
provider which of course is a fatal
thing because in that case we cannot
control if we cannot swap this device if
we don't have authority over it and it's
bad for our security bad for trust into
this kind of hardware we do not know
what these devices that are basically
black boxes are running it's bad for
innovation because many internet
providers tend to choose the cheapest
modem or router and put it out on the
market and there's no way of off
developing competition for better
devices which we see today was capable
Reuters this market is only still slowly
starting up and there's not much choice
not much innovation space for
compatibility
we have often seen that certain
telephone certain internet technologies
are not compatible the standard devices
that provides give us that in some cases
maybe could be exchanged but in many
cases could not and of course it's bad
for free software because if I operate
ruta and want to operate motor that's
based on first officers such as open dwt
that would not be possible now from
generator 2013 this topic became a topic
for us because and now since August 2016
the law says it's possible to obtain
your own water no matter which kind of
provider using but this process the fact
whether these providers actually go
along with that you know that is
something that steel keeps us busy today
having a good law which fortunately
happened is not enough you have to see
how the implementation works of the law
right next issue again the standard
question for the statistics who of you
has heard something about radio lockdown
ah that's significantly less significant
fewer people now in my opinion this is
actually worse this is a year you a new
directive with the elegant name to
certain 14 / 43 / EU nao this names of
this kind of forbids non-conforming
software on devices prohibits them now
that means software that possibly would
not match with the existing broadcast
regulations sort of signal strength
technologies that certain broadcast
devices have to contain so produces have
to soon as the directive enforce soon as
make us manufacturers actually have to
apply this new law which will be in next
summer July it says
they would basically have to check each
firmware for conformity and if the
firmware is not found to be conforming
or if it's unknown whether it's
conforming they have to ensure that this
firm is not cannot be loaded onto the
device we're talking about any kind of
broadcasting device any device that can
receive or send radio signals not just
Reuters therefore but also smart phones
Wi-Fi chips in laptops gps receivers
everything has to be locked down to
prevent any software running on them
that might break those regulations now
that in effect is a kind of drm of
course it's a lockdown that
manufacturers have to implement by
certain signature list there's a lot of
unclear details here but that of course
keep this very busy because that is very
bad for free software projects for free
flight funk projects that offer Wi-Fi to
the public to open wrt so any kinds of
projects that want to put software and
devices are developed software that is
supposed to be put on devices and there
are many of those so that again is bad
for competition and innovation
it's a very normal business model for
companies to buy finished products and
chops and then put their own software on
it
such as Wi-Fi providers so their
business model is very much in danger
here and it's definitely not a good
thing for a fair competition it's bad
for security because we cannot put our
own firmware that we trust on our
devices and i do not have to tell you
how many security holes there are in
default firmware of of broadcasting
devices and of course it's bad for
sustainability it used to be possible
for Reuters that do not receive updates
anymore to put open wrt on them to
continue using the device in particular
if you have security in mind you would
have to throw devices away as soon as
well if they don't get updates and you
can freshen yourself
so that has been something to do with
since the autumn of 2015 although
different peoples actually passed in
but for a long time it would
unfortunately wasn't noticed and this
will be keeping us busy for a few years
to free for a few years to come and we
hope that the Commission will define
certain classes of devices that will not
be affected by this directive so that
these negative consequences could be
mitigated somewhat so i will now as i
said i will be going through is some
small tricks that I have acquired by
ever that are about getting active
politically that not just applicable to
large projects such as radio lockdown
and composite rules but also for the
smaller projects and activities for
example if you in your municipality want
to push free software because you see
that huge amount of money being spent on
non-free software on restrictive
constant on contracts and you want to
get active Hume maybe think you may be
able to think of thousands of other
examples where you are very clear that
politically something has to be done and
i'll say it again
technical solutions are only a solution
for a short time or of the medium term
if you want to have sustainable change
sustained change you have to get active
politically and it's not too hard to do
if you are prepared well you'll have
done a lot of the work already before
getting active before you pick a topic
or if you have picked up your topic
annoy you know roughly what it should be
then i recommend a realistic and precise
target to find an objective what you
want to achieve often this will be
voluntary work and that you want to put
this in for a clear target this was a
problem with the radio lockdown
we have this directive on the table and
didn't quite know how should we approach
this
how can we mitigate the problem the
director had been passed it have been
through Parliament there's not much to
do realistically
to reverse the whole directive so then
you start finding looking for ways of
precise ways of twisting things a bit
and not and that's important to say do
not define unrealistic targets and if
you can change the whole world tomorrow
have a small target target's that can
change as well very important
it's also sounds trivial but it's very
important collect information and keep
maintaining that information well and
process it well that's what we did with
the capacitors and radar lock down the
knowledge that we acquired over hours of
complicated looking at complex
technological issues we were thinking
about presenting that we had the FSF a
website of course that was an obvious
place but if you get active start a blog
setup we cave for the organizations that
want to work on this so help others to
get into the topic quicker than you have
done
that's how you can collect more
information motivate had people to deal
with the topic educated histological
topics when the topic runs for about two
or three years like this rom problem
with the Rooter beings are required it
helps to have a timeline we disarm with
routing requirements using in
journalists in order to show them when
the topic get started what had happened
what was therefore because people had
later came the economic ministry to it
to contribute to understand all of this
is a little bit difficult so it helps to
have a little bit of a timeline for this
is also a good motivation to see how
much you've already accomplished
another important thing is to have a
have common terminology it's very happy
that with this term for four required
routers has come along in German this
word is very well known and many people
raise their hand when I asked about this
about who noses and its issues for most
people and also from the media not only
from you
it's a little bit more difficult with
the with the directive because it's
coming from the EU and english we call a
radio lockdown but in but in german it's
a little bit more difficult because you
want to try to bring it over across
different different languages and
sometimes it can be a little bit
difficult if you want to become active
try to find such a slogan or term you
can use to describe these things you
have different supporters then it helps
to be able to work altogether
speaking of of supporters it's always
good also to build alliances it doesn't
have to be a huge topic this can also be
a community topic in which you can work
on I can't say it enough
look over the table and look for
uncommon agents uncommon members for
example in on the Congress we won't
probably do much with companies although
they might also find the political
situation not very good for their
company
something try to work also with with
journalists and with NGOs industry
associations we were with associations
with consumer protection people to where
it was about capacity Reuters but also
ready lockdown we work with individual
companies whose complete existence was
threatened by this and it helps them to
to form new networks communication
networks are important we use mailing
lists but many activists prefer
something like slack or IRC channels or
whatever so if you have a few people
that you work with find ways of
activating many people in a very short
time so consider whatever you are
working at find very unique a single
communication channel it's important to
give yourselves feedback for each other
and ask for feedback to for example if
you write a blog entry about the topic
that you are busy with it it's was
asking supporters are completely new
people what they think about that and if
there are things that you do not
completely know about yet things that
you're not quite sure about how to deal
with certain information for example
things that go overhead in a way to get
others involved it's good and we did
this with the rotor lockdown we had this
whole contract or all the differences
legal texts from the European Parliament
that's not the most exciting kind of
nighttime nectar not the shortest either
so it'sit's legalese basically and of
course I'm not a great expert on this I
had to ask people and ask what does this
means there are still things that are
unclear to us about the way such a
directive should be interpreted
and work with this in an offensive
proactive way and say this is clear to
us already but this site don't quite
understand yet and turn this into a kind
of critique if that's appropriate
it's ideal if you could find get others
involved in actions it was quite
difficult with the rotor lockdown
believe radio lockdown directly was hard
to find people who we we could tell what
to do because they factor it the law
existed we were dealing with the federal
network agency in Germany and I about
the bed capacity which is it was very
hard to define what people could do now
that we have the law since the first of
august and your final that includes can
be chosen freely by people we have well
we actually found an action that we
could do to get others involved will be
sent out test devices and ask them to to
experiment whether these devices would
work on their connections so that can
generate more echo and get more people
informed about the new opportunities and
of course is good for us to get some
some feedback
does it work can you now use the new law
and and link connecting devices it does
it is possible in any case we found but
we couldn't have found it in any other
way
concerning radio lockdown we had a
public statement wrote up a few
paragraphs about the whole topic our
demands and thanks to a fantastic idea
of 5 from friends
I the whole thing turned into a public
letter that detto organizations and
companies could sign and that now give
us 40 institutions that are supporting
our demands and that at the same time is
a huge foundation to find supporters and
alliances and if you have something like
that with the topic like you want to
work on that is very very big thing to
have
in general to trust very short essay
petitions online petitions is not
something that we have a lot of
experience with and it's important to
not let those petitions peter out as it
were and if you haven't got the support
base and try to start an online petition
from from scratch out of thin air
it might just fail and could actually
result in your wasting a lot of time
that is my experience at least maybe
others have had some other experience
the last point and maybe the most
important one is communication
you also have to do everything you're
working on you have to bring it to
others and and therefore you have to ask
for who should this be why am i doing
all of this am I doing this only for
myself or my doing this for my friends
or for our hacker space but maybe also
thinking a little bit further
maybe there are other about other people
who would also be interested in this and
then you can try to find arguments for
why this would be interesting to other
people
once you've found some something you've
broken all up then it's nice to try to
quickly build a description of this
using the three-sentence role you want
to describe your topic in three
different sentences and it is what's it
about
why is it important and then how can we
actually solve this was an option that
we can use in order to solve this
problem and we can do this in three
different sentences then we can reuse
that for everything if we're talking to
journalists if we're talking to
colleagues but also possibly in other
works as well love articles
so even if the things get very complex
you can always see it broken down into
these three sentences in particular if
you want to talk to journalists as i
said this can be the local journalist
from from the small paper have as next
an interesting story to tell them this
was quite easy with capacity Reuters
because as soon as we noticed that there
were public statements and hearings and
individual statements we heard that the
330 people that had art to the first
public consultation only about a handful
of the answers was in favor of kumasi
Reuters and the rest more than three and
people were against it including
companies of course that means that the
story was quite simple to tell all
citizens are basically against
compulsory Reuters most companies are
and only a very small handful such as
the net internet providers and and
network operators are in favor of it now
this is of course of fantastic David
against Goliath story and if you have
something like that it's a very good
introduction to give to journalists a
good hook for them to use and that
motivates you and in this way you can
keep giving updates and keep the whole
issue going now I'm praise and critique
is very important
praise is underrated when it came to the
composite Reuters the economic ministry
the federal ministry in Germany which
took away leadership of the whole
associate away from the network agency
probably the one happy with the
publication that made and they then
drafted law which was surprisingly good
we were wondering ourselves how this
kind of full you turn could have taken
place because what the network actually
had written had been quite disappointing
and that we praise not overwhelmingly
but it's important not to forget to
sometimes give praise to politicians to
authorities administrations
to critique of as well of course but
that's more easy to do for activists and
last but not least get out of the filter
but the one that you build yourselves
this series are huge fans of trouble I
can tell you
ninety percent of the people hundred
percent of the people are against
compulsory reuters/andrew lockdown
I couldn't say from the people in this
room but what about the rest of the
ninety-nine point nine percent of the
general population keep trying to find
new actors new agents have been over
running slightly but just PP to go to
the obstacles
what can happen I something that will
probably happen is that you are
suffering from information overload and
what of course helps there is to find
partners as early as possible that you
can work with all if necessary I kind of
reduce the topic you can't always cover
everything you can't always achieve
everything so pick a particular aspect
and keep working on that and maybe then
extend from that later if you have more
resources
what can also happen is that there is no
interest area that there is a difference
in the public the rotor thing was kind
of slow at first were rotors yeah
everyone has a little bit who knows
really what they are a large part of the
population don't and what helps there is
to link it to another topic which was
what was which was very good was the
whole Snowden affair that then came up
where the security aspect could be
linked if you have free software in in
public administration that you want to
support you could talk about tax
squandering tax money being squandered
taxpayers money and if there is progress
particular programs if the positive
progress interest can quickly increase
they were for a long time there was
hardly anything of the expert press were
popular things but then towards august
we had to torture site computer build so
large general and large computer papers
more
this every important paper so you
wouldn't believe how quickly things can
get going and what can also happen is
that there are phases of boredom that
cannot be avoided you can kind of bridge
them by working on something else and
maybe do some preparation work God the
radio lockdown thing there was not a lot
that could be done for a long time we're
kind of in midair not quite knowing
where to go but then things can make
take a turn very quickly talking very
lockdown to have been a few
opportunities that have shown up we will
probably be able to join the working
group or the expert group for the
Commission the EU Commission and the
whole thing has got momentum again and i
hope that we can keep their pick up on
that and then and make it stronger so
keep going and know that these things
can happen
we haven't got too many too much time
for discussion but please go to the FSF
assembly which i think is on the first
floor and at nineteen thirties after
this there will be a session on radio
lockdown where we will try to bring as
many organizations in as we can
organizations that want to work on this
kind of working meeting tomorrow then
there'll be a follow-up to this to that
meeting community wife is your night at
night at 19 hours 7pm and also very nice
a lightning talk from scientific working
look at the technical university of
dumpsters who might had not heard about
at all they are holding a lightning talk
about the same topic and they'll be
saying why this is very bad from a
scientific point of view so again I'll
invite you to be there I'll go there
myself thanks for your attention
yeah Hank inspired and beanie thing is
gonna show you this week so if you have
questions we don't have much time left
for them but go to the microphone and
the signal agent has a question from the
internet we have multiple questions from
the internet we're gonna start with the
first someone to asking as a radio
amateur how does it look you because
some of these some of these rules with
the UH the radio is trying to how does
it look then with a looking to control
one on airport the answers i would like
to say that in the directive for the
radio shot down there is a risk there is
a exception for amateurs there
this would allow many to experiment as
well so devices it's not suffering from
from this lockdown
I of course will make it harder for
radiometers to get good hardware and and
our position of course is that that is a
very bad thing and we want to have as
many exceptions from that directive as
we possibly can
everyone is another question
ok i will be the person holding the
lightning talk tomorrow about that
scientific initiative and i would like
to add it's not just about why it's bad
for science for scientists but also what
we can do and we have a common statement
that we prepared and we are looking for
scientific groups that want to work on
devices of all kinds and would like to
be able to continue working so if you
have are in a scientific back with us
working with this with a scientific
background come to that like to talk or
talk to me all go to the cows villa
assembly which is where r pamphlets are
ok so if someone has is doing scientific
work please approach this young man
ok signal ancient showing up again with
the last question someone ask about the
legal situation about dongles on devices
how it does that is not compatible with
property law
good question property law is I as I'm
not a legal expert but I don't think
it's a huge obstacle because the devices
are not going to be in giving documents
in retrospect these are devices that are
sold with Donald so if i buy a device
like this and i know that restriction
like this is in force on the device then
legally is probably not a problem
because I knew this when i boarded the
lockdown isn't brought in at a later
stage which doesn't make the whole thing
much better but i don't think there's a
drop a problem with property law
unfortunately
okay thank you another applause for
Mark's me please
[Applause]
[Music]