my name is Jojo from Fudan University
and today I am going to talk about some
vulnerabilities in the mainstream mobile
payment systems so we knew that mobile
payments it's so popular today and the
over in in lost a year over 660 point
seven trillion u.s. dollar transactions
what was conducted by a channel solely
in China and besides China mobile
payments are also available in a lot of
countries like India the USA and with
mobile payments you cannot only cannot
only eat at restaurant pay pay bills to
taxi driver and go shopping but also
call a lot in a lot of scenarios and the
mobile payment services were operated by
now to only financial companies but also
internet accompanies for the financial
company there are usually banks and card
associations and an internet accompany
includes something like Ali pay and a 10
cent and I don't know if you know that
mobile payments usually don't use
Network because personally a lot of
transactions just to happen indoors
whether the saludo network is not good
and Wi-Fi it so I find the more is
usually not available for guests and in
a network initialization it's always a
very slow process so if each transaction
is should be conducted through the
internet there must be a relevant long
period of loading time for instance for
each transaction so the mobile payments
give me designers just decided to not
use network even if there is Network to
avoid delays and this is a
widely deployed an offline payment
scheme diagram to do a payment the
payment application firstly generate a
piece of token for the user the token is
generated by hashing the time the
current time the user ID and the secret
key pre-shared between the user and the
mobile service provider in the token
will be modulated to one of the channel
the channels can be something like QR
code audio channel or just post machine
channel and then the smartphone well
transmitted token by other channels and
then the token will be received by the
vendor through the channel and then the
vendor will decode to token from the
from the receive the signal and then
pass the token to a back-end server for
verification the server where firstly
check if the token is indeed generated
by the claim the user by retrieving the
secret key from the database using the
user ID claim divided by the account
associated with the token and then use
exactly the same hash algorithm to
generate a token and then compare the
generated token with the received a
token if they are exactly the same that
means the token is indeed generated by
err authenticated authenticating the
user and then check if the token is
already used the token is designed for
one-time use only so if the token were
already mapped by the server by the
server the token is regarded as a valid
editon then check the generation time a
token has a relatively short period
purity of lifetime usually some minutes
or half an hour so if the term if the
token was generated alone ago it cannot
be used a to do a transaction
and we found out there oddly there are
at least the two weak points for the
offline payment schemes first one is
that the token transmission is in
broadcaster channel indicating that
there's no encryption during the
transaction during the transmission and
the de token can be sniffed by nearby
adversaries and the second the token is
not bounded with a specific transaction
so anyone snifter the token can use the
token to purchase at another place with
with with money up to the daily limit
but the security is not that bad
assuming that someone its purchasing
using the mobile payment to the mobile
phone general token for the user and
then transmit a token while a
broadcaster channel the token can be
received by the post machine and the can
also be sniffed at by inaudible by an
attacker
however the post machine will
immediately sent to token to backpack in
the server for verification and
immediately the token is invalidated
because the tokens for one-time use only
so the sneak the token is immediately
invalidated and it cannot be used to
purchase some things and another place
however we found that if we somehow can
disconnect the post machine from the
back in the server the sniff the token
can be kept alive in it to tune an
attack but for practical attack how can
how can attack a sniffer token why at
the physical channel the check out the
channel including wireless signal audio
and a QR code and so we devised at least
one sniffing scheme for each channel in
a second the second question is how to
interrupt the ongoing transaction
because if the ongoing transaction
not interrupted the token will be
verified by the server and then
immediately invalidate it now and we
targeted at the mobile post machine and
the vending machine is too kind of post
machines whether the transaction can be
easily interrupted and we also tried
locally our method to to interrupt the
transaction and a remotely method and
then the last question is how to spend a
token how to spend a sniff the token had
another place the first two problems are
all soft and the last problem is now
they're difficult to solve and we talk
to the four kinds of payment the first
one is MST based mobile payment MST
based mobile payment payments is popular
in the in the USA because the vendors in
USA are hesitated to update their post
machines to support all kinds of new
newly emerging mobile payments so most
of vendors in the USA are still using
the traditional magnetic strip card post
machine and that they don't update
however a company named the loop page
just found that the post machine come a
post machine comes with a magnetic ahead
to sense the data stored in a magnetic
strip cart when a user swipes magnetic
strip cart the magnetic strip which is
in fact magnetic materials will
stimulate the magnetic hat inside the
post machine which is consisted of which
consists of a coil and and magnetic
circle magnifico ring we know that the
swiping magnetic strip will generate
over a magnetic of
and at a coil when it's exposed to a
variety a field where generate
electricity current and a current it's
just the signal representing a data
stored in the magnetic strip cards so a
mobile phone company just acquired the
the the company devising an MST and to
use the the maps MST to make mobile
payments the phone is encrypted with a
coil the coil was also used to to
wireless charging and when the mobile
phone user used the mobile phone to make
a payment the move the mobile phone will
generate a token and then modulate the
token to electricity signal and then use
the electricity signal to drive the coil
and then end another coil of the mobile
phone will generate magnetic field and
the magnetic field will stimulate the
coil of the magnetic hat inside an post
machine so the traditional post machine
which was designed to support magnetic
field court only can be used to do
mobile payment so in the earth scheme a
user need only put his mobile phone near
to a post machine and then the post
machine will complete the token
broadcast process and then the post
machine can receive the token and send
it to back in the server for a vacation
and once the transaction is approved the
post machine just will feel as if some a
user is swiping a traditional magnetic
strip card in a print asleep for the
user we found that the scheme was
claimed to work only in a 3 inch
distance which means the token can only
be received in as in around 7
centimeters however with our man-made
coil antennae we successfully received
it a token and two meters away from the
from the mobile phone which means an
attacker if only he is standing near by
the batter the counter he can't sleep
the token and then a lot of post
machines are eventually mobile post
machine indicating at the post machine
is connected to the back and a server
via wireless channel which can be easily
jammed using the commercial jammer so
when the channel between the mobile
posts and back in the server it's
interrupted the sniff the token can be
kept alive and it can be transferred to
another place to the clutter of the
attacker for spending the clutter need
only use a very simple magnetic strip
caught writer to write the readers need
the token into a piece of blank magnetic
strip card and adjusted swipe the card
at another counter to purchase things
and those pictures show the devices we
use to launch attack the the left and
most one is a computer as well as well
as well as the coil antenna the coil
antenna is connected to the computer via
the 3.5 millimeter jacket audio jacket
in the left and the right picture is a
commercial jammer which is purchased at
watch on Los inch engine and that this
device can selectively Jam wireless
channels such as GSM Wi-Fi CDMA pcs pcs
and then the middle one is a commercial
strip card writer
it can help attackers to write to write
any data into the into a blank magnetic
strip card
the cost of the attack it's very very
cheap around twenty to thirty US dollar
and the second target is a sound pay
sound page waddly deployed by vending
machines because of its low cost the
vending machine need only add a recorder
to support this kind of mobile payment
when a user is going to use sound pay
his mobile phone where general piece of
token and then modulates the token into
a clip of audio and then the mobile
phone were played the audio the audio
can be recorded by the vending machine
and then the token can be decoded and
then the running machine just to send
the token to back-end server for
verification
usually it's via a little network
because people may move the vending
machine from one place to another so
usually it is not widely connected and
similarly we found out this token can
also be sniffed a piety or attack by
simply just turning on recorder and the
connection between the server and the
vending machine can just also be jammed
by the jammer and the recorded token can
just be replayed by playing the recorded
audio to purchase another vending
machine and the left are two attacks are
based on QR code
Yuriko dates are extremely popular
payment method and that there are two
modes for QR code mobile payments first
ones b-2s mode in which a phone just the
scans the QR code printed by the vendor
to pay to the vendor in a second is b2l
mode where a pair just presents the QR
code generated by his mobile phone under
the post scanner of the vendor to pay
and there our work based on the the
second type b2l mode so the cure code is
generated by the mobile phone carry a
token okay the first question is how to
sniff a live QR code token this is a
picture taken by the front camera of a
mobile phone we know that from the right
side picture we know that the token the
QR code token can just a be sniffed by
watching the reflection from the post
scanner so the attacker need only in in
fact the victim by installing a malware
and the malware need only turned on the
front camera during the transaction so
the QR code is reflected and captured by
the front camera but a more important
question is how to keep the QR code
alive because if no special measures is
taken the QR code will be simultaneously
scanned by the post machine and be used
to do verification so it will be
validated immediately so the malware
need only draw a white block over the
positioning marker of the QR code
because one of the positioning mark of
the QR code is it's overlaid so the QR
code can no longer be scanned by the
post machine scanner
however the token is still there
so the tokens kept alive in this way and
in a pure coat cure called image through
the glass of the so we're the length of
the Karaka of the reposed scanner can be
sent to the Cluedo of the attacker for
spending besides this the attack we have
also found a security flaw of the QR
code payment the QR codes can carrying a
payment token it's meant to be very
sensitive because anyone with this token
can make a purchase however in the
implementation the QR code is also user
used as a name card for many transfer
which means the payment of QR code can
be scanned by post machine to make
opponent make a payment also you can
also be scanned by your friend if your
friend want to transfer money to you and
he doesn't know your account number and
we found that during this process one
could it be attacked even if he is never
infected with malware if you just use a
face-to-face money transfer and he's
payee if the the payer just your friends
is infected because the malware inside
malware inside the payer can have the
same UI as the mobile payment and when
malware detects detected that the
authentic the authentic mobile payment
app is in the for front and the camera
is being you is being using the mobile
payment is scanning and the malware just
jumps to the forefront to capture a live
QR code and more importantly how to keep
the QR code alive the malware can out
creat
immediately because if if the malware
quit immediately the code the token will
be consumed by the authentic payment
application but if the mail well stay
here the process will be noticed by the
user because the transaction is not
going home so the mail well need only
launch a bluetooth pairing process by
launching a bluetooth pairing process
the the mobile phone of the payee will
show or a confirmation window to ask the
user to confirm the pairing process and
then immediately the mail will cancel
this process so the window where this
disappear this process may only remain
for hundreds of milliseconds which means
there will be only a flash in the
victims mobile phone and then the left
token it's neat and kept alive because a
new token is generated in the victim's
phone because the mobile payment mobile
payment application in the victim's
phone it's put into background and then
poor to the foreground so a new QR code
is generated and at this new generated
QR code will be used to continue the
normal transaction ok after we finish
that for tax we report it to their
service providers including the the
largest mobile payment service provider
in China and adapt service provider
immediately revoked the payment
application cured the payment QR code as
named cart around a week after we our
report and for the reflection attack
they commit it
you do a background check to ensure that
there is no background application using
the front camera when a transaction is
ongoing and we learned a lot from those
attacks the payment token it's so
sensitive
so you should be too you should be
carefully treated when it's being
transmitted to the mobile post machine
he shouldn't be transmitted over a
simply simplex channel that doesn't have
challenge response process and there
must be anti sniffing protections and
the token should be bound to a
transaction when is generated in that
case even if our tokens
it's sniffed by an attacker the attacker
can expand it add another place okay
that's all of the presentation thank you
for your time in any question
[Applause]