our name is Dan we work at the Atlas
insecurity team over in Sydney we're
gonna be talking to you today about
breach detection at scale with AWS honey
tokens I would like to say I really
appreciate you all actually being here
and not in the reception drinking free
beer right now we will understand if you
have to leave so we're just gonna start
with what we hope are the two stupidest
things you see at this conference today
at least on stage if you anything you
see at an after-party is your own
business okay so what I'm about to do is
generate an annotated AWS credential so
the location that I'll store these
credentials will be on screen at
security conference and the order of
these credentials will be anyone in the
room I guess okay
ideally we are there we go okay so these
are some live AWS credentials you can
use them if you like I'll just
demonstrate that there they're live
it's surely the cameras got it
and what are you doing now down I'm just
checking that they're actually alive
once I can remember how to spell let's
see alright cool so you can see these
are some live creds there for a user in
the spacecraft group the user is called
eight eight three nine something cool
but yeah don't worry about writing those
down because we're now gonna do the
second and dumber thing and just like
put them on paste bin let's go alright
so that'll be on paste bins recent paste
feed for the next like fifteen minutes
if you want them the yours okay we're
doing a talk we should probably do the
talk over to Dan who's gonna explain
what we're actually doing with our lives
I might come over here so how many
people in the room are familiar with
honey tokens okay okay tough crowd
alright this is not a honey token it's a
honey coin it could be a good investment
but I probably suggest you don't buy it
but if you want to send me money anyway
that's fine you can go ahead and do that
so what is a honey token so honey token
is just any form of credential or thing
or resource that you use that you do
monitoring and logging on but doesn't
exist anywhere else like in in practical
terms so in general use
they won't exist so honey token can be
anything from an email address that
doesn't belong to anyone and it's just a
generally available it can be a DNS name
that no one should ever resolve it can
be a URL that no one ever visits but
generally anything that in practice in
the real or doesn't get touched only
gets touched where and say an attacker
finds it
and thinks it's a little bit weird sorry
we're just having some trouble with this
lady speaker notes Oh mr. B down there
so AWS keys so AWS keys are really
interesting for a few reasons first of
all they're they you access the AWS API
when you want to do any action in AWS
and that's really nice because the API
is globally accessible internet
accessible it's always on it's never off
and really to do any any action at all
you have to use this API it's the keys
AWS keys are generally extremely
valuable so an attacker might find them
and they might realize they're the keys
to your kingdom
they might control your entire internet
infrastructure for example and they get
generated a lot just in everyday use
right so as an SRE you lead them to
manage your AWS infrastructure as a user
you need them to log in if you're doing
an integration with a third-party
service but the AWS keys are required so
they just exist everywhere and then they
can do pretty much anything anything
that you can do through the API which is
everything in AWS although the credits
can do and then finally the last thing
is attackers look for these things right
so whenever some some account gets
compromised for example like when we see
a HipChat or straight account getting
compromised one of the first things that
attackers do is look for a ki a which is
the the prefix for most AWS access case
so what they're really looking for is
how can I get another credential that
gets me to pivot to something else
something different something more how
many of you guys know what this is right
it's we call them strategies in
Australia some other places they're
called
instant lottery tickets but they have
some really nice unique properties which
are very similar to AWS access keys that
being
that in order to find out if you've won
anything like if you've won the prize
you have to scratch the lottery ticket
and so for an attacker or anyone else
who finds an access key what they have
to do is that there's no other way to
find out if it's useful if it's in fact
the keys to the kingdom as an example
other than to use the access case and
that's the only way you find out so you
effectively have to scratch the lottery
ticket which is your AWS access key
there's there's generally no downside to
scratching them and/or using the access
key and the prize for an attacker
generally is you can spin up as many ec2
instances as you want to mined Bitcoin
whenever you want another great property
of these things is that they're
everywhere I don't know if you can see
that but they're in places like a text
file on your CEOs CIOs desktop that says
AWS root access keys CSV do not delete
super important or wherever else you
might put them you might put them in
your in your startup variables on a
server for example some people put them
in there in their github their public
did hub repositories and then find lots
of Bitcoin mining going on in their
accounts but they're generally
everywhere yep so I guess the final
property that we really care about is
that while they while these access keys
might be the keys to the kingdom they
don't have to be AWS provides a really
complex and full-featured policy
infrastructure like access management
infrastructure which means that you can
basically say hey this access key can't
be used for anything the policy that you
seen on see on screen effectively says
for all actions on all resources we're
going to deny access so this this so any
access key that has this policy
basically can't do anything except for
one thing and that's the call that Dan
made at the start of this talk which is
get caller identity which is effectively
the hue
of AWS the AWS API so you can set this
policy and the other nice thing that
will happen is AWS has a full-featured
logging capability and so all of these
deny or allow actions will get logged
and then you can do something with them
so going back to our scratchy metaphor
we have we have a the properties that we
care about the access keys are really
valuable they're ubiquitous they're
everywhere attackers will find them so
they won't think they're weird and
they're really easy to secure and have a
really detailed logging infrastructure
so the only difference now if we make
them honey tokens is effectively that
instead of the prize being you get to
mine Bitcoin everywhere if you scratch
the key the prize is for being a honey
token is that you get caught so that's
nice for us but not so nice for the
attackers okay so this is really nice if
you want to generate a single access
token and put it on your size of desktop
there's a really easy way to do that a
company called think'st has provided a
free to use website called canary tokens
and you can just go there type set AWS
access key type in some metadata about
it hit the generate button it'll give
you an access key and you can put it on
your size those desktop that's really
nice you can do the same thing for other
types of honey tokens like the ones we
mentioned before like a word document
DNS host name URL and that kind of thing
this is really great for when you want
to do individual instances of honey
tokens but you might have noticed that
how the talk of our title was breach
detection at scale so obviously one-off
instances is kind of not what we want so
what if you want to do this on thousands
of machines or you have thousands of
managers in your company and you want to
place a honey token on each of their
desktops so
there there before we looked into this
there was no real way to do this at
scale so in order to address these
scaling problems that we were running
into we we made project space crab and
for the avoidance of any doubt dan has a
very important thing to say about space
crab you will notice that the crab is
not in space the space is inside the
crab and it's very important I don't
know I just work here
ok so project space crab is an AWS
CloudFormation stack CloudFormation
stack is just a set of instructions that
tells AWS what to do it deploys a couple
of things that we care about the first
one is a data store which we use to
store the annotations that you saw us
adding to credentials earlier some
policies including the denial token
policy that you saw on screen before
some lambdas and when lambdas are just
Python scripts that AWS runs for you an
alerting pipeline and an API gateway the
API gateway is just a HTTP wrapper in
front of some of those lambdas so edible
us excuse me space crab lets you make
annotated AWS keys that have no access
to do anything at scale so the pieces of
metadata that we collect like the
location so where it's being stored the
onus or whose problem is it if somebody
uses this token and any miscellaneous
notes have you saw that earlier in my
demo all the keys get the denial policy
as we mentioned if anyone ever tries to
use one of those credentials all of
those actions get logged into an s3
bucket and then one of the many many
lambdas that we've written processes
through that log looks for keys that it
knows about and if it finds one grabs
the extended metadata attributes from
the data store and pushes them into an
alerting pipeline that alerting pipeline
is basically on the edge there another
couple of lambdas you can use those to
send yourself an email or log the
send an email that goes into your
ticketing system or paid you on page of
duty or really anything else that you
can write a lambda function to do we
haven't written any more alerting
options because those are the ones that
we want but if you would like to have a
different alerting thing this is an open
source project you can contribute to it
today once you've generated the stack
you can generate up to 10,000 tokens the
reason for that limit is that AWS has a
per account user limit of 5,000 users
and each user can have two tokens we
asked them can we get more users can we
get more tokens per user and they
laughed at us and told us to go away so
if you need to generate more than 10,000
tokens you'll need to spin up a second
AWS account but 10,000 tokens is enough
to cover your fleet of workstations or
you know micro services for your cloud
service that you run or to put an
individual record in everybody's like
online password saving service that they
use or your third-party logging
analytics okay so you might have some
questions about this and we're going to
just do a little Q&A here it would try
it head off any of the questions that
you might have sir this one's mine down
deep artificial intelligence powered by
mache on
I'm currently being paged okay let's
thank you veggie for informing me that I
used my token earlier today so I'm just
trying to get to this second tab but I
cannot find the mouse where is it okay
just so for an example
if I reload this there will be a page of
duty incident
right so that's resolved so you can see
here the notes that I put in hi mum the
action that I took with this with this
token and the user identity principle ID
the metadata that we added to that thing
and the source IP address which is an
extremely useful thing to know if
somebody is touching your infrastructure
okay all right back to the thought
leadership I wasn't finished down let's
let's just skip to the next one all
right all right so how do I set up space
crap okay setting up space crab is is
fun and relatively easy go to this URL
clone the repository and basically
follow the instructions in the readme
and the slides will be up later so you
don't worry about writing stuff down
unless you want to so inside the
repository there's a script called
manager dot PI it asks you a bunch of
questions like who what's the AWS user
who owns this what's your page of duty
events key fill out those things and
wait about 45 minutes and the stack will
get spun up and then you will have a
functional deployed stack all right so
if I've deployed the stack how do i
generate tokens to put them somewhere
that's a really great question Dan and
I'm glad you asked it depends entirely
on your infrastructure so if you have a
fleet management interface for your work
stations like Casper if you use max or a
bunch of PowerShell scripts and some
GPIO stuff if you've run Windows you can
get those to run a script that pulls
down credentials from space crab and
stores them somewhere on disk so here
which is entirely unreadable sorry about
that
is a bash script that I wrote for Casper
to do exactly that thing it hits an API
gateway that you get from the spacecraft
stack generates tokens stores them on
disk but maybe you don't want to put
them on your workstations you maybe want
to put them on your cloud like your
micro services so you just put a similar
thing to this somewhere in your
deployment
pipeline for your microservices or you
can write a script to like generate
these and email them to your CEO for
some reason or run them through your
third-party logging Analytics JavaScript
that you have on all of your corporate
websites for some reason and see who's
reading those logs it's entirely up to
you Patrick gray has a suggestion print
them out put them on a post-it note and
stick them on a monitor for the next
time you have a video interview in your
room that's maybe not very scalable so
but if we tell people that we're using
honey tokens doesn't that make them
useless dan I mean probably not if a red
teamer or god forbid an actual hacker
finds some credentials lying around on
your cisors desktop and doesn't use them
because they're afraid they're a honey
token then you you win basically it's
not what you wanted those honey tokens
to do which is tell you that that person
is there but you still you know you
still win if they walk away from valid
credentials
so here's chubs one of our Australian
bug bounty Kings who is terrified of
honey tokens which is fantastic all
right then I'm a manager I want to know
how much this thing costs it's a very
important question and so our enterprise
scale spacecraft deployments cost
between 200 and 300 dollars a week which
i think is under even your purchasing
limit yeah yeah okay so once you've
deployed space crab and you've
effectively secured your perimeter
you've secured your squishy inside bits
as well you might you'll have a lot of
free time on your hands and you'll
probably get bored and you might want to
know what do people actually do with
lete credentials if they find them on
the Internet
so we set up some infrastructure to test
this because again we had a lot of spare
time we spun up a separate AWS account
that didn't have any of our production
data in it it's probably a good idea
just generally and we ran a little
script in that every half an hour and
the script would go to space crab
generator token
and then put a token in github gist's or
in a github repository or finally on
pastebin so the first thing that we
learned when we started doing this is
that AWS monitors github public repos
very closely if you put a lot of keys in
your public github repos AWS will open a
lot of support cases about the keys that
you put in your public github repo they
do that about 30 times per account
before they basically write you off as
an idiot and stop doing that the second
thing that we learned is that if you
ignore those support cases for long
enough
someone from Seattle will call you the
day after Christmas is their time to say
hey Dan what are you doing with all
these compromised keys and when you say
oh no it's fine I did it on purpose
I want those to be there they say ok
thanks I'll have to get back to you and
then the third thing that we learned is
that posting hundreds of keys to the
Internet is against the AWS Terms of Use
and we have to stop so we unfortunately
could only run this experiment for like
a week and a half before we were told to
you know delete your account basically
so yeah we didn't run this for as long
as we wanted to I also like to say that
all the people I talked to at AWS were
like super useful and super helpful and
thought this research was cool and also
that I should stop and delete my account
so in our sadly truncated research we
found that there are exactly two kinds
of people who use compromised AWS
accounts the first one will find some
credentials lying around in github and
put them in like a GUI s3 bucket
browsing program and they'll try and
list bucket since when they see that
they can't list any buckets they just
give up they lack discipline the second
kind will collect all of the credentials
that he finds and then puts it put them
in a Python script that they wrote and
try every API that AWS offers
so they're not necessarily interested in
listing buckets or just spinning up ec2
instances they'll also try and find all
of the weird little information
disclosure vectors that you might be
able to get with an AWS key that they
can then use to spin up ec2 instances
and like mine Bitcoin there might be
other types of people if you run this
experiment for more than a week but
those are the two that we saw so here's
some exciting statistics on github if
you post your credentials to a public
github repo or to a public github gist
there's a pretty much an 83% chance that
someone is going to use those and they
will use them 30 minutes exactly after
you post them I have no idea why it's 30
minutes exactly but it's 30 minutes plus
or minus a couple of seconds every time
we do this it's maybe something to do
with how github search works but I I
don't know if you have any ideas please
tell me because it confuses me a lot on
the other hand pastebin has a completely
different exploitation profile so only
9% of the tokens that we stored on
pastebin actually were attempted to be
exploited and that's a better hit rate
than I've had in some commercial secret
storage services that I've used
personally so they spin is a great place
to store your secrets so paste bin
pastes also just have a different
exploitation profile generally when you
post something to pay spin 50 or 60 IP
addresses around the world immediately
scrape that because they're constantly
scraping the front page of paste bin but
if it falls off the front page you
basically can't find it for generally
about 15 days because paste bin only
updates its paste to Google search like
once a month or so and people are
grabbing these immediately but they're
not acting on them as quickly so with
github you post it someone uses it
immediately they're done
but with paste bin we saw times between
a little bit more than 12 hours up to
nearly two days later before somebody
actually tried to use them which means
if you're in a competitive intelligence
thing there's probably a market gap for
scraping stuff on pastebin and telling
people about it
free product idea go for your life okay
the most secure place that I found to
post credentials on the Internet
is just put them in a picture on Twitter
I put the words unhackable
infrastructure in a tweet and nobody
cared enough to like look at it and go
down your see code is awful they're like
six different uh C's right there and
also there's there's like an API key
right at the bottom of that picture
which I personally found extremely
disappointing but if you need to store
something secret put it on a low traffic
Twitter account okay
we do not have a strong finish
unfortunately but we do have some calls
to action the first is use honey tokens
put them around your network you'll
learn horrible things and it'll be fun
and it's mostly pretty easy and also
please contribute to space crap it's an
open-source project it's on bit bucket
you can fork it and give us suggestions
for making our JSON less horrible or add
new alerting mechanisms if that's
something that you're interested in
Thanks does anyone have any questions or
everyone wants to go to the reception
and drink the free beer okay I'm with
you thanks everyone