hi good afternoon everyone welcome to
the talk new compact vulnerabilities in
Linux device drivers this is a twenty
five minutes
talk so just ignore the schedule outside
my name is chen foo and that is my
colleague comfy
we are security researcher and
developers at by dou X lab they have
been focused on mobile IOT and Linux
kernel security our major work is
developing security solutions for
Baidu's a ice platforms besides that we
also do some security researchers
including finding vulnerabilities in
linux kernel and device drivers in last
year Humphrey and I got more than 30
Linux kernel and device driver series
this is our agenda first we will
introduce the concept of compact and the
security risks of combat then we will
introduce some compact vulnerabilities
found in the past few years and we will
introduce how we found a new type of
compact one abilities in Linux device
drivers after that we will give some
advices and medications to developers
and security researchers at last we will
have some conclusions ok let's start
compat is the 32-bit compatibility mode
in 64-bit Linux kernels on a 64-bit
Linux system when the 32-bit user a user
space program makes a system call the
compact version of the system called
entry is used instead of sorry instead
of the original 64-bit system called
entry in general the reason that Linux
kernel use compact mode system call is
to handle the differences in the data
sizes as we know many system costs have
parameters with different sizes in
32-bit and 64-bit system for example a
structure parameter in the Cisco may
have a pointer type or long type field
in it
their size our platform dependent so
when the 32-bit user space program makes
a system call and passes parameters into
kernel compact mode system call will
first convert the values of these
parameters into corresponding 6 to
64-bit values this is an example of set
time of days is called on the left side
there is the 64-bit system call on the
right side there's the compact mode
system call we can see on the left that
a user time value structure is directly
copied into kernel time value structure
using copy from user and on the right
you can see that the type of user
parameter which is compact time value
and the kernel structure which is time
value they are different so the compact
version uses a function called compact
get time value to convert user compat
stamp value structure to kernel time
value structure also from this case we
can notice that there are two placate
duplicate codes in these two functions
we can see that this part of codes are
the same so from this example we can
notice some potential security risks of
compact code the first a security risk
is code redundancy actually code
redundancy is common in many compact
mode system called implementations in
Linux kernel which means two similar
copies of code and data structures need
to be maintained with no doubt this
maintenance efforts introduce more
security risks and furthermore compared
to original 64-bit system calls their
compact counterpart you really have some
additional definition of data structures
and additional type tab conversion and
additional
data processing logic which exposed new
attack surfaces to user mode processes
in the past few years there are some but
not too many compatible abilities has
been discovered almost all of them are
found in device drivers we think there
are two reasons first compared to the
number of system calls the number of
device drivers are much more and
secondly device drivers usually have to
handle more complex data structures than
normal system calls and the most common
route costs of this vulnerabilities is
the inconsistency between compact and
non compact mode there are two types of
inconsistency are the first is the
inconsistency of data structure
definition and the second one is the
inconsistency of user input validation
logic let's see some examples this is an
example of inconsistency of data
structure definition in this case the
left one and DP layer committee 132 is
the 32-bit user space data structure
while the right one MDP Kevon is the
corresponding 64-bit kernel space
structure the two structures have almost
the same definition making it seems easy
to convert however the real field we can
see that that a refilled reserved in
these two structures have different size
this should have be the same but
developer made a mistake so the one in
the left is larger than one in the right
and then when kernel costs mem copy to
copy data from the larger one to the
smaller one there's a stack overflow
in this case we can see the
inconsistency of user input validation
logic this function IEP ROM init config
32 is the campaign mode version of
function e to e EP ROM in it config
which is not shown in this code snippet
and the EP ROM in it config function are
correctly validates user input well we
can see that this compound mode version
does not validate which leads to heap
overflow so the patch we can see that is
simply adding validation logic on it and
in this case a function card is compact
task is used to implement both compact
and noncom had a logic in one function
this can reduce some code redundancy but
still can't eliminate the inconsistency
so in this function when implementing
compile logic the developer forget to
validate the user space pointer power
setting eater and it sighs sets down
which leads to out of bounds array
access based on our research on those
paths compatibilities we found that the
past research on compatibilities only
focuses on normal program logic
so this vulnerabilities looks just like
any other vulnerabilities in any other
part of the kernel assumes nothing
special but during the research on those
vulnerabilities we went deep into many
device drivers code and we found that in
device drivers
compared and non compact hosts you
really mix together making the whole
program logic very complex even
confusing so we came up with a question
can this mixed codes cause some expected
program logic even causing some security
problems then my colleague conve will
introduce our research and finding
hello I'm competing at a continue and we
know I'll come to a la mota commonly
used the interface in device drivers
so I will research many focused on our
control
this is a symbol our country of blue
tata inti white drivers and we know how
control have saved parameters the
further a pilot is quite well
the second parameter command is the
device dependent aquatic order thus
other parameter is a pointer to you the
memory you early it appointed to a
structure lost rugged hyper depend on
specific device drivers and command 164
Peter process invokes out on top in the
passage 64-bit aware of parameters to
Colonel then Colonel will invoke
unlocked I'll control with this 64-bit
version of user parameters
130 to be the process involves our
control in the passages study to be the
wording of all parameters that Colonel
Connor will invoke compare our control
instead in device drivers we define the
second of our control commander
parameters
commander 32 are used up by only city to
be the program's
commander 64 are used by only thing for
builder programs and some common command
can be used by posts 32-bit and 64-bit
programs because that corresponding tell
structures
so the outcome two parameters are the
same 32-bit and 64-bit platforms
after analyzing many different device
drivers Dakota we summarized this
typical detailed approach out of our
control in device driver implementations
in motor device drivers
no matter compared or non non compared
mode there are functionality are the
same so compare our control and unlock
the adventure was account some common
cause to implement there some
functionality and the motor important
the difference between compared our
control and unlock the outcome to the
company our control had one extra step
in needed to convert a study to be the
wording of the parameters to 64-bit the
world
compared to our control we will make a
conversion according to the value of a
commander 32 so we had a fresh idea what
you will intentionally confuse the
company our control parameters with
unloaded our control parameters will it
affect the behavior of the conversion
not coding security problems then we
listed the following six conditions with
the computer parameters and try to
verify whether they have a security
problem
further we found unlock the outcome to
another have become weary on behavior in
a more fall and the name of five when
you pass a commander so the tool to
unlock the outcome job it will be
filtered so number four and the number
five argued out second in number six
when you pass a peach doctor 32 with the
commander 64 how control car will
written fell directly because the size
of the target appointed by historical
SATA 2 is less than what the colonel
need so number six ruled out as a lotta
processing logical of pathology a
parameter in our control depend on the
value of commander so we ignore the
wearable piece doctor only focusing on
how change of the second parameter
command will affect our control
so number three is equivalent to come
head our control with the commander
study two and peace doctors little
parameters which in the normal case
so which other need either to focus on
the safety of company control with 64
Peter commander
then we Annelle and light the many
demise drivers try to find know what
behavior will be triggered if we pass
commander 64 and carefully control a
diminishes the pitch other parameters in
some of them will found when commander
64 is passed up to compare our control
and its second parameter the check and
confirm will be bypassed then with the
carefully constructed a malicious v
other parameters in some of common
common cold
we amend data to Jericho no
vulnerabilities so we wanted a to
discover more vulnerability by father
ego sitting in Linux is called panel
tools including Trinity and the city
color to notice about the competitor so
we added a compared supporter continuity
and acid color then I use them to
further device driver as expected we
discovered a more vulnerabilities
here I summarized the full security
issues that can code by the type of
competitive and abilities since this
logical vulnerability causes the check
and converter are you input beam by
pattern maliciously you the input for
the course every security problems
depending on behaviors bypassed by
passing verification are you the input
elements can lead to a outer bound
reader and the writer told it array
that's causing probability at collision
by passing verification are you the
input a point of value can lead to
arbitrator memory read not coding
information leakage
compared to a local user space in the
unit or allocate us best memory in
Colonel CAI Malaga ayuda instead of it
for checker and Nakamura which increases
operational internal memory that
increasing the security risk
one check and converter a bipod using in
the competitor today in common code to
deal with the campaign mode and the
64-bit mode it is easy to call logic
confusion ignoring the security auditor
of the compatible in common core and it
is more likely to cause security
problems when by patent checker and
camera here I lived to see me we found
to further illustrate this vulnerability
type in the Left diagram the second
stable process the study to be the
commander including check and convert a
u.s. importer if we part directly is
corresponding 64-bit a command the very
tender of us bad point
check the PI copy form user will be
bypassed so it can be assigned not
invaluable without any
arbitrator address access why you the
mem copy
this is a second example in the left a
diagram the second step of processes the
study to be the commander copy from user
checks to the euler's best pointer even
way passes directly to the corresponding
64-bit command the validation will be by
pasta this pointer can be assigned to
any value without he-he arbitrary
address access why did the dereference
the in a third step
here we summarize the three tips to
mitigate the compare the vulnerability
try to use compare the a local user
space instead of camera the entire user
input checker and converted under
conversion avoiding security problems
caused by the rebel operation and
commemorate try to avoid the using a the
competitors in common codes to deal with
the compare code and 64-bit mode which
make all logical computer and the
security problems we can use compare a
local us best to help calm weather
illness but you know parameters from
company mode to 64-bit model then
proceed in common cold so as to avoid
using a competitor's try to use dot
instead of point in user input to
minimize the very tight validation of
user of you the important Chinese best
for efficiency and security
this is our devices development and data
and in Europe should suggesting the tech
team and the oddity of
competi code for tools and coding in
tools should give more attention to
compare the code security researchers
can continue to explore compare the
attack on more platforms
so this bitch I hope to help you
understand the concept and the security
risk of combat and we'll add some
compare the vulnerabilities in a part
more important we identified a new type
of combative on abilities in device
drivers which had not needed covered by
any others before and last time I wanted
to show you how to discover the kind of
vulnerabilities and how to avoid them in
development thank you
any questions
okay
[Music]