[Music]
all right so who is CSC now surprisingly
to me
only 4% Canadians in the survey knew
what CSC is so just show of hand in this
room knows what about the communications
security establishment already and
here's the 4% right here right now
fantastic so I will zoom through those
parts of the remarks because that you
know that already for the three or four
of you who don't know what the CSC is
I'll mention it very briefly so the
communication security establishment is
the national cyber security and foreign
signals intelligence agency we play an
integral role in helping to protect
Canada Canadians against cyber threats
terrorism foreign espionage attacks in
our democracy in our way of life told
you I get a cool job we worked with the
Canada Canadian Armed Forces or in
overseas military operations like
Afghanistan Iraq Mali recently CSC also
is the lead technical and operational
cyber security agency for the Government
of Canada you knew that as of 1 October
we are now the home of the Canadian
Centre for cyber security my new job and
I am proud to say today as the 1st of
November and we survived month number
one and that's fantastic
I wasn't bragging so much a month ago
I'll tell you that so the intent here is
we're supposed to be and become the the
cornerstone for the federal government
cyber security CSC is home to some smart
and Eirene really really smart people
and we have top-shelf code makers we
have top-shelf code breakers we have
mathematicians computer scientists
linguists analysts in a gigantic support
team and of course some of Canada's best
cybersecurity experts our expertise is
rooted in over 70 years of proud history
from the complex bold World War two
environment through the Cold War through
9/11 all the way to the complex
environment that we live in today with
multiple diverse threats that we face
the men and women of CSC were there
along the way we put the Canada's most
sensitive information in infrastructures
in many ways but we don't do it alone
according to 2017 report by the Canadian
Chamber of Commerce
Canadian economy loses more than 3
billion each year to cybercrime and if
I'm not mistaken I read report early
this week from the stats Canada that
number is now 4 billion estimated each
year this is the reality we face and the
cost of cybercrime worldwide is expected
to hit hold your hats six trillions
annually by 2021 while CSE works to
protect Canada against a host of foreign
threats the world needs to counter cyber
criminals too by leveraging law
enforcement which is why to do this we
will collaborate with the RCMP s
cybercrime coordination unit also
announced the national cybersecurity
strategy I think I'm supposed to use
that at some point there we go my
apologies but since you're only with us
already let's go to the next one to help
galvanize Canada's national cyber
security posture the government launched
an updated national cybersecurity
strategy in June of this year informed
by over 2,000 submissions from folks
like you and from corporations the
strategy addresses the gaps in areas for
improvement in Canada's current
cybersecurity climate the end result
will be better defence against cyber
threats greater security prosperity for
Canadians of course will be three main
themes security resilience innovation
research skill talent and leadership and
collaboration let me start and walk
through that building secure and
resilient Canadians Ibsen's systems is
really the first step to defence against
cyber threats but what type of threats
are we facing while you and this room
know this as much as I do today's
threats are coming at us more often for
more places and for more reasons to
attack tours range from sophisticated
foreign States to criminals and even
unskilled but highly motivated
individual hackers some are looking for
personal information others want
intellectual property or research others
are simply in it to make some bucks make
some money and as your there's lots of
money to be made still others want to
manipulate confuse miss inform and
divide I can share a couple of
real-world examples that you all know
already today ransomware has become
increasingly popular among threat actors
why because it makes money it generates
income it's a business you can go online
under the darker oh I'm slipping again
stay to the script you can go online of
the dark grip you can buy several cyber
enablers for bad things right it is a
market this was illustrated by the
global wanna cry attack back in May 2017
mana cry affected over two hundred
thousand victims in 150 countries an
estimated global four billion dollars in
lost productivity
wanna cry attack used worms made it to
self-replicate and moved pretty fast
across may 2018 cyber criminals
contacted two Canadian banks and claimed
to have accessed the personal
informations of tens of thousands of
clients the cyber criminals threatened
to release the information unless the
banks paid them 1 million in ransom we
had universities in Canada that were
taken for ransom we had private
institutions taken for ransom we had
government in state entities to confer
ransom this is growing and this is a big
business place these are more than just
attacks on our infrastructures they are
more than just attacks on our company's
net worth it's about attacks on
employees on reputation
it's about attacks on our economy and
security or famine fundamental freedoms
and I think most importantly it's about
attacks on our trust and confidence the
good news is it can be defended against
the impact can be contained and we can
do this together now how can Canadian
system owners begin to keep their
network secure and be resilient against
cyber threats like these it's that way
that's where I get to brag a little I
don't gonna brag throughout the
presentation of course the Canadian
Centre for cybersecurity publishes
advice and guidance to help them do just
that what do you have behind me is one
example amongst many of those advice and
guidance it's not just advice for
government it used to be but we're the
creation of a cyber center we want to
make that available for Canada and
Canadians
it's for any network owner one of the
most frequently accessed pieces of
advice on our website is this the top 10
IT security actions 10 simple steps to a
more secure and resilient network and
some folks that room will confirm to you
that what I've tasked my team to do is
make it simple find the things that get
us the most security for the least
effort the easiest to understand find
things that you can do at scale that
help Canada and Canadians in fact back
to this one in many cases doing just the
top four actions can reduce your threat
surface by as much as 80 percent as I
manage the cybersecurity part
should portfolio for the last three
years I met a lot of private sector
industries and government
representatives and let me tell you a
lot of people need help they want to do
the right things often they just don't
know what to do I became best friends
with many of them because I would I was
willing to go and sit down with the
Board of Directors and the presidents
and present the value proposition of
what you protect when you do something
and what you put at stake when you don't
protect yourselves most I say most cyber
advise adversaries are not that
sophisticated the goal is to make it
more difficult more expensive for them
to succeed if you can check them even a
bit they're likely to move on easier
targets it's the old bear analogy right
we're all running as a pack you don't
want to be the slowest runner and gut
for a bit you don't want to cover
yourself in honey so just keep running
IT security basics are just that basics
they're not sexy they may make you less
likely to become a victim and in a world
where cyber risk equates business risk
and where cyber attack often means
stolen assets recovery costs penalties
loss of confidence and productivity why
not invest in straightforward achievable
approaches the basic things I talked
about earlier one of those things is
moving to cloud it's an operative step
up our security but there could also be
some barriers to cloud adoption business
owners need to understand what sort of
risk of vulnerabilities their
organization may face and risk which
risks they are comfortable accepting the
cyber center works in collaboration with
Treasury Board already in public service
procurement Canada to help reduce those
barriers by developing security
requirements for contracting making
cloud available for government agencies
the cyber centers advice regarding the
protection and key some cue bullets
includes some of this kind of advice
making sure users are using proper
identification and authentication making
sure the cloud service providers and
ministers are properly cleared to manage
your data making sure the business
owners has the opportunity to inspect
the physical security of data centers to
make up the cloud not all clouds are
created equal make sure the processing
of offshore data is properly properly
protected make sure the data that you've
identified goes to where it should go
and then you're comfortable where it's
going make
the departments that follow an IT
security risk management make sure the
department's follow an IT security risk
management framework process now this is
the advice that we put together for
government and government procurement so
the next challenge
Jeff is to make that available to
everybody and everyone in this room Jeff
you're dozing off there buddy keeping an
eye on you
the second pillar of cyber security
strategy is about innovation innovation
is key to being effective in cyber
security and in turn cybersecurity
drives innovation in economic activity
in Canada making money is a good thing
it pays more taxes it's a good thing
right having a thriving economy is a
good thing
innovation is therefore a good thing
with a global cybersecurity industry
forecast to grow by 66% in the next
couple of years thousands of additional
jobs could be created for Canadians
that's both great news and bad news
thousands of new jobs means that
education and research institutions are
gearing up to train and equip the next
generation of cyber experts
it also means we will all be competing
for this new environment for this new
cyber expertise in these folks if you
and if you'll forgive me about people
I'm gonna boast a little bit about CSE
our mission has required us to innovate
for more than seven decades and to
respond to changing government
requirements in a very dynamic technical
environment this is possibly our
greatest strength and sets us apart from
many others in government with 84% of
CSE employees feeling that they are
strongly encouraged to be innovative in
their day to day work and I challenge
you to ask the folks in the room today
if that's true or not that's 17 percent
higher than the average government
responds the way our teams are set up
that we are building is designed the way
our computing platforms are configured
all fosters innovation well of course we
have red lines our employees operate
within the law they must demonstrate
integrity and value diversity but we ask
them to think at managing audacity not
managing risk and we expect them to fail
on the road to success they need to take
smart chances and solve tough problems
diversity also helps drive innovation
and CSC is a very diverse in culture
skills and gender that brings us fresh
perspectives creative ideas interesting
ways of looking at problems in fact Cece
has been named one of Canada's top
employers for young people in power
because of our diversity particularly in
gender almost 40% 40% of our employees
are women on the surface that may not
look like a very impressive number but
you might not know that the same metric
in Silicon Valley is 30%
so that's 10% more than Silicon Valley
CC has a higher percentage of women
working in technical roles than Google
Facebook or Twitter but we know there is
more that needs to be done it's fine to
be innovative but if we don't find ways
to share the fruits of our innovation
we're not effective because much of what
CSC does has been doing for 70 years is
classified we have struggled to share
our technical expertise and innovation
outside of our top secret walls we're
improving though and again ask the folks
in the room
CeeCee was proud to publicly release one
of our innovative cybersecurity tools
assembly line behind me develop in built
in-house assembly line is a malware tool
that automates a detection and analysis
of malicious files as they hit the
network or system that is a project a
proof of concept that we can move our
tools from top-secret highly classified
to unclassified and shift to Co
development and Co design assembly line
allows system owners to better protect
their data from theft and compromise it
allows cyber security community to
jointly develop this open source
software cyber experts from academia and
the private sector can customize it and
prove it for the benefit of their entire
community give back and I can tell you
that it's been downloaded thousands of
times in dozens of countries including
Russia and China it is now used by the
Norwegian Bank representing about a
quarter of that country's clients it's
used by now core energy large provincial
corporate air quartered in Newfoundland
Labrador that manages the provinces
energy resources even target the second
largest department store retailer
acknowledged using assembly line and the
cyber center will continue to work with
our critical infrastructure partners to
integrate assembly line and we encourage
our partners to provide feedback on the
quality and relevance of the tools the
challenge I gave the team is take this
go open-source and learn how to do open
source take the feedback be humble get
the community engaged if all of us in
this room are
developing and co designing we stand a
better chance of winning this battle
assembly line is one of many examples
that by working together we are stronger
and more resilient it demonstrate that
cybersecurity really is a team sport
that's a third pillar of the cyber
strategy leadership and collaboration
here we are
on 1 October that's where the Canadian
Center for cyber security really comes
into play cyber security experts from
the Canadian side see Sir the Canadians
cyber Incident Response Center shared
services Canada's that Sock'em share
services Canada in the IT security
branch of CSC those three organizations
were removed from their parent
organizations and bring brought together
as the Canadian Centre for cyber
security under CSC the cyber center
modernizers the government of Canada's
approach to cyber security into a unique
innovative forward-looking open
organization the mission is to help
reduce the cyber risk faced by Canada
and Canadians in our digital world
simply put it'll be the front door for
cyber security at the federal level a
front door for government but also for
industry academia and if I can go off
script for a second what I've used as an
analogy for others before it's a
lighthouse it's a lighthouse with three
floors my first floor is my innovation
and collaboration floor you can walk in
there's no security guards I've got to
Pat you down and take all your
electronics away quite the opposite they
welcome you into a room for innovation
your private sector you want to bring in
some new tools and some great idea your
from the local university or foreign
university and you have a project that
you want to demonstrate you come into
our place you actually show off you
bring your clients on this town you show
them the tool now well put some bars for
coming through the door it has to be new
it has to address new problems you have
to Bend together with others there has
to be benefit for the community but we
have an open-door policy on that first
floor on my second floor I'm going to
integrate operations and coordination so
as a National Center now what I want to
connect is not just the federal
government but all levels of government
and the critical infrastructure sector
systems of importance to the government
and I'm making that a little more
generic because really there are things
that change over time and a good example
of that is next year's election if we're
having elections coming up of course
that's a critical
for structure for Canada if a few years
laters as there's the Olympics of course
as a critical infrastructure for Canada
that's what that second floor is about
my third floor might be a bit bit small
but it's a very important floor and
that's where I stay connected with
communication security establishment and
the notes we'll talk about this in a
second but I don't think we could be as
successful at this game without our
foreign intelligence awareness in
knowledge but I'll come back to that so
I do have to go back to the script at
some point so what will the summary
Center do it will provide advice
guidance to help others make security
into system design it will partner with
vendors system operators that the
Communication Service Providers academia
to innovate on some of Canada's toughest
cyber problems it will certify advanced
commercial and government cryptographic
equipment and ensure that good crypt is
built properly it will defend the
government of Canada's networks against
a wide range of malicious activity and
most importantly it will share what we
learned with the private sector to help
them defend themselves against threats
it's a hub for our community but I would
be remiss if I didn't acknowledge that
part of the cyber centers unique
advantages CSCS other lines of business
foreign signals intelligence mission now
you might not know this if you're the
four people in the room that didn't know
about CSC but we covertly monitor
communications and signals of foreign
targets allowing us to detect and better
understand foreign base threats as they
develop we have an eye on the world we
see what that looks like
we see it move around we understand how
it operates we see it morph you see a
change that's the foreign signals
intelligence saying that in the middle
of this circle is the knowledge and
expertise that brings CSCS effectiveness
together and there's no shortage of
those threats facing the Government of
Canada interesting statistics every day
hundreds of millions of malicious
activities directed at the Government of
Canada networks including up to 1
billion 1 billion
riki attempts of vulnerabilities every
day 25 million direct attempts to
install malicious software on our
networks every day over 90,000 malicious
attempts to get into our databases every
single day it's a busy world out there
and it's not getting quieter
we know that cyber center can't do it
alone we ascribe to the idea that
cybersecurity through collaboration
that's why we were building partnerships
with academia in the private sector a
recent example of collaboration in our
recent project between the cyber center
the Canadian Institute for cyber
security at the University of New
Brunswick and Amazon Web Services in
working to test cyber defense
technologies we found that there was a
lack of high quality publicly available
security datasets to address this issue
we reached out to our partners joined up
with UNB you Andy indicated they might
be interested in this problem we needed
to get some compute we found a friend
AWS we got all of us together and
generated a dataset that represents I
think it's 10 departments 500 employees
13 days of our 10 days of hacking on 13
different scenarios that dataset is now
available on AWS you can if you're a
cyber security researcher anyone or you
have a tool you want to test it out you
can go on AWS access this data set and
test your tools and demonstrate your
theories and prove yourself to be worthy
to go into the innovation center the
challenge of getting the right
information to do research and
innovation is one that's that was
probably the most dire of need in the
last two years so that's why we picked
this project to go first but in fact
remember my first floor if you have a
bright complicated problem don't just
bring solutions bring problems as well
problem boxes are really important part
of the solution set what you do is you
come to the center and say you have this
problem
am I the only one who has this problem
you find friends have a common problem
and then we band together to look for
solutions and we make these solutions
available to the community the cyber
center also works with associations such
as the cyber threats the Canadians every
threat exchange is ztx see CTX if you
don't know is a collective of Canada's
largest banks telcos power and other
major organizations collaborating to
share cyber threat information across
sectors we don't stop there we also work
with international organizations like
the global cyber alliance the various US
ice ax FSI sects and other independent
electricity system
operators and others the key once again
is creating these communities and giving
people with the different perspectives
together we don't claim to know it all
but we know that the power of the
community knows it all and if we can
just harness and work it together we can
find a better solution so we want to
work with you we have provided specific
information to help you defend your
networks in the past we tip you when we
see something that you need to address
we provide advice on specific cyber
threats related to your sector when we
see it
these are everyday actions in our
partnerships and relationships but these
are early days as well for our
relationship we know we have a lot to
offer based on our unique aperture and
knowledge and we need you to come to the
door and ask us to help you we are
committed to raising public awareness
about how we see cyber threat
manifesting in Canada in fact we're
preparing to release our first national
cyber cyber threat report in a few days
the report will discuss strategic cyber
threats that face can Eaton facing
Canadian businesses critical
infrastructures and public institutions
and without giving too much of it away
here it will focus heavily of course on
cybercrime the biggest threat facing all
of us today the report will be informed
by CSC cyber defense data the expertise
of our people our assessment of the
overall cyber threat landscape and let
me pause there for a second our
knowledge is based on foreign signals
intelligence awareness and what we see
of government networks in Canada that's
not enough
I see 250,000 clients and what they do
every day that's the federal government
but collectively there are 37 million
citizens in this country that we need to
protect so again by joining together by
banding together we can do with much
more prominent among our concerns are
threats to Canada's democratic process
that bears mentioning as we're about to
enter an election year and we've all
seen and heard about cyber threats to
elections and the democratic processes
in other countries in fact last year we
published a first-of-its-kind public
report on cyber threats to democratic
processes and institutions we'll be
updating that report in early 2019 we're
also delivering regular thread briefings
to government officials cyber security
advice and guidance to political parties
into those running in or considering
running for
office as CSC in the cyber center work
to share knowledge and expertise we're
mindful that our role is not to
duplicate your cybersecurity efforts
it's to fill the gap between the IT
services that are provided today and the
most the most sophisticated
cybersecurity threats our goal is to
partner with the Kenyan security
industry to make us all safer so we're
all protected to the same degree as we
have been able to protect the Government
of Canada because all Canadians and all
of your customers want to connect online
with trust and confidence in closing I
want to leave you assured that CSC in
the cyber centre are playing critical
roles in all three pillars of the
government's national cybersecurity
strategy our advice and guidance can
help you in other Canadian critical
system owners build more resilient and
secure networks we are dedicated in
innovating as an organization increasing
diversity that drives innovation and
sharing that innovation for the benefit
of everyone we are providing leadership
for the Government of Canada and
collaborating with you and other others
in private sector to help thwart today's
cyber threats and to be ready to face to
the doors of tomorrow the bottom line an
ultimate goal is to make Canada
unattractive to cyber threat actors but
we can't do it alone it will take all of
us in this room and all of us in this
country to ensure Canadian cyber space
is trusted and resilient and we look
forward to collaborating with us
partners in this noble pursuit
collaborating for a secure Canada it's
not just important it's essential on
that I close and look forward to your
questions
[Applause]
[Music]