[Music]
cool so we're here to talk about
self-driving cars right and the first
thing that I think people don't realize
about self-driving cars there's a bunch
of levels to these things and the the
first one is kind of level zero this is
a car that isn't really self-driving at
all it's made as a designation for
things that don't self drive right and
so as a little bit of background we've
worked at uber I worked at DD for a
while we work at a company called crews
now doing security for self-driving cars
so after we hacked cars we moved on to
try to figure out ways we could like
secure the newest technologies and so
self-driving cars are pretty cool things
we'll talk lots about it but not these
things these are the cars that I grew up
with it they're not gonna get hacked
they're the safest from cyber tech you
want to be probably not very safe from
an actual real world life usage so you
know as we move on to the next level of
these things we have things like a Jeep
Cherokee right and and these are cars
that have some kind of assistance
available to you they'll kind of break
if it's about to hit something it'll
kind of slightly adjust the steering it
may Park for you but generally speaking
the driver is still responsible for all
control right so this idiot oh wait
that's me
this idiot so this is this is we'll talk
about this in a bit but this is we
crashed Andy Greenberg into a ditch
there and he's from New York and they
don't know how to drive cars I guess so
I don't he also cried too for the record
Andy Greenberg cried yeah he was he was
terrified anyway so he couldn't get it
out so local Midwestern boy had to get
in the car and and retrieve it from the
ditch which which I did do exactly but
as you move on right you have kind of
partial levels of automation this gets
us into the Tesla territory I don't know
if they took the name autopilot off I
think they did right but essentially
this will give you some ability for the
car to drive and kind of make decisions
on it
but at the end of the day still for
level three the drivers still
responsible so while you have may have
this system that does things that that
look like autonomous driving in
actuality when it comes down to it the
the drivers still responsible for all
these things that all right so it'll
salt drive for a bit but if you're not
holding on the steering wheel it'll
it'll beep at you because you're
supposed to be responsible despite what
the ads that Tesla sometimes say and
like GM has a similar technology and
there it has a camera that looks in your
eyes and if it notices your eyes aren't
looking at the road it beeps at you so
these are technologies to make sure like
yes we're helping you we're not trying
to drive the car by itself you're not
allowed to get sleepy right so sorry the
level to so level 3 now is we're getting
a point where the car in certain
situations doesn't expect intervention I
think a good example is outies what
traffic jam pilot essentially you could
sit there and read the newspaper or
Twitter or whatever people read in the
car and it will do its thing for you
without much expectation for you to take
over right so in this case it's in a
very particular situation it will drive
for you but you you you get out of that
situation or it finds in an error that
it can't handle then you're supposed to
take back control so you don't have to
pay attention all the time but you have
to still be kind of ready to happen if
something goes wrong so this takes us to
level 4 and level 4 is what Charlie and
I are concerned with and what we what we
do as he said before we used to work at
uber on their level 4 cars and we now
work at cruise automation on our kind of
level 4 cars that's a picture of one
there these are designed to solely drive
themselves there there doesn't even need
to be a driver in the car there may not
even be a steering wheel and pedals it
is probably limited in area it's not
going to go everywhere you're not gonna
go to Grandma's house but if it Maps
some area this car is capable and
supposed to be capable of driving
without human intervention alright so
for a particular fixed area and
particular conditions like weather
conditions the car can drive itself with
no human
and when we talk about security
self-driving cars we're talking about
this we're not talking about securing
Tesla's or so what yeah a lot of times
we like Oh what about self-driving cars
and we'll talk about a Tesla or
something in traffic jam while those are
interesting these are really what piques
our interest and this is kind of where
our expertise lies now because we're on
kind of company number two from e
company number three for Charlie of
figuring out how to secure these things
against the tax we're running out of
companies or for we are running out of
cut this might be it we got to work at
crews forever now level five is
basically KITT from Knight Rider it will
go anywhere and do anything and handle
any situation we have we're not there
yet
robbery not a problem yeah rob the bank
for you haul it out no one's driving no
big deal this is basically the the end
goal the holy grail for self-driving
right you set a car in the road and it
can literally go anywhere dirt road you
know in the city whatever KITT from
Knight Rider hopefully it comes someday
yeah we're not there we don't know how
to get there but someday hopefully we'll
live in a world where that's the case so
there's lots of companies that are
working on this problem and some have
have done more than others if you look
at some of these statistics you'll see
well like one of the things and some of
these statistics are a little old but
the thing that's sort of amazing is way
mo for example has driven 4 million
actually they've driven 10 million miles
now so like imagine how long like humans
never gonna drive anywhere close if you
have a car with a hundred thousand miles
on it right you've probably had that car
for quite some time
think about orders of magnitude more
mouse-driven right and the reason they
have to drive so many miles is the cars
need to to be tested and like these
weird corner cases that maybe you see
once in a lifetime but they need to be
able to see that enough to test it and
make sure it handles that situation and
maybe iterate and like maybe didn't
handle it so they add some new code and
then they got tested again but you can't
just make these weird once and lifetime
things happen spontaneously you have to
just drive and drive and drive until you
see those things actually and you'll
notice there's kind of three names
listed here but you'll go online and
you'll see 40 companies they're doing it
try driverless cars right and they're
doing their demo and it's on the highway
and it's great that's awesome you know
what's really hard to do pull up to a
stoplight with someone crossing when
they're not supposed to
a bicyclists on your right someone
coming behind you and bi to make a blind
left and that's why you have to drive
all these mouths and that's why this is
a really hard problem it's not driving
on the highway
that's generally okay and people were
smart and can figure that out it's
really the crazy interactions and crazy
situations that you get yourself into as
a driver that that requires all these
mouths to be driven and the other thing
to notice about those three companies is
their goal at least for now is to end in
a ride-sharing kind of situation so none
of these companies at the current time
plan to sell the car so they're not
building self-driving cars intending to
sell them to people who will just drive
them or or have them drift ride them
around there they're set up to be like
you would call one happen it would take
you somewhere you'd hop out and it would
drive off and that's gonna have a lot of
implications when we talk about the
security of the cars so there's what a
way mo looks like it's in a Pacifica
yeah I think way mo recently to just
we're the first ones to sign that they
could operate without a driver in the
vehicle in California so yeah and
they've been doing that already and yeah
in Arizona and way mo has been doing
this for ten years Google you know so
they've they've been kind of doing this
whole project the longest I think their
car is kind of ugly I'm not a Pacifica
guy not a Pacific guy here's the the
uber car that both Charlie and I spent
some time you know securing I think it's
a better looking car than that Pacifica
minivan personally having the Consumer
Reports cars it's it's a pretty slick
looking Volvo xc90 again they they've
been on the streets for a while they're
off the streets now for a bit and you
know they're still doing active
development for these things so yeah
they had an actual ride-sharing service
before anyone else that you could just
any person could call for an uber and
sometimes one of these would show so I
lived in Pittsburgh where the
development of this was mainly based and
it was cool because the way they mapped
the city my house ended up being on that
map so I would get one of these kind of
to and from work almost every day so I
got to take driverless cars to work
every day which is rad and it didn't
cost me anything so it was cool so if
you like one of the things you want to
look at on these pictures is what's
different about this car from an XD 90
which is buy from a lot and right away
you notice there's stuff on the roof so
there's gonna be like some high NARS and
some other
censors there's gonna be cameras along
the edges and and more radars and other
things so just keep an eye out for
things that look different and we'll
talk more about like the actual
differences in a bit but you'll notice
like it does if you saw that driving
down the road you'd be like what is that
thing so it they look different than the
normal cars obody look at that that
looks like a beaut huh that's probably
the best-looking one out less in this
company big toy I would definitely
definitely pitch this in a sales pitch
real quick now no so this is what the
first second third generation cruise
vehicle again you'll notice a bunch of
different sensors on it right you have
radars that try to see things at short
distances long distance lied ours on the
roof and a bunch of other sensor
packages the other big differentiator in
this car then the other two is this one
is purely electric so you're no longer
dealing with hybrid vehicles the reason
that everyone uses hybrid vehicles is
we'll talk later you have these massive
computes in the car and you need all
that electricity but the cool thing
about this is you no longer have to
worry about things like oil changes or
putting gasoline in it you know these
things are purely electrical and they
can get a charge and be on their way
everything is kind of right about these
is like say uber buys these cars from
Volvo but this is a car that's made it
in a General Motors factory because
General Motors owns a bunch of cruise so
the self-driving car rolls all the
factory ready to go instead of buying a
car and added a bunch of crap to it yeah
has anyone been in one raising hands
anyone one person sweet yeah it is it's
a pretty wide experience like your the
cars driving the steering wheels turning
the person is in touch with the gas the
brake it's it's a it's a great
experience and it's cool to see right
and it's wild at first and then you do
it a bunch and then it's not it's just
sort of boring and that's kind of the
point yes I used to take like a selfie
every time I was in the car and then I
was just like just just go just just let
it drive hurry all right so let's talk
about some of the differences that
you'll see and we already talked about
this but it's basically but it takes a
car and it adds much hardware to it and
it makes the car like way more expensive
it's more expensive than you'd want to
buy even if you could buy it unless you
were some millionaires yeah exactly so
to give you example some of those things
like a lidar on the roof depending on
which one you buy can be seventy five
thousand dollars for a single device and
it can break and you can maybe brick it
if you do bad stuff like these are
really expensive right now the cost of
these will come down in time as we
figure out you know as a technology
group how to make them cheaper but right
now it's prohibitively expensive for an
individual to do this type of thing so
the biggest difference you'll notice in
the car is the is the the roof with all
the sensors and so here you'll see this
is them installing in a factory and you
can see a bunch of those little things
that look like big hockey pucks those
are elide ours and we'll talk a little
bit later it looks like in a bit I don't
think if you see anything else but
usually on the front of the car there'll
be some extra radars
over you bunch of cameras and the sensor
package where the black dots are those
are cameras and those aren't like you
know dashcam cameras these are super
high resolution cameras capable of you
know doing image matching of in
classifications and things like cars and
bikes and people so lidar we talked a
lot about this is what the computer
basically sees so lidar is it's a in
this one it's spinning it's shooting out
pulses of light I guess and recording
how long it takes to come back and and
you get an idea of
you know what's out there and then it
has some sort of algorithms that try to
map that into things that it can
classify so here you can see the blue
boxes it thinks for people and and it is
and the red boxes or cars and so from
that it can you know determine what what
the world looks like so you look at
something like a Tesla they're trying to
do everything with with pure cameras
with with images we just kind of like
how humans work but all the three that
we've been spending a lot of time on use
lidar because this is kind of the best
technology for yes
what what's crazy is most people use
valid ein light ours right now and I
think David Hall and his brother of the
guy they'd been that company I'm a dummy
but they somehow figured out how to
measure the bouncing of light using
electronics which kind of blows my mind
right you're using electricity to
measure the speed of light and that's
essentially how lidar works it just
shoots lasers about and figures out how
fast it bounces back off the things that
it hit the compute is the main
difference you know I think especially
we've been kind of chatting about car
security for five six years at this
point and most people think of you know
this is just an ECU this one unit the
compute needed to process all this
images and light our data points and
radar and kind of time synchronize that
and make it work is more like a Bitcoin
mining rig than it is an ECU in in a
regular car right a massive amount of
computers needed to do this stuff yep
and so there's also gonna be a part
where you've got this huge computer it's
got all these the sensors that it's
reading from and then it's got to decide
what to do so it's like okay I want to
start turning the steering wheel so it
needs to communicate that to the rest of
the car and so the rest of the car is
probably just a standard car which is
kept talking like a can bus all the
components and so it needs to be some
sort of link between those big computer
making decisions and the can bus and so
usually there'll be some extra ECU that
translates from whatever the computer
wants to talk to the can lesson and tell
it to do things like you know speed up
or slow down or turn the steering wheel
yeah the big point for this right now is
almost well everyone who's doing kind of
self-driving is taking a car that was
originally built
to be a passenger vehicle like have a
driver in it and kind of making it a
self-driving car so that's kind of why
this architecture is necessary in the
future you could see companies building
specifically self-driving cars so when
they're designing a car they're not even
designing it to have a steering wheel in
it or pedals or things like that right
you know compute could directly make
these actuators do things so this is
kind of a byproduct of just the world we
were worrying right now not to mention
the computers we use are just like
regular computers they're not specially
designed to be in a car so they're not
gonna have some some dedicated interface
to talk to the car components next up is
the the riders in the car have to have
some sort of interface to talk to the
car so right now this is on the left you
can see what way Mo's looks like on the
right is ubers and they're basically
just like tablets of some kind
and this'll you can use to say like you
know tell the cars stop because it's
supposed to be a ride-sharing service or
like where you want to go take a selfie
yourself as you're on your trip Twitter
you can do that yes some of them do have
built-in selfie taking technologies had
a thing where you could have button it
would take a selfie and post it and
hashtag it for you the future is these
things are used to provide data to the
the passenger about what the car seen to
give them some sort of confidence like
you can see that the car sees there's a
person you can see that the car is
intending to turn it otherwise you're
like what's going on so it's nice that
it's just a way for the computer to kind
of reassure the passenger that
everything's okay right now they're
using them as Charlie said it's
reassurance
hey yes I see those that's a bike and
that's a person and we know a stop signs
coming up and we see the lights red not
green stuff like that
Ethernet so so again we're using these
massive computes and they need to send
more data than then what's usually sent
on a vehicle bus in comes Ethernet which
is great right because we understand
this Ethernet is kind of the wave of the
future when it comes to automotive
because you have more bandwidth it's
faster kind of you know more universally
understood than things like CANbus and
that's essentially how all this stuff
communicates with each other network
switches compute devices that Ethernet
think of this just
much like a data center you have in an
office but it's in a car all right
well talk about some bit but it's good
for security because can basically sucks
for security and we know how to secure
stuff on Ethernet so it's a big help the
more stuff we can get on Ethernet so
like we've seen the you know the we're
not gonna show exactly how the cars
we've seen or built and but we've seen
two or three different versions of it
and basically they all have this sort of
architecture and that you know there's
gonna be some differences but they're
all gonna have you know some sort of
sensors hooked up to Ethernet and the
reason that is is because the types of
sensors you buy off the market or
already set up for Ethernet they're not
set up for any kind of other things so
stuff gonna be some Ethernet component
there's gonna be this big computer we
talked about there's gonna be some
device that communicates to the outside
world and then there's gonna be a bunch
of vehicle ECU's like your brake
controller or your engine and those are
gonna be on can and then there's gonna
be some link in between them and so
these are the components the way you
hook them up might be a little bit
different so a might instead of looking
like this it might look more like this
so maybe things are some of the things
that cameras are plugged directly into
the computer or your Tom Macs might be
directly plugged to the computer or
maybe the computer is plugged straight
kind of into the module it goes to the
can and working so I'm going to Ethernet
so there's like a few variations but for
the most part the topology of the inside
of the car looks exactly like this yeah
so there's no kind of set standard right
like people just make it up and it's
definitely not this Wow for an advanced
company it's not like this for four
people competing in this space right now
for it is not that right it's more like
this so it's it's it's just your trunk
you just full computer pieces and
switches and and you know massive
computers and it's like you're not going
to put your suitcase in the trunk any
more like just deal with that yeah just
don't take a suitcase just buy new
clothes where you go in this trash yeah
but you know in just to go back to the
previous picture these are kind of
prototyping right if you would see one
of these in productions you definitely
don't have a Netgear soho switch in the
back right like you you have real actual
parts but you do stuff like this when
you want to figure out if something
works right and then this is how it
looks now but maybe in 20 years it's
going to look like one little time
ECU and that's it yeah I mean look these
things right I mean this was this would
been a supercomputer so long ago you
would only think that things like that
in cars will get smaller and smaller as
time goes on yep
okay so this is like a super important
point is you get a lot of people talking
about like how do cars know where
they're at right and people just assume
as GPS because that's how we get around
like when you want a good from point A
to point B you put in your Google Maps
and it takes you there via GPS but GPS
is not accurate enough for self-driving
cars we have to use this technology
called localization in a way this works
is you sent out a car first it takes a
very detailed map of where everything is
it knows where every you know speed bump
every pothole every bush everything in
the world that knows where it is exactly
and then you drop the car down in the
middle of someplace and it can tell it
takes a lidar reading and by comparing
its lidar reading to these previous
readings that it's that this mapping
Cardos it knows exactly where it is to
within like I don't know a centimeters
yeah you know you're doing with GPS
you're dealing with give or take a
couple meters right for the high
resolution localization needed for
self-driving cars we're talking
centimeters right so it definitely can
tell if the kerb is a foot away or 1/2
foot away right so this is very
important and again this is what level 4
is level 5 is KITT from Knight Rider
driving where every once level 4 is hey
we've mapped this city or we've mapped
this portion of this city to the
centimeter level now we're gonna use
these sensors to do a thing called like
background subtraction right we know
what the world looks like what is it
what what's new here alright and if you
want to know like why the big difference
in level 4 in level 5 is this map so if
you didn't need the map we could get to
level 5 but but the map is so important
to us right now
because that's the way that the lidar
works and that's the way we figure out
where things are there and he mentioned
the subtraction thing what that means is
like if you've taken a scan of a
particular road like a hundred times and
then all of a sudden you take another
scan and there's this new thing then you
know that wasn't there before that's
probably like a person or a car or
something that's not normally there so
it's it's like too hard computationally
to figure out everything like you've
never
before but by figuring out what the
world usually looks like and comparing
that to what you see now you are able to
pull things out of that you might say
Chris and Charlie doesn't that mean that
these cars are on the street constantly
mapping and looking at things because a
new construction site could pop up
tomorrow yes these cars are always out
mapping most of the time if you would
see self-driving cars on the street
their mapping cars getting new
information and uploading those maps
which are updated you know daily by
daily so yes these cars are always out
the street right now figuring out what's
new and letting the other cars know and
so here's how like a video of
localization in action so you can see
that what the car is seen and the car is
the thing in the red and as you pull
back you can see in the white is what
the the world look like in different
spots to the car and so am i comparing
what it sees in the green to all these
different sort of images it hasn't white
and knows exactly where it's at so
that's how localization works and we'll
talk about why this is important mostly
because if you know you like you see a
lot of things in the paper about GPS and
and how like oh well we'll spoof GPS and
make all of the self-driving cars crash
it's like it doesn't matter they don't
use GPS so you can spoof all you want
and the cars are gonna use local way man
its rightful way they also require a
certain level of connectivity right I
mean in most modern cars this is a nice
luxury feature you can hit a button and
attempts I'm going to talk to and they
can figure out Diagnostics but again as
Charlie said before the kind of big
players in this are doing it for
ride-sharing so you're gonna need to
know where the car is where it needs to
go it's gonna want to tell you stuff hey
here's how fast I'm going here's the
software I'm running things like that
right and so some cars today aren't
connected at all but soldering cars are
always gonna have some connectivity
finally let's talk about hacking hmm
here's my boys so uh a lot of people
think that we were the first view of the
highway car not true these guys were so
a group of academics back in 2011 I
think they hacked a car and the way it
was this beautiful car over here and so
I want to talk about how hacking works
against cars because if you don't
understand how actual attacks work you
can't build effective defenses so we'll
talk real quickly about
all the different attacks that have
happened and that'll help steer us in
ways to figure out how to defend against
them so the way the academics did it
they had two ways they did it so the
first one was through a Bluetooth
vulnerability so the head unit like the
radio of the car had a boner ability and
the way they process Bluetooth so at the
if these guys were within 30 meters of
the car like Bluetooth range they could
send some Bluetooth frames hack into it
get code execution on the head unit and
then they want to do something like
control the brakes but it turned out
that there was they were the the radio
the head unit was not on the same can
bus as the brake so they couldn't just
directly send messages to the brakes
there was this gateway module in between
and the game a module separated those
two networks but they were able to
reprogram the gateway module to let him
do whatever they wanted and one of the
things they wanted to do is send
messages to the brakes and they were
able to do that we'll see this is like a
common thing in car hacking and and
something that's really important think
about it so that was their their first
attack like their being within 30 meters
is like pretty rad you don't have to
like touch the car but still like that
wouldn't say it was cool not rad by my
definition okay okay okay have you say
so did I do all right so they found
another another version of their attack
which was stronger which was through the
cellular network so this one didn't have
that 30 meter range limit yeah it also
had some other limitations which I'm not
getting into anyway this one was pretty
good so they could just dial into a car
because the car had these cellular
modems there was a vulnerability they
had code execution on it and that
particular telematics unit was already
on the same bus as the brakes so they
could just in two steps they could hack
into the telematics unit
send messages to the brakes and control
the brakes and again this was they could
do from anywhere it's pretty rad
it definitely was rad right and this is
what basically inspired us to get into
car hacking is reading this paper right
this is no limitation this car is just
somewhere in the United States and they
can hack into it and apply the brakes
that's Wow
so here's a video of them doing their
attack so yeah so it's not it's not like
in Greenburgh style it's it's very safe
there Joel right organized they care
about people's safety
so yeah so you see like the guy's got a
crush Lebanon okay I don't think we gave
me any greenberg crash I'll do me
his hair is this helmet yes anyway
they're driving they're gonna remotely
attack this car and they lock up the
brakes and and make it come to a stop on
a on a race track
yeah just like it's pretty awesome
so so yeah so that was their attack and
like when when I read that paper I was
like dude let's let's do this like I was
stoked right it's like but but when you
read a paper and you want to get into it
it's uh like how do you expand on that
like how do you extend their work and
the problem for from us was they did
everything they did from like you know
the complete execution of you know car
hacking remotely to control that brakes
like there was nothing else for us to
really do which was kind of a bummer but
but one thing that was different about
what they did and versus what we did was
they didn't really publish anything so
they didn't say what kind of car it was
although we know like we're not dumb
they say her car was they didn't say
what the vulnerability was they didn't
say what message they sent they didn't
say how they controlled the brakes it
was like just like hey we did this and I
totally believe them but there was no
way you could use that to make cars
safer or two to make car hacking like to
learn how to do car hacking it wasn't
useful to really anyone except Justin as
a like a welcome awareness of this
problem imagine alpha-1 releases
smashing the stack for fun and profit
and it's basically like yeah you can use
stack data to hack a computer have fun
y'all right so like we wanted we were
like no information needs to be free we
want to release it all right so there's
us so we in a few years later in 2014 we
did the Jeep and we release all our
tools and and we we like hundreds of
pages of paper all our tools all our
theta we want people to learn from this
we want other people to go and and kind
of do this stuff we're only two guys we
can only look at so many cars right and
the other thing that was different was
not really something we did but
technology had improved from tooth out
the car they had think it was a 2010 car
and ours is it doesn't 14 so in four
years car technology improves a lot and
so now the only the only reason they
could only do brakes was that was the
only thing that was computer-controlled
but now
we have steering and acceleration so we
had more things we could play with and
we did so let's look at how our attack
worked and you'll start to notice
similarities and that's kind of the
point of talking about this is we had a
remote code execution through the the
cellular connection of the car we had to
reprogram this gateway chip because we
couldn't directly send messages to
things we reprogrammed that chip this is
exactly what that connects did and then
we could send messages to the brakes and
steering so very similar to the attack
that that the first attack that academic
sent but we we had steering control
because at the time when they did it
there wasn't things like steering assist
or parking assist but when we had this
car there was which were computer
controlled so that gave us the ability
to do more right it wasn't that we were
smarter and figured out how to control
steering it was just that their computer
didn't have the ability to control
steering and as time moves on right more
things in the car computer controlled
that's an inevitability so this is at
the end of it right so here's our demo
it's also a test track we we were cool
it was in a cornfield don't worry yeah
so yeah so you'll notice in the video
remotely attack into the car control the
steering turn the steering wheel to the
right I'm hacking he's driving and
you'll notice if you see it that he the
steering wheel turns he tries to fight
back and get control the car yeah but
it's too late we're already I need to
take some more high-performance driving
school lessons I could countersteer fast
enough and we right so that's that was
our attack since then there's been some
other attacks that you may or may not
have heard of so in 2016 the Keene team
from China hacked into a Tesla and the
way their attack worked was again a very
similar diagram you'll notice there's
was a web browser exploit and that ran
on the what they call the CID which is
like the head unit the big screen and
the Tesla there's a web browser web
browser exploit so they got control of
that but again that particular component
can't send messages directly to the can
bus and so they had to have this gateway
in between they reprogram the Gateway
just like all these other people did
then they could send messages to the
breaks and make it do stuff and
that's the another item of note to is
they exploit an old WebKit bug so this
was like a known vulnerability and
WebKit and it just so happened that
shockingly the car didn't have the most
up-to-date version of the browser right
so this again is where the future of
automotive internet things is going is
they're gonna borrow where they can
write you don't want to write a brand
new web browser you're gonna use
something that's known but at the same
time if you can't keep it up to patch
level bugs exist right and so one of the
things also to think about this is are
tax and the academic attack well you
could do from anywhere in the country
you could attack any car you wanted here
because it's attacking into a web
browser you have to get the the victim
to do something you have to get them to
click a link or to have visited to be
nearby and try to intercept some
messages and trick their web browser
newsom so anyway it was a much harder
attack it wasn't quite as dangerous in
the sense of scale as the other attacks
were you talking about so let's see
their demo contra
oh they're gonna apply the brakes here
so uh it's like that I'm here he's
driving this thing this message cracks
me up that you should only do this if
you're a security researcher I guess we
can do that
[Applause]
they're implicitly telling us we can do
exactly that so yeah that's their attack
it's it's a you you'll notice like it's
you know the same kind of thing it's
like you get your foot in the door of
the car you reprogram something that's
keeping you from sending kin messages
then you send a message and make it do
stuff so in 2018 they weren't done the
same exact guys keen team they found a
boner building the BMW i3 this
vulnerability was a little different so
here they had if they could trick the
the cellular modem to connect to their
malicious base station they could send
text messages to it again this meant
that you had to be kind of local to the
car so you weren't gonna be able tech
any car you had to be nearby and then
again there was this gateway in the way
of controlling messages to the the
steering or brakes or whatever and this
time they did not figure out a way to
reprogram the gateway so progress is
being made this is like an example of
effective this defense in the sense that
they did get execution code execution on
to the the head unit but they were not
able to control the brakes because of
this gateway module so like you can
start to learn lessons like okay well if
we have a gateway module let's like make
it really tough that you can't just
reprogram it really easy yep seems
reasonable right so you know again we're
concerned mainly with remote attacks
right yes there are a bunch of local
attacks you can do but at the same time
if you're in the car you can also just
light on fire whatever if you want right
local attacks with physical control
that's that's the our biggest concern
right because that's when things start
include you know dealing with passenger
safety driver safety if if you saw those
diagrams you kind of saw how it all went
down and they all had similarities it
was kind of some on authenticate access
to the vehicle and then the ability to
reprogram Porsches portions to do
whatever you want and then the ability
to make actuators perform physical
actions so it's it's pretty kind of well
known how these attacks all work and
then at least that gives us a good
blueprint to how to secure these things
all right and of all that research we
talked about that's the only research
that's ever been done
and that showed remote attack to
physical control so of all the things
you hear about in car hacking like this
is it soz for exactly three examples for
the fourth one was kind of like what
what doesn't work so so yeah so don't be
like too super scared of car hacking
like it's never been done by bad guy
it's only been done by researchers and
only those three groups have done it but
that's not to say we're not concerned
with it right the stakes are just higher
if my Amex gets stolen with some browser
exploit and they got on my banking of
information
someone's gonna make me whole the reason
that we are so proactive about this is
it does involve human safety human life
so that's why we're really serious about
it even though there aren't active
exploit campaigns going on right now
Chris tell us about some advantages of
self-driving cars oh man so at first you
look at this right and this is a
daunting task this is a picture of a
prototype of what Cruz's future cars may
look like you'll notice no steering
wheel no pedals right nothing for anyone
to actually drive with it's basically a
seat on wheels and it goes at first this
is a daunting task well before even as
Charlie mentioned when we hacked the
steering of the Jeep I at least had a
shot I failed
driving failed miserably but I had a
shot to grab that wheel and correct the
course I'm ready feel better that you
had a shot no I don't feel good about
myself in general but that's beyond the
scope of this presentation but yeah in
here right there there's no shot this is
all computer control there's no physical
things for anyone to grab on to maybe
other than the oh bar right so it's
really important to get security right
in these kinds of cars so tell us
alright so the nice thing is we have
advantages a lot of the problems and and
I'll use the Jeep again because I'm most
familiar the biggest problem there was
we were able to compromise this over the
seller airwaves there was no way for
this to be updated over the airwaves
right Tesla has that advantage but at
the time Fiat Chrysler didn't the cool
thing about self-driving cars are right
now they're all owned by the company not
by the people that means they come home
every night that means they can get
updates every night that means we can
ensure if we are using some open source
software that at least on a daily if not
more than multiple times a day they are
capable of getting updates they're
locked away it's not let these things
right now or just sitting on the street
they come out with these garages there's
security guards it's not like people
were in there physically tampering with
them so we we have some advantages right
now from a self-driving effort that
permits us to ensure that these cars get
updates and have some level of physical
safety there's not someone monkeying
around at all yeah you also get the
chance when the car comes in every night
to get charged up or whatever that you
can check it out like does it look like
someone's tampered with it is there
something that's been busted open is
there any like weird thing with the
hardware so there's pre-flight checks
before every single one of these goes
out right there's physical inspection
there's software inspection before they
even go on the road so it's not like
it's just Yolo and they go wherever they
want like there's a process to make this
happen right and compare that to a car
that you just buy from a dealer and the
dealer sells it to you they may never
see it again it might be ten years later
it's still in the road it's never been
into a shop and you have no idea what's
going on with it even figure this we
bricked three head units in the Jeep and
no one knew that we even tried to hack
it over that period of time right well
my dealer knew but your dealer did but
you know as a whole they they didn't
right right if for some reason this car
comes in and something it's bricked
we're like well let's let's do an
investigation this is yeah weird yeah my
dealer just knew I was having some
serious radio problems sold you lemon I
know they really did they finally got it
right on the third time so the other
thing you get from these this the fact
that we're a ride-sharing service that
owns cars as opposed to selling cars is
we can monitor where they go all the
time we can monitor what they're doing
we can there's something this message is
constantly saying everything's okay or
not okay and where you wouldn't
necessarily want that on a car that you
bought like I don't want Ford to know
that I'm driving my Mustang down the
road or whatever but it's okay in this
situation because it's you know you
don't know in the car yeah now I mean we
have to secure these things but at the
same time when you have a constant
stream of telemetry information coming
back you know more about what is on the
car and what's happening in real time
you could imagine having things like an
intrusion detection system or true in
prevention system that's like hey I saw
some weird-ass these are net frames and
then you can act accordingly so one of
the most important things about these
cars since we're not trying to sell
is we don't have to try to sell all
these features that security people hate
and that customers love so you don't
want to like you know you wouldn't sell
car necessarily now that you couldn't
sync your phone to with Bluetooth
because like all your competitors are
doing that so you have to do it but you
can you can take the Bluetooth out of a
self-driving car because you it's a
self-driving car you don't you're in it
for ten minutes you don't need to sync
your phone to you can physically remove
a radio chip right like it's not you
don't even have to do say like oh hey
let's not have this featured enabled
like in some cars like you can say
remove the that that five from the board
right and so you get you end up in a
situation where one of the attacks they
the one the academics did that just
can't happen in this car because it
doesn't even have a Bluetooth chip
anymore so so yeah and you can do that
same for Wi-Fi or you know the the the
stock head unit you can just rip that
out because you don't need to be jamming
on your tunes while you're in a
self-driving car and and at least for
the time being
these self-driving cars or ride-sharing
cars right which means they're I think
were released as that at one point it
was like the average ride is two miles
or less right people are gonna be in
these cars for minutes not hours so
they're not actually too concerned with
having Bluetooth or any of this other
stuff they kind of just want to get
where they're going and so we can use
that like the best thing you can do
instead of trying to secure a Wi-Fi
stack or secure a Bluetooth stack is
just remove it and then it's definitely
not gonna have any bugs we we are very
unpopular gentlemen sometimes when we're
like oh yeah just rip that out like
physically like it rip it out and like a
customer - I don't want it it's out see
so that's the basically our job is
removing code and removing hardware
that's the biggest thing that we
contribute to the car we benefit through
obscurity at this point - now obviously
this isn't you know true security but at
this given time
you can't go grab one of our cars with
one of our sensor packages and our
compute in it only we have those things
it took Charlie and I nine ish months
with the Jeep and we physically had it
in our persons and we're kind of
reversing stuff all day long right now
this is one of our advantages you can't
go out and grab this car why don't you
hack an airplane the reason I would hack
an airplane because I can't get an
airplane I can't keep airplay in my
house to figure out how to hack it right
right and that's
matter of fact I'm not you know so the
same applies to this so it's quite what
you'd read in the press
you can't just hack something without
ever having seen it and like no matter
how good you are so the only person I've
ever seen blind pop something on the
first try was Neil Mehta and this was
like some weird service and this was
back when I was at IBM x-force that's
the only time I've witnessed that
happening and that was before like that
was before their snack Canaries and
Neil's badass but like that's what I'm
saying it's it's impossible to do this
if you're just blind right I mean we
don't rely on this solely it just
happens to be something that it works in
our favor so I mean it's it's not all
happy things like we're talking about
how easy self-driving car security is
well it's it's kind of hard to so let's
talk about some of the things that make
it really hard so we before we talked
about Ethernet and how it's basically
ubiquitous when it comes to self-driving
cars and probably the modern automobile
the hard part about this right now is
most Ethernet is UDP packets just just
just hammer as much information across
the wire as possible that means when you
talk to a supplier like oh okay we're
gonna do TLS ensure that communications
secure we don't even have a TCP stack
and you're like well like we can't
do TLS you're like oh well can you can
you do that it's like well we came to
you TCP it's like damn okay the drive
board that right it's one of those
things where it evolved out of the
necessity of bandwidth not out of the
necessity of kind of security and
integrity so yeah you end up in a
situation where you could figure out you
could take the lessons learned in the
corporate world and enterprise world and
say like ok we've got an Ethernet switch
we know how to secure these things so
let's do it
and then but the very first time you try
to do something you run into these kind
of roadblocks that these are not laptops
these are ECU's that don't do like this
examiner technic even the Linux 802 1x
client works fairly well but you don't
even have such things right now in these
type of components do a search for
yourself yeah so here's the L dine is
the biggest manufacturer of lidar so if
you go to their site and you want to
know about 802 1 X support for that it
they don't even talk about it like it
doesn't exist and then like if you go
and ask it about TLS suite
two bits yeah so they actually had TLS
uh no wait actually what they have
terrestrial laser scanner shade oh well
how to lock I'm sure that's right it
sounds rad but rather than TLS actually
but it doesn't help you when it comes
time to secure the data that's going
from the lidar to the to the computer
yep so yeah those are a bunch of hard
things but again we talked about having
to prioritize this stuff just like in
the corporate or network world you don't
want to you're not gonna try to chase
every bug in every flaw down right I'm
sure there are memory corruption flaws
in image parsers and things like that
but in reality what are you concerned
with you're concerned with remote
attacks that can compromise the vehicle
potentially pivot and physically control
it like that that is the the the biggest
kind of fear that we would have that can
happen and that's how we do our security
and that's how we model our threats is
that's what we're really concerned with
yeah if you work in the corporate world
you're familiar with the fact you don't
have unlimited resources if you did you
could secure everything but we have
finite resources and finite time and so
you have to prioritize where you put
your efforts and this is our number one
priority
we don't want an attack that scales to
the whole fleet and you can do remotely
and take down every single car at once
like that's the number one thing that we
focused on and make hard number two so
this the second thing we focus on and
once we have we've devoted enough
resources to that that we feel
comfortable the next thing is we worry
about
well remote attacks but you got to be
kind of close and so this is the things
that we talk about like would Bluetooth
or you know the base station the
malicious base station or something like
that and so these are still dangerous
like you don't have to have the car you
don't have to physically touch it but
you have to at least be nearby so it
doesn't scale to the whole fleet it just
scales to some location where the bad
guy is and so we worry about this but
not quite as much and and you know as
defenders we're familiar with how
attackers abuse these type of things
right you can think about this just as
you would any pen test if your
consultants write you're gonna look at
Wi-Fi you're gonna look at whatever
radio they have you're gonna look at
Bluetooth so the reason we definitely
this is second on our priority list is
because it's kind of known attack
surface right the cell their vehicle
stuff is still pretty bespoke there's
only three groups on the on the plane
have kind of have done that but this
stuff is you know kind of more
commoditized the next up is physical
attack so we do care about physical
attacks because they can affect the car
but not as much because if you've got a
physically tamper with the car it's
you're more likely to get caught it
doesn't scale hopefully we can detect
these things have happened and so this
is lower on the priority list and
basically the three ways this could
happen is you could imagine someone
plugging a device into a port that's in
the car or wiring a device directly into
a can bus or trying to reflash the
firmware on devices we have trying to
become a plus certified on our compute
stack yeah he looks like he already got
that certification yeah and and the cool
thing is when you're focusing on the
remote attacks and the remote aspect a
lot of it is you know authorization and
integrity issues and these also help
resolve the physical issues right you
could imagine that certain messages are
signed so they're the only you know the
proper authority can say turn the wheel
of car even if you're physically jacked
in you're not gonna have our signing
keys and you shouldn't be able to get
them and therefore that physical attack
might be kind of moot as well so I
mentioned this earlier and some of the
attacks that you hear about in the press
that get all the headlines are stuff
that we actually don't care about so
there's this one this article about like
oh by putting tape on stop signs you can
trick self-driving cars into not
stopping wrong right wrong so this is an
example of if a reporter would have
asked us we'd have said this is stupid
and then they wouldn't have quoted us
and then the article still what it came
out exactly like this
but the point is that the way that their
attack worked is they were using like
the camera would see the thing and use
OCR to figure out what it said and now
they think it says love or something
instead of stop I don't know why there
would be a love sign up but anyway we'll
have to stop baby love it so there's so
the point is that the the subject cars
don't do that self-driving cars don't
take you know camera images and try to
parse out the signs from the image
that's not the way they work the way
they work is they have a detailed map
the map says where the stop signs are no
matter what you put on the stop sign you
tear the stop sign down car still going
to stop because it knows
was a stop signs supposed to be there
because it's on the map it doesn't even
look for a stop sign just knows where
the stop signs are another thing to
realize too is yes these cars do machine
learning right but how do you train
those machine learning models you have
hundreds if not thousands of labelers so
when I said they're out mapping those
Street taking pictures and everything
everything that the machine learning
engine can't figure out you physically
sent a person there are rooms full of
people at uber at cruise at way mo
clicking saying yes that is a stop sign
yes that is a bicycle so again it's not
just hey take a picture of some sign and
we think it's a stop sign like they're
the machine learning models they use are
heavily groomed and take thousands of
man-hours to do so again it's not just
some open-source software package you're
good and it works like there's a lot of
work involved basically the theme of
this talk is we just rain on all other
research that's not a first but here's
another one that we want to rain on so
we already talked about this a bit so
it's like I'll Jam the GPS and crash all
the self-driving cars I already said
self-driving cars don't use GPS they use
localization so Jam all you want doesn't
matter exactly yeah these cars no you
know like we said up to the centimeter
where they're going so as long as they
know where they're at when they start
you don't need anything it just kind of
knows it has this map and it can drive
around it can go to point A and point B
right so maybe someday in the future
that would be a deal for a like KITT but
it's not a deal for self-driving cars at
level four all right so let's talk about
what we do and the sort of defense that
we build into self-driving cars to
secure them right so we care a lot about
that and we spend every day trying to do
it and these are sort of the some of the
the approaches that we use to try to
defend I think the the biggest one that
we really try to do and this is probably
because Charlie and I have spent most of
our career on the opposite side of the
table breaking stuff is reducing a stack
surface we know for sure that we can't
write secure software yet we know for
sure we can't make secure Hardware
because we've made careers out of break
in that stuff so what's the best method
to secure this remove it if you don't
need that software off if you don't need
the hardware kill it right this is
probably the the biggest thing that we
do because
we know that if it's removed it's
actually more secure yeah the next thing
we do is we make sure that the code that
is running on all the computers in the
car is really our code and we use a
secure boot for that verified boot and
so we make sure that the the code that's
running is cryptographically signed only
we can do that and so this makes sure
that it hasn't been tampered with or
that no one else can can reflash it if
you saw in all three attacks what
happened all three attackers us the you
wash and the keying team we had to
reprogram something with code signing a
verification any bit modified to that
code would fail right and it wouldn't be
be flashed not to say that that would
completely prevent us from figuring out
a way to execute code and you know not
all verified boot implementations are
flawless but it makes it much much more
difficult right so if fiat-chrysler
would have had code signing on that
gateway chip when we were attacking the
jeep we probably would have never gotten
passing I remember we had that bug
though I know but I'm pretty lazy I
don't know he would have got it we
wouldn't have so we wouldn't we wouldn't
have anyway the point is it would have
been so much harder that if we couldn't
just reprogram that chip with no
security at all but if they would have
had code signing it would have been we
probably would have had a black hat
talked about how we almost made the car
move yeah well we would know we do have
black guy talking like 20/20 about how
we've hacked the 2014 Jeep so it would
have been delayed many years oops I
forgot that's all ones like that yeah
key storage for things like that like I
said identity identity and authorization
for these type of things is paramount we
want to ensure that messages that
control the vehicle that physically
control it are actually signed by the
proper authorities and verified on the
other end again we've we've pulled keys
out of hardware before we've pulled keys
out of software so we want to make sure
that a lot of these devices that we're
using have things like hardware security
modules or tpms right so we can have
some some anchor some trust anchor in
there so we can sign things and verify
them without having to worry about
someone grabbing our vehicle ripping one
of these out and having our keys forever
yeah and so next thing encryption that's
a no-brainer we encrypt the data when it
leaves a car we encrypt what we can on
the
so if it gets stolen we don't lose that
code sign we already mentioned so any
code that we download any updates have
to be signed
make sure it's legitimate so we don't
just accepting code blindly up I think I
message met mentioned message signing
several times but I think one of the key
pieces that's lacking now and we're
spending a fair amount of effort on is
threat detection we know again as
attackers that there's really no such
thing as an unhackable system we make
careers out of doing that but we do want
to know if something is astray and the
good part about these networks while
there are similar to your corporate data
centers they're dissimilar in we know
what traffic will be there there's not
users browsing the web right even though
Ethernet traffic is there it's standard
we know what we should expect and if we
see things that stray from that we can
at least raise a flag all right so a
bunch of computers that we design
talking to each other in a very standard
predictable way and so attacks things
that are unusual things like we did in
the Jeep really stand out so it's pretty
easy to detect that something weirds
going on let's wrap it up wrap it up be
as you see right now there there have
been very few instances of remote
attacks the cars for physical control
that being said we're super concerned
with it because it and deals entails
passenger safety and driverless cars
kind of make some things easier because
we have some liberties that most
coroner's don't they come home every day
and some things harder because you know
there are no steering wheels and they
are more complex and there's a lot more
to review alright and and so like if
you're a researcher out there like the
reason we release our tools and we wrote
a bunch of papers is we want to get
people involved so continue continue
hacking stuff break cars write papers
release all your information so everyone
can learn from it right I mean we've had
many times where people came up to us
were like hey thanks for leaves and all
those papers now my department has more
budget at car company to not be named
right so it's cool we want people to do
that when we've only looked at a few
cars we want people to look at a bunch
of cars so then we can have you have
even more data points and even think of
the overall security all these vehicles
in a better fashion yeah when we hacked
a car we didn't want to be the car
hackers forever we wanted to be like
those guys who hacked the car along with
like the 50 other people who hacked cars
and it helped find bugs and that sort of
thing so keep it up with that being said
thanks for sticking around thanks for
countermeasure for having us we had a
blast
[Applause]
[Music]