[Music]
how many of you if you're trying to
decide which cybersecurity solution you
want to implement you're thinking you're
deciding should be Cisco should be
checkpoint how many of you would go into
Google look at the local psychic and
consult with her anybody yes okay no
there are some 1% of you okay now what
if I told you my friend Dan
he knows this incredible psychic the
amazing Zelda and he called her and she
told him go with the checkpoint solution
with firewall that was in September four
weeks later he still hasn't had a breach
she's amazing
so if you know that I say should use her
she's got a track record then who would
feel confidence in doing that hey okay
so now this might sound like a silly
question but seriously this is my life
okay working in data science and when
people find out what we do we work in
predictive analytics etc I get oh so you
guys are like Cambridge analytic
right now we as a serious science
company I employ PhDs and physics
masters and machine learning no we're
not like the guy at Cambridge analytical
high school dropout the pink hair who
claims that he got Briggs it and he did
the Trump election and all of those
things no we are not like that and and
so I wanted to talk to you today Mike
asked me to to speak today
on the topic of Cambridge analytic abhi
cuz I know and he knows that a lot of
you in your jobs not not just as in
cybersecurity but as chief information
officers etc are asked to look at
solutions and things that might violate
privacy your privacy protocols the laws
of the country and and so I wanted to
talk to you a bit today not just about
privacy but about
junk science if you will because I think
a lot of the time when we look at the
the stories and the coverage of
Cambridge analytic it was all about
whether or not they had violated privacy
and hardly anything on whether or not
they were actually responsible for the
things that they claimed to be
responsible for and if you look at the
science and you look at how they work
you will see that nothing that they did
no methodology that they followed could
have possibly been responsible for the
things they claim to be they are
essentially charlatans and I think it's
important to point that out because if
we believe that we have to violate our
clients privacy in order to get results
for the marketing team then you're much
more likely to to breach privacy and to
break the law but if you know that it's
not going to work anyway and that you
can get the marketing team the results
that they want be accurate and you don't
have to violate in any privacy in fact
you'll do better if you don't then
you're not tempted to do those things so
I want it to look a little bit at the
science what we know and to work and not
work in data science and talk a little
bit about privacy laws and how they're
likely to evolve in this space in Canada
and just so you know noting that
Cambridge analytic Adid was illegal in
Canada in fact I rap funded their their
company out in Vancouver they they did
not violate any Canadian privacy laws
they did violate European privacy laws
but they weren't operating in Europe so
none of what they did actually violates
Canadian privacy law yet but I wouldn't
go out and buy systems like that or buy
similar companies because probably those
laws are going to change in the wake of
that in public outcry and so it's not
something you want to invest in
necessarily but how do we know that it
that it didn't work and Cambridge
analytic a what they did was they sent
out surveys to people and based on those
surveys they created profiles of what
people were like and they had one of
five categories it's the ocean the ocean
psychographic profiles right open
chinches agreeable neurotic now this is
not new they claim that this is
something they invented they didn't I
remember seeing the ocean psychographics
when I worked in advertising 10 years
ago up on the wall in the boardroom it's
not you and you cannot use it to predict
how somebody is going to vote why not
well I'm feeling neurotic right now
right because I'm standing up in a
podium and I'm speaking but I'm not
neurotic all the time okay at least I
don't think so maybe my my co-workers
think so but I'm not neurotic all the
time I'm just neurotic now if you ask me
who I'm going to vote for now I might
say Donald Trump because frankly when
I'm up and I'm speaking he makes me feel
good about myself right but after a nice
glass of scotch tonight and I'm relaxing
I'm gonna feel more open and more
agreeable I'm going to change my opinion
the lesson is you cannot first of all
people's personalities change throughout
the day they changed the context that
they're in that's why I was there's
there's all sorts of you know I get
asked all sorts of questions or there's
this technology where you strap this
thing on to your brain and measure your
measures your brainwaves while you're
shopping for shoes and it says okay
you're this type of shopper well that's
if I'm shopping with for shoes of my own
if I'm shopping for shoes with a toddler
I have a totally different personality
right so are you gonna be measuring me
all the time it cost fifty thousand
dollars to wear one of these things it's
silly people's personalities change
throughout the day they change
throughout time and even if somebody
stayed the same way all the time they
were always agreeable or they were
always neurotic you still can't use that
label to say how somebody is going to
vote you also can't change somebody's
vote now think think about you can't get
people to do things that they don't
believe in so for example look at the
the the campaign to stop people from
drinking and driving how long did it
take the government with those ads
before we actually started to see a
reduction in drinking and driving it
actual fact on the streets anybody want
to hazard a guess
yeah took 20 years it took an entire
generation of advertising to do
something that makes logical sense it
was similar to quitting smoking it took
an entire generation it took kids seeing
their parents and grandparents dying
from the effects of lung cancer it took
a lot a lot a lot of PR work so to say
that you're gonna change somebody's vote
in a 30-day campaign is pretty crazy and
frankly I actually think people are just
using quebra gentle that it gives an
excuse because Americans don't want to
admit that they voted for Donald Trump
and they did he won fair and square it's
not because of ads that people saw from
Cambridge analytical so what Cambridge
analytic did with the business they were
in was micro targeting and as a CIO or
somebody works in information technology
you will often be asked from people in
the marketing group or people in your
business team we've got this new
fandangled solution it does micro
targeting it's an app it's gonna follow
Mike everywhere he goes it's gonna
record everybody he dates what he eats
for supper what he has for lunch what
he's doing and based on that we can
figure out that he's going to buy grapes
at 2:00 o'clock on Tuesday at the Metro
okay you know right away that this is
this is not it's not possible to track
what an individual is going to do even
if you have reams and reams and reams of
information on that person think about
your own life how many times this week
did your plans whatever they were get
derailed right you might have had plans
to do something the kid is sick your
wife falls down the stairs you're going
to meet with a co-worker he or she
cancels your plans are derailed so even
you can't figure out what you are going
to do tomorrow or this weekend you might
have plans but those plans will change
so for me to try and figure out because
I work in data science and I have lots
of data on you what you're going to do
this weekend I'm going to have a very
very high margin of error and I might be
right about one or two of you but if I
said everybody in this room I've got
enough date I'm gonna figure out what
all of you are doing two o'clock on
Saturday
day you should know right then and there
that's a snake oil salesman because
nobody can do that what we can do is
what actuaries have been doing for
decades in fact is do population trend
research so while the fortune-teller
probably only gets it right 1 or 2
percent of the time and that's why she's
living in a tent and you know scraping
by your insurance brokers are also in
the prediction business
they're called actuaries and they're not
living in a tent ok they're living very
well and they're making billions of
dollars in profits why because they
might look at you and say Ted
you look fantastic your parents live to
a hundred you don't smoke you don't
drink you're not neurotic I'm gonna give
you a million dollar life insurance
policy and then you walk out of the
office you get hit by a car
he's just lost a million dollars but
that's ok because he's got a hundred
thousand more people like you so he'll
be wrong 5 percent of the time but he'll
be right 95 percent of the time and that
kind of research works and we know that
so if you're going to be doing market
research or trend analysis you've got to
do it the way stat scan does it the way
Health Canada does it the way anybody
who has ever had success in research
does it you're looking at the aggregate
you're looking at population level
trends now that doesn't mean you can't
see trends and demographics that you
can't see trends in psychographics
absolutely you can but the longer out
you try to predict the less accurate it
will be it's just like the weather I can
tell you later today it's probably going
to be gray and damp if I try to tell you
what the weather's going to be like in
January
aside from cold I'm less likely to be
accurate ok so and that's because people
change etc etc of what I'm gonna buy
depends on somebody's birthday it is or
what-have-you things just change so
number one population level statistics
very accurate micro-targeting very
inaccurate what does that mean for
privacy is there any value
having reams and reams and reams of data
about Mike Zeus or am I better off
having reams of data about a hundred
thousand people like Mike and trying to
see trends avocados trending the keto
diet is trending or it's not trending I
think you know as people who have a
science-based background the population
level research is gonna be a lot more
accurate we've been doing micro
targeting for a while loyalty programs
what are what are companies doing now
they're getting out of the loyalty
programs why because they're very
expensive to run they're 2 to 3% of
revenue top-line revenue and they're not
giving you they're not improving their
improving sales in the sense that people
come back to you which is cool but you
can do that with better marketing better
pricing being more competitive having a
better product which is the better way
to compete rather than bribing people to
buy your product from a data point of
view loyalty programs go out of date
very very quickly we get a lot of
customers to say can we give you our
loyalty program information we say well
is it more than six months old yeah then
no no thank you
anything more than six months old we
were the official pollster for the
Ontario election 124 ridings we got a
hundred and eighteen bang on of the ones
we didn't get right five of them were
within a thousand votes so there were
only two that we really didn't get bang
on so we're able to do that with
population level research we now have
people coming up to us saying can I use
that AI that you used for the Ontario
election it's out of date so we have to
start it all over again and the Ontario
election was in June okay so data like I
said if you're trying to forecast too
far out you will be inaccurate if you've
got data in your system that is a year
old that is six months old forget it we
can get much much more accurate data
just going online and doing proper
sampling of the population mmm
what about apps that that that do
loyalty and track you obsessively and
all that again very expensive let's say
you're working for the LCBO and you've
got an app and you know that Mike likes
to drink Malbec and every time he drives
by sorry I'm picking on you the only
person whose name I know every time he
drives by the
see Bo he gets a pop-up thing for a
Malbec but now Mike's dating somebody
who doesn't drink he's moved off from
the Malbec or maybe he's moved away from
here altogether so he's now living in
Kapuskasing and you don't know what he's
drinking over there you get the picture
people change not only that but mike is
going to get sick of the pop-ups we know
this to apps that do these types of
things lasts on average 30 days before
people take them off their phone
take them off their system they get
tired of it they get tired of being
messaged to so we do know science does
show us that micro targeting works in
the short-term you will see short term
results
that's what hooks you in it's kind of
like when you go gambling you go to the
casino lochley me and you win a few
times and then now you're there all
night because you got it literally got
hooked micro-targeting will hook you
that way but it doesn't work in the long
term and it's not good science so what
does that mean from a policy perspective
we've been lobbying really hard and we
are you know an AI company that works in
human behavior research we have had the
tires kicked on us thankfully at
Parliament Hill by the Privacy
Commissioner we do work with Health
Canada we do a lot of work so there is
no privacy violation and yet it is
extremely accurate
like I said Ontario election 118 at 124
ridings no political pundit got that
close and that was with no human
intervention just the AI predict the
election how does she do it getting
representative samples of people on
social media they get all sorts of
questions about that isn't social media
bias that's why you get representative
samples with population level research
where we're not capturing names we're
not capturing any personal personally
identifiable information we can still
get extremely extremely accurate
information from a firmer for our
customers and from a policy perspective
so we are big fans not wholesale of the
GDP our implementation in Europe there
are some issues with it and we're
working with government here to make
sure we don't make the same mistakes
that were made in that legislation but
definitely very big advocates for
protecting personal information
just because it's the right thing to do
from a policy perspective and from a
privacy perspective and for your brand
but because it's actually going to get
you better results from a business
perspective hmm we'll have a lot of
customers who say will you show us your
algorithm because other companies won't
show us their algorithm that's probably
because they don't have one but
absolutely we do publish our algorithm
there is no black box we don't believe
in that we think that companies who are
working in this space should publish
their algorithms should make it clear
what they're doing to eliminate bias in
training because we get that a lot as
well how do I know that the results
aren't biased because we've all heard
about the recidivism AI that you know
was locking up visible minorities all
the time and things like that so yes we
have to be open about that about the
algorithms that we use there are no
black boxes and if you're ever working
with companies in this space it is
absolutely crucial that you get to look
under those covers because otherwise how
do you know a that this is real science
and and be that what they are giving you
is going to be unbiased and accurate mmm
most importantly and it's important to
be able to distinguish between a
methodology and a tool so we get all the
time oh we have social media listening
we're using radian6 we're using Sysomos
we're using all these things those are
tools and each time that you run them
you will get a different results why
because they're using reservoir sampling
so it takes in the first 50,000 posts
analyzes that but there are trillions of
posts on any given topic they're doing
keyword searches they're not doing it
they're not looking at representative
random samples of the population so of
course you know if you're doing a
keyword search you're getting a biased
result because you're only looking for
people speaking on that topic what you
want to be able to do is pull up you
want to do a people search not a keyword
search get a representative sample and
say how many people are talking about
this topic and what are they saying
you'll get radically different results
when you do the keyword it will be
different every time and that's why when
you when you see in the paper they'll
say this
survey is right within one point two
percentage points 19 times out of 20
what they mean is if you were to give
this methodology to 20 different
scientists and they were all to run it
they'd get the exact 19 of them would
get the exact same results that is
science based research when it's
repeatable if you were to do the same
thing with some of these tools night 20
people go out and do it 19 of them would
have radically different results that is
not a science-based research study so
these are the types of things that you
can that you can do to ensure that
you're getting real science in your data
research that you are not violating
privacy that you're not subject to to
bias and and that's about it I didn't
want to make it too long during lunch I
wanted to leave things open for for
questions yes we are doing the midterm
elections if anybody has questions about
that in the US but are there any
questions that people have because I
wanted to get into questions pretty
quickly so that we get engaged yep yes
so the so let me see if I got your
question right so trying to predict how
each person will vote is impossible but
could I if I figured out the
demographics and the personalities the
people in the room influenced them to
vote a different way if I had enough
time so now it's important to understand
what I would not be doing is selling
selling skis to people who live in the
desert okay so it's it's really almost
impossible to get people to do things
that they wouldn't otherwise do or that
they don't believe in it takes a long
time to change public opinion normally
but what we can do so in the work that
we've done we've seen that it's probably
about 1% of any kind of advertising or
work that you put out there will
actually move the needle we are able to
see what that 1% is and it doesn't have
to be digital we can look at speeches we
could look at television ads we can look
at bus ads and we can see what's working
and what isn't working so that we can
concentrate on those things that are
working now we did do some work for a
company in the United States last year
they had a chemical mostly used in farms
but the protest was coming from people
who were using it on their lawns and
there was concern that the that the
chemical could have adverse health
effects specifically on children and
pets now the research most of the
research showed that it didn't there was
one bit of research that showed that it
could so it was going up in front of the
EPA to be to be voted on two things that
were interesting number one when
something goes in front of the EPA in
the United States the cases that are
going up unlike an Environment Canada or
we have a hearing it's closed there
everything is open it's up on the
website we're going to be looking at
this chemical whatever and then all
these all the groups like Greenpeace and
the World Wildlife Fund or whatever can
then come and launch a campaign against
this this chemical so they hired us to
say how many protests are we going to
get when we go in front of the EPA we
told them and because we don't ask any
questions or anything right we're
gleaning all this information quietly we
told them you won't get any between zero
and two thousand because there's always
an interval and the the person who had
hired us said well that's just
ridiculous like you said I I was into
this AI thing but now I totally don't
believe in it because you know he said
you have to realize here in the US there
are people who their full-time job is to
protest so they're definitely going to
be protesting with the lowest number of
calls we've ever had when we've gone in
front the EPA is three hundred and fifty
thousand so we had our tail between our
legs we walked out very embarrassed to
this day that was last year they haven't
had a single call okay so the AI was
bang on so they hired us back now there
was legislation to ban the chemical and
they wanted to know and at the time that
this legislation was coming through
fifty six percent of the population was
against the chemical so they were going
to lose in public opinion they hired us
and we did what's called message testing
to figure out now this is not
brainwashing people it's important to
understand the distinction it's not
convinced you know lying to people or
convincing them of things that aren't
true it's saying here are we've only got
one kick at the can here there's lots we
could say we could say oh look there
have been 1,200 studies
you know only one of them said it was
bad there could be messaging that says
look if we get rid of this chemical
farmers aren't going to be able to make
food in the price of food I mean they
will be able make food but the price of
food is gonna skyrocket it's gonna
affect your pocketbook so there are all
sorts of different messages they like
the farmer one we said no go with the
studies there have been lots of studies
and they show this they went and we
showed we were able to show them if you
did the farmer message it won't change
public opinion at all but if you do this
other one it will and they did the other
one it changed public opinion and the
legislation didn't pass so it's a long
way of answering your question because
these things are complicated but I want
to make it clear that we're not we're
not trying to convince people to do
things they don't believe in we're
making sure that people get the
information that is relevant to them
they want to know how many studies have
been done and what is what has been the
research on it when they're worried
about your health you're less concerned
about the price of corn okay once you've
got your health squared away then then
you have time to worry about the price
of corn so so that's what the research
showed and it worked very effectively so
all that to say you can use this that's
a branch of science called prescriptive
analytics it's where you're changing
behavior you're changing people's minds
it's very difficult to do it's a nascent
science prediction is much easier
prescriptive is much harder and it
typically takes quite a bit of time like
a year in a 30 day election campaign
when things are happening all the time
there's scandals resistors that one
thing we did find very clearly in the
Ontario election and other elections
we've had we're by the way the only
company in this country that got Bragg's
it right at 52% plus or minus one point
to one of only 16 companies in the world
to get that right so prediction is still
hard one things we notice is that
scandals don't affect public opinion the
way politicians think they do so we were
looking at it for the the Ontario
election that just passed and I was on
TV Oakes was giving regular commentary
and then they had the political pundits
who told who were telling us that these
scandals are really having a big effect
and I was the lone wolf saying no no
we've we're looking
we're looking at the stuffing the ballot
boxes and you know this set no thing and
Rob Doug Ford's widow and and it wasn't
moving a needle and one of the pundits
said you know I think Aaron's just
hearing all the Liberals who are posting
because they liberals have got a lot of
people posting and I said glad you
brought that up that's why we do
representative sampling we're able to
tell the difference those people aren't
in our sample but all that to say the
the scandals were not affecting how
people are going to vote what was
affecting except for one scandal which
was the NDP I thought it would be when
the NDP got the budget off by billion
dollars I thought that would hurt them
because you know that kind of hurts the
NDP where they're naturally hurting but
it didn't when she apologized everybody
forgave Andrew Horvath for that but the
Poppy's you know when they said poppies
were filling landfills or whatever it
was a slag veterans that did affect
their vote and the Hitler comment did
affect their vote but no other scandal
in the election was effective what was
effective was the tariffs Donald Trump
that really heard Andrea Horvath because
people thought okay well Andrew Horvath
space she came from Hamilton right so
steel town and and also sue st. Marie
where Algoma was headquartered they just
didn't see the NDP going up against
Donald Trump so that that affected their
popularity so we are able to see in a
very granular way what changes opinion
and if and we don't work for political
parties but if we did we would have said
talk about those those steel tariffs
don't bother with the sex scandals and
all of that because it really doesn't
change people's opinion at the end of
the day yep they can do that right now
so we're working with the number of
Elections bodies in other countries for
that so it is interesting I gave a talk
on this not too long ago on the whole
fake news thing and it was funny because
it was the government of Canada and they
were asking for people to come up with
you know what are your solutions for how
how we deal with fake news which we call
manufactured news just because we don't
want to use the same terminology as you
know the propaganda and so manufactured
news and how do you how do you detect it
now the others all came out
with okay well we're gonna look at the
news we're gonna have text analytics and
we're gonna say if they talk about hate
and all that kind of stuff and I got up
and I said okay the last okay that makes
us China right I think if we start going
through the content of what people are
putting out there and say no that
content I don't like that content take
that off that's hateful and you're
getting yourself into a really
precarious situation so what we said is
fake I'm saying you know manufactured
news or any kind of content that's put
out by it whether it's a state actor or
any other kind of actor moves through
the network differently from credible
news okay so if you come up with
something says okay Justin Justin
Trudeau's a pedophile
okay reasonable people are probably not
going to be circulating that to their
friends and family right and we get that
all the time where you get things that
you know we're obviously fake you don't
you don't spread it around because you
don't want to look like that person so
but there are certain pockets of the
population that will circulate it and
bots will circulate it so what we do is
we take a representative sample of the
population say 300,000 Canadians who we
know are representative of the
population and there's all sorts of ways
that we know that they're representative
but they are randomly chosen and they
they have the whole we can we can figure
out a lot about the population by you
know using text analytics and then we
just take the firehose from Twitter or
from Facebook or we have you just take
that firehose which is everything that
goes through or we do a reservoir sample
news that is manufactured we'll go
through quickly through the bots and
through certain populations may be alt
dot right or whatever we can create a
sample of alt out right and it'll move
quickly through those populations but in
the quote-unquote average population
that story will not circulate at the
same rate and that's what we do we say
this story is circulating in a
manufactured way put it aside and let a
human being look at it and make that
judgment and we feel that's a much
better way of handling that situation
than trying
to be the the the police who decide
whether or not something is worthy of
being circulated and we and we do that
also for things where somebody's saying
the polling station has changed things
like that we can we can detect those
things when the shooting happened in
Parliament Hill here in Ottawa we were
we were getting accurate reports of what
was happening before the police tweeted
them out we knew that Stephen Harper was
headed to Meech Lake because we were
seeing the tweets people saw him going
by in the car so all of those things so
from a security perspective from a fraud
perspective is definitely things that we
can do right now we could also prove
whether or not by the way Cambridge
analytic a really was effective in
moving the needle if they give the ads
that they put out there because
everything on social media is still
there we can go back to 2012 get a
representative sample we can go back to
the election to brexit to Trump and we
can and we can prove once and for all
but of course they're not they're not
giving that content up but we have put
that challenge out to them yes
24% of people will still vote for him
yes it's really interesting there
there's so the question was Trump says
he could shoot somebody in the middle of
Times Square and people will still vote
for him and yes that is true we there
are people who would still vote for him
he's got a good 24 percent of the base
in the United States that that will vote
for him I don't know if he's maybe if he
shot somebody in Times Square and and
you're not going to move that needle and
that's why we say to a lot of our
customers see these people over here
you're not changing that it's the people
in the middle or the people who are
unsure that's that sure that's your
target market and that's why when we're
when we say yes we can do prescriptive
analytics we can we can definitely use
marketing to to change minds and stuff
like that there's some people whose
minds you're never going to change and
interestingly because of the way the
boundaries are drawn in the United
States right now you know the Democrats
we're looking at getting about a 24 seat
majority in the midterms because the
Democrats are going to come out in high
numbers and the Trump supporters not but
if all the Trump supporters came
and all the Democrats came out or a
voter turnout were what it normally is
that's why you see everybody in the
states with the vote vote if voter
turnout were to say what it normally is
because Republicans are more likely to
vote than Democrats there would only be
a bit 11 seat difference which is kind
of astounding when you think of you know
what's going on there and that's that's
so with 24% of the vote and there's you
know over 400 districts in the United
States with just 24 percent support he
could almost you know come through and
win a majority but even even with with
that the the Democrats are gonna win
majority this time so what we're seeing
question I know there was another
question yep you oh yes the midterm yeah
so we are seeing a Democrat majority
like I said about by the 24 C's there
are still 80 districts that are very
much in contention so it could go either
way
but it looks like a Democrat majority
yes it's something about him we don't we
don't normally actually a sitting
president would have higher than 24%
actually like 24 percents really low for
somebody who's two years into his term
we we find it it differs from leader to
leader you know it's it's it's
interesting when we look at all of the
issues in the United States
Kojo G would have you all the issues
that are going on the only one that's
really moving the needle is the Brett
Kavanaugh issue
it's mobilizing women in ways that are
you know that it's actually mobilized
people that particular issue but nothing
else has NAFTA hasn't it's interesting
to that the jobs even though
unemployment's at 3.5%
one of the main things that's driving
youth to the polls in the midterms
because they almost never vote in
midterm elections is jobs because a lot
of educated Americans feel like young
graduates feel that these jobs are not
the kind of jobs they want you know
they're they don't want to work in the
coal mine they don't want to work in the
sector if you're graduating with a
degree and machine learning is Trump
doing the right thing for you you know
they don't feel that he is they feel the
it's not just having a job it's having
the right job so there's definitely a
big feeling of that their skills are not
going to be used and that America is not
poised for the economy of the future
there's definitely a a big current of
Americans who feel that way which is
unusual and the unemployment rate is so
low usually people are just happy about
that are there yep the biggest one we
see is sorry the question was what
mistakes do you see in the GDP are the
biggest one for us is explained ability
so from an AI perspective I'm speaking
here so explain ability is when you say
so for brexit for example we we saw it
was going to be a remain remain until
three days before the referendum and
then the AI toggled and said it's going
to be exit so I mean so we sent out a
press release the morning of before the
polls opened in England in Britain and
we said it's going to be an exit at 52%
plus or minus 1.2 like I said we were
the only company in this country that
said that so of course everybody who's
booking me for interviews right so I was
gonna be on CBC the next morning and
that night at 10 o'clock at night Nigel
Farage who was one of the leaders of the
exit group held a press conference and
said everybody go home we have lost even
though the results weren't in yet he
said my friends in the financial sector
hired the best pollsters in the world
and they all say it's going to be
remained and he was an exit guy so you
know so that producer at CBC texted me
10 o'clock at night and said you're
gonna be on first thing tomorrow morning
as the results are coming in right we
were just gonna be finding it at like
7:00 in the morning and Nigel Farage has
just conceded defeat do you want to
change your prediction because he's
feeling really sorry for me at this
point ray because he said you're gonna
be in with two others who say it's gonna
be remain so I call our chief scientists
at home are you sure
because I'm the one who's gonna like
look like the idiot backpedaling for 15
minutes live on the air and he said he
ran it again he said don't know what to
tell you Aaron it says exit at 52% so I
texted the producer back his name is
Howard Goldenthal you can verify with
him and I said we stand by our forecasts
it's going to be an exit at 52% and I
didn't sleep all night now and it was an
exit when I came in the other two they
told him don't come in you didn't get it
right the other two pollsters so it was
just me in the studio for 15 minutes
needing to explain what happened in
Britain right and so I spent the whole
night trying to figure out why is the AI
saying that that's why I say explain
ability is hard we had to go through
every hour for the last 72 hours
leading up to the referendum to see at
what point this thing toggled so we can
do explained ability we said to the AI
all right you know this event that event
this event that event nothing's moving
the needle we can say to the AI we can
unlike a human you can't say to a human
will pretend this event never happened
now how do you feel a person is not able
unless they're sociopathic or something
to divorce themselves from from that but
in AI can so you can say to an AI
pretend this never happened
now what is the result and it can
calculate that so as we were going
through all the events of the 72 hours
leading up to brexit and this is how we
know by the another reason we know
Cambridge analytic ydynt this unless
they shot Joe Cox is because we got up
to the assassination of Joe Cox and
before she died it was remain and then
we say Joe Cox is dead
exit okay now so then you think okay the
assassination of Joe Cox but it wasn't
the and by the way it wasn't like the
minute she died it was okay she died the
next day it still remain okay so we're
not thinking it's her assassination per
se what happened after her assassination
David Cameron gave a speech to the
nation and while he was speaking so we
went through his speaking engagement his
press conference and we
went through every line dad thought that
uh he gets to a point where he says
let's all observe silence in honor of
Joe Cox we're not gonna campaign we're
not going to go door to door you know we
want you to just observe this moment of
silence don't talk about it with your
friends and the a I said it was the
silence that caused the exit so why did
the silence cause the exit well okay
this is where it gets into explain
ability but what the a I noticed was
that if people came on with their
friends and said I'm thinking of voting
exit they would get pounced on your
xenophobe your anti-immigration your
this your that and so they would clam up
they'd go quiet and the AI noticed that
when they came back they tended to be
reading the pro exit stuff they tended
to be leaning more exit so the AI
rightly derived that once people went
silent they tend to toggle over to exit
they can't discuss their their their
fears so they take it out of the polls
we were seeing that with Trump as well
by the way silence is not good
keep keep people talking well unless you
you know you want your candidate to win
and then silence is good but all that to
say that explain ability took us a very
long time so your costs are gonna go
through the roof there are better ways
of making sure that your AI is not
biased or and the reason they want
explain ability is because of the whole
you know when they tried to use an AI
for calculating recidivism rates and the
AI was saying all black people are going
to you know commit crimes again more
than other people
that's a bias and us that's been
reflected in the AI because of the way
it was trained it wasn't a properly
trained AI so what you want to do is
make sure that your a is properly
trained so all those training materials
should be available because that will be
a lot more cost effective and lot more
effective than than doing explained
ability you want to make sure that your
algorithm is known and published I kind
of use the Phoenix example you know if
I'd given you all the code for Phoenix
ahead of time would you have known it
was going to screw up no you should have
done pilots in case studies okay so
there are ways of training it with
being overly burdensome and we think
explain ability is the wrong way to go
because sometimes you just won't be able
to explain it but what you will be able
to do is control the training and and
look at the algorithm yes
and what kind of controls do I have to
what
hold on I'm just gonna give you the
microphone sorry sorry I was just having
trouble hearing it turn it on maybe no
okay good say since you seem to have a
lot of influence and your data seems to
be very good in some ways how do you
deal with potential data and poisoning
from the internal like what kind of
controls you have to ensure that no
although your data from the outside may
be controlled
how about internally how are you
ensuring that it's not being yeah they
used to use your influence like whether
or not our staff are poisoning the data
staff or somebody potentially breaching
your systems to use that okay yes that's
an excellent question because and that's
so I'll answer the first one first with
staff it is it is so an nai is an
intelligence and like any intelligence
you know it's not that people asked me a
lot of time was the difference we in
analytics and AI and AI learns it learns
is we call it alien intelligence
actually at the office instead of
artificial because it is an intelligence
and you can bias it so one of the things
we don't allow right now our customers
to train their own ai's because you
really really need to know what you're
doing even our own staff do make
mistakes and we have ways of testing to
see whether or not they've made they
make mistakes because and we have found
that they do you and and they're highly
trained and they do this every day and
they still make mistakes and the and the
AI comes out bias I'll give you an
example just a simple example
statistical example because this is all
statistics in countries like in our
country in our judicial system we have a
we have a policy of ul when you're up
for trial that you are innocent until
proven guilty there are other countries
where you are guilty until proven
innocent and in countries where the
hypothesis is guilty until proven
innocent the conviction rate is actually
quite a bit higher statistically
significant so whatever hypothesis you
give the ai's
we had an example where we were doing
some work for a municipality and they
wanted to know are people worried about
crime the researcher mistakenly put in
crime is a problem well that's not what
you say to an AI because now the AI
makes the assumption crime is a problem
and needs to find evidence that it's not
a problem
so it's biased in favor of crime as the
problem so we had to fix it and say just
crime now it turned out to that they
thought city council were the crime
absolutely literally so we had to be
more precise what do we mean by crime
because obviously council didn't want
that kind so so you know you have to be
very precise and it's very hard to do so
that's all we don't aletter allow our
customers to do it now that's going to
change because obviously that puts a
human in the loop we are creating an AI
that trains the AI again to keep it very
very kind of professional and when that
happens there will be a lot more
precision in doing it and plus we'll be
able to work much more quickly after
that and the second question about
breaches the the beauty of it is because
facebook is paying for all the storage
and Twitter and Instagram and all those
guys we don't collect any data what we
do is we collect results so we'll crawl
through and people will say you know
that you know what I say to people is
weak we can't see anything that other
people can't see we don't breach any
privacy if you got your privacy turned
on you'd be surprised how many people
don't have the privacy turned on the way
they do I think they do but anyway you
know we're not we're not breaching any
privacy and what we look at is we know
what we're looking for and we just it's
ticking boxes so if you were to break
into our network there are no names
we're not going to pay to store all
these tweets and all these messages what
we're looking for is voting this way or
not voting this way or figuring out the
information so that we come up with a
game plan what people are feeling what's
motivating them that's what we're
capturing but it's not tied to
informations tied to demographics so 40
year old men feel this way what have you
no you're good yeah no that's a
that's a great question and I'd say
that's a concern so for example with we
had it just now we sent it a press
release this morning on the midterm
elections and we had to be very careful
we were the official pollster for tbo
and we had our a I was able to determine
if Andrew Horvath can get these writings
she can win the election she has to get
those writings it was like a path to
victory if she didn't get them and that
was how we we could tell early in the
night that she you know wasn't gonna win
but we were very careful but it's it's
it's an internal decision that we make
that we did not reveal those writing's
on the air we revealed one just to kind
of illustrate it and funny enough we
then tracked it so we did reveal one of
the writings and people in that like the
parties descended on that writing and
changed it change the outcome so it it
definitely can happen and so we are very
and you know do our people influenced by
polls yes they are we can prove that
absolutely so when you know there is
that that's you know there have been
questions about that before you know
because the political parties hire their
own pollsters and then they'll put at a
poll and say oh the Liberals are winning
or what-have-you
that does influence people so that's
true not only you know for an AI company
it's true for any company and
advertising what have you is the news
influencing or is the poll that you're
releasing it would have you influencing
public opinion and we know that it does
and it's not good for us because if we
say you know they're going to win by 24
seats and and here are the 80 districts
where it's contentious than those people
okay I better get out and vote now
because I'm in one of those 80 districts
you change the outcome and then my
forecast looks wrong right so it so but
we are conscious of that and and it is a
risk that's all I can say it's a risk
for everybody that we do influence
public opinion with this information
well thank you very much Aaron
[Music]