[Music]
good morning how's everybody doing yeah
well you're here we'll see if you still
feel about that same way after I'm done
but so so again I'm my name is Jeff Crum
I'm a security architect with IBM as you
can tell from the strange accent I'm not
from here I live in the u.s. I'm live in
Raleigh North Carolina so I don't know
if you picked that accident out or not
but nevertheless the topic I'm going to
talk about today is to me one of the
most fascinating and that which is why I
was drawn to it in the first place I
hope you'll find that it is as well this
notion of artificial intelligence we've
been hearing about I can remember for as
long as I've been dealing with computers
and given my advanced age you know
that's been a long time so 36 years with
IBM and have always been hearing you
know next year was when we were gonna
have AI or it was about five years out
and it was kind of a moving target and
whatever year you were in it was five
years away it's it's happening now and
so I'll give you some examples of that
during the talk but some of the things
that I thought would be useful to talk
about it we're gonna start off with a
video do you know who Tony Stark is do
you know who Iron Man is
would you be interested in having a Tony
Stark like experience with your computer
[Music]
I am Mike Spisak IBM master inventor
kids like Evan they're not clouded by
requirements or constraints they have
this sort of can-do attitude as usual
evan pops down into my office one day
and he's looking over my shoulder to see
what I'm working on and I'm showing him
how you can chat with Watson through the
keyboard and he said to me dad why can't
you talk to it with your voice so we
started to search around a little bit
about from ways we could do this right
we decide to order a Raspberry Pi
touchscreen and you can talk to it from
there we wired up Watson and an hour
later we were talking to it the
experience of talking to Haven is very
similar to an experience you might have
with talking to other voice enabled
technologies Haven helped me understand
ransom I like the look at Haven a little
bit more as a specialist it's helping
you specifically to understand and work
on cybersecurity events
Haven tell me about those threats the
most serious threat is at risk level 7.7
and is titled from where AirWatch
enrollment security bypass shall I pull
it up on screen
no thank you a company could see upwards
of 200,000 security events a day it
doesn't matter how many people we have
focused at that particular problem it
will never be enough to get ahead of the
vast amount of data that's being
generated cognitive technologies are
going to enable us to get ahead of that
curve by processing this information
quicker and at a large scale we're
always trying to think of new ways to
leverage Watson and cognitive to address
offenses and vulnerabilities
[Music]
I think the best of Haven is still yet
to be discovered I think the best of
Watson is still waiting to be invented
by someone maybe seven it would be
really cool to has such a big impact on
the way people live we're still adding
on new things and I don't think we're
done yet to be able to share those
experiences with him makes me really
really proud as a dad
what more can you ask for it to be able
to share your passion for technology
with your son who is equally as
passionate about it it's really it's
really special
[Music]
okay so there you go we've been working
on the Watson technology I'll talk a
little more about what that is and what
it's capable of and what we've done in
the real world with it but there's an
example with that I think is interesting
because we think of AI as a dehumanizing
thing and here you see a very human
story here's a father and a son working
on a technology and kids as he says are
not constrained by some of the
limitations that we naturally tend to
accept and so his son says why are you
typing to it why when you could talk to
it and so that's what they did has added
a voice interface so we're gonna find
voice interface whether you talk to this
system or not natural language
processing is an important part of what
we generally consider to be artificial
intelligence so a little bit more about
why we need this and Mike mentions that
in the video but I'll say some of these
things I know I'm preaching to the choir
on this we know that the threats
continue to increase the alerts continue
to increase relative to the number of
threats that are out there the number of
security specialists that we have who
can go work on those problems is not
increasing at nearly the same rate so we
have a net decline is the net of that
and you can see the amount of knowledge
that it takes you know when we were
talking about diagnosing issues in times
gone by it was relatively simple it
seemed complex then but it's nothing
compared to what we're dealing with
today this n dimensional problem that it
seems to be getting worse all the time
so we're asking more and more from fewer
and fewer and you can see if that trend
continues it's not the good guys that
come out on top it's the bad guys all of
those factors are working in favor of
the bad guys so we've got to do
something to turn the tables around
differently and this last statistic is
the one that's it's particularly
troubling to me now Mark Twain said
you've got lies damned lies and
statistics well so the you can decide
whether you want to trust this
particular projection or not but the
point is generally there we have a large
looming ahead of us in terms of the
problem space the number of
cybersecurity experts that it's going to
require in order to address the number
of problems that we're dealing with
we've got a gap we cannot make
cybersecurity experts
fast enough I mean look with current
technology it takes us nine months to
make a human so even then you've got a
lot more work you can't just you know
okay now we're gonna set you to work on
this problem so we're we're talking
about many years in order for us to even
start making a dent into that problem if
we go with the conventional course and
speed so what are we going to do to
address that I'm gonna suggest we have
to do a game changer we're gonna have to
work smarter we're gonna have to
leverage automation more and we're gonna
have to leverage other technologies like
artificial intelligence in order to
allow the number of people we have use
this as a force multiplier to be more
effective otherwise bad guys win and
we're hoping that that's not the case
so a typical security operation center
analyst when they see an incident come
across their desk they've got a lot of
things they have to do and this is just
a slight example of what that might be
but there's all sorts of steps that go
into the investigation looking and
seeing essentially what are the symptoms
what are the indicators have compromised
what are these things add up to what
does this pattern look like have I seen
this before and in a lot of cases we
have but one of the challenges we face
in the security area is that we deal
with lots of black swans we deal with
these one-off type of events so
automating response comes out to be a
difficult thing in most cases there are
some cases where you know in other words
put it this way if you want to automate
something you have to know in advance
what you're going to do you can't
automate an indeterminate action so if
you are looking at a problem that you've
never seen before a new attack here's a
new type of malware here's a new attack
technique it's it's going to be darn
near impossible to automate the
appropriate response to that because you
haven't seen it before so the focus in
many cases needs to be
automation as an assist and
orchestration as a way to manage all of
the pieces and again before it's
multipliers but what could we do to
simplify this task right here
the investigative phase if you think
about all the information that like I
said that an analyst has to have it's
increasing but who has time to continue
to increase their knowledge base in
their head if they're fighting fires all
day long and I don't know about you but
everything I read doesn't mean I retain
and even if I retain it doesn't mean I'm
instantly able to apply it in always the
right circumstances so those are
challenges with this sort of
carbon-based technology that we are so
again I'm going to suggest silicon might
be able to help us here so let's take a
look at about AI artificial intelligence
everybody and his dog is talking about
this these days all the vendors I'm sure
hitting you over the head with their
wonderful AI capabilities and so here I
am to do the same thing you're thinking
so what I'm going to try to do though is
at least level the playing field in
terms of understanding what is AI well
it's a lot of different things to a lot
of different people but we'll start with
a few definition definitions that we
could hopefully agree on so the first is
Webster says it's a branch of computer
science dealing with the simulation of
intelligent behavior and computers
sounds simple enough that nothing
objectionable I think about that except
what is intelligent behavior so it's
easy to say but it's another thing to
define we think of humans as intelligent
beings but I can tell you not all of
them are all that intelligent so you
know what what defines that what do we
can say what level of intelligence do we
consider it to be intelligent right
Oxford English Dictionary the theory of
and deploying development of computer
systems able to perform tasks normally
recurring requiring human intelligence
such as visual perception speech
recognition decision-making and
translation between languages so now you
start to see a little further definition
of what that intelligence might mean
through a few examples because generally
we would take those actions those
abilities to do those kinds of things
and say something that could do that we
think possesses intelligence because we
think it requires intelligence to
accomplish some of those things so what
does it all really boil down to AI is
essentially essentially involves making
computers more able to match or exceed
human intelligence in its various forms
by mimicking the human ability to
discover infer and reason notice how in
all of these definitions we're comparing
whatever the AI thing is to us so we
think we are the the top and we're
trying to make other systems be able to
do what we're able to do now when our
alien overlords arrive we may decide
that we set the bar too low in terms of
what was what was the ultimate objective
but until then we we don't know of
things that are more intelligent than us
so we don't have any other basis to
compare to so we'll continue to use us
as an example and what we want to be
able to do I think it's important to
think about AI as a group of
technologies plural as opposed to a
single technology so we'll tend to talk
about them as a group because it's
easier to do that but in fact if someone
says you know my product is doing AI or
I'm doing AI research they could be
doing any one of these things and be
very different than what someone else is
doing so you can see some of the
possibilities here reasoning and
problem-solving and that one's actually
really very hard if you think about what
we're talking with with a an intelligent
system a cognitive system that's very
different than what I was trained to
create back when I was in school and
dinosaurs roamed the earth and that sort
of thing the we were programming systems
and that's what of course most systems
are still programmed systems programming
if you think about it at it's as its
essence is taking the intelligence of
the programmer codifying that into a
procedure and then putting that into a
system so that it can run repeatedly
based upon certain inputs then give you
certain outputs but we've kind of frozen
the intelligence of the
programmer captured that codified it and
put it into the system
that's a program system that's what we
all learned in computer science to
create for the most part a cognitive
system thinks on its own and learns on
its own now it may start off really
really stupid and by the way so do
humans if you don't believe me go look
at little kids and what do they do when
every time they see something goes right
in the mouth so that's how they're
trying to learn and they're trying to
figure out you know is this edible or
not you know what is it like so as we
grow we start to learn more things and
then hopefully we learn everything
doesn't go in the mouth first although
there's a few then then some other
things that we do here knowledge
representation planning a planning is an
interesting thing that's something we
all take for granted and we do it a
million times a day simple things that
we plan out I'm not talking about
looking at your calendar I'm talking
about planning if I'm going to you know
how I walk down these stairs and I need
to move this way and then I need to move
one foot in front of the other in this
sort of thing it's all automatic to us
but there was a step of planning
involved in doing that some other things
like perception recognizing things so
that chair until I came here today I've
never seen a chair that looks exactly
like that chair but I've seen an awful
lot of chairs in my life and when I
looked at that I knew it was a chair you
didn't have to tell me that because it
had certain qualities that made it chair
like now if we were talking about a
program system we'd have to Train it
that that's a chair and then the next
one that comes along we'll have to train
that that one is a chair and the next
one is a chair and the next one is a
chair and all the infinite number of
chairs that we have but in this case an
intelligent being is able to see that
there are certain things here and
generalize extrapolate and in most of
the times were right sometimes we're
wrong sometimes we suffer from bias and
we say that thing looks like a chair we
go sit on it then we find out no it
really wasn't
and the thing falls apart okay so
sometimes we're not always right but but
we do those kind of judgments those are
all aspects creativity
general intelligence social intelligence
again we're all different in terms of
our own intelligence so it's not
surprising that computer science would
lead us to different areas within AI and
different disciplines now when someone
says I've got a security tool that does
AI it's not doing all of that for sure
so no one that I'm aware of has an AI
system that does all of that
simultaneously so everyone's picking out
pieces of the subfields of this and
trying to focus on it some of the terms
that that you'll see here are the focus
especially within the security space
what most of the vendors are doing is
this thing here called machine learning
so machine learning is a subfield of AI
and computer science that has as its
root statistics and mathematical
optimization so machine learning is
where the system there's two different
types supervised and unsupervised
machine learning but you're basically
doing a sort of statistical analysis
building patterns and then making
generalizations from those patterns
drawing conclusions from those patterns
so that's it's again rooted in
statistics so that's but we're allowing
the system to go off and discover and
give us insights back that we otherwise
would have to mine out on our own in my
new detail deep learning you can see a
little bit different version of that but
machine learning is what most people are
doing if they if a vendor tells you
they've got security product that does
AI it's probably machine learning and
that's good
because we're doing as an industry a lot
of people are doing some really cool
stuff with machine learning that is
simplifying the job of sock analysts and
so forth but there's some other aspects
those are aspects of AI cognitive
computing is another type of AI that
leverages machine learning and deep
learning and some other things like
natural language processing so we'll
talk about that a little bit more as we
move along I think in the interest of
time I'm gonna leave these hopefully I
think everyone will be able to download
the slides and you can take a look and
read these definitions on your own but
I'm gonna flip through this for right
now and talk a little bit more about
sort of a hierarchy of computing
capabilities moving
more and more toward an intelligent
system so we start off with some really
basic stuff here you know basic search
capabilities pattern matching
correlation and rules most of our early
generation of security information event
management systems were essentially we
have log management systems where we
could do search collect all the logs
from all of our systems and then go back
and search on them and then the the sims
would come along and start doing this
and now the better security of
information and event management systems
are able to do this sort of analytics
that's really where everybody's going
when they're talking about data lakes
and mining insights and this sort of
stuff this is this is where we are but
cognition is a different thing cognition
is another turn of the crank that's
where the system is really thinking its
reasoning it's not just looking at a
data set and saying okay I think this is
the next one you know in the series or
this is the outlier that's all really
important stuff but there's more to it
than that if we're talking about
actually comprehending so I'll give you
an example of of something that
certainly when this first came out I
mean remember the early search engines
on the internet were not great if you
put in a search term you generally got
back a lot of information and about 2/3
of it was really not what you were
looking for and maybe the one that you
really wanted was on about the second or
third page of the search results but it
certainly wasn't likely to be in the top
three well now Google came along and
revolutionized that and now most of the
time if you have a reasonably
well-formed search whatever you're
looking for it's probably in the top two
or three of results it's going to return
so we'd say that's pretty smart
is it AI is it cognitive and I'm gonna
suggest to you that it's not for this
reason here's an example if you put this
in to Google show pictures of everything
except pink elephants and we all know
what that means and what does Google
return to you exactly a bunch of
pictures of pink elephants now why did
it do that now by the way if you asked
me Jeff give me a bunch of pictures of
everything except pink elephants and
then that's the only thing I brought
you back you say Jeff you're a
what is wrong with you did you not hear
what I said but we don't we don't say it
because Google does some amazing stuff
in the other types of cases but you can
see it's missing the the does it really
understand what you're asking for no
because what it's doing is keyword
search it looked for and found pink
elephants images pictures okay I know
what that is here you go and it missed
the the intent of what their query was
so if we're gonna have really artificial
intelligence it's got to understand the
full intent the full context of all
these things that are happening it
sometimes we say something at one point
and it means a different thing than what
you would mean if you said exactly the
same words at a different time in a
different context and we're used to
understanding that context all the time
sometimes we have misunderstandings but
generally humans manage that sort of
misunderstanding or confusing ambiguity
pretty well all right how about AI in
the real world I've talked about the
abstract the definitions of the terms
that sort of stuff is this stuff real
what can it really do so IBM I think was
about six years ago decided with the
Watson system and I'm going to talk
about this in terms of the use case so
this is not we don't have a machine that
you can buy if you want to win a
jeopardy we will not sell you the Watson
system so that you can go win but this
was - - basically like a lot of things
if you think about when when we sent
humans to the moon for the first time we
had to develop a lot of underlying
technologies in order to support that
and there were a lot of things that came
out of you know the space program that
weren't necessarily space related but
they were still really important
supporting technologies like velcro and
tang I mean what would we do with that
Tang evidently a lot because I haven't
seen it in a long time so maybe that
one's time has passed but so this was
one of those kind of grand challenges
that we say if we could make a system
that was smart enough to win at jeopardy
now that would be something now why is
that something why is that a big deal we
already made a system
deep blue that was winning at chess and
beating grandmasters around the world
and you would think us chess chess is an
infinitely complex game to play if you
could really play that and beat the best
in the world
then you must be a super genius but the
system that plays chess and beats
grandmasters can not tie its own shoes I
mean it it can't do some other really
rudimentary things that you and I would
think would be expected jeopardy is a
very different type of problem than
chess is first of all in jeopardy you're
given answers and then you formulate
questions and you're as your response so
that's just a little bit weird the
second thing is jeopardy uses a lot of
figures of speech idioms puns rhymes
plays on words all of this kind of stuff
as a way that is in fact part of the
clue so if you read it literally and you
don't have the context of what those
kind of sort of jokes and twists mean
you will absolutely get the question
wrong so you've got to not only
understand literally what the words mean
but what they mean in that context and
what they're referring to in some sort
of twisted ways at times that's not
necessarily the way we tend to think of
that word but oh yeah it kind of also
has this other meaning as well that's
what makes it complex and then the other
things that make it complex are with to
win at jeopardy you can't just be an
expert on geography you have to also
know arts you have to know sports you
have to know history you have to know
politics you have to food all these
different subjects so it's so many
different domains it's really rare for
someone to be expert in so many
different domains and be able to think
that quickly because speed is what you
have to win with is this as well if
you're slow as I may be if you come up
with the right answer it's not going to
matter
they're already on to the next question
so you've got to be fast oh and then
there's this other thing if you answer
incorrectly you lose points so before
you decide to chime in you have to have
decided whether this is worth taking the
risk how confident am I in my answer and
do that sort of risk calculation now
humans do this
all the time in really fast moments we
had a system that was going to have to
do all of that but the hardest part of
that I think is dealing with the
arbitrariness of our language and trying
to sort through that and if any of you
speak you know I'm sure many of you
speak more than one language whichever
one if you were very familiar with one
language first when you first started
learning the other sometimes somebody
would tell you a joke and it didn't make
any sense
you translate it literally you get the
words out but it's not funny and then as
you start to understand the
idiosyncrasies of the language then you
start to get it so Watson had to
understand all of that in order to win
so that was the challenge we were up
against and you would think in order to
win that you'd have to be pretty smart
and you do and in fact Watson competed
against two former grand champions of
Jeopardy and beat them like rented mules
it really wasn't all that close so this
was this was remarkable and I can tell
you this was on national TV for three
nights I think in a row that they showed
this at an IBM facility and look there
were a lot of nervous executives when
this was going on because this was our
chance to fail in front of the world or
succeed and thankfully we succeeded with
this and it made a big splash and then
everything went quiet for a long time
and then we started seeing the practical
real-world examples of applying that
kind of technology and the one that I
like best is one that was profiled on 60
minutes I assume you're familiar with
the show in the US a news magazine
that's weekly so this happened this was
profiling a work that was done at the
University of North Carolina Lineberger
Cancer Center and I live in North
Carolina in Raleigh so this is about 25
miles away from me so not too far away
so that made it feel even more close to
home but what they did in this
particular profile is to give you a
background I wasn't expert in this so
I'm just telling you what I saw from the
from the story apparently at the best
cancer centers you know that's where you
end up with some of the toughest cases
so if someone responds to traditional
therapies great they go home and they're
in good shape if they don't what's next
well you go to see the specialist and
they have what they call a tumor board
so a doctor comes and presents a
patient's case in front of you know a
room full of other specialists who are
experts in the field and they all
discuss the case and then make
recommendations of what other
alternative therapies to try and this is
normal mode of operation so the thought
here was okay taking on Jeopardy was a
really hard problem why don't we see
what we can do about cancer now that
sounds nuts to me to even suggest that
that we could try to make a dent in that
and of course there's no cure for cancer
in in the in the abstract and the large
but make a dent in the way it's treated
would be even I mean they talk about the
impact of humanity in doing something
like that so they started working on
teaching Watson the language of oncology
the language of cancer treatment which
is not simple right and it turns out
that there are 8,000 new medical
research papers published every day so
if you're on the tumor board it would be
really good if you had read all of those
every day so you could apply the latest
research to every single case that came
in to you but we can't even read 8,000
pages a day much less 8,000 papers and
you can imagine what research papers
read like this is not going to be
trivial stuff so that's beyond human
capacity to do it's not beyond the
capacity of a cognitive system to
consume that level of information build
a knowledge graph and be able to apply
that that was our thought so why don't
we try to teach Watson this and of
course initially just like a human like
a child when they first start learning
they learn a lot of ridiculous stuff and
say some things that are kind of crazy
and kind of funny and stuff like that
sometimes it's not funny so we have to
realize you know it's going to take us a
while to ramp this up so when I tell you
about all of these great possibilities
I'm also
to temper this with the understanding
that again think of the way a child
learns sometimes they'll give you
moments of brilliance followed by hours
of unbelievable stupidity it seems you
know how did you possibly think that was
a good idea to do that and then
hopefully if they live long enough they
get to you know learn from those
mistakes and and do better so what we
had to do though this is serious stuff
so we needed to make sure that that this
system really understood and was going
to act first of all safely efficaciously
the Hippocratic oath first thing do no
harm so they tested it studied a
thousand patients that who had already
been through the tumor board tumor board
had given their recommendation now we're
gonna see what Watson would have done
with these had they been presented to to
that system and it came out it matched
ninety nine percent of the time now
that's pretty good because I think if
you've got ten doctors you're probably
in a room you're likely to have fifteen
opinions so they imagine the notion of
building a system that's going to match
the collective expertise of a bunch of
doctors who don't even all agree is a
hard task and to do that 99% of the time
means this is a big deal especially for
all those people who won't have access
to a tumor board think about the vast
number of people in the world who will
never have their cases presented because
there's only so many cancer centers and
only so many experts so all of a sudden
this starts making this much more
available Watson found this was a really
cool part in thirty percent of the cases
additional therapies that the tumor
board didn't think to recommend yet once
they looked at them said yeah this would
be a good idea so I'm not talking about
let's go recommend the patient during
chickens blood this is stuff that that
seemed like it made sense to try so
that's a I think that's breakthrough
stuff now it doesn't mean cancer is
cured of course and Watson's going to
make mistakes just like doctors make
mistakes we're still and the same
treatment that cures one person kills
another one so this is hard stuff to do
here
so don't expect miracles but
this is progress and this is not
something we could have done with
conventional programmed computer systems
I remember one of the first things I
wanted to do when I first started back
in high school putting my hands on a
computer I thought this would be really
cool if I could build a flowchart of
medical diagnosis I had wanted to be a
doctor before I decided to get into
computer science so I thought gosh you
could present your symptoms and it would
kick out and tell you what you've got
and I was very naive of course we still
have a hard time with systems doing that
sort of thing because there's so many
different things and patients present in
so many different ways some people are
asymptomatic and some people have
symptoms that point to other things and
symptoms overlap but nevertheless so
that's two applications of artificial
intelligence to win a jeopardy and I can
tell you IBM's business model is not to
collect all the Jeopardy winnings
because that's not going to be enough
revenue to keep the shareholders happy
so we've got to move to other things so
then the next one was was oncology and
now and now we're branching out and
doing this in a lot of other spaces but
we're here to talk about cybersecurity
what does all this have to do with you
know could we takes a machine that wins
a jeopardy and is helping treat cancer
and have it actually apply that kind of
technology to cybersecurity that would
be a cool thing if we could do that so
let's talk about it what's the problem
that we have to deal with well one of
the things is the information that we
have available to us comes in a lot of
different forms if you look at this
iceberg this stuff up here on the top up
here security events and alerts logs
configuration data user network activity
threat and vulnerability feeds you can
take that and feed that to your sim your
security information event management
system and it eats that stuff for
breakfast why is it able to make sense
of that because it's structured it knows
what a log record is supposed to look
like coming from a particular source so
you can program a parser to take that
and say okay the first five bytes are
this the next 12 bytes are this the next
16 bytes are that and then it reads all
those in and it can start matching
patterns it can start looking for
correlations it can
applying rules and policies and that's
how Sims work so all of that stuff on
the top is current course and speed for
us we know how to do that it's
structured data now what happens if you
take a word doc or a PDF or a PowerPoint
or a website and feed that to your sim
he chokes doesn't know what to do with
that well whoops I mean to go there yet
what if you take an industry publication
an analyst report a conference
presentation let's say we take my
presentation from this conference and
feed that into your sim give it the
PowerPoint and see what it does it has
no idea what to do with that a research
paper written by security researchers
about a new proof-of-concept attack feed
that to your sim and watch it choke on
the other hand a cognitive system that
understands natural language can read
comprehend and then reason over that
data so that's a different deal that's
what we as humans do the problem is we
just can't do it fast enough because in
our field now there's not 8,000 new
papers every day in the security space
but there's a lot it's way more than you
can keep up with believe me I'm finding
this out firsthand the hard way I'm
working on my PhD right now so I'm
trying to read a whole bunch of other
papers and it's just mine knowing at
times to try to get through this stuff
and try to remember it all and then
create my own contributions to it so the
the point being though is that we think
this stuff up here may be the tip of the
iceberg that maybe only about 10 percent
of the security information that's
available across the universe and so
we're looking at another 80 or 90
percent of the information is in
unstructured formats it was designed for
humans to consume not for machines to
consume so that means we need a machine
that's smart enough to read like humans
understand like humans but not make some
of the mistakes that we as humans make
not suffer from some of the the the bias
issues and fatigue and just all kinds of
other things
that we have so that's that's
what's unique by the way I'll go back to
that one more time to make that point
what a lot of vendors are doing with
machine learning is really fantastic
stuff but it's not this they're not
doing this they're not you're not
feeding Word docs into those systems and
having them understand what that means
and then say oh yeah I read a paper the
other day and it looks like to me what
you have is a malware campaign that
matches what this research paper was
talking about that's a different kind of
thing that's a cognitive system that's
different than machine learning and so
that's I want to underscore that to try
to get away from some of the the hype
and and get to what what really is
happening so what we've done with Watson
then is take and build this the term is
a corpus of information it's a knowledge
base where it's consuming information
from lots of different sources all day
long and it's constantly getting smarter
and it's constantly growing its base
when we first started doing this in fact
we used a lot of universities students
to help us with it in the US and in
Canada and training it it's one thing
for it to read all of this stuff but is
another thing for it to comprehend and
make sense of what all this stuff means
and in fact early on just like a child
Watson made some really ridiculous kind
of conclusions you thought malware was a
place I don't know how it got to that
conclusion but it read about this and
assumed that that was a location and we
had to retrain it no that's not what it
means and again think how a child learns
they will start to put together
different unrelated things in a way that
you didn't expect and they'll come to an
incorrect conclusion we correct that
thinking and then they move on it's the
same kind of thing with a cognitive
system so that's why you see some of
these ridiculous things as it starts on
and you're gonna see reports of systems
that don't work in the early days just
like humans don't work in the early days
either all that well but they get
smarter over time and that's what we're
trying to do here so constantly
refreshing this keeping up with the
information that we have but one of the
things that comes up when I've given
this presentation before somebody else
so what you're talking about is going to
replace all of us and that's not what
I'm talking about in fact this is what
I'm talking about I'm talking about we
have security analytics today security
information event management systems
that are good at this and people aren't
you know we know that we're not really
great at consuming mass quantities of
data and correlating on it you know if
we can correlate we can look at you know
10 20 maybe a hundred data points and
start seeing patterns but if it comes
millions or billions we don't know what
to do with that we can only see the
macro type of correlations so we have
systems that do this and that's where
the statistical analysis and analytics
and all that stuff comes into account
and helps us this sort of stuff anomaly
detection visualization workflow
priority prioritization based upon rules
and things like that
so that's what Sims do really well what
a cognitive system does really well is
this unstructured analysis looking at
natural language like you saw in the
video at the beginning or in documents
written for humans to read reading that
understanding it comprehending it
applying it using machine learning doing
QA with the system so you could ask it
questions like the kid was doing you
know with with Haven which is the name
of the voice interface into this bias
elimination I mentioned earlier is a big
deal for us because we will tend to see
what it is if we go in looking for
something that's what will tend to find
which means we may miss the things we're
not looking for now a computing system
though can be trained to look for
everything at the same time like when I
look at this room as my as I scan
there's just billions of billions of
pixels of graphical data hitting the
back of my retinas it's all hitting
there but I'm not processing all of it
because my brain isn't fast enough to
deal with all of that so what do I tend
to focus on while I tend to focus on the
people now there's not more information
in the visual image in a person than
there is in you know all the other
things around but that's how we're
that's our bias will tend to focus on
people
before I focus on chairs and that's
helped us evolutionary evolutionarily
the the our forebears who were better at
focusing on chairs than humans didn't
replicate so much therefore we don't
have their genes so that's how how we've
ended up as we are so the point here
being a cognitive system is designed to
do some of these things and eliminate
some of the bias it can look at a
situation in in a neutral way and then
see what really does stand out well
where's the place for us well it turns
out neither of these technologies are
really very good at any of this morals
dilemmas trade-offs ok we're under
attack what are we supposed to do about
it
remember this is a Black Swan we can't
automate it we don't we've never seen
this before what's the appropriate
action do I shut this down because we're
getting an attack well maybe in certain
circumstances I would shut that down but
then another certain certain certain
circumstances shutting it down maybe me
basically doing a denial service on my
own organization so I don't want to do
that I don't want to shut the whole
business down so there's decisions and
this is the kind of stuff that we excel
at because we're not great at finding
the needle and the haystack but if you
give us a bunch of needles we can start
to tell you what these mean and how we
can use them so there's a place for all
of us in this is the other thing my
other part of the answer to that
question is about this replacing people
who are we going to replace remember
that shortage that skills gap that I
said we have 1.8 million people we can't
afford to be replacing people we can't
making enough people we're gonna have to
make the people a lot more effective so
that's that's not really the issue in
fact it's been referred to sometimes as
AI at this stage it's augmented
intelligence it's not it's not a
replacement it's augmenting what humans
could otherwise be doing so this is an
example of what we might be able to do
take a knowledge graph that includes
literally millions or even billions of
data points of nodes of not just think
about IP addresses but think about all
the different items or
objects within that IP address all the
different things are running on your
system that all correspond to one IP
address and represent all of that in one
big graph and then try to figure out
what is which part of that is related to
the incident that I'm seeing on my
screen right now across the entire
network and how it might relate to other
people's networks that are not under my
control well this is what what we're
we're doing is an example with this so
here you see a visualization that shows
a malware campaign and it's showing you
the graph that shows just the affected
nodes in that so it's filtering out all
the other stuff that's not so important
and you could with this potentially
figure out who did what who was the
first one to be infected who did they
infect who are the bad actors who are
the ones that are unintentionally being
affected and sort of a drive-by
kind of way and so forth and so I know
it's gonna be impossible to read here
but the language down here after it's
done its analysis is it basically comes
back and says you know you gave me a
problem and incident and I'm telling you
I see much more here I see you know
hundreds of systems that are affected in
a larger campaign and here's what they
all are and by the way if you if you
want to understand how I came to that
conclusion I can show you my work and I
can show you my my confidence in that
conclusion because sometimes the system
can come to the wrong conclusion you can
look at its confidence to see it slow
and say okay I'm not gonna bet the farm
on this particular conclusion and in
other cases oh yeah that's really solid
I'm gonna look at in fact I'm gonna go
ahead and read the research paper that
that this AI system use in order to come
to that conclusion so that I can verify
it for myself so I can learn for myself
and that's what's possible so this is
not this is not fiction this is
something that is available today in
fact we've had some cases where one
organization claims a 50 X improvement
in their investigation time so that this
is and this is not isolated so now some
people experience better or worse
results your mileage may vary all those
caveats and things like that depend
on to a great extent how we're well
tuned your sim system is and then how
well you're able to take advantage of
this what feeds have you added into it
and that sort of stuff
so I don't want to get into the
specifics of individual products or
capabilities but just to show you what
sort of is the art of the possible and
if more than anything to whet your
appetite for what the future could lead
to this because we are still in the very
earliest of days with this and you're
gonna you'll see things I mean with the
typical I was a gardener has the the
hype curve and we hit the trough of
disillusionment that's that's coming for
some it's already there but then after
the trough of disillusionment comes the
reality then we start moving in a more
steady state and we start actually
getting problems solved as opposed to
just a lot of hype and and so hopefully
that's that's the area that we're headed
to next because I think we've hit the
hype curve part pretty strong and you
may think my talk just did I hope not if
you wants a little more information more
reading and things like this on the
subject there's a website here I've
included the link this is about sort of
what IBM is doing in the in this this
space if my talk I went too fast and you
want to go you know a little bit slower
then we've got artificial intelligence a
cyber security for dummies
and if that is too elementary then we
have a paper that's essentially
artificial intelligence and security by
dummies and I am one of those so it was
a couple of colleagues of mine and mean
we went together and put this frequently
asked questions document together to try
to and that's that's what a lot of this
presentation is based on by the way I
didn't have anything to do with the
dummies book I was the dummy on the
other paper so if you want to do some
reading and kind of get take this at
your own pace then you can do that so
that's what those resources are there
for and I think with that I am done
[Applause]
[Music]