yeah I am former I am a former ta o
operator so if you guys haven't heard
NSA has a program called tailored access
operations where essentially they have
certified operators that chase down
terrorists and things of that nature I
was doing operations in ta o through mid
2011 when I was at ta o I was
responsible for running counterterrorism
operations as the technical director for
C T so I bring a fresh perspective I'd
say to kind of the cyber defensive realm
and what I'd like to talk about today is
is walk through what is hunt operations
and kind of the concept then the way
that we see it inside route 9b let me
give you a little background on who
route 9b is so we are we are a
commercial entity what makes us unique
is I have more than 40 former ta o
operators on staff conducting operations
for our clients as part of it we provide
several different services so we started
out in the training realm training for
us being focused around operational
execution so we teach we teach students
how to exploit how to maintain
tradecraft how not to get caught and
then we teach them how to go and defend
against those same capabilities so
bypassing security products then how to
use the security product or use open
source capabilities to go through and
find find them we have an emerging
technologies division emerging
technologies is product development so I
have everything from a hunt platform
which I'll show you guys today through
to a credential assessment capability as
well as a couple other unique
capabilities that we provide to our
commercial clients we have cyber
operations cyber operations for us is
really focused around hunt operations
using folks that understand how an
adversary maneuvers will remote into a
client's infrastructure and then
actively engage to get into a cyber
Knife fight with an adversary
essentially we're looking for those
folks that are bypassing your EDR
platforms in addition to that we do all
your traditional IT security stuff so
pentesting vulnerable
the assessments malware analysis
everything that the industry's been
doing for the last 20 plus years we roll
that up in there as well
threat intelligence were we're not a
threat feed so what my threat Intel team
is is made up of a group of analysts
that have conducted operations in the
past and really what they provide is
threat knowledge so they'll sit there
they lurk in the dark web they've
created seasoned personas they've become
friends with organizations like
anonymous and then they sit there and
monitor their IRC chats identify if
they're going to potentially launch a
campaign and then they take that data
and they roll that back into our clients
so I'm holding two different ways here
and then we have network defense
operations so network defense operations
has really managed security services or
MDR services for the organization we
never we didn't initially intend to move
into that space we were really looking
to be a hunt provider but what was
happening is as I was coming in many of
my clients would have an MSS provider
already we wouldn't tell the MSS
provider that we are coming and then we
deploy our payloads across the
environment without pre-configuration
and the MSS provider went and see us and
so then the clients started to get
themself into a spot where they said
well wait a second if route 9b is able
to essentially exploit on the my machine
and navigate through my network and I'm
not being told
then what service are you providing for
me so in a lot of cases they started to
move away from the MSS and gave us the
data which has really been fantastic
because it allows for us to focus our
hunt operations the last kind of bullet
point here that I want to talk about is
to to us in route 9b cybersecurity well
let me step back if I look at the
majority of organizations that say they
are cyber security companies what I'd
say is that 98% of them our IT security
firms that have rebranded because the
word cyber sexy and there's money tied
to it to us in route 9b cybersecurity is
the convergence of IT security ot
security and intelligence all brought
together without intelligence
it's just ITC
security and ot security and so for us
everything we do inside the organization
has an intelligence aspect to it we're
constantly learning and then rolling
that back into the capabilities I think
this has gone a long way especially here
in Canada with sapper labs we recently
just one defense ideas and so we'll be
providing some attribution type work to
the Canadian government all right let's
step into the the real discussion now
so this slide up here everyone's seen it
its traditional defense-in-depth if you
go through you get your degree or you
take CISSP this is what's being touted
as the way to secure your environment as
we follow this all we keep doing is
stacking technology on top of each other
in the current environment today so
we're taking in IDs we take EDR
platforms we basically will add
perimeter security products but the
problem is it's not really helping it's
not stopping the JPMorgan's from being
breached an adversary is still getting
in because the adversary understands
that we are going to secure ourselves in
this manner and that we're going to
follow specific compliance rules and
everything else and effectively we are
creating a playbook for the adversary to
be able to maneuver and exploit your
operating environment in addition by
stacking technology on top top of each
other well we're finding in the security
industry is that many cases when you
deploy maybe an antivirus and a needy
are together that you're actually
creating additional vulnerabilities that
you didn't know about or and by bringing
these capabilities in it's allowing the
adversary to use those to their
advantage if we were to take a look and
put it in a physical model here
essentially what we've done is we've
created a secure perimeter and the model
we've gone after is stop the adversary
from ever getting in you will never ever
achieve that you can try all that you
want but an adversary is going to breach
your network security has to adapt
from trying to stop them from being able
to gain initial access to stopping them
from getting to their motive don't allow
them to get to their critical
infrastructure effectively by putting
firewalls and IDS's and IPS is and just
sticking them on the outside once you
get Spearfish that's 1995 hacking at its
finest net use past the hash for the win
right so we've essentially allowed our
internal our internal networks to be a
soft squishy Center we've conceded that
space in the security environment today
this slide I think is the evidence of
what I'm talking about in every one of
these cases and what I'd say if I if I
went up to that siz oh he probably had
whatever the newest technology was the
prob and the technology probably
actually saw it or caught it but didn't
necessarily stop it no one is
complaining that they don't have enough
data
everyone has too much data now the
problem is no one knows what to look for
because we're trying to stop everything
as opposed to being focused around our
infrastructure around our networks let's
consider a few things here when we take
a look at it from an attacker
perspective in my previous life when I
was exploiting or going after a target I
would initially perform reconnaissance I
would go through and I'd find a way that
to go and enable access for myself in
that operating environment once I ended
up gaining access after I did recon and
exploit it onto the target the next
thing that I would do is I would go
steal their security settings I would
basically take what antivirus what EDR
product do they have what passive
technologies do they have around me that
potentially could catch me when I
maneuvering through the network I would
then take that I would come back into a
virtual environment and I recreate that
operating environment
that would allow for me to know that if
I do a and B as an attacker security
product will do C so I'll do a and D
so that I can maintain access I would
then continuously monitor that target to
go through and identify what security
mechanisms are they going to put in
place or changes are they putting and
then before they could deploy those I
would go and put those in inside my
little virtual environment or my lab and
I would test again and that would allow
for me to maintain persistent access on
my targets for several years at a time
it allowed for me to continuously out
mover the outmaneuver the defender
because they would go through their
testing components as well and then that
would that would allow for me to to be
successful now I'd give you that that
background here because the attacker has
a motive the attacker has a methodology
the attacker is a human that understands
how to get around the automated security
products that you're putting in place
what we are not doing as defenders is we
are not matching the attacker on the
playing field we're not putting another
human defender maneuvering through the
network ready to engage as a former
attacker there was no no pain caused to
me once I got in your environment if I
lost a payload or I lost some specific
capability that was fine because I could
continuously go through and maneuver
there was really no fear and I would not
use my O'Dea in every single instance I
would use whatever the lowest possible
capability was 1995 hacking net use
right like I said I would use that every
chance I could once I was in the network
so that I went and burn my capabilities
so really that bullet point there
humans are thinking right they're
adapting your attacker is adapting to
your network environment it's time that
as security professionals we started
that thing our network environments to
the attackers I pretty much already hit
on this point really the one I want to
drive home is kind of that last bullet
point the chief scientists at route 9b
de Vaux Smith he does quite a bit on
trying to secure airplanes and
submarines and everything else and I
thought his quote at a conference not
too long ago was spot-on we're likely
we're as likely to build a secure
computer system as we are to build an
aircraft that cannot be shot down in
this environment we are being challenged
by sophisticated adversaries whether
it's an organization like Anonymous or a
nation-state adversary like a Russian
apt yet we are and you are are in
control of your operating environment
and responsible for the security of that
environment yet we are not spending or
putting the ability for our people to be
able to defend the network appropriately
one of the one of the kind of concepts I
think it's almost like asking our people
to stand on the front line without a gun
we wouldn't do that in the military so
why are we doing it with computer
networks and environments all right so
what is hunting so there's a lot of
concepts out there and it's a very
muddied word for anyone that's heard of
threat hunting organiz there's a couple
different takes some organizations look
at it as event log analysis that is not
hunting to me it's a necessary
requirement when you're doing security
but going through and doing event log
analysis is an after-the-fact analytics
environment that causes you then to go
and respond additionally what what I
find some folks saying threat hunting is
is looking at network traffic after the
fact in fact there's one financial
institution that has hunt parties once a
month so every 30 days they have a hunt
party and they look through all their
logs and then when they identify a
potential breach they go and make a
change that is no different than what we
are doing in the early 2000s that is
still not hunting to me so the way that
I see hunting is it's maneuver warfare
in your own operating environment it's
allowing humans
to go through and look for an adversary
bypassing your security products and
then actively engage the adversary find
them fix it and finish right that's
really what hunting is it's about
allowing a human to go through your
environment and patrol through their
space looking for that 5% or 7% of
sophisticated attackers that know how to
bypass those products or to maneuver in
your operating environment there's some
things to consider defenders actually
understand their network or they should
I'll take that back they should
understand their network we know what
reality is
so they actually they have the advantage
the problem is attackers when they come
in they have to learn your environment
and they will take whatever that kind of
soft squishy Center is and maneuver to
that machine but they're there for a
motive they're not exploiting every
single box when I would exploit into an
environment I knew what I was coming for
maybe it's the domain controller maybe I
want to steal source code maybe I want
some PII data and I will navigate to the
machines that are housing those I'm not
doing like the defenders doing and
trying to go through and look at it logs
from every single endpoint that I have
in that in that environment they're very
strategic very tactical so let's look at
this model again what I'm proposing and
what I propose for Hunt is putting the
human back at the center of the
operations so if you take a look here
let's pretend that this was a physical
model I'll use a being former military
I'll use a military installation if I
was driving up to a military
installation for a meeting as I start
driving to that installation I'm going
to see a fence going around the compound
there's going to be barbed wire on top
of the fence there's going to be a
camera probably in every single corner
that I go to I'll pull up to the front
gate the guards gonna be there checking
my ID to make sure I can come on he's
probably going to have a gun and there's
gonna be a barricade stopping me from
being able to just drive on through
after they check my access and verify
that I can get on to that base for
legitimate reasons they'll allow me to
drive through that compound as I Drive
through I'm probably going to pass
military troop formations maybe some
armored vehicles more cameras more SiC
control controlled buildings on there so
in that model they're in in that
physical model that I just described the
fence and the barbed wire are not going
to stop me from gaining access if I want
to get over the 13 foot fence I bring a
14-foot ladder right every one of those
components though are there to help
enable the defender the camera is
providing telemetry to let them know
whether or not I actually was able to
get on and if I'd now put that back to
cybersecurity and the way we're doing it
today all that we have is we have
basically that fence and that barbed
wire and then we have someone monitoring
the camera and then when there's a
breach they call someone and then
someone goes and shows up there's no one
actively going through and making sure
that there's a not an attacker already
gaining access and so what you look at
here is this is how I see cyber security
really coming together
a true cyber security approach would
have one a good training foundation but
two you would have an attack surface
baseline you would attempt to come after
yourself the way the adversary would not
just doing an expose basically launch
next pose and then dump out the 400-page
report it's helpful but it's not really
security right instead what I what I
propose is understanding how an
adversary would come after you
understanding the groups that are most
likely to attack you and then testing
against your perimeter products to make
sure they can't bypass next everyone has
pretty much everyone has a sock nowadays
right or they're all headed that way
so you have managed security services
that are collecting data from your EDR
platforms from your web forwarding your
syslog data whatever have you
all of that is really good data that
allows for you to identify that
someone's there
and then respond that's traditional
traditional security as you get into the
center here this is really where the
crux comes in of hunt hunt is putting a
human back at the center of the
operations as I had mentioned and
allowing them to navigate look for an
adversary and then actively engage in
your operating environment and so the
way that I propose hunt to happen is
using an offensive minded approach sit
back the way an attacker would and
navigate through your environment
looking for an anomaly as you identify
the anomaly it then turns into an
incident response and forensic type
investigation now in this approach
though with hunt what I'm not talking
about is you were not hunting 1 million
machines all at the same time that's
what an antivirus is for instead what
I'm talking about
is understanding your business context
understand your critical infrastructure
realizing yet it could be multiple
things assume that an attacker when they
compromise you is going to navigate to
that path so when you're hunting in that
type of environment you hunt the
critical infrastructure and slowly peel
back the layers hitting different
Network segments looking for anomalies
that are taking place and then come up
with a plan to actively engage now in
addition to that you see there's a
threat Intel line that goes through
threat Intel feeds each of these
components I talked about the attackers
are adapting to your environment once
they identify that you bought product X
they figure out their way around and
that's how they're going to come come in
what defenders need to do is they need
to be able to adapt to the attacker
instead of chasing file paths and
signatures from a threat Intel feed you
should be understanding why they would
come after you where they would try to
maneuver and focus your energy there by
being able to be focused there the
threat Intel will constantly end up
changing the way that you implement your
security practices and mechanism so
adversary
suit to us is allowing for an
interactive operator to sit in a
sock-like environment and execute
operations it's proactive in its
approach it's going back and making sure
that your investments that you've put in
to your EDR products and your abs and
everything else that they're actually
finding what they should be and if
they're not it's allowing for you or the
human to do the active engagement
identify and respond the way we caused
pain to an adversary is by burning his
capabilities forcing him to go different
paths when it's hard on the on the
attacker the attacker will go to a
different network I this already when
you're when you're conducting hunt
operations if I was doing a forensic
investigation I have a patient zero
that's what caused me to go in and do
that investigation right there's
something there that is forcing me to
look at it is a post-mortem incident
response I have a patient zero as well I
had something that's causing me to
elevate it to become an incident when
you're doing hunt operations
everything's a patient zero you need to
assume that your network is already
compromised and that the adversary is is
going to maneuver to take your data or
whatever have you hunt will always lead
to an incident response investigation if
you're proactive then you should be
finding adversaries in your network and
then you should be coming up with a plan
to be able to go and execute we have a
retail client that gets breached every
single month no lie every single month
they have a breach but they're
conducting proactive operations and the
adversary has never been able to get to
their end goal now as I mentioned
earlier I don't ever tell a client we
are going to stop them from being
breached because it's impossible what we
do is we focus when we're hunting again
around keeping them from being a
to live in the operating environment for
whatever the new stat is 140 days or so
so in order to execute hunt you need to
have a methodology the methodology
really needs to be focused again around
the human defender being in that
operating environment and having full
freedom of movement and full control to
actively engage they need the attacker
to start looking over their shoulder
when they're exploiting in the way that
I see hunt operations is through a
basically a four-step approach first
phase one in mass collection you could
do that today with the EDR products you
could do it today through WMI whatever
you have you could use those
capabilities to reach out and collect
now when you're pulling it back instead
of looking for signatures you should be
looking for anomalies the easiest way to
do this when you're hunting understand
your network right get a baseline build
a baseline because you probably all have
a gold image so build a baseline and
then from there do comparisons of your
collection against those baselines as
you go through and you're pulling back
data through the in mass collection
that's going to lead into ultimately
what's the second phase identification
of an IOC indicator of compromise that's
going to give you an anomaly to go and
start to do the investigation for now
all of this that I'm talking through I'm
talking about doing it remotely doing it
interactively from a centralized
location executing against hosts in your
environment from there after you
identify the IOC it becomes targeted
collection and forensics now much of
that much of those first three steps
that I just kind of alluded to are in
many people's incident response plans
today they're just not doing it
continuously going through the network
in a stealthy manner looking for the
adversary finally
the thing about hunt so those first
three there is a plethora of
organizations that say they hunt and
only do those that is collection it's a
subset of what hunt is but what hunt
really is is response activities that's
how I see hunt this would be for any of
you that that actually hunt animals and
I hate using this analogy but it's a
good one it this component we don't call
hunt let me step back we don't call hunt
in in that space
sticking a GoPro in a tree stand and
then going back and checking it
that is not hunt we need that data but
in cybersecurity that's very much what
we're doing right that's that event log
analysis I'm talking about after the
fact and that's what what some folks are
calling hunt what hunt is is having a
human there with a rifle ready to shoot
that human is going to be disguised
going to be stealthy going to try to
blend into the environment so that he
can target his prey
this is what I'm talking about in
cybersecurity hunt requires a response
activity and it requires essentially a
methodology of how you're going to to
interact that methodology is going to be
different for every single person in
this room and for every business based
off of context in order to be successful
organizations need to build a common
platform for themselves now there's a
number of different capabilities out
there that allow for for you to be able
to go through and execute hunt
operations CrowdStrike Falcon would be a
good idea our platform for you to be
able to go through and start doing those
types of activities what they do is when
you're doing this you should be doing it
more stealthy so predominantly or
preferably you would not have a
persistent agent that was sitting there
for the adversary to see and the reason
I say that is if you think back to what
I explained the way I used to attack I
would steal that persistent agent's
capabilities and figure out how am I
going to go through and maneuver so it
should be an agentless technology that's
being used by a human defender to
execute you also don't
automate everything automation is good
technology's good you need it but you
can't automate the human the human
attacker will figure out what those
response activities are going to be the
end goal is really to try to cause pain
to that adversary but focus on not
allowing them to get to their intended
target so we need to think like the
adversary and maneuver like the
adversary we need to be stealthy in the
approach and very tactical in the
engagement of how we are going to to
take them out once we identify them some
additional things I hit on a bunch of
these already you want the ability to be
able to detect and engage the attacker
so when the attacker is there you want
to be able to get into the CyberKnife
fight with them you want to be able to
get into that hand-to-hand combat so
that the attacker is now on the
defensive he's trying to figure out what
can he do what should he do where does
he go from there the capability also
shouldn't be only is solely focused
around Windows and Linux machines really
any capability or platform that you have
should be able to pull off of a
pacemaker if you want to or an internet
some internet of things maybe a
satellite hop you should be able to
engage any one of those environments
collect data and correlate it in a
unified platform so that you can have
visualization back to the automated
piece I often get asked why we didn't go
fully automate it and I'll save you from
going through all the bullet points on
the slide but at the end of the day it's
exactly what I said the human will
figure out what the response activity is
going to be from the automated platform
and so any any capability you have you
need to really combine those two the
human has to be able to engage with the
technology so that they can actively
actively pursue that adversary when
you're doing operations like this as
well I guess I should have said earlier
when you're conducting hunt operations
the nice thing about hunt in this
approach is you control all of the
assets already if you're a corporation
and so you can reach in your environment
collect data and pursue adversaries and
engage them without violating any laws
you can also passively collect data or
intelligence beyond the wire beyond your
perimeter to see are they coming after
you and then you can take that data and
you can actually start to hand it over
to people with the appropriate authority
like an FBI or or something that effect
where they can act they can go beyond
and take it to prosecution let's talk
about a couple concepts and then I'll
show you guys a product there's this
agent verse agentless concept that I
want to hit on so I talked about
persistent agents many of you already
have a persistent agent inside your
environment think of it like an
antivirus type solution those
capabilities are good but they are
defeatable I hope I'm not telling anyone
something new there right those
capabilities are defeatable a good
adversary is gonna figure out how to get
around
so the agentless approach that i'm
talking about is really just in time
execution concept you don't want to be
residing on the box constantly because
the adversary when they get there will
identify what that technology is and
then go back and do do testing so by
being able to hunt with an agentless
approach you are maintaining the ability
to stealthily maneuver through that
network so the adversary does not know
you're there and deliver capability just
in time so really just shoving something
out to the Machine executing collecting
data pulling it back there's some
advantages to that advantages being if
it's done right you can have global
reach to any product that's out there as
well as it gives significant amounts of
scalability talk through this that you
have no persistence and it's harder for
the adversary to know that it's there
and in most cases today
they're not looking over their shoulder
any hunt platform that gets developed I
talked about should have a response
activity but you should have the ability
to be able to collect metadata pull back
files be able to parse memory remotely
over the wire and then be able to really
again respond to two other concepts I
want to hit real quick in an exploit
when the attacker throws it exploit and
gains gains access there's really two
parts to any exploit there's the
vulnerability which in most cases is the
spearfishing it's the end user right
there's the vulnerability and there's
the payload when the exploit gets
delivered if there's no payload attached
then all you're going to have is an
exploit that does nothing the payload is
the real special sauce in that exploit
environment that could be anything from
a denial service through to an implant
through to whatever they're looking to
achieve so very important concept
because what is being used in most cases
is they will take that payload and use
it over and over again and if it's a
well-written payload infrastructure with
polymorphism built in then they're going
to be able to maintain access in your
environment for a long period of time
second concept I want to talk about real
quick is the concept of a stager so for
those of you that that aren't really
technical when an exploit gets delivered
and the payload gets executed back in
1995 we would basically throw the
exploit and and the payload and
everything would be on the target from a
forensic standpoint the forensic
investigator would come up they take a
memory image or they take a live memory
image and they knew all of my capability
right so what the attackers started to
do is move to a staging infrastructure
and so what it is is it allows for a
modular type environment so when I throw
my first exploit and I gain access
that stager will call back and execute
some code typically when it calls back
it'll grab what we call the stage right
and insert that directly into memory so
if you've written from an attacker
perspective if I've written a good first
stage then I'm going to be able to
maintain access for example everyone
probably has heard of Metasploit
Metasploit works off of a stage
meterpreter works off a stage type
infrastructure if I rewrite the first
stage like I do in Python and things
like that i bypass whatever the endpoint
security product is allowing for me to
have access and then I can use
traditional meterpreter capabilities now
when you do this in today's environment
most hackers allow for their code base
to stay directly in memory so they will
inject into memory all of their modules
so if they have a hash stump module
mimikatz module whatever have you
all of those are already stored so from
a defensive perspective it's easy on a
forensic investigation to go back and
see what capabilities they had available
to them now if it's done properly they
will have multiple stages they will only
execute what they need at a given time
so that they're not burning all of their
capabilities in one shot guys following
that all right so in summary there
before I show you guys our platform
really well what I proposed is putting
the human and in an act in an offensive
type manner to provide defense allow the
human defender freedom of movement
inside your environment and give them
take their handcuffs off and let them
engage
all right give me one second
so what what I'm showing you here this
is route 9 B's version of a hunt
platform now there's as I mentioned
there's a plethora of capabilities out
there right that we've built our own but
you could use WMI you could use
Metasploit if you want really you could
use any type of capability but I want to
walk you guys through the concept of a
hunt operation as I just kind of
described it so that you can see some of
the benefits so once I authenticate here
what we have is the way we've designed
it is we've given role-based access as
part of the platform so when any user
that ends up logging in they can have
individualized payloads so from a
training perspective what we do is I
have an apprentice journeyman master
level and then what we do is we allow
the apprentice maybe only one task to be
executed and then as they graduate
through their individual training plan
we can add additional capabilities we
work off of the concept of operations is
the way that we do it today so what an
operation is is it could be really could
be anything that you defined but I could
say I want to do a new operation and
company X is that new operation and then
underneath company X I might have VLAN 1
through VLAN 1,000,001 and I I can now
create individual baselines as part of
those sub children operations and then
roll them back up so it allows for quick
comparison for the operator to identify
any anomalies that are inside their
environment we have a couple different
components here I've created a
countermeasures operation already you
have collections collections is exactly
that doing some form of collection
against the the endpoint that you want
to you want to target analysis is is
basically just rolling it all up for you
to find an anomaly quickly and then you
have your management things here
reporting and auditing every good
product needs a reporting tool
so inside collections here good it's big
up there inside collections here I can
go through and I can specify a delivery
mechanism to find targets however I want
so I could literally use nmap if I
wanted to find a targets list and then
populate targets that way we have one
built in or organizations can use
whatever capability they want to go and
find those similarly everything that we
deliver we call a payload so a payload
back to that stage the infrastructure
standpoint I talk through we shove a
stager over and then we directly inject
code into every machine to collect we
then exfil over an encrypted named pipe
back to our database and then we we
visualize that data we are acting like
the attacker inside of the environment
payloads could be both local and remote
so I can dump out a payload take it and
double-click it on an endpoint and get
the data or I can remotely deploy it and
so that I can go and pull back data sets
in that concept if I had if your
organization had at any home or
something like that we would just deploy
the payloads over top of what's already
been approved or similarly you can blend
in and use just WMI or win RM or
whatever whatever you want against
Windows machines you can add endpoints
as part of the environment so I'm not
going to give you guys everything in the
product here but you can add two end
points I can query domain controllers
and then populate a list of hosts that's
what you have here I can specify
credentials so this is called evil core
and then I can validate targets are
alive and so inside here what it's doing
is it's going to go through it'll tell
me whether or not I have any targets up
for a collection standpoint and then I
can go through and I can start to
specify as targets come up I can specify
the payload collection capabilities and
so these are all swappable so for
organizations that have their own d4
kits or their own incident response or
own collectors you roll those in and it
becomes a payload infrastructure that
gets delivered just in time for
execution it's literally a shopping cart
menu approach to deploying payloads and
pulling back data sets all data I'll say
from executed payload I did some
analytics here already
all data comes back into the analysis
engine and through this analytics engine
here we conduct a baseline so I can
build out I could take an NS r L image
essentially take NS RL and load that
into the database and then do
comparisons of hashes or file paths of
target operating systems what I'm
looking for in those environments is an
anomaly if I run a hunt operation
against a Windows machine today and then
I run it again tomorrow and solitaire is
up that's going to present an anomaly to
me or something that's different
similarly I can compare operations
against each other to say show me what's
different from from previous now as it
comes back into the database we made it
easy we put the virus total up here once
you click on a hash or similarly you can
consult the Oracle Google and all of
those are swappable everything in this
interface that I'm doing is a restful
api so to the automation to the folks
that love automation yes it can be
automated now as we go through one of
the big differentiators we have in our
product
is I have the ability to remotely deploy
a payload and parse memory live on the
system so I can see if someone did a DLL
inject on it on an operating system or
if they did a write process memory
technique using off you skated shellcode
similar to what Chinese a PT's do and so
inside here if I click on one of these
hosts I can actually say show me every
uh one second I actually clicked on the
house sorry so what I just did there is
I clicked on a specific box that I know
has malware because I deployed a malware
in there it's actually a Chinese situ
server that I have Kyle calling home do
a Chinese situ server what you have here
is you have the targets every time you
do a collection it gets a unique gooood
and then it comes back with the host
name now on the right hand side what I
said is go ahead and show me processes
that have anomalies so what we did is we
took the windows core we took linux
kernel's we went back and said if we
were going to gain execution what are
all the ways that we would gain
execution and then we built the product
to catch ourselves effectively and so
what you'll see here is in this
particular instance I can identify that
bandwidth L has the green checks means
an anomaly in each one of those
components so if you guys are wondering
well what does that consist of well if
you see the rwx component there that's
read write execute permissions in the in
the binary I also see that there's PE
portable executable format telling me
that there's a PE header residing inside
of memory so at this point now
effectively what I've been able to do is
do that in mass collection step that
first step identify an anomaly and that
leads into an indicator of compromise
which is what I just got to now now from
here I can go into very targeted
collection and go say I want to take a
look or I want to do a forensic grab or
I want to dump the virtual address space
of this specific process and turn it
into
traditional forensics and IR over the
wire or I can go and engage I could kill
the process in this case kill bandwidth
l across the network or I could take a
look and say what other what other
machines in this operating environment
have something similar and do a larger
sweep of the target this is where it
gets dictated based off of what each
organization feels comfortable with give
me one second
so what I'm showing you right here is
there was bandwidth L good it's nice and
big up there
there's bandwidth L that's the actual
collection so it's showing me what was
residing in memory at this specific time
that I collected and so as I scrolled
down here I can see that there's an MZ
header with execute read/write
permissions so for those of you that
don't do live memory analysis in pretty
much every case of a sophisticated and
not nation-states sophisticated
adversary which most of them are what
they'll try to do is move themselves
into memory and once they're in memory
then they're able to bypass your current
security products that are deployed
you're persistent agents and it allows
for them to maintain continuous access
so what this is showing is that there's
code sitting inside of memory at this
point in time now if anyone's used
volatility mal fine this is basically an
apples to apples comparison to
volatilities mal fine type functionality
now from here I can dive in and I can go
and kill that specific process or I can
grep through memory and say show me
everything that's in memory and then I
can push that out across the enterprise
looking for for hacker handles and
things like that that are inside there
so inside route 9b the way we define
hunt operations I'm seeing I'm running
out of time so the way we define hunt
operations again is interactive
operations putting a human back at the
center using an agentless type
capability to actively engage right and
so this is where in my opinion all
organizations need to move themselves or
else they are just going to continue
deploying static defenses and hoping for
the best and we will never win that way
so with that I'd like to see and I have
five minutes left I'd like to open it up
for our questions
I think we have a couple