it is time for our first talk our first
speaker is joe gray he is presenting
net flossant i think i'm supposed to
pronounce it like that taking an often
overlooked data source and
operationalizing it
gripping your pillow
tight
so thanks for coming to the talk we've
already had the mic drop so my job here
is done
so
it's been great
um
all jokes aside uh thanks for coming out
thanks for coming to the first
b-sides back in person
it's so good to actually have people
nearby and not be
communicating via discord and go to
webinar and zoom and
all of those fun things
please have fun and
be safe but safety third of course
that being said welcome to
net flucent
taking an often overlooked data source
and operationalizing it
anyone who knows me knows i like click
bait titles so that's kind of what this
is
and uh we'll get down to the meat and
potatoes of it in a moment so
about me i'm the founder and instructor
for the ascension by day i'm a threat
hunt and intelligence engineer at
mercari
i wrote practical social engineering
which if you're interested i'll be
selling downstairs
once this is done
and i like to compete quite a bit as
well i'm the 2017 derbycon social
engineering capture the flag winner and
a member of the ocean search party
winning teams at defcon 28 and 29.
so
moving into the actual context of the
presentation why this presentation
well when we think network forensics
what immediately comes to mind
i mean
pcapps right pcaps or it didn't happen
that's a very common phrase that we hear
and pcaps are universal truths
but that's what we
normally gravitate to because of the
additional rich context that you get
from a packet capture and i'm not going
to stand up here and dispute the
validity of
a pcap in terms of the importance
or the value
but
it leaves another source
overlooked and that other source is
netflow
and honestly a lot of devices natively
generate netflow
but
you know really
do we do we really even look at it right
it's does it become just another data
source is it just another
log source for us to import into the sim
so that we can
you know make
sim companies that charge by
data in and data out exponentially rich
is is that the case
so within this the agenda for today
we're going to talk about the basis of
network forensics we're going to talk
about what is netflow we'll do a little
bit of a comparison between packet
captures and netflow
and then
i struggle with whether to use the term
extracting
or deducing or inferring
net flow from pcaps
and then we'll talk about analysis and
next steps the next steps that's where
the word osen comes into play so with
this the basis of network forensics we
typically have three main sources and
that would be your logs your packet
captures and netflow
so when we talk about logs by definition
they are
evidence generated chronicling a
sequence of events
from something like say a firewall a
switch a load balancer
but either way it's memorializing that
an event occurred
and yes there are problems with logs
they can be overwritten they can be
somewhat altered depending on who has
access and what capability they have
that would be
fairly sinister
you have problems such as things like
time stomping that can affect the
validity of a log
packet captures it's the collection of
network data
in basically bytes and bits that's going
to allow further analysis reconstruction
extraction and then even going as far as
to say carve files out
if that's what was occurring
and then with that you've got netflow
which is metadata metadata being data
about the data data to explain the data
to say
that besides knoxville is on may 13th of
that
would be a log that memorializes the
event of today
saying that at 906 a.m
the temperature was 66 degrees
fahrenheit that's what i was looking at
with my watch
that is an example also of memorializing
but it's also data about the data it's
data about today
so you could consider that
metadata of sorts
it's still an irrefutable data point
but
it's data about
the data so data about today and please
do not play a drinking game
consuming alcohol for every time i
mentioned the word data
i i will say that
fort sanders and children's hospital are
relatively close we're not far from
university of tennessee but i do not
want to be the cause of a congested
emergency room so please do not play a
drinking game with that
with that though um
you can ascertain a lot of
valuable insight from
this netflow from two perspectives the
the east-west which would be your
lateral movement communications between
two internal hosts or your north south
which would be internal to external or
vice versa
so as we look at this here are some of
the pros and cons and i've kind of
already touched on some of this
logs are great and they are considered
universal truths
until they aren't until they are stomped
uh until they are altered until they are
corrupted until they are deleted and
you know oftentimes
uh anyone in here working and consulting
how many times have you went into a
present or into a
consulting engagement only to find out
that logging is not properly configured
and if you do incident response i'm
going to say that you're probably going
to say that you see that more often than
if you do pin testing
right because unless someone is
directing and this is something that
through my time doing uh full-time for
about the last five years that i've
learned
if there's not an explicit directive to
say thou shalt do this this particular
way
they
it typically is not even i wouldn't even
say minimum viable product
not even minimum viable security right
if you want an example of that look at
the dmarc records for any given
organization unless they're operating in
the federal government which is uh
covered by department of homeland
security binding operating directive
um which basically says you must have
dmarc and it must be set to reject
go look at dmarc records you're going to
see so many that have a policy set to
none
i can guarantee you
that more than likely the reason that it
is set that way is because someone said
you have to be compliant with this
framework and this framework says you
have to have a dmarc record it does
doesn't say you have to be in
uh quarantine or reject it just says you
have to have a record so therefore
you're checking the box and we and
but it accomplishes nothing
right
logging is really no different because
the thing about logging is you have a
coefficient
of
storage time and security that you also
have to maintain with that when i'm
giving ocean training and i'm talking to
people who are just coming up through
the ranks in ocean i have the
conversation quite frequently of if you
collect it you are obligated to secure
it if you collect it you've got to store
it
it doesn't matter
where you're storing it
you're going to have to pay for that
storage in some way shape or form
eventually
that five terabyte external hard drive
that you have it's going to fill up
eventually you're going to have to pay
your monthly
cloud storage bill it's going to cost
money and then with that you've got to
secure it so that's another
i wouldn't say pro and i wouldn't say
con but it's a blessing and a curse a
pro and a con if you will
as it relates to logging you also have
things like deletion time stomping and
honestly they vary in file size
depending on the size of your
architecture
you may have exceptionally small log
files or you may have tremendous log
files
so
keep that in mind with packet captures
they are excellent and they are also
considered universal truths but they are
somewhat short-sighted at times due to
things like
encrypted protocols if you don't have
the key
to be able to decrypt encrypted
communications
it's useless right you can see the
traffic occurred you can see oh well
this client was connected to a vpn
but you can't see what was going on in
the vpn right
and
does that really is that really going to
help you
the big con i would say really with
packet captures would be the file size
because if you're transferring a four
terabyte file
guess how big your packet capture is
going to be
at least that size
so it's
cumbersome to store and secure something
of that size
and honestly using wireshark it's kind
of difficult to
natively do statistic analysis you can
do a lot of analysis i am not going to
tell you that wireshark is not worth its
weight in gold and in fact i'll actually
say it's probably worth my weight in
gold uh since software really doesn't
weigh anything
right
but that being said
you can't see the complete picture
so that leads us to
netflow so
it's often not used because the
philosophy is we've got logs we've got
pcaps why do we need this
right
but it's often
comparable in size to log files
sometimes a little bit bigger sometimes
a little bit smaller but it's definitely
not the size of a packet capture you do
have less visibility i'm going to put
that out there for you right now you
have less visibility but it is easy to
analyze and perform that statistic
analysis
so in talking about netflow
we'll hit a brief history and then talk
about netflow versus ipfix so basically
it was introduced in 1996 by cisco to
collect traffic as it traverses an
interface
as with many other things
it was designed with the purpose of
troubleshooting
it's still used for troubleshooting
but i mean look at how many other things
that we use in a security context that
was made for troubleshooting
for all you pin testers here i mean
factor in that ps exec
if you're living off the land
was
created for
troubleshooting and remote system
administration so
it's the use in the abuse case scenario
but with that
within netflow it requires three
components
the exporter the collector and storage
so
that's the three elements that you need
it's not going to affect your files but
if you're going to set up quote
proper netflow within your architecture
that's what you're going to need
so
a device to export it a device to
collect it
possibly your sim and then of course
some place to store it comparing netflow
to ipfix
we have several versions of netflow
version 5 is probably the most common
through my research i found that version
9 is probably the second most common
basically the thing that varies between
it would be the names of the fields and
some have more fields than others so you
have other
potentials for
analysis with that
technically ipfix has nothing to do with
netflow
um but
it
at the same time is also technically
called netflow version 10. so
one of those
weird
kind of legacy things right
so with that here are your standard
fields for netflow pretty much
universally across the board
if you've played with packet captures
these probably look familiar to you so
time
source and destination
ip
and port
it could be your ip protocol your type
of service
you could see it as bytes or packets or
octets sent and received
so as we look at this
this is going back into what is netflow
but this is to kind of help us
understand it a little bit more
factor in
think of it this way
netflow is like kleenex
or q-tip
or google
we have facial tissues we have cotton
swabs and we have search engines
but
the fact that i was on a sales call
about 10 years ago with someone trying
to sell a search appliance and they
were a competitor to google and they
used google as a verb
when discussing their own product
it's kind of the same thing with netflow
right
you have netflow you have ipfix at the
end of the day kind of think of it like
a hammer if you're a hammer everything's
a nail
so if you're doing this everything's in
netflow
you can you can get into the weeds if
you're talking to the network
administrators network engineers
they're probably
more apt than many to get been out of
shape about whether it's netflow or
ipfix but
it's it's a semantics thing
so with that you've got some rfcs to
discuss it but you know
this is early in the morning but and
normally i would not be awake this early
my work day normally starts at 11 but
i'm not going to bore you with rfcs to
put you to sleep this early
that would be more of a
appropriate for closing closing time
so comparing pcaps and netflow
right
netflow it's going to abbreviate the
story it is the tldr it is the macro
perspective of
the story
you're going to have your smaller file
sizes meaning it's you're going to be
able to store more and it's going to be
easier to traverse around and allow
others to gain access to it
and honestly it's
fairly easy to import into pretty much
any sim
and honestly also in csv format so with
csv format the beautiful thing with that
is
oh well i'm just doing independent
research i don't have a sim i don't have
the ability to stand up something like
elk or
uh alien vault osim or graylog how do i
do this it's like it's a csv do you have
excel or do you have
python pandas do you have openoffice
there's a lot of ways that you can
analyze it which is good but it doesn't
include the packet contents even if we
have a stream of connection over http
and you transfer a file just a text file
that says hello world
with a packet capture you could carve
that out
with a net flow you're not going to be
able to
but
at the end of the day it's valuable
moving to
packet captures
it tells the whole story
it is the
token version
of the story you're gonna have 30 pages
describing what the trees smelled like
you're going to have 19 hours of movies
walking around
i'm not a big lord of the rings fan
but either way
it's going to tell the whole story it's
not going to be the cliff notes that you
read three days before your ap english 4
exam about lord of the rings
the cliff notes or netflow will tell you
that there were trees
and it may tell you that the trees had a
scent
but
if you want to know the whole story
you've got to go the other route and
that's basically packet captures
so with that as i said earlier
there is the philosophy that's prevalent
across industry if p caps or it didn't
happen
i can't disagree with that
and with that
it also allows things like stream
filtering so you can hone in on a
particular line of conversation between
two hosts and it also allows carving
but again you have that larger file size
and it's also
valuable which is good because that's
what we're trying to do we're trying to
bring value right
so
continuing with this we're going to talk
about how we would go about
extracting or
i like the term inferring
i stuck with
extracting in the presentation but
it's not truly extracting as much as it
more is
inferring um the net flow from pcaps so
if you come across a packet capture and
you don't
have access to a net flow interface or
you know you're just
you're doing some google foo and you do
a google door for something with file
type pcapp and you come across it and
you're like
hey you know i might want to actually
analyze this as if it's netflow
so you wouldn't have access to the
interface that captured it so
how would you come across it well i've
got some tools and scripts that i'm
going to hook you up with
so what we'll need for this
basically you need your packet capture
if you want packet captures to use for
this
the one that i'm going to use in the
admittedly pre-recorded demonstration
came from active countermeasures
they have a thing on their website
called malware of the day
and with it basically it's to help you
get used to doing
various types of
analysis or hunt type activities so with
that you can download those p caps and
run them through the tool test them that
way if you're doing any ctfs like in the
intelligence village there are no packet
captures today so sorry you can't test
it there
but anywhere you have a packet capture
you can do this
you'll need a linux host with silk
if you use the sans soft elk system i
believe it is native there
you it may also be native on just
regular sift i'm not 100 certain on that
but you can just install silk wherever
as well
optionally for analysis you could use
excel openoffice any of the above
you could also use something like elk in
the pre-recorded
demo piece i actually have elk
uh as part of that
and then also
you've got jupiter notebook with pandas
and unfortunately that was the one thing
that was going to be a live demo today
and wouldn't you know i ran an update
and it fell and went boom
wouldn't you know
so
uh but with that i mean
we can still talk through it so
to do this basically
here's the script for it um if anyone
wants it i'll share my contact info at
the very end and you can just either
stop by the intel village or shoot me a
message on twitter or linkedin or
whatever i'll give you these commands no
big deal
but basically within silk you're using
rwp to flow
and then the path to the actual pcap and
then you have to give it an output path
that's going to create a file type of rw
from there you run the next script which
would be rw cut
set the delimiter to a comma
so you can have a comma separated value
csv
you choose your timestamp format in this
case
i'm going with iso
and then your output path that's going
to be
the name of your csv file that you're
going to create and then
your
uh rw file
and then once you're done with that
now you have a csv that you can analyze
using any of the above
so
and
i accidentally duplicated that
so now
we are up at the demonstration piece so
let me
shift my displays momentarily
and we'll start here so
this is
uh basically
an instance of
silk so i stood up a custom host with
this this dfir techniques host this was
basically
during my period of unemployment me
tinkering with various uh forensics and
incident response tools
so i installed it there
and
ultimately uh this is just basically
running through it so
uh right here is that rwp to flow so p
caps uh we're using the evil os 10
underscore one hour p cap
uh and then basically we're just putting
it in a different directory
keeping the host name or the file name
intact with dot rw
do that cool oh i messed up when you
know
so now
still messing up
there we go and at this point we've
executed the rw cut
with the delimited with the comma
timestamp format iso
output path evil os 10
uh underscore one and then there's the
dot rw file and then at that point we
have it and we can verify it
so here's all of them
as you can see i put all the rw files
into
one particular location so that was what
caused the hiccup with the uh
the command earlier but basically you
know we have
the csvs and the rws as well
and that's really all there is to doing
the actual conversion
um moving from there though
right here we have
elk
so i will tell you i
i appreciate elk
but
standing elk stack elastic search log
stash and cabana standing it up from the
ground up can be a major pain
in
the derriere
major
so
if you're going to test this out
what i did
was i signed up on elastic's website for
a 14-day free trial
be careful if you go past that 14-day
free trial because i also had all my
honey pots connected to a free trial
and once i got out of the free trial
period it was supposed to cost me 50 a
month 13 days in the month my bill was
be careful what you connect to it
if you're only doing this kind of stuff
you're probably safe if you connect it
to a bunch of honey pots hanging out on
digital ocean
probably not the best of ideas
my my wallet learned and overcame
fortunately that was before i was
unemployed
so anyway to do this it's actually
fairly simple
you literally just say upload a file and
oh wouldn't you know there's a netflow
file
so this is what the csv looks like start
time source ip address source cc
destination ip address
and so on i don't need to read all of
them but basically we are able to see
what this looks like and then each entry
right here there's your
uh date and your time
and then from here you have your ip
address
cc being country code in this case
that's an additional field that that
particular file has so they've used
something like
geojson or some other
geo geolocation
mechanism to say this ip address
is assigned to say the united states an
organization in the u.s or
as we see over here
brazil
right and then we have the actual
um
the protocol the source port
so forth and so on and we can go all the
way across
some of these you're gonna see the same
some you're not going to see the same
it's going to vary depending on what
inputs you have
uh if it's coming native
netflow you're more likely going to have
something like this if it's coming from
uh silk it's going to be like
lowercase s
uh ip and then the ipo b upper case
so it's going to vary but ultimately as
with anything once you do the analysis
once you run that initial script you
need to validate what you have anyway so
that you know your your field names and
your headers anyway so
just go through and check it to see what
you have
from there you know we can scroll
through look at all this this gives us
everything as it's put into elk we give
it an index name
in this case
like if you're using soft elk for
example
they already have
elk built into it because it's soft elk
and it was built for
network forensics but the caveat is it
to be able to import stuff directly to
it is a little bit trickier than if you
do just a generic elk instance
because you have to match your
field names up and make sure that
everything is compliant uh because
they've already predetermined the
indexes uh they've already
indexes or should i say indices either
way
um with that it's already predetermined
and they've already got the dashboards
built so if you're doing it on your own
you'll have to build your own dashboards
but
it's
pretty much point and click it's not
terribly challenging
but from there i just gave it
i try to start everything with netflow
hyphen so that way i can use the same
dashboards repetitively because
i try to work smarter not harder
try
um and then from there let me skip ahead
a little bit so i ended up naming it
demo one it goes through so it's going
to process the file it's going to create
the index have your ingest pipeline
because at the end of the day elk was
built to receive files on
on the fly not just whenever you upload
it but in this case we're only using it
for the upload portion
so it's going to do that
sometimes it takes a little bit
and now we have everything there
so
it's just going to search across here
and this is the same data so this is
just exploring it so it's using the
discover tab to look at it this i mean
you can do this exact same thing in
excel you can do the exact same thing i
mean from the linux command line it's
not going to be as pretty
it's not going to be as delimited it'll
be just as delimited but
it won't be as aesthetically pleasing
but you could still do it
and then from there you can literally
run through
just have a look around verify
verify the fidelity of your data you
want to make sure that you've got good
quality data and something's not flubbed
up
like whenever i pull certain things from
an api like from one of the data breach
apis that i connect to it never fails
that somewhere in the usernames field is
a file hash and somewhere under address
is
probably a password so you've got to go
through and take a look at it clean it
up make sure everything's correct
but anyway we go through creating some
visualizations here like i said it's
literally point and click so right here
we've got
client ip addresses
so with this particular field uh
you've got client ip address but then
you've also got source and destination
so client ip address takes both
source and destination into account
but in this right now
you know for example
you're working in a sock you've got
netflow data and they say hey
we've just got smacked with a denial of
service who are the top five
chattiest hosts
you can find it out with netflow
or i'm sorry you can find that out with
a pcap
honestly your sim should be able to tell
you this but
for example maybe you don't have
a sim or
you don't have access to the sim
or
you might just want a challenge
you might be chasing one of those
promotions or
or something to that effect you might
want to be demonstrating your
ability to automate or think outside the
box
here's a here's a way for you to do it
so you can accomplish the same thing
here
and then there you go there's your top
five talkers so boom we have this now
the next time that i import netflow i
can change it uh right over here instead
of netflow demo to netflow whatever
whatever i named the next one
populated
so now we see client and destinations
what do we what are we going to do next
oh ports
so what happens when you see a bunch of
port 500
any ideas
it's a vpn
so
it's going to tell you just as much as a
pcap will
except it's a smaller file
and it can give you a little bit more
information because you can look at it
if you're filtering by a particular port
like say for example port 500 and you
could actually look and see
who patient zero is so you can do your
your
basic analysis to find out the root
cause of things
i will say with ports because it's a
numeric value
at times
elk will try to add all those numbers up
for you
it's like
i know we don't have a port 73814
unless there's a new rfc that i've not
heard about
oh
it's ipv7
totally saying that in jest
but like right here
number of octets that's one way to look
at it cool oh look right here we have a
median right so think about this from a
statistic analysis perspective
let's go back to high school or college
stats
we're not going to go into any like
really
disgusting things like confidence
intervals or anything like that
you've got three measurements that make
the most sense for you right
mean
median
standard deviation
right
mean is going to be your average so
that's going to be of all
data points this most accurately
describes
the general tendency of all other data
points
right you've got median which means that
across the board this is the most
center
data point
it
in some cases if we're talking about a
perfect bell-shaped curve
the mean and the median should be the
same but this is real life we don't have
bell-shaped curves well we do
occasionally but
not a perfect one so as a byproduct
there's a difference
and then finally you have your standard
deviation which speaks to
the general tendency to deviate from
the mean
so that shows you how much variance you
have a very high standard of standard
deviation indicates there's a lot of
variance a very low one indicates that
everything everything's clustered up
together pretty nicely so with that you
have those three measurements that you
could do here in this case we have the
median number of octets that's
indicative that of in this pcapp the
average is 114 000 uh octets or bytes
so
all right we have that cool
well
so there's the median
again
so you know just showing it different
ways
i mean the social engineer in me says
everybody interprets and learns
differently some people learn better
visually some people learn better by
reading some audibly some by seeing so
have it as many different ways as you
want now look i'm changing i'm creating
a new one that's the average so now
we're getting the mean here
that's
pretty
different wouldn't you think
that's
quite a bit larger than 114 000
without going deep into the actual
pcap and what was really happening
basically that lower number for the
median was indicative of beaconing
uh over
it's basically dns requests for text
records uh so that had a very small
packet size so that drove the number
down in that regard but in terms of the
higher average
there were several
file transfers
that were
very large that
basically offset it
so you had all the beaconing which drove
the median there but then to get the
average it's because of the large file
sizes
oh and look you can drag and drop and
move things around
you know do all the hokey pokeys you
want
so we can edit this so in this case i
said client let's change that to
source so it's not final right
and then with this you have other i
always like to turn the other off
because
with a large data set that other is
going to skew it pretty hard
so now we have source and we can look
and say oh well you know what our number
one
top talking source
is also the top talking destination
what's going on with this hmm that's
also an internet-facing ip address
enter the word oscent of the netflow
cent you now have an ip address to go
you know snooping on you you have a
target of interest for
say showdown or
url scan or
any of the tools du jour i mean honestly
google
so
you have all these mechanisms that you
can poke around with and find stuff and
then oh you want to filter it cool oh oh
actually you know what
i lied here's some jupiter
but
it's recorded um
so
if i were a fan of the band
train i would make a reference to drops
of jupiter but
i really i really lost interest when
hazel's sister came out
i would make a joke about my sisters not
having souls
but anyway this is what it looks like in
jupiter so
importing the csv file into jupiter
which is basically
a web-based python interface that allows
you immediate gratification that's why i
like jupiter
i've actually started writing all of my
ocean tools in jupiter now
because you can test it out and when
you're debugging it you don't have to
put like print works to here number one
works to hear number three works to hear
you see the exact line and
you're able to edit that data on the fly
without having to re-execute the entire
script you can copy and paste it and
move it on
so it works out really well so in this
case this is that same csv input into a
jupyter notebook
also with jupiter you can also analyze
it using the r language or also
uh the julia language i know a little
bit with r
not so much with julia but that's where
the word jupiter comes from
so with this i imported it into a pandas
data frame a pandas data frame is
basically an excel spreadsheet in memory
existing in python
it's very popular in the data science
world i'm a huge fan of it but anyway
what i've done here is
i i've said okay well we're doing it
iterating across the rows
and i want to know in terms of the
destination ip address i wanna know
the top four talkers hence the colon
four
and
right here we have them
and i apologize it's not showing as good
on the projector but
you're doing this from a browser it's
fairly easy to work with it
so
same thing with source
we get that same data
for the mean
literally it's just dot mean or dot
median or dot std for standard deviation
so from that we can do value counts so
right here doing the value counts this
is telling you on a per ip basis
how many entries there are for each
individual ip address this is giving you
context can you get this from a pcap yes
is it easy not always
because you have to filter it on strings
and do this and do that this right here
natively poof you could have all of the
queries that you want
built into a jupyter notebook import
that csv literally go up here
and click run
run across all the cells
your analysis is done with this
then you can go back to digging through
the pcap
going through the logs
silencing the alerts
contacting management
triggering incident response all the
things that you want to do all the
things that you should be doing that i'm
not telling you not to be doing i'm just
saying
this is another step that you can gain
additional context with
so as a byproduct you know we've got all
of this cool that's the same ip address
we saw before
oh and now we're back in elk with it so
we get that exact same thing so we're
able to filter and then when you do that
filter you can run that same analysis
and say
okay with this host what are the top
five hosts that talked to this host what
are the top five hosts that this host
talked to
if you know for example
if you know
for example within
a particular event
that
this host was compromised
at such and such time
you could set a filter
for around that time
and then you could filter based on that
hosts
and if you're trying to triage to
determine which host you should either
take off the network or investigate next
you now have context
you can do it with logs as well
but
do you really with a log do you really
care if
the compromise host literally just
pinged the other host or do you care
that it connected to the host via rdp or
ssh
right
pings can be important but
they don't provide you the full context
so this is going to give you more of
that so and again you can literally just
tinker around with this uh however you
see fit there's no right or wrong answer
uh you know with many things here
quite honestly the beautiful thing about
this with using with having the csv uh
you could do it natively in excel you
could put it in elk or you can run the
jupiter notebook but most importantly
i don't have to tell you which way works
best
i don't have to make that decision you
do
because i don't know your organization
just as much as you don't know mine
unless you might sell some clothes on
mercari but at the end of the day
what it boils down to is
you
can make it your own you can build your
own queries you can have your own
dashboards and honestly you can make
yourself look like a rock star
doing some of this so
with that
let me get back to powerpoint
so with that we've looked through it
uh just to reiterate here
you've got uh excel
you already have it right we've already
talked about this with elk
i'm not saying that excel cannot provide
visualization i'm not saying that
jupiter cannot provide visualization
both can
it's just a little bit heavier of a lift
so if you use elk you've got the native
vis the native capability of
visualization uh and then you can also
if you're using elk is a sim you can
import log data and other data points to
be able to integrate there if you go
with jupiter if you've got the python
chops you can go with jupiter
it's a little bit more complicated but
you're going to get better statistic
analysis
and
it's easier to repeat
and basically you reuse the same
notebook for
multiple
uh p caps
so
you know basically with that that leads
to the next steps the next steps as i
stated before
uh would be
you could ocent ocean the planet
start dropping some things into
things like virustotal or otx or just
your favorite threat intelligence ioc
ttp feed of choice
whatever you want there
but also importantly
it it can make for some really darn good
things to put into your reports
and that's where you're going to look
like a rock star
because
i said this in conversation yesterday i
meant it and i mean even continuing now
all the stuff that we just talked about
like it's all
for show right
what what do we get paid for
the
reports like
doing ocean investigations i mean
i've done some pretty wild stuff i found
some stuff that
quite frankly terrified me
but you know what the client didn't care
about
how i found it they cared that i had a
picture of it and some sort of
irrefutable proof saying that this was
what the case was so that they could do
whatever they needed to do
the same thing exists here having all
the cool tools is great
but at the same time
we do the tools for the show
reports for the dough and i didn't make
that up i really wish i did that came
that came from john strand actually so
i really wish i'd have thought it up but
here we are but basically that's what
you can do with it you can take the
screenshots from elk you can take those
data points from jupiter you can
i mean you can create the same
visualizations in jupyter write them to
a file import them in there as well and
i mean it's going to help going back to
what i said some people learn by hearing
some by seeing some by doing some by
reading
it allows you to
encompass this across the board as much
as possible so that people can get the
maximum comprehension from it and that's
ultimately what we want because
i arrived at the conclusion that
everybody working in infosec basically
works in some form of intelligence
right
intelligence at the end of the day uh i
mean
give or take whatever you want with it
but
the purpose of intelligence is to assist
in decision making
so our deliverables our products our
reports
should be
to inform in a mo in the most unbiased
way possible to assist in decision
making so having maximum comprehension
is
key with that being said i'll open it up
for questions
and while it's open for questions here's
my contact information
but
any
questions concerns complaints grievances
thoughts opinions or otherwise not that
i've ever rehearsed that phrase
okay i'll leave this up for a moment
and
uh with that being said
we've got the book signings in the
intelligence village downstairs corey
and myself are both selling our books
and signing them and uh the intelligence
village ctf will officially kick off at
10. the only thing you need is an
internet connection it could be on a
laptop could be on a phone tablet
um we're in knox county so i don't think
you have too much to worry about with ip
over avian carrier if we were a little
bit closer like monroe county might be a
little bit of a problem
i joke because my mom lives down in that
area and has dsl and it's awful i was
like
you got to get your neighbors to stop
hunting your ipo over avian carriers
your neighbors keep shooting your
carriers out of the sky
but anyway
that's that
if there are no questions uh thanks
everyone for coming out thanks for your
patience and uh
have a blast if i can be of any
assistance i will be in the intelligence
village pretty much all day thanks
[Applause]