all right and now we have
an amateur's guide to microchip
encapsulation chemistry with travis
goodspeed
[Music]
all right who likes
microchips
all right and if you really love
something you should boil it in acid
right
okay
[Applause]
this here
let's jump in a little bit closer
this is a complete 32-bit computer
including
ram
rom
it's connected to some other
ships on a board this is from a pcmcia
card
that stands for people can't memorize
corporate identification acronyms
um
for you youngins in the audience it used
to be that you'd buy a laptop and it
would weigh more than a brick and it
would not have wi-fi or ethernet and if
you wanted to get online you'd have to
install an extra card
this particular chip is from a
cryptography card
back then they didn't want you to have
cryptography and software
for fear that it would help the nazis or
something so
they
they made you buy it as a physical unit
and this was in a fortezza card which is
the replacement to the clipper chip
and it had a law enforcement access
field in it so you could
you could have cryptography but the cops
could undo it if they filed the right
paperwork
um
thankfully this standard died off in the
mid 90s and we don't use it anymore
so today i'm going to teach you how to
take a part a microchip and turn it into
bear glass like this and also how to
turn the bear glass into
a full photograph of the entire die
and how to do some other cool stuff like
if you zoom in close enough um
does anyone see this like
egyptian tablet like thingy right here
just to the
the right of my finger
if you zoom in really close on that
tablet
and you squint a little you can actually
see the ones and zeros of the boot rom
of this chip
and so when the chip is locked and
you're not allowed to read them you can
recover it photographically
and then from the photographs you can
get out like a file that you would load
into ida pro or gydra to reverse
engineer
another
thing that's pretty cool to do within
the the lab
this is one of my good fete boards i
designed these as an undergrad as like a
bus adapter but the cool thing about
this one is that little uh
circle that's burnt out of the side chip
this chip is an msp430f220
it's a 16-bit microcontroller that
contains the firmware to make it this
device
and by burning a hole in the outside i
can now shine lights into this chip
in order to mess with it as it's running
so
despite the whole burned in the
packaging of this chip this board is
still fully functional and still does
everything it's supposed to
this is a another msp430 chip which i've
live decapped the um the hole in this
package
allows the dye to be exposed so that i
can
shine a camera flash on it
and i'm not doing this to take pictures
i'm although
we do have cool pictures of it i'm
shining the camera flash because every
transistor on this microchip die is a
photo transistor and if you hit it with
light
it starts conducting electricity even
though maybe it's not supposed to
and if you hit the entire chip at once
with a very bright light
sometimes the readout protection on this
chip will fail and you will be allowed
to connect a debugger even though the
chip is locked and is not supposed to
allow its software to be read
and this is how you can get the firmware
out of a protected chip
you'll need some equipment to do this
this is my handy dandy hot plate
you'll note that the heat settings are
just in numbers from 0 to 10.
these very loosely correlate to
to real temperatures so you shouldn't
trust that it will keep the right
temperature at any given time
you need some beakers in order to hold
the acids these are pyrex glass
and they're great for everything except
for the hydrofluoric acid and the reason
for that is that the hydrofluoric acid
will eat the glass
and that winds up ruining your glassware
and your experiments
you'll need
pipettes so these little doohickeys
allow you to pick acid out of one jar
and put it into another
the big one on the left is what i use
for transferring
large amounts in the order of like 5 or
10 milliliters in order to entirely
drown a chip and then boil it on the hot
plate
the little one i use for stronger acids
in order to do the live decapping
and in that style i need a stronger acid
because the weak ones include water and
the water as a catalyst will burn off
the bonding wires that connect the chip
to the packaging
i've got these little squirt gun bottles
with acetone and water and isopropyl
alcohol this is not the type of ipa that
you drink
basically
we're using the acetone
to clean gunk off of the chip because
it's really good at dissolving stuff
we do this after the acid has broken it
apart
the ipa the isopropyl alcohol is not as
good as acetone at like picking up junk
but it's a lot easier to manufacture ipa
cleanly
so if i let acetone dry on the chip then
it will leave a residue behind
but if i use isopropyl alcohol in a
second bath for the chip then i can get
that residue off and have clean
photographs instead of dirty ones
you'll need a microscope
this is the cheap one that i keep in my
lab i've had this one since grad school
it's um
you know there's a single column that
you look down it's metallurgical which
means that the light comes through the
lens to hit the surface
rather than
coming up through a glass slide like you
might have in high school biology class
and the reason for this is that the
silicon dioxide is opaque to light when
it becomes thick enough to be a chip
so if you try to shine a light through
it it gets blocked and you see nothing
we also need some chemicals this is um
65 nitric acid
this is the weaker nitric acid that i
use and
um it's nice for
destroying the packaging of the entire
chip
because the water inside of it will also
take off the bonding wires and that gets
me a very thin piece of glass that i can
photograph
i also got the good this is red
fuming nitric acid
instead of being 65 pure this stuff is
90 pure
uh it is at least 90 nitric acid and it
is at most 2 percent water
and that means that it will do very
little damage to the bonding wires and
this is how i'm able to remove the
packaging from a chip without damaging
it
you can use
regular nail polish remover as your
acetone
like i said this stuff is not completely
clean if you let it dry on a surface you
will then see gunk left over
but i don't care because i've got
isopropyl alcohol and for this stage the
99 reagent grade is a lot better as far
as cleaning stuff off giving you good
pictures
do not use this without a proper fume
hood but you can also use hydrofluoric
acid which is available
commercially as rust stain remover
to
remove layers of the microchip after you
have extracted the glass from the
package
um this is useful because as we burn
lower into the chip we have fewer things
on the surface blocking our view
on a smart card this is absolutely
essential because smart cards will have
like a maze of wiring on the surface
in order to detect your
messing around with them
and you have to remove all of those
wires in order to photograph any of the
organs of the chip like where the cpu is
or where the ram is where the rom is
and because the hydrofluoric acid
dissolves glass you have to use these
like plastic beakers in order to heat it
up to
knock the chip out
so we're now ready for our first
experiment um
we are going to use 65 nitric acid and
we are going to dissolve a chip
packaging in it in order to get the bare
glass and then we're going to photograph
the glass
so
this is the acid that we're using this
is the big two and a half liter jug
we're not going with the the stronger
stuff
these are our two chips
this is the ch-582m from a company
called wch
they're a chinese chip manufacturer
who has been making
lots of different microcontroller class
and radio class chips
over the past few years they're doing
many which are compatible with western
ships in order to be drop-in
replacements
so i bought the entire series and now
i'm photographing all of them in order
to see how they relate
um you begin with a beaker with the two
chips in it can anyone spot what's
dangerous in this photo
exactly the fingers and the gloves
so
you put the gloves on you open up the
nitric acid i use this little storage
bottle so that i don't have to bring the
the big jug around because if i spill
something out of that jug i can like
dissolve my oven
um
after dropping the acid onto the chips
and before any heat is applied
the uh the liquid will turn green and
you'll see this as like it looks like
ink coming off of the bottom of the chip
packaging
this is the ground pad and the pins of
the chip dissolving within the acid
um
green or blue will indicate metals like
copper um
a proper chemist could tell you more
about which means which and why
we then heat the packaging up
we're aiming at about 100 degrees
celsius
which is beneath the boiling point of
the acid but the hotter the acid is the
faster the reaction is and at room
temperature this acid is not strong
enough to dissolve the chip packaging
which is why we have to bump it up a bit
you are aiming for a temperature that is
high enough that the package will
dissolve but not so high that the acid
will boil off
and all of this is being performed
inside of a fume hood
with
forced air ventilation so all of the air
is being sucked out of the front of the
fume hood where i sit
and then pulled out through the top of
the fume hood and then vented out of a
window in order to
keep my air clean
after a while
you'll start seeing the
the package fall apart
and the bare dye will be visible but it
will still be covered with a little bit
of gunk or residue left over from the
chip
here you can see
there's like a chip in the bottom right
and all those little specks all of that
used to be packaging on this chip
remember this was these were
two
packaged chips and some clear liquid
when we began now the liquid is green
and the packaging is crumbling apart
like a wet oreo
here are the two of them um this little
square here and that one up there
um
because they're still covered in gunk we
can't photograph them yet
so to fix that
we spray acetone over them in order to
uh knock off a bit of the surface gunk
and this leaves us with the um the two
bear dice at the bottom of a beaker of
acetone
which we put into an ultrasonic bath
this is a commercial jewelry cleaner
some other people who do this sort of
work they don't like to use the
ultrasonic bath
because the sharp edges of the chips
hitting against the side of the beaker
will sometimes chip or damage them
and you can see this damage in my dive
photographs
here's a close-up you can see the two
dice here
the gray one on the left is upside down
you will see a flat gray for the bottom
side of almost every chip
the front side is what has all of the
pretty colors and the fancy wiring in it
and that's usually covered in more
gunk than the back side is
as soon as you hit the button on your
ultrasonic cleaner
all of this black gunk
will start shaking around and very
quickly falling off of the chip and
dissolving within the acetone
so very quickly we have two clean dice
we then take these to the cheap
microscope this is the one in the lab
and we put it under the light and we
look at it and all we're looking to see
at this point is like how much gunk is
left on the dye
if i see a lot of it i'll dump it into
another acid bath
i might use a different acid such as
sulfuric acid depending upon the
epoxy chemistry of that individual
package
and then the end result is this clean
dye
floating in
sorry
this is floating in isopropyl alcohol
and remember isopropyl alcohol is good
because it is clean
i take it down to my photography
table this way
still in the beaker
and then as i remove it i have one
remaining problem which is that even
though the isopropyl alcohol is a lot
cleaner than the acetone it's still not
perfectly clean there is some
microscopic stuff dissolved in it
and if i allow it to dry on the surface
of my chip
then it's going to leave behind a little
residue that will show up in my
photographs
to fix that
i use computer air duster
and
with my tweezers i hold the dye in place
as i do a burst of air from the side
this causes all of the isopropyl alcohol
to fly off the side
taking its
dissolved stuff with it and that gives
me a clean dye that i can photograph
if this step
messes up or if i don't use clean
tweezers or
if like dirt from the surrounding area
or maybe a moth comes in and flies onto
it
i've not ruined everything i just have
less clear photographs
so many of these stages can be skipped
if you just need to quickly know answer
some small question
like does the chip have mask rom visible
from the surface
at this point i use a better microscope
this microscope is still a cheaper model
it's an m scope it's about yay tall
it has
two binoculars for my eyes and then it
has a third trinocular adapter for a
camera
this is a usbc camera that runs straight
to my desktop and i have a hot key
whenever i hit the power button on my
sun type 6 keyboard it snaps a
photograph and stores that as part of
the set
at low magnification sometimes you can
fit the entire chip within view
but
we want like crazy details we would
rather have
an image
of a size that we could blow up to fill
an entire wall
rather than of a size that
you know is napkin or book sized so the
way to do that is just to switch to the
higher magnification lens within the
microscope
and as we do that we have the problem
that
we only get to see one corner of the
chip and not everything is in focus over
here on the the far right side the focus
is off
so what we can do is we can move around
right if i move the microscope a little
bit to the right
i get another view and if i move it a
bit further i get a third view
jumping back to the far left here
we can start stacking these images
together right because these three are
the same chip just shown in different
positions
so if we photograph the entire chip that
way we can overlap them in order to
create a single panorama with the entire
chip in view
doing this manually works fine for a
chip like this where i can fit the
entire width in only three photographs
but it is excruciating for larger chips
that require many different
many different steps so there's this
computer program called hug in
huggin is a graphical user interface for
another package called pano tools
and
hug in has looked at all of the images
in my collection
and
all of these little points that you see
highlighted
are the same point between the left
image and the right image
even though the left image and the right
image are at different locations
and so huggin is able to identify all of
these overlapping points
and crunch the numbers together and then
throw out the ones that are false
positives or poor matches
and if it works out right it can then
take all of the different photos that
i've taken maybe 100 of them maybe 500
and it can stitch them into a single
composite image of very high resolution
where i can zoom in on any details that
i need or
or see any piece of the chip
conveniently
and you can recognize a few details of
this from the surface like
on the bottom
you see that some of those little
squares have a circle in them and some
of them don't
those are bonding pads and anything with
a circle on it has had a bonding wire
ripped off
anything without a circle never had a
connection
so
maybe if we touch a needle to one of
those we can access a special test mode
of the chip that was used during
manufacturing but never packaged
on this particular chip there was a
second die that would sit in the middle
and
this upper row on the bottom would
connect to that second die while the
bottom row would connect to the outside
of the physical packaging
so we might be able to tap the
communication between the two dice
within this package by touching needles
to one and not to the other
we also see those like
octagons in the the top right those are
inductors that tells us that this is a
radio chip and not a simple
microcontroller
but sometimes we need to see beneath the
surface
so the next experiment we're going to do
is um using rust stain remover this is
um like three percent hydrofluoric acid
um do any of you watch breaking bad do
you remember in the first season when uh
he kills the bad guy in his basement and
they have to get rid of the body
so he brings some chemical jugs home
from uh the high school that he works at
and dissolves the bodies on them that's
hydrofluoric acid it is not true that it
would dissolve the whole body but it
would dissolve the bathtub so they got
the math half right
um
because it dissolves glass
you need to use a plastic beaker for
this
um of a particular sort that can handle
the the temperatures and
um
the reason why we do this uh this is a
surface photograph of a chip from a
blood glucose sensor
if you're diabetic and you want to check
your insulin without having to stab your
finger
you can put one of these things on your
shoulder and then you can tap it with
your phone and your phone will ask this
chip what your blood glucose is um it's
a medical god send especially um you
know for stubborn patients who don't
want to deal with finger pricking
um
but if you look at the surface of it
you see that it's like kind of faint and
blurry and if you zoom all the way in
you can see that there's this pattern of
like
little
metal dots
and this pattern is a fill layer in
order to have
you know fewer gaps on the surface
smart cards will go a step further and
all of this metal will be connected into
a crazy maze
so that the maze can't be broken while
keeping the chip functional
for photography we've already broken the
chip we've already removed all of the
bonding wires but we want to know what's
beneath the surface
so this is the chip at the top
and if we boil it in hydrofluoric acid
for like five minutes
we can remove that top layer and begin
to see more organs of the chip we can
now see where the rom is we can see
where the s-ram is
this chip has a crazy
non-volatile memory called fram and we
can also identify that visually
and you can see
uh pieces of it like if i flip between
them
some of these large areas are completely
invisible from the surface some of these
big rectangles
and then
as i jump down they become visible and
if i go just a bit further
they become really well separated and i
can now see that like the the cpu is
probably that t on the right
and that the um the memories are in
different locations and this lets me
understand more about the chip that i'm
working with
at the extreme end of this is reverse
engineering the um
uh the gate structure of the chip uh
which i've not done firsthand but which
you can find in literature for um
like the the myfair classic had its
cryptography reverse engineered this is
a
an nxp
rfid tag used for building access
uh
karsten knoll and starbug and uh henrik
platz and a few other fine people they
they took these de-layered photographs
of that rfid tag and they were able to
reverse engineer the
proprietary cryptographic algorithm used
by the tag
in order to recover the keys of all of
the tags and break that
system
so this is great if you're trying to
photograph a dead thing if you're trying
to see what
what used to be there and then get rid
of it
our final experiment for today is going
to involve the stronger acid this is red
fuming nitric acid this is at least 90
percent
nitric acid this is at most 2 percent
water
when you open this bottle there is like
a mist of uh acid fumes that come out of
it
um
this is the one that you really want the
gloves on for and use
latex gloves do not use nitrile gloves
not the blue ones the blue ones will
catch on fire if you put three drops of
this stuff on them
this is our friendly neighborhood
fortesa card
trademarked by the nsa i think
in the mid 90s you would use this for
secure telephones you would have a
pcmcia slot on the side of the phone you
would insert your card you would know
your pin number and this would allow you
to make secret phone calls
you could also plug it into your laptop
and your laptop could use it to send
secret emails
all of these cards have long died they
depended upon a battery that would back
up ram in order to hold the keys so as
the batteries died all of the keys died
with them
a fellow who also does chip photography
by the name of john mcmaster just sent
me a giant box of them and i'm going to
see if i can get the code out or or
something fun with them
but for today we're going to use this as
our target example
so this is the pcmc card with the
metal packaging removed you can see the
the card slot on the right which is what
we connect to the laptop motherboard
and this big
microtronics chip the myk-82 by vlsi
semiconductor
this is the secret sauce chip
and you can see there's an arm logo in
the corner of the chip that's how we
know that this contains a cpu
in order to live decap this we first
heat it up on the hot plate
and then
we take some of the red fuming nitric
acid and we move it to a beaker using
the the large pipet
this is the last time that i will use
the large pipette because the small
pipette with a very teeny tip allows me
to put very little acid onto my target
when i first started doing this i would
use a metal mask
using um like metal duct tape
i stopped doing that because i
found that it was easier to just put a
very little amount of acid in the center
of the chip patiently wait for it to
drill down and then wash it off with
acetone
so we take just the tiniest bit out you
can see the the yellow in the pipette is
very very little
and then i put just a single smallest
possible drop and this drop has to come
directly from the tip like you would use
in a fountain pen this can't be a drop
that builds up and then falls off of the
tip because that will be too much acid
um i let it sit there and sort of bubble
away for just a second
and then i move the board over to a
large beaker and i squirt acetone out of
my squirt gun bottle at it
and
you can see the the acetone sort of
running down the side of it um the
boiling point of acetone is very low
so
as i squirt the stuff out
the board still dries off very quickly
and i'm not leaving behind any residue
you can see that the there's this little
circle in the center
and that the vlsi logo is damaged um
this acid has torn away that small bit
of the packaging of the chip while
leaving everything else intact all of
the other pins are intact there is no
rust elsewhere on the board there is no
damage
i keep repeating this i keep
putting just the tiniest bit in to fill
that cavity that i'm drilling down
under heat i wait for that cavity to
expand
and then i put more onto it and with
each step the circle grows a little bit
wider
and a little bit deeper um
and eventually we start seeing stuff
inside
this piece here is actually a copper
ground plane
i don't know whether it's a security
feature or whether it's a coincidence
but the dye in this chip is actually
stored upside down
this does become a good demonstration
though for why
the copper metal on the top of the chip
is not damaged by
the red female nitric acid
in this photo i've only used red fuming
nitric
if i then put a little drop of the 65
it starts changing color becoming less
shiny
and if i leave that drop there
it boils in this green color which as i
told you before indicates that metal is
breaking apart and then forming
compounds with the acid and if i go far
enough through this using red nitric
again
this little
glass here is the
back side of the microchip
which has none of the interesting
details but we'll do things like
allow infrared light to leak out
so you can run the chip
in a dark room
under a microscope and then
record the the session in infrared light
in order to see
which pieces are lighting up a fellow by
the name of dimitri no nasal
does some experiments with that
i can then repeat this on the
sram chip u4 down in this corner in
order to expose it
but what i really want is the top
of the vlsi chip
to see that that same picture in the
glass so i turn it upside down
you can see here that the
secret government chip was made in
taiwan
and then i repeat the the same
experiment i put a tiny amount of acid
in the middle of it i allow that to
boil up i wash it off with acetone
this forms like a little cavity and then
as i repeat this eventually the dye is
exposed
and now i've got the functioning
microchip visible from the surface
without damaging any of the bonding
wires or breaking the chip or its
functionality
these experiments are
not so useful on their own or without
combining it with something else
so
you might want photographs of a chip in
order to know what model number it is
many times when you're taking something
apart you'll find a black epoxy blob on
the board with no package that has a
part number but you still need to know
what's inside
and this sort of chemistry can answer
that question for you
you can also
you also sometimes find a
chip that is locked and you're not
allowed to read the firmware out of it
by removing the lid of the package and
shining a light in either a laser at
some particular area or by hitting a
camera flash the entire thing
you can confuse the flip-flops that
record the state of whether or not
you're allowed to
read the memory out of the chip
and by knocking them loose you can then
freely read the firmware out and get a
copy of like the firmware to protected
medical equipment
you can stick needles into the chip they
make these micro positioner probes that
have
like an etched tungsten needle coming
off the edge of them and they have
little knobs that you turn in order to
move that needle around the chip and
touch a particular area and then they
have an amplifier so that you can
see that signal on your oscilloscope
even though that signal never was
supposed to have been brought out of the
chip
if you can touch an address or a data
line this way you can then leak memory
out of the chip or sort of watch as it's
doing its thinking
um
and uh it's a hell of a lot of fun to be
able to do this
um i got out of this hobby for 10 years
and i recently got back into it i
converted my upstairs kitchen
uh all of the
all of the photos that you've seen today
and all of the uh techniques
are from my home lab
so
um
and this is nacho
he's nacho cat
um thank you for your time and attention
and if you have any questions um
i'd like to hear them and i've also got
a couple of books to give away of um
pocket gtfo from no starts press yes
oh
um
so so the question was how did i
discover all of this um
very little of this is entirely new work
um most of this i've learned from books
or from discussions with other people
chris tarnowski and brookhill helped me
out when i was getting started
and john mcmaster helped me get back
into this hobby after
i left it and
all of my tools in storage
the
the proper technical name for this in
forward engineering as opposed to
reverse engineering
it's called failure analysis
and you can find books on failure
analysis chemistry
that walk you through all of these
procedures but they sort of assume that
you're going to have a very well-funded
lab to do it in
and so they don't answer such questions
as like what's the best equipment to
purchase by ebay or which chemicals can
i get at the home depot
questions which are important if you're
trying to do this at home
so yes
why can't you use a plastic or sorry a
metal applique instead of the plastic
pipette to gently
apply the
higher strength acid to d-cap
so
it's not that the acid has no reaction
against the metal
it's the the reaction becomes buffered
by the initial reaction sort of like
stainless steel and atmosphere um the
surface of stainless steel is a very
fine layer of rust
um which is why like and same for um
aluminum so if you put gallium or
mercury on top of aluminum you can rust
it all to hell
similarly the
the pipette the plastic one has no
reaction against the acid
i can leave a pipet sitting in the acid
for a week come back and none of it has
been damaged
for metal it buffers enough that i'm not
going to damage the wires during any
individual reaction but if i were to
like forget that i had the acid there
and i would leave it then eventually the
water from the atmosphere would be
enough of a catalyst to melt a metal
pipette
yes so so for light
camera flash
everything just booms uh but with a
laser how how accurate can you get
uh as in can you touch
a single transistor or
is it right so the
and again the signal transistor thing is
something that i've read about but not
done firsthand um
in cmos you basically have one
transistor that is pulling the voltage
high and another that pulls it low and
you balance all of these so that they
don't conflict with each other
the easiest thing that you can do with a
laser focus through a microscope is you
can hit the transistor that is supposed
to not be conducting
and then it will conduct a little bit
and you will be wasting electricity
between high and low voltage
there's a fellow by the name of sergey
so i hope that i'm pronouncing that
right
he did a dissertation on um
on these sort of like semi-invasive
photovoltaic attacks where you have
opened up the packaging invasively but
you are um
you're not sticking any needles in
you're only shining light in
as for light against the whole package
you are damaging or you are damaging the
state of like half the flip-flops
s-ram will sometimes go wonky
um
you have to arrange it so that when
everything gets scrambled
the piece that you wanted to
hit also flips over and then you can
correct everything else so in in my case
for using that technique against an
msp430 that allowed me to connect to
debugger and then through the debugger i
was able to like reset all of the values
that i needed for the flash memory to
work and all of the other configurations
that i owe
cool
um
yes any other questions uh yes yes
is there any that this won't work
on or will it work on most of them so
the question was is there any chip that
this won't work on um
there are chips that i've read about
which
will include like
a mems function like an accelerometer
and then if the mems
you know micro electron
micro electrical mechanical systems
they're really tiny and fragile
and the acids that i'm using might
damage that as i'm taking the chip apart
so you can use that as a sort of sensor
you can also include um
like a photo transistor
in order to intentionally recognize the
background light
i've read about these being in smart
cards but most of my practical
experience has been with consumer
microcontrollers which do not include
these features because they would
decrease the reliability
and increase the cost of the chip
without providing any advantage to the
manufacturer
so defenses against this are possible
but they're rare
even
the
microtronics chip that i showed
you know
it has the die upside down but it has
nothing else that i've found that tries
to make it hard to take apart
so
yes
[Music]
excellent question
no i'm a bit lazy about that i i use um
i boil it off where i use baking soda
what was the question oh the question
was do i use any bases to react against
the acid in order to make it neutral
before
disposing of it
for a spill i drown and drown the finger
in soap and i cuss like a sailor
um
it is important to know the difference
the 65 nitric
it's like um it numbs your nerves before
it starts melting your flesh
so if you spill some of it it's like a
little tingly feeling but it doesn't
actually hurt until the next day when a
big chunk of your finger is gone
and when you start using latex gloves
with it you'll notice that they turn
yellow
which is all of the acid that you would
have gotten on your fingers if you
hadn't used the gloves
and that's why it's important to use
these safety
things ritualistically
rather than only when you expect that
you're doing something dumb as um
it's the the hold my beer principle of
safety
so how how do you want to give away
these books all right ask some questions
you want to do some challenges or um so
so those are for a different thing oh
these are for different these are for
the uh the lock picking challenge okay
um the kid in the black hills shirt if
you could pass this back to him
and um
i've got volumes two and three who would
like each
yes
and one more all right if you could pass
that to him so that i don't uh
gentlemen in the besides maroon b-sides
t-shirt
which b-sides is that
tampa i like it i like the pirate theme
cool
and that's the end of my show thank you
for your time and attention
[Applause]