so to kick off this morning one of the
things I really enjoy doing every year
as a as a university organization with
some history and a lot of moving parts
what we try to do is recognize
individuals who have contributed to the
mission of serious to the mission of
cyber security and privacy here at
Purdue and who have done things that we
would consider to be really outstanding
the first award that we give every year
we call the pillar of serious award and
this is given to an individual who over
a period of years has provided
outstanding support for our mission in
one way or another so sometimes this has
gone to our corporate partners sometimes
this has gone to faculty sometimes has
gone to our staff but these are
individuals who over a period of years
have continued to support what we do
sometimes without recognition and this
is a way for us to publicly thank them
and acknowledge what they've done this
year's award goes to someone who joined
us about a decade ago and has worked
tirelessly to help advance the cause of
not only the education aspects of the
the center but also the outreach and the
teaching and has pretty much always been
there whenever we've called and said we
need somebody can you rearrange your
schedule and the answer is almost always
yes and and that's an accomplishment
when you are a faculty member running
lots of projects and students and during
the last few years has also been running
the cyber Center at Discovery Park an
incredible number of achievements and
one of the most highly cited faculty
members we have in computer science or
insecurity in general here with the
university we have been so fortunate and
continue to be so fortunate to have
elisa bertino as a colleague and this
year's pillar of serious
as a spa side I was in Italy and what
reason I moved the era was because of
serious serious was a very worldwide
well known and that really was a very
excited about this opportunity I'm still
very excited today even more serious is
a great place to be and we have a lot of
sponsors with whom we do a lot of
exciting work a lot of students great
leadership so I don't know what I did to
deserve this award I'm very happy about
it thank you allah a second a word that
we give every year is called the diamond
award and this goes to a student who has
graduated or well will graduate by the
end of the summer session or or who's
already graduated basically and we
recognize this person as someone who has
overcome various kinds of difficulties
to succeed in an outstanding manner and
in studies here at serious and we issued
a call for nominations and got an
exceedingly long nomination of this
individual is a hardware nello here
forward so i'm not going to try and read
this all up and then keep you in
anticipation it because it will be
obvious but let me know here that says
are before he got here earned two
masters degrees in both robotics and
astronautics at the university of rome
and then came here to pursue further
studies working in astro arrow in the
area of systems of systems and
control and has done all of its course
work with the GPA of 40 which is a great
accomplishment for a graduate student
coming in although we had great great
preparation he's been a key member of
the research group over in the system of
systems and part of the challenges for
the work he's done in developing his
software and his algorithms has been the
fact that he doesn't he's not a US
citizen and so in Astro arrow and some
of security we have a set of
restrictions that make it difficult to
gain access to some of the data and
software that would make that possible
nonetheless his work has found its way
into those environments it has inspired
work he's gotten commendations from
there's this huge list of organizations
and people who recognized what he's done
in addition to working on his ph.d and
finishing that up he's also earned a
third masters in planetary geology and
with an interest I guess in spaceflight
and robotics and who knows where that's
going to take you but it's part of this
overall pattern of achievement he's had
a number of peer-reviewed papers where
he's been first author seven of those at
least for those of you who saw posters
here last year he was one of the poster
winners he's got some journal articles
that have just appeared and and in
general is just an astonishing scholar
one of the kinds of people that we are
so proud to have here and have as an
alumnus during some of the breaks take
some time say hello to Cesare and
congratulate him on his achievement
which is this year's serious diamond to
work
yeah and that was not by planning but I
guess that goes to show first of all we
have this very global reach to be able
to bring in students and faculty and and
visitors from all around the world we go
after the best expertise wherever it
resides and what we can't bring in we
produce so the third set of awards that
we give each year are based on the
poster session so any of you were here
last night had a chance to go through
and we had I think was 56 posters 57
posters of current research projects and
those those aren't all of our research
projects we probably have at least half
again as many that are active those are
the ones where the students were able to
take time out and produce posters to
describe what they're doing that we're
in a position where we could share with
all of you some of what's going on we
had a set of secret judges eyes are
still so secret can I ask them to to
stand up and identify themselves because
it was a lot of work we'd like to
acknowledge our judges so judges if
you're in the room stand up and thank
you we had four judges there two of them
and what they did is they went around
they identified those posters that look
to be particularly well-suited for
recognition evaluated them listen to the
students asked questions rank them and
then we came up with a set of awards
based on the posters and the students
presentation of those posters and what
we do is we present those students with
a certificate and there will be a small
cash prize that's provided by our
partners the certificate I'll give today
is is a placeholder we'll have the
actual one to give out probably next
week
let me also preface this by saying the
fact that I am also a faculty advisor to
some students means my name or my
students may have come up but I didn't
have anything to do with the judging
honest Joel coordinated at all and well
you know you may have your questions
about Joel but that's a whole different
issue so third place advised by
Professor sort of bug she and myself
Christopher guitar Azure Chris are you
here okay so Chris got third place and
that was for the deceptive memory
systems countering anti forensics with
deception and
up
it's in here somewhere
there it is second place advised by
Himanta maji and ning li li is wang yi
zhi Tianhe wang and omar territory are
you here this is for the poster symbol
based visual cryptographic
authentication mechanisms attacks and
new constructions any of those students
here it's before noon and graduate
students yes and some of us faculty
thank heavens for strong coffee okay and
the first place poster award advised by
my khattala and myself with
participation of Geoff Avery christopher
gutierrez and mohammed el machaca her
SATs passwords ending path is Jeff here
or and we know Chris isn't here if you
see those if you see those individuals
you can wish them a congratulations will
have their posters as well as all the
others available online you'll be able
to see those shortly along with some of
the videos of the talks and that will
help get tide you over until next year's
security symposium