welcome to the serious seminar for March
9th today I'm pleased to welcome
Professor Ryan Henry who comes to us
from downstate is a professor in in in
computer science at Indiana University
professor Henry got his PhD at the
University of Waterloo so he also comes
to us from from north of here and is
going to be talking to us today about
practical private information retrieval
thanks ok so as Chris mentioned I'm
going to be talking about private
information retrieval I saw on the
website for serious that students are
offered credit to attend this so I was
counting on several students and I kind
of tailored the talk a little bit to be
more to teach you a little bit about how
PIR works rather than to focus on like
the really technical new contributions
so there will be a lot of giving you the
the background behind how these things
actually work and then I'll talk about
some of the new stuff towards the end so
let's start with the problem statement
what are we trying to do so private
information retrieval as you can
probably imagine has something to do
with information retrieval which is this
basic problem of a user trying to fetch
some sort of data from a database so the
user is going to issue a request and is
going to get back a response and this in
and of itself there's a lot of
interesting research questions that you
can ask what we're interested in is what
if we want some notion of privacy here
so I had a conversation recently with my
10 year old niece who was once a very
big Justin Bieber fan and she has
informed me that it is no longer cool to
be a Justin Bieber fan so for the sake
of this example let's suppose that this
request here is for Justin Bieber videos
which might be rather embarrassing so we
want to figure out can we protect the
privacy of this user who's looking for
Justin Bieber videos on the internet now
those of you who know about tor might
say this is an easy problem to solve
you just connect over the Tor
network you send your request for Bieber
videos through tour you get your
response back and now the website this
the server has no idea who it was
looking for these embarrassing Bieber
videos and this of course works for this
particular example but what if instead
of searching for Justin Bieber the user
was searching for some top-secret patent
idea trying to decide is this a novel
idea should I devote the next 6 months
of my life to researching this this what
I believe to be a novel idea what if the
website or the database that's being
queried here is owned by some
multinational corporation with billion
dollar research budget who sees this
idea and goes ah that's a brilliant idea
let's bring this to market before that
user has an opportunity to commercialize
so here tor doesn't help the website or
the server doesn't know whose idea this
is but they still learn the brilliant
idea and so we're solving the wrong
problem using tor here what we really
want to solve is the problem of allowing
the user to query the database and
having the database not have a clue what
it is the user looked for so we're not
going to try to protect the identity of
the user we're going to try to protect
the contents of the query if you want to
protect the identity of the user you can
do all of this over tor and then you get
both notions of privacy okay so that's
that's the basic hand-wavy version of
what exactly is PIR a slightly more
formal definition but by no means the
the cryptographic definition is that
private information retrieval is just
the database technique that is going to
allow a user to query a database while
protecting from the database server the
contents of the user's query and PIR is
how we'll usually refer to private
information retrieval let's see standard
acronym okay so some of you might be
wondering is this actually possible to
query a database and get responses
without the database learning what you
asked for or what it sent you so to
convince you this is possible let's look
at the sort of the trivial way to do
this so the trivial way to do this is
the user is going to ask the database
for something just a very generic query
that says hey I'm looking for something
and the database server is going to say
ok here
everything I've got now you can look up
locally what particular thing you're
looking for and of course this gives you
perfect privacy because the database
server didn't the query didn't contain
any information about what you were
looking for the database server just
sent you everything it doesn't know
which things you were actually looking
for it doesn't even know whether you
found what you wanted so we get perfect
privacy but the communication overhead
is huge imagine searching Google this
way you go to Google and say hey I'm
looking for a website and they say okay
here's the whole internet find the
website he doesn't scale very well so we
need something a little bit more
practical than this so there's a second
requirement beyond the privacy
requirement which we usually call nom
triviality which says that the cost of
this entire interaction between the
client and the server should scale as
little o n where n is the number of bits
in the database and in practice we don't
want this asymptotic norm we really want
that the cost of everything is really
really small compared to the time it
would take to just download this whole
database so now it's less clear if this
is actually possible but it turns out it
is and there's three basic ways that we
know how to solve this problem so the
first one uses home morphic encryption
this has got some really nice properties
but is extremely slow second one users
trusted hardware which has some promise
as long as you can trust the hardware
and the third one uses coding theory and
this is the approach we're going to talk
about in this talk is this coding theory
based approach ok so start with a little
bit of formal model how are we actually
going to set this up we're gonna think
of our database as a matrix this is an R
by s matrix over a finite field if
you're not familiar with finite fields
all you really need to know here is that
it's a mathematical object where you can
do addition you can do multiplication
and you can find inverses so you can
find something if I give you a you can
find a inverse so when you multiply them
together you get one and as long as we
just need any sort of setting where
we're working in a finite set and we
have those properties each of the rows
of this matrix is one of the records in
our database so these are the things
that a user might try to fetch are the
rows of this database and we've just
decomposed each record into a sequence
of words of elements from this field
using some sort of encoding mechanism
now to query this database well this is
the non private way to query this
database perhaps not the way you would
do it if you were implementing on
private queries but this works so you
could send a standard basis vector so
one of these vectors from the the most
obvious basis for the vector space F to
the R so R is the number of rows in the
matrix so there's just a vector that has
all zeros everywhere except for one
position that has a 1 so if you're
looking for the J throw or the j-3 kurd
in this database you're going to put the
one in the J DH position of this vector
and the database server in this non
private scheme is going to answer this
query by multiplying the vector you sent
by the database and if you do this it's
fairly easy to see that you're gonna get
the result that you want so basically
the first row of the matrix is going to
be multiplied by 0 and you're going to
add that to the second row multiplied by
0 and add that to the third row
multiplied by 0 and so on and only the J
throw is going to be multiplied by one
so all of the other rows are going to
disappear but that J throw is going to
be left behind and you're going to get
the record that you were looking for ok
so this seems to work but it's not
private at all so now we need to figure
out what are we going to do to take this
basic approach and turn this into a
private information retrieval protocol
so the idea is to replicate the database
and then this guy here is giving us the
second part of the suggestion and that
is we're going to take this query that
we were multiplying against a database
and we're going to secret share it using
something called Shamir's secret sharing
scheme and this here is shared one
suggesting that so we replicate the
database and then we secret share this
vector component wise we share the first
component the second component and so on
and we send a different vector of secret
chairs to each server ok so what is the
secret sharing thing I'm talking about
the idea is actually very simple suppose
you want to share a secret denoted by
this purple point with the word secret
pointing at it we want to share this
amongst a set of L shareholders so that
any pair of them can work together then
look at the more general case so in this
case we're looking at any pair of them
can reconstruct it and we want the
additional property that any individual
shareholder doesn't know anything about
the secret so you could think of this a
common way to explain why you might want
to do this is the generals that hold the
keys to launch the nukes right you don't
want some general who's having a bad day
to launch the nukes but if several
generals come together and decide we
need to launch these nukes then we want
them to be able to do that and if one of
the generals suffers a heart attack or
something like that we want to make sure
that the the remaining generals could
still launch the nuke so we want to
allow any subsets in this case of two
generals to launch two nukes but we
don't want some rogue general launching
the nukes so the way that we accomplish
this is we think of the secret as a
point on the y-axis and then we choose a
random slope and we form the line that
passes through that secret with the
slope that we chose and then each of the
other shareholders each of the other
generals in this case or each of the PIR
servers in our PIR example are going to
get different points on this line and so
well as you can see here the shares are
just points on a line so if one
shareholder is trying to figure out what
the secret is you kind of have to ignore
all those other points we just have one
point so it could very well be that this
is the secret because the line that
passes through this point also passes
through the secret but for any other
possible secret there's exactly one line
that connects this shareholders point to
that secret and so without some other
information it's impossible to tell
which of these is the correct secret so
it could be this point it could be this
point it could be this point etc as soon
as a second shareholder comes to the
table we now have two points which
uniquely determines the line and we can
figure out very easily what the secret
is so this is how you do the two out of
El version we want slightly more general
version where there's potentially more
shareholders required to come together
and so here I'll show the four out of El
version the idea is very similar we let
the secret be this point on the y
intercept but now instead of passing a
line through the point
we pass a random polynomial in this case
of degree three through the secret and
then we give different points on this
polynomial to each of the shareholders
and it's a little bit harder to see how
they're gonna reconstruct the polynomial
from Lees but it turns out that it's
actually very easy to reconstruct a
polynomial through the set of points and
then you learn the secrets so in this
case if three points on this polynomial
every secret is possible but as soon as
you have a fourth point you reconstruct
the unique polynomial and you can just
read off what the secret is okay so
let's abstract this out into what the
scheme actually looks like so the T out
of LRT plus one out of El secret sharing
scheme our goal is we have a secret s we
want to share it amongst L different
shareholders we want to do this in such
a way that any t plus one or more of
them can easily figure out what the
secret is but any T or fewer of them
can't learn anything about the secret
and we're gonna do this by choosing a
polynomial that has degree T when you
evaluate this polynomial at zero you get
the secret and is otherwise uniform
random from our field with the
coefficients from our field in order to
reconstruct the secret these
shareholders are just going to use oh
and each shareholder is going to get a
point on this polynomial different point
it doesn't matter which points they get
as long as they're not the one that
holds the secret and then to reconstruct
they're going to use Lagrange
interpolation or some other polynomial
interpolation algorithm so the exact
details of that formula aren't important
but it should be easy to see that asking
a computer to do that it's no big deal
it can do it very quickly and this
explains why we need a finite field
because we need to be able to I don't
have a pointer you need to be able to
compute that inverse there that's that's
basically the only reason we need a
field okay so this gives us privacy but
does it actually give us information
retrieval that's the next question so it
turns out it does the reason that it
does is because Shamir's secret sharing
has a nice property which we call
linearity so the observation here is if
you evaluate a polynomial at 0 and you
get a and you evaluate some other
polynomial at 0 and you get B if you add
these two polynomials together and then
evaluate them at 0 you're just going to
get a plus B so they just add up nice
when you add and if i take the
polynomial that evaluates to at zero to
a and I multiply it by a scalar C then I
evaluate that at zero I get C times a so
I can add these things and the the
secrets that they encode just add and I
can multiply by scalars and the secret
same code just multiply likewise when we
look at what's happening in that PIR
protocol it's all linear as well so when
you multiply a vector times a matrix
you're just taking a bunch of scalar
multiple scalar multiples and then
you're adding them together and when you
go to reconstruct the Lagrangian
interpolation formula you're doing a
bunch of scalar multiplies in an
addition so everything here it just
requires that scalar multiplication and
addition holds so we can take secret
cherries multiply them by scalars etc
now we can do our vector matrix multiply
so back to the protocol the user is
going to Shamir secret share this
standard basis vector one component at a
time send the resulting vectors of
shares to the various servers the
server's are going to multiply the
vectors of shares by the database and
the result back to the client and then
the client is going to use the ground
interpolation to reconstruct a vector
which gives the row that it was looking
for and this is going to give us perfect
privacy provided not too many of the
database servers are talking to one
another and no privacy if that
assumption doesn't hold excuse me
okay so yep II we have PIR can we get on
to the new stuff so that all everything
I've told you so far is be known for a
long time and it's not my own ideas but
what I'm gonna tell you now is is the
new stuff so the first thing we're gonna
look at is can we let users fetch
several blocks without just doing
several queries in a row so can we do
this at a lower cost and in particular
we're gonna try to let you fetch several
blocks and have the cost all of the
various costs involved be about the same
as just fetching one block so how might
we do this let's go back to the the
basic idea the basic idea was we're
gonna take one of these standard basis
vectors and multiply it by the matrix
but we're gonna use secret cheering to
split this computation up if you wanted
to fetch several blocks you could send
all of these requests simultaneously as
one big long matrix and now rather than
doing a vector matrix multiplication
you're doing a matrix matrix
multiplication and one immediate
observation is that the cost of
multiplying two matrices if you use a
fast matrix multiplication algorithm is
a little bit lower than the cost of
doing each row individually so we can
save a little bit of computation cost
but the communication cost doesn't
change the computation cost doesn't
change too dramatically so can we do
better than this and it turns out yeah
we can do a lot better than this the way
we're gonna do it is we're gonna use
something called a ramp scheme so going
back to basic secret cheering we can
draw a graph like this to represent how
much data or how much information that
data is revealed to the shareholders
based on how many shares they have so if
we have this is the two out of L version
if you have fewer than two shares
I know it's discrete and I've drawn it
as if it's continuous but just ignore
that if you have fewer than two shares
you have zero information nothing at all
about the secret as soon as you have two
shares you jump up to complete
information we know everything there is
to know about the secret because we have
two shares we can reconstruct the line
in a wrap scheme
we relax us a little bit if you have
fewer than two shares you still have
zero information at all about the secret
but now to get complete information you
have to have seed in this case four you
have to have t plus Q shares so in the
secret sharing scheme it was Q plus one
here we're saying or T plus one now
we're saying is t plus Q for some q and
q could be bigger than one and the
upshot of this is we can now fit q times
as many secret bits into each share so
the shares are still just points on a
polynomial they haven't changed they
look exactly like they used to but
they're now encoding Q times as many
secret bits so how might we do this this
is again still not a new idea ramp
schemes have been studied basically as
long as secret sharing schemes that
Venus have been studied I was an infant
when people were first looking at this
stuff so let's I can't claim credit for
this but this is the way that almost
every paper in fact every paper that
I've ever seen this is how they do the
ramp scheme version of Shamir secret
sharing so in the original version we
had a say in this case a quadratic
polynomial the constant coefficient I
keep thinking I can use a laser pointer
but I can't the constant coefficient is
the secret and the other coefficients
are uniform random and so the general
way to turn this into a ramp scheme the
most common way is to replace one of
these random coefficients with another
secret and then in order to make sure
that we still have the level of privacy
we had before add another term so we
increase the degree of the polynomial by
one we have the two lowest order
coefficients are now two secrets there's
another way you can do it and this is
apparently not very common but it seems
very natural to me rather than replacing
coefficients with secrets we can think
of okay the secret is a point on the
polynomial it's a specific point and we
can encode a different secret at a
different point in the polynomial and
again we're gonna have to increase the
degree of the polynomial to make sure we
get our privacy but rather than using
coefficients to store secrets we're
going to use
points so here we have our first secret
at the y-intercept but now when you
evaluate this polynomial at one you get
a different secret so rather than the
linear coefficient it's the evaluation
at one that gives a second secret and
then to form our secret cheering
polynomial we'll choose a couple of
other points completely at random and
then we'll interpolate through them to
find the polynomial that connects our
secrets to these random points and then
we'll evaluate it at some other places
to get other shares for other
shareholders so we have two different
ways to share in this case two secrets
in the same secret certain polynomial
the question is why might we want to use
one version over the other and in many
cases it really doesn't matter which one
you use but in our case the second
option has a distinct advantage so in
particular if you look at the first
option this is a really simple
conceptually you know you just did the
secrets are just coefficients you
interpolate that polynomial and you read
the coefficients off but it's only kind
of sort of homomorphic so if you
multiply two of these polynomials
together that first secret multiplies
together but the secret that you get on
the Consular the linear term here isn't
the product of the linear terms of the
two polynomials you multiplied together
it's some other more complicated formula
and if you had lots of secrets it gets
more and more complicated we could tell
you exactly what these things are going
to look like but they're never going to
be the product of our two secrets only
the constant term will give us the
product of our two secrets B and D in
this case when we look at the second
option though right so the constant
terms multiply the higher order terms do
not multiply when we look at the second
option it's a little bit more
complicated sort of it's actually not if
you look at it the right way they're
both just linear combinations of
different in different bases so it's
actually equivalent but it's got a nicer
homomorphic property so no matter where
which point we're talking about which
x-coordinate we're talking about on the
polynomials when you multiply two
polynomials together and evaluate it at
that point it's the same as evaluating
those two polynomials at that point and
then multiplying together so the secrets
when you evaluate at 0 multiply together
and the secrets when you evaluate it
multiplied together this is going to be
a big advantage for us when we go back
to Pio okay so now I said you want to
get cue blocks we have one of these
matrices it's got cue rows in it and
each one is just a standard query what
we're gonna do is we're gonna use one of
these rap schemes and we're going to
encode all of these queries together in
a single vector so we're gonna choose
polynomials that pass through so this
polynomial f1 here when you evaluate it
at 0 you get this component when you
evaluate it at 1 you get this and when
we evaluate at 2 you get the next one
and when you evaluate it at Q minus 1
you get this and then it has T random
points at it and we've interpolate it
through those to get a degree T plus Q
polynomial t plus Q minus one polynomial
and f2 likewise when evaluated at 0 you
get this when you evaluate it at 1 you
get this when you evaluate it at 2 you
get this and so on
so we've taken our matrix with Q rows
and we've turned it into still just a
vector of secret shares and then going
back to the PIR protocol we still just
send one evaluation of this vector to
each of the servers and they still just
do the multiplication and if you think
about it or scribble on a piece of paper
it's very easy to come in to yourself
that they're going to the responses they
give back will interpolate to Q
different records instead of just one
and so if you look at what does this
mean for performance this is giving the
per server cost of running the protocol
Goldberg 2007 is the basic protocol that
I started with that I was modifying with
the RAM schemes and then the batch
queries is what I just talked about if
you want to get cue records with
Goldbergs protocol you upload a length
our vector but you have to upload q of
them so you upload q our field elements
to each server you download a length s
element for each query so you download Q
s field elements from each server each
server is doing a vector matrix multiply
which takes our s it's actually 2 RS
field operations not our s and we have
to do that q times and the storage cost
at each server is RS States Thor the
whole matrix
in our cost all of those are the same
but without the cues around so we
basically if Q is one the costs are the
same but as soon as Q is two we've cut
the cost down by a factor of two if Q is
three we've cut it down by a factor of
three and so on so we have a factor Q
improvement in everything except for the
storage cost at the server's so that's
pretty cool but what's the trade-off
here
well okay don't worry about the
trade-off let's just move on
so our second goal is let's fetch only
one block again but let's do it at a way
lower cost and fetching one block used
to cost so the idea here is actually
very similar we're gonna take the
database in this case rather than the
query and we're gonna use these ramp
schemes so with first step is you take
the database which has these are rows
and we're gonna express it in sort of a
block form we're gonna say let's look at
it as R over u matrices stacked on top
of each other where each matrix is of
height u so we're just rewriting at this
point we're saying take the first new
rows call them one matrix and then
they're stacked on top of the next Uros
that's the second matrix and so on then
once we've done that we're going to use
this rap scheme construction we don't
have to choose any random points here we
just interpolate through the various
rows of these block matrices so we find
a vector of polynomials where when you
evaluate these polynomials like the
first polynomial in this vector of
polynomials at zero you get the first
component from from you get this guy and
when you evaluate that first polynomial
at one you get this guy and when you
evaluate the second polynomial in the
first vector at zero you get this guy
and so on so we're just taking our
matrix we're thinking of it as a
collection of smaller matrices and then
we're encoding each matrix into a vector
of polynomials if we want we could
choose some random points in there and
we get something called tau independence
which I'm not really going to talk about
it's useful property if you want to make
sure that
database servers can't actually learn
the contents of the database they're
helping to host so we're gonna assume
the database servers are allowed to know
that so here we've taken the database
which was R by s and we've turned it
into R over u by s polynomials then
we're gonna take these polynomials and
we're gonna give evaluations these
vectors of polynomials are I guess
matrices of polymers and we're gonna
give evaluations teach server so now
each server rather than holding a
database of dimensions R by s holds a
database of dimensions are over u by s
so they're holding a factor u less data
that they were before and the user can
query these these databases in pretty
much the exact same way they were
querying before the only difference is
if I want the first role from the
original matrix then I need to query the
first row in this matrix so this row and
I need to hide my secret in the secret
cheering polynomial at x equals 0 and if
I want the second row I still query the
first row of this matrix but I hide my
secret for this query the secret
standard basis vector at x equals 1 at a
different point and now when I multiply
the two polynomials together because of
that nice homomorphic property I talked
about everything works out and I get
back the the particular row that I was
looking for so when we look at the cost
of this compared to Goldbergs protocol
oh those queues shouldn't be there
that's a copy-paste there so I'm we're
only looking at the cost to fetch one
block and this should say one so this
should be RS RS RS in this new protocol
the upload cost is now only R over you
because we're sending a shorter vector
because now our matrix that each server
holds is a factor you shorter the
computation cost is now R over u by s
instead of R by s so we've saved a
factor u computation time at each one of
the servers and the storage cost for
each server is also reduced by a factor
u because now instead
holding the whole thing they're holding
something that's effect are you smaller
so we've minimized again three of the
costs by factory you I've actually gone
through this a lot faster than I had
expected so yeah there's some more but I
didn't expect to be a quite so soon so
anyways that that's cool too but
seriously like I just glossed over the
trade off last time what is the trade
off there's got to be a trade off you
can't just like infinitely make things
faster so it turns off yes there is a
trade off and so the trade off comes
from what's called Byzantine robustness
so I kept saying we have L servers we're
gonna create secret shares so that at
most T out of L servers can collude and
we have privacy if if you thought about
that you might have wondered why would
you set T less than like L minus one
right you need T plus 1 points to
interpolate you set T equals to L minus
1 and then you can always interpolate
but that way you've maximized the number
of servers that are allowed to clewd
without troubling things happening and
it turns out there's a reason why you
might want to set the privacy threshold
smaller than the total number of servers
and that's because after we've
replicated our database to lots of
different servers we have to worry about
what happens if one of these servers is
evil or misbehaving in some way maybe
it's a malfunction and gives us a bad
response right so when we're talking to
one database server either that server
works or it doesn't if it doesn't were
out of luck great yields of database if
he doesn't answer a query well we're
kind of messed up but now that we've
split it to lots of servers it only
takes one bad apple to possibly spoil
the whole query and so the protocols in
particularly the protocol I was just
talking about has a nice way to deal
with some of the servers giving bad
responses and that is to look at these
secret shares and interpret them as
reed-solomon codes for those of you who
know what those are and then you can
throw standard coding theory algorithms
to figure out which responses were
incorrect and still interpolate but in
order to do this you need to have extra
responses so nice visualization is if
we're looking at the linear case the you
need to to reconstruct if I have extra
points on this line and then one
point that's not on the line it's pretty
easy to see that okay this was the bad
share I can still figure out what the
line is here because all of these other
points are on the line so that
visualization is not so nice when you
look at higher degree polynomials but
the basic idea is exactly the same and
there exists efficient algorithms that
can figure out which points are the
wrong points and can still find the
polynomial as long as we set that
privacy threshold to be lower than the
total number of servers now in the first
paper that came up with this basic
protocol the actual title of the paper
was improving the robustness of private
information retrieval and the main
contribution of this paper was that it
could handle this exceptionally large
number of Byzantine servers so L is the
total number of servers T is the privacy
threshold that it can handle this many
servers which bad responses which was a
big improvement over prior work fast
forward five years we have better
decoding algorithms and some neat ideas
the bound for this exact same protocol
just changing what the client does
improve to this which means that now we
can handle way more Byzantine servers so
the observation is if you were happy
with T and L and V back here then
there's some wiggle room we can change
the degrees of polynomials have the same
level of robustness same level of
privacy and maybe use some of that extra
space to get better throughput so we end
up with a set of parameters that we can
play with so L here is the number of
database servers T is that privacy
threshold it says how many of them are
allowed to clewd so if T collude nothing
bad happens if T plus 1 collude bad
things tau is that independence level I
mentioned before we could add extra
random points when we're doing the
encoding to stop servers from learning
the database so tau is how many servers
are allowed to talk to one another
before they can learn the database by
default it's just zero but if you want
to bump it up you can Q is the number of
records that we get in each query you
that parameter where we were shrinking
the database down and then V is how many
Byzantine servers we can tolerate and we
can set these parameters any way we want
as long as it satisfies this very simple
equation and it's just a linear equation
where you're adding them all together so
this gives us lots of wiggle room to set
parameters as we please
so I've gone through this way faster
than I had actually expected so I'll say
a little bit more that I don't have
slides to cover so one thing that I've
actually looked at recently is just how
low can we set V so how high can we set
Q and you in particular I guess the
other thing I didn't mention is that you
can combine those two approaches there's
a couple of little technical details
that are relatively easy to work out and
now I can fetch Q blocks for a factor
you lower than the cost of fetching one
block and that's where this equation
comes from then the question becomes how
low can we set V in practice right that
we want to support robustness for a good
reason
how low can we set V and so if you
consider a model where the server's have
some reason why they're actually
participating say for example they get
some small monetary incentive to
participate every time the answer query
they get a small amount of money for it
the observation is that if they give you
a bad response and you're able to
reconstruct so if so few of them gave
you a bad response that only V were
malicious only V were Byzantine and
you're able to reconstruct you not only
learn the record you were looking for
but you figure out which ones of these
servers gave you bad responses and you
can stop involving them in future
queries and so they stopped getting paid
for participating and so if you make a
rationality argument based on that you
can show that these servers will
actually always behave as if Q and you
are both set to the smallest possible
value because there's a very simple
argument to show that they can't tell
the difference between actually sorry
they'll behave as if Q is set to the
smallest value is fixed because they
can't tell whether Q is being set to 1
or 2 or 3 or 4 etc and so as long as
users
occasionally send queries where q was
set to one with some you know
unpredictably with some non-negligible
probability the server's can do this
cost-benefit calculation and say is it
worth my effort to try to mess up this
query or should I just answer honestly
if I want to keep getting paid because
they know if they ever get caught they
stop getting paid forever and then you
can make a rationality argument and show
in practice we can set V to zero almost
always and then with some probability
you set V to be as high as it can go and
you send a query and you catch any bad
guys and that prevents the bad guys from
even trying to mess up queries so
there's a lot of more things that you
can do with these techniques one thing
that I've actually been looking at
recently with this approach is so we
want to fetch several records from a
database what if we don't know a priori
which records we want but we want to
leverage this fact that we can actually
fetch queue of them at a time for a
lower cost than fetching just one so
there are existing approaches which lets
you query indexes in a database and
figure out what you're looking for say
to search by keyword or to do SQL
queries we can actually combine this
idea of encoding the databases together
like shrinking the databases as
polynomials and doing batch queries at
the homomorphic properties the additive
properties and multiplicative properties
of the polynomials in order to issue
queries that go against the database and
the result of the query is a new batch
query a new query for different queue
elements that are customized towards
what the user is looking for so you can
have index databases that consists of
queries you send a query against the
index database and it creates a new
query by combining things it's rows and
then issues that against a new database
and sends the result back to you and you
can actually issue very interesting
types of queries I wish I would have
made a slide for that because it's
actually I just didn't think I'd have
time for this so you can do some really
interesting things so I've been looking
at places where this would be a useful
thing to be able to do one application
that came to mind immediately is
something like Twitter so if you're
querying the Twitter database using PIR
its gonna be
slow cuz a Twitter database is huge not
only that but what are you querying for
say I'm following anacott or Chris on
Twitter and I want anak it's most recent
tweets or Chris's most recent tweets
which row do I ask for if I know which
row to ask for I've already seen the
tweet so I have this problem of I need
to know which row to ask for and there's
a ton of rows because each row is a
different tweet and there's the ton of
rows but there's not that many users I
mean there are a lot of users but
compared to the number of tweets there's
a very small number of users so we can
use this index idea to say rather than
querying for the row containing anak
it's most recent tweet I can say I want
the row in the index that lists anak
it's most recent tweets and now I can
say I want the 10 most recent tweets and
my query is for anacott not for his most
recent tweets and that index database
will translate this into a query for
anacott Sten most recent tweets wherever
they happen to reside in the database
process that query against the database
send the result back to me so now I
don't need to know where records reside
in the database I can just say I want to
query the most recent tweets index and I
need to know where anak 'it's wrote
which is a static thing in that database
resides and it'll always give me Anika's
10 most recent tweets or Chris's 10 most
recent tweets or anybody else's there
could be other data other indexes into
the database that lets you query it
using different views so you could for
example ask for the most retweeted
queries by anacott or I'm not a big
Twitter user so I don't know other ways
that you might want to look for tweets
but any anything that you can come up
with you could conceivably build a
different index floor and so by querying
the index you're leaking what you're
looking for whether it's most recent or
most influential or trending or whatever
but you're not leaking whose tweets
you're actually looking for and you're
eliminating your decoupling the location
in the database from how the query is
formed so now the user can issue these
queries without actually having to know
the whole structure of the database and
in a Twitter example this is
particularly important because Twitter
will allow you to query their database
but they actually go out of their way to
make sure that
you cannot scrape the entire database
they don't want you to know the entire
structure of their entire database they
just want you to be able access it
through their API and this actually lets
you do that whereas traditional PIR
techniques wouldn't actually even make
that possible
so there's lots of applications beyond
just making things faster yeah so I
guess into 10k is the most prominent
will be hashtags when it when
interesting keyword thing can be
hashtags
well now coming to here the batching
that you're performing is fraud the
queries from a single user yes can
something happens when you when they
have several users were making
simultaneous queries and maybe you can
use some of the batching there yeah that
is a much more difficult problem there
is stuff you can do so actually going
back to I said can we do better than
this just using fast matrix
multiplication there's actually a recent
paper by well by Ian and Casey I don't
know if you know Casey where it was that
that basically was based on this
observation that okay his back further
than I thought that multiplying this
matrix by the database is a lot more
efficient than multiplying each row
individually and so they updated the per
C++ as the implementation of this basic
protocol not the stuff I've been talking
about today they updated it so that the
server can accumulate a bunch of queries
and then do a fast matrix multiplication
so that gives you a little bit of
performance gain over processing each
individually if you want to use the ramp
scheme based stuff that I was talking
about today you have to be very careful
so it is possible to encode the queries
at sort of random x coordinates within
your polynomials so that and then reveal
which x coordinate the queries being
encoded into the server so that the
server can collect different queries
that were encoded at different x
coordinates and combine them but now you
have sort of two options from here so
it's going to combine these two build so
just using the editor
Bertie's of the polynomials can combine
them to build a single query that it
evaluates against a database now it can
either send that result back to all the
users in which case the users can
interpolate to each of these x
coordinates and figure out what other
people were looking for or it can try to
randomize things for you yeah but you
that that willing to communicate with
each other if so if users are willing to
communicate with each other it's a
relatively easy problem it's actually
quite quite easy to combine them they
can even if they're willing to
coordinate and they're willing to leak
to one another what they're searching
for then they can not interactively send
those things that they don't even have
to talk to one another as long as
they've a priori like agreed on how this
is gonna work
and then they learn each other's queries
if you're trying to hide from each user
the other users queries then you either
have to trust the database servers to
randomize the responses before they send
them back which the randomization is
easy but it has to be coordinated
amongst all servers and you have to
trust them to do it or the users have to
somehow construct their queries in such
a way that they can decode them but
other users won't know how to decode
them and the only way you can really do
that is to issue you know queries and
previous rounds that give you random
linear combinations of the database that
you can use to hide which standard basis
vector you're sending and you end up in
do you have to make some wonky
assumptions oh yeah you can do it but
the assumptions you have to be very
careful about yeah it would be
interesting to see whether there's a
really good way to do that but I haven't
put - I've thought about it but not
in-depth yet well I have a question one
thing that always has bothered me about
private information retrieval is the
name and that is because you know it's
really as you say you're using the terms
queries and/or index lookup which is
really what it is when we think about
information retrieval it's often best
match there is no exact answer you're
looking for something that's that's
close now you know and I've always
looked at this
said you know this just doesn't address
that problem at all I'm wondering have
you thought about this because when I
realize a lot of what you do a lot of
information retrieval techniques do
reduce to matrix multiplications have
you thought much about is there a way to
get best match retrieval weather than
exact match retrieval out of these i've
thought a little bit about that and
there are some kind of things that you
can sort of do i I haven't thought a lot
about it and I'm really not an expert in
how the best match algorithm stuff work
in it I agree that there's probably a
lot of potential for that some of the
stuff that I've been looking at is like
the index things that I sort of talked
about a little bit at the end I've been
looking at how do you look for things
where the thing might not be in the
database or you don't know where it
resides at the database and you're
rather trying to issue queries for like
a contextual query I'm looking for
something of this sort give me the best
matches and so if you can predict what
sorts of questions users might ask it's
very easy to prepare indexes that will
answer the queries and give the best
matches for the query even if no exact
match misses exist if you want to be
able to do things like find the closest
to a particular query what nothing
exists and you don't want to have to
anticipate all the possible questions
you can do this with interaction so if
there is one query and based on the
response you issue another query then
you can build complicated data
structures you can build any data
structure really you want and have the
Pierre query go through the data
structure and then anything that you can
solve non privately with that data
structure you can solve privately so
this is how the keyword searches and
stuff typically work you construct a
b-tree over the database the users query
the B tree recursively until they found
the coordinate that they actually want
and then the issue query for that
coordinate and so the stuff I've been
looking at is explicitly non interactive
you do not have this back and forth you
send a query the query gets transformed
into the query you actually want and
then it gets evaluated and then sent
back to you but those are really the
only two things and and people have done
a related sort of
the SQL query type thing as well that's
very similar to the bee tree thing I
proposed that's basically all that's
being done at this point
I guess somewhat sort of related I did
some work in the past on using PIR to do
ecommerce and we were looking at so if
you were to envision a sort of
competitor to Amazon's Kindle Store
where everything was purchased using
private information retrieval so we
wanted to solve the problem of can you
sell things where things have different
prices and knowing how much a person
paid will reveal a large a lot of
information about what they would say
bought so we want to hide the price that
they paid but make sure they pay the
correct price and to throw a wrench into
things let's say there's Amazon Prime
membership so these people are allowed
to get some things for free and maybe
other things are cheaper than for a
non-member and we want to be able to
support all of this but have it
completely oblivious so first off if you
want to do payments you need to say
prepay for a credit card they're like a
debit card type thing that has a balance
in it and now you just have to prove
that I have enough money in my thing to
pay for whatever is I'm getting and I've
subtracted the appropriate amount and we
were able to build a nice protocol it
that lets you do these purchases then we
started to think okay so is Amazon ever
going to support something like this
well no obviously not because Amazon
wants to know what you purchased they
don't just want to get the braids amount
of money they want to be able to do
analytics they want to know what's
purchased when and so we were able to
show how you can build histograms of
sales and say well this was downloaded X
number of times this was downloaded Y
times and this was downloaded Z times
without revealing who purchased what at
what time and if you have to pay
commissions to different people we were
able to show okay based on how many
times this was downloaded and whether
they were Prime members or non Prime
members and so on how much money is this
person who owns that the intellectual
property how much did they get paid and
we realized that with that same data we
were able to do things like build sub
databases that like the sort the
database according to puffy
and so on and you could issue a query
against a the top half of the database
and so you're revealing explicitly that
I don't want something from the bottom
half of the database but the stuff in
the bottom after the database is known
to be the stuff that nobody wants and so
most users want stuff in the top half
and so by revealing I want something in
the top half you're revealing I want one
of the popular things that everybody
wants and so you're kind of minimizing
what's leaked to get these savings of
I'm querying a subset of the database
and so using that sort of thing you
could also possibly get some sort of
useful information retrieval stuff that
we never thought of that strew I mean we
that was sort of like a passing comment
at the end of the paper was lucky you
could also do this there's some
intricate privacy ramifications that
we're not going to explore we're just
pointing out that this is a possibility
in it might be so if you're doing the
half-and-half thing we actually assume
that it's a preeto distribution and we
just for sake of arguments at 8020 rule
80% of users want the top 20% 20% of
users want the bottom 80% now we thought
okay well that's you know you're still
you're leaking relatively small amount
or you are leaking that the important
bit of information that you want the
uncommon stuff but now most of its
uncommon stuff so narrowing it down to
which uncommon stuff is still very hard
I mean it's impossible to actually
narrow it down further based on the PIR
but yeah it that's when you start doing
things like that the privacy guarantees
go from very clear-cut you reveal
nothing but you're doing a query to very
nuanced and intricate and hard to
actually reason about so I don't know
whether that answers or evades your
questions but that's yes I think cash in
math that you did a little bit before
this you want to break the rule boy in
matrix and what they call them is that
what you had or I just for space i
transposed to get a column so you
multiply a row by it and you get a row
but I transposed it so it would fit on
this
slide nice okay so it's your I think
you're referring to right here yes yeah
so you're taking a row matrix that has
the same length as the height of the
database you multiply by a database you
get a row matrix but I wrote the
transpose just because otherwise it
wouldn't have fit Thanks any other
questions so one question typically as
many of the practical studies started to
make it appear they found that the key
problem is not the communication but
rather computation which is basically
you have to touch each of the element
yes in your thing so can something
happen there I mean even now when you
are reducing the effort you're reducing
there forever factor you but if you
count all the server's it still our RS
divided by U and actually multiply with
the know L so in that sense it's maybe
more than RS it is more than Rs yeah
it's silly I mean it has to be more than
RS because L has to be bigger than you
it seems like this computation I mean
there are interesting studies and when
you have a really fast network maybe
that's where the TV LP are look started
to better because these computations are
huge so now it's up there the saving
grace is that this is they were already
inherently distributing that computation
over several nodes and the computation
at each node has to do is embarrassingly
is embarrassingly parallel Liza below
you can parallelize it basically in not
infinitely but I guess you can paralyze
it until each node or each core does
like one multiplication and there's no
synchronization issues you just multiply
one thing and then you add the things
and there you don't have to synchronize
you just have to click the results and
add them together so that the
parallelization is very easy but you're
absolutely right that it's still at the
end of the day a lot of computation it
has to happen so that's part of
reason why it's interesting to be able
to shrink it by a factor you I we have
been looking just in the past couple
weeks my student and I started looking
at what happens when you so there was a
little bit of background there was a
paper in 2014 that showed that under
ridiculous trade-offs but still very
interesting you can do PIR where at the
end of the day you download one extra
bit of data compared to an on private
query only one bit exactly one bit and
it was like a tight you get this one
extra bit you have to have exponentially
many servers and you have to upload
something the size of the database to
each server and there's like it's just a
crazy all the other parameters are crazy
but you can download only one bit extra
and so we thought okay then then then
they had this impossibility result say
if you only want to download one extra
bit you can't do much better than we
just did but if you are willing to
download C a factor two or a factor four
more bits then you can do you can reduce
all of these parameters quite a bit and
so we thought what if we use the U and Q
here to recreate this so we take our
rows that are each this long and we chop
them down into like really short rows
and split them over a whole bunch of
rows and then we use the U to shrink
that database down and we say rather
than trying to fit this all into the L
servers we already have we just say well
let these more servers now write these
other proteins other protocols are
saying the number of servers has to be
linear in the size of the data so what
if we say something similar and we say
we're gonna make these parameters really
big and we're gonna just add more
servers so we could still answer a query
and you get some really interesting
asymptotic so if one thing we can do PIR
where you download exactly twice the
size of a record and unlike the other
protocols where no two servers conclude
and nobody can know which subset of
servers you queried here you have like
an honest majority assumption instead
did the cost per node becomes like
logarithmic multiplications instead of
linear but if you add up all what every
node is doing it's still what more than
our times s and that just seems to be
inherent unless you change the threat
model like if you change the goal of the
PIR to get there's basically there's an
impossibility results are coming up
against then unless you change the
definitions you really can't get around
that result