ok so it's like we can start
hi everyone today I am very glad to
introduce a Maria interviews from Cisco
her professional credentials are
comprised of 20 years of experience in
engineering department of defense
solutions for hardware software pki and
network systems she has multiple patents
and has co-authored protected documents
around cyber security and other
confidential solutions in the security
area today she will be talking about
intelligent cyber security thank you so
too today we're going to discuss
improving outcomes with services here
with me is a senior here at Purdue Shawn
gladden and he's one of our top analysts
so it's going to be exciting to hear him
speak today as well to the audience here
absolutely so just some quick oversight
in regards to information security the
digital evolution where you have the
digital company and the internet of
everything is which which is where Cisco
solely operates in IOT so the internet
of everything is really the mother of
all markets and transitions moving on in
the digital evolution we have the
digital company where you see the mobile
fourteen percent cloud five to ten and
then you have I OT which is ninety
percent so what happens when this is all
out there for everyone access you have
security challenges you need to change
some business models some dynamic threat
landscape and also some complexity and
fragmentation within those you'll see
sorry I wanted to walk out to three
within those you'll see the different
areas and how they rate for each of the
three areas we spoke about earlier
most of our threats are hidden in plain
sight the number one biggest threat and
pretty much any area agency or company
would probably be the insider threat so
you have a lot of the companies nowadays
have you bringing in BYOD ch where you
stick into your company network but you
most of them should give you the option
to where they will remove all your data
even if it is your own device since it's
connected to their network some of the
security silos complicate protection
reason being is the way they lay out the
different various services that can
actually help them in assisting in
providing against any types of threats
so this is our cisco hypothesis where
you have the digital evolution
operational focus talent shortage and
they go across all these various
business units visibility threat
platform advisory integration and
managed these are some examples of where
our intelligence come from and how much
we really see so there's daily security
intelligence go ahead
Oh go back there we go you guys see that
that's a pretty significant amount of
data the security services portfolio
between advisory integration and managed
services shows you the various areas and
how each one is unique some of the
security advisories we have risk and
compliance ioe security and then we also
have threat management our incident
response services we have an amazing
incident response service team as well
as all the other teams involved they're
the first ones like any emergency
essential personnel to triage anything
that comes into the into that we ingest
to verify some of the integrated
security solutions with integration
migration and optimization those are
some of the different areas that yeah
some of the different areas that were
able to communicate with depending on
the hardware and some of course our
hardware and the different things that
we can connect product support hosted
security and managed security where you
have your advanced threat analytics so
this is the time put your glasses on so
with a TA we have analytics people
intelligence and technology
ata is a variety of things within the
ATA that we operate in within the
security operations center we do a
variety of things this shows you how in
each realm for analytics people
technology and intelligence where we may
gather and correlate this information so
what it enables ATA which is us we
enable speed accuracy and focus so we
give you the ability for rapid threat
detection reduces the mean time to
respond high fidelity cuts down on false
positives and then increase visibility
and control illuminates security blind
spots within that many of our customers
receive many benefits as some of those
comprehensive coverage strategic focus
customer relations risk mitigation and
proactive security so some of the
scalable sets that are out there for the
different clients can be an essentials
enhanced in a premier package the
different the different various ones
give you different levels and enhanced
security some edits another step give
you intrusion prevention system some
monitoring your modules adding in
different equipment so it depends on
what you're looking at for your network
and how you want to have a redundant
backup and or some sort of security
backup for it let's start with the
threat landscape Yeah right I guess it's
my turn so for the threat landscape we
have nineteen point seven billion total
threat blocks daily which is seven point
two trillion yearly where as you can see
on the graph or on the little pie chart
82,000 virus blocks 181 million spyware
blocks 818 million web blocks which
since I'm an analytics i'm a member of
our analytics person
my job is to actually filter through all
this so what we end up doing is on our
system it Flags all these different
threats then it hits the the analysts
excuse me it's the analysts and then
it's up to us in order to filter out
what's a false positive what's a true
positive and then escalated as necessary
that true positive is it something that
got blocked by the customers firewall or
was it something that got through the
firewall and got onto a system we are
Talos multi-tiered defense Talos is an
organization within Cisco that does a
lot of our security research so they're
on the bleeding edge of what the
scariest stuff out there is so you'll
hear a term called zero day which is a
vulnerability that has not been released
especially by the companies that have
them so a zero day and Adobe that's
something that's very common
unfortunately is an Adobe vulnerability
that Adobe doesn't know if it's an
unaware of Tallus is on the bleeding
edge of figuring those out and they're
divided into these five departments each
department is integral into what Alice
does so the threat intelligence that's
what I was just talking about where
they're the ones who are actively trying
to figure out these zero days they see
new malware they break it down detection
research there they find what are called
our indicators of compromise so if a
system is infected with something what
about it gives away the infection does
it have a pop-up does it do some
something weird on the network that's an
indicator of compromise outreach they're
the people who will go out and talk to
the leaders of our organizations tell
them what the newest threat is they'll
go if they find a zero-day they're the
ones who go to Adobe and say hey you
have a zero-day here's what it is here's
how you fix it vulnerability rd they're
just basically wrapped into the threat
intelligence so they're the ones that
are actively trying to find and create
malware in order to try to block it and
then our engine development so that's
the intelligent systems web anemal Intel
they're the ones who are doing our
sandboxes so a lot of this malware has
gotten very very smart and knows if
we're trying to figure out it's there so
we create a sandbox basically a fake
computer or if you're familiar with it a
virtual machine and we let them out
where it do its job and we watch it we
have our intelligence framework so our
intelligence feeds our common things
you've probably heard of whitelist
blacklist known IP addresses and domains
for malware DNS so the common things
that you would see around
industry-specific that would be partners
and customers so the customers that we
do our work with we work very closely
with in order to make sure hey if you
see something strange you let us know
about it if we find some intelligence
well let you know about it so we work
very very close with the customers open
source virustotal malware calm hyper
analysis these are all websites you can
go to and see hey what are the
indicators compromise for this or I've
got the suspicious file so you throw it
on there and they do the sandboxing for
you cisco unique intelligence our source
fire which is our IDs system very good
very very good at catching bad stuff
going through network we have threat
grid which is our proprietary sandbox
Talos which is the organization that I
talked about a few slides ago opendns I
think that was last year or two years
ago we acquired opendns I think so there
is a public version in a private version
the private version costs money the
public version is still open dns free
for everyone to use and then our threat
information platform so we have our
internal bu data or focused feeds and
intelligence so what we get off of the
customers will do the number crunching
on it and find anything new so tell us
likes to pride themselves and finding a
lot of this ransomware and being able to
mitigate it so a lot of you might have
heard of locky or cryptex or a lot of
these bad ransom waves that have been
floating around but basically lock up
your systems and
hold them hostage what was the last
ransomware anyone heard of that a
hospital wasn't involved with ransomware
do you know what the name of that ransom
or was that's okay it's fine probably
not a whole lot Sam Sam that was the big
kick the big campaign it was Sam Sam and
then there's actually recently been a
lot another locky campaign so that
vertical the health industry vertical is
a very very common big target for
ransomware campaigns because has PII
exactly personal identifiable
information so and the the trick for
ransomware is they don't steal the info
they don't even look at it they just
encrypt it and say give us a million
dollars or you don't get it back and the
hospitals are going to pay for two
reasons one they need that information
to operate in two they don't want
anybody to know they were compromised so
they're going to pay so Talos will go
out and actively try to crack them our
so they're going to try to find the
decryption keys and try to save these
hospitals money so the back the back
side of our source fireboxes our snort
and snore is a preprocessor that looks
at traffic as it goes through does some
very initial number crunching how many
of you familiar with regex or that
concept it's basically a super powerful
version of that so it's doing it on the
wire on the fly and we give it rules to
recognize certain regex in the packets
and the malware writers can get pretty
pretty involved in trying to dupe it so
instead of writing a character they'll
write it in hex or they'll write it in
HTML so the snort rules will figure that
out same thing with our clam AV
signature family so you can do
signature-based so a hash you take the
malware file turn it into a hash that
hashes a signature you just do signature
recognition which can be fairly quick
because once you've got the hash it's
just
up we have our analysis over you so
architecture we have our full packets
and this is part of what makes Cisco's
active threat analytics very very
powerful as we have access to full
packet capture to our premier customers
not all of our customers give it give it
to us but the premier side they do and
that's how we do a lot of our analysis
because once we have full pcap we can do
a lot with it it's a lot of pcap data
yes so one of our customers I think of
full day's worth of pcap is like on the
order of 50 to 100 terabytes depending
upon the customer sure so a pcap is a
paki capture so how many of you are
familiar with what a packet is okay also
fair number of you so what we're doing
is we're watching the wire for these
packets we're actively looking for it
and the way that an IDs works
achievement IPS is will split off a line
from the customers network and do it in
parallel where one of the line goes to
where it's supposed to go out to the ISP
the branch off the parallel goes into
our IPS and we look at what goes through
it and we'll capture that data and store
it for one of our customer actually for
two of our customers they're short for
an amount of time that's feasible for
that's what I was just about to say is
we have two clients where we get so much
pcap that we have to dump the data after
about a day right other clients have
much less traffic where we can store it
for a few days and that could be
something based on what part of the
network we're looking at
absolutely please use your mic please
yes here yeah I want to ask about
anonymous network store so you see the
packet comes from nowhere and a source
IP is masked then so you analyze it so
Tor network nodes are known there's a
list of them and we're not ultimately
looking at the not necessarily the
destination but we can flag that it's
from a tor network which on our
customers tour node traffic is anomalous
so we're going to take a look at it if
it's encrypted there's only so much we
can do with it which I think might be
the source of your question is if it's
encrypted traffic yeah there's only so
much we can do with it but there's a lot
of metadata involved with that that
could be forensic Lee identified tonight
for the need so basically we could fare
it out if it's a tour node within their
network so we see the last node and then
out to the destination is that
destination to known bad yes or no or
even more simply are you seeing tour no
traffic on a production network so
you've got I'm just using example like
caterpillar so if you see toward no
traffic on caterpillar that's not right
that's anomalous so we can flag it and
get to the source of it but a lot of the
really bad stuff so for example botnets
right we'll use IRC traffic and IRC
traffic is not normally encrypted
additionally if you're on IRC traffic
that's going to be anomalous and we can
fly that
any more questions so when do you say
like something anomalous happens what's
the process like that you start looking
into and whether it should be flagged or
not what kind of things excellent
question so going along with this slide
it is based on the telemetry we have in
the customers network and the rules
we've set in place will determine
whether or not traffic is anomalous and
that's based on negotiations with the
customer they'll say this is the network
we have this is what we define as
anomalous and we'll write rules the flag
it and then for example if we have a
customer that's got two separate
networks for example Purdue has a guest
network and a production production
Network the guest network will be looked
at differently than the production
Network and will have different rules
fight against it and certain customers
Willa to make sure you hold your mind
got it thank you well also for example
on the guest network the customer might
tell us to use less rules because it's
the guest network their disappearing
certain things that happen on it or to
ignore certain events whereas on a
production at work they're going to say
we don't want to see any traffic to
Facebook that Facebook will be flagged
as anomalous traffic and that's because
the customer wants it flagged as such so
it's ultimately up to the customer
determine what's anomalous and what
isn't aside from the obvious oh this is
bot met traffic or this is ransomware
traffic we do send out reports and let
them know what's out there so they can
be aware but certain networks just don't
block certain things so they have to
have them open mmm no problem any other
questions
so when you say you work to all those
pcap files it it's both motorized
traffic so we may as well as outgoing
right we look at pcap traffic that's not
only inbound and outgoing but also look
at inter network traffic so you'll have
networks within the company that are
communicating with each other and we
also look at that and that's defined as
north-south and east-west traffic north
south is outbound to the internet or
something external to the network
east-west traffic is internal to the
network so we'll watch both north-south
and east-west traffic to see oh this is
going to a weird website or hey this
computer looks like it's trying to
infect another computer on its network
anymore it's good question good question
okay so from the slide you can see are
different methods of telemetry and Intel
which are basically the ones that I went
over earlier so we'll have our ATA
sensors are Cisco products the internal
events so things that get flagged by
their firewalls things that get flagged
by the pieces of hardware we install
which is the job of integration they'll
actually go out and stick server units
in the customers network to help guard
it and then all this will be ingested
stored searched basically we're parsing
the data in order to make it readable
because if you send terabytes of data at
the analyst they're just going to think
I have no time to do this No so we have
to actually parse it at least somewhat
and we use different tools that will
actually crunch the data and parse into
something readable our favorite tool is
of course Wireshark where I shark is
awesome and then our analytic functions
would be hunts deterministic analyses
parson normalize it which is all just
fancy terms to say we have people that
sit there and watch the data
once in place so what a hunt and a play
our is completely different for what we
do on a normal day and by normal day I
mean we sit watch traffic so what
normally will happen is something
happens on the customer Network our
devices flag it and send us a ticket and
we'll look at the ticket will parse it
will go through it tell the customer yes
this is bad fix it or no this isn't bad
ignore it what a hunt is are things that
we know are either not being caught by
our device something we just learned
from Intel or something that we're
getting kind of sparse readings on and
we'll go and actively look in the
customer Network for it we'll go pull
down their peak apps will go through
their data look for indicators
compromise and we're going out of our
way to go and try to find these things
for them in a play is for example email
so email campaigns I don't know if you
guys are familiar with fishing campaigns
where people try to get in with a fake
email or what have you we'll go looking
for those will also get emails where
people in the company have been emailed
bad files their ransom where they've
been emailed them and they get flagged
so we'll go through those there's our
email place or security operations so it
all focuses around our sock which we
have our primary sock is in RTP in North
Carolina we just opened one and crack
out Poland I actually do a one-on-one
with our sake and Japan and we had one
in Australia I think that one got shut
down and I believe we're gonna set up
we're gonna set up something in England
I know we just we just acquired probably
yeah we just acquired poor call us so
something is it something is coming for
them yes what is a sock because I don't
think it's a system-on-a-chip correct
our stock is our security operations
center so think of those kind of
think of Star Wars and you have the
captain's room right where everyone's on
the bridge on the bridge everyone has
their assigned duties captain has what
he needs up on the screen and you take
your commands as needed everyone's a
colleague of course and everyone talks
to each other but sometimes they come in
and it's like this that this that move
so it's a security operations center and
that's exactly how it operates how how
ours is divided is will have we have
three different ranks of people we have
tier 1 analysts to your tune analyst and
investigators each tier being a build
upon the next one so tier 1 is the
baseline that's what I am I'm the first
line of defense i find something
anomalous where I think hey this this is
bad and I think it made on the customer
Network I give it to tier 2 tier 2 guy
gets the file blows it up verifies that
it's bad says okay yeah it's bad and it
got downloaded so he bumps in for the
investigator and investigators the one
who does the reverse engineering the
malware he's the guy who says yes this
is on the customer Network yes it's
dialing out I'm sending them a ticket so
our investigators are basically the
captains of the sock they're the ones
who ultimately hold the power and well
we have at least one per shift and
that's part of what makes our security
operations center and by extension ra ta
very very likeable to our customers is
we have 24 hour seven days a week
someone is watching their network
absolutely and there's always an
investigator on shift so there's always
somebody in the captain's chair I have a
question could you resolve the situation
when the employee leaks some sensitive
corporate data how can you distinguish
does the employees and advertisement
sheet or it's some sensitive spec for
the product to have some machine
learning model maybe are you looking in
regards to protecting someone else's
data or internally for example corporate
employees since out
Mike's so like an accident so like an
accidental release of information there
was a more maliciously so either way to
see if you can detect it if we consider
complicated case it's encrypted so
employee encrypted something you don't
know what is inside and it went to some
unknown email address there are various
ways to detect that type of information
based on each agency and what their
rules and regulations are so for each
event we would have that in a statement
of work and we would have an agreement
to be able to do certain things but
there are various types of tools that
can be utilized to find that information
down to a file hash what's also
interesting is where I'm describing to
you our advanced threat analytics for
external customers there's an internal
version to Cisco specifically that is
also watching our traffic correct so
they'll notice oh if we're sending
something encrypted out to something
that probably shouldn't be communicated
to they're gonna flag and let our
managers now I wonder do you use any
machine learning model because it's hard
to check each email who sent what it's
in the pipeline we are working
proprietary that's that's really all I
can say about is that we're working on
it any other questions removal good
question so our event correlation
analysis we identify suspicious patterns
in data flow which could be as much as
someone just says hey this is something
we see often enough let's write
something for it that detects it too hey
this IP address is coming up often
enough let's let's do a hunt to see if
we can find that more and it ends up
being something that's a camp that's
part of a campaign pretty much
everything we just walked through prior
to coming through this with the various
different levels of interaction between
the analysts and and what they're doing
with their work
we also will have analysis using our
vulnerability correlation so sis logs
data logs DNS logs we have lots and lots
of logs that we go digging through that
backward there we go so we also have our
indirect net flow analysis so we will
leverage net flow to export excuse me
leverage Cisco's netflow feature
exported by network and security
applications so basically one that some
eise's as we're going to look at the
data or just exporting it so
deterministic rules base are the snort
rules I was talking about earlier where
we'll apply a rule on the preprocessor
data we'll hit it and it will flag yes
or no did it trip the role our
statistical analysis would be do we see
anomalous DNS traffic so that could be
traffic to a DNS server that a company
or corporation has never used before and
we'll see that over the course of days
or weeks we'll also have our heuristic
analysis so we look at a bunch of data
it's a big big data the buzzword it is
there's your zero day was on that slide
yep data science analysis same thing big
data and we're basically just crunching
through to see patterns and anomalous
indicators compromise that's a very
intense analysis there and then there's
your machine learning this is our
machine learning we also use tons of
metadata and for our essentials
customers we actually have no access to
pcap we have none of their packet
captures we only have the metadata and
yet we still have to make calls on it so
getting used to not having the pcap and
just seeing the metadata for example
where was the original where was it
going and is where it's going something
in almost to the customer so is this oh
it's a business part
in Europe or is this some weird IP in
China so that in automatically you can
say hey yeah this is bad so event
correlation yeah so our event
correlation inbound SQL slammer which is
a variant of an ex boy where well we
have the target IP address the port
source IP address and geolocation so we
know this metadata we can flag it as an
ominous that make sense I see I see how
you're in the data it's good questions
went back with you hi go backwards hmm
netflow so our net flow is captured by
devices captured from devices by
centralized network collectors such as
stealthWatch so basically it's
corroborating all the data together in a
single packet so we can look at it and
analyze it for anomalies so this could
be getting all the DNS traffic together
in one so we can look at it as a whole
versus individual DNS servers syslog
message parsing yeah simple enough where
we're given the syslog and we're giving
the messages and we look to see if
there's anything in them that are odd
how do you deal with the sampling
wouldn't that flow data it's not really
a full pack packet capture right its
metadata so we deal with the same way
but it's also same hold true and it
ultimately will end up dealing with how
the customer wants us to handle it a lot
of the customers will like for
essentials we don't get this log data
for the premier we get syslog data and
then based on the syslog data they'll
have us do specific things with it so
for example if we know that there is
data to specific like IP address that we
know is bad that's flagged so it'll be
flagged and we can corroborate it with
the syslog data and see oh there are
some machines in our network that are
dialing out to that so what data are you
referring to is there something in
addition to well no they I mean that
flows sampled so I mean that's a that's
a pretty basic case okay I have a
malicious IP but you're not really doing
anomalous I mean anomalous detection is
very difficult when you're look when you
don't have when it's sampled data right
because you're not really understanding
the communication so you can't take like
statistical deviations of that like it's
sampled so I'm asking how you know you
had a chart that was characterizing you
know this is a particular worm or
whatever but that's all sampled data so
that's the
a lot of context to that it isn't really
I mean that's kind of like fall
statistics right there right leak so
think of it more like I've worked with
net flow for a decade so okay so I
personally haven't done any of the net
flow stuff the closest thing that I got
to doing with it was working on a
project with DNS data and we took a
year's worth of DNS data from a customer
so terabytes and terabytes of
information and this customer we knew
how to breach so we were trying to
corroborate the data saying oh ok so do
we see some anomalous DNS traffic we did
but the the trouble was getting the data
to sit instead of just having a hunch
where we could just say bye I this is
weird trying to actually get the data to
prove that's what it was so yes it's
totally about context interesting i'd
like to have an offline discussion
that's good yeah we do that machine
learning queries which that's definitely
in the work I have not actually gotten
to work with it too much so our
proactive customization which we look at
all the big security contenders McAfee
kaspersky all of them and get together
and buy get together I mean they'll say
what what bad stuff happened at what
time and the security community is very
tight-knit so if Facebook find something
want some anomaly or vulnerability
they're going to share it so we're
watching that if we find something we'll
share it so it's basically updating all
of our tools with whatever everyone else
is found so that you can find all the
newest threats so very quickly we're
going to run through 80 a threat hunting
here's the cyber kill chain it's due to
the amount of time that we have 20 years
late and so the cyber kill chain is
basically the steps that malware goes
through in order to basically get your
machine and it will be from the
basically all the way from hitting your
machine and looking at it too
finally exfiltrating data so right here
is the cyber kill chain recon lure
redirect the exploit kit dropper files
the call home and finally the data theft
which is the exfiltration so we try our
goal is to try to hit this as early in
the chain as we can the earlier in the
chain you can hit it the better off you
are absolutely so our management cycle
is reactive in and in my opinion that's
unfortunate but that has to deal with
the nature of the of the business we
have to be reactive absolutely so
they're also as proactive as well right
it's just you can get in trouble if you
do Proactiv to proactively and it's
catered per each client so each Network
each in infrastructure they have their
own types of security policies that they
deal with in different various agencies
that they also get compliance from so
they have different things that they do
so we have to comply to that for them
some attacks and attend detection so
angler exploit kit how many of you guys
are familiar with well let me ask that
first question how many of you familiar
with an exploit kit all right awesome
that's more than I thought so for those
of you who don't know what an exploit
kit is it's basically software that's
tailored to a certain exploit so in
Adobe if there is a certain exploit a
kit will be created to use it and the
purpose of the exploit kit is to use the
exploit to put bed software on whatever
is running it so anglers kind of died
out because a lot of the people that
wrote it have been caught dire banking
malware so it's basically hooks into the
browser to steal your de steal
credentials so you you're typing to
browser and after gates which is the
scariest kind of malware is the kind of
problem exactly so tell us reverse
engineered it
up there is basically its functionality
in a flow chart so taluses also created
new detection methods to analyze
basically the indicators to compromise
for it thank you so the different type
of interfaces that are utilized for an
analyst to do their searches and
investigations once they start at the
initial triage of an incident here is
the advanced threat analytics threat
detection example for dried X shows you
the decap correlation and analysis so
then we also have for examples like
right here it's got our elasticsearch
got our packet capture and our metadata
ground which is through bro and net flow
generation so more on the example for
droid x where it's being flagged by the
IP address that's what ultimately gets
flagged right and then once the
connection was observed the
investigators search for correlating
events so basically our Tier one says
this is a known bad IP our tier 2 said
this is definitely giving out bad stuff
and our investigator finally says
alright let's go hunting for it on their
network so we were hoping that we could
walk you through a different a detailed
investigation with an and analyst and
what they do with a TA on some of the
things that they're analyzing and this
is to show you some of the information
that they'll see right so the servers
located in Russia generally are two
known Bad's is if we see companies
communicating in Russia or China and
they explicitly you told us we don't
deal in China or Russia that's bad
server give a post so we know it's to
live then here we'll have the packet cap
part of the packet capture so they can
it was obfuscated it so it makes it very
hard for human eyes to read mine in work
so we try to write programs that'll help
the office
the code so Java codes very very common
that's the code that was found that was
buried and everything this is how we
ultimately will sanitize it so to make
sure that insert person from company
here doesn't accidentally click on the
bad link and get it will sanitize it
like so take a picture of a picture of
another picture and insert it towards
non touchable here's a where it was
downloaded so temp directory as this D
SHhhh see so we were able to actually
say we're got downloaded and it was
flagged as malware by seven out of 57
programs so we definitely let them know
about it so I know we were short on time
and we walked you through some of the
integral steps that are taken when
someone is looking at particular
information for a compromise on anyone's
network especially with any of our
clientele does anyone have any questions
thoughts concerns we're going to be here
after so if you have time to stay we can
answer questions that weren't answered
during broadcast absolutely okay thank
you thank you
you