hi everyone thank you for coming tonight
it is my pleasure to announce Dickie
George who comes to us from the applied
physics lab at Johns Hopkins University
and before that was several years as a
mathematician at the NSA it's going to
be talking to us about the role of the
NSA in the development of des i could
probably introduce myself as well I'm
Lauren Stewart I'm just the president of
the serious student association who is a
sponsor of this talk we're really glad
to have all of you here and without any
further ado I will let Dickie take it
away thank you very much I do have one
more thing to say if you have questions
he's perfectly willing to take them
during the talk we have this microphone
which I'll be walking around we have
this microphone back here so that your
questions can be recorded so that they
will be available for all posterity so
keep that in mind when you're asking
questions okay yeah it's important to
being recorded I think that's a good
thing so for me the sounds loud to me is
this tool out is that ok ok so for me
this uh this talk started back in 2010 I
was talking to a gentleman from RSA at
2010 he was saying next year's RSA
conference is the 20th anniversary be
nice if we had something big now
coincidentally i was planning to retire
in 2011 and so I used that as an excuse
to talk to the director and say we ought
to declassify the whole des story and he
said that's that's a good idea we ought
to now the reason I wanted to do was des
was back in 72 it turns out that I was
the last person at NSA who has played
any role in that who had participated in
the evaluation and I knew if I retired
before was Declassified it was never
going to get out because it was it was a
pretty quiet story all through its life
so this gave me an opportunity to do
that that was kind of fun this is the
third time I've given the talk I gave it
RSA and I gave it once in a class but
this one's being recorded I think that's
really nice it's nice to have this for
history so please do ask questions now
I'll also tell you that when i when i
did this talk at RSA i did it on a when
wednesday or thursday but during the
keynotes the tuesday keynotes they had a
panel a 45-minute panel on this story
where it was just question and answers
the panel i was on the panel and there
were four public cryptographers who were
asking questions that that tape is still
available on youtube if you want to see
it it's pretty interesting the for
public guys probably people you know
that was a whit dippy in Marty Hellman
adi shamir and ron rivest so they were
guys who had been involved in in the
game and they were friends man it was a
it was a fun panel the the unfun part of
it was when they announced it as soon as
they now still all forums started
sending me the questions on emails
hoping i would answer them before the
panel i had to keep telling i'm not
going to answer the questions before we
do it live you know so it's got to be
spontaneous I can't be giving you guys
all the answers up front so it of course
Holman said that but I've been waiting
30 years and I may die before this panel
yeah but it was fun so now let me sit
stage a little bit for what's going on
back in the 70s for a lot of you the
world was different back then you're not
not familiar the story at all in 1972
crypto was not a commercial thing there
were a few companies mostly European
that we're doing things not well they
basically do the same thing they've been
doing in World War two the real crypto
is being done by governments around the
world and nobody else got to play so
that was the state of the art at the
same time if you look at the what was
going on in the world I worked in the
information assurance Directorate at NSA
by the way of a few years was 41 so it
was really a few years
at that point in time the information
assurance director which had about 2500
people that were doing this evaluation
of crypto and implementation of crypto
that director did not own a computer we
were doing the work with with paper and
pencil and then you know about 72 73 we
got a line over to another building
where we could borrow some time on
another part of the agency's computer
and so you could read your cards in and
you got to run a program a day and of
course there were about seven cards up
front that were control cards and if you
got any one of those wrong you didn't
get to run anything that day that was
the way it went so it was a very much
different world in about nineteen
seventy-two someone decided that the
Commerce is going to it's going to be
using computers we need to have some
kind of encryption to protect that
information now at the same time I was
sitting in my desk in 1973 when the
director of information assurance at NSA
walked by my desk and said what are you
working on I said I'm working on a
computer cryptographic algorithm he said
what I said well it's it's going to be
an encryption algorithm that's designed
to run in software he said okay don't
spend more than ten percent of your time
on that because we will never run crypto
and software you can't trust computers
and that was that was the world back
then so when they told NBS national
bureau of standards which is now NIST
that we need an algorithm for commercial
use to protect the information the first
thing they did was come to NSA and say
would you design us an algorithm there
was a lot of discussion a lot of
discussion at all levels at NSA at my
level I was that was 72 I was younger
the lot of the discussion was
technically could we do it and how would
we do it at the more senior levels the
questions were if we put down an
algorithm at no one's going to use it
because they think it's going to be
hooked if anybody finds an attack on it
they're going to know we hoped it even
even if we didn't so this politically is
going to be a disaster force no matter
what way we go if you think about the
world of crypto back then we designed
things like like Vincent Vincent a
handheld radio that a for observer uses
it's got an algorithm in it the
algorithm was designed in 1957 we
evaluated it for 12 years to ensure that
there was nothing that could go wrong
then we implemented it and we looked at
that implementation when I said we
looked at that implementation I spent
six months with the engineering diagrams
for that thing failing every resistor
every gate every register stage every
breaking every line to see what could go
wrong in anything serious that went
wrong we put an alarm in so that it
would be caught if it happened so well
we actually fielded that in 1976 so took
19 years from design to fielding it's
still out in the field so it's been 40
years it's never headed anything changed
has never had a problem unlike an
operating system which changes every
Tuesday so it was a different world but
that 12 years of evaluation of the logic
we relied on that to make sure we
weren't missing anything and Wendy I
said we're going to we're going to put
this out in a year we were nervous that
that we would design something and there
would be a problem with it so the agency
said we don't want to we don't want to
design the algorithm now when we said we
don't want to design the algorithm there
were big equities concerns and equities
are balancing the offense in the deep
so everybody thinks cripta verbal sighs
when you think of equity concerned that
wasn't it because the offense wanted a
16-bit variable and nobody was going to
buy that right because I that's a joke
so that wasn't the concern what what the
offense really wanted was they wanted to
make sure that we weren't teaching the
world how to make good crypto they
weren't worried about us teaching the
Russians how to make good crypto they
were worried if I was teaching the world
how to make good crypto that was the big
concern in that well that was you know
if you fast-forward to skipjack days
that that's where we that that rose
again from the dead that said same
concern so it was decided that we would
not design the algorithm but the
director told the director of NIST with
MBS the time told them that yes we will
evaluate the algorithm that is proposed
to make sure that there's not anything
there as far as we can tell again it was
one going to be a one-year evaluation
but we will evaluate it to make sure
that there's no weakness there and we'll
tell you if we find anything and the
director of NSA said I want to be able
to assure the director of missed that
the algorithm is as strong as advertised
that there aren't shortcut attacks that
we find so if we find anything we are
going to tell them so those the ground
rules were playing under at that point
in time now mr. put out a call for what
one of these algorithms the algorithm
could be used as a data encryption
standard and they got three submissions
all were from professors that wanted a
lot of money to study the problem and of
course the directors and bs said that's
not really what I'm looking for i'm
looking for an algorithm and so we
looked around and looked around came
back to NSA
and said can't get one can you design
one so we went through the same
discussion again will we do it what's it
going to look like there were a lot of
discussions inside about what it should
look like and as we were in the middle
of those discussions someone found out
that IBM was working on an algorithm
that they were planned at planning to
commercialize it's called Lucifer it was
going to go out and the the main
designer of that algorithm was it was a
gentleman who had worked in the Army
Security Agency and it worked on Krypto
with NSA so there was a feeling that he
actually knew what he was doing and this
might be a decent algorithm they went
they went to IBM and talked to them in
IBM agreed to give up their commercial
plans to donate the algorithm to the
government for non national security use
and they would put it into the
competition so NBS put out another call
and they got three more applicants one
another professor who asked for a lot of
money to study the problem they got a
company that said they would allow NBS
to use their algorithm but they wanted
to remain proprietary so no one would
know what it looked like and they wanted
to charge for use NBS said that's not
really what we had in mind when we were
looking for a data encryption standard
it really has to be visible to the
public so that the public can evaluate
it and the third was Lucifer so Lucifer
went in and they talked to the director
once again he set up similar ground
rules he said ok we are going to
evaluate this we're going to look at it
see if there's any attack that's short
of exhaustion we're going to tell you if
we have if it doesn't meet its
advertised strength and we won't make
any will make we want to or suggest any
changes unless they are critical to the
security so if we find an attack will
tell you will tell IBM
and we'll work with them to fix it if we
don't find an attack we won't make any
changes it sounds pretty fair and then
they set up the most convoluted
evaluation system you can imagine they
set up one small team of people to work
with IBM to give them any information
they might ask and they were told any
question that IBM asks you answer it ok
so you've got to be completely honest
with them and they they cleared the
people at IBM so they could get that
information if it needed to be
classified they set up a team of people
to evaluate the the algorithm a smallish
team and everyone knew that those teams
existed that the evaluation team and the
team that worked with IBM shortly after
that they set up a shadow evaluation
team to do an evaluation it was team
that nobody knew about I was on the
shadow I was actually on the first team
as a bit player but I was on the shadow
team as you know make sure we really
don't miss anything it's funny when I
was getting ready to give this talk I
was up talking to my best friend at NSA
who I've worked with virtually every day
for 35 years until he retired really
worked with them closely every day and I
was talking about giving this talking in
he said oh do you want my notes
he said do you want my notes and I said
your notes you never worked on des he
said oh yeah i was on the Chado team
that was watching your team you just
didn't know there was another team that
existed I don't know how many shadow
teams that were watching those other
things but it seems like everybody was
involved and nobody knew it so it was a
crazy system but when we worked with IBM
we gave them everybody knows what des
looks like it's got a its got a bit
permutations got s boxes the s-boxes our
little ejs box has for permutations of
the numbers from 0 to 15 so we gave them
eight criteria to generate those s boxes
there was a ninth criteria that IBM
didn't know about and that was the that
was the criteria to block differential
cryptanalytic attacks because
differential cryptanalysis was
classified at the time so what we said
was generate a bunch of s boxes and then
we'll help you pick the set of now what
our plan was was to see which of these
thousand permutations they submitted
satisfied that ninth criteria and we
just say let's use these it seems pretty
reasonable the problem is that ninth
criteria was really really tricky it was
any single bid in has to guess to go to
at least two bits out at least one of
those bits has to be on the outside so
because the outside bits get spread over
and have more influence in blah blah
blah blah blah and asking that to happen
for every single one bit off put too
much restriction on those little
permutations little permutations are
funny anyway if you show anybody a
little permutation he's going to find
all sorts of things that look non-random
because the human eye just does that so
we took all of the permutations that IBM
had given us and couldn't find a that
mat that met
ninth criteria so the the team that was
working with IBM generated permutations
that met all nine criteria gave them
back to IBM and said let's use these we
didn't know if IBM would notice that
those were not permutations that they've
given us or not because they gave us
lots and lots of these little
permutations could have could have been
a set from that but someone did and
someone actually said that we you know
we got these permutations back from NSA
and they were all changed we don't know
what happened well when they announced
that the world immediately assumed
that's where the hook was and as they
had planted a hook in that permutation
now when I say the world it wasn't
everybody adi shamir told me that he
never believed we hoped it because he
knew we wanted to read Russian you meant
Russian mail and the Russians weren't
going to use it so why would we bother
to Hogan and in some sense that's true
I've got a lot of stories about funny
things that happened with Audi we had
some good times over theirs but this was
this was not a bad thing from an NSA
point of view because there was no hook
in those s boxes they were they were
there to block that attack and it was
much better for us in two ways to have
people think that that's where the hook
was because it meant the only people who
were probably going to use it were the
commercial people in the US were being
going to be forced to use it the world
wasn't going to use it second it was
much better for us to have people
looking at those permutations trying to
figure out what the trapdoor is rather
than figuring out why we used those to
make it stronger much better from them
to try to attack them than to think what
were they doing so that worked out
pretty well now
one of the questions that Marty asked
was why didn't you change the key
schedule key schedules way to a simple
he said I spent months on that key
schedule and my answer was yeah I spent
years on that key schedule you spent
months if I had been able to find
anything wrong so that looked to me like
it was way week it looked like it was
way too simple if I could have found the
hint of an attack I could have fixed it
but the ground rule said that if we
couldn't find an attack we couldn't
change anything so i think was took minh
said you know when it came back they
hadn't changed the wire they hadn't
changed the line they hadn't changed
anything and that's really true we
hadn't changed any wires we hadn't
changed the permutation we hadn't
changed the key schedule we hadn't done
anything all we did was the what's the S
boxes now the other the other big issue
of course was 56 bits of crypto verbal
that was an information assurance equity
so back in the 50s we were trying with
one of the things that they did when
they set up NSA was it said we don't
want to be caught in the situation that
the Germans were caught in World War two
where they knew there was an attack on
enigma but they didn't think that
anybody would spend the money to build
anything to exploit it we don't want to
fall prey to that and so Jim Fraser
developed something that was akin to
Moore's law to predict where technology
was going to go in the future he did a
little bit at a finer granularity
because different technologies evolve at
different rates so so there were things
that were happening like tape readers we
used to use well you could predict what
was going to happen with tape reader
technology that was it that was a big
cost for us it could get better but it
wasn't going to get better forever and
so the improvement was going to want to
tail off you were only going to get so
much better things like that so we had
something we had standards that would
tell us how good things had to be and we
knew what we were requiring of
communication systems that the
government was using now remember when
we did Vincent we evaluated that
algorithm for 12 years and then we
evaluated the implementation for another
7 the implementation is so critical
because that's what you're usually
attacking you're usually attacking an
implementation not not the not the
algorithm itself it's pretty easy to
find the problem with the algorithm it's
really hard to find a problem with the
implementation because implementations
change I'm ever one time when we were
looking at that at that handheld thing
and we had we had end end clocks of
delay built-in built-in in one place and
when we went to test it we got n plus 1
and we're thinking what the heck how
does that happen well it happens because
the blasted wire was too long it slowed
down the signal enough that we did it
built in another delay bed for us and so
we had changed the whole design because
that that was the first implementation
you had to build that any you were never
get another one that had that extra
delay bit as times were going to change
those are the kind of things you need to
worry about another thing another
interesting that happened we had to we
had another line that was long well the
signal was was kind of dying out so we
had to put an amplifier on it the guy
who built it the company that built it
found they could buy amplifiers with
with an inverter cheaper than they could
buy amplifiers and so they used those so
suddenly we got an inverter in the
middle of our machine that we weren't
expecting you got to know about those
things and sometimes those things matter
like if you're adding a day plus B plus
C in an implementation you never add a
plus B plus C back in the old days you
add a to b then you take that some and
add it to see if you take a plus B plus
C it's different than if you take a plus
B plus C
when you go through and look at the
failure things that can happen it's a
different case and we had to throw a
whole series away one time because they
decided well that will just add b2c
first instead of it be first you can't
you can't make changes like that so the
implementation is so critical you got to
worry about that that's what we knew was
going to be attacked so when we were
looking at this algorithm we said if we
put a lot of crypto variable in here we
know what's going to happen the military
is going to say i can buy those des
boxes cheap i'm going to start using
those and we had no idea what the
implementation was going to be so the
director of information assurance said
make that crypt of herbal small enough
that the military won't be allowed to
use it the director the director said I
got to make it secure I can't I can't be
playing around like that so I actually
found a meeting notes from a meeting
that there were only two people in two
people plus an exec because neither the
two were going to take notes on anything
they had to have somebody who recorded
what was going on but Jim Fraser and the
director got together and then the
director said how big do I have to make
it to be safe into the future and it's
remember this was early 70s and Jim
Fraser said to go out to 1990 you need
56 bits but then you've got a dick
you've got decertified at nineteen
ninety because because in 1991 it's
going to be it's going to be attackable
so the director called up the director
of NBS and said we want to go 56 bits
it's going to give you till nineteen
ninety director of NB I said we're only
going to use the yes for three or four
years and then we'll replace it with
next version sure that's fine he didn't
understand how hard it was going to be
changed that thing out so that's where
the 56 bits came from now there's
another thing to happen that's parity
bits
and parity bits came because of again if
an IAD thing see we were used to dealing
with military military guys are out in
the field into muddy it's raining it's
all sorts of crap in the way they put
crypto variables in they have a piece of
paper strip of paper that they pull
through a little machine a key reader
it's got a metal comb in the air that
picks up the holes in the paper tape
tells it what the variable is doesn't
always work real well fact I'm zit
doesn't work real well so they added
parody on the reason they added parody
on if you do that the machine will tell
you it didn't pass parody try again you
don't want to put the wrong crypto
verbal in if you if you put the wrong
crypt of air berlin encrypt a message
send it out you're going to get a note
back in in the clear saying hey I can't
understand you so you try again you send
the same message out with a slightly
different variable that's a very bad
situation we didn't want to fall prey to
that so we routinely added parity bits
to make sure that the thing had loaded
right now it's a little bit different
working in a bank than working out in
the field so we probably would have been
okay without it but that's that's where
those bits of parity came from it's just
tradition so at this point in time we
went out with a 56 bit version 56 bits
also happened to fall nicely inside the
range of what we knew differential
cryptanalysis could do because we were
looking at this and I had a path that
took it down to just about 56 and so I I
can tell the director I'm pretty happy
about this because it looks like you're
going to be able to say yes it meets its
advertised strength whereas if you made
it big yeah you're awfully familiar with
differential cryptanalysis a complicated
Crypt variable schedule wouldn't help
you much with differential cryptanalysis
what you're looking for some kind of
structure you usually do something like
say you know I'm going to assume a
little bit crypt of arable go in find it
find these kind
things and go back and look for the
structure at the end or you can start
with structure at the beginning go down
assume some variable down here back up
see if the structure exists so you're
not you're not making tons of variable
assumptions the complicated mixing
encrypted verbal wouldn't have helped
you a whole lot so at that point in time
it looked like everything was good we
had the world was sure that we had hook
the thing through the S boxes and so
there were papers coming out left and
right about so if some guys would even
say it's it's s box 6 that they hooked
here's how it works and you're thinking
really you know if you're going to tell
me this is where it is you got to talk
about the attackers don't just tell me
it's got to be this box and when I
looked at some of those s boxes they
really looked bad and we were pretty
happy that they looked that bad because
what a target that was for the world I
mean if the world is telling everybody
don't trust the thing that's great Marty
Hellman had it had a nice piece of work
on his memory trade-off time memory
trade-off I was great work it gave
people a lot of opportunity to do some
really neat things now that's the reason
that this was such a critical point in
the development of cryptography for the
world what made NSA the leader in
cryptography was we had the best
problems right we we had the best
designers in the world and we were
looking at their crypto and trying to
find problems with it nobody had those
kind of problems to work on that was
awesome we also had a critical mass of
people we had a thousand mathematicians
looking at these problems and sharing
the information with each other every
day so the best problems and a critical
mass of people thinking about it that's
how you own the space and we did on it
what we did with des was we gave the
world a problem to concentrate on and
then the internet popped up ARPANET and
that gave the world virtual critical
mass I remember I was I was having
dinner without his schmear one time and
we were I was talking about about his
work and he hauls out of slapped Isis
let me show you my emails from the 70s
and so we started going through his eat
he still had his emails from the 70s
when he had worked on this stuff it's in
there what was real emails because i
think the real email didn't start to
about 91 or something like that but but
it was notes that they were sending back
and forth so that so that was fun stuff
really fun stuff and then you know we
had differential analysis not because of
des we had it because of other
algorithms that have work done and then
we could apply it to DES you're never
going to find differential crypt
analysis by looking at des just doesn't
work so the the Japanese published an
algorithm called feel in the 80s and Adi
looked at that and he had this idea of
looking at differences to see what would
happen and he tracked it through and he
figured out what differential
cryptanalysis would do by looking at
feel he founded it just destroyed feel
so I said well I wondered what that
would do on des this should work on des
so he started looking at des and he kept
applying it in he just couldn't find a
good path through and it drove him nuts
he said these s boxes just don't let my
pants work and they all were coming
everything he tried would be 56 or worse
the best he could find was 56 and he
said you know
they changed the s-boxes I wonder so he
generated about 10 sets of random s
boxes and tried them in DES and he got
work factors on every one of them
between two to the 16th and 2 to the 32
so every random set that he tried his
differential cryptanalytic attack worked
really well so I remember the word came
out in 89 that shamir was going to
announce some des work didn't say he was
going to announce an attacks he's going
to announce some des work now I knew
what he had done on feel and so the
guess was it was differential
cryptanalytic all I was hoping was he
didn't find a better path than I had
because I was going to be screwed so
when his work came out that he had found
the best path that we had it was really
cool but in his paper when he talked
about this this path and he talked about
how it works so much better on every
other s box he presented him showed how
well it worked he hypothesized that
there was in ninth criteria that wasn't
divulged to the public and blocks
differential crypt analysis which was
exactly right but of course that was
published in nineteen ninety and as he
did that we announced the des was no
longer certified for use so the whole
thing played itself out really
beautifully just at the time when when
it was announced that NSA had been good
guys and had blocked an attack rather
than putting in an attack it became
attackable in real life the timing was
perfect the analysis was beautiful I
remember he was giving a talk when I
talked at our say Adi gave a talk the
next day about public crypt analysis of
da the public
roll and he was talking about his
relationship with NSA how he used to
send letters to the director with his
ideas on Krypto and the director would
send it back nice letters now the
director wasn't send him letters he was
signing the letters but but all of the
outside crypto stuff was coming to me
and most of it was what you might expect
to would be but sometimes you get
somebody like like a Shamir who's
actually telling you really good stuff
and so you know I'd write very nice
letters back to him the director would
send him he actually flashed one up at
the board and i start i started laughing
he said weightman have you seen this
letter i said yes on that letter he said
did you write that letter and i'm
sitting about 20 rows back in the
auditorium smiling yeah you know it
there are a lot of brilliant guys on the
outside doing really good work in it I
think this des was a really really
important good thing it gave us all an
opportunity to work together to share in
in this knowledge in the development and
there's been a lot of work since then
really good work where people are having
great ideas that we all benefit from you
know for me it's we want to get secure
stuff out there we want to protect
ourselves and I think it's it only aids
us all when we have more knowledge but
this was one of the really really
exciting events it brought the public in
it used a fairly a fairly simple
algorithm people could look at yeah you
when you're talking about s-boxes 0 to
15 people can see those numbers they can
understand them it's not like you're
using a permutation on 0 2 256 just too
big and too complicated for people look
at when you're talking about 30 to 15
people can look at it they can see
patterns they can have ideas mail and
dwell when he was this design I think
Nolan was the best designer ever knew he
also said you know I want to design my
algorithm so that's this much better
than required
because I know if it's this much better
you're not going to spend any time
looking at it you're going to go after
somebody else's junk that you know you
can beat but if I tantalize you with
something that's this much better i know
you're going to spend time looking at my
thing and i want you to try to evaluate
eiler know if there's something wrong
with it so that was kind of the golden
rule you don't try to hide security hide
insecurity with complexity you want it
to be obviously secure you don't want to
make it a complexity problem spaghetti
code we used to call it you want to you
want to be close des was close now that
differential cryptanalytic attack that
was just about exhaustion lot of text
required a lot of text ton of texts but
but it was about it was about it
exhaustion it was and it was really cool
of this this whole story was great and I
think it was a nice opportunity for the
world to see ya you know NSA can play
fair when I was on the stage with with
with the ADI and and marty and witten in
Ronda they said did you think about
hooking it and I said not for a second
because i knew i wasn't smart enough to
build a hook in that you guys wouldn't
find some time in the next 15 years and
that was really true that was that was
that's the big story for crypto and NSA
we're smart enough to know we aren't
smart enough to do that and that's just
not a good thing to do the good thing to
do is talk on you build it right and if
we build it right and implement it right
the country wins that that's all it
takes and you know we we got the best
designers we got the best developers in
the world that's how we win that's how
we got the es that internet think really
kind of threw a monkey wrench in but
yeah yeah that was that was the that was
the one thing I didn't foresee I knew we
were given him a good problem but I
thought people would be working in
isolation doggone it they weren't they
were all working together
and what a tremendous boon that's been
for the world to be able to work on
problems like that in a group it's
really really nice to see so they asked
me what my biggest regret was when I saw
the work was being done and I said my
biggest regret is it you know I got to
write letters to Adi about his good
ideas but they weren't coming from me I
would have loved to be able to work with
him that would that would have been a
really cool thing for me and I was stuck
in this little closed I only I had a
thousand people to work with but I
didn't have him and I think it would
have would have been really neat for me
to have to be able to work with them so
that that's the biggest regret that I
have is that we we don't get to work
with everybody we are locked up by this
classification system I remember Brian
snow at one of the rsas they asked him
if they thought NSA would stay ahead of
the world in crypto and he said of
course because we get to see everything
that everybody else publishes and you
don't get to see anything we publish if
we can't stay ahead of you will really
suck yes it just add to the record a
little bit dougie a number of places
sort of extended the life of des or at
least their use of it with the ds3 any
comment you want to make around that
please do sure so Triple DES where use
three de esas together it's it's nice
for one reason if you use the same as
variable to decrypt and encrypt and
decrypt it it's compatible with a single
des it's solid it's a little bit longer
but we got over worrying about the
government using that by that time so
that was not a big deal for us I don't
think that the politicians for saw that
and I don't think that that the techies
were we're thinking that was going to
happen either because we thought you
know this thing is going to last it's
five or six years and be replaced by
something else but not Triple DES the
reason we didn't think Triple DES was
because of the efficiency you know it's
it's three times slower and everybody's
looking for faster not slower
so you know you can take almost any any
algorithm and run a thousand rounds on
it you're probably okay it's just the
throughput is going to be terrible so
just just as a side note remember when
the call for des came out there were
only there was only one real applicant
for it when the call for AES came out
and that one des guy was a guy who
worked with NSA on Krypto so this was
not a pure commercial guy but when a es
came out there were about 15 proposals
and they were almost all from private
guys in fact the only one that really
had anything wrong with it was the
German government submission all the
private ones were good and that shows
how far the commercial world had come
yes Mike police because they're
recording I apologize I'm probably the
least intelligent person in this room
and I don't have the background and all
the things you're talking about I went
to UCLA right after the ARPANET thing
started stuff it sounds to me like
you're talking about messages in your
encryption continuous conversation the
same thing the internet grew up out of
is that as opposed to single
transactions so des could be used in any
way and most of it really was commercial
stuff it was banking stuff so it was
transactions and that kind of data but
it could have been used in any way and
probably was I'm sure I'm sure
conversations were like resident single
transaction create a simpler base to
where you can encrypt everything
differently each time as long as you
keep a record of how to decrypt that if
it's needed you mean change the crypt of
air bleach time yep not not back then
because changing the crypto it's not
like there was no RSA back then okay so
it was it was all that paper taste three
have different types of but the way you
approach them though
so you could do something like add a
counter in each time but nobody did yeah
I'll tell you that you're talking key
management and the world did not much as
they didn't understand crypto they
really didn't understand commander
that's where the problem is growing up
commercially today yeah thnkx can't keep
you out of their storage records you
can't protect a record from a merchant
merchant sorry have to store all the
stuff the banks have to store all the
stuff everything goes on on the Internet
today has to be stored and you can't use
a single coding for that because if
somebody figures out how to I mean this
is way it's it's seeming to me if
somebody figures out the one log and get
into everything yeah but that key
management is hard though it's really
cumbersome for anybody to do and so you
have that trade-off you also have to
remember that if you've got something
that's managing key then that's going to
be the target they're not going after
the data they're going to go after the
key management and do after that so
you've got to watch out for that that's
the that's the real Holy Grail because
if you get that you can get everything
so you also have to worry about if
you're storing everything everything in
a huge database well yeah you you want
to have different encryption for each
one because you don't want to decrypt
the whole thing to get to this thing you
want to go after a piece by piece so
yeah but back in the early days of des
that wasn't the game I think yeah the
game was I'll tell you we we went to a
bank in New York and they were saying
they were taking us through saying and
we're using des for this here and we're
using it back in this system here and
we're using it here we're using here
amusing here and finally one of the guy
said well that's a lot of uses what are
you doing for key management and the
security guy said that's the good news
we don't need key management it came
with key
which point you say okay that's true
story by the way sad but true any
questions remember this is being
recorded in any question you have
somebody else is going to wish somebody
had asked not so much fun Dez but you
have any comments about blockchain and
Internet of Things and topics like that
as it relates to crypto yeah I mean
Internet of Things it's going to be a
bear yeah you've already got
refrigerators that are spamming the
world and being parts of botnets the
medical devices I think of the most
problematic because if someone says you
kind of fib you later in here you don't
want that you don't want it password
encrypted cuz if something goes wrong
you want that guy to be able to find out
what's going on you want anybody there
to be able to find out what's going on
but that means has got to be open so
that anybody can also do anything now I
was in a meeting the other day it seems
like seems like every everybody in this
blasted meeting it was not an APL
meeting it was a community thing that
we're putting on a cyber conference
everybody there seemed to have some kind
of a a body pump that was given them
stuff for some kind of a diabetic
condition type 2 diabetes or whatever
but they're all talking about that and
saying well you know I sometimes I said
it for this insolence sometime I said it
for that insulin I'm thinking you know
that that changing that setting if you
can do that remotely somebody else can
do that remotely and if you've got the
wrong setting for the insulin you're
getting that's probably not a good
situation these this stuff is really
scary it's also true that it well beyond
des now one of the things we're thinking
about is what's next after RSA if you
believe in quantum computers then you
need to worry about that and I think we
do need to worry about that and when I
say we it's not NSA it's the world needs
to worry about that i was i was talking
to one of the guys
who's a professor in saying well you
know it's it's only the government that
has this intelligence life it would just
wait until someone really builds one and
then we'll change that stuff right away
and I said you know number one you're
not gonna change it right away it's good
it's going to take a while and number
two it's not true that's only the
government has intelligence life you've
got your health records you've got your
your investment your banking all that
stuff but health in particular you're
that stuff is not going to change over
time you've got to protect that and
you've got to understand that that's
maybe not for me but for my grandkids
their their health records going to be
important 50 years from now might be for
me see how lucky I am now some of that
some of the things on the internet of
things are likely to remain unchanged
for 15 or 20 years because they're built
in two big devices so I'm going to put
you on the spot with two questions okay
the first one is are you actually sattui
she Nakamoto perhaps good answer and the
those of you don't know you can google
and the second one is I'll state my
opinion so it's on the record as well I
think it is wrong to build in
intentional weaknesses for law
enforcement access to personal
communications because that weakens
everything and for all governments and
that's not necessarily a good result
that's my opinion do you have anything
you'd like to say on the subject sure
you're writing first for a number of
reasons there's ubiquitous crypto out
there there's no way you're going to be
able to design it so the bad guys are
vulnerable the really bad guys you might
be able to pick up some some fool who's
doing something the little guy you're
not getting the big guys you might get a
little guy but there's no question
you're going to put everybody else at
risk because you're not going to be able
to contain the access to that law
enforcement field other governments are
going to have it even if it's only in
the u.s. if you're going to give it to
police departments it's gone all you're
going to do is put the average
citizen at risk you're not you're not
really going to do anything beneficial
for law enforcement but you are going to
pretty much put everybody else of the
creek so if even if the government
designs it if you can't let commercial
people design it they will they will
screw it up I get back when we were
doing this the Scalia stuff I used to
see stuff from companies all the time
and I would beg them not to try to do it
because they were totally incompetent at
designing this stuff they didn't have
crypto guys even your big companies did
not have crypto guys I was on a on a
piano one time it was a talking to the
National Academy of Sciences talking on
developmental of workforce they want to
know how many savvy cyber people Crips a
crypto cyber cyber people you had to
have they asked me first I said Johns
Hopkins we have 5,000 people I need a
thousand people that are really good and
I need everybody to be pretty good they
would to cisco they asked the cisco guy
he said we've got 30,000 people i need
300 of them to understand cyber security
I think at cisco you need 300 people
you've got to be kidding you know if
it's not 15,000 you're not doing your
job so you know to think they're gonna
do that by the way next guy was John
Deere he said I have 60,000 people I
need 12 who know something about cyber I
said 12 how do you keep your network up
with 12 yeah I said your time I said
you're 12 any good he said I don't know
maybe how would I know but so so there
are plenty of jobs for cyber security
guys
yeah that's good I spent a lot of time
talking to the guy and he just said you
know I don't have a threat model and I
got to be able to sell it to them to the
board and without any kind of a threat
model I can't convince him I need to
spend money on cybersecurity chimp ooh
yeah so my question is any predictions
on when we should start worrying about
quantum computers that could actually
break for real crypto crypto yeah you
know that is such a good question it
seems like about 30 years ago I was told
they were 20 years away yeah we keep
hearing it's 20 years away I don't know
if we ever get there but if we don't get
there it'll be for one of two reasons
something better happened or there's no
commercial market for it because right
now it's not much good for anything but
but that then we don't have a lot of
algorithm all the algorithms that seem
to be very efficient will solve that
kind of problem so NSA has already come
out and said that we should start
thinking about the follow-on a so I
think that that's good advice the
the follow-on to RSA they should start
thinking about what is going to replace
it for the world because NSA right now
is using commercial stuff almost
exclusively even the stuff they build
themselves is called suite b which is
still exactly the same algorithms that
are used in the commercial stuff so we
it's not going to be NSA coming up with
a government version it's going to be we
as a country maybe we as o is a world
need to come up with the next one is it
lattice based I don't know the problem
with lattice basis looks good but how
much work has really been done you know
no it hasn't been labeled as the answer
yet and when it's labeled as the answer
that's when you're going to get the
really good work on it until people
think it's it's the problem to solve
you're not going to get people trying to
solve it
it's going to say the quantum who will
break all the public key crypto but
symmetric keys I mean you're still not
going to break aes with so so it's it
helps it takes it down to basically the
square root square root of huge well
squirts so it takes it from 256 to 128
but there's also a big coefficient
outside so it's so it's a lot of work I
was to the to the 128 where as opposed
to a little work down to the 250 it it's
still around to the 192 so yeah this the
symmetric stuff is good and maybe we
just go back to the 70s when we use
symmetric to rekey symmetric yeah you
can do that I want to lead you to when I
asked about IOT I was thinking of a
lightweight crypto and ask for any
speculation you have on the viability
some people say if I can do an IP stack
I can do crypto if others say not you
want to speculate so there actually has
been work on lightweight crypto and
they're trying to come up with something
that might be a good standard I think I
think it's a good problem because with
these with the little devices the stuff
they're putting in refrigerators there's
not a lot of horsepower there now it
could be by the time they come up with
something there'll be a lot more
horsepower there you know when you think
about what's in your watch compared to
what was in a computer in the IAD 30
years ago so it's about the same so it
could be could be the refrigerator is
going to be smart as a car that can
drive itself hopefully refrigerator
doesn't leave the house but yeah but it
could have that kind of horsepower in it
okay thank you very much