good evening everyone today I'm very
happy to
my colleague Jeremiah blocky Jeremiah is
a theoretical computer scientist who is
interested in applying fundamental ideas
from computer science to address
practical problems in usable privacy and
security Jeremiah's research interest
span several topics for example
developing usable authentication
protocols for humans multiple exploring
easy ways for humans to create and
remember multiple strong passwords and
designing secure cryptographic protocols
that are so simple that they can be run
by humans prior to joining our
department Jeremiah did his PhD from CMU
and was also a postdoc at Microsoft
Research New England today Jeremiah will
be talking about usable and secure human
authentication all right thanks for the
introduction so I'm going to talk to you
today about creating and remembering
multiple passwords so this talk is on
the collection of works with some of my
co-authors have been fortunate to be a
path of opportunity to work with a lot
of great people over the years so shown
up here on the slide we have my advisors
Manuel Blum and Anupam data and saranga
commander II who was a grad student with
me at Carnegie Mellon and his adviser
lori greiner so to start off this talk I
want to ask you to memorize a few
secrets so I want you to imagine that
Bill Clinton is standing on this beach
here and I want you to imagine that he
is tickling a peach all right take a
second and really visualize that maybe
the peaches laughing as Bill Clinton's
tickling it there will be a test at the
end of the talk alright so that's person
action object Bill Clinton tickling a
peach all right everyone got it let's
move on to our second experiment let's
imagine Albert Einstein standing in this
rip on this railroad track and I want
you to imagine imagine that he's
puckering up and kissing a piranha all
right everyone got it that's
Einstein kissing a piranha really try to
visualize that okay so today we're going
to be talking about password management
and password management is the task that
we all face every day when we go online
visit a website and that website
requires us to either create a password
or remember a password that we've
already created to authenticate the
challenge is that users don't just have
one password they have multiple accounts
so they need to authenticate with they
need to create and remember passwords
for all of for all these different
accounts so there's two competing goals
when the user tries to manage his
passwords security and usability and
informally security means that we don't
want adversaries cracking into our
accounts you know stealing our money
usability means that we don't want to
tear our hair out trying to remember all
of these darn passwords so let's look
first at the issue of security what
could go wrong and in increasing order
of danger there are three types of
attacks that an adversary could mount
online attacks offline attacks in plain
text recovery attacks I'll illustrate
each attack in the next few slides so
your online attack is your simplest form
of attack here the user registers an
account it picks his favorite password
maybe this is a bank account and he puts
a bunch of money in his bank account and
now the adversary just comes along and
he tries lots of popular password
guesses so maybe tries password he
doesn't get in he tries 123456 in this
case he gets in and can steal the user's
money so to defend against online
attacks oftentimes organizations
institute some sort of K strikes policy
in which the user is locked out after a
few incorrect guesses these policies are
relatively effective if the user picks a
strong password but of course if users
select predictable passwords like 12
3456 there's a chance that the adversary
might still break in the second type of
attack is even more dangerous here the
user registers for an account with his
favorite password again and the server
stores picks a random value
all the salt and they append this value
to the user's password in this case
unbreakable with the salt value appended
and they run this value through a hash
function and what they store on their
server is the cryptographic hash of the
password with assault appended so what
can happen you know due to
vulnerabilities and the software that
the server is running or due to
configuration errors oftentimes an
adversary is able to break into the
server and steal the cryptographic hash
file in this case the adversary can try
as many guesses as he wants he's only
limited by the resources that he's
willing to invest trying to crack the
users password so you know here the
adversary might download his favorite
tool there's you know lots of open
source tools that the adversary could
use John the Ripper is one of them he
can rent time on amazon's cloud or it
can use his own computer and you can
just brute force try lots and lots of
guesses in a large dictionary and see if
the users password matches any of these
passwords so this is unfortunately a
common problem password breaches at
major companies have affected millions
of users and as I've given this a talk
this talk over the year this Wall of
shame if you will has grown and grown
and grown so here's my slide from four
or five years ago here's a more recent
version of the slide and Yahoo really
gets extra credit for releasing the
cryptographic hash values of half a
billion users this was in the news a
week and a half ago I think where it was
500 billion password hashes and they
they've been leaked so if you have an
account on yahoo an adversary
potentially is running this type of
attack right now against your very own
password alright so the final type of
attack is a plaintext recovery attack
and fishing is one example of a
plaintext recovery attack so in this
case you know the user thinks he's
logging into paypal calm but whoopsie
didn't check the URL carefully and
this is actually pay Paul calm and in
this case he just sends the adversary
the password directly notice that in
this case it doesn't really matter how
strong the users password is because he
just gave it to the adversary there's no
no need for that verse area to crack the
password he just has it so fishing is
one example of this type of attack of
course there are lots of other examples
you could have malware on your computer
you could have a hidden camera when you
login or the website where you have the
account may just not encrypt their
passwords period for example rock you
developed games for facebook and they
decided not to encrypt their passwords
and later someone was able to break into
their servers using an SQL basic SQL
injection attack and there were 30 2.6
million passwords that are now published
online because of this and plain text
recovery is a real issue it not only
affects the account that was breached
but it can affect other accounts as well
so in particular users often reuse the
same password at multiple accounts so if
the user obtains your paypal com
password perhaps you can try using the
same password at other accounts and see
if he's successful and the problem
propagates all right so the user is
given the task of creating and
remembering multiple different passwords
in the face of all these different
threats and this is a challenging
problem and there's lots of advice that
we tend to give users traditionally and
the advice typically sounds something
like the following don't make your
password too short use a mix of upper
and lower case letters these numbers as
well as letters don't use words or names
use special symbols don't write your
password down don't ever reuse your
passwords and oh by the way if you could
change them every 90 days that would be
great yeah question
so there are programs are called he
passes their password management and
last time Mike I counted the accounts
that i have with is almost 20 in each
one of them is at a different password
and it's really hard to track down all
the passwords sometimes you forget them
so there are program called opossum I'm
thinking of actually using one of these
programs so what do you think of that
okay that's a great question so there
are password managers that kind of
automate the task of creating and
remembering multiple passwords and
password managers come with trade-offs
security and usability trade-offs so one
password manager called LastPass has
kind of been a frequent target recently
there was a breach back in 2015 and a
recent security vulnerability in 2016 so
you know well it addresses some security
concerns so there's also a single point
of failure and if you implement the
password manager incorrectly or if you
enter your master password on any
machine that's infected then you've just
given the adversary all of your
credentials so there are costs and
benefits to using a password manager and
you would have to evaluate those costs
and benefits for example if you tend to
authenticate frequently from public
computers or from a friend's computer i
would recommend against using a password
manager because now you have to expose
your master password on multiple
different devices and if you can't
ensure that any that every of these
devices is malware free then you're
exposing your master password every time
every time you authenticate so that's a
that's a great question ok so right this
is a challenging problem and that leads
me to the second point users are
frustrated with all these suggestions
it's just unusable you can't you can't
follow all these suggestions it's it's
impossible so there's a need to
reevaluate traditional advice and
Randall
ro author of the popular web comic XKCD
in fact suggested that we've been doing
passwords wrong for many years so you
know typically if you follow the
suggestions you might pick a word make
some number substitutions you know add
some special symbols at the end he's
suggesting that these these types of
passwords have much lower entropy
they're much easier to crack than just
picking four random words and he's
suggesting that for random words are
actually much easier to remember than a
than a password that looks like this now
there's been some interesting studies
recently actually coming out of out of
Purdue in which they actually asked
users to pick word based passwords XKCD
style and they found that when users are
providing the source of randomness
actually there's a pretty high collision
rate so with user randomness you know
these passwords actually aren't that
secure you might think that they have 44
bits of entropy and that's true if you
pick each word independently uniformly
at random but when users are asked to
select these words it oftentimes isn't
independent their selections oftentimes
aren't at random all right so let's look
at a couple password management
strategies that a user might adopt so
scheme one will call reuse and here just
imagine picking four random words XKCD
style and reusing that password at every
different account so at Amazon your
password is correct course battery
staple at eBay your password is also
correct towards battery staple etc all
right so well there's a natural variant
of this called strong random independent
which is basically the same thing except
for each different account you pick a
different set of forwards so Amazon
might be correct course battery staple
and eBay might be banana baseball bat
potato a table or something something
like that and for every new website that
you create you just memorize for four
new words so intuitively you might think
the first
sounds easy to do and the second one
sounds sounds quite challenging but can
we actually quantify this quantify this
intuition all right so let's go back to
the problem of password management and
let's look first at usability how can we
actually quantify the usability of a
proposed password management strategy so
to talk about usability we have to talk
about human memory and this is
challenging because human memory is not
a hard disk right this is not just a
platter where you can execute read and
write operations so human memory is
lossy that's what makes the the problem
challenging and human memory doesn't
work by just simply writing to a cell
and reading from a cell well what does
human memory look like human memories
associative so if I tell you the word
Apple you might be reminded of certain
products constructed by a company named
Apple that might remind you of text
messages you sent on said product or it
might remind you of late CEO of that
company that might remind you of other
famous CEOs and that might remind you of
you know other operating systems
designed by that CEO or maybe the word
Apple will remind remind you of other
fruits in this case you might think of
oranges you might think of orange juice
and then you might start thinking about
what you had for breakfast so when we
talk about memory it's in human memory
it's important to think about queues
what was the context when a memory was
created and stored in the human brain
the context includes the surrounding
environment when a new secret is
memorized that might include sounds what
you're hearing around you might include
your visual surroundings maybe you're
sitting at your desk when you're
creating a new password and it might
involve the website that you're sitting
in front of probably just a text box
with the label password maybe you're
also thinking about some other stuff
like tests that you have to take later
in the week and and whatnot so later on
when you try to retrieve this the secret
much of this context will be lost
so later when you try to retrieve your
your password probably the only context
that's that's the same as just this text
box that says Amazon and password
alright so how can we quantify usability
well a first attempt to quantify
usability involves chunking so suppose I
ask you to memorize the following string
NBC CBS ABC probably not too difficult
right now suppose I ask you to memorize
this string tkq izr lwp probably a
little bit more challenging why is that
well the first string is three chunks of
information three popular broadcasting
companies that most of us are familiar
with and the second string is nine
chunks of information unless you can
find some sort of meaningful way to
combine these these characters into
meaningful words it's nine independent
pieces of information that you have to
memorize so this suggests a natural goal
which is just minimize the number of
chunks in all of your passwords and this
is a natural goal but I want to argue
that this is a very incomplete goal why
do I argue that this is incomplete so
well because human memory is vast but
lossy we have plenty of space or
capacity in our brains to store all
these secrets but yet our brain
continually discards the passwords that
we've memorized we've all experienced
this at one time or another so our basic
premise is that if you memorize the
secret you need to rehearse it or you're
likely to forget that secret now the
question is how much work do you
actually have to do to memorize and
rehearse all the secrets and to quantify
usability we're going to introduce a
rehearsal assumption which basically
quantifies how often you'll need to
rehearse the secret if you want to
continue remembering it so okay here in
this picture you know suppose the user
hasn't logged into amazon for a while
maybe three months in this case the user
is likely to forget
forget that particular password so our
our memory capability is motivated by a
user study we conducted and in this user
study we gave users for person action
object stories much like the ones I gave
you at the start of this lecture and ask
them to memorize all four of these
stories and each point on this graph
represents a point in time at which we
asks ask users to return and rehearse
all four of their person action object
stories and here this graph shows the
fraction of users that were successful
when they returned divided by the total
fraction of users that actually returned
to complete that that rehearsal round
and here we can see that you know with
ten rehearsals over one hundred and
fifty six days users are highly
successful remembering all four of their
person action object stories in fact on
the last rehearsal this is the tenth
rehearsal 156 days after they initially
memorized all four stories a hundred
percent of users that returned
remembered all four of their stories
this is even after a gap of about sixty
four days since their previous rehearsal
the key point here is that memories are
strengthened with repetition yeah kind
of a slide showing the number of like
the raw number of returners and such for
those wrong number of returners um I
think it was about fifty percent of
users completed every rehearsal round so
this was a study on Amazon Mechanical
Turk and we initially invited everyone
to complete the first phase which was
memorization phase and after they
completed it we would send them emails
to ask them to return and if a user
wasn't able to return in a timely
fashion than we had to drop them from
the study if a user returned and forgot
one of their stories then we would
remind them and invite them to continue
continue participating but the key
challenge here is actually you know a
lot of users on mechanical
just don't return for follow-up studies
period and in fact you'll see that from
the memorization phase to the first
rehearsal round where the drop off is
you know about sixty percent of users
returned for that first first-round
conditioned on users returning for that
first round the return rate was pretty
high so users that that return tend to
keep returning and users that don't like
to participate in follow-up studies just
don't participate this is this is kind
of a global phenomena in all studies
that you would conduct on Mechanical
Turk with a follow-up phase you know
every every study I've seen has a return
rate of about sixty percent so for
whatever reason you know forty percent
of users either missed the reminder or
they're too busy when they get it and
just never never return okay so uh
motivated by the user study and by some
other studies older studies in cognitive
psychology we introduced the following
rehearsal assumption the assumption
basically says that you'll remember a
secret that you've memorized if you were
rehearse it at least once during each of
the following time intervals once
between day one and day two once between
day 2 and day for once between day four
and day eight of course you can adjust
the parameters of this model so that you
know the intervals don't double each
time but for simplicity we're going to
just use this as a running example okay
so now we have this assumption let's
suppose now that the user visits there
amazon account maybe on day four day
five day eight well in this case they're
naturally going to satisfy some of these
rehearsal requirements every time they
visit amazon they have to type in their
password and rehearse the corresponding
secret all right let's suppose that the
user also has a google account and that
he visits google maybe at day one and a
half maybe day four and a half maybe day
nine etc
well okay in this case we can use X sub
T to denote the total number of extra
her CIL's necessary to remember all of
your passwords forty days so in this
case whoop let's suppose that I asked
you for the value of x eight how many
extra her CIL's with these are need to
do to remember all of his passwords for
eight days well the answer depends on
what strategy the user is adopting
suppose that the user is reusing the
same password every everywhere how many
extra rehearsals just that user need to
do anyone want to venture a guess yeah
right so yeah if the passwords the same
then there's no no extra her CIL's
because you get it you get a practice
round during each of these each of these
intervals suppose instead that the user
picks independent passwords for each
account how many X rehearsals with these
are need to do in this case
maybe like 10 net so a half an extra
rehearsal kind of thing um okay well so
uh let's I guess break this down so the
user has an Amazon password which they
don't rehearse during this window so if
we want to guarantee that the user
remembers the password we're going to
have to remind the user to rehearse
rehearse their password once during this
window and that's you know an extra
rehearsal beyond what they would do in
their natural course of internet usage
similarly for Google the user is going
to have to be reminded to rehearse as
google password once during this
interval because he doesn't visit Google
during that time interval so in this
case there's two extra rehearsals that
the user would need to do to remember
all those passwords for eight days so
our usability measure is actually going
to be X T just the total number of extra
rehearsals to remember all of your
passwords forty days and now our
usability goal is naturally minimize the
total number of rehearsal reminders
beyond a natural internet usage alright
so so we looked at a toy example but so
what about users that have you know more
than two accounts so you can introduce a
model of of the user in particular you
can introduce a model of an active user
with 75 accounts you know some of these
accounts they visit every day some of
the accounts maybe they visit once every
week maybe some of the accounts they
only visit once a month and now you can
actually predict how many extra her
CIL's disease or need over his lifetime
to remember all of these passwords and
even our active user needs about 3,000
extra rehearsal reminders over his
lifetime to remember all of his
passwords if the user reuses the same
password then even our infrequent or
occasional user basically never needs an
extra rehearsal reminder at all so our
in free our occasional user only needs a
point one that means with you know
probability one-tenth you might need to
send them one rehearsal reminder over
his lifetime and our infrequent you
user who's visiting most of his accounts
you know once a month or once a year
think of grandma when you think of the
infrequent user would only need three
extra rehearsal reminders of her his or
her lifetime to remember remember all
for passwords alright so we have one
scheme that's usable and one scheme
that's unusable so if we weren't
concerned about security at all the
answer is obvious just reuse the same
password all right of course security is
an issue so we have to talk about
security and how we want to quantify
security so before i define security
formally let me just go over our
high-level approach or philosophy so we
want to make a dangerous world
assumption a lot of times so when people
do password analysis they're only
looking at current adversaries they're
looking at how secure their scheme would
be against current attackers but in our
view it's not enough to just defend
against existing adversaries because
after you propose a new strategy the
adversary can adapt his scheme to be as
effective as possible against your
strategy so we want to make a dangerous
world assumption we want to assume that
the adversary is going to adapt his
attack to be as effective as possible
against our scheme and we want to
provide guarantees even when things go
wrong so this means that even if the
adversary sees the cryptographic hash of
your password and maybe one of your
other passwords he still shouldn't be
able to crack that cryptographic hash so
this means that offline attacks should
fail with high probability and we want
to limit the damage of successful
phishing attacks alright so formally
we're going to treat security as a game
between the user and the adversary and
the user moves first in this game he
picks his password management strategy
and now he registers for registers at
lots of different accounts with
passwords following whatever strategy he
picked and now the adversary gets to
move and the adversary gets to point at
you know let's say one of the users
account accounts
this case PayPal and say show me the
users paypal com password and in the
game the adversaries shown the users
paypal com password then the adversary
gets to point out one of the users
accounts and say show me the
cryptographic hash of the users let's
say playstation com password and in this
case the adversary gets the
cryptographic hash value and now the
adversaries given a budget with which to
crack the users password for example
maybe the adversary is given a million
dollars to rent computing resources on
Amazon Cloud and now we can use these
resources to try to crack crack teasers
password so he's given a fixed number of
guesses that he's that he's able to try
and the num the specific number of
guesses depends depends largely on the
particular password hash function that
was used so if say sha-256 was your
password hash function then within a
second on a GPU you can evaluate
billions and billions of password
guesses if you do a little bit of key
stretching for example bcrypt instead of
returning the hash value it iterates
this hash function lots of times to make
this process more expensive and there
are even more effective key stretching
pools besides bcrypt for example I might
recommend s crypt or other memory hard
functions if you want to if you want to
do password hashing but once this
password hash function is fixed then
there's a cost cost associated with
computing the stash function and that
gives the adversary a fixed number of
guesses that he can try so the user wins
this game if the adversary fails to
crack any of the passwords that he
doesn't already have so in this case you
know if the adversary manages to get any
of the users other passwords other than
paypal com the user the adversary would
win this game and if the adversary fails
then the user wins this game so to
formalize this we say that the adversary
can compromise at most our sites plain
text recovery attacks and the adversary
can execute offline attacks against at
most H additional sites
and due to resource constraints the
adversary has a budget cue that he's
willing that he's able to spend during
an offline attack the adversary wins
this game if he can compromise any new
sites and this looks like alphabet soup
but throwing all the parameters of the
game on one slide we say that a scheme
is Q Delta M s rh secure if the
probability that the adversary wins this
game given all the parameters is that
most Delta here RQ is number of offline
guesses m is the number of user accounts
s is the number of online guesses that
the adversary can try before he gets
locked out r is the number of plaintext
passwords that the adversary gets to
observe and h is the number of password
hashes that the adversary gets to
observe so as a simple example q delta m
311 security is when the adversary gets
one password and one password hash value
and q guess is to break that password
hash and it's secure if the if the user
wins this game with high probability all
right so well so what about security we
can use our two toys games again reusing
the same password we can look at
different security parameters well in
this case it's very easy to analyze once
the adversary gets one password it's
game over so the scheme isn't secure
with our equals one it isn't secure with
our equals to R equals three etc once
the user gets one once adversary gets
one password it's game over similarly if
we pick independent passwords it doesn't
matter how many passwords the adversary
actually observed so he's not going to
learn anything about these there's other
passwords because they're independent
and because they're strong and random
he's unlikely to crack any of these
passwords in an offline attack so in
this case we're secure under all of
these attack scenarios so great we have
one scheme that's usable and highly
insecure another scheme that's highly
unusable but secure the question is can
we find anything better so
our approach as I hinted at at the
beginning of the talk uses person action
object stories and we're going to divide
these stories into two pieces a public Q
and a private secret so the public Q is
a scene and a person in this case LeBron
James on the bridge and the private
secret is a random action in a random
object that the user has associated with
these images so in this case LeBron
James is kicking a penguin on the bridge
by the way I don't have a violent
imagination that actually was the
randomly generated example okay so once
once the users memorized all these all
these stories what does the login screen
look like well login screen is just a
sequence of challenges in this case
you're asked for the action involving
LeBron James on the bridge then the
object then maybe the object involving
Albert Einstein at the railroad tracks
and the user has to type in all of these
secrets or maybe the first three letters
from each from each word all right and
similarly when the user are locked into
paypal you'll see a similar set of
challenges all right and if you are
paying attention you'll notice that this
first piece of the challenge was the
same for paypal and and for eBay or was
that eBay sorry paypal and Amazon all
right so we are sharing some of these
cues across different websites and as we
saw before sharing cues has certain
usability advantages one potentially
there's fewer stories to remember
overall and there's also more natural
rehearsal for each of the stories that
you have to memorize now of course the
question is what about security isn't
reusing secrets across websites and
insecure practice i well know and we'll
use a combinatorial design to ensure
that any pair of accounts has at most
gamma secret stories in common so in
this case you might think of gammas one
meaning that any pair of accounts that
the user has should share up most
one common secret so formally we can
introduce an NL gamma sharing set family
we're set family is just a sequence of
subsets s 1 through n sm each of these
subsets is a subset of the universe 1
through n and each subset should have
size l so here m is the total number of
passwords each subset corresponds to the
secrets that the user might use at a
particular account for example SI is the
secret that you use to authenticate to
account I and gamma tells you how much
information one password might leak
about another password l tells you how
long each password is and n is the total
number of Secrets that the user has to
memorize so this is an NL gamma sharing
sharing set family how many passwords
can you actually form if you use this
this trick well suppose that you only
are willing to memorize for person
action object stories like the users in
our mechanical turk study well in this
case i claim that you can actually form
up to 14 different passwords with the
guarantee that any pair of password any
with a guarantee that every password
uses for secrets in any pair of
passwords intersects in utmost to
secrets so in this case you have
security against an adversary who sees
one of your passwords but you don't
provide security against an adversary
you see is two of your passwords after
an adversary sees two of your passwords
he can potentially start to predict
other passwords all right well suppose
right to an adversary with one password
is unlikely to guess any of your other
passwords suppose that you have more
than 14 accounts suppose that you have
75 accounts well in this case if you're
willing to memorize 7 person action
object stories you can generate up to 75
passwords with the same exact security
guarantee all right so that's great but
what if you want stronger security
guarantees well ok suppose that you're
willing to memorize 15 person action
object stories in this
case you can have 75 unique passwords
with security against any adversary you
seen up to two of your passwords so if
the adversary gets to see any two of
your passwords of this choosing you
still can't predict any of your other
passwords and if you're really motivated
you could memorize 43 person action
object stories and in this case you'd
get two very extreme security guarantee
any adversary who's seen up to six of
your passwords is still not going to be
able to predict any of your other any of
your other passwords yeah if you do four
person action object stories do you know
how many passwords you could do with say
the two password security oh if you
memorize for person action object
stories security against to uh off the
top of my head uh I don't know I my
guess is not very many but I'd have to
actually try to run a computer program
to compute the corresponding
combinatorial design my intuition is not
very many but I could be wrong I could
be wrong about that so yet to get you
know to get stronger guarantees you know
this this technique is particularly
powerful as the number of stories grows
so you know with 15 stories i can get
security to and 75 accounts if i just
add one more story i think the number of
passwords that i could form skyrockets
up to like 160 or something like that so
you know the technique is powerful and
it's you do get a lot of growth once you
pass a certain threshold but my
conjecture is that if you want security
to with four stories you're you're still
not going to be passed that threshold
and yet the construction is not going to
be not going to be particularly large so
my guess is you can't create too many
too many passwords yeah
no I was wondering who gets to choose
the action and the object yeah that's it
that's an excellent question um so we're
recommending that these are actually
random system assigned actions and
objects in the user study we conducted
these were system assigned actions and
objects that the users were memorizing
and the reason we use system assigned
actions and objects is that you know if
users are selecting their own actions
and objects they might select an action
or an object that's highly correlated
with the person or seeing that they see
so if they have Bill Clinton on the
beach for example maybe actions like
swimming or objects like shark are
natural objects to associate with a
beach but in our case it was tickling a
peach because these are random actions
and objects you know it's it's not
something that's necessarily associated
with the person or scene and in fact you
know what we found is that these random
system assigned actions and objects are
are memorable so you know if you can go
with system assigned words that's
certainly the most most secure option
yeah yeah I wanted to ask the challenge
posed by amazon is fixed over time yes
and do amazon and paypal need to
coordinate who'd like what challenges
they will be posing right so okay that's
that's an excellent question so yes
first of all the challenge that you
would see when you visit amazon is going
to be fixed it's going to be the same
every time so your password is going to
be be the same every time you visit
amazon do amazon and ebay need to
coordinate i would love it if they would
realistically I don't think this is ever
going to happen so the way i use the
scheme personally is I just have a
spreadsheet on google where I record
amazon and the associated cues we are
working on developing a browser
attention which functions like a
password manager except that it doesn't
keep any secret state it just stores the
challenges that you would need to
authenticate every different website and
I say and one more question like in this
one so suppose today a kid starts and he
is able to remember only four stories
and 14 password suffices as he grows old
he might be willing to learn more
stories yes and does your community
really design in update dynamically or
it does it need to be refreshed
completely that's that's a great
question so currently know the
combinatorial design does not update
dynamically getting a combinatorial
design that does update dynamically is
one of the research directions that
we're trying to push hard right now so
that is that is a great question and I
think the intuition is spot-on you know
it's going to be tough for a user to
memorize 15 stories all at once and in
fact you know we would recommend so if
you adopt the scheme as is that you kind
of memorize the stories in advance
before you start using the scheme and
you just slowly memorize the stories
eventually you've memorized enough
stories and now you can start using the
scheme so that's a that's a great
question and the intuition is spot-on we
are trying very hard to push push in
that direction and kind of allow for
incremental memorization so a user can
start using the scheme after they
memorize for stories but increase
security over time all right so as far
as security goes if you use this 36 to
sharing set family so memorizing 15
stories each story gives you two secrets
in action in an object then you can get
security under the first three attack
scenarios but if the adversary sees two
of your passwords then potentially when
he sees another password he knows four
of the secrets and he can brute force
over the remaining two secrets so it's
not secure if the adversary sees to any
two passwords of his choosing and then
gets too
execute an offline attack and if you
only memorize for stories or seven
stories you pick this weaker weaker
version then you provide security under
this first scenario where the adversary
gets to see any one of your passwords
but security starts to break down if the
adversary gets more information for
example if he sees one of your passwords
and then gets the cryptographic hash
then he can execute a successful offline
attack alright so as far as usability we
can run the same same algorithm predict
to predict how many extra her CIL's the
user would need over his lifetime to
remember these secrets and here we can
see that you know our active user is
going to need somewhere between four and
ten extra her CIL's over his lifetime to
remember all these secrets and in fact
most of these rehearsals are going to
come within the first week after
memorizing all the secrets so after you
know in the first week you might have to
annoy the user a few times but after
that first week most likely the user is
going to continue to remember all of the
secrets that he's remembered so now we
have schemes that you know it's a little
bit more difficult to use than just
reusing the same password but much more
secure and it's a little bit less secure
than picking strong random independent
passwords but much more much more usable
all right so future directions as we
kind of hinted at how would you actually
use this this game well if you wanted to
adopt it right now you would have to
basically set up your own spreadsheet
and record amazon and here's the
associated cues you know LeBron James
action Bill Clinton object etc so we'd
like to develop a browser extension and
this is a project that we're working on
right now which would allow you to have
the computer just show you the
appropriate cues when you login so you
know right now for me the most annoying
feature of the scheme is not remembering
the secrets but opening up the
spreadsheet and finding the associated
cues so
if we can eliminate this challenge I
think this game is going to be much much
easier to use and also as Himanta
indicated gradual password strengthening
so can we allow a user to memorize for
password fourth person action object
stories initially and increase security
over time instead of demanding that the
users memorize all their secrets upfront
another important direction is
recovering forgotten secrets so you know
what happens if the user does happen to
forget one of these person action object
stories we have some ideas about ways to
construct a secure recovery mechanism
which would allow a user to recover any
forgotten secret given that he can
remember most of his other other stories
and in this case the idea would be to
use error correcting codes and some
other tools from cryptography to make
the mechanism something in it that's
completely inaccessible to an adversary
who doesn't know already know most of
these are secrets in a final direction
one that I think is potentially
interesting to explore is intrusion
detection so we have a model spaced
repetition model that allows us to
predict when a user is going to forget
their password if they don't rehearse so
what happens if you're a server and you
observe a user logging in at time one
he's successful you observe him login an
hour later he's successful and then you
know an hour later these are logs in
three times and he's unsuccessful every
time well that seems a little bit
suspicious because it seems like the
user has memorized the password and all
of a sudden he's forgotten it whereas if
you see the user login you know once
that day one and he gets the password
correct and then maybe you know three
months later he tries to log in and
these incorrect three times this might
be less suspicious so the question is
whether we can use the space repetition
model to actually gain some intuition
and predict which login attempts may or
may not be an entry
are trying to access the users account
so thank you for listening and I'll take
any questions all right I think we had
one yes yeah what is the role of two FA
in the password cracking cracking like
what is the role of two factor
authentication so I mean two factor
authentication could certainly be used
in addition in addition to any of this
games that we we propose you know of
course when a two-factor authentication
is great you know encourage anyone to
adopt it whenever possible it's not
universally available some companies
offer it some you know google offers at
some organizations tend not to offer it
but you know even if you use two-factor
authentication there's still there's
still that risk that an adversary will
break into the server and be able to
execute that offline attack on your on
your password so even then it's you know
even if you're using two-factor
authentication it's still good to have
independent passwords if if possible any
other questions yeah I think I already
asked you if that password based
authentication scheme has such a
difficulties why don't we move to
hardware based authentication or
fingerprint ok this is a this is a great
question so there's been a lot of work
over really last few decades trying to
replace passwords so you have hardware
authentication you have biometrics you
have graphical passwords you know you
have your RSA I you know securid tokens
and in 2004 Bill Gates kind of famously
declared the password is dead but you
know here's a plot of the number of
passwords that that are being used over
time
and you know there's this is the point
in time at which Bill Gates declares the
password is dead and this is what's
happened since so you know somehow
despite all of these attempts to replace
passwords they don't seem to be going
away well why is that so we have
password management software that's one
potential replacement but as we
mentioned earlier now you have to trust
all the computational devices that you
ever use what happens if one's infected
with malware or what happens if there's
a security breach at one of the password
managers that would be problematic of
course password managers are only one
alternative you know there's like
Hardware tokens biometrics I scanners
and there was a paper published in 2012
by be know her leave in or shot and
others called the quest to replace
passwords they kind of looked at all of
these proposed replacements and found
that really none of them is that silver
bullet that we that we need to replace
passwords so you know despite all their
issues a password has a low amortized
cost per user so if your Facebook and
you haven't you haven't raised capital
yet they had a million users before they
started to raise any capital you know
you can't issue all of your customers an
RSA securid tag it's just you know too
much money passwords are essentially
free to to implement you know there's
they're mature you have open source
implementations of password libraries
like bcrypt so it's kind of free to free
to implement so if you're a facebook and
you have these options are you going to
use passwords or are you going to use
you know RSA securid well of course
you're going to use passwords you know
similarly we could think about
biometrics well the advantage is there's
nothing to remember I just have to have
my finger but you know what happens if
an adversary is able to obtain my
biometric you know I can't change my
fingerprint once it's gone it's gone and
in fact you know I'm kind of leaking my
fingerprint every time I touch something
in fact i'm potentially licking my
finger print right now when I wave it in
front of the high-definition camera in
fact a German hacker looked at a
high-resolution photo of angela merkel's
of Angela Merkel zoomed in on one of her
fingers and actually was able to extract
the fingerprint and forge authentication
credentials so there's lots of proposed
replacements but none of these
replacements is strictly better than
passwords they have some some advantages
but they always come with that critical
disadvantage which means that you know
until we find a replacement that's going
to address all of these security and
usability criteria most likely passwords
are here to stay for better or worse
you