hi it's chris rides here from tyro
security
uh this is video two we've done in
partnership with the diana initiative
it's to help hiring managers
try and stop the bottlenecks that they
might be uh
finding in their hiring process so this
is the second video
and it's actually covering the interview
process
so i've got a saying i've kind of
adapted from
from something that we see commonly in
recruitment and i call it time
kills all fields so what does that mean
a long poor quality interview process
that results in candidates that think
you're not keen on them
results in candidates that take another
job before they can get to your final
stages
candidates that end up with multiple
officer offers and lots of processes
going on
um which can can completely change what
they
required or what they were looking for
at the beginning of your process
and what they're now looking for things
like salary
um other benefits also
it can also cause you know you'll take a
lot of time you can then have a lot more
to think about and all of a sudden
you're delaying your hiring and that
might mean that you
don't get your first choice and you miss
out on your second and third choice
candidates
and so we're going to focus on these
three things
it's going to be focusing on who
interviews going to focus on
how do they interview and then how do
you go around gathering feedback
so talk about interview panels um
i think it's really important that
they're very lean i've got to say in the
20 years i've been in recruitment
it was very common for me to see
processes with just one or two
interview people interviewing literally
two people on
on the interview panel two of them said
yes they bring people in
now it seems much more common to see
maybe four five six different people
interviewing even for non-exec positions
and and i think if
if people were if we were seeing that
people were staying longer in their
positions now
we'd be saying i can understand why
that's happening but the fact is we're
not seeing any any sort of increases in
how long people stay in jobs so
you know i i like to talk about keeping
your interview panel
as lean as possible so if they don't
need to be on the panel
they shouldn't be on the panel if this
is part of
somebody's role growing and you want
them to be part of the interview process
because
they're going to be doing that as part
of their their role at some point you
see them
as somebody that should be involved
that's great but until they're ready to
do an interview on your own
they should maybe just sit in with
somebody else's and and
and do that rather than adding an
additional interview stage
and also if you've got people in your
interview panel
that have very little time for
interviewing you should really think
about
alternatives to that person you know
they're clearly a very
very busy and because the delays that
they can cause
can cause real big issues remember time
kills
all fields and be very aware of extra
people on the panel
the more people you have on the panel
the less likelihood you're going to get
agreement across the board that every
person likes that person
and it's more likely that you're gonna
end up with either no hire at all
and sometimes we see companies come to
us and they've been looking for nine
months and
often it's when we sit down these are
the first things we go through the
processes
we see issues and and
so it can cause no higher at all or
you get a higher and that higher hasn't
got everybody's 100 buy-in because
you've gone with the majority
are you really setting that person up
for success are they going to come in
and work with the team
and do well with somebody there who's
thinking well i said no to this person
and you know do you want somebody that's
like i told you so i told them you told
you they wouldn't work out so
just bear that in mind let's keep it as
lean as possible
cut through do you really need all those
people on the panel so
once you've got that you then got to
think about what are those people
interview for
so each individual person you've got
what are they interviewing for
look at your essentials on the job
description we did that in the last
video
look at the essentials what are they
interviewing for
this person is interviewing for this
these two people both interview for this
do you need both of them on there so
start thinking about that
do they understand what they are
interviewing for
um are they all in the same page have
you actually had your whole interview
panel in a meeting and discussed
what's going to happen during that
interview have you discussed well this
person is going to be interviewing for
this
this person is going to be interviewing
for this are they all on the same page
have you actually discussed the plan be
surprised how many times people have not
actually done that
so remember as i always say kiss kiss
kiss
keep it simple
so you're thinking about the quality of
your interview process
and and also the quality of the people
interviewing how do they interview
so just remember when they you know when
do they actually interview
have you got the people in the right
order nothing worse than the candidate
or yourself even going through wasting
all this time both your time the
candidate's time going through all of
this process
only to find at the end that it's a no
and it's a no for something that should
have been picked up right at the
beginning
so have you got people in the right
order doing their interviews
right this could save you a lot of time
and it's you've got to think about your
branding and what it says about company
when
people get right the way to the end and
it doesn't work out right also
how do these people interview you this
is such a common issue
and hiring managers
don't like there's a lot of assuming
going on there's a lot of assuming
this is how my colleague interviews they
don't actually know
so as the hiring manager this person's
gonna work for you
have you sat in on an interview with
every single
person on your interview panel if not
why not
you should know exactly how the
interview should know what they're
interviewing for
and you should do that on a regular
basis you don't need to sit in everyone
but you know whether that's if you're
depending on how often you're hiring
you know should that be once a month you
know how often is it but you should
definitely
do that because it does change and
people interview one way in front of you
and then you know give it a couple of
months they might change their interview
style or the questions they're asking
and so it's really important that you
see it on the interviews it can bring
absolutely eye-opening results you know
it's really common to see duplication of
areas
two people interviewing for exactly the
same thing when they're not supposed to
that's not what you discussed
maybe somebody interviewing for one area
and then just going completely off into
a completely different area like a
completely different topic
and not even covering the area they
originally agreed to
and inappropriate questions you know
questions that
hr certainly wouldn't like to know of
being asked and lawyers
love that they're being asked so just
bear that in mind
so last part feedback you know
fast in-depth feedback this is what you
should be looking at
now when you book an hour of somebody's
time to do an interview are you booking
15 minutes straight afterwards
for them to take the time to give the
feedback while it's
fresh in their mind and whether that's
following whatever pro
process your company actually has and
you want to make sure you get detailed
feedback and you want to have the time
you don't want them to think
four days later what was it that was
that person i've actually had feedback
come
from the wrong person because they're
getting mixed up
you know because they've interviewed so
many people they're mixing up the
interview
so it's really important that the
feedback times booked
to do that we constantly see
people on the interview panel give
really superficial feedback
not in depth and that often take days to
actually give it
you know in-depth feedback whether it's
positive or negative
is really useful for recruiters hr
for people to do a better job by you to
make sure that you get people that
are better fit for what you're looking
for so it's really important that
your feedback is given in depth even
positive feedback
positive feedback's so hard to get in
depth just to tell really like this
about this person
this is what we discussed on their
resume it was really interesting it's a
great fit for this
you know just make sure that you know
you're you you do give that detailed
feedback
speed's really important so that kind of
moves us on to getting it to the
candidate quickly as well
you've got to ensure what your company
processes for giving feedback
who gives the feedback how does it
happen when does it happen
you want to make sure there are absolute
minimal delays between
getting that feedback and giving it to
the candidate and moving the process
on right we've seen candidates lost
both from the interviewers not getting
their feedback
quickly enough to hr you know we speak
to hr and internal recruiters baby
and they're telling us we still not
heard from this person well we're
talking to the hiring manager or cso and
they haven't had the feedback yet
so it's really important you emphasize
how the feedback comes very quickly
likewise we've seen feedback where we
get told the feedback's been passed to
hr and they'll get
back to you and you know a day two days
later we're hearing the feedback in some
cases it's actually positive feedback
which is just insane this is something
you need to do quickly
right quick feedback especially when
it's positive makes candidates feel
wanted
right and the opposite's true when
you know the exact opposite is true when
you're you're delaying that feedback
so you know remember let's get it done
let's get it done quickly
and the industry is very very small
right
every interview your team
your company you as an individual
is you know you're being looked at by
that candidate
and that can that's going to tell other
candidates going to tell other people in
the industry
what it was like to be interviewed by
you so you've got to think of that when
you're going through this process
so look that's the end of video two
don't forget
time kills all feels right let's get
spread through now you can contact me
via twitter
i'm not on there an awful lot when you
see me tweeting stuff it's usually from
my linkedin
linkedin's the best way to connect with
me make sure you put something
in the note that you know you've seen
this talk and
you know something along those lines i
get a lot of junk as i'm sure everybody
else does you know a lot of people
that want to connect that you know are
trying to do all sorts of things
probably nefarious
stuff as well bearing in mind that i run
a cyber security company so i have to be
very careful
so just take time bit time and put a
note in there you can also check out our
website www.tyrosex.com
you'd be able to connect and find me via
that as well so look
i really appreciate your time thank you
again for uh diana initiative to
you know working with us to allow us to
to do this and i hope you found it
really useful
thank you