hello everyone I have disliked flight
into my face so I don't see you a lot
but I would like to welcome you and to
get on my knees together with my
colleagues hope we are going to talk
about how to bypass morrow detection
mechanisms deployed in online banking ok
thank you all for coming because it's i
think quite late so what we do we are
both mental SYSOUT securing company is a
company based in Krakow before that we
both house have experience as a software
developers in our current occupation we
mostly taste as I said we are
professionals mostly
banking sites mobile applications web
applications related to financial sector
we have tested multiple multi-factor
systems multi-factor authentication for
certification systems also we did some
more analysis post-mortem and we help
our customers to stop and going moderate
tax ok that would be short about us
this is the agenda for today we are
going to start with such small
introduction to give you a call concepts
related to mother to and from our two to
start to discuss then we will discuss
potential attack vectors on script based
Muller
script based on tomorrow's elections and
then we will go through recommendations
for improvement in such solutions and
later on we are we want to discuss with
you I work so I pass the mic to cuba who
dis do this introduction part ok so
first we have to answer a simple
question why this topic is so
interesting well why is it hard to
protect online banking applications
against malware or viruses like this
time they are stand-alone executables
are not reliable you can sign for
example the virus fight to virustotal or
any other service and you can see that
not every antivirus catches positively
so the second thing is that our lazy
they do not want to install stand-alone
executables click 10 times then use
space or the discs and and anything all
the question for you are you lazy I
would like a simple question supposing
you you're sending transfer your online
banking applications for example it's
invoice for telecommunication services
you open your invoice for your copy your
bank account on dress on the first page
in the bank you you just paste this
address type your amount on the second
page you have to pass code which you
received on the second tunnel in the SMS
what do you do what do you compare of
course we compare the amount and you
compared the banking godless we fought
what what we compared with the screen
then you're lazy then you're lazy
because some of my where some of the
model where can change what you see on
the screen because it's in the banking
in the browser application what you
should do is actually comparing it to
the paper invoice or at least invoice in
the PDF file right ok so so there is a
market cap for new solutions on the
market the solutions which work in the
browser's which our client list in the
mean of you don't need to install any
standalone application you just you're
just a simple client who opened banking
website and all the magic stuff for
detection mechanism is done
automatically and that the last thing is
there is a lot of money and banking
industry we all know that ok so how does
my work or actually how the some of my
work first of all it interacts with the
browser using web being jerks most of my
most of banking model or does it do you
sweat being text we just small
JavaScript code which is included into
the into the banking website it's done
actually on the client side so so they
intercepted between the server and the
client
sometimes it works the other way for
example by changing the process memory
of the brosser changing banking account
address you know these mower so what is
the purpose of banking of course it's
still credentials to the banking
application intended transaction data to
steal the money and sometimes it
automates attacks by for example
clicking simulating user clicks or
actions
so how does JavaScript based malware
detection works so aim is to detect
our presence and it can work on
different layers so here is like a
simple diagram of of the data flow when
the user open the banking website so the
mechanism can catch signatures of the
HTTP response from the server to the
browser it can fingerprints the
terrorist groups and the block in the
brother of course it can fingerprint
user and blossom behavior I mean the
speed of clicking the speed of typing
letters and mouse movement that's how
Google recapturing the works of course
in the back there is some production
system which analyzes transactional data
and our detecting system can work also
there so the action of this solution is
to drop a remark sessions as compromised
what are the limits of the solution
these are the metals I mentioned before
her got a simple simple graph of
marketing audit ability of the solutions
and by marketing I mean marketing power
of of saying such phrases so when a
marketing person goes into the bank and
assay our solution uses HTTP response of
nature people from the bank ok why not
and also the ability of this is very big
like you can of course check which are
this which signatures which model
by the signatures and so on but when the
marketing person goes into the bank and
say oK we've got some fraud detection
system which uses a must in learning
deep learning and big data cloud systems
apt then the marketing of this is you
know why don't you know this is quite
hard recently we've been testing some
voice recognition technology actually
its voice authentication to the bank
we found some vulnerability we've been
able to bypass authentication voice
authentication once and for defender
actually wants is OK I posted one's
learning big data cloud computing system
updated to your apt I can't now we are
we are not vulnerable but okay come on
in place of banking I think once is
enough
ok small disclaimer
we do not represent any vendor we do not
create such solutions we can close out
one if you want we want to show mainly
implementation and architecture error
source the whole idea of script based
anti-malware and we want to talk about
what can be done to get the solutions
better so
victors for client using online banking
applications
our approach of testing was to meet the
brosser we've some underwear allies to
JavaScript of this detection solution
which comes from the web server analyzed
outgoing traffic and sometimes we had
access to the administrative interface
in the transactional system it was for
example other main console to view logs
and see the colors of the solution
I so our first idea was simple it's not
magic really we were intercepting a
sleepy trusting in the clean machine
infected machine we did some action
let's say that actually was to login
into bank what we see we did some JS
analyzes and we've seen that on the
infected machines are some different
paths different subdomains there were a
lot of base 64 strings which didn't
appear in the clinching traffic and
we've seen some encryption are symmetric
keys and so on so what we did actually
counting this HTTP requests we seeing
that on the cleaning machine we've got
just simple one action and on the
infected machine we've got something
more so what would you do issue if you
are operating model we're actually
creating a model where and you'll see
that your mother were on the infected
machine creates more HTTP requests what
would you do
one more time
ok well I mean we analyzed and we see
that this is a little bit stronger line
is is the requests we think that it is
prices there is money order anybody else
yeah I'd like so just disable these DVDs
SDP request and actually like if it
bleeds we can kill it so we we just for
example change DNS of these sub-domain
or just a sleepy request we can do this
in javascript no problem and its
bypassed so like for example for his use
family model where disabling the HTTP
request this other song request is just
like one line of code and it shows us a
bigger architecture problem because
actually like on a business level this
solution work by sending a red light so
the anti-malware magic script sends the
red light this machine is infected
why not send the red or green light
instead so all signatures check if there
was more aware and finally sent this
machine is generally no matter where we
called adverse inference ok so once the
mower was spotted we found 10 bility in
a few solutions in this red light
request there was there was another
solid contain some data logging of the
user the time and the behavior or
sometimes in the behavior it was said it
is suspicious sometimes it was even
the name of the malware so what would
you do for example this request if the
browser sends the request of of the
alert why not change it and so it's ok
this this machine is not infected its
machine off user to affected and
actually it worked pretty well so in the
other interface when we viewed the logs
you can see that there was no suspicious
activity from either one but from the
user to ok and last thing the like I
think most money for me was the first
things first so if this magic is a big
bunch of various groups its takes some
time to load the dumbest trade right we
we've been testing dissolution for such
a long time that I've been doing some
well it was not it was money well
testing but I was really doing it fast
so freaking blogging clicking blogging
typing passport and some at some point
on the infected machine locked so fast
fast enough that the anti-malware magic
didn't work it's because of the red line
is because of the red green
red green architecture problem
JavaScript download so I was able to log
on the infected machine with no other
well I possible thanks
ok so now we're going out to deep dive
into how this nature stuff works
brilliantly on the client side we have
some script JavaScript coyotes fall to
US sales are because JavaScript ease the
load it from the server actually you can
see it from the process itself out on
the other side on the server side we
have some API you related to this
solution of game and we have some
signatures present on the client site
will discuss it in a moment this is one
part of the second one is some reasoning
engine something which decides we are
going to send this art or not sometimes
it was related to some encryption a
symmetric encryption and still here
encryption is ok but you have to
remember that if Javascript and trips
and I think the public is also present
there so I was discussed this example
the message with the login user while
and user to was encrypted but still we
had to encryption key so the message
itself cannot be trusted in case of the
values that say the user right
what do you think about notification ok
that's why I think so I'm gonna say I'm
a fan of codification because it was you
have to understand the purpose of
education it's has to make more
difficult more time consuming more
resource consuming to attack a roadside
to analyze to understand what's going on
in here having the site we have
signatures so what we're looking for and
the reasoning engine how actually it
works
embedded on the client site so I think
we have to protect it
we have to make it hard to understand
the cult itself and also hiding in plain
sight also to embed in some real
JavaScript inside the application in
case of codification we found i dont
didn't escape cold at all or it was
easily to use it to buy possible but
still some applications if you look into
the transcripts related therefore skated
got it was quite easy to spot because it
was different
all of the rest of the card was not
obligated small parts was out that's
what interested us there so simple
obfuscation some pics and coding based
64 strengths
quite easily to the culture just what we
recommend in case of obligation is to
use multiple JavaScript obfuscation
taking that whilst
scripts and to change them for example
some of the solutions we generated each
time the JavaScript which was which were
taught it to analyze this anthem out of
26 for signatures was donated each every
time the page was loaded so you could
use the interchange
obfuscation techniques to make it hard
to understand and make it how to
automate their frustration of course how
to be there are speaking about
signatures we found two approaches
signatures server side and plain sight
how does the initial server-side works
basically user requests that some sites
you navigate to his banking site and he
got old ahd and I'll JavaScript CSS
files also he got this detection script
which signatures were really regular
expressions we extract parts of the
rendered HTML site and those parts store
struck months were sent back to allies
to the server so here the signatures may
be there weren't easy to see what some
of some of the analysis was done on the
server side but still we knew we now
which parts of the website where I sit
here and second approach was signatures
client site so they must be for
navigators and got all the stuff of HTML
JavaScript CSS stuff in it and also our
pilot action script and he got
signatures and battered US also in the
script which are what is signatures it
was some concern strength functions
which were the JavaScript related to
signature were looking for
your for example window object some
constant financial names variable names
sometimes also the type of the object
related to given name was also checked
and then signatures were analyzed and
the responses were sent back to the
server so actually doing as I said
before the obfuscation we are able to
see really which signatures which
JavaScript objects related to Web
injects
applications under my arm and was
looking for one other thing there are
two approach because here we have one
crisis to crisis in Italy industry
interests sorry initialization face when
he started and then the reporting face
when results are sent back to the server
so we had two phases actually and you
could either ask about that blocked the
first think the initialization and
secondly you can also manipulate what
was sent back to the server and one of
solutions we just thought it was like
this something there was an error of my
numbers and each signature practices
related to changing or not depending on
if the mother was found are not changing
that one of dole's in disarray and then
this area was sent back to the server so
basically we had if there is there were
no matter who were present on the
machine we had actual results
peres was sent back to the server as it
was sent to the browser so nonetheless
we had minor or not we could also folks
that we are clear message to the server
and send it back so
case of client-side signatures now
moving to the last part of our talk to
conclusions we divided into two groups
for potential buyers of such solutions
we think it's good approach to have to
boot or to buy this kind of social
because I think in the end user will get
them are under station so we have to
somehow protected business and this is
OK in case of buying don't believe and
military great technology dollars into
marketing bullshit ask for teachers how
it works to how it really works
request also left Imani our
infrastructure try to see how easily it
will marry into your existing web
applications into your existing
monitoring solution this is also such
solutions while layer of defense you
cannot forget you have to have strategy
right you have to have people watching
it what is also most importantly in such
a solution I think not them our
detection right which it holds but I
think one of the most important thing is
how weak it is social kind of response
to an ongoing malware attacks which it
doesn't stop at this very moment how
quickly I chose two nations can be
deployed to stop something which is
hurting you are really very moment okay
so also we think it's important to
gather knowledge insight have not only
have it but I understand how it works to
improve ourselves and to trust but
verify right you have to trust it works
but trying to check ok going to the
vendors I would like to second at all
the vendors we found our we are reported
to them and
we did it in a responsible discussion
matter so as I said before this is good
pass to build such lessons but still
have to remember that we have processor
servers HTTP HTML Javascript and all the
good and bad which comes with it so
remember . remember how JavaScript work
remember pluses and minuses of
codification think about your
architecture try to be one step before
your potential attackers what's next
actually we've finished allow some time
ago a paper which we can analyze the
sect help you both a solution like this
one if the intercepts police find us we
are here at the conference site or stand
you can write an email tweet it to us
wherever however I approached us however
you wish now questions if you have any I
don't see hands because of the light
just one maybe I was like yes please
quick question how reliable is it to
detect signatures like if I drink a
redbull is my signature of how use my
online banking very different if I'm
tired too drunk whatever else does that
bullet that's done using online banking
now I'm so fortunate to have to use it I
prefer online banking career instead of
going to the bank office in case of a
user secure a note I think most of the
time we are secure right so let's say it
will work
future of work of anti-malware work and
actually malware detection like
everything else in to the web
everything in the browser like some time
ago you had stand along clients with
banking and so on that were you actually
everything is in the web so so you have
to trust these solutions or maybe create
yours but there
question how if you should also mean
from your test how many times can detect
malware let's talk about tire and some
other mother which know if you're
talking about the rates of detection
we don't have like an arsenal of all my
were created actually if you want to get
infected by a specific model were
targeted for specific bank it's not very
easy you don't go to google and type in
fact me with the use targeted to let's
say ABC bank it's it's not so easy with
we don't have an arsenal of my work
actually I have to say we are not
strictly my were researchers we do not
do I could deep reverse engineering and
so on
most of this war is actually web
penetration test because it is a web web
solution yes it's another piece of
software which is outta to your web
application
e-banking web application which could
still have her abilities but still no
but section rates for lower is actually
one hundred percent for DS model where
four weeks until our solution have two
signatures right looks like a nineteen
viruses and efficient yeah well
sometimes it covers the nineties the
other solution gets 99 well yeah this is
pretty good I wanted to antivirus right
it's as good as is and is very moment
would be a bank would you advise me to
invest in such technologies or find some
different alternatives in order to
secure my client's yeah well that's
that's a question if you are buying
queef funds which can actually more like
software-as-a-service we choose which is
this kind of solution or you want to
create your your own crew your own team
working on lower actually in our opinion
I think like a small team of five people
or or maybe more
is enough to do all this work by the
bank itself
okay thank you for like two outs to my
colleague said I think and building an
in-house onto milos solutions could have
one advantage I think if that same our
creators will start to targeting such as
solutions I think they will start with
something which is mainstream like which
has biggest market adoption and if you
have it anyhow I think you could be a
little bit safer because you did it your
all you have to say it's built on top of
your application right but there are
social icons like we've heard from from
one of our client that's if the model
where operate there are sore
see that these bank is protected by ABC
anti-malware solution they do not start
as they do not touch base because it's
too much work to them and they rather
attack smaller bank which does not have
the solution was just during this rising
prices just a useful to or just called
tool to analyze this we know it
sometimes it could just go out of your
mind just realizing such things actually
and it was as I said it was quite easy
was sometimes one or two techniques used
the script wasn't big enough to try to
write Santos right I have two plus a few
hours
knowing of course before application
techniques but because it wasn't long
script and it was quite is the office
Kate it took me awhile to get to the
meaning of the functions outside because
also their names were obligated but we
did it by hand I to let's say to check
some scenarios we actually create some
tools in case of it was
plugins to for example cut
communications or to modify the script
on the fly to reach repeats artists but
it was mostly by hand
well that's mostly because our
translation tests are mostly money while
we do not use mainly scanners and
automated tools we prefer manual testing
yeah of course of course scapegoat our
souls on the very first used his
beautiful
until to make it pretty low key right
that's not really make it look richer so
I could ask the full up pushing if you
assume that every user has a unique
pattern they pressed keys how many
spelling errors they make a move their
mouse could use a similar technique to
figure out whether someone else is using
my count they don't have the pattern of
how I use my computer and my devices
what happens now I feel like we've seen
some solution which is like for example
Google Copper Creek upjohn know it
measures some speed of plagues and and
so on
there are many new authentication metals
for the banking industry like voice
authentication we had a lot of fun
testing recently voice recognition
technology like my colleagues went crazy
when I was speaking all day long into
the bank ADCB lured me into the bank ABC
then there were also some twenty stories
like one of the option if the voice of
integration software was to ask the bank
how much money of guarding polish its
and it rhymes with how we are just so
much poverty there and it worked
yeah so I think I think I haven't seen
such solution which will indicate user
by
by measuring their behavior but maybe
it's the future I've I think right now
there are tools which allow you in case
of this solution which allows me to say
if there is a real user bar or a script
which do this automatically but still we
saw some cases when there was no
automated tool to extract for example
money
compromised account but there was some
operators number the real human which
was doing the transfer himself so in
case with a remote desktop yeah so in
case I'm not sure how r ya when I think
we were able to see something funny
during our analysis we found out that
because we lost this case wasn't polish
let's say institutions financial
institution and we found out one quite
easy to spot problem during our analysis
of our most of the users do not change
at least do not change the language to
English before they started making trust
and that speaker interests and it shows
only dole's accounts were compromised
change the first thing they did change
language to all right but quite obvious
another one
so would you prefer to recommend
behavior and analyzes
users actions and bank or just provide
something like that
clientless malware detection system you
had to choose one
we realized I was let's say skip to
waste solutions which right it we're
using signatures so actually we didn't
bypass any solution which were using
really use our which were doing down
there saying right so I think those
things can be good enough
like this is a good way to do it good
way to protect your business from the
mall where it will have to understand
the purpose of fun similar solution it
has to minimize the risk but do not
delete the risk right it won't stop
everything but in most cases it will
stop popular
my family against you or any other
questions
factions fight with your thoughts of my
reduction of specific question to ask
because we do not provide such solution
but as we've seen its actually most 99%
of banking malware which is operating in
real now you know actually there was
some names took these names from one of
the vendor website
nice catch nice right there is some some
names but actually lowered the text
mechanism is as good as its signatures
so actually for most of signatures for
most of operating in rio yeah I does
this software has some did you discover
it has some finding false positives so
it's too sensitive that is recognizing
the user are similar but this kind of
behavior one solution and it caught some
automated tools which were looking to
bank but they were not aware they would
some intermediary payment companies
weeds do not want to pay the fee for the
bank for gathering gathering
transactional data but they just log
into the bank by their own but the other
I don't think so
out to other one other thing is some of
the signatures were let's say it was
forgiven my family was set of signatures
to check for example dysfunction that
sanction those streets drinks of given
names and if all of this were filed then
the backend server set ok this user is
infected with ABC Family came in case of
some of them were missing for example is
found two functions but only two strings
not free it generated some hours
something is not it was not red light
but it'll take a yellow so
it really didn't allege the right on
this particular one didn't hire 200 that
only when it was certain that given all
its present dissolution catch a
signature is like a function is a
function which does operate on the HTTP
request so sometimes it may happen that
on the bank website originated there is
a script which could be called by the by
this kind of solution actually vendors
of such solution analyze their website
the bank website before and create like
a targeted signatures in case of
signatures have to be careful because
for example the user also can the
developers of the web application can
put some names into its a window object
from global financial names which would
collide with your signatures right and
still having given a less a base 64 D
cult doesn't mean you have mild or maybe
the users developers develop deflection
for good reason right but still have to
protect you have to test it against pure
clean with application to call a false
positive example
in one bank there was a situation where
but like a liking to the Firefox I think
or or chrome injected some codes into
the banking website I think one of the
solution properties as well being
checked but it's it was not because it
was an original web browser plugging
ok so thank you very much and you should
get the follow-up paper or just leave
your business card or send us an email
thanks