writes this is the heart of Silicon
takashimaya other stuff here so I just
briefly address ourselves I'm Nick Zeeb
this is my colleague Daniel over here
but we're not coming today is we want to
cover the coin an overview some of the
attacks have been carried out against
the people the software and the protocol
and as we go along with gonna go from
less sophisticated taxed more
sophisticated attacks and as we go along
with an assault on explained it works
well see get the two in one
ok so in case you know nothing about it
coin is the Internet version of gold
that is a definite think of it it is
fundamentally limited they will only
ever be 20 1,000,000 coins found in the
whole time the whole the world and each
Bitcoin is currently worth about $240
right now so how can I use declined to
pay for things well here's a screenshot
of someone using a wallet application on
their phone to pay a merchant for a
service that providing here by scanning
the QR code that's all you need to do
you scan some as QR codes and he can
send the money now this much and has a
sign here says they accept Bitcoin so
you no longer have to use dirty old
government money over here now the point
about the coin is that you can make any
payment to anyone like this they don't
have to be next to you you can be
anywhere in the world and ask for
someone to send you money you can send
money to anyone in the world for any
amount for less than a cent within
minutes
also the payments that you make are
irreversible they're like handing over
cash so let's have a look at how we can
use the property to try and get hold of
some of these well as a No systems we
know the most wonderful part of a system
usually is found right here so let's see
if we can find someone who wants
something for nothing and give them
nothing for something so here is an
actual real scam that was run using
Bitcoin called crypto double and they
market themselves as a place where if
you give them money they gonna double
your money guaranteed in just 100 hours
now I'm sure all of you would look at
that go holy shit that is not legit that
sounds really dodgy well good night
everyone thought that way some people
thought billion
this is a really good idea if you if you
look into the selective it had a look at
the FAQ is like you know how how we can
guarantee this amazing claim you know
they would say like we're a bunch of
like really advanced traders like we
really know what we're doing with an
arbitrage these markets over here we can
use our superior knowledge of what's
going on with a double your money and he
said ok well why do you only take
Bitcoin or other keep their currencies
like that oh well you know because it's
cheaper to speed ascended we don't have
a credit card fees of course because
also ever stumble it makes it very
useful for them though if you'd invested
money in this afterwhile things started
to go wrong this is their Twitter feeds
the refuse so-called stuck withdrawals
don't worry about it is gonna be ok then
they claimed there was a highly
coordinated and massive DDoS attack but
don't worry our engineer handle it as
you can probably imagine this money
never got to see it come back and people
lost about half a million dollars in
this scheme so that's a very simple
social engineering trick
another way to you still get coins is to
make use of the property that pic
open-source anyone can take the Bitcoin
source code orkut make some minor
modifications to it and tell you that
they have been bent the next big thing
and if you guys are smart enough to get
an early on call at coin EA here if you
guys buy into this I'm going to
guarantee all rich is gonna be a next
big corn and of course this happens all
the time there's over 500 variants of
their currencies some of them are real
innovations are going wrong but I think
many of them are probably scams this
particular coin here was a coin that was
launched supposedly on the celebrity of
Kanye West and after he said he's not
supporting this project I decided to use
this picture said not everything that
shines as digital gold that's the
message here
ok let's have a look a bit more into the
software so this is a screenshot of a
wallet now I apologize for this dot
matrix projected that we're using here
but bear with me this is a a desktop
wallet and a wallet in bed
point is a bit of software that holds
that shows you what balance you have to
this user has only about 50 cents a bit
with a Bitcoin you have an address on
the system which people can use to send
you money and here is my address book
where you have other people's addresses
and that's what they look like and you
can see here they got the Free Software
Foundation WikiLeaks in other places you
can send money to and crucially and what
the what it does is the wallet allows
you to make transactions on the network
the wall it doesn't hold any bitcoins in
touch with a holes as a private key and
the private key is used to sign
transactions as you and anyone who has
access the private key cansada
transaction as you and move balances
around the network so you must keep your
private key private absolutely if that
doesn't happen you can be in trouble so
let's make use of that property how can
we get hold of someone's private key
well here's a good attempt this is a
real phishing attack that happened in
Bitcoin it is an email that said hello
David why not david most these a male
and you cannot be this that the summary
is can you please help me out here I've
got a pic when will it not that kind of
stuck please can you help me get them
out I thought you know thirty bitcoins
are stuck in this address in fact if you
look at this
explore aside here you could see they
were actually 31 stuck in this address
and they were saying okay please help me
she is my password can you please get
them out for me and send it to me thank
you very much so the aim is to try and
get you to click on this link to
download the so-called password yes as
you can probably imagine clicking on
that link doesn't actually give you
access to 30 victorians yeah it gives me
something like this which could sort of
be a password in a text documents the
kinda suspicious-looking command prompt
behind their baby indicates there's a
bit more going on this is actually just
setting up a persistent back door to
allow the attackers to remotely access
your machine and remotely access your
wallet and it's possible to encrypt
while it's been a lot of people do that
if they do then they just have to add
some key logger and pick up your
password for last and this is just one
little piece of malware there's a lot of
malware out there that's geared toward
attacking
decline in 2013 this report came out
last year about 2013 records found that
about 22 percent of the financial
related malware attacks that they were
texting right-to-carry towards attacking
people's bakeries are trying to steal
people's minds and its coverage like a
whole host of different types of malware
you got the access to all that we just
saw and there's other other piece of
malware which has she tried to attack
your wallet directly there is one called
clings to life which one typo says he
lost about $14,000 to that particular
piece of malware it would actually
masquerade as a legitimate speculated
utility to help you receive payments
more anonymously but it was in the
background or just interact with your
wallet and send all of your phones to
the attacker and this this property of
pretending to be a legitimate utility is
kind of common in the backline malware
like it lets the attack targets
elections are the kind of people that
are downloading these utilities are the
kind of people that would have any money
there's another one which poses a vanity
address generator so that would be
something I just generate a whole load
of public-private key pairs so that you
can get a more friendly bickering
address addresses their to ride from the
public key and they're typically not
particularly friendly this is what
address looks like that you can't really
tell anything from that address about
who's this is actually a dress for the
tales projects but it's sort of
machine-readable and not particularly
geared towards humans so what you would
do if you wanted to make a donation to
the tales projects then usually just go
to their web sites go find their
backline address and you're not gonna
just gonna typed out so people just copy
go to their wallets and then paste it in
there and then when you head saying
you're sending the bighorns two tables
or that's how things should work there
is another piece of ours does something
kind of needs you may have noticed that
the address that was pasted it there
doesn't actually match the dress that
was called this was some very simple
piece of malware which had at least one
guy sort of worried on reddit
this was something that someone actually
poses a big corner related game it was
like some RPG were you complete question
he supposedly are in real bitcoins as
rewards but really I just leave
something running in the background
which monitors your clipboard at any
time I see something that looks like a
Bitcoin address because they're quite
distinctive just replace it with the
address of the attacker and because
they're not very human readable most
people just gonna take it in and hits
and realize that you're sending money to
attack and one of the new things about
this is it's not going after just one
particular application of the wallet is
now a lot of different while it's a very
few native applications or web
applications as well this is a popular
web based while it's this one i think is
the most well-known web based while it
is run by blocking all the info on these
guys actually started out as a site for
allow you to view and navigate around
the corner transactions so this is their
their navigator interface and hear it
down here you can see these are the
recent transactions in Victoria and
these are these are not just your
transactions
this is not like your account history
kind of thing this is the show's all
transactions that were taking place on
on the bickering that work so one of the
things that you need to understand how
bickering works is that is to see how it
differs from conventional currencies
usually you would have some kind of
token like you have a dollar bill or you
can give to somebody and then you're
transferring some money today otherwise
they'll be some kind of central
authority like a bank for example which
will maintain people's balances and you
can ask your bank to transfer some money
to somebody else with the claim there is
none of that there is no physical tokens
are you can just hand to somebody and
central authorities what you have with
big line is a public ledger it's a
complete list of all the transactions
that ever happens in bickering and
because they are their public then
everybody on the network of potentially
a volume that work will have a copy of
this nature and because it's complete to
has every transaction has ever taken
place you can use this later to
calculate
balances are so at any given time you
know your balance is the sum of all of
the bighorns I've been sent to you
minus any big plans that you send
somebody else and when you want to
create a transactional you want to spend
because you say that these declines that
everybody knows I perceived I'm now
sending them over here and then
everybody knows that guy's balances
don't open your balances downtown so we
take a look at the transaction on the
left we go to transaction inputs this is
about where you're saying that you're
all these ones I'm spending and this
case the personal spending around nine
and a half declines and you can specify
multiple in particular if this guy when
it has been more than that you could
specify other transactions or receive
pic lines and then you have more to
spend in a transaction in this case he
sending it to the three outputs on the
right
transaction but this is the destination
addresses and if we take a look at this
one just here you can see this 1 2010
address is being sent about 2.3 6 picket
lines you can see that it says spent
this person who are set to they've
already spent that's because we have a
complete public list of transactions you
can go forward and see this is the
transaction where they are spending
their bickering this this is the address
with the 2.36 Pickering's and this is
how the transactions or to fit together
the output from one transaction make up
to later transactions so the way that
you ensure that the intended recipients
can can spend that kind of interesting
as well how that works
say Alice went to st. end according to
Bob she doesn't have to name Bob
directly in the transaction
what she does is Jackie poses a puzzle
that only bob consult and this is done
using the built-in programming language
so here Alice creates a a partial
program which is locking up the phones
here she sending ten horns are now
locked up
only Baba be able to unlock some and
when bob despite even suspenders he
created jobs public he said this is what
indicating that it's possible to
anybody's allowed to spend them and when
he decides to spend them he creates
another transaction where he specifies
some data which completes this program
and this program now can be executed so
when bob creates a transaction that you
will broadcast network and everybody
will be able to execute this program in
its entirety and verify that this is a
valid transaction and what this does
best buy the signature on the private
and the public key the signature is
signing the transaction that he's
created with the private key that
corresponds to the public yet he
specified and the public he must have to
the value that specifies and her are
open scripts and if all of those things
are true then everybody knows that this
is a legitimate transaction fees were in
fact intended for ball but he has now
spent so if we take a look at a real
transaction here this is unlocked and
again you can see you have the output
scripts down there has got to grips
because this transaction is sending to
two different addresses and this kind of
program here this is the the same kind
of her going to show you in this the
previous lies this is the most common
way of sending because it's called it
paid a public key hash because it's got
the hash of the recipients public in it
and these instructions here the things
starting with all these are the
parameters of the bickering programming
language that only a few that make up
this this kind of transaction but
there's a lot more opcodes in the
language but which allows you to be much
more flexible with the transactions are
you create it also lets you do a lot of
other kind of funny things there's one
interesting opportunity and bad
arbitrate any transaction so here you
can see this transaction has an
opportune statements which is just
sending a message to you guys and this
is used for a variety of different
things there is a proven system service
which lets you upload documents and it
gets embedded in it
transaction and you can then see or
anybody can see that at the time that
transactions created that document
existed in that form there's also a
proposal last month from the people I'm
TLS for using Opera tiring to help pls
certificate revocation you don't need to
use significant revenue revocation lists
her spirit ever given that we can
invading army dating transactions
there's a lot more fun things you can do
it that's very common mistake that a lot
of developers make when they're building
software which is correctly identify
user inputs usually developers think
about input as being the ways in which
users interacting with the software that
they're writing at the bottom of that
users click on the forms a subnet but
given that anybody in the world can
invade arbitrary data and it's now being
displayed in a website this is
effectively inputs to this particular
site and given that it was only a matter
of time before somebody tried putting
JavaScript any transaction fairly benign
example it doesn't do anything now but I
used to look more like that we're
actually executing JavaScript and that
that's kind of a dangerous thing to do
to be executing our retreat JavaScript
in the context of a javascript declined
while it was there is a very simple
attack here where you just saying
somebody some small number of declines
in your including JavaScript in the
transaction and when they see they they
click on the transaction and the
JavaScript execution and transfers their
entire balance back to you a while ago
blocked or chain of 66 that there's also
an hour and 45 limit on the amount of
Haiti can include an inopportune
statements it's being increased age
bites but at the moment
40 bytes is all you have to work for or
how to work with forty-eight happens to
be the exact amount to do that to you
can embed
external javascript using a URL
shortener if you're using a GPS it
should really require 41 bytes but if
you just miss off the closing angle
bracket on your script and then the
browser is quite forgiving it was a
minor development Aaron it executed
anyway so that's something you can do a
transaction outfits but let's have a
look at a transaction input again so I
mentioned before that the transaction
inputs that's an example wolpe specified
area a signature and a public key and
there they are you can see these unblock
change the signatures are actually
produced using the elliptic curve
digital signature algorithm and I'm not
gonna go deep into the mass spam and how
easy to say works but the important part
to know is that your signature consists
of two components are an ass valleys and
there is a random number AM which is
used to make up there is there's also
the private key K which is used to make
up the ass value and one of the rules
say is that you must never reuse the
same value of n for multiple signatures
are the same private key if you do one
thing that will happen is that this
value will also be the same across
multiple signatures and that makes these
signatures very easy to spot you can
just look through all the transactions
that some of these signs and if you find
one where the more the one where they
are components of a second-round match
then you know it was created using the
same value and the other side effect of
that you can take the two values from
those two signatures and you can
actually held directly calculate the
private key so once a private even
compromise that anybody can go and spend
your bitcoins so it is important they
use a strong random number generator
there the value of m is large enough
that any half-decent random number
generator should never be values RAM but
sometimes people don't do random
terribly well we can take a look at this
transaction here
these signatures was added to our
components which if we zoom in on those
you'll see the identical which means
these two signatures were produced using
the same value of n so the private key
is not compromised and this seems to
happen it seems like about once a year
this is an example from 2012 in 2013
there is a weakness in job is secure
around him which led to the Android
becoming while it's repeating am values
which made which allows some people's
private key to be compromised than last
year blocked chain had a similar issue
the iraqi trying to update their
JavaScript wallets to increase people
they're using and they accidentally
reduced to 21 points so they were a
repeat repeat again values very often in
this case there when this started
happening and these transactions with
them
repeated our values are showing up on
the ledger there is one guy called you
who actually spotted this was going on
and he swept up more than $300,000 worth
of coins from compromise private keys
and then once blocking fix the issue he
gave it all back so that was kind of
nice and this is a problem that doesn't
just affect bickering it's anybody's
using ECSA can be potentially vulnerable
to this kind of attack in 2010 this is
the same technique that the group they
deliver flow actually used to crack the
private key is used her signing codes
for the ps3 in that case is random
number generator just always return the
same value which made it quite easy for
them the slide I showed you earlier but
with a mass on it from there
talk they gave a chaos and yet this is
one way that private keys can be
compromised like a private keys
obviously it's quite important to keep
them private which does mean that if you
happen to be on television
don't hold it up to the camera to show
people what the private key looks like
the headlines that follow that kind of
inevitable by Stan ok so let's have
a bit reluctant to the actual more so we
mention that decline is a peer-to-peer
network there is like this said there's
no central note there's no one bit of
fun of computing architecture you can
take out working it is like BitTorrent
in that notes really connect to each
other and they share the statement at
work with each other so at this point
you have what we call a distributed
ledger every node in the network is
aware that currently alice is the holder
of two bitcoins and Bob owns one that
everyone is in agreement about that fact
so let's have a look at what the notes
are actually storing it's not just the
current state they actually in the
entire history of all transactions ever
taken place like that was saying and
they do this through a data structure
that we can show here what they do is
they group about 10 minutes with the
transactions into a collection called
the block and that block will then be
referenced by another block this is the
first transactions in the next election
I get take place on another block and a
half point up points back to the
previous block and this way the
structure keeps building up in an
immutable ledger that cannot have a
history changed by simply pointing
backwards the previous block using this
data structure has called the block
chain that's so as its ok so how do new
transactions get included a block how
does actually do that to happen at any
one point in the network you have the
last known blocks in at the last agreed
block which is here and you have a bunch
of transactions that are not getting a
block people have to simply broadcast
network broadcasting any note and the
crime bill use what's called a gossip
protocol where I tell a message to you
say you tell tell your friends I tell
their friends are just spreads like
wildfire that whenever a copy of
everything is broadcast so after that
there is a race that happens were all
the nodes and who attempt to create the
next block their gold miners they will
take all of the outstanding transactions
the unconfirmed ones here adds a random
value to all the outstanding
transactions and then they will take a
hash of this all the state up and create
a hash value and bit the Bitcoin
protocol specifies that the first person
you can find a number here that will
produce a hash value below a certain
value called the difficulty
it gets the gets to create a new block
and so what happens if people try lotto
numbers in the first person to find
something that works again you can't
predict the outcome so you just have to
keep going until you find one in this
case the difficulty was below a thousand
is the first person to find a solution
what they do they take all outstanding
transactions like this the group into a
block and they add crucially one extra
transaction in there called the block
reward this is how all new pic when I
created only because I created by people
created by people mining and creating
new blocks currencies issued currently
for every person who could generate a
block the rewards 25 bitcoins with a
network started the reward was fifty
bitcoins and next year is gonna be
twelve and a half so every four years
the reward hops and asymptotically
approaches the finite limit of 21
million that will never be exceeded ok
that's what mining is so its
distribution network so it is actually
possible that's roughly around the same
time to minors on the network will find
a valid solution to the next block and
what happened in that case well in that
case you have what's called a fork this
happens about once a day on average
what that means is that two people
broadcast the new block both of which
build on the last good luck here and in
that in that case what happens is the
big one network is temporarily split
what happens as everyone who sees this
blog first we'll try and extend this
blog bubbling up above it and everyone
who sees this blog for us will try to
extend this block now what that means is
that you have such a voting process
happening on the pic on network people
vote with their identities coin mining
and running a network synonymous and
Watkins free to join and leave you give
an identity what you vote with is your
passion power so if say whatever I
seventy-five hashing power is trying to
send this block and thirty this block it
is likely that next book will be fine
and will be extending this one here and
the Bitcoin protocol says that people
should always switch to try to extend
the longest blocked the one that most
amount of work put into it and because
you
because you know anyone else will do
that it is in your rationale interest
through the same because if you try to
extend this one and this will become
longer and longer people ignore your
blocks and your reward will be ignored
so just for your selfish interests it is
rational for you to orphan the block you
working on down here to give up on it
and join everyone else on this side of
the network over here and that's how pat
Quinn re-creates the synchrony between
the network and the speedway
what this also means in terms of how one
can attack the network is that if any
single actor just to amass more than 50%
of the entire hashing part of the
network what you could do as you could
split up the block chain from any point
onwards and decide what you want to put
these blocks now there are some limits
to this you can't put invalid
transactions in it because the
cryptographic suggests will no longer
match and the network will ignore that
the one thing you can do is you can
decide not to include transactions so if
you really wanted to you could produce
empty blocks and basically sense of
transactions this would cause a 51%
attack it's quite expensive because they
have the big one network is now in Ormus
but you couldn't do it the other problem
would be that would be detectable people
would notice 0 for no good reason the
miners are censoring transactions
something's wrong let's go investigates
and the other nice thing about pat Quinn
is that because it creates a beautiful
history he's blocked numbers you can go
back to any point in the Bitcoin history
and restart the network from a block
that we all agreed in fact there was a
security problem found early on in
Bitcoin where the output of a
transaction to add up to be the same as
imports but it wasn't checking for
numeric overflow the someone managed to
create you know several billion Bitcoin
in a transaction by simply using the
overflow the outputs and the way that
was fixed was at the Bitcoin quartet's
got to get inside guys stop the
bloodshed from it let's go back to the
previous blog that we know is good and
go from there again that was many years
ago was only on the protocol because the
transaction histories immutable you can
go back and restore any block in the
case of 51% attack people probably to
say okay shot 256 which is the hashing
algorithm be concurrent users is
compromised somebody has amassed more
than 50% of the power it let's change
some other
hashing algorithm that's probably what
would happen but again this attack is
the most expensive one you probably
think of because it's just so much
community power so it going to work
requires only that you know half the
network is roughly being honest in what
they're doing okay so what does that
mean for a single transaction that means
a single transaction has the following
lifecycle what is first broadcast
network and not include any block it's
what we call on confirm transaction that
within a few seconds ascent of the
entire network and everyone can see the
transaction being broadcast when the
first miner to the block and it will
happen in about five minutes on average
because it takes 10 minutes to make a
blocking your randomly going to
broadcast it halfway through the process
and you get your transaction including
one block in the clintons this is called
won confirmation if someone does the
block on top of that block you get to
confirmations and three confirmations
and so on
as your transaction gets buried deeper
and deeper into the block chain the
Chancellor is will be able to
successfully for the network in the way
that we saw become lower and lower
exponentially so so what does that mean
for a merchant's well it means if you're
sending some coffee you can probably
accepts a single transaction because
it's quite hard to put the block chain
if you want a Ferrari you might want to
wait twenty thirty minutes before let
dry before court case I had some sort of
ability to foot the network so you can
choose any amount of 31 in terms of
accepting transactions so if a merchant
is being quite lacks and they accept
unconfirmed transactions what could you
in theory due to attack that merchants
well you can carry out something called
a double spend attack so in this example
alice is the attacker network currently
agrees that alice is the only holder of
the one that exists and bobcat have no
but concert hall now in this example Bob
Katter merchants and the connection
between their two nodes limits lower
than the way that Alice connects to them
so what else can do is Alice
simultaneously broadcast two
contradictory transactions to each of
them she compromise bobber Bitcoin and
promised aimed at quantico
at the same time and if they accept
those transactions are unconfirmed and
palaces managed to position itself the
network in this way that she can push
for direct her transactions directed by
Venkat which takes quite a bit of
analysis of the network and figuring out
which know it's connected to she
couldn't they are a double spin attack
and if bob cat immediately go and send
out the goods without any confirmations
and she could essentially get two of
whatever she's ordering now this this is
not a problem for biklin itself because
the next minor who create the block out
this cannot include both these
transactions these transactions contract
each other if you saw the block and put
both of these in the block everyone else
on that work will ignore your block
solution your award you will lose 25
declines because it's not ballot so it
is not in their interest to do something
stupid like that because you're putting
real hashing power on the line its cost
you some effort electricity do this so
it's just act rationally like i say this
is not you just have to carry out either
because you need to know exactly how
networks going to the network and so on
but it could in theory possible so in
practice merchants will accept higher
taxes if you buy a coffee but not if
you're buying a Lamborghini so ok let's
have a look at the structure a
transaction again so it can transaction
consists of two parts like data showing
schematically these you think of it like
this that is the transaction
a statement of intent saying I want to
send this particular pic on my own
person and you sign it with a signature
and this case Alice now remember from
then slide the signature has two parts
are now unfortunately the CBSA there is
a slight problem that allows someone to
take a valid signature RSS make a minor
mathematical mutation to the F compared
to the signature you take the negative
value and take it
modulus and it's not important to
understand what the mathematical
transformation is it simply important
that the way he said yes they work so
allows you to make a minor formatting
change the signature when you do this
you can only change the way that
signature looks you cannot change any of
this change any of this journal of
matches all you can do is slight change
of formatting of a signature and it
still valid
so how could we use that knowledge to
attack the network
well let's imagine the scenario let's
imagine alice is the big one exchange
and she has users and sometimes uses one
take their money out so lets the user
Bob wants to withdraw his one big one
from the exchange he says to allen's
please everyone but conjugates ok he go
bob here's the transaction I have signed
as Alice and your Bitcoin she tried to
send this to the network however Bob the
attacker has figured out which no Dallas
users to connect to network with and
what he does is he mad animal attacks
out essentially he at this point the
transaction being broadcast the network
he goes and changes it he goes and makes
a minor formatting changes that
indicates that benefit and that what
happens is this message is still valid
yet still are correct to say it's a
slightly different from its signature so
the network will go ahead and will
confirm this transaction and it'll all
go through everything is good bugs guys
back on now what does he goes out and
say hey wait a minute I never got my
money can you please check on this
transaction used to send out and about
issues if alice is foolish
she simply will take a hash of her
transaction ago oh that hash a kind that
come from anyone the network and if
she's very foolish she will not just
rebroadcast the same transaction should
choose the ballot she will generate a
different transaction there is a big
corner has not yet been spent and sends
it get into the network I guess what
does bob does exact same thing again and
if alice is extremely stupid she will
automate this process I never check any
this complaint just keep sending it over
and over and over again in fact the kind
of person who might do this would be
like someone who would try to implement
a site using PHP and they probably look
like this this was in fact the the way
that talks claim that their pic winds
were hacked they use transaction
malleability the protocol
and people stole money because the
automated this process up to three
sending transactions over and over again
and it caused the loss of over a half a
billion with the Bitcoin so yeah that
wasn't very good I should point out this
point that many researchers believe that
this is something convenient in the
protocol that markets has blamed the
problem on it's likely that were
actually an insider attack that monks
was actually insolvent long before this
happened but publicly the transaction
malleability explained as what they
blamed for this problem yet so if anyone
is looking to steal the exchanges are
pretty good targets ago after half a
billion dollars worth of becoming this
is the largest ever becoming heist in
history
this one actually peremptory got out of
business been there been other attacks
against exchanges earlier this year but
stamp is there another popular change
these days they were hacked as well
using transaction liability but they
lost about five million dollars they're
a bit more switched on when it comes to
security which is why they only lost
this small amount and and they're still
going but let's go back and look at man
the middle attacks even mention how this
can help reduce transaction malleability
attacks and won the problem is that
there is no inherent prevention for
mandela tax like there's no endpoint
validation like your account with us for
example it's a peer-to-peer network
you're connecting to random people on
the internet and you don't really know
anything about them so you could be
connected to any body and the way they
can get around the the peer-to-peer
traffic problem like the problem finding
your initial setup ears is that there is
this well-known list of DNS addresses
and when you start your wallet
it will resolve those addresses and they
always resolve to a a long list of
recent appearance on the network so that
should give you a list of like one or
two hundred IP addresses that you can
then connect so if an attacker is in the
position to influence your DNS or they
can just get in between you and one of
these IP addresses or all of them then
they can ensure that all of your traffic
goes through them and that's that's one
way of doing getting in the middle
there's another attack against Tory
users are going back to the transaction
the way you validate transactions I
showed you earlier there is a program
that gets executed there is a possible
denial of service attack against are you
repeatedly saying invalid transactions
and you force the execution to try and
validate them that will always fail and
the way because protect itself from that
is that anytime you say and more than a
hundred invalid transactions and your IP
address will be banned for 24 hours so
the attack in stories to say and a whole
load of invalid transactions through the
Tor exit know it and get all the tour
exit nodes bands and then you run your
notes and getting through tour will have
to be connecting through either your
exit node or to your to your big day
going through your exit now then they
can attack your industry directly to
their big going there anyway so that's
one of the ways of getting in the middle
of a tour users the trouble with mandala
taxes that transaction malleability
thing that mitnick was talking about
there's not really much else you can do
once you're in the middle
you can prevent the user from sending
transactions but you can't really do
anything to steal their bickering and
their private key is still reasonably
secure on their computer doesn't give
you any accidents so you can create
transactions on their behalf
all you can do is stop them from sending
you steal anything
ok so in the last 12 briefly touch upon
some of the ways in which pic when
security is improving right now so it
works through a bunch of clowns upgraded
to a pic when improving proposal or a
bit so here's one that's actually going
to go right now this is to solve the
transaction value probability probably
talked about so there's already a known
solution to this basically the it's a
tightening up on the rules eg signatures
can be negative and there's a few other
places in the protocol allows similar
things like you can like nope at some of
the input argument that showed but it's
always the same idea you can make a
minor formatting changes transaction
that doesn't invalidate it and the
change the hash of it and here is
already bit 62 is already the proposed
solution of how to tighten up a concert
is no longer possible is not is not
being the code yet has not been released
yet but it is on his way to be happening
so that's gonna get taken care of
another way that because it is improving
is that in a normal transaction as we've
seen as only a single signature here so
only one private key to compromise on a
compromise alice's funds well biklin now
also has a possibility of saying funds
can be locked up in such a way that you
require more than one thing to do it you
can do like a scheme here but you say
you have to have at least two out of
three signatures on any transaction to
be able to spend these funds and what
that lets you do that lets you create
independent private keys have never ever
been on the same computer never on the
same machine that exist in different
parts of the world
different hard run different OS's and
transactions created Alice has to
independently side and sort of cat
before the transaction is valued at all
so that means the attacker has to
compromise multiple points at the same
time for this attack to work in fact
this is the solution that fits that went
to after they are five million dollars
he talked about whether use an
independent organization called it go
that will independently side transaction
and run them through much of risk
profiling things you could do things
like the other organization will only
sign them if that's you know less than
certain amount or if it looks dodgy
because of the way that the patterns are
happening in Europe taking too much out
one day it may stop it and go and say
wait a minute this looks wrong are you
sure you want to sign this another way
to pick on security is improving is that
people are like develop hardware well
it's the idea of hardware wallets is
that you would never ever let the
private key escape the hardware what you
what you can do is you can plug this
device into a laptop that could be
compromised the only thing laptop can do
is proposed a transaction to the to the
hardware and you have to physically
press YES or NO to add a signature to it
there's various schemes that have
noticed but they have pins and you can
use this in combination with multi sake
we're one of the suggested we produce
the hardware while at the other one is
on your Android device or somewhere else
but will become harder while it can also
look very differently this is an example
of a bit as an overlay onto a SIM card
that adds Bitcoin hardware functionality
to any dumb phone as an example
another way that people have been
talking in terms of improving the hard
way is to use trusted computing platform
that trusted platform modules this is
getting more common on hardware hardware
comes with these modules that will only
allow code that has a verified
cryptographic signature to execute and
only under those conditions will this
chip release the private key necessary
to sign a transaction so helpful there
as well
ok so lastly let's go through the things
we covered the talk this is a reminder
of how we saw signs the first wave
showed you was able to trick people
sending to you always attack the human
so he's just point another we can do it
is trying to slow down as a malware
always a favorite cross-site scripting
you can take advantage of people having
bad random number generators you can
just simply watch television until
someone shows you the private key you
can amass more than half of the entire
hashing power the network kind of
expensive
you can double spend of merchants are
waiting for transactions if you have
knowledge of the network setup and you
can exploit transaction malleability
while still possible to do that before
they fix it
okay thank you very much for coming to
talk
I'm not very familiar with this
presentation very basic question how do
I get these because I have to buy them
from somewhere you mentioned that there
is no central authority so I different
vendors that he can buy from ya so
there's there's plenty of exchanges out
there some better than others like we
showed a mean really should be the ones
I got tax there's multiple exchanges out
their existing different countries you
can you can sell things are picking up
now this is the chancellor of the UK
George Osborne using a pic on ATM is
putting in money and it gets real big
close out 2011 other option is always to
steal them to mind but coins that's
probably that's not that easy anymore
because it is modeled on goals in that
is limited but also on the way the goals
in mind in the early days anyone could
go to California stick their hand into a
stream and golden nuggets and that was
CPU mining that it got harder people had
to use graphics cards to mine it and as
the Bitcoin as it became harder and
harder and the Justice difficulty to
keep the blocks for 10 minutes now you
have to use special hardware basics
basically so that's what we're going to
do it I wouldn't recommend that to an
average user
thank you
$40 roughly what howard said I was at
work
ok so here is a graph that shows the
price of the ballot the price of Bitcoin
as maybe you guys can see this was the
Great Crash 2012 but here it went from
$35 a gloss over 90% with a $2 and corn
is a is like is like gold its its prices
only by supply and demand far as I know
there are no dodgy bankers in London who
fix this price every day so yeah it's
simply how to run it by how much you
want to sell now because big one is like
gold it has a slight periodic problem
where people get very excited about the
coin and the price goes up and people
look at you go oh my god the price going
up I must buy bitcoins and the price for
the fire people go oh my god is going up
by more and of course that's not
sustainable and then eventually crashes
and it happened a few times now this was
this crash happened to your when finally
collapsed it's been a bit much they were
around 200 now the hope is that as big
advances it will become more and more
stable less volatile and probably end up
looking a bit like gold gold 24 @ rates
than has periods where goes up but it
it's not as wild and crazy young big
toys 6 years old so we're hoping it'll
come down and be like oh but in the long
run it should appreciate in value simply
because of limited government money
keeps being printed quantative easing
programs are very popular around the
world right now the clinton have
quantities and is not possible to not
allow it
question this is the supply curve a pic
on we are around there are a lot of the
security of the bills on
big number of analysts people network
especially the minors so what will
happen when an op-ed cards have been in
mind what will happen to the security
model is this already planned or have to
adapt
question yes our plans so as we were
alluding to in the early days in the
beginning of work through that in the
beginning Bitcoin mining the block
reporters 50 big ones every block has
now been have 225 and it keeps going
down which looks like this so a bit
closer to rewards get from mining we
didn't mention the second the second is
transact transaction fees you can
include a small transaction fee
currently includes something like a
tenth of aus sent for any such
transaction to get including the block
chain and the hope as bad as we run out
as we approach the limit of 21 million
in the next hundred years that they
become very popular enough the
transaction fees will be enough to cover
the cost of mining so we should see a
balance remaining award subsidies of the
country found two transaction fees
taking over and securing the network by
the miners ok thank you very much