today we are going to talk about iris
taking a transit penetration testing and
forensic techniques my name server let
me briefly introduce myself before
starting my name is Omar on the left
hand side I'm currently employed rate
KPN has known as Royal Dutch telecom and
I used to repair companies like their
eyes and IBM by my colleague Mark
couldn't make it here but if you ever
happen to be coming at us and have a
beer on us they are trying we are going
to cover basically the address thanks
techniques on our application reverse
engineering particularly dealing with
668 four-bit application static and
dynamic analysis and hunting for the RSA
keys and the cryptography on this
platform and also a bit of penetration
testing automation techniques
communication interception how many of
you have already done some penetration
testing on mobile environments could you
raise your hands
few of them and how many of your health
already done some reverse engineering
Corp penetration testing on statistical
on iOS environment than 100 K
story will cover everything so you have
some clue to catch up with variations
whatever inspires us to prepare a
presentation on these under-thirty is
mostly we do a lot of penetration
testing on the mobile environment so we
want automated I now live it because the
mobile environment and applications are
evolving being part of day today our
life day by day and exploration areas
disclosure song the exponentially did
not only related to the surveillance
simple implants shifted our focus on the
mobile devices as you may see hurt
German financial yeah I'm John America
while being intercepted her cause and
listen by the some government and I you
throught kids are not only its Terry
anymore and its practical is being sold
exchanged by the underground of the
Internet is became a service and the
reverse engineering car armament I
really fun and we are going to see it
all together
I a security architecture is look like
this we can analyze two major companies
want us to userspace the second one is
the kernel space
user party consists of applications
sandbox user partition operating system
partition all within the encrypted file
system and the kernel part consists of
the security clearance security elements
if you break down all the competence
encryption and data protection
its aim to provide mobile users to
protect their data from Star stolen
attempts and without modifying it make
it secure the major company ISL Marmont
securities being provided by the
security secure enclaves securing levees
introduced highest devices after April a
seven processors and then later on
security cleverest simply a coprocessor
which consists of memory and hardware
encryption automated simply
number if you ever tell to cryptography
incident number is the one of the major
companies of the cryptographic that
makes this reliable and strong and
they're all security backs that can be
analyzed in two groups
system came back and the external team X
very achieved encrypted device
Keith for the local device and the one
external is being accused imply to speak
up there
encryption key are being stored
to make security framework simply is
built upon the russet PST tremor did it
was first used in FreeBSD systems it
simply look like this it provides for
different interfaces for security some
complication and it defines the virtual
filesystem process techno inter-process
communication and the pipe inter-process
communication and people is in for a
interface provides frame for more
general model dividing tracing and the
traces to allow developers to instrument
and analyze their applications just a
break down into the war basics basics
when you have as a mobile developer was
to develop your application and put in a
device and when you started on your
application is simply creates a process
and politics right I wanted to run it in
walks to sandbox in its system call this
is some called dynamic library to check
specific policies and these polices
transfer to the sandbox kernel extension
and then check specific policy profiles
and then it is still specific policy
profile to the your application and send
suspected a signal whether it is
installed properly or not this simply
defines what you can achieve within the
mobile application and
what you're allowed to do what you are
not if you want if you want to look very
attractive it looks like this you create
a process to make siskel to the makeout
make liar takes federal policy applied
or not and they simply sandbox final
extension is just making a regular
expression to check whether your policy
is making a profile which is already
defined in the IRS friend so on the left
side they have profiles documented
profiles like your application could
have like has no right to do the Kinect
know her from truck operations or try to
do the directory or the specific
directories but there are also some
profile undocumented to reverse
engineers found the 405 pirate
engineering from malicious application
developer or security researcher it
could be interesting for you for example
this profile
Mobile Safari mobile mail a PSD
expression of December compiler d
profile you can perform other actions
within the company within the for
example you can access to the log
directories recent locations
temporary directories love directories
and etc and profile you is look like
this you simply walk to tamper with
their profile given as argument to the
court and file encryption under the
entire system is looking like this
you're hardly key coming from the
security and clever and the past year
was arrested twice in the final + key
these are combined and involve conveyed
to the class key and we have encryption
file metadata for each key and it is
encrypted
file encryption also defines API classes
to define specific actions on the file
operation within the environment for
example find protection we can setup
file without any protection the
protection could be complete unless open
and this API cluster also define some
attributes like they are tributes are
working like this for example then you
want too long to write to the file you
can define as their this operation could
be done after last device are open or
you can simply a low profile Tempe
regional race or eat all this and called
can be shipped either unless stated goal
or DNS File Manager this sample
difference between two courses by using
File Manager over any state the reason
behind this weekend's festivities
attribute any state that doesn't give
such option to the developer as I
mentioned she baked locations the x-pro
internal locations are stored on your
device this directory private lockdown
direction directory with in your room
and they're also external items pick-up
location that contains your for instance
make device and it contains all the
encryption keys and they're open source
and commercial solutions there you can
perform crypto directly attacks and you
can try to find out to keep at it is
being improved some make the changes
take place after iOS
eight and they were russians of the
lamentations make a file structure has
been changed a little bit on the 64 bit
implementation mcAfee is simply
executable on the iOS devices and it
looks likes this
the maker of 64 bit implementation built
upon the 32 bit however the segment
Sicamous little be changed for for
instance the trigger a structure called
segment come on 64 defiance VMware
structures that you can destroy some
specific privileges which part of the
VMware the and memories can be read can
be not from a security perspective this
is important because you would wanna
know which location is being used by
program and for instance encryption keys
thought what kind of action could be
done because if a malicious application
runs on the Apple iOS device and
application uses wrong permissions on
the segment we can do
malicious actions and another to
cellmark mechanism couldn't be used in
the proper way to write these are the
most technical and youth terror to kill
information I prepared to presentation
as
hands on the challenge you will be
provided to all the executables after
the conference talk from get up you can
download and try I S binaries
implementers and corruption aidid to
protect executables from piracy so the
consistency integrity check checked by
the encryption so it's the section in
the executive will then be used to deal
with it or to do with applications on
the environment is simply use object to
and then finding corruption section if
they encrypt decrypt idea section is
returned for us let me step by nearly is
encrypted so in the past we used to find
out
encryption section and rearm addressed
virtual memory address and defined
length of it and we simply run the
executable there to better define the
sections time to binary and we can
simply extract unencrypted executable
the game it's pretty Meistersinger on
the 64 bit Marmont the only some of
those differences we need to use LLDP
debugger it is the user's the ceiling I
keyworth and syntax and its comforted
default compiler within its called
framework how you can get everything is
stored on their ex called default
directory so you can simply attach to do
is tell you till you find a specific
images that you are dealing with for
instance I was dealing with 28 points
7.1 implementation so it contains all
the helpers and utilities and other
Pacific directory of the Y support like
the most important one is you will need
a vector
to be able to run the boxer on your iOS
device device we need to set the file
for the box over the discipline some
back policy file that you define what
your executable can does on the day why
simply if it cannot around for example
process I D for each task ran outside
court an extra so that's what we want
because we want to attach executable to
do the bugger server on the device and
the debugging operations so there's a
tool called court sign you can define
and title as XML file and then signed
executable and you can simply uploaded
to the jailbroken iOS device was applied
to execute of all you want to create a
TCP connection to the device and
debugging on your computer so when
you're on LGBT bloggers you can
selectively removed iOS version that you
are physically dealing with if you write
a letter on select remote also it will
show you all the supported versions of
the IRS implementation up till now while
I was doing reverse engineering on the
device
my environment supported up till version
8.1 however I was dealing with an
executable 64 bit executable which was
created and developed for version 7.1
you define your executable file finder
process I D and you cannot connect to do
the box server IP address is 215 is my
jailbroken devices IP address by dr.
Reddy's listening on that port 6667 I
attached connected I list out the tracks
it seems like the application is being
attached to the democracy since
everything fine if you ever done now
we're on now this is for reverse
engineering yours and I authentication
shouldn't be so much difficult
especially if you know there are Packers
for x86
like it applies a lot of opera station
and creeps stolen by a lot of
abstraction that you need to tell it
like it is not the case for iOS
applications
I grabbed a binary and all of that back
to the my application so I was using
either since there is no obligation and
exit rather marmots I can easily resolve
the functions name correctly and it
seems all groups it correctly result of
function names and arguments declaration
so whenever I do reverse engineering
static analysis I always look for the
imports and the interesting function
means the application I was dealing with
simply using cryptography the crib some
interesting information official the
network traffic
so I really interesting function as you
can see there are some interesting
function themselves like their public
key they're saying they can tell
something about it and you can look on
the function definitions on the Apple
Developer Forum and see how it is being
used so it was very interesting that the
application was evaluating function
while this fact applications was
evaluating shattered by the sounds and
call in here
public and calling infection on
objectives he is a little bit different
than C++ in C++ Object point is followed
by the function parent function them and
function parameters and object for the
objective see the perimeters different
as it comes after the color and
dysfunctional always get into makes me
confident because these are the default
function called you may take on the
Apple Developer Forum the function
prototypes its case the block size
public key name and takes the security
trust
and this specific costs and says like
fashion
certainly cannot be read this classic
authors needs to be used somewhere that
function actually able to function and
its specific location I can simply used
vulgar to obtain either the private or
public depending on their implementation
so when I jumped to do cross references
it looked like it to memory allocation
and then set it to the 02 aliquet
something else store it makes me curious
because that looks like anyone areata
certificate these are the specific steps
that you need to take and
and just as a reference lol DBA comments
pretty much similar to the GDP colored
ok the encryption file the location for
encrypted file and it is being called by
the probably the function is being
private or public key reversing on my
mind is looking like this
observed application what is doing drove
encryption and obtained for that by
binary what needs to be taken out and
combine static and dynamic analysis and
now once I obtain a location ideas first
week function names what I need to do is
just to observe and analyze binary on
the debugger so I reattach my executable
to their old it'd be so I can define the
good thing about dividing and reverse
engineering environment if you can
simply path a break point to do specific
function as it is shown on the very
first screenshot like file encrypted
encrypted file whatever eight-point run
the executable and see what happens and
I run until the end of the extra
function by stepping in and then i dont
memory with 11 GB comment like memory
card file take it to the flat file and I
opened it was containing two SATA
Seagate it is a public that case however
when I was testing the replication the
prism implemented done a private key
later on they switch to do
public it was a good thing and correct
implementation
groups most common issues are related to
the week so retired control you secure
storage like the information stored on
your local device which is supposed to
be on for example keychain and etc and
people things like unemployment
programmers are always lazy and they
didn't like it
mobile application so you can not pretty
much you cannot do pretty much anything
so they rely on most of the time
assumptions so if you want to analyze
group we can do I tend to do subsections
like application mapping climbed a
psychic network assets are attacks it
pretty much similar to do mobile storage
replication assessment but only subtle
differences binary is being involved the
platform mapping and data flow is
different and the API said being used
his friend part of the frame can find
someone else's needs to be involved to
do testing
can be a shoot for instance forwarding
your traffic to your device of course
you need a jailbroken device its
entirety dynamic port forwarding so I
can pass today my Wireshark interesting
to have a packet analyzer if you
recently implemented copper catalyzed
are so you don't need a lot of packages
to be able to run on making make some
violent so it could be interesting
because if you manage to obtain public
or the private key that increased
communication you can't really thick
lips your practice for example wilder
Wireshark implemented yet
script whenever it's going slow here you
can easily decrypt communication on the
fly but what if not what if you cannot
obtain increase or encryption key at all
so this time the function who can come
into play
faction who can use a technique is
simply we are using to function
you are calling your function i Function
created by you obtain the information
passed by the function and then let go
to function
supposed to work as a tease and the
fires SSL implementation of it as it
follows its Alcan takes needs to be
defined and the data past as a pointer
date a land and size to be processed and
in a similar manner as a seller rights
operation is the finest as well you have
dated a talent in the process ID but
they will be processed implement and you
can check out the details on the
development Developer Center important
and interesting parties you can
implement and function who so these are
ready and the right call will be
forwarded to your own function and
obtain the content and let the
application
road as it is supposed to be the way
it's supposed to be so we implemented a
sample who the source code will be
published on it up for you can take a
look on it is simply a dynamic library
so you can involve dynamic library while
executing an executable and it'll
intercept while the function cause as
defined so you can obtain the cell
contacts
so weak came once implemented early care
and interesting analogy Captain Hook's
style so we intercept every function
keeps a copy for us
content for herself as a similar money
or NSA does in the manner it look like
this you cannot do everything in the
plaintext so the point we want to draw
is that you know rootkit from the IRS
and my mind is not constitute area
anymore if you take a look on drop on
the project is one of the node only it's
simply implement software implant it
starting formation and passes to do
anything for storing and this is the
sample code maybe you have seen on
internet it is iPhone rootkit book so it
simply shows and implement the sample
hooting for example the microphone
listening so you can implement a call
that because while you are talking
someone else on your phone
the penetration tester you did binary
analysis you would wanna do some
automation day-to-day tasks to be able
to accomplish something
actions that you don't wanna do by
handle the time and make some gains some
free time on analyzing two interesting
things so while the application level
analysis really like we really love to
use extensions the extent of my writing
Python or Java code and there are short
party interesting extension that you can
use these are the most common extension
classes that you can use to play
extended frame framework like to
retrieve cookies extended called mixed
or register actions and interest in
science fiction points perot has revised
counter just simply sent automated
playlist and return back so you can
define all points to automate
application-level analysis and these are
the sum
come on extension that you can use for
example interesting one else could be
active can vary can passively planning a
party in injection and it can also be
interesting if you are using trip
inspect scanner so you can share the
results between our plan expect
additional color is looking like this
you can define specific actions for
example contacts in the firing line size
XXS injection an extra like comparing
different return rallies better there
can be a potential privilege escalation
or not and burp extension one of the
interesting one is where you can do
generation automation based on for
example username and password brute
forcing and one of my favorite one is
Exetel validator play a game where you
run JavaScript running on that server it
simply sends your payload to the server
and you run an extension generated
validated payload pat so it will able to
validate whether application is
vulnerable by simply matching regular
expression the keeper to the five yr
functional relations so if the job
security is being
and weight it on the insertion points
the application you are testing that
means we can alternate testing without
dealing the manual analysis so did the
sample test area defined payloads and
it's just ran to the store and we are
taking record is being matched the
regular expression be defined on the
scare and they said thank you are right
you have any questions
yeah
when it comes to designing an
application it's
well i assume that it's better to use
application medications done that but do
you have any suggestions about more
detail
checklist for developers for wireless
applications
well i has already defined
tactical handguard that you can apply
wild designing your cryptography
application Exchange and etc
was to simply standardization of the
Common Fund burner abilities I would
definitely recommend taking on the
development forum and other questions I
guess no