I'm soda bottles from Bala bit and we
are a Hungarian vendor and you might
have heard about us let me start the
four-story fifteen years ago there was a
guy who thought about what to write for
his teases and it turned out that he had
no good tools for log management so he
decided to write software for that
purpose
this to Paul's sister Kenji this is what
you might know is well known and open
source community and this is our leading
products for log management and we've
all just introduced in a few months to
the market product called transporter
which is great too
to analyze the behavior of users it is
great to let you see the anomalous to
let you see where to focus on and today
we've all talked a bit about a control
box we will talk about that solution
where he is a privilege activity
monitoring at all and how many of you
know what this is
hands up everyone who knows that oh I
think there are more people please tell
me what this is
yes exactly so shocked control box is
like the black box for the eighth
infrastructure its security device and
it helps challenged us to learn more and
more about
requirements which are changing but
before I get into death let me explain
what shall control box does so it's
basically transparent proxy based
solution which takes the connection
request from the client side
Creuset and our stores and after re-
encrypting it gets forwarded to the
server side this happens also the other
way around so we perform a friend
so-called friendly man in the middle so
you understand why it's really important
to be well prepared for requirements in
terms of security for our customers
before I go on let me show you how
amazing this is in real life to do that
will open an RDP connection to a
completely normal Windows Server and
right after moving dad over to dad
desktop session behaves exactly like
this session would act without an
appliance I will just quickly create
some content that you see that this is
exactly what we will see when I replayed
a session and it's really simple to
replay such recordings as you might
recall we are in between the client and
the server and we offer the transparent
way to replay to record and an easy way
to replay the sessions I recorded all
already have already recorded some
special
but easily browse through the recorded
sessions for now have all look forward
confidence because I remember that I
entered it as you see and we immediately
see the results we see it was entered
here just like if we would sit behind
administrator and if it is interesting
for us we can immediately replay it in
our browser that's i think thats
fantastic because it's really a great
tool to replay the sessions and there's
also one thing which makes it really a
great security tool for you if open SSH
connection for example they want to
login I haven't started tutor and how
it's also able to protect your
infrastructure but why is that neither
you must know the things we used to use
to solve our security challenges are
challenging task not really usable
anymore because we can't really put a
fence around are important service
anymore
computers are in the cloud and
third-party administrators are accessing
our servers we don't have such a tight
control over security offer
infrastructure anymore that like the
used to have so to keep our system safe
and secure is an ongoing challenge for
you as administrators as people who are
dealing with
security incidents on a daily basis and
also for us as a vendor to provide the
best tools for you to successfully
address those challenges and it's also a
big responsibility because if something
malicious happens then you're the ones
whose name is on the line and afterwards
we are the ones who you claim to not
helping you in having a secure safe and
secure system but you think why me why
would anybody
hack my systems why would I be to target
this can happen for several reasons
let's say on a boring Saturday afternoon
some script kiddie decides to try out
his new tools and they pick your service
to mess around with or you have a third
party company who are doing
administrative services for you and they
decide to find out more
confidential information about the
company then you could provide them by
yourself or you work for a company who
has really important data and provide
crucial services and some hackers are
paid to find the weaknesses and weak
points of your security infrastructure
all those could be applied to any of us
so what could we do the most important
thing is to do everything to stop these
attacks to make it as difficult as
possible for them to gain access to your
systems to your date up its it seems
like an impossible task impossible task
but let's see if we could address this
if we could stop those attackers as
you know when you have your
infrastructural publicly available when
you when you offer services which can be
reached by people not system itself
where you need to another
system around it where you can put
borders in protecting it from
unauthorized access but you can harden
the system you can put layers before it
to make it difficult to reach such a
layer could be let's say our solution we
have hardened appliance shop control box
especially to make it really difficult
for you guys want to access your system
to gain access to that we focused on
those parts wear something could be
exploited and we also want to offer you
a different concept because if you apply
needed level of trust where it needs to
be applied and you have two healthy
level of mistrust where it needs to be
there then it's an easier task when do
you need to put your trust in first of
all you need to trust your co-workers
you need to trust the people who have
normal access to your servers you need
to trust the vendor that he does
everything in his power to provide hard
and security tool to make towards the
tax really difficult and you need to
have some healthy mistrust in the
direction of the people who let's say
our outsourced people and you have only
some isolates and some legal contracts
that protect your infrastructure and of
course this will change the whole
picture because right now as security
approaches used to be I like that that
you have tight control from a technical
perspective over what is going on in
your system if someone has access to
your resources and what with this
approach with the solution like that
features hardened
for your purposes you can let go a bit
of the control you can allow your
trusted people more and even you're a
bit mister so people can can have bigger
possibilities but still with having
everything audited having everything
recorded gives you a level of
observation which is like the flight
data recorder you have seen previously
so what what is what is really important
in this area that you need to find ways
to address those changing requirements
you find tools that helps you to address
these and you need to always educate
yourself you need to quit question the
Wonder to make sure that they really
they're really aware of your needs and
they really want to provide you with the
tools which you which will make you
successfully successful and yeah that's
that's what I want to leave here today
as a message those three important
things always find a way to be a step
ahead of the cybercriminals of the
militias attackers always surround
yourself with people who you can trust
that they are reliable and always get
the tools which makes it possible for
you to achieve safe and secure
infrastructure thank you very much for
listening to those thoughts and thank
you for being here and you all if you
have more detailed questions about this
new approach of observation instead of
control or the technologies we are
offering you you can find us at our
proof and you can also visit our web
page on the internet do you have any
questions if not then thank you very
much for being here