this is you send there and I'm going to
talk today about attacking white Targets
in big bouncy
so um who am I understand they are known
as USA 98g
I mean backbone cheese since 2014
approximately I'm also the CEO of Lobby
Minify which provides band testing
services to companies
so the subject of today is really
interesting because every time you might
get some white Targets in big monkey and
you're not sure where to start and how
to how to approach a Target and start um
hunting for breaks on it
so what are white scoop targets what
script targets refer to a system or
network that is being tested for
vulnerabilities over a large area
of range or components
so some examples of white sweep circuit
in background are obviously Yahoo Apple
FIS atlasan and you have other couple of
um really interesting targets and really
interesting by multiple
programs that I provide wild scoop
targets
so what's some interesting
in choosing white targets when doing
back bouncy
so because of the size of the of the
scoop
um there is like a bigger chance for you
to find vulnerabilities because the
scope is really
um large and so you might find some
assets that other hackers haven't hacked
on yet and that you might be lucky
finding those um
other people haven't found yet
so the main interesting part in this um
in this in this um whole thing is
finding the targets that others haven't
hacked on
so this increases your chance to find
liabilities as you have a bigger surface
to explore
what are the challenges that come into
place when hacking on this kind of
targets
so the scoop is too large and you don't
know where to start
it's easy to miss vulnerabilities
without using a systematic approach
because you're just like random opening
this link closing this lane and then you
you get lost you don't know where just
where you have
stopped your last um hiking session
and as it's a wise group targets it
means also that other hackers might be
hacking on it because they are also
um looking for the low-hanging fruits
so the strategies is start by doing your
casual subdomain enumeration
and then use a lot of
permutation based on the words found on
the target so that means that for
example if I find
um a sub domain list for this target.com
that I'm hacking on I'm going to try to
grab as much words as possible from this
list that I had and then try to do some
permutation based on these words
so for example here
um when we use Google DNS by ships then
you might find for example for firstly
you might have
125 sub domains after using dualgns and
doing some permutations and resolving
again now you have way more sub domains
you have 172 sub domains
but that's just like
um a really small amount of supplements
you can find because by doing more more
and more permutation you're likely to to
be going to find many interesting
many interesting sub domain that other
people have haven't seen yet
so we need more subdomains what do we do
there is this new tool called regulator
that's a really good by um trumpet that
I have seen recently and so basically
what it does is that it does like some
intelligent permutation on the list that
you have
and so by using these tools after
grudginess you might
really get way most of the means that
you had because it's going to be to make
it better
um permutation list and once you resolve
that I bet that you are going to find
way more some domains um to hack on
what I usually love doing is that after
doing these bus steps I'm going again to
repeat the same process two or three
times to make sure that I get way more
sub domain that I had in the first place
so keep going deeper and
um don't hesitate to do full power
scanning on the subtle means found GUI
Wayback machine our ship archive.org
just grew up on the the links that you
can because everything is going to be
really
um useful for the next steps
you can also use Katana Goose spider
hackroller to to grow the subdomains and
save all the output in one file sort
unique and then you have a really good
list of um of family or really good
links or from targets you can hack on on
point some maybe PHP file other
interesting files that you might find
and start gripping for addressing
strings in this list of um crowded files
so for example I'm going to search for
for admin because I know that I'm good
at finding authentication
bypasses in admin panels
or maybe
um I'm going to look for application
that type of registration and points so
that I can do some authenticated scan uh
to educated testing
and maybe I'm going to hack on API so
I'm just going to search for apis and
start hiking on that
so use also darking often people just do
Google working but they don't do being
working Dr good working
ask.fm.king and
um while doing hiking on backbone
targets and docking I have found some
many cases where Bing does find
endpoints or subdomains or pages that
Google haven't found when talking on
Google
so don't leverage this powerful tools
and don't hesitate to try to talk on
every
um search engine that you find
so here let's go and start with some
real world examples so
um I had this company I was hacking on
that had a huge School
and after going through the previous
steps I found the following subdomain
which says like API something.target.com
and browsing to it it says like API pre
version number blah blah blah download
and this is the APK apks that um
the company is using for this for
employees there
I download all the apis and started
looking for some interesting and print
some interesting secrets and I have
found
nothing
so I copied the title of the page I've
pasted it on Google and Bing and I'm
just like trying to share some other
Pages using the same title and they have
found the same
um page on another subdomain but now it
give this gave me
um
um this gave me another page using the
same
the same like um
uh sending me the same app AP guys but
now with retail modification little
thing so we can see on the seats this
says 10 January
2022 while the other one back there said
9th of May 2022
and so this said this was like oops this
is going
um good because this is something that
happened from before let me download
this and see because obviously most of
the time the earlier version of
application are the one that contains
the most vulnerabilities and maybe if
it's a Dev version so maybe it can
contain some credentials
and bingo while opening the application
I have found this bunch of leaks in it
dot properties file that give me like
um really good access to every aspect of
that company I was lacking on
so we had OCTA secrets we had some SMS
apis we had a lot of other
um
credentials to services
so um I also found remote command
execution on this company sub domains
after doing permutation and with them
regulator and I found this some sub
domain that I didn't have so this is
obviously not the real
um
not the real subliment PGI but um when
you find some weight scoop when you're
hiking on Race targets don't hesitate to
collaborate and ask other hackers if
they have credentials to some panels
because
so I have found this um endpoint that is
upload in my I'm calling results from
Katana and stuff and
um I opened the link and I've seen that
it needs authentication there was there
was no register on points so I just GM
at like a friend of migrizzle and I
asked man do you have some good answer
for this application I know that you're
hacking on this um company and he says
yeah and I said okay
um do you want to collaborate and then
that's how we started
and we got um these three launchers and
then we can we could um find remote
common execution because I know that
there was there was an upload on point
and um so this one point um needed a
valid XLS file
um triggered a bit to include some ASP
code and when opening the file then
there was that could be executed on the
target
so
um other things is that you can use
Axiom to leverage speed of from scanning
because for example if you get 3 000
subdomains you're not going to be able
to put for us or who's the host in one
hour or two but by using Axiom with for
example 50 or
um 60
instances DPS is you can firstly get to
that in a matter of hours so I sent I
started brute forcing the subdomains I
had with Axiom and foof and it found
some interesting file to set GP
error.php so I know that a lot of people
mind just like skip okay it says like
error it might sound like four or four
error and stuff so it's not interesting
but when opening it
I have found that it was leaking the
database credentials because it had like
an error in this in the script
um going forward you can also use
Showdown door game because
um you can do like SSL company or
organization or with the fertility
National Services and then you can find
some IPS which doesn't have
um which don't have um hostname assigned
to
so a real world example of that is that
I have found this IP from should I'm
talking I'm moving to the IP directly it
just says
um you've been redirected to octave for
Authentication
and but um don't um don't forget that
you you have always to try to find some
face on the targets that will direct you
to login or or Octan points because some
ACLS might might not be really well
configured
and by doing choosing on that um
subdomain I have found this um this
endpoint that says BPL WS login
and by sending a post request to this um
to this endpoint I have seen unsupported
media type and so I have also found out
that it uses it it accepts XML data
so the application expects XMS data
maybe we can find some xcc here
and so firstly I have started testing a
bit and it was finally vulnerable to out
of bond um
um xxc and so here we had the DDT file
on my server which contained this um
this entity which sends back a file to
my web collaborator
and after sending the blind xss payload
a blind ECC play payload and hosting the
DDT on my system then I could see that
the application was sending back the
data of the file I requested to my
collaborator on point
so another really good example of how to
approach good white scope targets is
doing more being talking because
everyone is talking on Google so maybe
you might have more more chances trying
to be on other search on Giants
so um Sandy copyright company 2022 being
Dorking it revealed a new domain that I
did not have in my data set
and it was time for me to find some
vulnerabilities and looking at the
application I have started testing
around and trying to find some
interesting things and here I have seen
that
the The Good the session cookie was
vulnerable to SQL injection and so by
sending this some sleep payload I can
see that the applications sleeping 20
um 20 000 milliseconds it's probably
that it's doing time tool on the back
end in some functions
um so the strategies mostly it's to use
tools such as
um monitoring your subdomains and try to
monitor keep up to date with some sub
domains to be able to hack on the
targets because before other hackers do
um focus on your strengths for example
if you see PHP or maybe if you say
aspects maybe this can turn you on and
start you know spending more more time
on the target
collaborate with other hackers because
obviously
um together we hit harder
and sharks of domains sharp credentials
show interesting on points maybe you
don't have the no Nations that someone
else's have
be some be consistent don't give up
easily it's not because you are not
finally get back today or tomorrow that
will never be finding a bug on this some
specific company
and the most important of all for me is
to stick to a target for at least two or
three months from myself I think that
this is a perfect time to know that um
okay I'm done hacking this target I want
to to switch but um hiking on my script
targets requires a lot of time to know
exactly how everything is built up from
the
Target side and know some tweaks that
might work on these targets
so um try to stick to a target for a
good reasonable amount of time to to to
hack on
also um while doing this um this um
talk I open I AIS out and now you can
use you can leverage chat open AI to try
to code some tools that you've always
dreamed of so for example here I ask um
chat that open AI to
read the golang tool that's going to
search for secrets in a list of your uh
all of links I will send it and then
directly it's really easy to to build
tools based on your creativity here
thank you for your time and thank you
for watching this um talk and listening
to me and I'll see you soon thank you