welcome to my talk about rfcs if you
have no freaking ID what rfcs actually
mean don't panic because that's exactly
what we're going to discuss in the next
20 minutes or so but not before I do
quick introduction of myself so my name
is
and I work as the head of hackers at
Integrity which is as you all know
um the number one book Bounty platform I
know jokes aside please do sign up it
does help my kpis but so far the
commercial message let's focus on my
research now I've been book bounty
hunting since 2011 and ever since I
think I reported over three dollar
vulnerabilities
um mostly concerning privacy the
anonymization attacks and then
especially for web applications I would
usually dig into the email and ticketing
systems
um I do consider myself a live hacking
event veteran I love them
um I love the competitive aspect but
also the fact that it just
um that you get to see so many people in
public and that you get to share so much
information and do research together
um I wouldn't really consider myself an
academic and never really went to
University
but now you know I'm I I like to do like
some research especially in-depth
research on certain subjects and to
share them with the world and I guess
this is one of them and that is also
something that my colleagues at life
hacky events May say about me is that I
just simply like reading the
documentation to do my own research in
fact in the first hour of any life
hacking event I will usually not even
open my computer but I would rather just
read the documentation and then also see
what kind of underlying infrastructure
the actual service that we are supposed
to hack has and if there's documentation
about that I will also gladly read it I
think it's really underestimated how
important this is at least I mean from
my own of observations I tend to find a
lot of vulnerabilities that could have
easily been discovered by simply reading
the books the dogs sorry they they give
you a lot of edge cases but also give
some details about Integrations and it
really helps you to think like a
developer like why they made certain
choices but especially also how they
expect their users to behave
and if we go to the master of all
documents
um really the underlying documents of
our other documents we would come to the
RFC what is an RFC it stands for request
for comments and it's basically whenever
you have an ID you can publish this as a
request for comments so everybody can
give a comment and there's special
performance on how to write an RFC and
whenever you publish this RFC it will go
or be evaluated by a task force which is
called the eitf now there's a whole
process to get your RFC officially
published by them we won't go too much
into detail because that would kind of
take us too far but what you want to
know is that rfcs have been around for a
whole while actually the first one was
published in 1969
um and also that these are not
necessarily industry standards because
there's a various amount of rfcs that
haven't really
um seen most of the World Wide Web that
are simply there
um and also just meant to be some edge
cases or more maybe experimental
informational or also simply as a joke
um one of my favorite joke rfcs are
these and they concern the IP
transmission over Aryan carriers AKA
pigeons I guess in the world in the
scenario that the world would come to an
end then we still have an RFC or a
proposal on how we can finally
communicate over pigeons but some people
were crazy enough to try this in 2001 in
Norway I guess they just released a page
of pigeons with IP packets attached to
their uh to their wings or something and
that they found out that about less than
half would actually make its destination
and you know it would take 50 to 100
minutes to get a response time back
which is not super great for Bing so let
us hope that the end of the world is not
for tomorrow uh but I just want to point
out like the the importance of of this
uh because it even finds their ways
because it's an official RFC it finds
their ways to book Bounty uh guidelines
and this is a screenshot of Goldman's
sex guidelines and they will officially
ask you not to send over any pigeons
that know how to sniff the traffic from
their office I guess that's uh that's a
very complete
um big Bounty policy I can only upload
this but it kind of shows how there's
like a lot of
rfcs on very on various subjects let's
say and that they shouldn't always
um be taken seriously but some of these
rfcs they are rather obsolete now
um yet we do use them every day there's
for example one rfcs that states that a
subdomain or you know or just a URL
pointing to a document server for
example to to a host HTTP documents or
HTTP HTML documents should start with
www which is already a long word to
pronounce uh let alone type every time I
think if it would just all omit the www
from speech but especially also from
from writing in URLs we would like live
10 years longer but yeah it is what it
is it was part of a request years ago of
Tim bernersley and now we're still stuck
with it but even this guy I mean the guy
who is
um who they say invented the Internet or
is would have been one of the creators
of the internet even he regrets some of
this I think he recent simply said in in
an interview actually that he's
regretting you know these two dashes
right over here because they don't
really serve a purpose and you know it
just adds to the characters but
apparently that was just the way some
programming uh syntax was was done back
then but so you see things that are
obsolete now but invented years ago they
still make it to our current life every
day
um and I think this is a very good
picture to kind of represent a modern
digital
infrastructure it's built upon years and
years and years of good ideas but also
maybe some questionable ideas or just
ideas that are no longer really relevant
but it doesn't mean that all of these
old standards or old rfcs are no longer
present in our current technology so
knowledge of them can be quite important
um what is interesting however is that
some of these rfcs even if they're not
really known they will disclose some
security risks
um but most developers however will not
go and read the RFC of just everything
that they're creating so as a hacker it
kind of creates an opportunity window
um so if you decide to read the rfcs it
may end up in some nice bugs and
sometimes it's just a given like if you
would read the rfcs most rfcs since a
certain date they require you to list
security consideration even if there's
none they require you to think about
like how can this possibly be abused so
whatever you're doing research or maybe
a web or other component and trying to
hack it please do check out the security
concentration section in the actual RFC
um but also
sometimes there's mistakes I mean humans
maker of season humans also make
mistakes and sometimes it will happen
that there's a crucial error in an RFC
that people have already implemented
that needs to be adapted so it can be
very good to kind of get the Errata of
the rfcs and see what the differences or
how certain things were corrected
because some technology may still run on
the first version of the actual rfcs
something personally that I always tend
to look for are the optional parameters
or you know extensions that are
disclosed in rfcs why because they may
be very optional like pointing to the
edge cases developer may still choose to
implement them or support them but
they're like hidden you know they're
very often retested as part of a pen
test and they can be a hidden treasure
to customer data
I'm just going to start with uh with a
common RFC that you may have come across
or at least with the implementation of
it which is of course domain name I mean
all the assets or most of the assets
will have to test will contain a domain
name so here's my question to you and
feel free to answer in the comments
esponeria.easy.edu is this a valid
qualified fully qualified domain name
feel free to answer whatever you think
um so the answer is actually no because
according to RFC 1034
every part so the subdomain and then of
course the root domain which is IC and
then also the TLD which is the last part
they would need a trailing dot at the
end because it signifies the end of that
part and it also counts for the last
part now obviously you don't see this a
lot but it doesn't mean that it's no
longer supported for example if you
would go to Google and like write a DOT
behind the.com it will actually just
continue to work or like interestingly
it will treat it as a totally different
origin so this may already lead to some
interesting bugs but yeah it's it's
something interesting to consider by the
way you can also bypass some paywalls
with it
um so it's always just add a DOT and see
what happens
now I just want to give you guys a very
specific example of this for which I got
a nice Bounty
um and this report is public so I can
talk about it
um so basically I was testing Shopify as
part of a life hacking event and they
had a couple of steps where you could
link your own Shopify instance to custom
domain obviously whenever you start a
shop you don't want a URL like wholesale
shops shopifyapps.com I mean you want
your own domain for example in the indie
or shop.nt.io
um and the only thing they required you
to do is set the cname your C name of
your subdomain so shop.into.io to this
uh wholesale shops shopifyapps.com
and this would allow you within the
Shopify app to link your domain and that
would be enough from the moment you
would do this it would now serve your
website so very simply steps but
obviously there's some flaws with it I
mean they whenever I have a dangling
pointer to this I can just link my own
shop in the UI and I can essentially
take it take over that domain I can
perform a sub domain takeover so this is
how it looked like whenever you would
link your wholesale domain it now no
longer shows anything Shopify it does
show shop.nt.io and it asks you to sign
in
so let's say that we wanna you know we
wanna link it again so what if an
attacker so you see this is already
linked over here um so I already set it
up and now you would go to Shopify would
go to wholesale preferences and enter my
domain uh for your own store of course
and you try to link my domain it will
give you an error it will say I'm sorry
um person on the other side I can I
cannot do this for you why of course
because it's already connected to my
store and you cannot take the domain
name of somebody else
so I was just thinking what if we just
enter
shop.integrity.aio instead because for
the system it's not the same same domain
name but for the DNS it's actually just
the same the same you know I can just
make it propagate to the same thing and
this actually worked so I was able to
link you or you as an attacker would be
have been able to link like the fully
coil qualified domain name for any
Shopify domain wholesale domain out
there
um and you could just link your own
store so this would be shop.nt.io and
this would be shop.nt.io dot according
to Shopify these were two different
stores and one was not linked but the c
m records was also pointing to it so it
said okay let me just
um serve the website on this in this
case it was my real store so that is of
course a problem because now if I could
have enacted JavaScript on there I could
have just recreated the web page and
entered some phishing credentials or
phishing like capture keylog or whatever
and I could have yeah essentially taken
over their accounts and it would still
have been on my domain name that was of
course still SSL protected Etc so it was
quite an interesting bug it's also
public on hacker one if you want to have
a read
um I can see if I can drop the link in
the description there's also a more if
you didn't get the whole part there's
also an explainer video that I made on
it and I got like 3.1 K in total just
for a simple Dot so it's it's just a
good trick and I'm sure that there's
more more of these uh vulnerable
then there's also URLs domain name is
not necessarily URL because a URL also
includes the part after the.com for
example
you will see a lot of URLs being used in
various web applications
the URLs can be quite funky and I
recently saw this tweets by better which
is the author of curl and he asked us if
this is a valid URL
so if you think this is a valid URL
please do let me know something in the
comments
because it is a valid URL so
congratulations everybody that thought
that this is a valid URL but
um I wouldn't say it looks like one so
let's see what this URL is actually made
of first we have a scheme that we have
the user then we have
a password which is slash slash HTTP
slash
a host
above which also contains double slashes
but it doesn't really matter it's still
perfectly valid according to the RFC
then there's a query parameter and then
there's the hash and that's it right
this is a fully
functional URL that is completely valid
and compliant with the RFC
now and I believe or orange side has a
great talk on this we won't go too much
into depth we don't have that time
but basically what is interesting about
knowing all of these tricks and knowing
how how confusing URLs can be is that
various URL parsers will also treat them
differently
and for example if you would have an ad
symbol over here or maybe over there one
URL parser would think that the URL
Starts Here whereas in reality the URL
uh would start there and maybe other URL
parsers would go to the last odds and
would take it which would basically
start from here which would allow you to
bypass whitelists or blacklists so
that's always important to consider
than if you're not dealing with any
domain names of URLs of course we also
have IP addresses
so let's take a look at an IP address
and ways to write it so of course this
IP address can be written in various
ways you can omit some numbers you can
just convert it to hexadecimals and then
of course you can also omit some numbers
there's also of course the IPv6
notations the hexadecimal notation
etc etc I mean the sky is the limit and
you can also go for the decimal notation
so uh this this is a perfectly valid IP
address and if you're as a system only
blocking this then of course you you
kind of have a problem because all of
them will resolve to the same IP address
um so yeah it's it's always very good to
know to read the RC and to see on how
many different ways we can write
something as simple as an IP address
same with email addresses by the way if
we would look at an email address it
looks pretty straightforward right
because a local part and a domain and
that's really it but let's allow look at
the local Parts it's supposed to have
according to the RC Latin letters digits
that's all normal and dots but not in
front not in the back and not in the
middle like two two behind each other
but what's quite funky is that it
actually allows you to have all of these
characters in the email address so this
is a valid email address and of course
for people for example even in Sweden or
Norway or in China they they also
support utf-8 some clients still do not
support it but it doesn't say that it's
not a valid email address so this is
also a valid email address which would
of course expose us to normalization
attacks and then if we quote the actual
Parts the local part we can even do more
funky stuff and we can have an atom
there we can have slashes in there
spacious steps and even emojis which of
course you know will lead to a various
set of payloads which I will show in a
minute
we have also wild cards so you can use a
plus a minus and parenthesis to get some
stuff in there
and then the domain name itself is less
funky there's less flexibility over here
but what is interesting is that you can
have IP addresses in there within
brackets this may be used for ssrf
so it's also quite quite interesting and
of course this allows you to inject a
couple of interesting or bypass
um the valid email Checker of various
web apps and still inject a couple of
interesting payloads such as cross-site
scripting templating action SQL index
and Etc but even parameter pollution and
header injection
people tend to forget about these but I
found my most critical bugs actually
using headering action in email
addresses because of course if you can
get into an SMTP server and make it do
fancy stuff that's that's kind of where
all the good things are
um there's actually like if you would
send this out uh this would actually
still work in Gmail so you can there's
like this HTML in action supported by
Gmail you can just try it out and this
would be the email address you would be
sending uh from reported it to the to
the Google security team but it seems to
be working as intended
um so yeah it's uh it's like a little
Easter egg for hackers
um if somebody can pop an exercise from
it please go ahead you can keep the
bounty but other than that of course you
can you can bypass some other stuff as
well for example situations where you
have a white listed domain name that you
have to you know you have still have to
receive the email as an attacker but
it's from a company I mean it has to end
with a company domain that you know of
course are not a part of and you can try
stuff like this right because email
Parcels they tend to separate emails
with semicolon so what happens is that
you know you would try this which is a
valid email address it would try to send
to all the parts so first to India it
doesn't work then to NT at nt.aio which
actually works and then to the last part
it doesn't work as well this email would
actually arrive and you would still be
able to get in even though your domain
name is not the same as a whitelisted
domain
um so yeah there's there's that actually
um I do know that slack was not actually
vulnerable to this but it's an example
um simply because it's a It's the Most
Known technique or this is used
um something else that picked my
interests are in subscribe links
um because whenever for example this is
or and and forgive me the subtle product
marketing uh but emails tend to have
like an unsubscribe link and for some
reason and I didn't know how back in the
days
um your email client will actually allow
you to unsubscribe even without
scrolling all the way down so assuming
okay where do they get this information
from
um so I looked into the email headers
and I saw that most of these emails
would have like and this was also part
of the RFC a list and subscribe header
which would allow you to either send an
email or send a post request to a
certain URL
um and then if you would do this for
example let's say that we would set the
list and subscribe to meal 2 at
co.test.com
set a subject and then a body sent money
now to whatever
and this is what basically you would see
I mean the attacker would spam you with
stuff and you would try to unsubscribe
your Gmail client would just be like
okay I need to send an email to CEO at
target.com this is the subject this is
the body
um and it would actually arrive now this
was not actually working in Gmail uh
quite important but I was trying out
some email clients
um a couple of years ago and it actually
worked it didn't work in Gmail but I'm
using the the same layouts as an example
um there's also ssrf
um of course you've seen the URL in the
header so what if instead of an email we
just Supply URL and then we click and
subscribe so I'm just putting my burp
collaborator payload over here or just
my own server and actually like whenever
this person would click and subscribe
the actual email client again it was not
Gmail would send this ping back to my
server which was which was quite cool
and then one last example to finish with
phone numbers
um I haven't really talked about this
technique a lot I'm still exploring but
feel free to do your own research and
use it for book monthly purposes as well
we all think telephone numbers look like
this right you start with a global kind
of call Country ID and then you have the
local number
um pretty straightforward a lot of
applications use them but then I went to
read the RFC and it turns out there's a
lot of additional parameters you can add
to it you can supply the extension like
after it
um and you can have like phone contacts
like it's it's meant for really old
systems but many email validators will
still take care of these
um parameters and they will still allow
them so you can also Supply some service
codes so you know it's when everyone you
you would call like a service line and
you would be asked to deep dial a couple
of options then you can basically
already dial them as you're calling the
number to to speed things up
um so a lot of people don't know this so
naturally I was looking for ways to to
kind of abuse it and I was starting with
this one because this one obviously can
include some Latin characters
um
and first I was like hey maybe we can
just let me just try to like verify this
this phone number and see if it actually
would arrive and it would actually
arrive so I would try to and this is my
own phone number I should probably have
redacted that but it just don't
call me
um and um yeah basically I was able to
um to get some
some some confirmation codes in so this
was actually a valid email address and
the service would actually confirm my
email address which was you know which
was quite cool
but then again what if instead of this
um your confirmed email address the one
that you got a code for for actually
contains a cross-size scripting payload
this is an example of an actual website
and it kind of worked
um you can you can get cross-size
scriptings in valid phone numbers
also this is a ref because this thing is
actually supposed to contain a domain
name and then some old systems may do I
haven't really seen a get lookup yet but
some old systems may do a DNS lookup for
some reason
uh but more interestingly and this can
lead to account takeovers OTP spraying
slash Brute Force
um this Behavior happens whenever
you know you get a couple of attempts to
get like a password reset code per phone
number but if you can always
um
get like a different phone number but
the back ends will convert it to the
original phone number for example using
some common common libraries that also
include this flow then this can lead to
account takeover
um let's say that your scenario this is
the victim's
um phone number a urine scenario that
you kind of want to get their passwords
reset codes it gets sent as a text
message to their phone number but of
course you can't really know what the
what the code is but still you wanna you
wanna reset their passwords so one of
the things that you can do is
um
you could technically like first thing
every 100 will do is try all the codes
or try to just submit a lot of the same
like do this over and over and over
again try the same code every single
time and then just pray and spray and
hope that one day you will hit the right
code but most of these systems will just
lock you out
and then you have to wait for 10 minutes
and then maybe 30 minutes this also
prevents some higher bills on their side
but let's say that you know I'm
trying to get like
uh to guess the OTP that was sent to my
phone number which is which is this
phone number after four minutes or four
attempts I get a block for 10 minutes we
can easily bypass this for some systems
and eventually reach account takeover
let's say that we have the same but not
really the same phone number so my phone
number plus an extension added to it and
just try it over and over and over again
so we can get in four to five to six
requests
then we get another phone number that is
also resolving to my account on the back
end 789 and we kind of automate this
until we are able to kind of test all of
the potential codes of course we can
also test the same code every single
time because this really shows you that
per email per phone number you can just
test it and whenever the back end kind
of normalizes it and also relates to
your accounts but still the blocking
procedure is done on uh on a string
basis and doesn't really consider this
you can just do zero click account
takeover by abusing these very easily
and you'd be surprised how many how many
systems still support it so after a
while you will find the correct codes
and you'll be able to log in and reset
the password obviously there's also
stuff like buffer overflow
there were some spoofing vulnerabilities
so for example where you supply the
local number here and then the first
like in a parameter pollution attack the
first one would be uh like this this
would be a Dutch phone number and this
would be a Belgian phone number uh but
then one system would see it as a ditch
phone number the other system would see
it as a Belgian phone number some
scenarios you would be able to if
somebody with exactly the same local
phone number with the different country
code signed up
um you would be able to take on their
account by the system accidentally
taking the wrong parameter and sending
the password reset code to your account
so I mean feel free to to hunt for this
I've seen it walking in a lot of
interesting uh like Fortune 500
companies
um they fixed some of it already uh but
yeah
um feel free to uh to test for it and
let me know how it goes always happy to
to do more research on it but it's just
an example I found this whenever When I
Was preparing for this talk
um so it really shows that the moment
you start researching some rfcs you can
actually find some some great stuff with
it thank you so much for attending this
30 minute talk and do not forget to
follow us on Twitter and master them
thank you