sorry I'm short y'all can see me in the
back so Krista to make the next thing
awesome today and you are here at my
presentation so I will do my best to
make this awesome and I'm a newbie so
thank you for coming to see my
presentation I really appreciate that
anybody came at all so thank you my name
is Celeste I did graduate from Kent
State with a computer science degree in
December of last year so I am very much
a newbie but I have been in the computer
science field since 2013 so I work at
Kent State all throughout college doing
log analysis I even had an internship at
the FBI doing cybersecurity but don't
ask me about it because I can't tell you
uh and then I now work for a company
called Oh a connection full-time doing
log analysis and Incident Response oh
and I love puzzles and cats but that's a
different presentation and then I know a
lot of you have a lot more cybersecurity
experience than I do so I'm always open
to feedback from comments whether it's
about my presentation or just my
speaking skills in general I also have a
brand new website called I don't speak
geek where I will be publishing all of
these slides so you don't have to worry
about taking notes or pictures of the
slides or anything and then of course
you can email me too with any of your
feedback comments as well as mention it
to me here so the way I see it LOB's are
all part of a puzzle all the different
types of logs we can connect whether
it's DNS logs firewall logs web
application logs you name it are your
puzzle pieces that come together to get
a big picture of what's going on in your
systems tada look so you have no idea
how hard that was to put together so
take a minute to appreciate that slide
so what I want to cover with you guys
today I'm really briefly going to talk
about some of the tools that you can use
to analyze your logs but I'm not going
to talk about that too much because it's
not the main point and there's a lot of
other presentations that go way more
in-depth than this one I do and then I'm
gonna go over some real quick and easy
searches that you can set up in your log
aggregator to start getting a bit
picture of what's going on in your
system and then I'm going to talk about
how you can extend this presentation
more than just a couple searches that I
talk through and then of course if you
guys have any questions I'm open to
answering those as well so the tools and
your log aggregators there's a lot of
different types of log aggregators out
there that'll accomplish what you're
looking for there's a full list complete
with cost and feature comparison that
sacrified comm which is this link that
you all can't see but for the purpose of
this presentation all the examples are
gonna be from Splunk just that's what
I'm most familiar with but a lot of
these should accomplish what you're
looking to do just a high-level view of
how these work so of course you need to
get logs into your aggregator you really
can't do analysis without it of course
you can always import your logs into the
aggregator but a lot of them also have
agents you can install on the computer
or server you want to get logs from and
then just forward those back to your log
aggregator once they get there you'll
have to parse your logs depending on
what system you use
I think log stash calls it the filter
Splunk calls of the indexer regardless
it's gonna go through your logs and make
them searchable usually by turning them
into key value pairs and then once
you've done that you're ready to start
searching you've got all your public
pieces in your box it's time to start
putting the puzzle together so when I
first started with log analysis of
course I started right out of college so
I don't have the systems administration
background or the networking background
that a lot of other people and InfoSec
have so I got to learn all about the
systems at the same time I was learning
how to do log analysis and I was really
really really overwhelmed by the sheer
amount of logs that are generated like
overwhelmingly amount of logs and then
there's no good resort resources online
that say here are 10 things everybody
should be monitoring for they're like oh
look at DNS logs and I go ok cool
looking at the NS logs what am I looking
for so I put together this search now
that I've been doing it for a few years
that way you guys can get started doing
long analysis
some start seeing that big picture so
the first thing I want to go over is
password changes after hours of course
this varies by company but in general
employees don't really log in before
7:00 a.m. or after 6:00 p.m. they're
even less likely to be changing their
password during those times so you can
monitor for that kind of activity to see
if there's anything unusual going on of
course you can do this with a lot of
different log types you can do it with
windows logs web application log etc for
this particular example I chose to look
at Windows logs
um can we hear me okay I feel like I'm
going in out okay cool so for Windows
logs there's event codes which specify
sort of what's going on event code for
7:00 to 3:00 means that a user tried to
change their own password and for 7:00
to 4:00 means that somebody tried to
change somebody else's password so
there's also the security ID field which
identifies the users involved the first
one is the user who is affected by the
change and then the second is the user
who made the change I have that
backwards first is the user who made the
change seconds these are affected and
then of course we're mostly interested
in the hour in which this occurred so I
created a new field that extracts the
hour value out of the time stamps so we
can look at just that value and then I
specify we're only interested if it's
less than 7 or greater than 18 which is
6 p.m. and then of course because logs
are really painful to look at we're
going to take out all the important
information and put it in a table so I
just pulled out the timestamp the users
involved in whether or not they were
successful of course you can add more
information like where the change
occurred IP address all that sorts of
stuff so here you can see that I changed
my password at 7 p.m. if it's small
that's what happened so of course
password changes can occur for all sorts
of different reasons what's more
interesting is what happens around this
password change so if you see that I
changed my password and then all sudden
I'm sending out 50,000 emails or I
updated my direct deposit information
that's a little bit more concerning so
changes to ad groups are particularly
important
specifically ones that give highly
privileged access so think domain admin
network admin workstation admin those
are important groups that you really
want to pay attention to who's being
added or removed from those groups so
once again I chose to look at Windows
event logs event code for seven to eight
is a user who is added to an ad group
and for seven to nine as a user was
removed from an ad group and then of
course monitoring every ad group change
would be a bit intense especially
because a lot of AD group changes happen
as part of normal business operations so
I chose to specify a few ad accounts or
D groups that I was interested in
monitoring access to so once again you
have your security ID field with the
user who made the change and the user
who was affected by the change this time
there's a third value that specifies
what ad group was involved and then I
added a few extra fields just to make it
a little bit more human readable to
quickly determine whether a user is
being added or removed from the group
and then once again we throw it all into
a table so here you can see that I added
my boyfriend Zack to the main admin
group but Zack does not work at the same
company as I do so that's probably a
little bit of a problem multiple account
lockout so sometimes an account can be
locked out you know continuously over
and over again simply because there's a
bad password sync you know something
along those lines it can also be an
early indicator of a brute force attack
so it's worth paying attention to so
once again we're looking at windows logs
and I'm taking the account lockout log
which is four seven four zero and I'm
grouping them by user so all of the logs
that have the same user or I all now
group together and then I'm specifically
interested where there's more than one
lockout because of course users can miss
enter their password a couple times get
locked out you know that's normal but
once you start seeing more than one
lockout account that becomes a lot more
interesting and then once again we can
throw it all into a table
I also created a new field specifically
for the timestamp Splunk isn't real
happy when you group events to get
other that timestamp stops working
properly so I created a special field
for that just so we can see the lockout
times and then in the table you can see
I got locked out of exchange multiple
times all within about 20 minutes what
happened was I changed my password and
then the mail app on my phone didn't
realize that and kept trying to log in
the same you know old password so and is
this a security issue probably not but
it does help us help operations so a lot
of people see us as the know people you
know we just oh can we do this no can we
do this no you know so the more that we
can help operations and other teams the
less scary we seem to the rest of the
company and then they're more likely to
help us when we actually need them to do
something so these kind of searches will
help them as well
generic accounts are something I feel
like a lot of companies overlook so for
example you know at your company you
might have info at company comm which is
just a generic account that's used that
people can send emails to so the problem
with this though is I should have access
to that mailbox like to read email reply
as email but I should never really have
user name password access to this
generic account so if you see people
attempting to log into that generic
account that might start raising some
red flags so we can look at Windows logs
specifically the failed log and attempt
or lockout accounts and then you can
specify your generic accounts that
you're interested in of course a lot of
companies have a lot of generic accounts
so the other thing you can do is export
a list of generic accounts from ad into
a CSV file then upload that CSV file to
your log aggregator and search against
the file instead of having to manually
enter all of your generic accounts into
the search query then once again we'll
check out our table so you can see that
there were a lot of login attempts to
our marketing account turns out there
was a system that had open ports that
should not have been which allowed
anybody in the world to try to
authenticate to this system so people
were trying just random usernames and
passwords so thankful we were able to
see this before they were able to
correctly guessed the password and
closed those ports before anything
happened so attempted logins to accounts
that don't exist or are disabled so once
again we can look at failed login
attempts in Windows but we can
specifically look at why the login
failed so there's a thing called sub
status code the first one here which I
know is painful to read means that the
account login failed because the account
doesn't exist there's no account to
login to the second one being that the
login failed because this accounts
disabled nobody's allowed to log into it
there's a full list of these online for
reference if you're interested in more
failed login reasons because like I said
they're not real easy to read and then
we can group those failed logins by IP
address so we can get an idea of you
know who's trying to do this and then
just for human readability every name
the field to quickly see this is the
number of failed attempts and then we
can throw it on the table and I made
sure that the ones with the most
attempts were sorted at the top so we
can quickly get an idea of where the
problem is so here you can see that we
had 36 failed logins to these two
accounts which I blacked out is obvious
so what had happened here was we had
users who created important production
scripts that ran under their own user
account and then when they left they
fail so we had important actions for our
production systems I didn't get executed
because these scripts failed so we had
to quickly figure out what these scripts
were thanks to IP address we were able
to do that fast and get those running
under a service account instead of user
accounts unusual location so this is
good for companies that are very local
only have a couple offices within the
area where you really wouldn't see
logins from maybe anywhere other than
Cleveland you know of course employees
travel you know you have people logging
in when they're traveling but in general
you probably shouldn't see a log in from
Nigeria just saying so this time I
decided to look at our VPN log
specifically successful connections and
then Splunk has this really
cool feature called IP location where
you can pull in the geolocation of IP
addresses right into the log aggregator
and so we can get all of that
information about each of the IP
addresses in our logs and then I'm
specifically looking for any VPN
connections outside of the United States
and then because of the way the not
operator works in Splunk if you have a
null country value it doesn't return
results properly so I went ahead and set
a default for that and then once again
threw it into a table oh look my
accounts accessed from Nigeria problem
problem this is all fake data by the way
I didn't actually get access in Nigeria
I probably wouldn't be allowed to give
this presentation if I did so so this is
good if your company's more global so
you can't really you know you'll have
people logging in from all over the
country so instead what we're gonna look
for is logins that physically wouldn't
be possible so think about you know
login from the United States sorry this
is my voice so think about a login from
the United States and then five minutes
later a login from like China you know
that that physically wouldn't be
possible and nobody's gonna be paying to
China it's just not gonna happen so once
again we're gonna look at our VPN logs
and we're going to group it by user um
there is a much more in-depth version of
this presentation that was done at the
2016 besides Cleveland they use a lot of
like math and calculations to figure out
what would be possible and what wouldn't
be so if you want to make a really
accurate search I suggest checking out
their presentations that link there at
the bottom I am sorry you are getting
rained on so just real real quick brief
version of this which is much less
complex um say if you guys want to like
crowd in here that's cool don't I get
rained on
we won't bite I promise
well I won't I can't promise for anybody
else so anyway real fast
I am I just grouped all of these logins
by user and then I specified if there is
more than one country involved in that
login to go ahead and return those
results like I said it's a really simple
version you can find the more complex
version on iron geek if you want to set
that up so here you can see that I was
accessed from the United States and
United Kingdom within about 10 hours
possible flight time depending on your
layover but still might raise some
suspicion so this is sort of the inverse
of the previous search instead of one
user being accessed from multiple
locations you have multiple users being
accessed from the same location so of
course this could be you know employees
collaborating off-site this could be a
husband-and-wife logging in from the
same location but it's still worth
checking out if you start seeing one IP
address accessing 30 50 100 of your
accounts you know it's a big indicator
that there's been a massive compromise
so once again we're looking at VPN logs
and I'm gonna group them all together by
piece so we can figure out where they're
all coming from and then I'm gonna say
only show me results where there are
more than one user associated with an IP
address and then once we get again we
can pull in all the geolocation info and
put in a table and oh look Iran is
accessing not just one but multiple of
our accounts that's something we
probably want to do something about so
and the last and personally my favorite
is connections to malicious domains so
if you weren't aware there are people
that keep a list of malicious domains
whether it's fishing or malware infected
websites and then you can download that
list into a CSV file and upload it into
your log aggregator
and say hey or any of my users accessing
these you know known malicious domains
so for this we're gonna look at our DNS
logs and then you have to make sure that
the field and Splunk
is the same as your column name and your
CSV file
so you have to do some renaming and then
of course the URLs and DNS logs aren't
real pretty so we're going to do some
regex
to make them look the way we're used to
seeing them and then we're going to
compare our DNS logs with that CSV file
to see if there are any matches
and sure enough we had a couple users
visiting phishing websites follow up
with them yes they submitted information
yes we get to go through the whole
computer clean password reset process
the whole nine yards
so that's it for my quick searches that
y'all can set up there's a couple of
ways that you can take this implement
all those and then keep going with it a
couple questions to ask yourself what
should be happening in our systems if
it's not happening is that a problem
which shouldn't be happening our systems
that's definitely a problem and then
check for any anomalies are there any
severe spikes or dips and activity you
know suddenly there's normally like 50
logins a day now there's 5,000 logins a
day is that a problem maybe people are
just finding out about you and that's
really cool
or maybe it's somebody attacking your
website so and then once you build all
of these really cool fancy searches
share them with the community so people
like me who like don't know where to
start have something to help get their
systems up and running like I mentioned
earlier I have the new website where I'm
posting all of this if you want to send
your searches to me and I can share them
and I'm so sorry about the rain so yeah
feel free to send those to me we can get
them all posted build sort of a
community where you can go to really
help improve your log monitoring and
that is pretty much it thank God any
questions before you run through the
rain no was like that good that there's
no questions good
I have so he asked if I have seen the
white paper about spotting the adversary
in Windows Event log which I do I think
is a really great resource and a place
to get you started with some of those I
think some of those will you know be
very useful when some of them won't
depending on your company size but it's
a very good place to get started one of
the things I want to do with my website
is not just have a list of searches but
break it down like I did step by step so
if you're new to a log source if you've
never looked at Windows you can
understand what each of the things mean
because event codes there's a lot of
event codes you know trying to find
those lists can be very expensive yes
that's a good place to start there are
other websites like Ghost Blanc or
there's like the Big Blue Book of Splunk
logs that also have a lot of searches
where you can get started so yes lots of
resources any other questions
good sorry
there may be so the question is in the
Windows registry are there not lists of
websites to avoid I'm not super familiar
with the Windows registry there may be I
know I think the websites that I
mentioned are all community driven so as
soon as a new one's found they submit it
to this forum and it gets uploaded so
I'm not sure how often the Windows one
might be updated but the online websites
to have these lists are updated very
frequently so any other questions okay I
think we are good thank you very much
for coming to my presentation and of
dealing with the rain I appreciate it so
thanks for making a newbie very happy
yeah thank you