all right good afternoon can everyone
hear me I can definitely hear me so if I
fade away just yell or say something and
I'll speak back up again I apologize now
I did not backlight screen test this
presentation so hopefully these slides
are still logical for everybody my name
is Michael Mendez I am talking about
securing code today just the basics I
cannot cram that down into you in 50
minutes if I could most of us would be
out of a job and there'd be no need for
the conference a little background on
myself I am a senior developer much like
Sam I have been doing this quite a long
time or more time than I would really
like to admit to on on video been
writing a lot of code over the years I
first started getting interested in the
security aspects of code when I was
writing an application as a former life
as an emergency manager to share 911
with the other emergency managers
players side of things is a little
old-school still you still see a lot of
firefighters with the little pagers on
their hips that beep and drive you nuts
when you're out at the movies technology
is still catching up with us so I was
writing a mobile app that would let the
first responders see what was going on
you know as the ambulance and a route is
the chief going what's the actual call
and I was working with a technical
sergeant in the Sheriff's Department to
get access to that data and we started
thinking about the impact of that data
being online at all so that's where this
kind of started for me since then a
little bit of a life change brought me
out here to Cleveland not developing
full-time I've also been an educator for
quite a while so I apologize if I talk
to your ear off I'm also a homebrewer so
I'm definitely a fan of sibling revelry
contributing to today and I will also
happily talk your ear off about all
things brewing related a little lauda
scope
uh you can find me on twitter at relics
cough you won't really hear much from me
because i really use it to read more
than I use it to contributes maybe
someday that'll change and email Michael
G Mendes at gmail so securing code I got
a question for you guys why are we still
talking about this I mean really we have
literally decades of guidance on how to
do this well as long as I've been
writing code there's been documentation
out there to use so we don't screw this
up
whatever I'm lazy I'm not gonna read all
of that okay fine
how about the piles of requirements
sitting next to you on your desk that
carry some of these carry very heavily
penalties and legal requirements that we
just happen to ignore absolutely it is
that important no it's not thank you
[Laughter]
gdpr though is obviously what everyone's
focus is on right now seeing is that
went into effect just a couple weeks ago
I ran into this within my own company as
we were implementing our solutions and
getting everything turned on to be in
compliance even internally we had some
discourse as to how some of that needed
to be interpreted that resulted not only
in internal counsel getting involved
with also outside counsel getting
involved so we could determine what we
were going to do as a company and what
they considered the risk to be and
really what we needed to comply with and
that's just one out of all of these you
know the jury is still out on what kind
of teeth gdpr is actually going to have
it's so new we haven't really seen
anything come out of it yet in terms of
somebody actually being confronted with
this
or being in violation maybe within the
last week I haven't checked i-i-i do
hear that there were charges the Dave
took a fact I haven't heard if there's
any resolution on that yet if it can
actually be fully enforced but a lot of
these can be and to be honest actually a
quick question where my developers at
okay where am I is OHS at Wow only one
in the room well you're the one I'm
targeting today so this presentation is
very much for you you know a lot of
companies are still regularly violating
a lot of these policies we know it's we
don't want to talk about it but we know
it so where does that leave us when we
actually look at our code couple studies
that have been done there's been a lot
more than this I just kind of picked a
couple out Carnegie Mellon did a study
20 to 30 bugs per thousand lines of code
well if you do the math that makes
99.98% bug free okay
another study specifically on the Linux
kernel found even fewer ninety-nine
point nine nine eight percent bug free
even better so why are we worried about
this we're worried about this when it
becomes a matter of scale when you look
at Windows 10 which has a common
estimate of about 50 million lines of
code now you're looking at a million
bucks
are we a little more worried now okay
million line of bugs 50 million lines of
code still not horrendous it's not great
I'm not gonna sleep well but it gets
worse last year in the NVE
database of bugs 32% of those bugs
hearing a cbss score of four or greater
a score of four or greater
immediately puts your company in
violation of PCI
doesn't matter if it actually impacts
your ability to process credit cards
you're still in violation just by having
that vulnerability it's about a third
now I know we still pay a lot of
attention to network and yeah network is
still beating us up in terms of the
quantity of problems we have with
securing our networks but software is
definitely leaning away in the quality
of those bugs and how bad they are when
they come out I just love the dumpster
fire gift here by the way so Oh wasp the
number one thing I know us right now and
it's been on the list forever
Injection flaws such as sequel no sequel
OS an LDAP injection occur when
untrusted data is sent to an interpreter
as part of a command or query the
attackers hostile data can trick the
interpreter into executing unintended
commands or accessing data without
proper authorization everyone get that
Abraham Lincoln by the way I don't know
if you can see that in the back what
does that actually mean we blindly
trusted something the user gave us and
we put it somewhere important that's
what it boils down to it has been on the
OWASP list as far as I cared to look
back and it's still one of the worst
things that gets to us if you're a
developer you have to keep one key thing
in mind whenever you're dealing with
something a user gives you users are two
things they're dumb or they're malicious
that's it that's your assumption all the
time
I am constantly reminded of men in black
with the line of a person is smart
people are dumb panicky dangerous
animals and you know it's
that's how you need to live as a
developer be paranoid be crazy worried
about it so I'm not going to give you
guys an overwhelming amount of code
examples some of you are devs I've got
one is Oh buried in the back the last
time I told you guys developers keep
these things in mind I know the lot of
these are gonna be familiar to you I
know it's hard to keep this going the
two greatest things personally that I
think kill us right now in terms of
software quality in terms of security
our Minimum Viable Product and
continuous integration the push in our
organizations to have a Minimum Viable
Product as soon as possible and keep
that speed of business going absolutely
kills us because it overrides security
because no one above our pay grade gives
a crap and then you wrap on that nice
little blanket of continuous integration
especially as the developer cuz I'm like
well you know if there's a bug or CI I
can patch it as soon as I see it I don't
have to wait three months for a release
and worry about it in the meantime but
that's also assuming I'm finding the
bugs as soon as I'm creating them and
that little safety blanket
oh well I'll fix it as soon as I see it
really doesn't mean anything to us so
this particular example is PHP you also
see some JavaScript I'm a web guy I'm an
open stack guy not like Sam who him who
had all those great tools in VB for us
an hour ago don't worry about the
language I want you guys to focus on the
concepts of what I'm talking about
so in this examples anybody see
something bad and of course you do
anybody know what's bad Rob
right so there's actually two things
here the first is the fact that I am
running a function in PHP that is
basically giving me shell is letting me
run things at the OS level I can call
other applications I can run scripts
that I happen to know the names of
anything that just don't do it if you
have any use case where you can get away
from doing things like this in your code
do it don't even let it be a factor in
the first place because the moment you
introduce a function like that into your
code any exploit somebody finds is
running outside of your code environment
and on your OS the other problem with
this is that we're passing variables
into that script that we're running what
our users what are the two things of our
users malicious dumb either one of those
things can break so if we're passing
variables into something that's giving
us OS level access to the machine we're
on that's it somebody will find it if
you absolutely have to do this because I
get it
there are use cases there are things you
can't get around you just you have to
drop to this old script because no one
understands what the hell it does but it
still works and we need it to work for
the business to work so I've got to do
this do everything in your power to make
sure you have done due diligence with
what you're giving it you want to make
sure that the user that your web server
is running as has as few permissions as
possible on the system the bare minimum
it needs to actually run on the server
avoid using the user input if you can
get away from that and just have
something run on its own fine much
smaller worry and the last thing is
clean and validate user provided data
this is going to be a recurring theme
for the next few slides
another example
nice little form I don't know how
legible this is in the far back but
there's some extra text in here at the
top field it's a basic login form
username password now let's see here the
extra text is after a username so you
guys can see it and it's not obfuscated
as a password field and reality we would
usually be doing this more in the
password side this is an example of
malicious so this is somebody coming in
and saying you know what
I know sequel I know how the commands
work I know the language I'm gonna take
some guesses as to how you're using the
data I give you and putting it into the
query and I'm gonna see if I can build
my own query so if this actually looks
like when you do it wrong on the back
end store it in the code is going to be
the string that is actually your sequel
command and in that in this example the
email field and the password field are
being dropped straight in so what that
means for us is that as this gets passed
through to the actual sequel server in
the backend the special characters that
our malicious person dropped in changed
the query and it's no longer selecting
where our username and password our
presence because they short-circuited it
and they said show me where the email is
this and the password is this or if one
equals one how many times is one gonna
equal one always so what have they done
they're logged in as whatever they want
to be
that's a sequel injection it is still
one of the most prevalent problems today
why because we're trusting people
panicky dumb animals ourselves included
present company so how do we
to get around this if you're a dev
you've got to do your sanitizing you've
got to do your validation you've got to
do it every time I know it's a pain in
the butt but it's got to be done if
you're an ISO or you're in any kind of
position where you are responsible for
reviewing code or should be reviewing
code some key things to look for is that
anytime you're taking data in from
somebody you're looking for things that
clean it up and then you want to make
sure it's still what you need it to be
so as sanitizing right here we're taking
our password we're replacing whatever
comes in especially for a special
character of the single quote and if we
see that single quote and a password
we're gonna yank it out so in our
password policy can we allow single
quotes yes or no no because we're
getting yank it out right so when you're
letting your users create accounts you
got to make sure they're not using these
things by pulling that single quote out
just that one character for this example
you fixed the problem their sequel
injection won't work they're gonna get
an error because the sequel that's
getting passed is just gonna fail and
it's gonna say there's a problem with it
after you sanitize you still need to
make sure that what's left still meet
your criteria so if your password policy
is it needs to be eight digits or longer
and you strip all bad characters and
it's shorter it no longer meets what you
need right
the longer the password is the harder it
is to crack even even if you're using
not as great hashing so I mean this is
just an example I'm just kind of giving
common situations here a lot of places
you see a characters or more
adoption and as standards have increased
over the years so I mean it's really
password complexity really kicked up
five years ago where you started to see
more support for special characters at
all
we're devs we're lazy if it's not a
character or an integer that's easy to
test for it's bad well then we started
doing special characters but then the
guys on the the malicious side of the
fence went oh well you know it's getting
really common for them to just you know
use an exclamation point at the end of a
crappy password or all these other
little things so the longer string
started become more popular because it's
easier for us to remember so it's kind
of the next counter wave of one side
fighting the other I would absolutely
endorse the longer your password the
better you know the whole trick today of
come up with a sentence that you can
just easily remember and inject that and
do your capitalization and everything
else yeah that's gonna be far better you
don't see that support in a lot of
places because their code base is built
where developers we're lazy you don't
want to rebuild it yet so we absolutely
have to
so sanitizing get the bad crap out of it
validating make sure it's still valid
for your actual use case make sure an
email is still an email better is let
your database protect you
so from the PHP side of things there are
a set of different functions in PHP one
are my sequel don't use it the second
generation that came out was my Seco Lee
my sqli it was another function to make
a connection to and talk to your
database don't bother with it skip right
to PDL PDO is a third set that lets you
connect and talk to your database PDO is
a very generically written approach to
doing this
if you happen to be a PHP dove and
you're using PDO you can use PDO to talk
to my sequel MS sequel Postgres so you
already can talk to all of your database
formats because it takes the most
standard version of the sequel syntax
what helps us here is that we start to
isolate things out of our code now you
see question marks in places of where a
couple minutes ago we had email and
password dropped right into the string
we've moved those and we're passing
those to our sequel database separately
so we're telling our database this is
the string of what we want you to do
here are the variables we want you to
use and sequel itself does its own due
diligence on top of our sanitizing and
validating that keeps us even safer best
situation do both those of you who were
paying attention this morning this is
now the second time you have seen the
bhabhi tables example today and there
are a lot of reasons to do both that go
beyond just us being safe I know that's
a hard sell the quicker you can sell the
rare intelligent on the up and level
user that they've made a mistake the
better right the better for their
experience smoother things will be the
quicker things will get on so on your
front end the quicker you can say you
know what this passwords not long enough
the better any note developers out there
none okay how many of you have been on
sites in the last couple years where
every keystroke you're seeing
validations update on the page that's
awesome isn't it
built what go that route you're giving
immediate feedback you're checking and
sanitizing and preventing bad stuff from
even being submitted in the first
that's all on the front end it's great
it's an awesome experience for the user
what happens if we only do that on the
front end proxy and submit your own
stuff I got a bunch of hackers in the
room this is like 101 for you guys I'm
gonna open up postman or any number of
another example of application that lets
me submit stuff to your server as if I
used your form me as the bad guy all I
have to do is look at your form figure
out the field names drop in whatever I
want
hit submit I didn't use your website all
that front end checks that you did
completely useless so you have to chuck
in the front for your user experience
check again on the back to make sure
you're still protected so another one
buffer overflow condition exists when a
program attempts to put more data in a
buffer than it can hold or when a
program attempts to put data in memory
area passed a buffer in this case the
buffer is sequential section memory
located allocated to contain anything
from a character string to an array of
integers writing outside the bounds of a
block of allocated memory can corrupt
they crash the program to cause the
execution of malicious code whoo that
was brave Sir Robin by the way this one
is actually no longer or I should say
not currently on the OWASP top pen
I still say it should be because it's
still really prevalent why don't we hear
about this much anymore
well frankly Oh first of all what does
it actually mean we asked for an email
they sent us a novel things got worse
from there so there's your there's your
normal you know a plain text translation
there why don't we see this any more or
not too much right now it's really hard
that's why we're all here and we have
jobs if you're Honda on the security
side of things it's hard to do you are
pushing something past its bounds but
you don't even know where those mile
markers are to begin with it's a lot of
try
an error it takes a lot of understanding
of low-level code and it's not easy it's
also very likely that unless you are
being hyper targeted they're gonna give
up before they put that much time and
investment into getting you in
particular but it's so easy to prevent
that we shouldn't just forget about it
we've already heard a couple times today
how people are pulling things out of
their toolkit from ten years ago
and they're rediscovering just how easy
it is to use those tools because in the
intervening time we all forgot about
that exploit and no one's looking at it
anymore
so don't forget about it what do we do
more cleaning and sanitizing check your
field length make your fields only as
long as they need to be that's it
that'll cover you the vast majority of
the time so there's a couple approaches
one approach is if you're expecting an
email address and you decide an email
address is maybe at the top end sixty
characters and that's all you're gonna
give them you can either truncate it and
say I'm only gonna keep the first 60 I'm
gonna junk the rest or you say you know
what tough I'm not taking it at all give
me something more realistic and this is
hard to do I can tell you this is hard
to do because I have a moderately long
name and I work for a company with a
very long domain name I have not been
able to register for certain sites
because my email is longer than they
think a normal email should be so there
is a trade-off here there's a little bit
of a check and balance I must be doing
great there's a band playing for me in
the background so you have to make your
logical decisions here of what's
realistic personally I would trend
towards a ladder if it looks bad it
probably is ask them to do it again give
them a nice little form if they are
legit having a problem let us know
contact us
give you're good users the ability to
reach out to you so you can adjust these
metrics later what do we need to check
everything everything that comes from
the user even if it doesn't sound like
it's coming from a user if you're it if
you're not a developer you're thinking
okay I've got to check my form yes
absolutely you do have to check
everything that comes through a form but
us hacker guys who aren't using your
form can also manipulate different
things like the headers that are coming
along with that submission that's kind
of background information that's that
gives us more detail about where is this
form submission coming from there are
hidden fields that you may not see on
your browser that we as developers use
in the background so we can hide things
that we need to know like a source and
where you came from or which page you
happen to land on and we just want that
more easily so we stick it on the form
but we don't put it on the screen if I'm
a bad guy I can look at your code I can
see those hidden fields and I can
manipulate those two so shown fields
hidden fields headers if you're a dev
you're gonna understand these next few a
little bit more post contents you get
contents and your cookies anything
that's not coming from your own trusted
data source you have to be doing these
things on sanitized validate and you
have reduced your problems dramatically
questions so far
surprised I didn't get one question
which is but I really want to use
question marks and apostrophes and
quotes and I do need that it is valid
for my user to give that to me okay fine
only on those fields accept them but
encode them as their actual HTML value
so if you do need to save it and spit it
out back on the screen like you're
letting somebody submit a blog or a
review or something like that
and code it first before you
ever do anything with it so if they are
trying to be malicious you still shut
them down
now I'm gonna pick up my developers a
little bit more because I am terrible at
this and I will admit it I will admit it
to the facts that this is one of my
applications and I stumbled across this
a couple weeks ago the bat on me for not
doing my own code review on myself
before putting something into production
when you're developing and you're trying
to figure out why the freaking thing
isn't working the way it's supposed to
be what do we start doing you start
spitting stuff out to the logs right
what are we bad about doing from moving
them when we're done this one jumped out
at me because I'm sure a couple of you
were share the sentiment I usually
precede those things with a common
acraman like WTF because that's usually
how I'm feeling at that point in the
process and that is actually what caught
my eye now I did kind of tweak this one
so it's not actually anything bad but
there's a lot of sensitive information
that you can be reviewing that you're
forgetting about when you're done why
can't I log in why is this not working
just show me what's actually coming out
of the clear-text ik credentials oops
why can't I get my database connection
to work this has got to be telling me
something show me the credentials I'm
using show me my connection string to my
sequel server and oh there it is oh I
didn't take the comment back out that
stuff lives there the other piece I was
in here in this example was the data
that's actually being rendered to the
screen not as bad but there may be more
pieces of data here that I'm getting
from an API then I want my users to see
or that they should be able to see them
screen so you've got to check your code
and get rid of all those console logs
and error logs and you don't want that
would spit out to the browser so
code reviewers the iso's when you're
looking at code if you see console dot
log red flag the only time you should
see that is if you're giving your end
user an error you want them to be able
to tell you about how many of you have
had applications crash and you see error
code 1 X 0 5 5 3 3 yeah utterly useless
to us right as an end user but you call
them up and like oh what code did you
get ok and then someone in the
background is looking at up in their
documentation the end user gained zero
information but it still facilitates us
getting what we need we don't need to
tell them exactly what the error is we
don't need to tell them the important
thing or the sensitive thing forgot I
have highlights on that one least
privileged no one in your system should
be able to do anything more than they
absolutely need to get their job done so
this now we're getting more away from
code examples for getting the structural
examples this is an example of that same
type of blogging kind of concept so here
we've identified three roles your
anonymous so you can basically just log
in and read stuff you're a user read
posts or reset your own password or
you're an admin you can manage accounts
and you can create content does that
sound good
nobody wants to answer because they
figure there's a trick right is it
better than nothing better than nothing
right if this is a blog style system
where your users are giving you content
you see an issue if I'm a user what a
wine need in order to give you content
right permission
where do I have that on the screen admin
oh crap
all my users are now admins bad right we
didn't follow least privilege
so to fix this example we'd have to
split out another layer now we have a
content creator that sits between our
users and our admins they can do more
but they can't do everything this
happens more than it should as not so
much as an open source guy but as a just
give me an application that quickly does
what I need user permissions come up all
the time there are systems that we use
at work where we have more admins than
we like because they just didn't really
structure things right not because their
developers did a bad job of this because
us as end users are panicky animals
we're trying to use their software in a
way it wasn't meant to be used we're
pushing the bounds of it we're trying to
use it away that they didn't really
think people were gonna want now we're
up against that wall another common
problem authentication itself make sure
you're authentication is strong make
sure you're hashing is strong if you're
in any type of code review situation and
you see md5 anywhere shut that thing
down it's outdated it's easily
reversible at this point there are
entire sites online that you can go to
and you can put in a hash and get the
password back or you can put in your
password they'll give you the hash and
then they conveniently add it to their
database it's not safe anymore the
metric has gone up so you want to make
sure that these things are up to par the
older the application is the more likely
you're gonna see things like this not
because the devs did a bad job it was
perfectly valid back then but it hasn't
been touched in five years if you're
having a hard time selling that the
newer ones are faster good 4 / 4
better user experience time to upgrade
another thing to keep in mind architects
and ISO s use only what you need so
everybody remember a couple years ago
and a facebook messenger first came out
and everyone was up in arms because a
pretty much asked for every single
permission to possibly could on your
device did anyone still install
messenger I'm seeing some nods I still
refuse to I'm sure there's any other
apps on my phone that do it though only
access what you need on the same side of
that store only what you need this is a
place where I know we're all really bad
because it's so common we all do it yes
this is very big on gdpr and actually
getting permission even have the
information in the first place is
probably the most key provision of it so
you want to store only what you need are
you ever actually going to snail mail
someone that's in your database maybe
you are fine by all means get it if
you're not why are you asking for it
are you actually ever gonna call a user
why do you need their phone number
demographics are great i every every
marketing person in the world would be
screaming at me for not taking that
information great I get it you want
demographics you want to know where your
users are you want to know their
interests you want to all these things
but you do not have to tie it to their
actual user record store it somewhere
else give it a whole different key don't
tie it together your marketing team will
be happy and you'll be safer is it
available somewhere else how many of you
for the developers out there are using
something like Facebook or Google or any
of the
open authentication mechanisms to allow
users to register for your site none I'd
actually say good to that but if you are
and you already have access to that
information there don't also store it in
your system you have access to it and if
it gets breached through Facebook
because they logged in to your site
using their Facebook credentials by your
problem it's Facebook's problem much
like their laundry list of problems
right now personal pet peeve how many of
you have applied for jobs at any time in
the last few years you upload your
resume and you still have to fill out
every single freaking thing that you
already put on your resume why are we
still doing this first of all developers
I know we need to get better at the epic
text reading and it is a difficult
problem to solve but really hiring
companies stop read my resume that's why
I put hours into it if you have it don't
ask for it again why not why not just
store the data I mean obviously you have
gdpr problems but what about legal
issues anybody hear about Alexa case
with Amazon where officers were trying
to get information off the Alexa because
they're pretty sure it recorded the
murder legit thing and there is a big
court case about whether or not they
could access it to get evidence now if
they could and they could solve it
awesome for that case maybe not so great
feeling for the rest of us you have
Alexis in our house that are recording
all the time but your company needs to
decide their acceptance of that risk is
recording all of that data on the off
chance you might use it worth what it
could mean in terms of lawsuits federal
agencies coming to you for data the
pressure to comply with that we keep
hearing more and more companies that
have been helping out ice
and had to feel good at the time if they
were helping and then we have things
like what happens with immigration in
the last couple weeks and all of a
sudden they're canceling all those
programs and trying to pull out of those
contracts because of the bad PR did
anybody consider the PR before they
started handing over all that data
hopefully they did maybe they thought it
was worth the risk obviously they didn't
after the fact this really does go well
beyond I'm sitting at my desk and I'm
typing out my code and I'm putting a
form together the ramifications of what
you're collecting need to be looked at
across the entire organization if your
company does not have an ISO they don't
have security teams they're not thinking
about these things and they don't have
leadership in the room talking about
risk you're in a very bad place
finally for storing what you need ask on
demand if you may need something you
have a problem on your site and you want
that user you want to be able to reach
out to that user to find out what
happened you don't have to store their
phone number from the day they sign up
you need their phone number when they
report a problem and you need a means to
reach back to them store it there only
ask for it then and only keep it as long
as you need it when that tickets closed
junk it you don't need that data anymore
the next time they have a bug they can
tell you what phone number they want to
be called at that time how can we
improve our code in general beyond
architecture is putting ourselves into a
smaller box developers how many of you
use an IDE good how many don't use an
IDE or my note patters yeah use the IDE
use the add-on tools use your code smell
tools pretty much every IDE out there
regardless of language has some type of
integrated thing or add-on that helps
you write code that helps you review
code to color codes things so you can
see problems it can give you hints like
hey your spacing is kind
this isn't really readable those
readability have anything to do with
security absolutely if I'm reviewing
your code and I can't read it how
confident can I be that I'm not missing
something
commenting how important is commenting
in the function of code in the function
of code I know this feels dirty to say
not up its butt we still need it you
need it to look and figure out what you
were thinking six months ago when you
wrote that function in the first place
but you also needed to understand what's
going on or what is supposed to be going
on so if you're not using an IDE
please start especially if you're diving
all the time I know it feels good to get
that code written out without any
assistance and find your bugs without
having to tell you where your bugs are
but your work day will go better and
soeul everyone else's duplicated code
needs to end I'm sorry did you have a
question
coming up on unit testing actually yep
and if you can't read this one by the
way in the back it's code quality
measurement by WTF spur a minute the
more there are the worse the code is so
duplicate a code why is duplicated code
bad
I wrote a function it works I copied it
to ten other places where I need that
thing to happen right six months down
the road I find a bug in that function I
fix it I forget about the nine other
places I've copied it to in the meantime
what do I still have nine more bucks
right key programming concept that you
hear all the time is dry don't repeat
yourself anybody who's doing a lot of
functional programming or
object-oriented programming is used to
hearing this and this is why when you
find the bug you fix it in how many
places one bugs gone no more problem
yangmi anybody out there know what yeah
genious
I just heard this one recently I kind of
liked it you aren't gonna need it
I at this point in my career as I'm kind
of transitioning more into information
security and less out of development I'm
really focusing right now just on our
API and as somebody building an API I
want to give my dev team every possible
tool to make their lives easy so they
can just quickly roll things out they
can ask her whatever information they
want I need to stop doing that if
there's no use case for it
don't proactively build it you aren't
gonna need it until you need it
if you roll it out in the mean time and
somebody malicious comes across that end
point that you're not really using and
you're not paying attention to you're
not gonna find the problem so this is
one of those few times that I'll tell
the developers stay lazy if you don't
eat it don't build it dead code right
along the same lines of yagna you needed
it at one point and you're
refactored and you moved on to the next
projects and you never took that out of
your end point now you have dead code
you're not using anywhere if you're not
using it you're not paying attention to
it same problem is the Agni what helps
us their documentation watch your logs
and use code analysis tools to try to
find that dead code unit testing unit
testing is one of the best things we can
do as developers to cover ourselves and
I'm gonna ask in a second but I'm gonna
guess we might see one or two hands
who's actually doing unit testing two
hands a couple more in the back do you
do it everywhere probably more in the
back than the front right right so what
is unit testing we're writing code to
test our code before we write our code
okay unit testing takes a lot of
planning first we've got to sit down and
figure out what our application is then
we've got to figure out what we need to
actually build the application and then
we're rushing because we want that
Minimum Viable Product as soon as
possible to get out in front of people
before your devs
start writing code they need to write
tests about what they need to build so
if I figure out the fact that I need a
function that adds two numbers I'm not
gonna sit down and write the function
that adds two numbers I'm going to sit
down and go okay well what are the best
and worst cases to go back to Sam's
example from his presentation with
airline tickets if you should never have
a ticket price below fifty dollars you
should test debt function to make sure
it doesn't allow that to happen or that
it gives you an error if it does happen
because then instead of having to write
your sequel to send you an email to tell
you what happened when it happened you
prevented it right out of the gate so
you sit down and you write all the tests
you need to make sure that function does
exactly what it needs to do every time
it only gives you things that are in
bounds then you write your code then you
use your testing framework to test it
you give it all those rules and tests
you give it the source code it runs its
tests and you get your passes in your
fails and it tells you hey it didn't let
me put in a ticket price of less than 50
but it did let me put one in that was
more than a thousand it found the
problem before you put the code into
production so you fix it and then you
move on and you keep those unit tests
because as your application evolves over
time and you add more features here and
more features there you may screw up the
function and the next time you run your
unit tests before you push your code out
it's gonna say hey dummy
remember that whole ten thousand limit
thing you're breaking it fix it you
prevented the code from go prevented the
bug from going in your code and getting
out the door unit testing is huge we
should all be doing it
it's not easy developers don't like
writing unit tests they'd rather write
the code move on with their days and get
on to the next ticket but it needs to be
done finally
code review devs I'm sure you're all
doing code reviews right looking at each
other's code picking on each other
blaming each other and your repos right
has to happen try to be nice about it
well we've got to keep doing it the more
eyes on the code the less buggy was
gonna see we saw that way back in the
beginning when we talked about closed
source versus open source rates of error
in the studies Linux had a lot fewer
didn't it you know why more eyes on it
any questions yes
my sequel I fixed some of the problems
that my sequel couldn't support as a
function call in PHP it was a step in
the right direction for security but at
the same time PTO was already there it
was a band-aid on a problem that
shouldn't have existed so I would say
skip it go right to PDO you're gonna get
something more powerful and if your
company ever decides they want to go to
a different database you're probably
covered as long as it's a sequel based
database without rewriting your code at
all if you're using MySQL functions or
mysqli functions in your PHP code and
they decide they want to go to a post
press server you've got a lot of work
ahead of you any other questions all
right thanks guys