you ready Dave one second it's like old
times Dave old times I'll actually speak
into the mic - no no audio clips please
no you did am I ready all right all
right everyone welcome to my talk using
technology to defend digital privacy and
human rights so I kind of like to
starting my talks off with kind of what
you're gonna learn and what we're going
to talk about and I like breaking it
down into three things because
statistically they say that we we as
humans can only remember three things
after one-hour talk so hopefully you can
remember these things hopefully you'll
learn something at the end but we'll
talk about why it's important to defend
our digital privacy which as you know we
live in a crazy world right now where I
think digital privacy is more important
than ever the first time I gave this
talk last year was to a bunch of Israeli
lawyers and journalists which was
fascinating to me because I the dialogue
that I had with them kind of opened up
my eyes to things that journalists and
other people that are kind of on the
front lines of human rights and other
things going on across the world they
have to protect their privacy a little
bit differently then then us normal
people do so I'll share some interesting
things about their struggles and what
they're doing but I've kind of broken
this brokenness talk down to you know
all of us an InfoSec of how can we do
how can we do our jobs better and how
can we protect our own privacy while we
use the Internet
so we'll talk about what a threat model
is around digital privacy and then
something I like to call a personal risk
assessment so depending on what you're
using the internet for or depending on
what maybe your organization is doing or
if maybe you're in law enforcement or
the military or you're doing things that
need to be covert for certain reasons
we'll talk about how you adjust your
risk based on the things that you're
doing and then we'll talk about what the
latest tools and techniques are out that
are out there it's a huge topic so I've
tried to break it down to things that
you can use you know daily in your job
or whatever you're using the internet
for and some good takeaways from that so
a little bit about me my name's Tom
Weston on the manager of penetration
testing at Varick code I lead a team of
remote pen testers we've got 13 pen
testers across the US and one in London
so it's it's an exciting job to say the
least I also do a lot of research around
security and privacy you probably seen
talks I've done in the past and things
like that around socially around social
media and privacy also done some pen
testing talks in the past not so much
anymore but I've really kind of found a
focus more recently just on the topic of
privacy and I've been working in cyber
security and lowsec for around 14 years
or so so I've got a lot of great stories
worked with a lot of you actually
probably from podcasts and other local
community events so and founder and a
co-host of the weekly shared security
podcast so if you're interested in the
topics I'm speaking on we discuss all
the latest news and all kinds of things
on the podcast every week so question
out for everybody so what recent
technology related privacy or human
rights issue is most concerning to you
and they can name something in the news
recently there's a huge list
let's let's let's break it down right so
everyone knows this guy right that may
be the most flattering picture I found
of Mark Zuckerberg to be honest that's
when I think there's like some memes
going around about all the different
facial expressions mark has in front of
the US Congress when he had to testify
would not want to be that guy right so
so we all know about Cambridge analytic
oh right we won't beat a dead horse that
was a big deal right
all over the news all over the media
what's shocking to me is no one realized
oh my god Facebook is collecting all
this information about me yeah well
they've been doing this for a long long
time and now people come the realization
that I shouldn't click on those quizzes
I shouldn't install these apps I should
adjust my privacy settings yeah exactly
so yeah he's in big trouble and it's an
interesting time to be at Facebook I'm
sure
and then there's Russia right Russia
Russia Russia everything is Russia but
it's a big deal even in the news
recently you know everyone's coming out
and saying hey if you're going to the
World Cup
you probably shouldn't even bring a cell
phone or turn it off the Russians are
actively hacking and they are actively
violating privacy all over the place
there seems like there's one story after
another about Russia here's another one
a telegram messenger which will we'll
talk a little bit about but you know the
russian government saying hey give me
the encryption keys to your messaging
app or you can't use it in russia this
is kind of a big deal in the privacy
world and there's other countries as
well that i'll talk about that are doing
things as well including our own that we
need to be careful of and who's who's
our this story about the your cell phone
location data being leaked from all the
major US wireless carriers they have
been selling our data our location data
to these shady third-party companies
forever and it's come out that because
some security researcher found a flaw
and an api where he's able to track
anybody their real-time location
just by manipulating an API Brian Krebs
reported on this this kind of got big
news media attention and not a lot of
people know that you can actually now
turn this off if you go into your set
your privacy settings whether you have
18 T or verizon they actually made this
available I don't know if they've made
this available recently because I don't
if you heard yesterday the US Supreme
Court ruled that location data cell
phone location data is now protected by
the Fourth Amendment which is a huge
yeah exactly huge victory for privacy in
the United States because for years the
government has fought against the e FF
and others saying you know we do every
want with this data so huge news so you
gotta go to your privacy settings it
varies by carrier but go to their
website and you can it's probably buried
like all their other privacy controls
are but there's other stuff going on in
the world that you know we've kind of
lost attention to you right like the
great China firewall like far like China
still has huge control over their
internet and and what you can
communicate and what you can do in China
still a very big deal the Mexican
government United Arab Emirates Egypt
they are always doing things to track
their citizens a big issue what I found
fascinating actually talking to a
journalist about the Mexican government
there's a huge problem with the drug
cartels in Mexico and they have the
heart I guess the Mexican government has
a hard time like using their zero-days
and other things they buy from these
companies on the drug cartels because
guess what the drug cartels are using
flip phones still because they know and
they're smart enough that if I carry a
smartphone the nation state of Mexico is
going to try to target me so they're
still back using old technology and pen
and paper and and all of that and that's
why it's been so hard but these nation
states have zero days they have these
things that they're buying to exploits
and to track people and we have some
examples here as well but mass
surveillance across the globe right it's
it's our country it's every country it
we're all in this huge problem lately
with
mass surveillance who's this guy this
the second most hated guy on the
Internet the FCC Commissioner right this
guy and there's probably a million memes
about him but net neutrality right there
is a privacy components of that besides
all the internet fast lanes that
everyone's talking about that we're all
gonna have to pay more to use the
internet but now you know with the loss
of net neutrality it allows your ISP to
now see what you're doing and they can
take your traffic and they could
potentially give you more ads or sell
that information so it's now I think
more than ever
we need to think about you know how
we're protecting our privacy when we're
using the Internet and again I think
that was another flattering picture that
I found of him so why do you think it's
important that we defend our digital
rights our digital privacy and human
rights I think there's several things
but privacy essentially is a human right
right and don't take my word for it
actually there is article 12 the United
Nations Declaration of Human Rights back
in 1948 which was done by every free
nation in the world stating that
everyone is entitled to the right of
privacy I won't mention the fact that
the United States is now no longer on
the United Nations Human Rights Council
which just happened last week that's a
whole other talk maybe but still
regardless across the world every free
nation recognizes that we have to have
privacy who's over there argument I have
nothing to hide so who cares about
privacy yeah that's that's such
right I always say like well here I'll
give you my email address you email me
your passwords to your all your email
accounts and just let me go through all
your emails I guarantee you no one's
going to do that right because even if
you have nothing to hide privacy is
still important and then lastly people
say privacy is dead so who cares right
well it's more important ever just read
the news read the things I've been
talking about it is very scary out there
so
first thing we had to do is understand
the threat and so we know the difference
between like threat and risk right at a
very basic level right so take for
example you have a car you go to park
your car somewhere there's always a
threat of your car being being stolen
there's always that risk but the risk is
higher if you park it and say a bad
neighborhood that has high crime versus
maybe the suburbs where there is a low
crime rate right so it's understanding a
difference between threat and risk but
we can apply this to our privacy as well
which is something called front modeling
threat modeling from the i.t or the
security perspective very similar in the
privacy world I really liked to use what
the e FF has done here under their
surveillance self defense they have a
whole online course on this but this is
pulled from the e FF called accessing a
writ assessing your risks and it's
called threat modeling and it's a very
simple process you go through of
basically asking five questions to
yourself so what do you want to protect
who do you want to protect it from how
likely is it that you need to protect it
how bad are those consequences if you
fail and of course how much trouble are
you willing to go through in order to
prevent those threats it's a very simple
model and so if you take what you you're
doing on the internet or what you're
using it for answer these questions you
can have a good idea of what type of
risk assessment you need to do for your
activities which leads us to a risk
assessment right so based on your threat
model what types of tools what types of
techniques are appropriate for the
activities that you want to do and I
want to say that this is a very personal
decision so nobody can tell you what you
need to do only you you can answer those
questions so for example if I want to
hide my browsing habits from third-party
ad trackers or an ISP which might be low
risk to you maybe you need to use a VPN
and maybe you know privacy badger and
some browser plug-ins and that's fine
for you and you're willing to accept
that risk now maybe you're not
comfortable giving facebook all your
personal data so some of you may say
screw it I'm just going to delete my
Facebook account
I can't handle it
others will say you know what I'm okay
giving some of my data to Facebook I
accept that risk so maybe I'm going to
use you know I'm gonna sandbox what I'm
doing or some something else some other
technique but if you're a journalist in
a foreign country reporting on human
rights abuses you are definitely going
to have a higher risk risk perspective
than somebody else and you may even use
a burner laptop burner phone tour signal
those types of things for communication
because you are in harm's way so the
idea here is to adjust this based on
what you are comfortable with and we'll
talk about today some of the tools and
techniques based on those risk levels
that you can do now yours is important
there are trade-offs to risk as we all
know nothing is a hundred percent secure
so nothing I'm going to talk about is a
hundred percent if somebody tells you or
a vendor or products as our stuff is 100
percent secure your safe forever it's
right it's snake oil we all
know that real risk can also be a very
hard to determine again based on your
personal situation it can change my
advice here too is to keep it simple
over complicating anything as we know in
security it can lead the mistakes and
lead the problems so whatever threat
model you're working on and whatever
risk you accept keep it as simple as
possible because mistakes can lead to
the compromise of your security and
privacy especially if you are in harm's
way and you definitely have a higher
risk level than somebody else so what
are the threats surveillance tracking
threats right these can come in many
forms state-sponsored local sponsor
targeted we all have seen the news about
stingray devices being installed all
over the place and like Washington DC
right by the White House stingray
devices are a real thing they are out
there they could be out there right at
this conference we have no idea right
but that's something to consider right
depending on your risk level and what
you're willing to accept you may want to
think about using a different form of
communication because of the threat of a
stingray device but there's also
targeted right so specific people can be
targeted for the information that they
have especially human rights defenders
that have things that the government may
want to hide or other things like that
we've seen this in the news as well this
is where people get targeted with
zero-days and other other types of
things that nation-states have the money
and the capability of doing and then of
course we have our RS ISPs and mobile
providers right just like the recent
example selling our location data to
Shady third parties it is happening we
all know this stuff right phishing and
malware threats those can also affect
our privacy I'll talk a little bit more
about some advanced malware that's
that's being found out there that is
specifically targeting the privacy area
and human rights but this all leads the
things of violating our privacy giving
away personal and financial information
still very very common so this guy right
here I'm Edmund sewer he is a human
rights activist based out of the United
Arab Emirates just recently in fact he
was sentenced to 10 years in prison for
the things that he posted on social
media on Twitter about the United United
Arab Emirates and their governments for
years he's been tracked and targeted by
the government for the things that he's
done including talking about human
rights abuses within his own country and
finally the government caught up to him
and threw him in jail what I find
interesting about his story is that he
was the target in 2016 of a zero-day
attack who's heard of the Pegasus
malware right that targeted iOS back
then it was a malware that was sold by a
company called the NSO group that sells
only to governments and nation-states
and these were the text messages that
Ahmed received which of course said
click these links for new secrets about
torture of Emirates in state prisons and
of course clicking that link would
instantly compromise the device allowing
full access and there was no patch until
Apple finally figured it out and patched
it later
the reason I bring this up is because
nation states still have zero days
they've got these things they're out
there and just something to be aware of
so they are targeting others like Ahmed
right now with these types of things and
don't think that depending on your job
and other things we know these things
can get out there right so it's
something to be aware of but I thought
this was fascinating if you're
interested to read more about his story
citizens citizen lab is the you can
google his name there's a great story
about him and we'll see where it goes
but he's gonna be imprisoned for a long
time unfortunately so we also have
communication threats right so
interception of our messages whether
that be social media emails web traffic
text messages wireless networks right
this wireless network I'm sure is very
secure this is a security conference
however I would say you know this
probably is a little lower risk then say
Def Con in Las Vegas Def Con high-risk
guys like seriously just don't even use
the Wi-Fi right we know that here might
get away with it it might be okay except
for Dave he might have some sniffing
rubber ducky thing going on but anyway
so we'll talk a little bit about
end-to-end encryption technology and
where we're at with that and there's a
lot of great communication apps and now
that you can use to really provide
better privacy and then knowing as well
you know stolen or confiscation of your
personal device right we all know about
things going at the border now right
with your iPhone and how there's this
really weird gray area at the US border
where you're really legally in this in
this space where they can look at your
devices they can look at your laptops
they're allowed to do that so thinking
about if your device is compromised and
you have sensitive information how are
you going to protect that so we'll talk
a little bit about locking down devices
appropriate to your level of risk here's
my favorite part
internet ad tracking right anyone ever
wonder how all those ads follow you
around like you know how does Facebook
know
or something I was just searching on
google or I was on Amazon and now the
ads are just popping up in my newsfeed
it's like is it it's almost like black
magic but it's not right this has been
going on for a long time so the
old-school way of Internet ads was you
visit a website you get a cookie right
come back later the website shows you
products you're looking at this is this
is nothing crazy right this is typical
stuff it's how the internet works how
some sites still do their ad tracking
this one I call old school plus 1.so you
visit a website gives you a cookie from
a third party ad network and then you
visit a different website at a later
time that website pulls ads from the
same network you get ads from what
you're looking at from the first site so
this is what they call remarketing in
the marketing industry very very common
take that up a notch they have now have
a technique called cookie syncing that
allows two completely different ad
networks to cross-reference identifiers
for you so shared data from one ad
system can now give you more ads because
now you're in the system then of course
we have search engine ads right so you
search for a product on Google Google
builds this nice profile of you it's
actually kind of scary actually Google
has a whole suite of privacy tools that
will kind of show you what they've been
collecting and you can go you know kind
of analyze that and determine I don't
like that that freaks me out and turn it
off but Google has a huge profile of you
if you have a Google account and you're
logged in while you're doing Google
searches so if you've seen those social
logins for all those apps mobile apps
sites they have you know face login with
facebook login with Google
well that is another way just the target
ads to you it simplifies your login
process for you but it also allows more
ads to be pushed to you if you have a
Google home or Amazon Alexa it's even
better right because now you're putting
search queries into one of those devices
which goes into your account and it's
just a way for more ads to target you
and then we have the social network ads
right so you're logged into Facebook you
visit a website that has a tracking
pixel or a like button and you go back
to Facebook and now you see ads based on
what you are looking for this happens
all the time if you're searching for
something in Amazon and you'll see those
ads now there's also the targeted by
audience and this is the big difference
that I when I talk to people they're
like oh I didn't know that yes Facebook
makes all their money from advertising
so if you're logged into Facebook you
start seeing ads in products or services
you did not visit but they are very
close to your likes and your personal
interests because Facebook will allow
group ads to be sold and targeted based
on your demographics so whether you're
you know thirty-five year old male or
female and you like kittens right you're
gonna start seeing kittens popping up on
Facebook with a bunch of ads Facebook
makes a ton of money off of ads it is
their main source of revenue
so just in q1 of 2018 they made eleven
point nine billion in revenue and the
majority of that was ads there's a lot
of freaking money so they make that all
off of your personal information you are
the products so what about mobile apps
so mobile apps don't use cookies but it
really doesn't matter from an advertiser
your phone still has a unique device ID
and then that sense of the app developer
and guess what that is then correlated
to you and that's why searching for
something say on the names on mobile app
will bring up ads in facebook in the
desktop version is because all that
information is correlated when you're
logging into those accounts I've also
had people ask me like what about
incognito or private mode or people some
people call porn mode right you know
that'll protect me right because that
you know we don't allow cookies in
incognito mode so I'm safe right well
there's something called browser
fingerprinting which has gotten over the
last couple of years much more advanced
I can actually do a whole talk on
browser fingerprinting it's fascinating
even if you have cookies turned off
based on your your headers and
everything that you're sending to that
server including you know the ability of
JavaScript we know JavaScript is very
powerful in a browser so with a little
bit of JavaScript and just by the
information your browser is sending in a
regular web request they can find your
your operating system screen resolution
timezone language all of these things
are correlated into a fingerprint and
then that's designed to continue to
track you even outside of incognito mode
if you're if you're interested to know
more about this topic check out ESS
project it's pen optic it's kind of an
odd word you can go to that site and
it'll actually fingerprint your browser
and give you an idea of what your
browser is telling you and then they'll
tell you how to lock that down using a
browser plugin like privacy badger which
we'll talk about and the other site is a
my unique and you can go there and check
that out as well
fascinating stuff so let's get into the
tools first thing worth mentioning
security and privacy awareness right
always educate yourself on social
engineering phishing attempts it is
still the number one attack vector that
we see I also understand how
corporations sites and apps are using
your data gdpr has gotten a lot of heat
I think when it came out but overall I
think gdpr is a good thing for user
privacy across the world
I think I'm personally sick of seeing
all the cookie pop-ups of yes this cos
site once these cookies yes yes yes and
all the emails of hey we've updated our
privacy policy just want to let you know
yep yep I know thanks I just wanna
please make it stop
but I get it right Europeans are way far
ahead of us in the United States in
terms of laws and policies around
privacy but I think it's a good thing
overall so we'll see where it goes so
just just start thinking about of your
threat model you may be more at risk
than others for a phishing attack I
think everybody in general is at risk
for fishing but when I mean your risk
level thinking about it am I going to be
specifically targeted based on what
I'm doing on the internet maybe higher
than others so let's talk a little bit
about privacy web browsers because this
has really been interesting over the
last year we're starting to see more of
the browsers come out with more privacy
features and I think it's not because of
gdpr I think it's just that's naturally
where they're going standard browsers
that people are using like chrome
Microsoft edge they're just not keeping
up it's just not happening we've seen a
lot more privacy controls put into
Firefox which has been great
in fact Firefox quantum is I my
personally my favorite browser now just
because the extensibility and how fast
it is I think it's great but there's
others coming in the market now like
brave anybody use brave few of you yeah
it's it's a it's an up-and-coming
browser we'll talk about some
differences in a minute but they're
doing some interesting things right so
there is this now trend in privacy of
opting in to things like these
blockchain based
ad systems where they're going to pay
you for your time to watch an ad so it's
kind of flipping around the ad in the
marketing model where you know you're
gonna be comped for seeing advertising
as it you know if it's appropriate to
you and you want to do that you can do
that now paying you in crypto that's a
whole other talk probably right but and
it's blockchain pull their talk but I
think it's kind of innovative that we're
flipping that privacy paradigm around a
bit where we're gonna start comping
users for for giving away information so
Firefox vs. brave both are open source
which is great brave is based off of
chromium
so whether or not there's a little
controversy because that's related to
Google and you know they all say Google
is now the evil empire so if you
associated with that that's cool but
regardless it's still open source brave
has built-in adblock and additional
privacy controls already built in the
browser like fingerprint blocking in
fact it I believe they use disconnect if
you're familiar with that they've built
that in so you don't
to worry about add-ons like you do in
firefox everything's built in for you
and that's the difference of Firefox
right the add-ons are really nice
because you can extend it the way that
you want you can install the things that
you want and you're not kind of tied in
brave also has some controversy with the
way that they handle search data with
ads so braid has a partnership with
DuckDuckGo I don't have a problem with
go I think it's a you know they are will
talk a little bit about search engines
but there is some controversy that they
do handle some metadata and they give
that to DuckDuckGo still doesn't
identify you but still has search
information so just something to be
aware of browser plugins so there are a
ton out there these are the ones that
I've broken out that I think everybody
should be using I'm a huge fan of pretty
much anything from the e FF the
Electronic Frontier Foundation but
specifically a privacy badger I think is
one of the best web tracking prevention
plugins you can use disconnect is also
very good and definitely worth checking
out
in terms of ad blocking there are you
know I used to back in the day use like
ad ad block plus but I've stopped using
them after I've read more about have the
shady things that they're doing with
purposely unblocking certain advertisers
and other things because they have
connections I like you block origin
because it's customizable and its first
open source so definitely check that out
and then I I'm a big fan of HTTPS
Everywhere which forces HTTPS were
available so sometimes there will be you
know links and other things on a web
page that are HTTP it'll go out and
attempt the HTTPS version of that and
automatically make those connections for
you so it kind of over all across the
web it's just a nice thing to run the
background and just the force HTTP for
you some other things you might be
interested to is cookie auto-delete will
Mass custom delete cookies which is nice
you matrix just like no script will give
you control to block scripts I kind of
say these are a little more for advanced
users I wouldn't let my mom use no
script because the internet would come
we break right so but for us right you
know scary professionals you may want to
consider that you matrix I think is a
little bit better because there's
actually more advanced things you can do
the no script but just my opinion so
privacy where search engines so to that
I recommend start page I actually anyone
use start page not a lot of people have
heard of them but what they do is they
act as a proxy between you and Google
because one of the problems I find with
these third-party search engines is the
search just the results suck I mean they
just do you really can't compete with
Google right DuckDuckGo has that problem
is like sometimes a hard time using it I
have to switch back over to Google start
page will acts as a proxy there's a
little bit of a pause when you search
but all the results come back exactly
from Google which is kind of cool and it
basically scrubs all your personal
information they say they don't keep
logs they won't keep logs of your
searches you know those types of things
but it's interesting for sure and then
DuckDuckGo you know they've been around
for a while again no logs ip's you know
are stored not as robust as google they
do say they store some metadata of the
searches for you know track you know
whatever analytics and other types of
things but those are two that I would
recommend tor well it's been all time to
time on tour we all know what this is
the Onion Router I bring it up because
it's still one of the best best ways and
best tools that you can use to you know
well first of all obviously access what
we call the dark web now when you hear
dark web I always think of that stupid
Equifax or whatever that commercial is
on TV that we're gonna do a dark web
deep web scan of all your personal
information and they're not really doing
a scan we all know that right
yeah but again tor is still a very
valuable communication tool for you know
anonymous communication without being
tracked we'll talk about some of the
pros and cons because there are some
cons that everyone should be aware of
but there are mostly more pros
easy to use a nice browser package that
is constantly updated by the Tor project
free open source again all positives
plus the ability for I know talking to
some journalists and other people that
have high risk profiles you know bridge
servers pluggable transports to
circumvent censorship and blocking in
certain countries probably the only way
you can do it is really with tor but
it's it's a really great tool some cons
I think we all know that exit relays can
eavesdrop on communications there have
been instances of that in the past man
in middle attacks still possible I'm
just like in any other you know SSL type
situation can be intercepted and then
it's possible for an ISP or a global
adversary to know you're using tor just
by looking at the network traffic which
could identify you as somebody maybe you
know being a target there are techniques
of using like say VPN on top of Tor to
kind of mitigate some of that but and
I've got some links to a page that if
you want to dig deeper into some tor
configurations you can definitely do
that on the other con that a lot people
say is tor slow I mean it is it I think
it's getting better when I use tor now
it's much faster than it was five five
ten years ago but is a little bit slow
so how you get it I mentioned already
the tor browser through the desktop
there are also iOS and Android versions
the one that I recommend if you go in
the App Store you're going to see a ton
of junk out there just like you do with
any kind of app so be very very careful
what you download but specifically the
ones that are supported by the Tor
project are the onion browser on iOS and
then Android it's or BOTS or or Fox are
both the and those are all open source
and then lastly we'll talk a little bit
about using a virtual machine or
bootable environments the two that we'll
talk about today are tails and who Nix
and I want to mention I 2p really
quickly
anyone ever use ITP a few of you yeah
you know it's it's similar to tor and
some
because it's anonymous Network but much
smaller not as many users it's really
used for more secure peer-to-peer
communication hidden services those
types of things actually talk to a
journalist that uses it for file
transfer between their organization and
and herself when she's out in the field
which I thought was interesting but I
mentioned it because there may be
specific use cases for ITP and I think
it's a pretty cool project so VMs VMs
just like in our day to day job can be
used on regular hardware but when you're
talking about a privacy focused
operating system like tails and who Nix
which we'll talk about they give you a
lot more security and a lot more control
and there's no need for additional
hardware so you may be in a situation
where maybe you don't need to take a
burner laptop or maybe you do and then
maybe you want to install VMware
whatever no VirtualBox on that machine
and then load up a privacy focused
operating system and be on your way keep
in mind that the risks though with the
VMS right if the host operating system
is compromised most likely you might
just say your VM is as well also if your
laptop is confiscated
they'll probably know you're using a VM
so something to think about
as well so tails tails is a complete
operating system and it's really
designed to be used from a USB stick or
a DVD but no one has DVDs anymore right
I mean that's that's gone but USB stick
where nothing is ever written to the
host system that the project has done a
great job of really making a secure
operating system for people that need to
use it includes all the tools you need
has tor built in ready to go and sale
stands for the EM music incognito live
system so meaning that it forgets itself
which is pretty cool so you can run it
in a VM you can run it's like I said off
of a USB stick and I'll have links to
all these things here I'll tell you
where to get this stuff if you're
interested in down low
and playing with it the one thing I've
I've noted in my experiments with it is
there are some hardware compatibility
issues so if you're running like a
32-bit system like a laptop it just
doesn't work right so you got to have
64-bit it needs to run something newer
but but it's cool and it's customizable
too so you can have like persistent
storage and other types of things if you
want and it's nice because it'll
automatically reset itself which is good
now who Nix anyone ever play with who
Nix a few of you okay great yeah not a
lot of people have heard of it but this
is actually a full virtual machine
environment that acts as a gateway and a
workstation
the Gateway runs tor and the work
station runs user applications on a
completely isolated network so
everything is pre-installed just like in
the Tales environments and they've
automatically put safe defaults for
everything so literally you can pop this
in install both systems and you're on
your way so how this works is you have
the workstation and then you have a
gateway so you turn on the gateway first
the gateway basically connects to tor
and then you have another workstation
that connects just to this gateway so
essentially everything all your network
connections have to go through the
gateway which protects every type of app
that's going to use your internet
connection it's going to pipe it all the
way through tor which is pretty cool I
like this personally because I can then
customize my environment install the
tools that I want and then I can I'm
safely assured that I'm not gonna have
DNS leaks or anything else all going
through that system so I highly
recommend checking out the project it's
it's always updated it's a very active
project and people are always
contributing to it so pros and cons
again easy use on multiple systems I
talked about some of the the good things
about it you can install the things that
you need you know who Nix is not and
music like tales because it is a virtual
machine so some workarounds is you could
do a snapshot and control it that way
but that is definitely a con depending
on your situation but again I think it's
a really cool environment to use
so let's talk about VPNs right pros and
cons of VPNs so first of all any
potential VPN provider that you're going
to use definitely do your homework
because I'll start with the cons because
I think we all know the pros of a VPN
but even the companies that say they
don't keep logs they may be able to be
convinced by law enforcement and
governments to keep logs
so essentially you are trusting a third
party just if they say they don't keep
logs you just kind of kind of go with it
and hope that they say what that they're
not keeping logs but it's hard all right
we have to trust these third parties and
some third parties are more trustworthy
than others and I'll mention a few so
you can be the judge but the other thing
too with VPNs is I kind of lean more
towards the VPNs that have alternate
payment methods because one of the
things that all VPN providers are going
to keep is payment records so which
includes your credit card which includes
your name your address those types of
things well they may not keep logs of
your searches they still have payment
information because that's how they make
money so keep in mind that could be a
way of having you tracked as well signal
who use a signal hopefully a lot of you
yay excellent all right I mean you chant
a signal despite I know there have been
issues recently with some of the desktop
clients have having remote code
execution other things but again what
client software doesn't have remote code
execution right pretty much everything
but they do a good job they keep it
up-to-date and they communicate about
the risks and other things quite
frequently so if you're not familiar
signal it's an end to end encryption
application for Android Apple iOS
desktop uses the Internet to send text
messages video images and phone calls as
well so you can completely use it to
replace your phone and your cell
communication if necessary it's
developed by open whisper systems which
hopefully might even know is is the
project started by mocks Moxie
Marlinspike
who's a great privacy advocate also like
sailing if you ever get to meet Moxie
he's actually sailed I think crowd are
all around the world or something he's a
really interesting guy but doing really
cool stuff was signal one thing I
mentioned about signal is the censorship
circumvention which has been in the news
recently because that is now not working
thank you to Google and Amazon so signal
was kind of the pioneer and using
something called domain fronted requests
so domain fronting is basically a DNS
query that goes out that has one name
which they call the front domain and
then the host header is hidden from the
sensor or the nation-states
which actually carries another covert
destination so it's kind of a trick to
pull the sensor to allow traffic through
unfortunately Google and Amazon have
shut that down for lots of reasons I
think just because they don't like
getting involved in those types of
things I don't think they did it to
really you know cause human rights
issues or other things but so they the
relays blog I saw from them they're
looking at other options for this but
just so everyone is aware this does not
work right now all their secure
messaging services so whatsapp I
mentioned this because it does use
signals end-to-end encryption which is a
good thing
it also has a huge user base so 1
billion users use whatsapp they do keep
some metadata so location device info
cookies things like that and here's the
kicker though it's owned by Facebook so
whether or not you want to support a
facebook owned application is up to you
but know that it does use signals
encryption protocol which is a good
thing so again up to your risk level
then there's Facebook messenger which is
I think like the number three secure
messaging app the challenge with
Facebook Messenger is well the side
that's a Facebook app you actually have
to turn secret conversations on and when
you do though it's good because it uses
signals encryption protocol but it's an
opt-in type of thing so anything you're
sending
like right now if I send somebody a
message on facebook messenger it's not
encrypted and can be read so keep that
in mind
again very feature-rich because it's
Facebook right and of course they use
metadata for you guessed it ad targeting
so keep that in mind in the last two
things so here I mentioned is PGP PGP is
kind of gotten a bad rap recently with
who's heard of the e-file
vulnerabilities yeah and the email
clients you know they just update your
clients there is a lot of controversy
about where this is a huge issue or not
I don't think it's that big of a deal
PGP is still used you know quite a bit
and it still can be used securely it's
it's a lot older we know that but it can
be used in a privacy situation
absolutely so I wanted to mention that
and then there's a lot more third-party
secure email services coming out if
you've heard a protonmail
which is actually one email service that
I recommend because they don't keep any
logs it's open source they provide an
encryption there's a lot more of those
types of services one thing I would
recommend is that you check the origin
of where some of these services
originate so for example protonmail
is from Switzerland and they have very
very different laws in Switzerland than
they do in the United States which
actually have better protections for
users privacy so just something to
consider when you're choosing an email
client and the other thing I'm doing it
I'm probably gonna put a blog post out
about is if you've ever tried to move
from like Gmail to another email
provider it is like a nightmare so
because I've been trying to move more of
my stuff over to protonmail and it's
it's just very challenging so it's so
mobile devices and just your you know
any mobile device you've got to do some
basics right and these are my
recommended basics for any mobile device
so firstly you know full disk encryption
mandatory on Android you got in you got
to have full disk encryption you don't
have to worry about that in iOS but with
Android absolutely so make sure that's
enabled long complex passcode of 8 to 12
characters minimum set the device to
your race after 10 failed attempts or
depending on your risk level and then
just disabling any features that may be
used against you so whether that's
Bluetooth Wi-Fi
touch ID face ID location services
adjust as necessary and then always keep
your device up-to-date I know this is
harder in the Android world because of
something we like to call device
fragmentation where depending on your
carrier and depending on your you know
Samsung or whoever has your device they
may never update your device it's just
the way the Android world works compared
to iOS they're always keeping it up to
date but keep that in mind especially
with if you heard the news about what
iOS Apple is doing in iOS
12 with forcing the passcode to show up
more frequently because of the gray key
technology that law enforcement and
governments are using to break into
iPhones Apple is trying to catch up and
prevent that from happening so we'll see
what happens there but always keep your
device up to date and then if you're a
high risk individual if you're attending
a protest or if you may be under the
threat of arrest
these are the things that I recommend
turning off location services disable
remove any cloud backups because those
could be accessed by governments and law
enforcement log out of your apps if
you're not using them and then swiping
up to use your camera from the lock
screen so you want to unlock your device
and always keep in mind that you may
want to use a burner mobile device
depending on what you're doing and I
have some links to some recommended
burner mobile devices which are are
pretty cool and which leads me to
disposable devices ones that you can
throw away or not worry if you lose it
or if it is confiscated it may not be a
big deal so netbooks are really good
Chromebooks are cheap you could use
those you know SIM cards as well just
depending on the country that you're
traveling to you can get these pretty
easily and again the cons of a
disposable device really are around the
security features and of course payment
right so how are you gonna pay for that
probably should pay it in cash but also
note that when you are buying anything
you are probably on a surveillance
camera buying it so
keep that in mind that's right so the
last thing I wanted to talk about was
something called the Moscow rules so
anyone here what this is this is an
interesting thing so back in the day
during the Cold War the CIA used to give
these rules out to their agents when
they were dealing with Russian
operatives and these are the kind of a
set of guidelines and what I did here is
I kind of pulled the things out that I
think applied to digital privacy that we
should all be aware of and those three
things are never go against your gut so
when you're thinking about a tool or
technique usually your gut instinct is
the right one right we know this and
just anything with life right probably
should have gone my gut yeah you
probably should have so think about that
when you're going into a situation vary
your pattern and stay within your cover
this means change the things that you're
doing so for example you know you may
want not one to use the same VPN
provider for a year you may want to
change that to another one or you may
want to use a different browser for
certain activities compared to other
things so you want to change it up vary
the things that you're using in terms of
tools and techniques which will limit
the amount that you can be tracked and
then keep your options open right
because we've mentioned already nothing
is 100% secure there's going to be
vulnerabilities found in the tools and
the plugins we've seen it with signal
and other things stay up to date think
about using different tools and services
if you need to
when vulnerabilities happen and you
could be much more secure so in summary
so know understand your threat model
risk will vary by individual situation
always always keep it simple use the
tools and technology that we talked
about to your advantage
educate yourself on privacy security
awareness because that is always
changing a lot going on in the world
change your routine with the tools that
you're using multiple user accounts
rotate those devices that you talked
about and really share the need for
digital privacy and human rights with
others that's the biggest
I know for me the sharing is with you
hopefully you can talk to your friends
and family about maybe some you know
tips and tools that you've used we've
talked about today and then sharing the
message because it's really important
more information
EF f definitely follow them check them
out they're doing awesome things for
privacy in the world I highly recommend
supporting them as an organization they
also have great privacy guides news and
tools that they do my recommended
third-party services
I prefer private Internet access for VPN
they have probably the best track record
that I have and the most transparency in
terms of what they're doing in terms of
logs and other things again I'm trusting
them that they are not keeping logs but
they could be coerced like any other
provider to give up those logs so be
careful and then I've already mentioned
protonmail I think they're a great
service again based in Switzerland and
just a really good tool privacy tools IO
is a really really good reference site
for a lot of the tools that I've talked
about today as well as a whole host of
other things to reference and really
good guides as well so highly recommend
that sites and then I put on my blog if
you go to this bitly link privacy -
links it's pretty much everything I've
talked about during the talk and links
to things like burner devices and all
those other things that you can check
out and that is a safe link to click by
the way I will lead you astray
all right so questions yeah
what was your question
sesame credit system social credit score
I have not heard that yeah that is
interesting so it's like your credit
score but everybody will know the Oh
oh I see Oh gotcha gotcha that's
interesting
scary yeah oh do add-on step on each
other they can absolutely which is why I
recommend only using like one ad blocker
one tracker and not to like I wouldn't
use adblock adblock plus and you you
block origin at the same time they're
probably going to criss cross and if
anything and they're gonna cause more of
a CPU spike in your browser which is
going to you know make your system angry
Spencer
besides the e FF they are always on the
news arm they're always reporting on the
latest things which is great
there's a couple other links that I've
put into my my blog which you can check
out to news sources yeah
I'd start with the e FF yeah yes I was
approached so his question was how do I
get involved with speaking to
journalists about privacy I was I was
asked by this online I guess there like
a webinar type company that had a need
for some privacy talks specifically for
journalists and lawyers and people that
are kind of in harm's way so I think
someone just family maybe through my
podcast or something and asked me but
I'm looking at doing more of that with
maybe it might be speaking out like a
journalism conference or other types of
things where people are you know kind of
day-to-day line of fire type of work
which would be interesting but yeah kind
of just somebody just emailed me and was
like hey you want to talk about this and
I just happen to be you know really into
researching this stuff at the time and
it worked out yeah
a question was around how I see the the
cell phone tracking Supreme Court
decision playing out I think it's gonna
be interesting to see how the major
wireless providers change their tune in
terms of how your you're able to lock
that down and prevent location data from
going out I found 18 t's policy on it
fascinating because I just happened to
get a email the day that that's on
Friday saying because of the merger with
Time Warner we have updated our privacy
policy and I don't know if that was
ironic because the Supreme Court
decision was made in the morning and
then in the afternoon I get this email
but I went in I looked at my privacy
settings and I just noticed that they
say you can either opt out by going to
each individual third party and of
course they don't give you a list they
just tell you okay well that could be
hundreds or you can go to your privacy
settings and actually disable location
sharing with third parties and that's
why I'm Twitter I threw out a tweet like
has this always been here or is this
just ironic to a Supreme Court decision
I don't know but my opinion is I think
we're gonna see more communication I
think I think they have to legally now
communicate to their consumer base that
we are not allowed to use your location
data either without your permission or
without a warrant and so we'll see what
happens but there's probably hundreds of
companies that have partnerships with
the wireless carriers to to use our
location data real time and so I was a
government official I'd probably find
one of those third parties and just go
through them and you know avoid the
warrant situation so we'll see what
happens it's fascinating though yeah
yeah
well okay awesome
so the gentleman here said there's a
great humble bumble deal for
cybersecurity right now for private
Internet access it was a $15.00
cybersecurity bundle so DuckDuckGo that
all right well hey I'll be I'll be
building for questions after but thanks
for attending the talk