our next presenter is a writer and a
computer publicist he actually wrote the
first personal computer article in the
popular magazine galaxy ax in january of
1981 Galaxia sorry galaxia which i
believe is well known in Serbia and
since then has been covering every
aspect of Technology please welcome to
the stage day on wrist on of ish
okay I'm they understand which I am
editor-in-chief of PC press computer
magazine and I'm going to talk about the
long and bumpy road we made to get to
the internet here in Serbia it is I hope
an interesting thing because people take
internet now for granted but it wasn't
that way it all started in 1986 quite a
long time ago and we got at our
University vax decnet machines and this
was my first email address in my life
but it was not very powerful email
address because I could only communicate
with other people at the university and
later at other parts of Yugoslavia but
not to the world then in 1989 we got
beat net connection bit now not very
well known is because it's time network
and it's European a component was earned
European academic and research network
so somebody told us you will now get
really mail addresses you we would have
the ability to send emails to everywhere
in the world to the America and we asked
what yes you can send email some text to
a friend in America and he will receive
it in like five minutes and how much
does it cost well it costs nothing so
where is the catch there is no catch
well that that can't happen it's not
just not true but once we understood it
really is true we really love that and
used it and even learn how to download
encoded files from Treecko servers and
it all was going well until nineteen
ninety-two well now I am really a geek
and I really hate politics and I don't
want to talk about politics but just
little
politics here in nineteen eighty to
ninety two we had a war here the country
dissolved and the whole world decided
that we Serbs are the bad guys and as
you know the bad guys shouldn't have the
internet access so they cut us so we had
got nothing no internet access no email
nothing well so we lived in a country
handle under blockade and we had to do
all the work ourselves the key to do
that was BBS in November 1989 with one
colleague mr. cilenti voltage under the
computer magazine Ranieri which means
computers I was editor there we started
the BBS it was it first small BBS just
one line BBS but over time it grow to
three line by line 10 lines 15 lines and
became the largest baby st in Yugoslavia
which was not very difficult but also in
all this part of Balkan it was a
conference system run running using
original software we developed and the
main things with cells and words at
conferences there is compresses about
computers about communications about
lifestyle culture even politics and
people came there to talk about all that
mostly also to download some files
because it was the only way to download
new software public domain and other and
they had to pay some subscription about
eighty dollars per year which was a lot
of money at that time so there was no
not much digital photo cameras and
mobile phones at that time so I don't
have many photographs of thousand BBS
this one was taken from some TV show
where it was featured at it goriest
moments in 1994 I think it used
compaq deskpro server and it was my
lectures it was a workstation that we
call this server it hits 330 megabytes
disk and we when people talked a lot
that this became full but we could not
acquire another disk that would fit
compaq they needed some special disks so
we have to put another no-name pc with
the gigabyte disk at all ran under novel
network that will reserve us now each
phone line was powered by one dose
computer that are mostly outdated
computers even by that time but they
were cheap and that was all we could get
so every line was supported by one
computer they were connected to a
network and they communicated with the
users using by today's standards very
slow modems custom software was written
in microsoft see and turbo pascal and
the staffing food it one system manager
to system administrators about 12
moderators one secretary and I don't
know some three or four thousand users
now in order to use sesam you had to
have a computer which was expensive and
difficult to obtain in serbia be able to
connect the modem configure ports
configure the modem use communication
program read and understand the manual
you know this is the manual it's about
200 pages of small print of how to use
each of the commands and so pay eighty
dollars a year which was odd sometimes
standard salaries were maybe ten dollars
a month so it was a lot of money so we
have successful technically able people
and that was the secret of the success
people mostly talked on our BBS and here
you can see the first five were for 45
years people talks about computers and
other subjects and you can see there was
one hundred and forty thousand messages
in the best year that's a lot if you
take total number of characters if you
see how how many characters people wrote
that was text only we didn't have any
multimedia you couldn't impend some
pictures in that text it was only text
people written now you can see 120
megabytes of text and that little little
blue dot is the length of the Lord of
the Rings trilogy so you see how much
text people wrote of course that was not
so interesting at a lot of the Rings but
you know it was a great quantity and the
average length of a message wants
aborted 100 characters so compared it
with some messages now our Facebook
would say you're great go so it was
serious talk on many subjects but of
course we still needed the internet and
here comes the hacking part the phone
was a way to contact the bra destination
it was almost impossible to use because
it was extremely expensive and besides
the connections were lousy so we found
that they didn't cut x.25 network postal
network which was called you packing
serbia like yugoslavia packet network
but it was 960 bits per second pharaoh
whole country so it's not very fast but
by typing some username a password and
this number you could get too big for
example Biggs was bite information
exchange of the BBS of the byte magazine
famous log in there
pay their subscription and really get
really made address this was much my
first real email address I could only
send short messages it was expensive but
it really worked or some people found
another heck they could connect to
something called out I'll there were out
ice all over America you could connect
to the out I'll using packet network and
then dial a number in some area for
example new Virginia area and connect to
any BBS there is if the BBBS is free
then you can get some free access and
maybe send email or something but of
course you have to pay you per costs it
was slow and expensive but it worked so
people thought well let's use some
tricks let's make it even easier so they
did things like this you sent on a vax
computer email to this strange address
it says well go to using packet network
to some system in Swiss and then send
mail from there if somebody wants to
reply to you he has to use other address
to say go to that system and have it
mailed yet the message to a recipient it
was expensive not only for us but also
for that systems and they didn't like it
this particular system had an
administrator I remember even today he
was named smart in winter sunshine on
Pegasus bebes and he said well what are
you doing you are using our resources
why are you doing that we said well you
know we are cut from the internet we
this is the way to communicate with our
friends in the world and he said okay I
cannot allow that but i will stop
looking so
so we use that a lot at least he was a
good man so greetings talking wherever
he is now and now finally we found a
real solution one of our guys in
California State University decided to
route all the email to Serbia from his
office computer he had a computer in his
office and he puts a male around it and
we had strange email addresses like this
but it really worked and our friends of
the university made it work by on the
school of Electrical Engineering a
faculty or organizational scientists
they wrote some custom software that use
all the tricks to using our dials using
other means to deliver the mail receive
the email distribute that email using
UCP protocol to other computers in
Serbia and that system was slow but it
really worked it was also expensive but
we had money at the time you see one of
the
one of the notes we had many of these so
actually if you wait a bit to pay your
phone bill however big your phone bill
is it will meet will not be much money
because when this bank note was
published it was worked like two dollars
a week later it was worked like ten
cents so if you wait a week then the
bill goes down and finally you know we
lost all the wars so we were still the
bad guys but you know we were defeated
bad guys and defeated bad guys could
have internet access but it has to be
slow so we got one satellite link it was
64 kilobits per second for complete
country believe it or not done by the
University of Belgrade one company at
one bank and it was a beginning 1996 was
a wonderful year for Internet in Serbia
some time later we get the rest rail
links we had multiple providers and we
finally got to the internet even our
cells and went pro instead of home build
pcs we use professional equipment we
offered full internet access more diving
fault lines reported our software to
32-bit platform using the NT servers and
we became one of the important internet
providers but even most importantly a
social network was born a social network
of users and I have here a few lines
from wired article published in april
nineteen ninety-seven i think it was
called the internet revolution in
belgrade it was about how the users of
says and B&BS use the internet to
oppress the repressive government
and fight for their freedom and as you
can see it David call was one of the
three main points leaked in Serbia to
the net and the outside world and he
said that organizing these products the
culture without whose cooperation and
support the internet would not exist as
a political weapon so we came to the
politics again but it were important
times and eventually the repressive
regime was our own in night in two
hundred two thousand year well ISM we
had to come to the millennia in without
repressive regime well what happened
next everything was much easier but
somehow complicated at the same time we
got broadband fibers later we have a dsl
and cable internet we get mobile
networks ebanking the Comets global
corporation offer their equipment and
services our chasm was acquired by
certain investment fund it is now an
important internet provider and the
conference system still exists not it is
not used much that it exists it we moved
it to a virtual machine and anybody can
still tell Matt and access all those
conferences as messages and but the
which is much more important sell some
users are scattered around the world and
still communicated one way or another
using multiple means they all remember
it with happy thoughts and you know life
is a journey not a destination it was a
great journey I was proud to be a part
of it and it's bet the best part of my
life thank