hello everyone thank you guys for coming
I know it's very early in the morning
there's rain we've been drinking last
night some of us so I really appreciate
I hope you understand that you know
we've been overly ambitious with this
and we have a program that starts now
and ends at like 3am i hope you'll hold
on a stick around for you know for all
of it just before we get started a
little bit of a logistics you know so we
this is you know where most of the talks
are the workshops are in the space
that's right outside on the right
unfortunately we did have a we don't
have a case of a missing person Sutton
ashes that was supposed to do the DIYs
sint workshop he's just missing not
answering his phone we don't know what's
happened he was supposed to find from
London last night so for so it seems
like there's not gonna be a first
workshop is not gonna happen the other
one rather nearest one is on schedule
and he's been mobbed by a lot of people
already so so feel free to use that
other space if you guys want to start
working on badge hacking just feel free
to you know grab a table over there and
if you want to get a you just get
started early yeah okay i think that's
that's about it for all the logistics
for all the presenters if you didn't if
you didn't bring your powerpoint just
bring it to the AV desk or dad all right
hi so my name is Alexander my name is
Alexander Braddock I'm a ride for heck
they do a bunch of other stuff for
hackaday but uh so my primary day-to-day
role is uh is a CTO at a company called
supplier frame and kind of the easiest
way to explain about supplier from him
is is really just a whole bunch of super
nerdy computer science people really
passionate about electronics a lot of us
have you know academic or professional
backgrounds in with Johnny
but our kind of core expertise is softer
and you know what we try to do every day
is right software build tools that that
you know really help you know the how
people building harder you know to the
extent that we can and you know we kind
of hope we can hope we can do a lots are
you know big mission is something like
organizing the world of engineering
knowledge and you know being like a
Google of electronics and all that other
awesome stuff we've been around for you
know quite sometimes almost 10 years
almost 10 years now and you know we did
some fairly interesting things I'm not
going to get into but why are we
relevant because in the context of this
presentation is that you may remember
around three years ago our favorite
website hackaday came up with an article
that says hack days up for sale and you
know Hackett has been around for a while
also by 12 years started out as a blog
on engadget and since then had like a
really interesting interesting history
but you know it's a the previous owner
came to the point where you know he was
kind of stuck and I think that the way
the way he was thinking about hacked it
was more like a media company or
something like that and he decided to
sell it and you know we just woke up one
morning and we were like oh my god like
heck it is up for sale you know whoever
buys it is probably going to ruin it and
what do we buy and it's a little bit
weird like why would software company by
a you know a blog a website but we you
know we one of our engineers rent or CEO
who is an amazing guy is somewhere in
this audience I can see from all the
lights bahaha and and he convinced him
that you know we should really do this
and get with it and you know kind of
hope so our core idea was you know the
at the time hackaday put up a
Kickstarter campaign an IndieGoGo
campaign for a community to buy for a
community to buy hackaday and you know
Brian bench up for this elaborate
presentation about all the awesome
things that they would do with it and we
saw the presentation and it was like
well this is really cool you know maybe
maybe we can help maybe we can do
something about it and then I kind of
you know first year was really first
year of us acquiring hackaday people who
are equally suspicious you know where
you're going to do you know
ruin it so back from the day one we set
a you know a whole bunch of ethical
limitations around you know editorial
independence and really trying to do the
right thing and most importantly you
know because we are all software nerds
electronics nerds we really understand
this space we really kind of felt that
we can introduce something unique the
kind of things that other people
wouldn't do and you know truly your
triggers later I think we you know we
did a whole bunch of different stuff but
you know some of the things some of the
interesting things that we did on the
day one obviously being softer people we
said well what can we build with softer
and then we went out in we build
hackaday ayah which you know two years
in is really became you know become for
a lot about just a place where we hang
out and we always wanted to have
something that reminds us of a like a
BBS or something like that that in a
very special in its creation oriented
it's not like Facebook for hackers it's
more you know how do we create more like
a collaborative online environment for
for people to you know work with other
people and meet other people from around
the world and that's been you know
extremely successful and you know we
were kind of continuing to push it you
know the other part you know I'm
personally really proud of is the
editorial direction of hackaday with a
spearheaded by Mike's dish or managing
editor here somewhere you know we really
we really set out then it's like all its
2015 2016 what's big right now BuzzFeed
and catchy headlines and the media is
dead and the print is that no one cares
about any of this stuff but uh but we
still we we set as a mission to really
build a in a professional journalist
like organization that's that's you know
trying to do journalism the way it was
done in computing in the eighties in you
know 2015 which is you know completely
ridiculous and it's not just ridiculous
for the outside for when all the media
companies are dying it's all so
ridiculous in the for our community
because they're like Oliver I just we
just want hacks we don't want Brian
bench of crazy rants we don't want you
know investigative journalist pose but
we're really committed to this and I
think we've kind of come a long way and
you know we're going to continue pushing
pushing that because we kind of believe
it is the right thing to do you know
another thing that we that we did
and you know one thing that you may
learn we knew if you talk with us over
here that we don't do a lot of planning
a lot of things that we have done we're
really spontaneous were just like spur
of the moment why not we can do this and
all that stuff and one of the things
that came out of like late-night
drinking in Pasadena you know we had
this talk about well you know what is
you know the open hardware and you know
people and everyone builds their little
project and put it on the shelf but how
do we motivate people to really build
something more serious you know because
for the open hearted to really matter we
need production product great open
hardware products are the people can
build and you know so we were and it is
the time bench of came up with this
ridiculous idea of like a heck of a
space program and then we're drinking
and drinking and then flag was like well
what are we you know send some of the
space would that be would that be an
interesting incentive for people and
that that's how the heck of the price
was and then we were all just like
laughing then tomorrow morning for I
calls me up and he's like oh we should
really do this you know we can you know
figure out the money and so we started a
heck of a prize really just as a one of
the ways to give back to the community
and really to create a way to to
motivate people because we all know how
you know we all like to procrastinate
and it's and it's you know people here
the actual motivation so you know we're
doing a heck of a price for a third year
now and it's been growing and growing
and a lot of a lot of amazing project
came out of it and so you know we're
really happy about it and we're gonna
continue pushing it especially over the
last two years Sophie Kravitz who is
also here you know it's done an amazing
job and really kind of growing it so
yeah you know we're going to continue
doing that as well and then another
thing that we did also very
spontaneously like last year Sophie and
I were just sitting at being grumpy
about how in the u.s. there are no good
harder conference is because in
especially in electronics everyone is
trying to sell you something so a lot of
these are just like very you know sales
driven which is fine the problem is that
there are just no more conferences with
you know deep technical content and so
we were just you know being grumpy and
yeah and talking or what did we do why
don't we do a conference and something
was like yeah it should be a super
conference and so basically that was
like end of sep tember and then and then
we were like a woman should we do it and
you know why don't we do it at the end
of the heckler prize in November so we
send out a call for papers and you know
two months later there was a huge
conference in there's a great success
and
people were like you're just insane
trying to pull a conference in like that
short of a time frame but it turned out
to be amazing so you know we really like
that and then you know somehow we were
here now well I go what are we do a
conference in Belgrade and I'll explain
how do we how do we get there but
basically at some point in January we
put out a post that says oh well doing a
conference in Europe and it's going to
be in Belgrade and it's going to be
awesome and then you know heck of the
comments people like Oh Spain has the
weather the people in the Fiesta have
that so it's in weather sucks and then
so what people are immediately like
white Belgrade do I know this why not
that but you know that's fine we were
still here and you guys all show up and
we really appreciate that how we really
got there was was pretty funny is a you
know we did that we did the super con
and it was amazing and you know Belgrade
is very convenient for us I'm personally
for Belgrade we have an engineering team
here you know some of the really core
developers for supply frame you know
work here in the Belgrade office so
obviously that it was easy a lot of them
travel to us but then when we did the
supercar no one from Belgrade was there
so this amazing i bill KR lead see soft
guy who's sick today and couldn't come
was like really bummed out the key
called me and he was like why didn't you
call me to go to this conference is also
amazing you know he was kind of bummed
out and then Sophie from the day one
when she joined she was like a bell race
how exciting I want to go to Belgrade so
we were just like talking and then and
then and then we're like all of Sophie
maybe you can come to Belgrade maybe we
can do a little meet up like that's
that's really how this thing happened we
just wanted to have a small meet up in a
like a bar and then and then stitch was
like like oh I heard you know we're
going to Belgrade can I can I come and
and then we sent you know this Bilkey
who was here in Belgrade like oh can you
go find the venue and then somehow he we
were joking about like this space
because this is a this is a legendary
space for us it's a like a Belgrade
youth center a lot of events really
important for us we're happening at this
pace the first linux conferences were
happening here a lot of scene demoscene
events were happening here and i was
just jokingly my guys been like all can
you go and ask how much would it cost to
rent in this venue and then he went here
in the and the the price was like like
really only that the san francisco vents
are like super expensive so what do we
do it there
and then it was like well who's going to
talk and you know because like Serbia is
not a huge country there's not a massive
scene and then we said well why don't we
put a call out on half a day and then
maybe see someone maybe someone would
apply maybe from like you know Bulgaria
or Croatia or something like that and
then so we get some speakers and then
two days later we have much 50 talk
proposals and oh my god like this is not
via I think so we just you know kind of
decided to really try an event and you
know you may it may be funny but it's
been three months this is our you know
best planned event yet like three months
for us is too long we plan like in weeks
so we're all here and you're at the end
of this so that's how this happened but
why Belgrade okay so great you know you
guys love hackaday and Irene and I think
you know the the weirdest part is that
we we started to be like let's put our
tickets on eventbrite and let's put the
tickets on eventbrite then maybe some
people are going to buy it but then
we're going to put local tickets for
like serbian audience it turns out that
like serbian audience doesn't really
have western credit cards and eventbrite
apparently doesn't even take visa
electron which would we learned later so
but we sold out more than half of a
tickets within the first couple of days
and pretty much at the end over half of
people here you know came from from
outside of Serbia it just towards the
end there were no enough tickets left to
sell to the local audience but you know
some people you know figure the way out
and so I really applaud everyone they
really made an effort here but the
question is you know why Belgrade do you
guys love happy that you came here to
hang out with Sophie station but other
people and you know socialize with your
community and you know you a lot you
know number of people will go anywhere
for hackaday but why did we drag you to
Belgrade you know what what's so special
about this area and I think the team
here is not Belgrade itself is is that
they were trying to make a point that
the local cultures matter obviously
Belgrade is the closest to us and it's
given you know hackaday has a number
several people working on hackaday live
or have lived in Belgrade and a lot of
our local culture has really is really
is influencing some of the editorial
direction but the point is that the
local cultures matters and the the
computing culture that was
has evolved here in Serbia is really
weird and unique and like in a lot of
countries in Europe as opposed to maybe
us where it's more you know of one
uniform culture so if you think about
computing in Serbia and the weight
started in the in the eighties it's
really started out as the mix of this
magazine called the world of computers
that was trying to be like a survey he
was Latvian byte magazine that was the
idea but then there is somewhere along
the way it crossbred with this like
bizarre Italian comic called Allan fort
which is just like this wacky right
there it's really weird it's hard to
explain it and not many people get it
but like that that kind of a bizarre
graphic novel culture Hitchhiker's Guide
to the galaxy and like a lot of other
things that were happening here like
demoscene and things like that and as a
result of this there's this like a
really weird in and unique culture and
you know some of that some of that we
are also trying to you know some of that
weirdness we're trying to bring to
hackaday as well along with other types
of weirdness like Brian bench of Hunter
Thompson has style that and other people
things as well but uh the you know other
other cultures in Europe other countries
have their own flavors of computing and
it's you know like these things are very
important to cultivate and build on
because we don't all just want to be on
facebook and you know like the one the
same thing you know this is really
important but another thing that really
that really makes Belgrade very relevant
for hackaday is that a a year ago this
guy over here Chris gamo who runs you
know empower with Dave Jones you know he
was visiting Belgrade and so he asked us
like oh well you know who's famous
around here who can i interview for the
empower and and you know we immediately
said oh there's this guy boy Anthony
geezer you know big deal and he built
this computer in the 80s and he was part
of that the world of computers and like
that whole you know weird computing
cultures in the 80s you also need to
understand the difference in socialist
country and computing was not you know a
lot of things were a lot of concepts
were just independently reinventing here
just because people have no access to
information so and he was one of the
guys that really defined that culture so
we're not all it's why you have to meet
this guy and not none of us knew him
very much younger
but somehow we found his number
telephone book still use that and then
and then eventually he came to her
office recruits to interview him and we
started talking and and he didn't know
about hackaday but uh but you know he we
kind of you know to explain to him
everything that you know we were doing
what we were up to and he was really
excited and then you know a couple of
months later he actually started writing
for hackaday and you know some of the
most unique articles out there have been
written by him and via post water
projects on Hector day I oh and also you
know what some of the other heroes from
the 80s you know jump in with some
illustration for various pieces and I
was really proud of that and then so we
floated to the void the idea of like oh
well we might me do this conference and
then boy it was like oh well let's do a
badge so you know the badge it all of
you guys have and and a lot of other
weirdness there are some crypto puzzles
and a bunch of other stuff around the
conference is all voice so you know that
that was that was really important for
us and that's and that's really why you
know why we you know we feel Belger it
is kind of special for us because you
know we are continuing to bring some of
that culture into the DIA tutorial
directional hackaday and really the
point of this event is is not to promote
belgrade but it's just too to call
everyone to really dig deeper into like
their look unique local heritage as well
as much local history and then and then
see how these things can influence you
know what's gonna been happening today
especially in the domain of hardware
projects we all need like inspiration
for creativity so hopefully you know
maybe this next year this event is going
to be held somewhere else in Europe but
it as opposed to Belgrade where we have
a lot of people we are going to need
someone's help so if this is interesting
to you guys please let us know finally
you know there's nothing new Under the
Sun I just want to point out one thing
that I you know the the posters and the
art and everything you know this
conference is actually not unique it's
not original like this is a poster for
for the art show in zagreb croatia in
1969 and so there's this like computing
art movement that was primarily based in
croatia but also with a lot of people
from belgrade participate called bit
international
and you know they did some of the
amazing things so we just wanted to you
know honor a lot of times we just make
some blinky thing and we're like all I'm
genius no one has ever done that this
then you discover that people did you
know these kinds of things in a in a way
before and you know we should sort of
explore that and build on that yeah so
like with that this is that's that's
really all I just gonna one of the very
hand wavy but all I wanted to say as as
an introduction of you know why are we
here and what are we trying to
accomplish a bunch of other things
really contributed I just also want to
want to give my thanks to some of the
other people that really help organize
this conference obviously you know we
know a lot of people about also getting
sponsors very easy a number of us here
come from you know what I call a vast
mafia vest was this like internet
startup that started here in Belgrade
and then I went on to work somewhere
else and another guy you know when to
find this other company called seven
bridges serve you know so we just called
a couple of friends and we organized a
pretty much everything that's going to
happen here the food and and all that we
have to thank our sponsors you know for
that and I think just just a little bit
on the on the agenda today it's really
so we really you know once we discovered
that people are going to show up and a
lot of people are going to show up from
outside of Serbia we really try to put
on an event that that's you know very
ambitious so we start now with a lot of
talks we have a break at one for lunch
there's a break in the afternoon for
like cocktails there's a break
afterwards for dinner and then and then
at I think 930 we have concerts and we
have two bands we have two bands playing
here one is in you know in a it's kind
of bizarre the first band is actually so
all the bands are all engineers so like
the first band is actually all engineers
from the 7th company seven bridges and
then and the other the other band is uh
it's like actually a big deal band in
Serbia called called T so all these
things are going to go until midnight
and just please stick around and
of just you know honor engineers it's
actually the first been started as a
engineering in house band for four seven
bridges so you know give them sounds
like is there like first big concert and
and then and then at midnight so a lot
of people are going to show up at nine
because we're going to open it for the
concerts but in the meantime you know
you you can either hang out at the
concerts and work on your badges and
just try to do something and then at
midnight we're gonna do presentations
we're gonna do like a you know old
school demo scene style compa where you
know we're gonna showcase everything to
create earn your badges there's gonna be
some prizes and stuff like that we also
created an emulator so that other people
from around the web can contribute their
thing so even if you don't feel like
you're qualified in winning some of
these things please try to participate
in badge hacking because it's you know
just a great learning experience and
then after that like 1am or so there's
gonna be a DJ and you know we can we can
stay for as long as we want so please
stick around and act once again thank
you all for coming you know and
especially to everyone that you know flu
and took a train or whatever from all
parts of Europe I heard there are some
people they know that came doing further
away we really appreciate it and you
know hopefully hope you hope you have a
fun time here today thank you