hey good afternoon everyone
everyone hear me okay
cool uh thanks for coming to our talk uh
my name is kyle salaz
and i'm aaron buring and i just have to
say if i seem a little bit nervous today
it's because this is the first time i've
ever presented in front of my
seven-year-old daughter so she has
promised me that she would make at least
two funny faces at me though so that
should break the ice so it'll be all
right
all right uh so real quick we're going
to talk about a lot of stuff pertaining
to collecting logs from endpoints in the
network and if you hear uh some things
that you don't recognize or you don't
understand why we did some certain
things or turned on some certain things
we've done a couple of talks for uh
shmukon and then in mir khan which is i
think firecon or something this year
and then we've uh we've gotten an
article in ieee so take a look at those
and i'll give you some background into
why we did some things with immediate
app locker and host-based firewalls
so the point of of our talk today is to
kind of go over the our our last two
years with
deploying sims or simin in our
environment and how we went about
collecting logs uh
some very obvious goals here implement a
sim uh collect logs from what matters
not from everything and do it within
budget anyone here that's ever tried to
spec out a sim uh they're really really
expensive
and actually make use of it we don't
want to treat this like an ips sensor
where you just buy it and then
no one knows what to do with that
so if you do cyber security operations
uh you will likely have to deal with
phishing emails it's still the most
prominent attack vector
uh for compromising end hosts this is
one that came across our networks i'd
say in september and it's a you know
it's a receipt for some payment that the
user supposedly uh you know some
transaction that the user had done in
the past and it's a it's a word document
uh but the user doesn't know that the
word document has
embedded macros it calls on a script
that drops a
an exe that then makes a connection out
and starts encrypting their entire
profile so this is pretty standard stuff
our goal eventually after doing the
basics was to figure out how we can log
this stuff
and then proactively alert on it and
then search the entire enterprise for
artifacts from something like this
because this is the most common attack
vector
or at least the scariest in terms of
how apt starts
so the the point of this talk is if you
listen to your logs uh they'll have some
great things to tell you
uh i'm gonna go through some basics if
it bores you uh bear with me we'll get
to some of the more interesting stuff
that we did so we had a demo period we
evaluated a couple of sims i know it's
hard to do a demo sometimes you just
want to pick something look at the magic
quad and be like all right we're going
with vendor a because they're all the
way up here
uh
obviously you want to create your own
requirements and then make sure that you
don't exceed your budget
and then you want to document everything
uh and then you want to send a
requirements document out to some
vendors the usu the reason i say this is
because some vendors will if you send
them a requirements document they'll
usually the marketing guys will
answer everything like yeah we do
everything uh guess what when you buy it
and you have that document with their
responses you can come back and say you
don't do this or you don't do this well
but you said you did so you could you
have some leverage with the product
development team come back and have them
uh build some more uh
some more features that you actually
want uh that stuff is really expensive
if you want to hire consultants to do
that especially for the more higher end
uh sims
so let's go through the steps uh step
one you want to configure logging
obviously figure out what log sources
you want to log from and only pick the
events that you want to parse out don't
just send everything
we're going to go through the order of
what we did in terms of what we picked
out first and
and it was more of a methodical approach
i know it's kind of counterintuitive to
say i'm just going to send my firewall
logs to this you know half a million
dollar product that i just bought but
actually try to do that and then figure
out how that
how that works with with the sim
sometimes
you run into parsing issues run into
timing issues and we'll get through some
of those uh the other important thing
that we ran into this is that you will
have performance issues with some of the
some of the log sources the devices that
you turn logging on
for instance
switch acls if you ever turn those on
because you have all these acls that you
want a lot you want to see what what
kind of traffic's reversing your network
that'll if the switch is a little bit
smaller it'll bring down your switch so
that's some of the the things we kind of
ran into
the second step is actually figuring out
what you're going to send to your sim
uh we this is in the list of what we did
we started with perimeter firewalls ips
sensors that's an obvious one sim
vendors really do a good job picking up
on the common events that those those
lock sources generate domain controllers
for obvious reasons you want failed
logins you want domain admin logins you
want
any really any login and there are a lot
of rules built in for that
uh web and database servers we haven't
done much with database servers there's
it's kind of a tricky uh it's a tricky
device to log or or entity to log but we
we have done a lot with web servers and
there's a lot of good logging there that
we'll get into
uh load balancers and proxy devices uh
proxy devices are
are amazing if you have an inline proxy
and if you're doing ssl decryption there
are a lot of great logs that you can get
out of that and then all the
infrastructure stuff rsa servers vpn
devices
uh the one the bullet point before the
last talks about netflows jflows partial
packet captures full packet captures if
you have a gazillion dollars uh you can
feed a lot of that stuff into your sim
and it it kind of augments your log
sources so it acts as like a like a
crude dlp or even an ids really
and then the last bullet is client logs
and and that's what aaron's going to
cover in the second half of this talk
and that's kind of where we did a lot of
the custom stuff and and that's where we
want to lean in on the vendors
the sim vendors and the product vendors
to kind of do better there because it's
severely lacking in that area
the final step is
actually looking at the payload as it
gets parsed out in your sim
so
there are multiple
event timestamps that could be labeled
or thrown at a payload and uh half the
time those things aren't uh get
co-mangled like the event time versus
the storage time versus the start time
uh most most host-based firewall logs
don't sim vendors don't do a good job
parsing out those logs
also look at if the entire payload is
arriving so
we've had this with our proxy locks
where the law the payload is literally
too big and it just gets truncated so if
you have like a url at the top that's
really long urls can get really long and
then the source ip and the username or
beyond that then you don't get to see
that so that's just something to pay
attention to and then figure out if
things are actually getting mapped to
global categories uh
you know they're they're native uh
mappings in every product and and those
things don't always translate well so
depending on what you're sending there
you want to make sure that like a
username is getting mapped to the global
username that makes a difference because
if it's not then if you have a domain
controller and a firewall they both have
a username field and that category isn't
happening then the rules won't work
because the username doesn't translate
for the firewall logs
quick note on ntp uh just point
everything to one log source if you can
uh it's for obvious reasons you don't
want to have
uh an issue where you have
dhcp logs and let's say firewall logs
that are two minutes ahead somehow your
client made http connections before you
got a dhcp lease that is going to mess
with your um
your correlation engine
so and you're not able to actually do
anything forensically
if you if you have uh log sources that
are desperate in time so that's just
something to pay attention to
and then if you have chatty applications
that you know send a million packets of
requests within a second it gets really
hard if if the timing's off
absolutely yeah
and that completely depends on the
application
oh he said the depth of the time whether
it's milliseconds or actual seconds that
makes a difference uh how how granular
your your your setting your ntp settings
but
we'll get a little bit more into timing
when it comes to some of the other logs
uh if you do all this you and your logs
will start painting a really pretty
picture
hopefully so let's get into some of the
network logs that we've done uh proxy
logs we mentioned this is a huge
uh advantage if you can get this parsed
out so i wouldn't worry about system
logs initially unless you're
unless you're using your sim for both
operations and security so that's kind
of one of your requirements or your
operations guys going to be using your
sim or just your security guys
access logs are really where you want to
spend your time here we talked about
your url length being an issue most
vendors will fail here so that's
something you might have to take up with
them or increase the the payload side on
the on the proxy itself you could you
could switch uh syslog from udp to tcp
if you wanted and increase the packet
size so it doesn't have to go over udp
a cool thing that we discovered is you
can get every list of every file that
was downloaded or uploaded so your your
proxy sits in line
uh that's not going to be parsed out i
doubt it we haven't seen a sim that
parses out file uploads because it's in
the payload you can reject that stuff
out
uh i don't know if you have use for that
on a day-to-day basis but it would be
really cool to say
that file was downloaded two months ago
on this machine
and it'll you know if you're keeping
your logs long enough you have that data
user asian strings will infer
application execution so
you know if i use netcat or if i use ie
there's going to be some sort of user
agent string
associated there
and then domains obviously ip address
and the destination domains being logged
by your proxy because it is proxying
that entire connection
uh and then i think most proxies
nowadays allow you to integrate with
ldap or active directory so the username
for every outbound connection that's
going to be included in your log
flows and partial packet captures
there's really one
one sim vendor in town that does partial
peak pcaps so traditionally you do
netflows which is port and source and
destination ip and then the packet size
or you do full packet captures which is
very expensive you need storage
uh processing all that stuff so
this ones inventor can combine
flows with packet captures and then
that'll give you some interesting data
on your network because you get to span
ports in really strategic locations and
then you have kind of like a crude dlp
sensor where you can start detecting
like someone bringing up a new dns
server or new sql database or a new vlan
or something
and then it helps you identify
patterns of usage
baselines don't have to be complicated
initially i mean i've attended a lot of
talks that talk about how you baseline
something and then how you build these
really cool uh graphs and how you detect
anomalous behavior this is a
graph from our network for three days of
just network traffic as you can see from
around i don't know if you can see the
time but from around 11
p.m till 5am not much is going on it's
an easy rule if you see a spike in that
time frame you know throw an alert
similarly uh during the peak times it's
pretty
it's pretty obvious that if someone you
know tries to do something at the peak
of time you could say 20 over that
that peak let me know if that if that
triggers uh that's just that's some of
the things we've done uh from like a
very basic standpoint
uh the last bullet talks about strategic
choke points
so if you spam a port in front of your
proxy every connection going to the
internet will be the source ip will be
the proxy
same thing with dns if you spam a port
in front of your dns servers then all
the recursive queries go in your dns
folder are going to be sourced by the
dns server if you span a port behind
your dns servers or behind your proxy
then you're getting the client ip that's
making that connection so that's just
something we learned that pay attention
where your spanning ports if you're
doing flows or partial
packet captures
uh we talked a little bit about the
behavioral rules uh this is more of
we use this for insider threat kind of
things or rogue admins you know if
someone brings a new dns server
you should have a process for
you know change control if something
comes up you're aware of it
most sims allow you to build a network
topology
you basically feed it all the vlans tell
it what your dns servers your sql
servers are your web servers and then if
it sees anything outside of that it says
hey there's a new dns server on the
network there's a new web server
obviously that takes time to tune early
on but once you do that it's really not
a lot of tuning to do
depends on how big your network is
new network being created similarly how
many times you're creating new vlans
we've had admins try to create new vlans
to circumvent
a lot of our interesting protections
that we have so
that does happen
we talked about traffic patterns during
off hours those are easy rules and then
once you have a large data set you can
start creating more complex rules
web servers uh
again back to user agent strings if you
have multiple user agent strings being
sourced from the same ip address that's
unusual
you should probably write a rule alert
on that it's usually an indication of
someone's just trying different tools
files that should never be accessed
honey pots you could put a like a dummy
file and if someone downloads it we do
that then you alert on it it has no need
to be on that server but we put it up
there to see if someone tries to
download it
um
create alerts for access to protected
directories uh same thing if they don't
if they shouldn't be accessed
you should alert on that
uh load balancers again we have large
web environments that are in the dims
either usually fronted by load balancers
make sure that the load balancer is uh
capturing the source id of the client
that's making the request otherwise
you're seeing the source ip as the load
balancer making the connection to your
web server just just a common theme
how you've seen
dns logging has actually been really uh
hard for us to do because
before server 2012 r2 you really had no
good way to extract dns logs if you're
running
uh windows dns uh you have to turn on
debugging and then that dumps it to a
flat file and then you have to parse
that flat file somehow get it to your
sim debugging on a domain controller is
a bad idea even microsoft will tell you
that
so what we ended up doing is using the
proxy logs and aaron will talk about how
we've enabled the client firewall that's
logging all of the domains that you're
visiting as a client so we've used that
kind of to search any dns or you know to
augment the fact that we can't really do
dns at this time
what was that
yeah we could always do that
we tried to do that we tried to do some
things with flows but uh the the parsers
didn't play very well i mean it
we have some ideas bro is one of them
uh we do have 2012 right now so we're
probably not going to go the complicated
route and just get dns logs off of the
domain controllers
uh
there are some more interesting rules
that we could we want to write like the
the length of the domain and uh
some some other some other things that
you want to do but so far we really
haven't gotten a chance to do that but
those are some good ideas
uh finally some basic custom rules i'm
sure you've seen some of these
alert for an ip address that connects to
multiple hosts in your dmz across your
entire enterprise sure you have
legitimate vendors that might do that
but why would one ip connect to three
different web servers that have three
different functions so that that's
that's something you can alert on there
any critical ips signature
if those aren't tuned yet i think you
have bigger problems but you shouldn't
have critical
ips firing all the time that's just an
easy rule to set there
suspicious countries connecting to your
network i don't know if you do business
with all 200 plus countries you might
have friendly countries you might have
not so friendly countries most sims have
geo
identifying abilities so if you see an
ip address they automatically say this
is coming from china
you can create a rule this is every time
you see china or russia connect to my
dmz
create a rule or alert for that
multiple failed vpn logins obviously
that's to detect some sort of brute
force on your vpn servers
simultaneous logins from the same user
that's rare alerts from demand from the
domain admins group uh you shouldn't be
using domain admin across your network
if you are uh don't
uh alerts on new user agent strings this
is also from the proxy so if you have
the data set for every single user agent
string
that's been launched on your network and
you regex that out and say all right
here's my baseline for user agent
strings anything outside of this throw
an alert
that's just uh that's an easy regex to
write and then
all of a sudden when you have a new
security someone tries to run some new
tool that you don't have in that data
set uh you've got you've got some some
interesting forensics there so this is
the network side aaron's going to go
into the client side and some of the
things we did there
thanks
so on the client side this is where we
really like to call this more of a
proactive forensics approach our goal is
to try and collect logs that normally to
to get that sort of information you'd
have to do some sort of a dead disk
analysis you take an image fire up the
forensics tools dig in try to figure out
what ran when what network connections
it made all that sort of thing our goal
was rather to
get this logged as it's happening real
time pull those into the sim and be able
to alert on them and or if we need to go
back and investigate them be able to
just make it as simple as a sim query so
some of the types of logs that we wanted
to pull are client firewall logs if you
haven't turned on the client firewall on
all of your endpoints you're missing out
on a very valuable source of data turn
those on feed them into the sim and
start searching into them additionally
getting some
information about what applications are
actually running on your network this
can either come from application
whitelisting um
you know if you've got windows 7
enterprise or above you have access to
app locker you don't even have to turn
it on in enforced mode just log pull
those application execution logs in and
now you can see what's being executed
and when sysmon is a fantastic utility
and if you haven't kicked the tires on
that
you're really really missing out and
i'll show you some examples of how that
can be used in a moment other types of
event logs that might be interesting are
when is a new service installed on your
endpoints you know if you can alert on
that and you know that it's not
associated with a big push that's coming
from your applications team who's
installing some new software that's
definitely something that you want to
dig in on and look at
as long as you're kind of being prudent
about the types of logs that you're
bringing in you can really get some
interesting stuff out of this
and by bringing it into the sim we may
not even need to take that step of going
to a forensic investigation
now the problem though is typically sims
have been focused at let's pull in from
the servers and you probably have less
servers than endpoints now if you just
flip on logging on all of your endpoints
haphazardly and feed it into your sim
the system is going to go down
so we need to be a little more judicious
about what we bring in so i'm going to
talk about some examples of how we can
kind of source filter that down to to
get what really matters
for endpoint firewall logging if you
have one of the standard endpoint
security suites
chances are it has a firewall component
that can be enabled and what it's going
to end up doing is logging back at that
management console that management
console can then be configured to syslog
over to your sim and so that's the most
normal way to get those events in what's
awesome about these logs is it will tell
you the exact application that was
running that's something that even the
best next gen layer 7 inspecting
firewall is taking a guess at but they
can't give you the exact application
like this can from there you can create
some very simple rules i mean would a
user ever actually run ftp.exe from a
command line probably not now admins yes
admins yes and you can separate out
those out and have different rules to
trigger on your admin accounts um you
know
powershell you know if there if it's a a
bad red teamer who's still migrating
into notepad with metasploit there's an
easy detection that sort of thing so you
can get pretty pretty interesting stuff
um
some of the gotchas though
normalizing time that comes from your
clients can be difficult if you have a
laptop that's left your environment and
it's been out for a week or so when it
comes back and uploads those logs this
is something that the sims don't handle
very well those logs are going to come
from your your management appliance and
the sim is going to take those events
and say these just happened despite the
fact that they happened four days five
days maybe a week ago uh and they'll
trigger on a fence and say it happened
at this time and if you go circling at
that exact time you're gonna be like uh
no it didn't
um another consideration is when these
these clients come back you may get an
eps burst when they dump all these logs
that they've been offline for a while so
it's one of those questions you want to
ask your sim vendors is how do they deal
with kind of spikes in your events per
second
but really the best way to to manage
this is like i said source filter look
at what some of the more chatty
protocols are decide whether you
actually need them on your network i
mean
some of the ones that do a lot of
broadcasts ssdp net bios that sort of
thing do they really have a need to be
in your enterprise if not
block it at the source
it's better to disable it but also go
ahead and create a firewall rule that
blocks it if it's going to try and go
outbound
there are broadcast applications that
you're going to have to allow though
take for example dhcp if you can't get
onto the network it's not very useful so
but when dhcp comes online your clients
going to make a broadcast out to port 67
and say give me an ip address well every
other client on that same vlan is going
to drop that packet and say this is not
legitimate traffic and when all that
comes to your sim it's going to be a
couple hundred logs and your sims gonna
say someone's port scanning this vlan
that's not what's happening so you need
to make some decisions about what you
actually want to log and when you're
creating your firewall logs it might be
fine to create one that just says drop
inbound port 67 and don't log it's
probably not going to be you know it you
are kind of curtailing some of your
information but on the long term it's
really going to going to pay off and
having cleaner logs coming into your sim
and you know just a side note whatever
endpoint firewall you're using make sure
it's not something that can be
manipulated by your end users it should
be securely managed upstream
so here's just sort of an example of a
sample firewall and the colors aren't
coming out too well but what i really
wanted to show out here is you know the
log
as it's being sent to the sim is showing
up as though it was september 18th at 10
55 however further down in the the
payload we see that the start time was
actually on september 16th and so that's
exactly the issue that the the sims
going to have a problem with so when you
go back to investigate these things it's
very important that you take in into
consideration not just the time that the
event was triggered on the sim but the
actual log source time as you're going
through it
um but as i alluded to i mean there's
just gold in these in these logs you've
got the domain that it went to the exact
application that was run the rule name
that you had created in your firewall so
all these things are that are things
that you can key in on and and try to to
alert on within your sim
now windows client event logs
this is always a difficult issue with
the sim windows of course doesn't
support
syslog natively we've got to find some
other way to get those logs in there
one way that you can do this is
by using native windows functionality
use event log forwarding to bring it
into a central place and from there fire
those over at syslog otherwise check
with your sim vendor they probably have
some sort of an agent that will sit
local on your host that's going to cache
those logs and then upload them securely
securely to the system um but again this
is something that can easily overwhelm
your your sim if you're sending every
single event log from your clients your
sims just going to crash now your sim
vendor will be happy to sell you more
eps and to sell you bigger boxes and
that sort of thing but uh like we said
we wanted to do this on a budget so
check with your some vendors check your
your client see what you can work out
xpath queries if they support it are an
excellent way to minimize what's coming
into your sim so this is a way of
searching through your windows event
logs and picking out only those
individual events that you actually care
about
if you want some good examples of the
types of logs that you should be looking
at there's a fantastic paper that was
published by the nsa called spotting the
adversary with windows event log
monitoring
if you go through that and i still
wouldn't recommend that you pick out
every single one of those events and try
to bring it in for your organization
that's probably still going to be too
much do some xpath queries against your
own box see what's normal what makes
sense then pick out only those ones that
do do make sense to bring into the sim
but you know some obvious ones that
you're always going to want to see event
logs are being cleared key in on that
users are being added to a privileged
group key in on that and then app locker
or emmett logs i mean if you've deployed
emmett and you're seeing something
triggering on a dep or aslr violation
that's something you're going to want to
kind of want to investigate further
and
leveraging application execution logs is
something that i think is very
interesting that the sim vendors haven't
really gotten their arms around they're
starting to recognize that they need to
do this but there isn't doesn't seem to
be some sort of a common framework to
say
application execution happened at just
the same way that there is to say
network flow happened or network traffic
happened
so this is something that we really had
to spend a lot of time customizing
around parsing out what is application
execution and recognizing it as some
sort of an event
now you can monitor for your white
listing system to say these things got
blocked that can give you some
information about you know something
that shouldn't have happened but what's
going to be more interesting in the long
term is what actually got allowed to run
because that's what got by and that's
that's where you're getting actually
owned
advanced attackers aren't going to drop
new payloads they're going to use native
functionality against you and abuse it
against you so you need to baseline and
know what is normal execution and then
you can start looking for those abnormal
executions like really long encoded
strings associated with powershell
definitely something that you want to
key in on
applocker i've mentioned a couple of
times that's kind of uh
one of our old go-to's but it just
doesn't give you the same robust
information that sysmon does with sysmon
you're getting the full what was
launched what it
what its parent process was the hashes
of it and the user that did it so
going back to that first slide that kyle
brought up of that phishing email i mean
anyone see anything that that looks a
little odd here i know it's a little bit
hard to read but it's saying the parent
image is windword and the command line
that windward ran
was it launched
a batch file out of the temp directory
if word is ever running a batch file out
of attempt directory you've got issues
guaranteed now if you are application
whitelisting
good stuff you won't even see this log
you'll just see the blocked execution
which is great but if you're not this is
the sort of log that you can collect and
take to manage in management and say
this is how we got owned and this is why
we should be whitelisting so it's still
good information to bring in
types of tools that you you want to look
at and this actually references some
things that we've brought up in
presentations in the past these are uh
tools that would be normal for an admin
to run but if you see your average end
user running these from the command line
you probably have issues
wmic definitely never going to see an
end user do it half of your admins
probably struggle with using those tools
as well
powershell you might if it's integrated
into some of your normal scripts and so
again you need to have that full
command line and that's where you can do
some great searching against that these
other ones typically you're never going
to see an end user run them
so you definitely want to monitor for
that sort of thing and these are the
ones that are very unusual i mean
typically even your admins aren't going
to run these i.e exec you know that gets
called from powershell a lot if you've
been watching any of the the red team
talks lately they they love these tools
so we need to start looking for them and
seeing when they're being used against
us
so here's sort of you know going back to
the whole picture of what we talked
about from pulling things from the
perimeter all the way down to the
endpoint what does it look like when
we're actually doing an investigation so
we have an alert that would be triggered
in our network if there's a large
outbound flow of data to an ip address
that we have not previously whitelisted
meaning it's one of our trusted partners
it's going to trigger an offense when it
comes time to investigate that
you know if we looked at just the
perimeter firewall for that outbound ip
address the source ip is going to show
up as our proxy typically and that's not
going to give us much information since
we've sampled our flows from the user
side of the proxy we can actually figure
out okay what is the actual source ip
address that's great information
digging into the actual proxy and client
firewall logs
if we just search on that destination ip
we're going to be able to extract what
was the user agent and does that match
up with the application that was said to
be running from the firewall rules if
it's saying that it's user agent ie
but it's a randomly generated string of
letters for the executable you've got
issues
so that allows us to validate that it
was actually a legitimate program
if we have the full url which you would
get if you're doing full ssl decryption
you may be able to actually pick out
what was the file that was being
uploaded at that point in time and then
you pick up the phone and call the user
and say hey what was going on um you
know for us luckily fortunately
to date we've only had those calls where
they're like yeah i was uploading a
bunch of photos to gmail and we're like
well don't do that on our network so
that we don't have these triggers and
that sort of also gets the word out that
says yeah big brother is definitely
watching so
it's a good way to go into it but you
know this whole process since we've got
all this stuff into our sim and
centrally managed and cleaned up this
can be done in a matter of minutes
rather than having to go out to the end
point dig around and try and figure out
what happened
so what do we see as sort of the
failures of sim vendors at this point
at this point
there's just a lot of payloads that
aren't processed to their fullest extent
especially when you look at the newer
generations of stuff the next gen
whatever that's doing that application
identification they aren't picking that
out and correlating that back very
neatly
um
we sometimes in our experience i've seen
poor communication between the vendors
that are making the products and the sim
vendors themselves so those log parsers
are getting broken on a regular basis so
you know another thing that you need to
do if you're managing a sim is from time
to time do a search just for unknown
events or uncategorized events
you're going to see a lot of things in
there that you may have thought were
being properly processed by the sim but
weren't that's when you need to start
opening tickets
if you haven't opened a ticket with your
sim vendor
at least once or twice a month you're
probably not paying attention to it
enough to be be honest
um
a lot of the vendors will have their own
you know ip reputation list and things
like that that stuff in our experience
is really becoming less and less
valuable
as everything's starting to be moved
behind cdns or even the bad guys are
putting everything behind cloudflare
that's not going to be very useful at
all it's just noise that you probably
don't need so you know don't tell your
sim salesman i said this when he's
taking you out to lunch but you probably
don't need to subscribe to those if as
long as you have some clean traffic you
can find a better signal in your your
own stuff
timing is still a major issue the idea
that an endpoint might not be sending
logs in real time is that something that
they grasp with
and there also still just seems to be a
lot of lack of support for the
non-standard windows log types
if you say i want to pull things out of
the sysmon logs which isn't sitting in
security or applications or something
like that they're going to look at you
and say why and you have to kind of
explain this is what i want to do and
it's really cool
and then you have to jump through the
hoops of trying to get it properly
qualified so that they it's categorized
properly within the sim and there just
doesn't really seem to be any
correlation around application execution
at all
and that's where everyone in this room
comes in really i mean we're the
customers of these systems in many cases
and if we don't start calling our sem
vendors and saying this is what i want
they're not going to implement these
things i mean we we actually
unfortunately have a very good
relationship with our sim vendor to the
point where we have a quarterly call
with their developers where we're saying
this is what we're trying to do these
are the things that aren't working can
you please make this happen and what we
always hear as a response is well we
would love to but what we need to do is
have this come forward from multiple
customers so i'm begging you guys as
customers of your sim vendors call them
up say this is what i want to do let's
start getting this there
if you aren't spending the time to
configure the basics and cleaning up the
rogue services and whatnot you're really
wasting
time with your sim and money
your sim is only as good as the signal
it gets so this is why we advocate
taking the methodical approach add one
source at a time make sure it's looking
good and clean tweak it if need be don't
do anything more until you've got that
source in and it is painstaking and it
does take time and that's why two years
later we're just now giving this talk
saying we are feeling pretty good about
our sim but we still feel like we got a
whole lot of work to go so
your end goal just needs to be a low
noise environment that enables you to
actually detect when the anomalous
behavior happens
so if you have any questions i would be
happy to answer some of them now or if
you want to hit us up on twitter twitter
later we're we're glad to do that yes so
after you've applied the filters do you
find useful for all those client event
logs sysmon app locker
that and things like that
um
about how much data are you typically
seeing from the average workstation in
terms of the number of events as well as
like megabytes grenade okay so the
question is after we've done our
filtering down how much our eps per from
each individual source of the end points
are we seeing or how much per day are we
seeing um
honestly when we
we first started doing this our
chattiest log that we were trying to
bring in was app locker and in a single
day you could get 30 megabytes of data
if you pulled everything in so the first
thing we said was that's not going to
work if we're pulling that from all our
endpoints do we really need dll
application executions compared to just
exe executions that's a simple i know
you would want it but when you think
about you know thousands of endpoints
feeding it that's the type of decision
that you have to make and realize that
just getting the executable happening
that's far better than nothing so that
trimmed that down significantly i would
say on a daily basis just the endpoint
logs that we're pulling in from from an
endpoint is probably on the order of a
couple of hundred logs
and it sounds minimal but in our
experience we really
i mean for for event logs yes but for
your client firewall that is the top log
source that's the top talker yeah
because you have rules enabled for every
single client times
the number of clients you have so that
is the largest log source consump
consumer but for event windows event
logs yeah not that much windows event
logs is a couple hundred a day so i can
expand dramatically on that so um
the windows firewall logs generate two
messages 5156 5158 you do not need 5158
for any usefulness
process command process execution and
process terminations 468 4689 those top
four right there you do not need
termination because you just want to
know when something executes those top
four right there will equal more than
all the other logs combined
i can get my lovely license for my
personal lab stuff and all my research
is a one gig per day
um if i turn on all the stuff that's in
my windows logging sheet very similar to
what they're talking about which is
everything windows firewall process
execution sysmon fully fully loaded with
uh module executions and all that stuff
um i can easily fill in a day one
workstation one gig but if i filter and
you can actually get that off my website
i have an nx lav com file to give you an
idea how to filter stuff i can easily
get 10 clients 10 times the amount of
clients into that one gig per day
license and logly for example
it is very noisy but you can also then
taper it off over time saying well keep
it's 30 days and then i'll age it out
um but yeah it's it's huge but the value
is ginormous
and i would say you know something you
can do is again and we've said this in
other presentations don't let perfect be
the enemy of good start small if you
need to if you do nothing more than just
have
your agent that's able to collect logs
and able to be
tweaked when you need to to increase
what logs it's bringing in so if there
is some sort of an incident you can go
back and turn and ramp that up
but you know start with just what you
need i mean if you looked at the nsa
guide and all you did was enable
collection of one event type
ntlm lateral movement with a non-domain
account to show passing the hashtag as
things start there
it's better than nothing
and then from there you can just start
ramping it up and see where you get
comfortable on it at that point so
another great trick is creator know you
that has all this turned on
okay
and then you can drag your workstations
you want to investigate into that who
use added so that your your log will
spike up so i do this for a lot for
windows firewall because it's so noisy
that if i'm investigating somebody i
need these 12 clients added to this ou
and now that's automatically turned on
and then i can turn it off if i'm not
doing anything there's no other
indicator that i'm getting from the
lower level
loud logs you can totally control that
from gpo to apply stuff on and take
something
um that was but anyway the extent was uh
create a special lu that turns all this
stuff on drag systems into it
as you're investigating so you can bring
the logs up and then when you're done
investigating bring it back down and
then log for the short course stuff like
a new service you see five systems with
a new service for example okay i'm gonna
drag those five into the bucket that
turns all this stuff on collect it short
period to do your investigation then
pull them back out and you can get all
the nice data
come to a conclusion and then pull them
back out so ou's with just the
workstations you need are awesome any
other questions
yes sir
do you have any problems
so your dns example of getting rid of
specific ports i feel like my security
team would have the field they would be
disabling valid traffic versus if i have
a limitation in my license to just
collect that on a syslog server and just
knock
so the question is basically do we ever
have issues with our security team being
angry of us turning off certain logs in
order to try and filter up at the source
rather than trying to collect them all
and then process them um so you know one
of the fortunate things that we have is
you're actually looking at the entire
security team for our organization right
now
so
we arm wrestle sometimes if we need to
but we don't have too much internal
conflict or strife on that
but
you know in organizations where there's
that you know one thing that you might
consider is uh and something that even
our se from our sim vendor recommended
was you can always have a separate log
collector that does the filtering that
is capturing everything that isn't the
sim and you know it's just being a
syslog destination where you're keeping
it all but you're then doing that
filtering there and push that into the
sim where the ones that you care about
are going to be correlated and dealt
with that's one way to approach it
it's really one of those things where if
you've got a tricky organization you've
just got to you know
tell them well if you want to have all
these logs give us some of your budget
and we'd be happy to fill it in this is
cheap right so yeah
that's great
oh yeah we actually got another chip
we got one other question i would say
that uh if the item
on the security team usually i'm the one
pushing for more lobby and the ops team
is pushing back because they're looking
at um
uptime and response time of what they're
mastering their monitors so that becomes
the uh trade off in the
negotiation point between security and
ops not necessarily between security um
and so we end up having to figure out
what's the best bang for the buck and
how to alternatively collect the data we
need if
yeah i mean all of these i mean all of
this what it really comes down to is the
very one of the very first things that
we started saying is think about it as
an overall design architecture from the
get-go and you know one of those things
where they they talk about an ounce of
prevention is worth a pound of cure i
mean if you're thinking of it up front
of and having these discussions with
everyone as you're getting to roll this
out that can save you a lot of pain and
a lot of the these heartaches and
arguments internal strife after the fact
so other other questions or over here
i can say no i don't
so sorry
sir
the question is any experience with
deploying windows powershell logging you
said
from the endpoints and i think that's
one of the the newer features that are
you talking about the new features that
are coming out with the actual
powershell logging we actually haven't
gone that direction yet it's something
that we're interested in the future but
for now we're really just digging into
sysmond for that because sysmon is going
to give us the full powershell as it got
executed uh while we wouldn't
necessarily get get the logging if it's
inside of a script uh we get at least
the notification that the script went if
you if you took carlos perez's class he
talks about the logging specifically but
it's either
i think he compares sysmon logging with
powershelf initially until you start
talking about capturing uh transcripts
so if you want that level you definitely
want to turn it on but power cismod will
give you enough
unless you have a lot of storage again
i mean one of the things that um it's no
secret we love white listing and so we
are doing that and so for us it's not as
much of a concern that we wouldn't get
the full script uh as it was being
transpired or whatever because
that script's not going to execute and
it's going to be blocked
by the white listing level so it's more
that we have to worry about if they did
if they were as an admin running a power
shell um i do have extreme experience
i'm releasing a windows powershell
logging gg for this your main focus is
going to be there's two logs there's a
windows powershell log under the
security log area basic logs and then
under microsoft windows
there it i have a pretty loud voice but
i bet they're recording it sorry um and
then under the microsoft windows there's
another powershell log so if you want to
know about the subject a research what
ben 10 is doing uh ben 10 actually b be
in to ian
he's a powershell guru and he actually
slowed down
my release of the powershell logging so
a you're looking for event ids 501 to
execute you cannot get that unless you
create a default profile in that
enabling the two variables you need so
every session and powershell triggers
and then you'll get the command line
logging
most a matter of fact the
the laughing thing is you know that
example they gave you the menu with 10.
exe that that
malware in my workshop it was 9.exe so
they had the next version in their prezo
that launched a powershell backdoor to
ukraine in the case of my particular
sample that i was evaluating lab
in order to capture that you must have a
default profile but this particular
malware actually executed the execution
policy bypass no profile so no logging
occurred but the fact that i got that as
an alert
is going to tell me i won't get
powershell logging so i have to use
something else or just re-image the box
but you're looking at having to do those
two variables you're having a look in
the the windows powershell for a 500 or
501 you won't see those unless you do
those variables and then the windows
powershell log has some vents in the
4000 series but they're more like a
transcript dump so you'll have to parse
those out they're going to be
excessively long and cut off in some of
the sim solutions and that you can
detect the powershell executions that
were not executed with powershell.exe
and yes thank you microsoft there's a
way to launch powershell without using
powershell x exe um so watch out for
that if you want but yes there is
there's some info coming
and you know just some one thing i would
add just you hear powershell powershell
powershell powershell if you aren't up
on powershell start reading up on it but
also something else that i think is very
important
powershell should not be talking to the
internet for most of your endpoints ever
ever ever
if you go back to our schmukon
presentation we put up a slide there we
showed an example stack two firewall
rules if you need powershell to have
network access internally one that says
allow powershell internally one that
says block powershell all
and that cuts it off right there so
yeah it was fun with our last pen test
they were complaining about how uh
they couldn't do something and and he
was talking about it it's gonna be
difficult for me to come back and do
something like i'll do it i can actually
run powershell so
fun when you restrict it just to
yourselves so a lot of these ideas are
from pen testers so pinterest come in
they come in and they
they beat us up for a little bit and
we're like all right we're going to
build these rules and then they come
back again next year like oh you're
stopping this stuff
it's like yeah you have to take it a
step up and they do and then we're like
alright build rules for that so most of
this stuff comes from
pen testers kind of coming in and doing
their red teaming in our environment
any other questions
well thank you everyone for attending
hope you enjoyed the talk and feel free
to reach us out to us in the future