as it says my name is Jackie Rosenberg
I'm from draper which which is a
non-profit independent lab in kendall
square cambridge it's been there for it
was originally part of MIT and 40 years
ago it's spun out and became completely
independent it's about a fifteen hundred
person lab does everything from the
inertial guidance system for the Trident
missiles to making things really small
we've got bullied microscope microscopic
devices we've got little cameras little
very small celestial navigation that
will allow you to navigate when GPS has
been denied and we have a pretty
significant cyber security group and we
have the network trying to meet trying
to get me to connect to the and we have
this cyber security group that that I
lead right now and what what I wanted to
talk to you about was the inherent
vulnerability in the processes that we
use and as the previous speaker was
pointing out sometimes we we may / blow
some of the threats however I've been to
a number of top secret briefings that
talk about exactly who and what is
attacking the electric grid and so it's
it's pretty scary what that at least
what the nation states are doing and and
if we just continue with the current
approach to dealing with things they'll
they'll be able to have their way the
fact is that the processes that we use
in all devices whether it's your phone
or your laptop or a server are all
highly excuse me highly vulnerable
and the reason this has has occurred is
because the architecture for these
processors which is called the stored
memory architecture was invented by von
Neumann in 1945 and has been the same
architecture basically since then so
during most of that time especially in
the early days before it was even
transistors they were vacuum tubes and
they were very expensive and then you
know you can see in 1970 when Intel's
basically their first microprocessor
came out it had 2,000 transistors the
most recent quad core has 2.6 billion
transistors so that's Moore's law
operating as it as it has nice and
steady doubling the number of
transistors every 18 months all that
time but what's changed of course is
that back in the early days the concept
of somebody attacking your computer was
was laughable it was impossible and and
now it's not funny at all so you know
the Moore's law and the cheap processors
led to the internet led to mobile
devices the iPhone 5s is the st. is is a
thousand times more powerful than the
1975 Cray one supercomputer that cost
one-and-a-half million dollars so people
have a lot of power in their hand and
and they're connected to everyone and
now you can reach around the world and
you can you can try to take advantage of
someone also of course computers
increasingly protect valuable things and
another problem is is that software has
grown to be extremely large and complex
the e-class Mercedes has a hundred
million lines of code in it so what do
we do well so most of the time what we
do is we build a perimeter we patch
every week or every two weeks and then
we pray
and it's not working very well there's a
lot of people have lost their identity
have lost their credit cards have or
have been ransoms just it's it's it's
not a very good approach and here's a
chart that ends with e class mercedes
which is that what i mentioned 100
million lines of code windows seven is
about 40 million lines of code even MS
office is about almost 30 million and
but meanwhile we've studied what they
what they tend to use in terms of of
malware and it's lots of little little
programs even Stuxnet was which was very
sophisticated was made up of a lot of
small pieces that are averaging about
125 lines of code so this is a number
that you know I got this two days ago
and it may have gone up a little bit
since then it's the total number of
unique vulnerabilities that the miter
and NIST track so across all the world's
software that you know that that has
where vulnerabilities have been found
this is the number of of unique
different and different ones which is
still a really large number for someone
to start you know going through that
list and trying to use to exploit
against you know the billions and
billions of lines of code out there so I
this is of course obvious but it's still
worth worth saying out loud in that when
you're not talking about authentication
attacks or software or social
engineering attacks and and maybe the
rare really sophisticated side-channel
attacks that can you know watch the
electromagnetic emanations from your
devices
but all the rest of these are because
there's a bug in the software and and
and they're able to use that as a vector
of attack to to get in so people like
Steve McConnell who studied this a lot
wrote wrote a book group several books
about writing secure code and and and
just software engineering practices in
general has found that on that across
all types of applications that have been
deployed so we don't mean you know in
the lab that have been deployed no
matter what the programming language
consistently are about 15 between 15 and
50 bugs per thousand lines of code and
about ten percent of those are
potentially can be turned into attacks
cyber vulnerabilities so the Mercedes
has by this give them give them credit
for the low number one point five
million bugs and about a hundred and
fifty thousand vulnerabilities and we we
know of some of the vulnerabilities
there's an application you can you can
research and get that on your laptop
that has a Bluetooth and Wi-Fi can
driving along the road can get into the
air wireless air pressure sensor the
architecture of those cars which one
single bus that communicates all
information to anyone on the bus that's
interested in it can actually construct
a malicious packet to the engine control
unit and floor the accelerator and as as
the chart showed that the battle is
asymmetric we're building bigger and
bigger systems and even when we start
patching it turns out now that one of
the most frequent ways in which an
enterprise's attack is through their
intrusion detection systems because
they're about 10 million lines of code
and have bugs in it and almost always
need to have privileged access to the
rest of the system so
why haven't we if we've got all these
billions of transistors why haven't we
as an industry why is the computer
industry really attack this problem with
a vengeance and there I think a number
of reasons for it one is is that the
when you have an install base of
millions and millions of applications on
billions of devices you're not going to
take radical make radical changes you're
going to work in an incremental fashion
and so they're not going to they're not
going to you know break things so why is
everything so vulnerable well we have a
lot of software that's actually not that
well understood we were asked to take a
look at the a major weapon system for
the Navy and we went in there with with
a what we thought was a reasonable
question which is whoa what do you think
your cyber vulnerabilities are and they
said you don't understand it's not a
reasonable question we don't even
understand how it works can you help us
understand how it works and I probed a
little further why is that well it was
originally written in jovial how many of
you have written a jovial okay so then
when when the when man's last great
programming language called ADA came out
they they translated jovial to Ada and
then about two weeks later when everyone
realized ADA wasn't that they translated
it again to see which is where it is now
with the people that wrote the original
jovial code it's not just that they
don't work for the contractors anymore
they actually aren't alive anymore so
they have they have this problem
increasingly we have been as computer
scientists we have been making great
strides in our ability to do formal
verification of systems but not systems
that are really complicated that's still
way beyond the reach of doing the formal
methods you know proving
some property that you want to to
validate in your software hardware as
well so we still tend to write pretty
monolithic software so and the operating
systems are extremely guilty of this so
if you can compromise get you know
access as root or super user you pretty
much can take over the entire machine
whereas we've known for a long time if
you if you wrote critical services as a
set of independent entities that only
had what's called least privileged
access to what they need then you
compartmentalize the system and all hope
is not lost if somebody compromises one
of those services we also if you were to
try to come up with abstractions for
most of the hardware we have it's it's
it's it's very difficult to do so and
and people aren't willing to pay the
performance costs to create those kinds
of effective isolations in the hardware
either and then where this is you know
the the the key time when the computer
industry was just getting started and
and and really all that mattered was
smaller cheaper faster and in getting
climbing up that Moore's Law curve
quickly so this is what that
architecture you know looks like and
those of us that have been you know
working in this this area for a long
time call that single undifferentiated
memory raw seething bits because the
processor has absolutely no idea what
anything is it's just told go execute at
this address and it says okay that must
be an instruction it treats it as an
instruction and and starts executing so
if somebody finds a buffer overflow
vulnerability and can use that to
download a bunch of their code
instructions for this processor that
they're targeting there's a really good
chance they're going to be able to fig
also figure out a way to get the
processor by changing the return address
from you know the function that's on the
stack to the beginning of their code and
now the the processor has no ability to
help you stop that because it doesn't
know what's a pointer what's a buffer
what's an instruction what's just you
know data for you know a sequel query
and so this is you know part of the the
problem so what what we set out to do
this was a initially a project that
DARPA created as a result of reaction to
Stuxnet so yes it's true that Stuxnet
was a cooperative effort between one
really little company on the
Mediterranean and one dice a company I
meant country and a really big company
country in North America and it still
scared the people at the Pentagon
because they realized that we'd let the
cat out of the bag that we were we were
going to teach people how to do attacks
as sophisticated as Stuxnet and
following Stuxnet of course was Dooku
and Flame and Red October and those were
not all perpetrated by the same people
as Stuxnet yet they have the similar
kinds of look and feel to them so we
with this program that DARPA created in
2010 which was called crash they ended
up spending a hundred million dollars on
this research program and crash stands
for clean slate redesign of adaptive
secure house
so start over and and don't be tied to
the architectures of the past and is it
possible to make something that would be
immune to the the type of attack that
Stuxnet represents so take advantage of
inexpensive hardware follow well-known
security principles like the ones I just
mentioned least privileged
compartmentalization and use a lot of
formal verification because you don't
want to have to test this kind of thing
and come up with you know elaborate
manual tests to try to because you're
never going to get coverage you're going
to you're going to miss too much and so
the idea was okay we're going to use
these cheap transistors and we're going
to essentially the key here is can the
processor and the application /
programmer cooperate such that things
that you meant to have it do and meant
not to have it do are in fact the
processor is informed about that and can
avoid these these these kinds of issues
so this alone is not a new idea tagged
memory architectures are not a new idea
the list machine is a tag memory
architecture but mostly for other
reasons like garbage collection there
was a Burroughs machine that was a tag
memory architecture but no one has
really kind of taken the tag memory
architecture to its sort of natural it
to the extension where it can really
collaborate with the processor in terms
of security so an example is that so you
have a word in memory and associated
with it is another word so yeah it looks
like we've just doubled the use of the
memory but transitions are cheap and
besides we can optimize that a little
bit so the the metadata has things in it
like
I'm an instruction and there's also a
rule that says anything that comes in
over the network is always data and you
cannot change those things they the
compiler is a trusted piece of software
running on this machine it can specify
what's an instruction and that's that's
it also something is is is established
as a pointer that is the you know the
first address of a buffer and what the
metadata has is this is the beginning of
a buffer and the buffer is this long so
with this we can start to control
provenance who owns certain things and
and fine-grained access control so with
this we can actually implement on the
military side multi-level security this
is top secret this a secret this is
public in in the rest of the world you
know this is personally identifiable
information and it will never be any
anything lower than that we can actually
have other types of other types
specified with this instructions and
also we can prevent what's you know now
one of them the more dangerous types of
attacks that the sophisticated folks are
using is called return oriented
programming attacks and we can also this
can prevent that from happening so we we
created a an entity that's that's modif
the hardware's modified first with the
with the metadata and then with
something that's called a pump which is
a programmable unit for metadata
processing so the standard very you know
simple kind of normal processor
execution flow is on the left and you
know there's the program counter and
there's where instructions are stored so
that it can fetch the next instruction
and there's where the registers are
you know the registers that are storing
index variables and things like that
then you've got the ALU which is doing
the add subtract multiply divide jump
and you've got memory and and you've got
results and so the little green on the
left side of each of those of those
things including the PC including all
the registers in the memory is the
metadata tag and in parallel with the
ALU is something that is looking at the
tags and making a decision as to is this
operation that the ALU is doing the same
time as me valid should it be allowed so
the the idea number two is that what the
metadata in general point is is is a
pointer to memory so that we can have
arbitrary security policies not just I'm
an instruction and I'm data so so you
know here's a list of the kinds of
things kinds of policies that we can
create that the the pump mechanism can
enforce so as as the ALU is processing
the pump gets the metadata from the tags
of the appropriate operands and the pc
and and it if necessary it goes off and
gets the policy that is pointed to in
memory now in practice it rarely does
that because we create a pretty large
cache that avoid that that rarely misses
so that as the pump is looking to see is
is this is this a valid operation it's
able to get the answer by just looking
at the cash and I'll show you the
results of this in a minute the kinds of
things you can do in these micro
policies which is what we call them is
large and in fact these are security
policies but we can also
we have safety policies are sort of the
first cousin of security policies so for
example suppose that I have a that my
processor is in a an insulin pump and I
would like to create a safety property
that i would add to this list that says
even if the programmer made a mistake
and we get to this point in the program
where we're about to tell the pump to
inject some insulin if that means we
will have injected more than X
milligrams in the last 24 hours alert
alert the user alert everybody you can
and shut down because it would be better
to let the patient go into manual mode
then to kill them but that that's you
know and the same thing is true by the
way with all this autonomous this and
autonomous that we're going to have cars
that drive and drones that deliver
packages and it's all going to be
wonderful an autonomous and they'll
they'll never be any bugs and that
software you might want some safety
properties there so this is the it's a
slightly simplified diagram but what we
did was we took a conventional processor
and we got got into the guts of it and
modified the instruction processing
pipeline and added the the stage down at
the at the end near the end called the
pump so it's it's a it's not a very big
change to an existing processor the
processor that we're doing this to right
now we we did an initial test in
simulation a year ago on the dec alpha
processor so when we first started with
the the whole you know big crash program
i mentioned we took the clean slate part
of that really seriously and we invented
a new instruction set architecture and a
new operating system and everything just
so that we could prove that this was
possible
but that was research now what we're
what we're doing now is we'd like to
bring this out as a real processor that
could be used in embedded systems and
and why do I qualify and say embedded
systems because embedded systems tend to
have a fairly small software stack
compared to this ginormous software
stack that you have to deal with on
servers not to mention the huge
operating systems so to get started and
to and to start attacking the problem at
some pretty meaningful places were
focused on embedded systems so with that
processor on the on the Alpha we were
able to enforce four things
simultaneously that was all we really
wanted to prove memory safety which
means buffer overflow is actually
impossible to have happen control flow
integrity which prevents changing the
that where the processor is going to
jump to or you know where a return
address actually returns to taint
tracking which is am I about to release
top-secret information down a channel
that's public and type separation which
is it basically is helping what we try
to have our programming languages do but
sometimes they don't really do we ended
up having a performance penalty of about
ten percent and a modest energy overhead
and at least for this experiment it was
two times the area that we used we used
exactly twice as much memory but we
didn't do any optimizations so the other
cool thing about this is that we're not
we're not edging silicon to specifically
for any policy these are all policies
that are it's like micro coating and so
if we find that you know there's a new
attack that that is able to you know
successfully get in into this machine we
can we can deploy new policies
so there's the there's the you know
basic diagram of how this works so like
we said there's metadata bits attached
to the word the pumps going to resolve
them we we set it set it up so that the
programmer doesn't have to worry about
that the number of bits that there that
is in the metadata because it's
basically a pointer to an arbitrary
policy that they write and the the logic
that's being performed by the pump once
the rules are written is is a black box
to them they don't need to worry about
that so they can just think of the
metadata as a pointer so here's how it
basically this is the abstract function
of the pump so the opcode which might be
you know ad ad long or or jump and then
the following five things are the tags
not that not the pc itself but the tag
on the pc the tag on the instruction on
the opcode one opcode to and if there's
any memory reference and then all it
comes out on the out on the on the
backside is first of all is this
instruction going to be allowed to
happen what's the new tag on the pc and
if there is one what's the what's the
tag on the resulting operand so i will
show a couple of examples of this so
here's how we do this in for a buffer
overflow what we what we do is we say
when a pointer is being created like by
by the compiler when it's creating the
stack or by Malik when you call mallet
for storage on the heap there's a unique
color that's that's assigned to that
pointer and then to every one of the the
metadata bits for those words in
in memory so now you've got this region
of memory that's you know so to speak is
yellow and this is the policy then on a
load instruction which is that it's it
says an r1 is where the pointer to the
buffer is being referenced from and what
it's saying is this is allowed because
that first location in the result is
whether it's allowed or not and the
answer is yes if the memory location
that you're referencing is the same
color as the pointer and if you go one
one word past the end of the yellow
buffer and you're in the purple this
this will cause a segmentation fault and
then your fault handling will have to
deal with it but it will not allow that
that right to occur so if you if you
take out all social engineering password
guessing attacks which you know we would
just like to see people do better at
those seventy percent of the remaining
attacks are memory misuse which would be
caught by that previous now remember you
know if you've you've got a lot of code
that you've written you've got a lot of
buffers that you've used you've gone
through carefully and you've tried to
make sure that you've done the right
thing with the buffers but it's like a
window a house that has a hundred
windows and you you lock 99 of them so
so you'll catch the 99 and the processor
even when you've done a really good job
you might miss one the processor won't
even let that last one go through and
that's what we mean by the the code and
working with the processor to enforce
this here's another one which which
basically says at the time of that a
call occurs get the list of possible
targets that can that it is legal to
jump to when the call is is returning
and so so then which the compiler knows
of course so the the pc is constantly
being tagged with where where am i where
am i right now before i execute the next
instruction and that it's got a list of
the legal caller tags so now when the
instruction is is a is not a call
instruction it's able to say am i am i
jumping to a place that's legal for the
function that i'm currently in and that
stops a return oriented programming
attack and in general control flow
integrity and i'm just going to show one
more taint tracking is also used to
declare a rule that says no data that is
considered confidential or personally
identifiable can ever leave the machine
unless it's less it's encrypted so you
you you taint the pc such that that rule
is activated and and then at the moment
that it's about to be written to
register at a device driver it's it's
checked and it says i'm about to write
something that's not encrypted that's a
credit card number and it would
basically kick that back and this allows
you to also say that everything coming
in that's considered personally
identifiable or our or confidential is
also encrypted so it's not that useful
if there's only one security policy at a
time and so the tag can point to
essentially a list of as many as you
want and it I normally don't put up
things and say oh this is an eye chart I
wanted you to just look along the bottom
row so the the labels are things like
type information memory safety control
flow taint tracking and in all these
cases the the runtime overhead was eight
between eight and thirteen percent
there's one outlier which is because we
we really tried to do taint taint
tracking at two finer grained level and
it was it was / function and and we had
you know for the for the spec benchmark
that we used it ended up just exploding
and so we'd have to we have to back off
from that level of granularity but
that's we were very pleased with this
runtime even though we were tracking for
policy simultaneously all the way along
so I mentioned formal methods so these
each individual policy is simple enough
that we're able to build proofs in the
programming language or the proof
language it's if you're not familiar
with it the French are the leaders in
formal methods and there they created
this language caulk and it means rooster
and it's the symbol of France so it and
it is by far the best well they all say
it's the best best proof language that
that the formal methods community is
using so they were able to apply this to
information flow control which is which
is the the data equivalent of control
flow that is protecting against
exfiltration of data as my secret data
leaked out then there they were able to
verify that the implementation of it was
correct down to the hardware level we're
applying some random testing as well to
verify all this
and you know we're going to continue
really really hard on the the formal
methods on these policies we've done a
little bit of optimization so far and
we've reduced the overhead remember I
said at the beginning the area was
double and we've gotten that down to
only be essentially ten percent higher
that there's a couple of outliers the
bottom names are from the spec benchmark
that we were using and in in general we
got you know really dramatic
improvements and in a few cases that's
run time on the top and that's energy
over here and area is is way down from
two hundred percent so energy overhead
as I quoted earlier sixty percent
runtime overhead actually even as low as
seven percent we tend to quote ten
percent just to be safe so so here's
where Draper came in we started in this
project at Draper in July we took
basically it was my team that was doing
this under under DARPA and now we've
moved the team to Draper Draper's very
committed to to investing this
themselves and and then providing this
to both government and commercial
entities that have embedded systems and
so the processor that we decided to go
with is the risk five it's open source
it's been now it's been adopted by
Google and the the Sun division of
Oracle which it pains me to say but the
they are looking for a replacement for
the spark and it looks like it's going
to be the risk five we hear rumors that
a lot of other people are are very
excited about this it's been developed
in development for almost 15 years so
it's not it's not new and it is driven
by the
guy at Berkeley who is essentially the
father of the whole risk concept so
because because risk 5 exists with a
linux that works for it and a great tool
chain it means we can get something up
and running fast and in fact we started
in July and we'll have a fully working
system in February we we're doing all
we're doing a full suite of the of the
policies and we're we're developing
actually a language for specifying
policies and checking them we will
modify the compiler the compiler has to
be modified because it has to generate
some of these tags will have to run
through all of Linux even though Linux
works on the risk 5 Linux has places in
it where it actually writes past the end
of a buffer it gets away with it because
nobody else needed that word or words
past the end of the buffer but as soon
as you try to run that on this processor
which by the way as I had it on a
previous slide we called over which is
short for do-over and these are the
other things that that we have to to
build in this time frame and we're going
to try to you know go further than just
making sure Linux runs but actually
start separating it out into its
components and it's so the other thing
that that we're trying to do is to
create a community we're calling it a
hive a community of entities companies
government agencies universities that
want to work together to make systems
that are inherently secure will we're
hoping to have them influence what the
future direction of this should be share
with each other what they're learning
maybe build this chip into their bedded
systems
and get a lot of you know a lot of
interaction with my team as well we have
some very large companies and
universities involved so far it's
looking to be a pretty nice community of
people really anxious to change the game
on the the attackers so I just want to
you know summarize we know our processes
are really insecure and the architecture
that we've been using for a long time is
actually complicit in that but now with
so many transistors we can actually take
advantage of them and use some of them
for security and when people worry about
oh you know can i really afford ten
percent performance overhead you have to
put that into context of so what did
that cost target and and so we've got
you know we're one of a long line of
people that have figured out how to use
metadata tags on hardware we just think
we're going further than anyone else has
with it and that includes safety and the
way we're developing this it's with a
set of tools for it it's going to be
like developing software micro coded
software for specifically for security
but with the the same performance as if
it were in hardware so can I answer any
questions yeah
simply try
so
so the metadata is actually not
addressable by any software or any
hardware except the the pump itself so
once so it's it's it's not possible to
come in from the outside and and address
it and we know that kind of mechanism
works you know we know we know page
tables work we know you know those those
kinds of mechanisms work so that's
completely opaque you won't see that
that you won't even see those addresses
you will only see the addresses for the
payload words like a norm like a normal
machine now I'm not going to stand up
here and say nothing bad will ever
happen we're just we're trying to take a
giant leap and then we think we have a
mechanism where if somebody figures out
something that we didn't think of that
we can we can adapt to it yeah
I have some
if I wanted
I
that's absolutely right so existing
applications on these embedded devices
will will port through a simple a simple
recompile and run a series of tests to
make sure that they don't you know do
any any of these things that the
processor wouldn't you know allow then
if you want to go further and I'm just
restating what you said but it's exactly
right if you wanted to go further and
declare something as you know PII you
know this is a social security number we
we do have to add a couple of you know
extensions to to see to allow you to
specify that and for that to get you
know all the way pushed all the way down
into the metadata tag so that the
processor knows that
so we're in a machine like this if if if
somebody gets physical access to it then
pretty much all hope is lost and so what
we what we and then but you say well
wait in an embedded world physical
access can't prevention of physical
access can't be guaranteed so one of the
great technologies that Draper is the
lead in the world at is anti-tamper
technology we have to be good at it
because it has to be on all of the the
military stuff that we we create and we
now provide that to other companies so
when you know when a fighter jet is sold
to even an ally you know Egypt we
everything in it has anti-tamper on it
so we will make sure that our stuff has
that on it so yeah physical access is
really important we're even worried
about some of these side-channel attacks
and we're we've got one of the people in
this so-called hive who's looking at
what are the things you could do ahead
of time to you know prevent these side
channels side-channel attacks side
channel attack for example can from two
feet away you can actually see the power
fluctuations in a standard processor
enough so that you can actually spot
when it's running aes encryption if you
run it for about 15 million times you
can actually extract the key so we want
to have make sure there's a
countermeasure to that as well
yeah so there are in the micro policies
are secured by being put into an
encrypted store which which you know we
have to manage the key for and you do
have to have physical access there is no
updating of the micro policies over the
air because that would just be too
dangerous so if you're if you're going
to download a new micro policy it's got
to be code signed and then it's and it's
you know stored yeah so yeah where we
are we are we do have a TPM on board the
the chip so that we can manage the key
encryption and everything it's uh it's
it's not not easily accessible but it
has to be accessible through a very you
know one path only it's similar to the
fingerprint reader on the iPhone they
did a very good job on it there's almost
no code at all between the hardware
detection of the fingerprint and it
getting into you know the application
that's asked is this who they say they
are so a similar kind of short path yeah
I
right right
so that you know that's exactly the kind
of thing that we would like to have
people working on with us in this little
hive and just you know just looking a
few years out because so before I did
any of this defense you know or lab work
I was a serial entrepreneur started
several security companies and and
whatnot so I'm treating this like a
start-up you don't try to boil the ocean
day one right so you you pick a niche
and you try to get really good at it and
I think it'll take us about three years
to will have six significant customers
by then I project and and then I think
we'll be ready for what's the next step
now Draper never wants to become a chip
company it's not ever going to do that
but Draper could do what arm does you
know arm licenses armed makes nothing
and they make a 1.25 billion dollars a
year just writing contracts and
collecting checks for royalties so we
could license it we could sell it to a
bigger chip company and a lot of the
security things that you're you know
concerned about being applied here you
know we could start working on those
early or as it starts to you know take
off where we joined the risk five
foundation so we're the third member i'm
very pleased you know Google's first
Oracle second Draper third sort of a but
that'll but but the reason I mentioned
that is that they're very the whole
foundation is very interested in
standards applied to the risk five
security in particular and and in sort
of this ecosystem that could grow up
around and you know an open-source
instruction set architecture and I
should mention that there's a little bit
of secret sauce that will will keep back
but we're going to put everything else
we do back into open source
yeah so I can you know I can give my
card to anybody that wants it and I can
send you those I'm on any more time
drive time okay well we started early so
we'll finish early you have a question
so I don't know the answer to where AMD
is but Intel is coming out with another
set of small additional set of
instructions called mm x I think or is
it MPX and they are designed to but you
it's going to take a while because they
have to be rolled into the operating
system the the programming languages etc
but the idea of them is just to stop the
buffer overflow attacks so I think
you'll see those in the next they're
probably invisibly in the current chips
but you can't access them because
they're not fully debugged yet so you'll
probably see them in the next generation
of Intel chips but you probably won't
yet see support in all the rest of the
tools so it'll probably take another i
would say 35 years before those come out
and and that's you know one piece so
they're they're doing an incremental
approach the problem i have is that the
intel chip you know there nothing's been
thrown away since the you know 8080 in
1986 and so it's it's extremely complex
you you can't prove anything about it
whereas when you go back to you know a
risc processor which is clean especially
this one because it's it's relatively
new compared to you know arms an older
risk design that's had a lot added to it
nips of course has been around a long
time so it's it's it's kind of a nice
place to start all this
you could you couldn't do that you know
you have it enforced by the CPU yeah is
there a question over here um so you've
mentioned how much recent rages across a
target but if you go out and look at
google finance today targets enjoying a
stock price somewhere near a five-year
high right now so my question is are
there enough economic drivers in place
to you know drive the adoption of a chip
that might cost a little bit more you
know when investors don't penalize
companies for insecurity it's a very
good question and I fear that as a
country we tend to wait until there's a
huge disaster to react which is another
really good reason for us to focus on it
the embedded systems market you know we
have a limited amount of bandwidth so
I'm going to be very selective in the
and the first two whose hair is most on
fire about security are going to get our
attention you know as the first two
customers one of those seems to be this
glucose monitor because they want to
start surgically implanting glucose
monitors pricking the skin not good and
the the fact that you know if you if you
only have the patient monitor their
blood glucose level every so often it's
not continuously monitoring and so that
you know where as in those of us that
that you know generate insulin the
old-fashioned way you know we follow the
curve of you know the eating and the
sugars and etc and it's it's unhealthy
for them that they don't so they want to
embed these things so their hair is on
fire because they know that one highly
publicized incident on their device and
no surgeon is going to be allowed by the
their patients to open them up and put
this inside it's not that there is a
terrorist attack it's that you know
somebody attacks it because they can and
then it gets publicized the other
another one that we're we're talking to
and I can't mention any of the military
ones but that is the company that little
company makes this device that monitors
the temperature of something that's
critical like a big huge tank that could
go boom or things that are refrigerators
or freezers that have FDA regulated
things in them and they then send that
information back over a cell phone too
it's encrypted as it goes to wherever
being monitored but the devices
themselves are running the old the
standard processors that are vulnerable
and this is a company that you know
they've they've got a hundred thousand
of these devices installed but they're
still not a big company and one incident
could destroy them so target survived
but but you know someone else might not
great thank you very much