alright good morning everybody we're
gonna do a quick welcome yeah it's
everybody awake mostly did anybody go to
the endgame party last night anyone
there's a few people who are those
people are struggling and now after
endgame had way too much fun last night
all right welcome to the third annual
besides DC we are the actober festive
besides what we build ourselves as a
quick show of hands who's been here
before Wow tons of people any returning
black badges in the house anyone anyone
I turn off that radio before I deaf and
everybody and who's new to be sighs is
this like your first besides wow wow
about half cool well welcome so just
some quick housekeeping items before we
start please silence all the things that
make noise I know you have a really cool
ringtone but everybody else doesn't need
to hear it respect speakers organizers
volunteers and everybody else adhere to
our principles if you want to see those
there in the program manager don't be a
jerk as the main rule and the main thing
is participate there's tons of things to
do today there's lockpick village
there's Internet of Things village
there's plenty of great talks lined up I
mentioned lockpick wireless wireless CT
of everything else so definitely take a
chance to take a look around especially
if you're new tribe try checking out a
bunch of different things all right
who's who orange badges are organizers
that's myself Bob Weiss my my other
co-director any of our other people
Duran our finance director volunteers
yellow badges these are people who are
volunteering to help us put this
together direct you where you need to go
and do everything like that speakers
yeah volunteers will be wearing the rust
colored shirts speakers they were
wearing the white badges check them out
feel free to ask them questions in the
hallway I'm sure they'd love to talk to
you green is our sponsors we cannot put
this event on and have such a great
event without our sponsors so check them
out go to their tables say hi to them
security they're wearing the red shirts
obey them blue attendees that's you guys
thank you very much for coming out ok
this is our third year and 2012 mark
bolts and bill
sure email Jack Daniel and said hey why
isn't there besides in DC and he's like
congratulations you guys are putting it
on so three years later here we are this
is the first year with a crib kids con
that's upstairs you'll see them walking
around with their super awesome flashing
badges that I'm jealous ax we sold more
tickets in about the same time as last
year this is the second largest besides
globally only second to Las Vegas the
schedule is available on conf you I'll
put that link up a little bit so a quick
tour of it Internet of Things village
that's in London one that's basically
straight this way over by the elevators
they ran in at Def Con they called us
and said hey we'd like to bring it to
besides DC so check it out it's Internet
of Things devices and probably something
so hopelessly broken router hacking as
well Loch sport village there in London
to that's down the hallway past the
elevators they'll be there all day today
and all day tomorrow let you play with
tools crack locks open things up please
do not take the locks they have some for
sale ask questions please also don't
practice on any of the locks in the
hotel the wire
Kahuna don't listen to that guy wireless
CTF that's upstairs on the second floor
in the junior ballroom that is open to
conference attendees so go check that
out there will be a CTF there and you
can also learn from those guys crib kids
that starts at ten ten a.m. 10 1030 is
the crib kids keynote that will be in
this room after we reset the rooms for
the two tracks so any attendees are
welcome to check that out as well the
kruky kids keynote is Alicia Kazakh wits
it's going to be very interesting from
the sound of it something outside of
what we usually do in the computer
security field but I think it's going to
be very interesting the crib kids cotton
I do definitely want to give a shout out
to Jenny making David they did a ton of
work on this and really I think knocked
it out of the park so it's going to be
super cool alright schedule just really
quick schedule is on conf you big thanks
to Darnell for setting that up for us so
it's conf you calm there's a link for be
sized DC that's optimized for your phone
so you can look at it by time by speaker
by track everything like that so and it
has all the descriptions of the talks
and the bios of the speakers in there so
you can look it up carry it with you
super handy it also has the most
up-to-date list we had three talk
changes that are listed in there they're
all on sunday so the program will be a
little bit behind conf you at
registration they also have the list of
the talks that have changed so we just
that tiny conf you is really great not
only for our con the four others if you
do others it's a you know can you look
at it oh good I'll get closer Mike front
so confu is really good not only for our
con but for other cons they handle Def
Con and some of the besides and a lot of
the other events so it's a graphical
mobile-friendly website you can look at
the schedule and sort of very easy to
pit on your phone so recommend that you
hit that and sa it's very useful is Dave
in the audience thank you dave davis
confu guy
alright so on the subject of thanks we
have to go through our sponsors again
these are these are all people who are
helping put this con on so in our engage
the audience sponsors various groups
adapted threat division sands and net
Wars there anyone do networks last night
I think I see a couple of networks
t-shirts so you guys have fun to Annette
words last night I think that turned out
really great so it sounds like that
might be something we're going to do in
future years so keep an eye out for that
in next year all right above and beyond
sponsors HP this is their third third
year with us cobalt strike this is our
third year and there are lanyard sponsor
this year so thanks to them aruba is
back again see CSC / tenacity is back
again this this is our third straight
year and our new sponsors valiant
solutions and endgame thank you to all
dis consulting they're also sponsoring
the party tonight so big thanks to them
fireeye returning this year Palo Alto
Networks returning this year fidelis
returning this year as well and booz
allen hamilton above and beyond more
above and beyond sponsors in Milton
security GDIT antietam tenable mitre
core supporter sponsors hacker warehouse
go to Garrett's table out there he has
cool stuff system 1 clear jobs net
threat connect evident io guide point
security other thanks these are other
companies are supporting us in other
ways a critical stack sophos for the
networking gear speaking of the network
there is a wireless network the SSID
says the password is in it that's the
conference network for you guys please
don't hack the conference network I fix
it they donated tools for the crypt kids
a village upstairs tool obviously tool
DC putting on the lockpick village for
us every year they're doing a great job
we really appreciate them coming back
the Iron Horse pub for hosting us
tonight the marriott for giving us the
space to have the Conn in no Sarge press
and independent security evaluate errs
were the organization's yes so I want
you guys to know you all haven't paid a
lot of money for your tickets right and
the reason we're able besides
organizations nationally internationally
and us write our
are able to keep that ticket price down
is because of these sponsors right
without the sponsors this event does not
happen most of the money for for putting
this event on comes from the sponsorship
so spit takes some time if you see
anyone with a green badge or you stop by
the booths thank them listen to them
stop by the boots understand what their
what their pitching or what they're
trying to promote and and again they are
what is putting on this conference so
again be wrecked recognize that thank
you guys alright so our worthy
organizations we do some fundraising
here through sales of things in the swag
shop which will be open later today and
the we do try to donate every year to
eff and both both eff and hackers for
charity so we want to give back to the
community to support things that are
important to us ok the important part
the party tonight the fest in hack Tober
it's at the Iron Horse taproom begin 730
again altis consulting corporation Thank
You Jacob Porter and altis consulting
corporation to for sponsoring the party
for this year there will be drink
tickets and we're featuring a list of
local beers so virginia maryland DC
delaware and finally the team this is
all the people who have been working for
the last year to put all this together
spending nights weekends everything else
so big thanks to everybody here on this
list if you see them if you see a
volunteer if she and organizer
definitely thank them for their efforts
so it's not it's not a minute not a
trivial thing to put this on and
obviously big thanks to Jack Daniel for
kicking us in the button making us do it
Alex you didn't put yourself on that
list I know I didn't put myself on that
right big thanks Alex Norman also all
right so with that I will let Bob Bob
introduce our keynote mr. G mark hearty
thanks a lot so I've known G mark for I
don't know at least eight or nine years
he is the founder and president of
national security Corp he is an
internationally recognized speaker and I
don't know what two years ago gee Marc
and I did a talk and he literally ran in
from what was the name of the medicine
the army 10-miler in the middle of the
talk he was like okay I'm here so so
thanks for the army 10-miler for moving
there their event so they had it last
week so he could be here today so a chew
mark party thanks
and we were good to see how much hacking
they did on my laptop while I was away
survey says daunted at all okay welcome
hello why she didn't do see nothin you
need more Starbucks do something like
that anyway SQ park rd pleasure to be
here i'm gonna make a really tough to
the camera guys they walk all over the
place i bets problem let me know and
we'll go full the pony boy go straighten
presider i want to talk about credit
card fraud who here is going to credit
cards yeah we got dubba cards got him
okay who you're never reaches your hand
when you're asked to raise your hand
that would be that Lisa okay there you
check out the financial system I want to
talk about the direction we're going if
you notice letting cards are different
this year when we good things thank you
there we going and here i am i'm so used
to work without a microphone they I kind
of got too many of these things at home
they mate they make great collectors
items so we'll have to back up for the
recording yes no listen you're lost
nothing we could start over yet anyway
think about it what's been going on with
all these credit card breaches we look
at things like at Target and Sally's at
home depot and of course there's more
coming but what are they all got in
common yeah Dave well they all got it
they all got whacked they got whack of
the pretty big way and what they're
going after we're finding after as
criminals are going after credit card
and debit card information it's really
kind of a little bit back to go back
Willie Sutton remember the bank robber
when they asked him why do you rob banks
his answer was because that's where the
body is well this is where the money is
now it's last year's verizon data breach
report but you know he could still
squeak a little bit out of it they said
hey you know it's a year the retailer
bridge now of course any year could
probably be the year the retailer breach
it's just the nature of things because
with so much information available for
compromise it's really really kind of
hard to say no if you're an attacker
particularly if you don't even have to
gain physical access to a system to get
all the goodies that come out of it and
so what we want to think about is what's
going on here card fraud it's a huge
industry 11 billion dollars in 2013 went
up to about 12 and change in 2014 and
still trying to get some final number
sixteen billion dollars when you throw
in the cost of all their credit card
remediation you're gonna watch your
credit history for like seriously
remember that OPM hack whether they can
where they come out after the OPI
anybody here yeah you're probably part
of that if you've got a dot every we're
headed clearance and they say we'll give
you a free credit monitoring for a year
like seriously you think the Chinese you
don't all that's like it steal your
credit cards dudes hello anyway credit
cards oh yes they do want your money
about sixteen billion dollars total well
the problem is is expensive banks and
generally eat about sixty-three percent
of that loss almost two-thirds of it the
rest goes to the merchant saying okay if
a merchant didn't actually get that
three digit cvv on the back or they
didn't swipe the card because oh I left
my card at home but I remember my number
or card-not-present think online all
those folks tend to pay for it well the
thing is what's missing for that
equation you how much do you get ripped
off I don't know because you might not
know either unless you're kind of
meticulous about checking your
statements I even got popped about ten
years ago and I missed it cuz I was on
the road like I always am and it's like
a ten-dollar charge I read a couple
years later these guys stole two million
cards they made one $10 charge on each
of the two million cards and that's it
they threw the rest they threw the
numbers away well that was actually
pretty smart business model because they
got away with it because ten dollars
it's not worth getting on the phone and
arguing with your bag for 45 minutes so
you'll let it go and it scales up pretty
well well the US has got a huge
disproportionate amount of volume on
this mostly because while we don't
really have those Chip and PIN cards at
all Europeans use cuz well we're
Americans were better or smarter maybe
well so what's happened is banks as
default of these neural network type
things the systems that are basically
mainframe applications that run just
like a giant firewall if then else if
then else if then else and you can screw
with those rule sets if you want and you
can do it legally so for example if you
want to see if your bank is using a
certain type of fraud prevention and
you're a getting ready to go buy
something at best buy because it's
coming up a shopping season here's what
you do take your credit card go to the
gas station authorize your gas but then
cancel it then drive down to best buy
and buy your stuff and see what happens
alright that one-two punch ought to kick
into windows firewall rules and your
card ought to either be hey was a
problem with or declined or whatever now
you haven't committed for
god it's your old cart but what you're
doing is like you're doing a good hacker
you're probing like a black boxes rule
sets and that's exactly what criminals
have done over the last few years they
probed out that entire rule set and
they've kind of figured it out and so
this chip and pin or chip and signatures
were doing the u.s. is not going to
solve this problem it just changes the
nature of the fraud because if you think
about it we're going to find out that it
really doesn't do a whole lot for things
like online or card-not-present so card
fraud it's complex it's not a bunch of
computers dueling it out it's not like
some Star Trek thing where you're okay
you have to report to the disintegration
chamber because your sector was bombed
no these are set up the static defenses
attackers attack next week or next month
whenever you push the updates we push
the updates and it's a constantly losing
battles by the way anybody sign up for
Apple pay how's that working for you
you're like smiling was it easy to
seriously was it easy or hard to set up
Apple pay for your bank relatively
anybody have like a super easy way just
provision your card and go anybody had
to go like show up at a bank or actually
do a phone call or do some other nation
yeah because when Apple pay started out
what happened is Apple they're brilliant
they did the crypto well they did the
near field communications well they did
the interface with all the switches they
didn't think very carefully about how do
we provision the card and figure it out
pretty quickly with a stolen credit card
number and just create an itunes account
you can now provision your iphone 6 with
a stolen card and now you got Apple pay
but Apple pay is card present so very
low fraud concern charges always go
through but where's the card it's either
in your sock drawer or somebody else's
doctor or it's stolen so some of the
banks that started doing Apple pay early
on to do the easy provisioning six
thousand percent increase in fraud
massive spike in front because what you
do you go ahead you steal one of these
things then you come back and you go to
the apple store you said hey you know I
got one of these iphones last yeah
yesterday I like them so much I want to
buy them for everybody in my company and
and I'm going to pay for it with Apple
pay in the cars going wow this is
wonderful apples changing the world but
of course it's all stolen so Apple is
really one of the biggest victims of
that and they don't want to admit that
I've gotten emails from Apple saying hey
I'm sorry was learning things about us
they say well you guys
more lawyers than I do so no I'm not
going to talk to you you know what you
did go fix it and like anything else
we're starting to see improvements but
usually early adopters catch the first
arrows so typical fraud prevention we're
looking for this anomalous user behavior
what I mean think about in the beginning
for those of us hey Kahuna with a gray
hair we remember back in the 70s or no
hair in your case but in any case yeah
we have to add all this stuff out the
that's nothing i like about b-sides you
don't have to be politically correct
even in Washington DC so what happened
was this if you remember the old days
you got your first credit card you went
down to the Merkin you buy something
they had a little onion skin booklet
like little eight point font so you had
to be younger than we are now to read it
and they listed literally every single
stolen credit card that week and then
the next week they'd issue a new book
it's like a very very small certificate
revocation list but the problem was is
that it didn't scale too well when
things got a little bit bigger okay so
now it happened I remember there was a
clerk is like it can't find your number
in the book it's a good thing Lady you
know and that's probably why she was
there making minimum wage well the
problem was is that as more people
started using cars as hotlist got bigger
and bigger and bigger like a dot hosts
file which you couldn't go ahead and
scale to the size of the internet you
had to have something a little bit
bigger and better so what do we do we
want for these knuckle Buster run your
card through to these online validation
using this ooh a modem 1200 baud 24 and
things like that but here's a crazy
thing do you know what percentage of the
merchants still use an unauthenticated
unencrypted dial-up modem to run your
credit card about ninety percent because
if you want to do it across the internet
you have to pay extra to the merchant
bank so why would you do that if your
dry cleaner you don't want to say a bend
extra money on it so you put up with it
so the cool thing is so you can check
for authorization real time because now
you had a little bit of latency with
that little book right you can steal car
to money but nobody would know about it
to the next week but now you can go
ahead into a real time check online
that's pretty cool and so now we can
tell if your card not only is stolen or
not we can tell there's a balance on it
and whether or not the merchant should
take it merchants like this because it
helped
protect them then from people going
ahead having cards that were out of
money and if you didn't know that when
you did the knuckle Buster thing and
then you'd submitted it to your bank in
three days later you found out there's
no money there you got ripped off now we
don't have to worry about it anymore
well the problem is today for those
Monty Python fans how do you know she's
a witch of course what's the answer yeah
she floats all right you must be made of
wood so we look at all these solutions
that come out of these mainframe type
things these big copper and these are
hundred million dollar companies and oh
by the way you know working with mock 37
who Dan Woolies out there and yeah I got
their little card in here but talk to
these folks by the way that's really
cool they're a cybersecurity accelerator
and they helped fund this little guy
here which is why did all this research
for you guys so what do you do then is
we learn a behavior of a user and look
for anomalous stuff now do any of us
ever do anomalous things in her life oh
it's sort of defines us right and so it
works really well my grandma who's in
Ohio who doesn't drive more than 20
miles from her house and never charges
more than forty dollars on a credit card
solar guard Jose up in these Los Angeles
on a friday night for 800 bucks to the
best buy probably not grandma that's
easy to spot but the thing is is that
you get a lot of false positives that
way and so even spite of that 12 billion
dollars get past it and this is like an
intrusion detection intrusion prevention
but this is more of an IPS system if
it's blocking transactions people aren't
happy when your car doesn't work so
things are changing on the first of
October just a couple weeks ago what's
happened they've just realigned the
liability rules by the way you got told
2017 if you're in a gas pump and the
idea is this if you're a bank and you
issue cars you don't have that little
chip on there then you're paying for the
fraud if you're a merchant and you don't
take little chip you're paying for the
prod by lana the carrot doesn't doesn't
matter you're paying for it what if you
both are guilty well then you have an
arm wrestling or something they all work
out the rules but this is not the
federal government this is not the banks
that are saying this this is the
switches visa mastercard and discover
and american express by least 20 of them
out there in the united states alone
here's a
you take a look at the fraud equation
how much fraud losses do visa have every
year zero and mastercard 0 why because
it's in their contract we don't pay for
fraud in fact it's even better than that
fraudulent transaction comes through
their system they get a little
percentage of that too they're actually
making money on fraud dude that is one
rocket industry now you know why your
stock has been doing so well except
there's some other issues coming up so
before you go out and buy their stock
i'll give you some pointers on that so
how are we doing so far so as of this
past month eighteen percent up from
about three percent of the credit cards
now have a chip who here's got at least
one card with a chip on it look around
yeah that's about seventy percent who
here still has the old legacy ones in
your wallet Oh from some of the old
stuff yeah so we're in that transition
phase even though the rules have kicked
in by the way the estimate is going to
cost about 8 billion dollars for all
these donut shops and the Chinese
restaurants and the dry cleaners and
everybody else to upgrade all other
hardware well gee whiz for that kind of
money you could get for his estimates as
high as 35 but you could buy a bunch of
aircraft carriers and go rule part of
the world or you could take chip cards I
don't know about you but ruling part of
the world sounds more cool than taking a
different form of payment heck we'll use
Bitcoin and rule the world anyway not
too many merchant locations a lot of
these locations are maybe your big
organizations like Target who spent 100
million dollars fixed in their systems
but now they finally rolled them out
walmart was pretty much first major
retailers free so August and now you're
going to see the customer experience a
lot of frustration come black friday and
all these shopping when people instead
of swiping their card for half a second
gotta stick it in there and leave it in
there for six seconds seems like forever
when there's 10 people in line behind
you that think we're gonna see the first
fights coming out pretty soon it's
probably going to be on cops and i'm
sure it's gonna be down in pinellas park
florida because that's where everybody
is and the guys going to have no shirt
on and it's always said you have to be
if you want to be in cops and it's going
to be a fight about people get stuck in
line for these things so why are we
doing this because we got this chip and
pin thing it's not really pin it's not
while the chip we call it formerly
europay MasterCard and Visa EMV no to
get the first billing and it's
alphabetical know as Europe a is driven
by the Europe
it's been the standard there for several
years up in Canada now for about seven
years actually I guess eight and a half
of the exchange rate but in any case
we're finding that 92 the 20 countries
use Chip and PIN except for the US where
a special we're different we're going to
go to chip and pin when when we go to
the metric system cuz we're America yeah
we know better right so I ask the
Europeans I was over there a couple
times in the last two months oh why do
we do you Americans you love criminals
what do you mean you make movies about
them you elect them to public office I
mean it's it's it's an American thing
okay what else oh we got much worse
fraud no we already saw the statistics
it's much worse than us they're more
security conscious in Americans I don't
know you guys had more wars in last
century then you have although we're
trying to do our best to catch up
Europeans are smarter than Americans
I'll let you decide that for yourself
but let's look at the real reason why
this thing took off back in the United
States when you want to get a new phone
line 25 years ago what you do you called
up one of the baby bells or even before
the Bell System got broken up by Judge
green call up AT&T hey it's Tuesday you
got a new phone line by Friday so you
can take these new online credit card
checking things over in Europe though
they're running through PTT postal
telephone and telegraph PTT is one of
those ossified government organizations
it takes forever to get something done
and so you talk to somebody who grew up
over in France or Germany or Italy or
something like that back in the 70s or
it would take you six to eight months
seriously no kidding you get a new phone
line in well you can't do that you can't
scale these little onion skin revocation
list because you'd be setting out phone
books every week and so they had to come
up with something else so the idea was
we're going to bite the bullet we're
going to pay about ten times as much for
the card and we're going to put into the
hands of the merchants a way that they
can validate that the cardholder and the
card itself have a shared common secret
and that's really all we're talking
about by the way the software is written
in Java for those of us who think that's
a really fun idea here's an interesting
project for next year anyway wants to
work with me on a research project
looking at the code and trying to see
because how are you going to patch a
credit card
I mean we talk about the Internet of
Things we're already into here but a lot
of our money's tied up in this stuff
here when you insert into a reader the
device interrogate sit and then I asked
for the user so if you go to Europe it's
kind of nice because your card never
goes in the back room we don't see some
shifty-looking person go back there
skimming it a bunch of times they bring
a little machine out there you put it in
your peepee poo-poo and now you're in
cool well why can't we do that in
America well because we're Americans
besides what does it not do it doesn't
prove that there's any balance on the
card for example if it was a debit card
you don't know if his money it doesn't
prove necessarily if the cards even
valid if maybe it's been revoked it
doesn't prove that has been part of a
large time of fraud because and it
doesn't really check for anything if
your card not present because we don't
have e-commerce back in nineteen ninety
all he had was what 1 800 flowers and
like you're really gonna send flowers
your grandma with a stolen credit card
that's going to work like really welcome
time for reading the will so it doesn't
do any of these things but what it did
do is it solved a different problem back
then it allowed them to go ahead and do
computer sort of verification of what
that the cardholder and the card itself
shared a common secret of pin that's it
which is good when somebody stole one
card but what happens if these still 20
million cards see it doesn't scale very
well or when you think about why would
you even do that today well if you're in
the payment card industry and if your
abuse or MasterCard you're making these
ridiculous profits good idea though we
got a monopoly and now you've got things
like alternative forms of payment
Bitcoin currency Apple pay Samsung pay I
think JP Morgan Chase just announced
there is this past week a new form of
electronic payment we're going to see a
whole sea of payment forms that are
going to potentially rock this industry
to the core because remember who's
driving this it's Visa and MasterCard
who are driving the shift they want to
show something anything out to the user
the consumer to show that hey somebody's
doing something but the reality is is
that although there's a lot of fraud
being
lost Visa and MasterCard technically
make money on fraud and a certain odd
extent banks because they get such a big
percentage if you have a merchant bank
where you pay in three to five percent
to process anything from a visa or
mastercard up to an amex but we don't
have three to five percent fraud fraud
really is around 10 9 to 10 basis points
point zero zero nine and say a point
zero nine percent so how do you justify
three percent you make money on the
fraud because you can convince the
regulator is not to regulate us it's a
whole interesting system that if we
drove the fraud out or very low you
couldn't support those rates anymore and
you'd have to lower your rates which
would lower the cost to merchants which
would lower your prices now as we get to
this October first deadline in other
word past that we found out that it was
a big thing was like y2k it's like okay
what happened not a whole lot but we
find out that a lot of efforts were made
to try to go ahead and steal stuff so
let's take a quick look at a couple he
snakes target 40 million cars stolen so
guys stole the cards what's it going to
do is he got a cache about himself
seriously no way what do you do if you
take all these cards and you're going to
sell them off to some criminal gang so
we get someone like Al here he's going
to stand in there for a criminal gang
leader and Ellen is going to buy a whole
bunch of cards and in fact lots of gangs
going to buy lots of cards and then all
these cards worked away into circulation
see what you're starting to see here now
for the first time is there is an
ecosystem there is an entire underground
economy that starts not even with this
but the person who wrote the malware who
first did the memory scraping selling it
a person implemented it who then sells
the cards often the batches of to a
major website like a rescatar and yet
before I remind myself I got should have
some websites here yeah if you go to
their underground site here anybody
recognize this fine gentleman here Brian
Krebs yeah John's a great security blog
I'd like to meet the guy lives right
here in Northern Virginia although it's
interesting because in his exposé about
yo I'm in the underground hack hacking
your stuff and learning your wares he's
publishing all this and he's actually
pointing out to the criminals some other
operational security errors and failures
so what are the crooks doin they're
fixing it so although
they don't seem to like him to a certain
extent he's kind of a hero of the soviet
union because he is enabling the
criminals to get free consulting to fix
their errors and now the banks are
paying millions more trying to fix the
stuff you go to their website refund and
replace policy they move around a little
bit because yeah they're technically
extra legal but if you pay your host
country the right amount of money you
get to stick around for a while and you
can go look for car it's hard to see in
the back of the room that'll teach you
to pretend you're encouraged you should
have SAT up front but you can find here
cards $10 17 bucks six dollars why
because that chase card was getting
ready to expire at the end of the month
but what they have is they give you the
individual dumps the batches that they
came out of and they give you a
percentage because when the target stuff
first came out they're rated at one
hundred percent why because none of the
bank's none of the merchants none of the
card holders knew their card was
compromised you had a hundred percent
chance of that card being good if you
bought it early on they're still for
sale they're down around thirty percent
or so because what's happened after year
and a half a lot of these cards age
because typically you three years old so
to statistically fifty percent are dead
bigger banks just bit the bullet
reissued it but smaller banks credit
unions and things like that little bit
concerned about the fixed cost of
reissuing cards depending upon how big
you are it could be anywhere from three
to twelve dollars to reissue the card
send it out in the mail so they just
saying you know we're going to suck it
up and take our chances and some banks
has turned out to be a multi-million
dollar decision error but you can
actually get here zip code city state
the last four digits I was searching for
specific last for did used to match one
of my card the first six digits or
what's called tube in the back
identification number so one of the
things that Brian was pointing out is
said hey with the first six digits for
the bin knowing the bank knowing the
last four digits knowing the city in the
state in the zip code do you think you
could triangulate on your customers and
figure out which ones are for sale and
then preemptively kill them right why
would you point this out to the
criminals okay this is an operational
security error that they've been making
that has allowed clever banks to spot
stuff like that now you don't want to
kill them all or some little reverse
engineer what you're doing so again this
is a little game that you're playing
where you're trying to go ahead and
you're trying to
op them a little bit at a time do it in
a strategy so that they're not going to
figure out exactly how do you know what
you know you go back and you look at
World War two in the Enigma and the
challenge that came up for the Britain
when they learned that the Germans were
going to bomb Coventry fire bomb killing
hundreds maybe thousands of their
citizens what do you do do you evacuate
the city and let the Nazis know that you
can crack their code at which point you
never read another message or do you
take the hit and these are that's why
you get paid the big bucks right but
those are tough problems that's life and
death but you got to start thinking the
same way in this type of is because this
is economic warfare this is huge so
criminals that get around with these low
value tests they said you had years to
go ahead and poke around to these things
and figure out what will work so here's
this ecosystem I was talking about what
happens is is that you buy the card you
steal them you sell to the next guy cell
to the next guy cell to the next guy why
are you ever going to buy a cyst of
stolen credit cards it could be revoked
at any time by the bank you what do you
want to make sure that they're going to
do they're still going to work right so
how do you know they're still going to
work you run this little micro test
because I understand if I get a call
from my bag you know we just cancel your
guard cuz someone trying to spend eight
hundred and fifty seven dollars over in
London okay got it but they said you
know we cancel your carrot cuz somebody
spend a dollar thirty seven at a
starbucks seriously you back guys are
nuts but so what do you know you run a
little test like in starbucks and you
run it through hotel tests we've
literally catalog a couple thousands of
these tests which allow you then to go
ahead and run under the radar because
you do a little test early on and then
what do you do you void it out you
cancel the transaction so what happens
the bank pays nothing because the
merchant doesn't get money the merchant
might have had their credential stolen
they don't know what's going are the
cardholder sees nothing on your
statement nothing happened except for
what so this guy selling you the packing
stack of cards you take this hundred
cards you run a little test run a little
test run a little test other hundred
cards a hundred work or 98 or 50 it's
like I guess in the movies you see them
doing the heroin packets they're always
like tasting it I don't know what
heroines supposed to taste like I mean I
maybe they're just taking sure it's not
powdered sugar or something or powdered
milk I don't know but it's sort of like
tasting the credit card numbers so
anyway what they'll do is
now the bank doesn't see this the bank
doesn't see that they get no visibility
to list boom this cash out at the end
here's a crazy thing people seem to
think that a car gets stolen and gets
used a few minutes later it could be
weeks and sometimes months we've seen
cards in the underground for over a year
work on their way through the system
it's old stock it still sells but hey if
the validity rate on this batch is down
to twenty percent your may only paying a
few pennies per card instead of a couple
bucks it's worth it to give it a try
particularly if you're doing online
because what's your risk no one's going
to arrest you especially be coming
through tor so what not what happens to
do is the big challenges trying to
figure out can we spot these tests and
kill the cards before the cash out that
way we can figure that stuff that's kind
of the problem I've been focusing on
here this is not a sales pitch because
i'm outside now with my computer
security world working on bank stuff but
it's a really fun problem to take the
way that we think about problems and
apply it to different areas of industry
so the current problem is what we try to
profile users hey users are difficult to
profile why because they do anomalous
things for humans so do you ever get a
call from your bank or difficult rands
actually didn't work yeah that's a false
positive okay what's the problem with a
false positive well they're annoying and
they're embarrassing hey I've been doing
a start-up which means I'm eating it
things like subway all day long now I'm
finally getting an important meeting
with some back and take them out to like
a fancy French restaurant trying to wine
and dine this client and then the waiter
comes back and says a credit card has
been declined yeah as only a French
waiter could say pardon my french accent
there but what comes out of that is what
you're horribly embarrassed and what we
find out is a big percentage of
customers who just take that card either
never use it again or stick it in the
back of the wallet what card vendors
want you to have them on in front of the
wall they want their card to be first
there so what's in your wallet by the
way I did bring a card reader so we
could do some scanning remind me to do
this I'll show you some cool stuff and
some frightening stuff as well but
imagine trying your kid comes home with
a box of crickets or cockroaches and
you've got 500 of them do you want to
find out two hours later and then case
them all around the house or do you want
to get the kid on the front doorstep no
young man you train around get rid of
that thing and so that's the whole idea
is trying to change this entire fraud
paradigm around
now what we look at this false positive
huge amount of lost sales by the way 13
times the cost of false negatives if we
lose 12 billion de card fraud but we
give up a hundred and eighteen billion
in false positive fraud because it's not
really fraud it's just denied
transaction this is deals that just
don't go through that's huge impact and
so as they say people stop trying and so
here's a challenge where's where's the
fraud in there there are two fraudulent
transactions on that screen it's a big
data dump yes I'm stating to take a
picture good luck with the resolution
but and yes I did change the card
numbers to protect the innocent but this
stuff comes pouring in if you're a major
bank you might be getting literally
millions of transactions every 24 hours
we hate to be cliche you throw a big
data but in a way it's that sort of a
problem you're trying to look at this
big huge stream of information and
typically what financial companies do is
you look at it at the instant it comes
in because you've got a small amount of
time to make a decision now in this case
well we've done is we taking a little
different look we said hey wait a minute
instead of just looking at a transaction
good or bad is this grandma she and Ohio
is it a small transaction that's fast
set of rules now we say who else are you
shopping with because if you're doing
card fraud it doesn't scale very well if
you're only doing one car at a time by
that I mean that if I got to go online
steal one card get in the car drive down
Walmart go buy a gift card then run back
go ahead by another stunt no you take 50
at a time or if you're on the
wholesaling you're going to do it
literally thousand or up to a million at
a time huge blocks of the stuff move
around and now what we find out is this
particular card we were tracking went
shopping in six different places that
was very suspicious why because there's
nothing because the card had already
been killed it was a dead card this is a
zombie the cardholder had already had
their card reissued they cut up the old
card threw it away and yet the card is
still out shopping how could that be
because not all crooks are very careful
and sometimes people kind of really
never know that car that didn't work
last week maybe the card older put money
on to it so what we did that
as we said hey let's take a look it kind
of a guilt by association and we found
out that there was same card it was used
here with 50 other cards all in a very
short period of time all for the
identical transaction and what does that
tell you those other 50 cards are all
stolen we didn't know about any of them
it turns out there's a Coke machine in
one in particular part of California
it's on a loading dock and about once a
week I think it's fridays nights around
10pm must be a bus 50 people from around
America line up in front of that Coke
machine and they all by exactly one coke
at about 20 second intervals what's
going on here right somebody's got a new
stack of cards and by the way remember
that food chain that we saw that's not
somebody up here because they were going
to reverse it you can't reverse the
purchase of a coke so this is somebody
who's getting ready to drive down to the
store and cash out and when you cash out
what are you gonna buy best thing you
buy as a gift card why because then you
can fence the gift card and you broken
you laundered the money yeah you can buy
merchandise that you got to return the
merchandise I lost my receipt then we'll
have to give you a gift card okay that's
a good thing here is what most people
don't understand what's happening in
there is that when I go to a merchant I
go shopping there's an order system or I
could just be a point-of-sale that
information then gets sent to their
merchant bank they have an acquiring
bank that may then go through a payment
processor sort of aggregates all that
which then gets into your switch visa
mastercard discover american express etc
thats which then sends over to the
issuing bank which will authorize it
send it back up here account check it
validated come back that's about a 3-2
for second round trip so when you swipe
your card or now dip your card is the
correct term is the verb that's what's
happening but what it mean what's banks
every also been when they've been
waiting from this 3 6 10 12 month cycle
of things getting stolen to the last
three seconds to take a look seriously
it's like why do you want to wait till
the bullets already in the air before
you decide there's a sniper out there
maybe you should do a little bit
preemptive stuff as well so if you
understand this ecosystem you can also
see where you can go do stuff and now if
you understand how people work we find
that all these different tests that are
out there he said we found a couple
thousands of them have different
visibilities so I met a hotel hotel
tests are great because hotels when you
check in even if your room is prepaid
what do they want I carried for
incidentals do they charge your card no
they do what they call a
pre-authorization what a pre off does is
it says hey I'm going to pre-authorize
two hundred dollars so if you walk out
of here and we find out you empty the
minibar because he had the munchies or
something like that because it's an
Oregon or Washington or Denver they
might sell a lot in the minibar these
days I still have that girl scout it
made a fortune selling cookies outside
of marijuana shop and they kind of
called following says come on in any
case they get their money if you check
in get your pre off done on monday and
then on tuesday you cancel your card
saying it was stolen the hotel still
gets their money because they have
locked out that money which is why you
don't want to use a debit card to rent a
car because they're gonna block out like
fifty thousand dollars or something like
that you get it back two weeks later
fake merchants course you won't see that
card verify brute force i'm not gonna go
into the details in the chart the whole
idea is there's a lot of different ways
you can look at this stuff and remember
if you're a crooked you've been doing
this for a couple years you share it you
put out there on YouTube videos you put
it in onion there's all kinds of places
you can go ahead and get resources to
learn how to do card fraud and get good
at it and what we're doing is we are
saying hey wait a minute this is a link
analysis problem isn't it instead of
looking at it one dimensional images
here's your card and every time your
card is presented for a new transaction
we make a one-time decision does this
look like you so 50 people go into that
Coke machine have what 50 people that
are all being asked do you look like you
while buying a coke is not that unusual
so they all go through never triggers an
alarm nobody's saying 50 people from
around the country going to the same
coke machine should trigger an alarm and
oh by the way let's pull back on that
and now because of PCI DSS the data
security standards banks can't share
certain data you're not allowed to
crooks can share it kind of weird world
so all these things linked together
here's a real example again change a
little bit of the data to make sure that
it was anonymized but think about that
ecosystem legitimate card holder in June
goes amazon gets a one dollar
authorization that is reversed in seven
minutes later there's $11 charge live
real or fraud that's real because that's
what Amazon does you enter a car they're
going to say does this thing work and if
it does work they let you go to check
out if it doesn't work they don't let
you go to check out number two now four
days later Apple online to dollar charge
good sure why not now a month later they
say Cabela's what sets boarding goods
store yeah $12 sixty-six cents
authorization that is reversed hmm no
harm no foul so far but then the
following month we see a holiday in
seven dollar eighty two cent
pre-authorization also reversed and then
two weeks later a gymboree for seven
dollars it's approved and then a few
minutes later euro car parts 448 bucks
works Eurostar 110 bucks works punky
fish 695 buck Bam Bam Bam Bam but they
have to have her in that debit card
within a matter of seconds they've
emptied out almost twelve hundred
dollars out of their card maxed it out
now let's do a little bit of analysis
here what we think we know about what's
going on is it the same crook doing all
this stuff no because they got a
different mo because we found another
card just had two charges on it the same
date a cabela's almost the same time for
the same amount twelve dollars and
sixty-six cents what does that tell you
that that crook is the same person
because they do the same merchant for
the same amount now at 20-8 august at
eight fifty one is compared to 20-8
august at 851 so it's probably an
automated script euro car parts 448 euro
car parts for 42 different crook doing
what modifying their numbers a little
bit so you can start to look at the data
and figure out whose we're in the food
chain oh by the way they got NSF why
because the card only had three hundred
eighty bucks they try to hit it for 440
if they tried it for 370 you'd win but
most time you want to get in or get the
money and go and as soon as you get the
merchandise you get to chip some place
or you get a gift card you're home free
and the idea being is that now the
bank's stuck to deal with the loss and
there's all kinds of things we can find
these clones as we call them they're
copies a legitimate car the track to
which is what's on the mag stripe
on the back of the card so you look at
any card whether it's a hotel card or a
credit card you got a mag stripe and
touch it up to three tracks to data here
full mag stripe copy that's useful why
because you can clone the card cvv the
three digit code printed on the back of
your car door for digital in front of
the amex is not encoded in the mag
stripe better not be unless you got a
really dumb Bank which tells you then
that if a card is a card present
compromise which means they got the mag
stripe data it doesn't become a card not
present compromise where somebody has to
enter in the three digit cvv so there's
a pretty good firewall in between these
two types of fraud unless somebody gets
what we call the foals if they got
everything you got it so if i'm running
a skimmer if i'm at a restaurant or
something and i skim your card I write
down the three digits as well I got it
or if you look at target where they lost
40 million cards but 70 million customer
records with addresses and things like
that now if I'm trying to hack granmoun
Ohio I don't go ahead and buy her card
if I'm out in East Los Angeles I buy it
if I'm in Ohio and then what happens is
a credit card fraud algorithms gone
eight hundred dollar purchase I I guess
grandma is upgrading her television set
because she hasn't made a big purchase
in three years must be legit boom it
goes through because the more you know
about your target the better you can do
I'll show you some jumpers and things
like that and trainwreck cards and
already showed you a zombie it's already
been killed it's out shopping so what we
find then is that criminals and the
behavior or such that there are certain
things you gotta do to make this crime
scale you can't do one car at a time
usually do 20 30 50 100 there's big
batches because it's a batch processing
when you can let's see enough of the
batch you can start to infer patterns a
lot of times to buy exactly the same
items for the same merchant some crooks
are smarter they'll mix up the dollar
amounts a little oftentimes they may
only appear once before cash out now as
we're getting a more sophisticated to or
three times as they move from the
wholesaler to the retailer if you will
to the gang member and who by the way at
the very end you get a mule typical car
gets popped for about 250 bucks plus or
minus
so here's the deal hey you want to make
some money here's 50 cards you go back
and you bring me back ten thousand
dollars worth of stuff gift cards
anything more you keep anything less I
break your legs well that might not seem
like a bad deal and so what you can do
is if you start to get inside this
decision cycle you can start to mess
with these ecosystems somebody goes out
there and they started panicking when
all the cards that they knew we're good
half an hour ago half of them don't work
anymore and so what you can do is you're
going to show a little bit of heat and
gets content in there and now we find
out that even the chip cards can get
cloned as well we've seen some great
talks Kristen Padgett did a couple
things a couple years ago she talked
about near field communications cards
and Oh major malfunction talked about
cloning the chip cards so there's the
technologies out there it just raises
the cost of doing at wholesale instead
of costing you twenty to thirty cents a
card you might be spending three dollars
a card and that's a fixed cost if your
criminal trying to do all that stuff but
there's easier ways to do so like we've
seen in every other country that's going
over to the chips what do we do we go to
online fraud even better why because you
don't have to present yourself in front
of the merchant in front of cameras
where there might be a possibility local
sheriff could pick you up so what we're
doing is we just whack Amole push the
fraud down here and it pops up right
over there and so here's a car this is a
train wreck we see the 001 or legit cars
this is a real customer up here hmm
there's a marriott pulsar global
e-commerce boom all of a sudden on the
twenty-second we started seeing $67 591
50 51 the bam ba-bam until finally the
car ran out of money Oh 59 but it's
still going Bam Bam Bam Bam Bam Bam Bam
Bam Bam because is an automated script
it's not smart enough to stop because
well maybe the cards temporary might
work again but what does this tell you
if you're on the defense now I know a
list of the merchant ID is that they're
trying to use to run it against you see
you leak a little bit of information
every time and you can learn more and
more about your opponent's a jumper we
found this card moving around card
present real cardholder California card
not present and now we find within four
minutes the card goes from Illinois to
Alaska in a card present transaction not
going to happen and so again crooks make
mistakes little mistakes that don't seem
significant because a lot of the people
at the end of this whole pipeline
are going ahead go ahead and they're
trying to cash out they're not the
sophisticated crooks who upstream we're
making sure that they don't take any
part of this end game by the way when
target was hacked one of the first
question they got a call from one of the
bank's hit G mark you think they got the
pins because if they had the pins to all
the debit cards Wow let's like game over
and so I did a little bit of quick
research you find out the company that
manufactures the pin pads uses a special
key cryptography protocol that was
developed by the ANSI Banking Committee
x9 here's the crazy thing I helped write
this standard 1992 it's still around
what it was there's one major major key
for the merchant another one for the
device and every single transaction had
its own separate key so every pin came
out with a separate key and so and when
they found out that they were using the
stuff that I helped write 25 years like
cool you're good so within half an hour
I could tell the bank don't worry about
it and it turned out was the right call
so what happens that you get social
engineering and brute force by the way
there's no three tries and you're on a
credit card in this hacking so we see
things coming in 00 00 01 02 03 but the
average 500 to get a cvv 5,000 tries to
go ahead and hack a pin they don't time
out or we go ahead and social engineer
hello mr. well Sam hi this is your bank
calling hi this is Peggy and we
understand you were shopping at Target
well we want to protect you were going
to issue a new card because we don't
want you to be liable for any of the
fraud that might have been done oh wow
what a great Bank course you already
covered by Reggie anyway but most people
don't know that so what we like to do is
to just verify your current information
I'm going to send you over to our
automated system and ask you to validate
your PIN now you don't tell it to me no
bank employee is ever going to ask you
for a pen so don't ever give that up but
it's okay to tell it to the computer so
wait a minute please enter your PIN beep
boop thank you very much your card will
be on its way in seven to 10 days thank
you for being a customer of big bang of
course your car gets emptied out within
the next few minutes and we see a lot of
this social engineering so look at the
social engineering training for your
family your friends your companies and
things like that this zombie I showed
you this thing we had a little zombie
thing who goes out there it Krabs around
it cones itself we saw the big spread it
goes everywhere zipping through some of
these things here but we find out that
when clones are born what they do is
that they have different characteristics
so I can tell the type of fraud would
trace back to the type of compromise and
so online as they said online i can go
to youtube i can get a whole bunch of
videos i can learn how to do this and
for the most part once your online if
you get away with something you got away
with it involves shipping merchandise
yeah well its got actually the loading
dock and it usually goes to an abandoned
house or some other drop place and
merchants typically just share that list
of bad addresses but if I'm buying now
one of these gift cards it is just
electronic information is not physical
once it got it I got it because I can
shift it over to a gift card exchange
company and had that thing soul within
five minutes I can launder my laundered
money all kinds of tests that are out
there again go online if you want to
look at it some more kind of zipping
through here mostly because this is just
an encyclopedic list of things to think
about not so much cheating out of
information but basically telling you
that if you see these things that
there's a lot of stuff going on so if
you look at how do we going to protect
this ecosystem in the future we got a
hair worried about all these cash-outs
merchandise it gets brought in back the
next day hey I can't use it it's the
wrong size i don't like it i bought
extra that's okay here's your gift card
exactly what the crook wants and they'll
be careful what you buy used gift cards
on the underground market because i like
i'm saving money i did that for my
brother a few years ago before i started
getting into card fraud prevention
because he was working on his house a
bunch of home depot gift cards but what
i do i got a discount on him because i
bought him some place turned out the
lady said yeah these are stolen people
steal stuff off with a job site they
bring it back for for merchandise credit
we don't want to be part of that fraud
ecosystem but it's just sort of the cost
of doing business unfortunately you can
block certain transactions and now we
find out that there's certain dollar
values hey a fifty dollar gift card that
has a transaction fee that could be an
exit because it's 495 so 5495 is a as a
blacklisted number so you buy a candy
bar at the same time you buy your gift
card and now you throw off the
algorithms again it's trivial to defeat
these existing fixed algorithms cuz they
just like a bunch of rule sets so i look
for bad merchants i look for weak
merchants anything of value i can send
the mail drops all these are ways that I
cash out and I'm able to go ahead and
get stuff out of there so banks are
spending a fortune on the
cards they say they go in from our
thirty cents the three dollars a card
and all these little chips are expensive
by the way it'd be interesting to take a
look more at them merchants are spending
a fortune on this technology is anywhere
from eight to thirty billion dollars
when all is said and done with all these
new readers and of course criminals are
trying to cash these out yo and now as
al there these folks are trying to make
a ton of money off of this up and it's
working pretty well so that's a little
quick insight by the way got a mag
stripe reader show you a couple things
but that's the formal presentation on
this but let me shift over real quick
I've got a couple questions now that the
smart chip has been available the cost
of the fraud is purchase it's pushed to
the merchant if the merchant does not
invest in a chip card reader if the bank
how is going to clay out it'll be
interesting to see how it plays out
because they can't be cloned well it has
been done it's been demonstrated Def Con
a couple times and other hacker
conferences it's more expensive to do it
but it can be done especially you can
find a phone that Java so what's going
to happen there's going to be a lot of
blaming game no yes no yes arguing about
it it's can all get fought out and the
problem is ultimately you the user if
you're a victim of somebody cloning your
chipped card in the early days you just
couldn't get your money back because
they would argue is mathematically
impossible well we've since proven it is
possible it's just difficult when
somebody gets to a breakthrough on that
though it's going to be whole game
changer so again recognize that credit
cards and plastic goes back to the 1950s
and are we getting to a different thing
where for the most part our new means of
doing commerce is not going to be
plastic but it's going to be electronic
silicon and I think this is what's
happening with all these card companies
are going hey you know what we've got an
entrenched marketplace but look at Kodak
they missed the turn you can't buy
kodachrome anymore they you know
companies that Miss the turn because
they were so entrenched and so in love
with their own technology and so
recognize that I think going forward
we're going to see some real risks out
there other thoughts of questions yes
sir
right i mentioned that we just like not
relinquishing your cards in restaurants
well if all they have is a reader in the
back because some of these things are
fixed they're actually attached to the
the cart they're not going to drag that
entire cash register out to you you are
not at risk for more than fifty dollars
based upon regulation deregulation a
sign back in the carter administration
but i'd avoid dodgy restaurant side
avoids people that look weird if you're
really really really worried about a pic
hash or use a gift card that has a limit
and then once it goes to zero goes to
zero but that's a little bit more
expensive for you the customer but we're
starting to see competing technologies
with the near field communications like
Apple pay going to currency which is
going to do qrk a lot of different
things but yeah you're right that's
always unnerved European folks and they
think of the US as a high-risk area when
they come here for credit card fraud and
problem is I go over there with Mike
chip and it's not shipping pin I called
up a max I pay a lot of money for that
fancy American Express card oh we don't
issue pins unless you're not in the US
this is but everybody uses them I go to
buy groceries there you gotta wait line
45 minutes for someone going to get you
to sign a little piece of paper when
you're at the grocery it's like
seriously everybody else being boom Bing
boom and out it's inconvenient but they
figure all Americans aren't smart enough
to learn how to use pins I think reality
check is is that if we got everything
that way we might see fraud go down you
couldn't support those charges the banks
are able to levy on to the merchants and
that would change the ecosystem really
cut profits Durbin amendment did a lot
to cut profits by forcing certain
merchants certain banks they have to use
multiple paths to process their stuff
how we doing on time good wrap it up
alright it's what I do is wrap up on
time okay so we're really good by the
way if you want to see what's on your
wallet I've got a little card reader
here no this is not a skimmer this
doesn't fit in your hand but this is a
tractor reader and it's interesting
because you find out that in the back of
card you got your credit card number an
11 digit security code by the way the 11
digit security code I was going to show
you for my us a bank card is 11 zeros
seriously guys okay anyway thank you
very much hope you enjoyed a little
insight on card fraud and welcome to be
sides