alright what time is it are we on time
right now are we holding cool I guess
everyone's here thank you for showing up
for the last talk thank you for still
being you know awake enough to listen to
my dumb ass and thank you very much to
layer 1 for having me out here this is
kind of not a conventional talk for a
security con in many ways that you hear
a lot about code and you hear a lot
about you know all the real important
technical matters that you've been
seeing featured on all these talk tracks
and no it was like I don't know maybe I
mean I dig here and you talk about guns
but let's see where this goes I like to
mention this not only because I like
injecting locks into our lives as much
as we ever can like where can you put
better locks oh you didn't think you
could but also because I really think it
applies to a lot of us who have to
travel a lot and fly a lot and most of
you probably are flying not for pleasure
but for work because you know you've got
you got gear you've got shit you want to
take the more the regulations have
tightened how much you can bring easily
onto the plane like you can't bring nine
laptops without looking like a big
asshole you know scanning them all
through is so you want it you have to
pack it in your checked luggage we're
putting more and more expensive stuff in
our check bags so we can do our job and
our bags don't have any real security
outside of this sort of a solution so
Who am I I'm just you know the lockpick
guy you've seen me around a lot of
events I kind of go to a lot of cons now
since I don't have a real job anymore
unless you want to hire me for some
audit and most of these cons I you know
can't just get in my truck and roll I
have to fly I've had baggage problems
like the rest of us I've had baggage
theft in the past my bags get you no
hassle all the time after a really bad
episode of theft where I had to fill out
forms and you know I lost all my pics
and my knives and I said this this
fucking sucks i've got to do something
besides this there's got to be a better
way and now there is a better way now i
have hard sided psycho look and luggage
and heavy duty padlocks that I use all
the time when I fly these are not TSA
compliant locks these are proper ass
crazy padlocks which no one can really
get through you might think that's not
allowed it in fact is allowed and the
reason it's allowed is because I fly
with firearms
every time I get on a plane it's
absolutely simple to do it's the easiest
thing in the world and it results in
amazing security you can all do this
much more simply than you might realize
the end result of all this this is that
someone asked me once halfway through my
talk he was like so does that mean I
could put like laptops in the bag too
I'm like yeah that's yeah you see what I
did there you you're following along
that's what this is about this talk is
about how the law works in your favor to
use better locks in your stuff when you
fly and how it's simple some standards
you should be aware of first of all even
though airlines are private carriers
that can make up their own rules there
are federally mandated standards that
everyone up you know has to comply with
for flying with firearms they're
relatively you know uniform by every
airline every airline tweaks it a little
bit ultimately it just means your bag
has to be a heavy hard-sided case can't
have any soft bag for the main thing
containing the firearm and you have to
have a lock that only you have the key
to no one else is allowed to have access
no one else is allowed to get in your
bag it's really amazing when you tell
people that that even the TSA no one's
allowed in it's true no one is allowed
in without you standing right there your
bags can still be screened will tell you
all about how but if you declare your
weapon they'll give you a little you
know thing to fill out there you go from
that point on your bags can be properly
heavily locked certain specifics as I
say it does have to be a hard case your
ammo if you are traveling with any ammo
it's a separate classification airlines
have their own regs on that the standard
is 11 pounds you're limited to of ammo
but not everyone applies to that no
outside labels is something I love to
remind people of because airlines get
this wrong and I've had you know
arguments right there on the terminal
saying no you're breaking the law and I
tear a bag tag off and like please print
another one don't write on it what are
you doing what you actually will expect
what is going to happen if you want to
try this everything / normal everything
you've done a million times you show up
with your luggage you check you say here
I'm here's my info here's my booking
code I'm flying with X number pieces of
baggage today they all have to be
weighed like any other traveler when
you're going through this process you
say on by the way I'm
transporting firearms today I need to
fill out a declaration form every
airline has this little card that you
fill out you excuse o them your empty
weapon usually right there while you're
checking in that's sometimes this funny
i love when i would say i love when
there's like families traveling behind
me I like hmm but I mean like it's funny
but I've actually I feel very strongly
about that it shouldn't be a gas like
it's the health of our society when
average citizens are just seen walking
around with oh this is my firearm I
having to have today it should be
normalized for kids to see that they'll
give you a little card you slip it in
the bag you secure your bag right there
lock it up and then most often it is
taken immediately to a TSA screening
they have a specialized spot usually a
couple desks down sometimes right behind
the door somewhere but ultimately your
luggage is given a check they will know
that there's a clear expecting to see a
gun well and they see that and they see
nothing else suspicious and they say
okay well that's fine this was declared
and everything else is green thank you
have a good day if they need to check it
they'll call you over they say this was
your case right all right something
popped on our scanner can we get in here
you'll unlock it stand right there and
just kind of step back they'll go
through it there'll be much more
respectful going through your stuff than
they are back in the bowels of the
airport you know they'll actually move
clothes and fold them other and if they
don't I mean you can get in their face
and you're like actually that shirt
wasn't balled up like it's not going to
close yep can you put that back please
they don't like you to reach in while
they're doing it but you can direct I've
been like no can you please put them on
top of the pants and okay thank you turn
that around all right okay thanks a lot
i'll lock that up now you lock it up and
then a way it goes there are some
pointers you should be aware of that can
make this process work a lot better for
you well i suppose i say don't be a
dumbass I mean don't just walk up be
like oh yeah i'm flying to florida today
and that's great because i have a window
seat i have a gun you know no come on
you think about your statement when you
say it's AI need those forms i mean i'm
declaring firearms today obviously tag
your luggage a lot if it does get
mislaid somehow it's all the more
valuable because your steel is in there
when i say keep your cases locked as
much as possible I mean you should all
have them locked just by default when
you show up at the counter when you're
transporting to another oh we need you
to come over here now sir I've had an
instance where I wasn't paying attention
it was really busy and the airport
employees 00 su dia he's checked in okay
it's some guy just started like throwing
like that and I was like wait you're
sending that away it's not locked and
they had to run and like pull it off the
belt don't do that just hat there's it's
better to be asked oh we need to get in
this one more time oh we need to get in
this one sir like lock it off and take
it off if you need to put it right back
on the secondary area you can't always
count on it being in a smart place or an
accessible place if you have a smart
cart don't give it to someone else who's
like hey are you done with this because
you'll probably need it if you have
heavy bags and again no outside labels
that means nothing printed nothing
handwritten nothing specially fixed that
little declaration form you may have
seen it looks like a dangly tagged with
a string on it sometimes and some of
them used to be that's all been outlawed
it is against federal law it is
something you can get in their face
about I don't happen to encounter it a
lot I have my friends have it's just
something that sometimes you you know
keep escalating it get a supervisor I
have these wonderful I wish I brought
them I have these sheets that i could
give you all I did bring them I think
yeah we'll cover this in a minute I have
these just rule sheets nothing but
federal law some of them are even
laminated just keep it you know keep one
in your bag if you want to print your
own I have them on my website I'll show
you that but get in people's faces if
they are breaking the rules here you are
not the one who is wrong some things you
might think our external tags like hey
are you putting something on my bag
they're really not this big yellow and
striped one that's just an overweight
tag if your luggage is too heavy you
can't really get around the penalties be
like I'm sorry you know I've got all
these steel 1911s they weigh a lot
account me a break no you're going to
have to pay baggage penalties there's no
special allowance for ammo weight and
gun weight but has nothing to do with
weapons that little sticker I saw
applied to the the actual baggage tag
itself I was like what is that are they
putting something on my back there no
that's just the TSA has inspected this
bag if it was screened specially the
other day I got this slapped on my bag I
don't know if that's because I suddenly
got elite status on my star alliance or
if that's the new airport trick thing to
like oh there's guns in here
should have asked somebody and I used to
think these little TSA things I was like
well that's kind of neat you know
they're really secure they're all
hologram Dan you know if you know what
that is not now you can't like fake it
but now they've started producing ones
that aren't hologram they've just made
these little this has been cleared by
the TSA orange stickers so create your
own talk about that and what that means
for bag security some international
countries don't have our laws obviously
you will sometimes see tags on the
outside of your bags for international
travel it's totally possible to fly to
foreign domains with firearms as well
just call ahead find out what the policy
is where you're going more international
notes besides the tagging people ask me
about well isn't it you know hectic
clearing all those different custom hops
and everywhere else you're going no not
really I've never been stopped at
customs in general but even if I had
been I'm not doing anything wrong
because I know I'm traveling somewhere
where a firearm is legal you know I'm
not gonna bring my guns to Malaysia or
something or you know Amsterdam when we
go over there for har because countries
to scare guns but we go to Norway we go
to plenty of places Canada if you're
following the laws you don't have to
worry about the customs people messing
with you the customs people are mean and
likes early but they're paid to do a job
by being mean and surly they know their
job in and out they're not going to
hassle you the one international problem
you're going to find is airline staffers
who are not used to passengers at all
flying with firearms so this guy you
know sitting behind the Baltic Air
counter as a country whose probably band
firearms 20 years ago under communism
and he's just you know he's what you
have weapons I do not understand expect
quizzical looks from that guy you may
have to escalate it get a supervisor or
call ahead if you really find flying
like you know Bob's international air
travel but it is it Herman Munster what
I don't know he looks like Ethan Hawke
to me maybe he's got a new job work is
slow one other tip it doesn't have to do
with baggage hassles but it has to do
with the lines of security when you're
being screened how many people have ever
had something in your bag that they
didn't like and they frowned upon it and
they yell at you and ask you to throw it
out right exactly I like to tell people
it's a smart thing grab you know
obviously they say oh you can go mail it
to yourself
well yeah the post office is always like
a mile away and you can't get there and
back in time and it's a post office we
fly on weekends we fly on holidays we
fly when the mail is not even running
what airports do usually have though our
mail slots if you carry up you know a
forever stamp on an envelope or a
self-addressed priority pre-stamped
envelope you can easily throw whatever
you had they were bitching about in an
envelope shove it and you know a mail
slot which is there probably more places
than you realize when you go home look
at the airports if you're flying home
look for mail slots you'll see them
everywhere nobody sends like a look
where I am grandma postcard anymore but
you know the jet-setting people that's
why there were post offices and post
lots all through the airports and those
flat rate envelopes you can put a lot of
shit in those you know and they'll get
to your destination now technically with
the new laws only supposed to be like
was it 13 ounces or 14 ounces
technically though I don't know if
that's true or not I mean the website
online still says you can put like 70
pounds in that envelope and it's going
to get there as yeah as long as you can
close the envelope without destroying
the envelope in the process if someone
does hassle you at the line anywhere
else remember that you are following the
rules have the rule sheet I really like
come up after i'm done i printed a ton
of these for you guys if you want them
take a rule sheet shove it in your bag
and just quote these things keep
escalating it to other people you're not
the one I mean you guys all know this
from social engineering on down you're
not the one who needs to back down
you're not even trying to scam someone
here you're just trying to follow the
rules and just keep standing I said no
I'm not going to give that to you know
I'm really not going to let you take it
back in that room unlocked no I'm sorry
you are violating the law and keep
escalating it one more thing if the
problem of lost luggage it sucks being
that person it sucks having your bag
misrouted most bags by the way I mean it
we all had kind of a weird thing most
bags even ones that are lost get to you
eventually so if it doesn't get lost
forever which is pretty rare it will
come back to you after you fill out the
paperwork and sometimes they ship it to
you but again like this is one more
layer of removed from your care now it
was sent by some messenger service or it
was in some guys car it was in some
office in the airport for two days while
they tried to contact you if you
add locks on this you know that no one
has been in there the whole time and by
the time it gets to you it's still
locked that's a real big piece of mind
in my book a couple more tips if you
have any type of insurance that covers
your bags and the airlines are often
insured to some degree it can vary
particularly with weapons I'll talk to
you about that in a minute different air
carriers at different policies is it
possible what I mean to play with wait I
mean if you're like me and you're using
a really psycho padlock that weighs a
few pounds and if you're traveling with
you know kind of a heavy like pistol
that weighs a few pounds it's possible I
wouldn't recommend it to put your bag on
the belt if you if you're like a lot of
us who are right on the bubble like how
many people weigh their bags at home
before they go to the air for yak you're
traveling all this shit so you got your
49 pounds and they check you in you say
oh I'm traveling with weapons and here
you put the weapon in you put the lock
on maybe that added a few pounds that
weren't factored in I wouldn't recommend
that but I had to do it once and it
worked out pretty well can you put a
firearm in a hard case inside of another
case yes you can there are some really
nice cases this is a TSA approved case
that CHS let me check out here there's a
couple of things I will say about that
one it defeats this whole like I am
extra locking all my other stuff idea
you know you could put this in like a
duffel bag and it's allowed it's also
however the only way that I am aware of
that firearms have been stolen from
luggage in the past stealing a small
case out of a larger case that was not
locked or not locked properly is
something that's been a problem at
o'hare airport in a few other places
I've never ever known of a firearm
that's been stolen out of a large
unopenable bag I mean the only way is to
boost the whole piece of luggage which
really doesn't happen that often stuff
that gets stolen from baggage areas is
it be someone shoves it in a cargo pant
where they shove it in their little sack
that they have for their lunch that day
the real interesting trick what I say is
not just functional firearms if you're
not a gun person you know get out but be
alright let's say or whatever maybe you
live in some you know communist state
like I got to go hawaii for Chaka Khan
in June it's a real sob story I know I'm
really troubled by that know if you go
somewhere that's very gun unfriendly you
can use
firearms that aren't lethal firearms and
they still apply under the law i'm going
to show you and talk about some things
that are I should just let you know they
are both non-lethal and in any event
they are unloaded and I'm not the only
one who has verified that we had CHS up
here and we're all clear that's just I
feel it's appropriate to mention that to
you before you guys see any gear all of
the following things count in one way or
another as firearms under the law
obvious well 22 less 82 lesser degrees
obviously shown up in orange proper
lethal firearms completely count any
type you can think of if it's legal for
you to have it where you're going it
counts as a firearm you declare it flare
guns this is a you know German gecko
flare pistol beautifully made very cheap
it's about 25 bucks 30 bucks that expels
a projectile by means of a combustible
propellant under every sense of the word
under federal law it is a firearm it is
not a licensable thought you don't have
to have any paperwork for it in all 50
states you can still commit a crime and
be charged with a gun crime if you try
to brandish or threaten someone it's a
firearm under federal law that works
wonderfully if you ever think you're
traveling somewhere that's not gonna end
Lee starter pistols blank pistols and
theatrical weapons this is a theater
prop now it looks unbelievably real
that's because it does take a mo not
live ammo take blank ammo that
completely counts skirting the issue a
little bit would be replicas and the
like similar to the other one this is
not going to fire anything but a baggage
handler is not going to you no question
that if you say I'm checking this as a
fire I don't know if that's skirting the
law a bit but I mean I use it when I
need to and I don't want to take another
piece of actual steel with someone you
know treat an airsoft or a plastic
training blue gun as I don't think they
would I would not be surprised if you
were told by someone oh I need I need to
have this declared so be on the safe
side try to declare it be prepared
someone might tell you yeah you don't
have to sorry oh and you can't put this
lock on there no sorry gun parts and
hardware you guys know that the
Seaver itself the serialized receiver is
the firearm for purposes of FFL transfer
and I would never take you know even a
stripped receiver try to take it to a
secure sterile area of an airport it has
to be in your checked bag and if I was
transporting one I would probably
declare it not because i'm expecting to
leverage the law in my favor I might get
someone looking at me funny but I would
just feel more comfortable declaring it
because I think that's the right thing
to do I have if you want to listen to it
on the website or we could play it later
I'm sorry go ahead you said yeah in the
case of the receiver what I want to
check it for I would not just to comply
but I would want to check it for all
those purposes but I would be surprised
I would not be surprised if someone said
I don't think we have to declare this
sir yes Lloyd question what about sounds
I've never thought about that because a
sound suppressor under the NFA is
legally the weapon itself I would expect
that it's a good idea to declare it just
because you are under the law you are
transporting a weapon through this air
carrier I would expect quizzical looks
and people who don't understand
treatment I don't know about other
airlines well good i know one airline I
can't remember which one I know there is
an airline that despite you despite the
fact you could fly with firearms on them
they specifically say no sound
suppression devices interesting yeah a
lot of airlines have really strange
one-off policies that don't conform I
honestly don't know how that's that's
fair and proper visiting there a common
carrier they should not be able to
interfere under the Dean of the gun
owner Act I don't think that you're
allowed to be interfered with an
interstate transportation of your own
weapons but that's a whole other spiel
speaking of other airlines I have whole
reports on my site which I'll get into
about how every airline measures up I
think I even added that slide at the end
here if you just want to be double sure
i have a whole phone call by the way
with the TSA talking about flare guns
specifically and they're getting you
know you can hear who I talk to you can
hear her quote the rules and she's
saying oh absolutely flare guns blank
guns their apps
lutely firearms because I've had other
TSA people say no and I'm like dude call
this number and Cedeno speaks in Nancy
she'll tell you but yeah I mean that's
all up on the website too oh yeah how do
the carriers rate how do they all stack
up well you can read in much greater
detail on the packing site how I came to
these determinations ultimately i said
here's the federal standard consider you
know hardcase 11 pounds of ammo blah
blah blah how do airlines deviate from
that what it what extra policies do they
have sometimes they will have what I'll
consider idiot packing policies where
they don't let you put an infinite
number of firearms in one piece of
luggage they'll say oh you can only have
three long guns or five handguns it's
designed to make you use more bags and
pay extra bag fees it's very
transparently retarded sometimes they
are fussy about ammo whether it can be
in the same case or not the federal law
has no problem with it some airlines do
some don't like if your ammo is in
anything other than the original box all
of this is in great great detail where I
break it all down on the site in fact do
I have a little no I don't have a little
oh well and literally like I'll just
point some of the really horrible ones
why do some people have season
especially DS Northwest Airlines
actually recommends on their site and
customer care line the use of TSA
approved search alert locks even though
this is illegal under federal law they
not only do they dissuade you actively
multiple times in their text from
bringing weapons they say that they will
not allow any insurance coverage the
purchasing of new insurance and their
existing insurance does not cover any
firearms they are they're just one of
the most anti-gun airlines I've ever
seen and I was sorry they are cheap yes
well you know Southwest is pretty damn
cheap and Southwest is up there in the
eighth column now individual experience
is a different matter everyone can
report the occasional boneheaded staffer
but this is just about how their
policies as a whole rate one last little
tip it is possible sometimes people ask
me like do doesn't this add a lot of
hassle doesn't it delay you I'm like
well I always get to the airport really
responsibly early but and sometimes I
skip past people when i'm checking
weapons why because if you walk up and
you let's say grab a skycap you say hey
man I'm can I do these bags here and all
here
throw five dollars at him and he's
putting him on his car he's like oh by
the way I'm flying with firearms today I
don't think I can curb check these and
the skycap all the time for me anyways
like oh yeah you can't but here come on
in and they'll just lead me in past long
rows of people because they all know you
know the checking agents they all work
together and they smoke together no but
hey you know you Sylvia can you come
over here and help this man out he's
traveling with firearms today and the
guys like sticking around he wants to
see what I'm traveling with and ask him
to stick around because they know you
have to get to that secondary area and
they'll be the ones who will help you
get to get your stuff over there don't
count on that secondary area ever being
as convenient as you think especially
certain airports that have grown too
fast and didn't plan what LAX is a mess
newark and some other places the
secondary areas you know kind of around
the corner they'll try to get people who
are like okay unlock these and we'll
take him in this room and I said eyes or
you could just go ahead and take him in
the room you know according to the law
and if there's a problem I will come
open them well I don't think we can do
that I said why don't you cross that
bridge when we get to it send it through
the rapids game machine you'll tell me
if this is all moot anyway and they come
in oh yeah you were fine sir I've had
international travel where there simply
is no secondary area they're not set up
for it and if you believe this this was
in Newark as well I was called at the
gate I was paged I said yeah what do you
need I'm flying today this is a mess
traveler I said oh we needed to get in
one of your bags I said oh to the scans
yeah well we see you're traveling with
firearms can we need to get in one said
okay where you want me to go I was like
well the bag is way down in the thing
can you have your key like no and I had
to go back at I had to get a supervisor
and another supervisor and in the end
and this is not the I'm not feeling this
has happened to they brought the bag to
the gate and they opened it you know
like right around that little jetway
corner I'm sitting there I'm like okay
firearms out they're not allowed to
touch your firearms when the TSA in
specs things they will be no they'll
have two other just stay away from it'll
to say can you put that aside for a
second and they went through and they
said oh okay you're taking all these
locks what are all these handcuffs for
you know I get that a lot handcuffs are
I don't have it on the sheet but
handcuffs are legal there's a story of
someone who was arrested at an airport
for outstanding warrants it's on the TSA
his website and the article goes on to
say he was carrying all these other
things handcuffs at no time did anything
mr. Smith possessed was illegal simply
he was arrested on a warrant charge so
you're allowed to have handcuffs
anywhere you want in the airport's
apparently even though I get yelled at
for that and now I just don't even blink
I'm like other for rough sex I don't
even try to you know I just make up
fucking answers I don't even say I'm
going to a security Khan and I'm
teaching this you know gringo game so
that shuts them up pretty fast but yeah
literally you can skip ahead you can do
a lot of things this is not not hard at
all and it's not expensive yes Zack
airport dublin oh sorry and it says so
my bag gets flagged and they pull it
aside and the guy says very quietly
really do you have GF handcuffs in here
and I'm like no I think I know what
you're looking for and he certainly
thought I was having handcuffs for read
for a bit of vegetable absolutely but
but yeah and the ebc was absolutely fine
about it but Betty they saw it they're
like holy crap that looks like hiding
elves and I go flag immediately mm-hmm a
good thing that you got through the
question that becomes why didn't you
have handcuffs for pleasure purposes if
you were travelling to someplace need to
check Creek
I sometimes get asked just because all
the time we're at the village you know
Oh what locks to the best locks out
there we know we don't work for any of
these companies but i'll give you the
real quick rundown it's possible to get
incredibly good security in the sense of
unpickable practically and in some cases
almost uncut abul security within a
budget if you don't worry and most
people shouldn't worry at least of you
know bolt cutters on your bags if you
don't think someone's going to be
breaking into your bags that little
abloy executive model it's a full
protect core if you've been in the
village you know we're talking about
with the hablo a rotating disk it's a
pro tech padlock key retaining lock it's
a boron reinforce shackle so cutting and
even you know bolt cutting is going to
be damn hard in a small lightweight
package when I travel with the Pelican
cases for all my long guns that's just
what I throw on there you can get the
little discus lock the 2020 70 i love
the abloy puck it's a pro tech core in
just an insane freaking package for not
serious serious money and also i love
that it doesn't look like a lock the
other locks they're a little higher end
but they clearly look like locks and
someone asked me once isn't that a risk
in the airport like the bag throwers say
oh there's something good in here it's a
valid concern you know I'm not going to
say that there aren't some malicious
people out there working in in bag
transport and I'm not going to say that
their interest doesn't get peaked when
they see a lock if it's a serious lock
on a serious case that's enough to
dissuade them but I like that this you
know once it's on there just kind of
looks like a weird clasp or something as
far as luggage tight luggage on a budget
if you're curious what this is that I'm
traveling around with all the time it's
really effective it's a used mortar
round case these are unbelievably
available they are cheap their rugged is
all sin they're a little heavy this is
about 20 pounds empty so I mean I'm
really limited to 30 pounds of gear and
I'm on the bubble all the time they
don't have a nice heavy hasp so I throw
one on from home depot well door you
know spot tuck this the screws in place
but that is a fifteen dollar case you
can get a ton of them for however much
gear you have so for no money seriously
psycho luggage and for no real hassle
seriously ironclad security with proper
padlocks easy easy to do thank you so
much i'll talk to you have questions
there are a few people I should
specifically thank Datagram and and
scorch you guys are seriously awesome
the village the village how many people
came to the village right on I had a
blast they let me kind of show up and do
my gringo thing and those guys really
really rocked you too you are my sanity
this conference so very much thank you
guys and way to go against ep 4 drop
picking me up at the airport and that
whole bit of drama and especially the
noid evil and everyone at layer 14 for
having us all out including me it was a
real pleasure to be here so thank you
and any questions um is just carrying a
single firearm enough to lock all your
cases or you hard one per case the
question is well I mean you had this mic
so you guys heard them no you can't lock
cases if there are no firearms in them
so one okay but you're not required to
put all your guns in one case I had that
quite once I showed up with four of
these fuckers and I had a one pistol in
each one and the woman was like you know
it would be less work and you wouldn't
have to fill out all these forms if you
put them all in one case I was like oh I
see what you're doing there I never
thought of that wink wink um maybe next
time I'll do that lady but that would be
smart no you can't you can't lock
without the firearm but there's there's
literally like you can have a 22 caliber
derringer you can a little pocket gun it
does it counts you can have a shitty
flare gun it counts yes annoyed black
powder the weapon is legal I gotta get
out of that habit you shouldn't call
something a weapon unless you're using
it defensively the firearm is legal but
the propellant is not in any
circumstance you're allowed to transport
moderns cased ammo with smokeless
propellant you can't transport loose
powder which would include loose black
powder under any certain I'm aware of
mm-hmm
I would imagine you should I think well
depends if it's vintage cuz you guys
don't know if you know anything
manufactured pre 1899 pre
turn-of-the-century is not legally a
firearm under federal law so you can
transfer it without you know an FFL
involved I think for just simply not
having your bag disturbed somewhere in
the airport if it pops on a scan and for
the benefit of like why the fuck not why
wouldn't you want to lock it I would say
yes but you could get some guy trying to
say oh I don't know about that I have to
talk to somebody I would imagine mm-hmm
they expel a projectile yeah mm-hmm so I
think that would be the standard that
would open air lines are skitterish they
want to limit their sphere of liability
they want you to comply with this
declaration as much as that Kendall do
one and two do you have anything to say
about Pelican cases I mean I understand
that you have your ironclad bulletproof
mortar round case which is awesome it's
probably kind of a pain in the ass
logistically it is um I worked for a
company for a while that did training
was a fair isaac actually and to train
for example discover when we went to
discovers campus in chicago we had these
giant fuck off four foot across pelican
monster cases that we put some machines
in that was like eight inches of foam on
each side where i know they make those
things smaller oh yeah pelicans
wonderful i use them for my long arms
the 1700 series of rifle case for almost
the main reason besides the fact that
they're light and crush proof and all
that pelicans warranty it's like the
surefire warranty it's like we don't
care what you fucking did send the
broken pieces that went through a lawn
mower to us and you just get a new one
so i love pelican for that reason i also
love that if you go to their site the
googles will help you they have a whole
page it's nothing but a big table of
every case model they have and every air
carrier nationally and internationally
and what's carry on what's regular
what's oversized so you can plan
everything out well that's awesome yeah
how does a price stack up against the
15-dollar mortar case they they cost
more
by 1700 the long rifle case the nicest
one it's the only one in the 1700 family
that's not oversized oh i think is about
two hundred dollars or two hundred fifty
dollars yes sir cases for less calm
awesome i'll check it out if you're
traveling with just ammunition do you
still have to lock your bag do you still
have to lock your bag I've gotten
different answers when I've specifically
called about that question some people
say yes you absolutely should other
people have told me no I've never
personally tried it again I would say
it's one of those things where if you
are just I want to bring this ammo it's
a good idea to declare and see what they
say and try to just want err on the side
of caution but don't count on it always
going to work in your favor don't use
this as you're trying to leverage the
law in your favor because you might not
get someone who's going to you know not
give you a hard time about it the other
thing i will mention as I should have
slipped this in earlier any of these
small cases like this one the CHS his
case that is a lockable case any other
cases that are lockable like they have
the little loop you know for the padlock
cut that off if you want to try it this
way I worry and I have one friend that
they did this once they said oh well you
don't have to lock that whole big bag I
see that your little your little gun
case can you can just take your padlock
and put it on that that would make life
easier and they were trying to insist
that he didn't now thankfully the path
the shackle wouldn't fit through the
loops but don't if you're really worried
about them trying to scam me because the
more people do this they're going to try
to cut down on their overhead of work
consider that don't be like oh I'm going
to lock my little case and then I'm
going to lock my big case I've seen
people they say no we have to this lock
has to come off I've seen locks cut off
the big case before so be mindful of
that they'll don't give them an out
don't give them a direction they can
send you and be like oh I'm sorry I
can't I'd like to comply but I can't yes
sir
the types of locks you can and cannot
use the reason I bring it up because
it's exactly applies to what you're
talking about with these the case that I
loaned you those are called a secure it
they're they're manufactured for like
the American firearms certification and
instructors Institute or something weird
like that but none they have a
combination lock model so if a
combination if a combination lock does
not qualify then you it's a good case
for transport and they're inexpensive
and they're small but then you'd still
have to lock your bag combination locks
do qualify the law states they must be
locked with a a lock that the law states
no one else gets the key or combination
to so that's the reason the tsa locks
are not approved because it's well known
there's a master key that everyone has
out there I would also state that if
there was a generic mass produced like
the firearm trainers kit and every one
of them has the same key for like range
safety purposes you could make the case
that wouldn't be approved for this
because then the key is universally so
well known but yeah that's the port
that's the part you can really get in
someone's face when they say we need
this and say no you don't you you don't
get the key the key never can leave my
possession same thing with a combination
you say no I know the combination I'm
not going to tell you a neat idea but
that combination thing would be you
could always claim i bought this on ebay
i don't know the combination I can't
lock the inner case if someone really
gives you static so yeah there's that
anyone else yes sir
mm-hmm you know once you're there how do
you secure your firearm with your
destination so getting to and going
beyond the airport itself there's a few
things we should definitely cover tied
to it and I'm gonna get to yours i
should mention the airlines don't know
where you live in are coming from and
the airlines don't know where you are
ultimately staying so i could fly out of
New York with weapons that are not New
York legal and it is legal to do if the
weapons are legal where I am and I have
these firearms and I'm transporting
according to the law where they're
locked and unloaded I train I get to
it's just like the law treats a common
carrier airline is another interstate
highway so the safe passage provision
applies you can show up and you say here
my firearms I'm declaring you fly and I
can fly into you know here in the
People's Republic I could land here they
don't know that I'm staying in
California they it's not their business
to know and they want to limit their
liability so the airlines won't know you
could make the case oh I'm getting in a
car and driving a defcon with these
people so I'm gonna be in Nevada it's
not gonna work for me when I you know go
to chaka khan because i'm not going to
paddle somewhere out of Hawaii if they
know I'm going to Hawaii so but um yeah
so there's there's that to consider
specifically how do I keep things these
usually I can just kind of live out of
these when I'm getting to a destination
the locks are heavy enough and I can put
a Shane or something on them and chained
him to a pipe if early want to yeah i
mean at Def Con we have so much in the
way of crazy crap in all of our rooms
that it doesn't really matter but yeah
and it safe like I don't notify hotels
or anything that no no no if you guys
ever try to do that or don't do that I
never tell them what I'm transporting is
again the law is in your favor if you
are rent you're the tenant of that room
for the night that is your dwelling
under the law and they I don't believe
are supposed to be able to restrict what
you can again have I'm not a lawyer I
don't know this for sure but yeah that's
what I do I just keep the shit lock
there anyone else no I guess that's it
we can go drink thank you
you