I
we're rolling awesome okay everybody i'm
john mccrae I run a company called learn
security online it's a computer training
company and my favorite subject is SQL
injection I'm a pen tester by trade but
SQL injection I have no idea why but for
me it's just one of those
vulnerabilities that it's not like
cross-site scripting why need to trick
somebody you know it's kind of like the
old days of hacking I kind of feel like
it's me against that server you know I'm
really got to go for it so what we're
going to cover here is dependent on the
audience will kind of determine how
technical we're going to go so generally
what I do is I cover the background for
SQL injection basic attack methods and
then I like to go into this of what the
fuck for me as a tester I run into that
all the time it's not like a classic one
equals one to get into a site anymore
it's not you know just insert this tick
and all of a sudden the whole database
drops anymore you know it's funny errors
hits store procedures like you're
injecting into a stored procedure so
that's a little bit more complex so
depending on you know kind of audience
reaction if you guys are looking at me
like you're kind of bored we'll move a
little faster if you're looking at me
like bro I have no idea what the hell is
select statement is will go a little
slower cool all right so in case anybody
hasn't you know hasn't figured it out
I'm black what I would prefer that you
do is yell stuff out at me okay you know
I grew up in a loud house you know so
really like y'all's stuff out you don't
need to raise your hand sorry I don't
have any good home training so if you're
looking at something on the slide and
you're kind of like dude that's bullshit
say it okay don't be like politically
correct with me I was uh
is it just me or did he like really not
realize I'm up here like you know
penises haha ok so for real guys you
know if we're doing going through stuff
and it's you know a little boring your
kind of hey I already know that stuff
you know kind of nod your head so I know
pick it up and keep it moving cool all
right let's do this all right every time
I submit to these talks I always do this
talk called SQL injection for mere
mortals and it never gets accepted never
no one ever wants to know the basics and
I always run into this because every
time I'm teaching SQL injection I can
usually tell people don't have good
basics they really need the SQL
injection for mere mortals but I guess
it's just not a cool sounding talk you
know what I mean so I'm not going to
teach you the basics of SQL sucks to be
you i'm not doing it i'm not going to
teach you the basics of SQL injection
starts to be you I'm not doing it
because this is advanced so if you buy
me a rum and coke tonight teach you
whatever the hell you want to learn it's
all about the alcohol okay all right
you've got three traditional classes of
SQL injection you've got in band out of
band inferential I'm sure you guys are
good you can read the slides so in band
data is extracted using the same channel
that's used to inject out of band data
is retrieved using some sort of other
channel like DNS or HTTP you know the
sweet sexy stuff you know and then
inferential is you know either asking
questions that are true false questions
or based on time you know you're like
hey dude database if you're really the
system administrator can you wait 10
seconds before you give me a valid page
okay all right so let's look at this in
band injection like I said it comes over
the same channel this is classic you
know ID equals 1 or 1 equals and then
you're going to say convert aunt user
and then you'll actually get an error
saying syntax error converting the in
bar chart value Joe into a column of
data type int so essentially you're
asking the database hey can you take
this user and convert it to a data type
of integer and the database is going to
be like do you can't convert a string
into an integer the hell are you doing
bro
okay bye when it does that it actually
execute that query for you and you'll
get the result of that user query in the
error okay this is the most classic its
traditional and this is actually going
away all right out of band okay
everybody likes the sexy stuff okay I'm
doing SQL injection i'm getting all my
responses back over dns right it just
sounds cool don't it you know not like
there's really a real point in life to
actually do it but it sounds cool don't
it you like dude I was I was owning your
box and you know while I'm while I'm
pulling all the credit card data off
your database I got it all back over my
dns server dude you suck riot okay there
are some extreme cases where this is
actually necessary but generally when my
pen testing I haven't found where I
really had to use a lot of out of band
stuff it does work it is sexy there are
cases where you can actually get more
data you know per query via out of band
that's been generally be the only time
that I've really kind of felt like I
needed to do it okay all right
inferential inferential is what you're
starting to see a lot tools like SQL map
SQL ninja tools that essentially ask the
database a question so in this case this
is time-based SQL injection so you're
seeing that it's going to say if not
select system user is sa wait for 10
seconds so now what happens is you don't
get error messages you know there is no
ODB series odbc error you're not getting
an error message so you're asking the
database hey bro if you're running a
system administrator wait 10 seconds
before you show me the page okay so I
run into this or a lot of people have
we're both air is turned off and this is
the generally the attack technique I use
the most in those cases all right what
about tools scanner monkeys in a room
anybody who he's like who's like I'm a
consultant I run tools right I was I was
on a call with a customer one time and I
swear it was like well you know we're
really looking at higher in a pen tester
but you know we use backtrack
also that you're fucking scammer monkey
so that means you're a good pen tester
right awesome I get that all right so
let's look at the base of tools now I'm
sure the some of you guys have awesome
security budgets I don't so I only use
these open source tools so i can't even
say that but Mellie oak you know hope
work with me man I don't know what it is
but roll off from sins Post wrote that
one ok now you noticing that that one
does arrow based that's one type of SQL
injection w poison it's another tool it
does air-based SQL map most of us are
familiar with SQL map it does blind
true/false blind and union base if you
specify now what pity does air-based w
3f does era based and blind perros does
air-based and blind SQ ID only does
error does anybody kind of figured this
out what am i shooting for here come on
work with me people we all get a little
louder okay error based almost everybody
uses air based very few tools and in
this particular point in time no tool
does all three methods of SQL injection
so like the slut like the thing says Joe
I'm sick of this shit what the hell do
you mean by era based blind and union
okay so just like we said era base
you're attacking the database and it
actually causes an error Union base
you're actually a pending another select
statement to the URL so it says ID
equals 5 and the URL you're going to say
ID equals 5 space Union all you're going
to join a select statement from the
website to your own select statement and
now you can extract data that way and
then blind we already talked about that
extracting data be a true false or
time-based SQL injection click things
that are important for me my methodology
how do i do it first thing for me
identify the injection either
tool or manual key thing is you need to
identify the injection then you need to
determine the injection type is it ID
equals 5 you know page equals feedback
okay in other words is what's actually
being requested a string or an integer
and this is really important because if
it's a string you need to use a tick if
it's an integer you don't need to use a
tick super super important especially
when we get later into this talk and we
start talking about IDs evasion and
laughs evasion this is really really big
the next thing is how do i actually do
my attacks I always go for error based
first always go for air base first it's
the fastest okay it's the easiest if
that doesn't work and i can't get
verbose errors then I try for Union and
if that doesn't work last case worst
case last resort then i use blind you're
going to find that blind is so ungodly
slow it you know you're pulling data out
of the database one bit at a time i mean
literally huh and noisy yeah but i mean
does it really matter what admin do you
know really looks at his logs grown up
okay so why the focus on manual testing
so now that you understand that there's
three primary types of SQL injection can
you understand why being able to test
for SQL injection manually is so
important most scanners only look for
one type of injection all right so we're
going to stop here everybody with me so
far going too fast going too slow what
good case all right just like I can do
this man all right so let's jump on to
the next thing integer based SQL
injection integer base do i need the
tick no string based yes so when you're
looking this you immediately need to
figure out is it asking for a string or
an integer and if it's asking for a
string that's when I need my tick all
right we're going to jump on ms SQL
syntax the syntax / database is a little
bit different but once you kind of get
the
all for one it's really not that hard to
transition to the next type yeah we'll
cover a real little bit of MySQL if you
want to talk about oracle syntax and all
that kind of stuff hit me up after the
talk I'll fill you in show you all the
good places to get that kind of stuff
all right so air-based we've already
talked talked about I'd like to give
people this because this is really good
for extracting data what are the key
things you want to ask for who's the
user what's the database name what's the
server name what version is it running
these are great things okay and these
are my my little generic ones that kind
of just go right through them okay
generally what I find in pen testing is
when I look at the previous year's
report a lot of people will stop at just
showing that there's an SQL error like
I'll see look there's an odbc error okay
now for me is that kind of a punk kind
of move why is it apart kind of move
come on you're not actually proving it
okay the other thing that I've run into
is guys will say well you can generate
the air but it's not injectable Yeah
right bro yeah right bro that's kind of
like a girl who says well I don't
usually do this right you're kind of
like yeah whatever man come on okay all
right so union based SQL injection this
is what I was talking about where you're
adding the Union select statements to it
so the first thing I'll do is I'll try
for error based if air base doesn't work
I try for a union if i add union all
select there's actually a typo there
yeah that's right so union select all
one and then i should get an error the
same hey bro you have to have the
correct number of columns if you're
going to do a select statement there you
go oh ok cool so I just keep adding
Union all one two three until I finally
get no error message want to finally get
a ballot page now I know that I have the
correct number of columns and then all
of the specific functions user DB name
version and all that now I can put those
in okay blind blind takes forever this
is why we don't do it unless we
absolutely have
no choice so you asked the database hey
database if the user length is equal to
1 can you wait 10 seconds now it comes
back immediately ok well usually length
is in equal to 1 ok hey database if the
database user length is equal to 2 can
you wait 10 seconds sometimes starting
to see that this is taking a while what
if you have to like dump a database with
like three million records yeah yeah
awesome yeah so in these cases this is
why I try not to do blind cuz it takes
so freaking long but if you do you have
no choice or than great go for blind ok
all right you always need to break out
your handy-dandy hex ascii decimal chart
you're going to need this a lot ok
encoding is going to be huge with the
web stuff you always want to keep this
kind of chart handy I'm a geek don't get
me wrong ok but I don't have this stuff
memorized sorry ok ya ever like talk to
somebody and they're like oh yeah you
know it's a but that's not me so I have
a chart better yet have a mouse pad ok
so blind SQL injection where you're
extracting the user so you're saying hey
if the first letter of the character for
user is an a can you wait 10 seconds now
how long will this take guys is you're
going to be like is it ma is it a B is
it a see is it a d now here in D it
comes back after 10 seconds this is
taking a while this sucks ok all right
and then we immediately try the second
character ok is it an a is it a B is it
oh god this sucks ok all right and we
alway get down to what's an Oso now they
know now we know that the database user
is DB oh man that really sucked didn't
it ok this sucks alright so my SQL
syntax I'm going to kind of skip through
some of this I won't dig real deep into
this but generally with mysql there is
error based but most of the times you're
going to find that you're going
have to use Union and blind with MySQL
so let's jump on it all right key things
that you're going to need to know with
blind you're going to need to know the
number of tables excuse any number of
columns column names path to the website
a lot of times you have to guess table
names attacking mysql kind of sucks yeah
nowhere near as much fun as the tacky
and ms SQL alright so one of the things
that i really like to use is the order
by operator so i'll say ID equals 1
order by 10 and then if it gives me the
error message unknown column Tim and
order by Clause then I know ok it's less
than 10 columns so now have it so I'll
say order by five and now it returns a
valid page so now I know it's more than
five columns but less than what I'm glad
you guys are listening way to go ok so
you keep doing this until you figure out
how many columns you have and this works
for ms SQL as well all right now once
you actually come up with the correct
number of columns now you have to try
and figure out how we can get this
database to tell us what is the column
number we're going to use to pull data
out of it so generally what I do is I'll
change that ID to a negative number or
the word null now doing that causes the
rest of the columns to try to display so
usually what happens is you'll get some
numbers in the middle of the screen just
looks crazy you got a blank page with
like a five and a two in the middle of
the screen it kind of like okay this is
on this website is about to get the beat
down so this is an example of a website
and you see that i put the null in there
and it comes back and it tells me six
and three like ok so in column number
three do you see how I put user and then
column number six you see how I put
version and now the data displays right
to the middle of the screen so MySQL
version 50 45 and the user is WS user at
localhost ok so now you're proving that
you can extract
data from it okay and then the key
things that I like to use with mysql i
like to use user I like to use database
version and data derp whats the
directory with all the actual my SQL
files are stored okay good good good
good good okay um quick little tidbit
when you're using database and DB
underscore name with the parentheses if
you actually change that I should have
put that on the slide but I did it if
you actually put a 0 in the parentheses
that will give you the first database
and you can change it to a one you can
get the next database you can change it
to a two and you can keep iterating
through all of the databases on the box
i really should have put that on the
slides bat speaker ok so we've already
got this how do we get the user how do
we get the server name ok oh there it is
it is in the slides cock awesome I'm a
good speaker sure
they have to get less real
you are getting the user name of the
database user that's currently accessing
the database from the website right that
user needs to be able to determine that
these other databases are on the box
right so you'll have cases where you can
see okay there's 40 databases on this
box I can only access two of them I run
into that a lot but again proving to a
customer that you really can extract
data and the other thing that you can do
and we'll talk about this a couple of
slides later is you can brute force the
essay account so all via SQL injection
you can group force the essay account so
let's say I can enumerate 15 databases
and I'm running as user Joe instead of
user essay or dbo I'll just brute force
the database crack out a good 12 million
where dictionary remember admins don't
look at logs and you know go for it ok
so the Union we already talked about
changing it to a null we already talked
about okay and this is the true false
blind this is actually the method that
SQL map uses okay now you have to keep
it this in mind SQL map is making the
determination by same if one equals one
I get a valid page if one equals two I
get some sort of error page or invalid
page so this is why you'll run into
cases where you can trigger some sort of
error and then you do your one equals
one your one equals two and you get the
same page so now SQL map tells you it's
not injectable does that suck yes that
sucks okay all right the blind
time-based blind i use the wait for
delay method okay and you're going to
notice how you can ask it what version
you're running if you're running this
essay or if the current user is a member
of the sysadmin group okay good things
you can do okay all right SQL injection
in the real world who's been testing now
who's running into SQL injection does it
suck you're like
dude you know I'm trying to pull out
this error and it keeps giving me funky
errors anybody deal with that all right
so all right late at night I'm drinking
rum and coke when I'm contesting this is
me okay am you know I listen to youtube
and watch a lot of music and all that
kind of stuff but you know I get bigger
I don't care if you don't care if you
judge me I get better is it just me or
is it kind of jacked up that Little John
makes millions of dollars a year and the
guy only has a vocabulary of like two
words does that bother anybody like I'm
like pin testing banks and like breaking
into a multi-billion dollar systems and
all that kind of junk and I'm like dude
I'm not making that kind of money oh my
god so I'm a shirt and tie kind of guy
you know don't let the con thing for you
you know all day I'm the time suited up
you know sooty booty right so should I
trade in all that crap you know for a
mouthful of gold teeth some dreads baggy
pants 40 ounce and a fat blunt that's my
boy haha good what the fuck right I run
into this okay so in a little bitter so
we're going to own Little John com so
we've got Little John you know calm /
Lil Jon dot ASP okay the parameter
passing is little equals and we're going
to insert our tick so we get our
Microsoft lle DB error alright cool so
now I'm ready to go do my thing go
distract the data and all this kind of
stuff so I say okay convert int user
exactly what I taught you guys right and
then it gives you a really weird error
incorrect syntax near right parent is it
just me or our code is smoking crack
what the hell is up with that and I'm
not lying I think I must have spent
three days on this i'm reading the msdn
and all that news I actually had to sit
down and read micro shaft documentation
yeah you're like good god what is going
on with this so I don't know you know
what screw it I'm gonna put an extra
right parenthesis in it and it
work shoot three freakin days and that's
all it was like my god so it's stuff
like that where you might actually have
a tool that determines that it's
vulnerable but can extract data because
it doesn't realize that you actually
need an extra right parenthesis and this
is why you'll have pen testers who tell
you well you there's no need to fix that
vulnerability it's not really
exploitable right they just don't they
actually have a life they're not liking
me okay I will sit here all night with
my rum and coke and I will try to figure
this out right all right next one all
right so I'm trying to get the database
name and let's work in try to get the
version and it's working okay its
database enumerated yeah state-based
enumerated yeah this was a lot more
funny when I was drinking ok next one I
run into PHP so I'll pull it out data
just like I showed you guys right union
all select percent time twentieths of
space for those of you who don't know
okay but everybody knows they like do it
if I can know that okay fine smarty
pants okay so union i'll select one
union all select 12 then i get this
error text or in text or image data type
cannot be selected as distinctive
anybody else back there like dude I
don't know exactly man coders coders
need help bro coders need help so you
know this is when google translator
comes in helped it helpful because i
found some guy who was running into the
same thing on a chinese website so
translate it dude was like yeah if you
just do this text hello it'll let you
keep a numerate in the database I'm like
okay that makes a whole lot of freakin
sense okay all right so let's keep on
doing that right okay so now I'm doing
the same thing and doing the same thing
I get down to eight nine and it tells me
Oh operand type clash
okay text is incompatible with int this
sucks well I tried my hello thing I
didn't work okay you were like working
on something you like oh I got this a
shit that doesn't work okay so I threw
in the word null and it worked okay so
key tips always use union with all
because of images and had to realize
that when they're talking about in text
its cases where they have like actual
images in the database like thumbnails
okay you're like oh dude okay I get it
all right so use null in Union
injections for most data types instead
of trying to guess as a string is it you
know data is an integer is in text and
all that just grow null in there and
that usually works a lot you'll notice
what SQL map actually test for union
based on SQL injection it just says
Union no no no no no no so that it can
try to get by these types of errors
until you run into that you know text in
text image stuff all right privilege
escalation okay anybody read
Litchfield's work let's fail at this
dude is a freakin genius litchfield is
sick I can't believe this so he figures
out that this open rowset SQL oledb you
can actually make a connection to the
database and specify a username and
password to see if it allows you to
connect to it okay so now we use this to
determine if we can brute force we just
get our dictionary and we keep
substituting that password so you see
I'll have Joe all caps Joe lowercase Joe
with the zero and this is literally how
you brute force you just keep
iteratively asking it oh hey I'm trying
to make a connection to the database I'm
trying to connect as user SI with this
password okay Davis is like no that's
not it hey I'm trying to make a
connection to the database ssay with
this password okay and you just keep
iterating through it and can it's how
you brute force the essay account
alright next thing is now that you found
the correct username for the essay
account now you can use exact command
so you do the same thing with open row
set and you say okay exact master SP ad
server role member sa and you take the
current user and add them to the
sysadmin screwed okay sweet okay all
right password right so correct password
you can specify it right here specify
the password
dude you rock i wish i was like dan
kaminsky give you beer that good
explanation awesome okay oh sure sure
sure sure sure okay so whenever you
authenticate to the database you're
going in as si once you get the password
you authenticate to it you run the
stored procedure as Joe and then you you
add the current website account into the
sysadmin group you think I like that and
kind of wondering about you bro okay all
right so how do we do this in ms SQL so
you do the exact same thing and you add
that user okay or you're going to find
that it's a little bit different in 2005
vs 2000 so the next slide kind of breaks
it out a little bit more alright so
you're going to declare this variable
result declare Oh L ER and you're going
to throw in this shell right and then
we're going to execute this w script do
to do to do to do okay now select this
result and we're going to raise this
user and we're going to execute this
method and see if as si it can ping 127
dot 0 to 0 dot one with a count of eight
so now the reason that we're doing this
is because we want to see if we can ping
ourselves then we're running as SA and
then if it takes eight seconds for the
page to come back we know that it
executed the ping I wrote it with me you
guys rock okay all right so syntax and
SQL server 2005 is a little bit
different okay so you just say SP
configure show Advanced Options
reconfigure exact master
it's really all it is all right filter
evasion okay this stuff really isn't
quite so black and white okay when
you're dealing with filters you you
really kind of go with your gut you just
kind of keep messing with it until you
see that you bypass the filter okay so
the first one is client-side filtering
this is some coder idiot who's decided
that it would be a great idea to filter
our database in kill our database input
with JavaScript that's going to display
on the local page this makes a lot of
sense right this makes a lot of sense so
because Java scripts rendered on the
local browser the attacker has access to
all of the filtering that you're trying
to do right like does that pass the
common sense test no okay so this is
easy you can save the page locally
remove the offending javascript or
vbscript you can use a local proxy like
perros web scarab burp suite any of
these kinds of tools they find this type
of stuff okay next thing restrictive
blacklist sometimes you see coders who
think that they're going to stop SQL
injection what's saying you know what
I'm going to use a filter you're not
going to use things like less than
greater than you're not going to use tix
you're not going to do any of that stuff
ok guys so which type of SQL injection
requires the tick string-based so if
they're asking for an integer we don't
need the tick right okay so that filter
work great huh the next thing is instead
of saying one equals one because they're
not going to let us use an equal sign
well is one kind of like 12 kind of like
two awesome bypass that filter okay
signature-based IDs guys I hate IDS's I
hate ipss I was an IDs analyst for a
couple of years so my hatred is
justified okay all right so break out
your chart let's do this okay so you
grab yourself your first snorts
signature everybody community north sig
alright so alert TCP any IP address any
port number going to our web servers on
our web server ports that has tick or
one equals one that's a great freaking
signature isn't it how do we bypass that
guy's different numbers is eight like a
right is nine like nine okay so what if
it's integer base do we even need the
tick so the whole signature fails okay
all right so why do we have these
signatures this is catchy idiots that
that's exactly what I used to say when i
was in ids guy i would say we only catch
idiots we catch people who deserve to be
caught we catch people who don't know
where logs are stored on our is server
we catch people who don't know how to
you know that the tftp a file down then
I have these zero byte tftp files in the
root directory you know we catch idiots
we catch people who deserve it's like a
Darwinian kind of thing like we got to
get them off the planet dude okay all
right yes this is my opinion of IDs okay
guys like I got one yes I got an
attacker all right so now we got a
little bit more complex of an IDs
signature okay i'm gonna use pcre
perl-compatible regular expressions baby
okay don't mess with the regex right
this is when you like breaking out your
real kung fu huh so we're looking for
the word and or the word or and we're
looking for one equals one and we're not
even going to let you use those comments
see the dash dash can't use those or the
slash asterisk can't use those okay so
how do we bypass this one ideas
signature suck don't pay okay so you're
seeing the two equals two % 2d is how we
equate to the dash yeah is this looking
for hex no it is not okay so now if you
have open source tools like SQL map and
all these types of tools you can
actually go in and just change this
in your tool so that it uses 9 equals 9
+ % 2d instead of the hyphen okay and
that's how you get my ID SS ok learn
something uh snort normalizes the
traffic this is correct this is correct
snort normalizes the traffic ok but what
you can do is you can use things like
you tf7 utf-8 utf-16 is a lot of people
don't have that type of thing turned on
because it's too processor intensive all
right a little bit more complex of a
rule ok so now we've got to select from
we've got the dashes ok how do we beat
this what's my bypass technique I
converted the whole thing to hex so now
we look at the next one here's the Union
all we just converted the entire thing
to hex yeah next one you know a
lowercase s and an up go ahead where do
you give a stuff like that from the
get-go yeah Gary O'Leary has a unicode
encrypting tool it's like a couple
slides down you'll see what I have for
it yeah ok so also there's a ton of
websites you know ascii convert and all
that kind of stuff you know those are
good websites for that sort of thing ok
so are you guys noticing that the S or
presents 973 and signature six is the
lowercase s and the lowercase e and if
you look down in signature seven he's
got the lowercase s % 73 and percents
I'm 53 for the lowercase s and the
capital s ok so these are really really
good so how do we bypass that use a
different encoding type ok all right so
what I like to say about this IDs
evasion is pretty easy just ask Joe to
teach you how ok and it's just a whole
bunch of encoding its comment injection
where I've inserted comments in there ok
a lot of that stuff works now for those
of you who play with web application
firewalls this type of technology is
getting a lot better because they have
things with a compressed white space
they normalize traffic laughs are
lot tougher okay all right so this kind
of takes us to the next step how do i
how do we identify web application
firewalls web application firewalls and
my experience have been surprisingly
easy to find over determining if there's
an IDs or IPS solution in place so what
application firewalls they're all kinds
of quick to tell you dude imma laugh
don't do that yeah so our same
characters you know single tick quotes
less than ? you know that kind of stuff
a laugh will identify itself immediately
okay so here's an example of me throwing
a get request with curl reppin for 501
so when you get 50 one method not
implemented that's modsecurity okay so
boom figured that one out so if you
throw a tick and in the HTTP header you
see no hacking okay that's web night
okay told you like really stealthy huh
okay all right ah that page wasn't
supposed to be gone all right this is
Gary O'Leary's tool okay so it's got the
unit code and you can see how I just
throw like a script alert and it
automatically converts it for me this is
great for ids deviation okay so you can
take all of your different signatures
another website that i don't have in my
slides is PHP ID s they have a demo tool
where you can try all of your injections
and cross site scripting and they will
let you know what reg exes it's actually
detecting or bypassing or whatever the
case may be okay so here when you get
stuff like this it's an error code 200
but the actual message says condition
intercepted so in this case it's trying
to throw off automated scanners because
when it does something it gets an error
code 200 instead of some sort of oh oh e
oh D oh D be Ciera right table.chat you
can actually see that it's just giving
back two hundred okays okay no this
wasn't all right so dotnet defender
dotnet defender is what I ran into as a
laugh and my my most recent
Bank pen test and I never heard of
dotnet defender before this so if we're
getting this on tape you know hey sorry
i haven't notified the vendor so i was
looking at this and you know they give
you the big nasty gram see that look
dotnet defender block this you suck I
was kind of like okay I guess I suck
okay blot my request lo and behold
bypassing dotnet defender really wasn't
all that hard dotnet defender is looking
for the tick for its SQL injection
checks oh that's great awesome yep you
rock yeah buddy so there's me and
conveniently this 16 billion dollar
financial institution has its database
running as user DB oh it just doesn't
get any better like you can't make this
stuff up I mean really you can't make
this stuff up so you know little dot net
defender thing it's gone now I'm not
seeing hearing anymore so I said hey
remember that user thing I showed you
guys how to do now if you're noticing
you can't really see it but I had to use
that Gary O'Leary unicode encoding thing
to make it do this because when I just
put in regular select statements it
would catch that so I'd use the Unicode
encoding thing that I showed you a few
slides back okay and then did a select
version and he says yeah dude I'm
running SQL server 2005 okay I'm running
on a box that's server 2003 gives it up
like a cheap two-dollar ho right just
like too easy here you go take it take
it you want me turn around to listen
takes it okay all right then after that
I was like you know what hey while I'm
here let's grab the admin hashes yeah
yeah love dotnet defender all right and
that is my talk guys give you some basic
references for SQL injection some
tutorials pin test monkey he has the
best SQL injection cheat sheets his
cheat sheets rock okay and that is my
talk I will take questions now any
questions what
ma'am not very familiar with some of
this stuff could you that's okay I mean
like on the app see like the web
application firewall letter like IPS
like snort coupe do you put a definition
in their first inning okay don't let any
traffic through this says something like
Microsoft oledb air or something as an
outbound filter right yeah right but the
issue is that's only going to tech error
based SQL injection so what about union
based and blind well you're not getting
odbc errors so that's gonna nail you so
you're right the problem is because it's
not always just that one exactly cool
thanks exactly um when you're doing the
pen test yeah how do you attack against
sites that are using prepared statements
well prepared statements and
parameterised queries usually are not
vulnerable test well injection yeah so
that is the correct way to try to stop
SQL injection but you try to impress
somebody so I eat you are you working
towards business logic errors where
you're not actually triggering an error
within the code itself but within how
the application was designed okay
business logic testing is part of any
typical web app in test this is
specifically just SQL injection so
they're not using parameterised queries
structured statements a lot of people do
try to say oh if I just use stored
procedures that's not injectable that's
not true slow procedures are generally
injectable and that's when you have to
do all these you know inserting
semicolons and adding extra statements
and all that kind of stuff so if they're
using parameterised queries like you
said prepared statements generally
you're not going to find it vulnerable
to SQL injection and then you'll find
yourself having to do more stuff like
business logic you know what have they
added a new reporting engine to the
website you'll find like funky little
things you know they've got like some
sort of Crystal Reports plugin that's
you know got parameters passed to it
maybe you can mess with that but that's
just general web app testing I don't
know if that's making any sense at all
okay okay thanks
anybody else rum and coke teacher
whatever you want yeah that's my boy
haha alright guys I hope you enjoyed the
talk if you want the slides and all that
kind of stuff you'll have to just holler
at me off offline i'll give you slides
you know you know into your whatever the
case may be that's my man right there
okay yeah I have to give him a slide
since he runs the place okay alright
guys thanks for dealing with me
you