Oh check sure well everyone welcome to
layer 1 2009 I'm Strom Carlson so I know
I'm not on the schedule to give the talk
not as well said he can we talk tomorrow
you should be giving it to us hearing
talk from Joe McCray right now but he's
stuck in he's an airline hell or
something so they asked me to give this
talk at the last minute and it's kind of
funny because there's this this this
form that they give to us when we check
in to speak and it says please check in
with registration for your talk 20 to 30
minutes prior to going on stage this
will let us know that you're in fact
around so we don't have to activate
emergency plan Omega there's a little a
subscript which says we have no idea
what emergency plan Omega actually is
we're pretty sure it's panic but
apparently it's ask Strom to give a talk
so so so I mean they kind of asked me to
give this talk at very last possible
second I had to come something real
quick so I figured that you know since
we're here in since there is this
Catholic convention next door if you're
let's do a talk on gay dating the
Catholic way
that this talk is called why your mother
will never care about linux yes sorry
yeah sure yeah sorry em make sure so
that i don't know we've got to find him
so so anyway there was my um my aunt got
me a birthday card for our birthday a
couple months ago and it was kind of
funny I open it up and the card said on
the front for your birthday I'm gonna
send you a check for ten thousand
dollars you open it up and inside it
says just as soon as my nigerian friend
that i meant on the internet sends me 10
million dollars in government funds to
deposit in london i thought was kind of
cute but yeah so this is your mother and
this is linux and this is why they're
never going to talk never going to care
about each other so just a bit of it so
as far as a why I'm doing this talk I
went through some pretty bad tech burn
out a couple about a year and a half ago
it was I've been traveling a lot I've
been doing a lot of tech work and I'd
gotten about as heavy into tech tech
stuff as I had ever my life and it got
to the point weird I just really got
sick of it so this talk is kind of my
okay why Matt burned out and how do I
fix it talk so who wants to guess what
these people are standing in line for
how did you ever guess that yeah there
are they're all standing in line for an
iphone no notice how this guy apparently
doesn't want to be seen waiting in line
for the iphone but yeah this thing right
the jesus phone was that too much of a
but yeah the iphone right what's
interesting about this is it was
announced about six months before it
went on sale and everyone started
talking about this thing like really
really really talking about it and they
were saying all these things about it
they all they had seen was one demo but
Steve Jobs gave in the keynote right
they'd never touched it they never use
it for themselves they saw a demo and
they started saying things like this is
going to be the most revolutionary
device since the year nineteen
eighty-four yeah III was I mean I this
was what January 2007 I was looking
online I remember this was what everyone
was saying there there was no you know
well let's wait and see let's see you
know what this gonna be like know
everyone was falling over themselves to
praise this thing I'm thought to myself
well okay you know this is a fairly
typical claim but fairly typical of what
people were saying right but let me let
me think about this claim for a second
you know it seems like a calculated date
because the mobile phone was introduced
1983 the the Macintosh itself was
introduced 1984 um compact discs were
from the late 70s early 80s so maybe it
is the most revolutionary device of 984
because some of the other stuff hasn't
really you know it's been evolutionary
but not revolutionary force a ring but
then I thought to myself wait a second
how do you own digital cameras right how
many of you still use film on a regular
basis right two of you the digital
camera didn't become a consumer item
until 1988 and didn't really become a
viable going concern until the beginning
of this decade right and the digital
camera the simple little device which
has now completely replaced film as a
consumer product you know feel most kind
of a specialty item and has caused the
stock price of the kodak company to go
into an irreversible tailspin since the
year 2000 so you're telling me that the
iphone that the
that the camera the digital camera which
is has killed the market for consumer
film is less revolutionary than this
dinkus right sorry at dingus yeah di ngu
s not not that rubber boat thingy but so
I mean yeah I wouldn't say this is that
revolution here I mean for God's sake
there are things that it's only able to
do now which we've kind of taken for
granted you know so let's take a look at
this right why are we so obsessed with
these toys why do we go so balls crazy
about them why do we do these things
right why are we so obsessed with all of
this gadgetry so let's look at a few
different things right we're gonna look
at Apple right and and how people seem
to think they could do no wrong we're
going to look at Microsoft and see how
some people think they can do no right
right and we're going to look at Linux
which is kind of like the cult of code
and open source right so let's start by
looking at Apple Apple is you know
company all know about there are some
people using Apple computers in this
room right now and it's interesting
because Apple is led by a guy named of
course Steve Jobs who I mean it's kind
of interesting when you study the way
that Steve Jobs and Apple are so really
really interconnected the company went
after he left the company the company
kind of started faltering and just got
worse and worse worse until he came back
and now it's just been getting better
and better and better apparently it's
not like there's a cult of personality
going on with this earth at all you know
nothing I don't see that do you but I
mean an apple does make some products
but you're useful i mean these are not
bad products people buy these things
right i own an ipod at one point owned a
mac
until it fell apart but um let's not get
into that and these aren't bad products
right but the interesting thing about it
is that people are more crazy about
apple products in general then they are
about other company products I mean
there are sort of apocryphal stories of
people just noticing that you have a
Macintosh and coming up with our
Macintosh and starting to say things
like oh don't you just love your
Macintosh isn't the most wonderful thing
ever and people are a little nuts about
this I mean didn't take long searching
online to find people crazy enough to do
things like oh I don't know make porcius
of steve jobs out of Apple icons and
product photos and so on this is a bit
obsessive is it not I've never seen any
other company's product that people will
go out and buy and then post photos
themselves not just posing with but
actually licking the boxes of on flickr
I don't know who this guy is shenanigans
right but I mean people are undeniably
bonkers about Apple for whatever reason
right and the same people who are
bonkers about Apple seem to have more
than just a little bit of dislike for
Microsoft I mean maybe if you're in the
Apple camp and you think apple is the
greatest thing since sliced bread of a
telephone right and you think Steve Jobs
is the ultimately cool maybe Microsoft
just doesn't seem quite as sexy
right maybe by comparison to the kind of
cool young hip image at apple projects
Microsoft seems kind of maybe old and a
bit fuddy-duddy you know maybe what the
hell is that noise and you know and and
then honestly there are some people who
look at Steve Ballmer and see not just
this old fuddy-duddy CEO but someone a
little more evil right and I mean this
this has been going on for years I mean
people just don't for whatever reason
this is ridiculous right you know this
is ridiculous you know this is a
complete caricature a complete
outrageous caricature of the way things
are I mean look Apple does evil things
Apple does good things Microsoft as evil
things Microsoft does good things right
they're both reasonably large companies
and I mean we know it's childish but
sometimes we do it anyway right but even
Steve Jobs said this is kind of childish
right he said we have to let go of this
notion that for Apple to win Microsoft
has to lose do you ever remember when he
said this no we had to let go of this
notion for that for Apple to win
Microsoft has to lose the era of setting
this up as a competition between Apple
and Microsoft is over as far as I'm
concerned do any of you remember when he
said this no 1997 right when Apple had
just bought next and Steve Jobs was back
in the helmet apple an apple was about
this close to no longer existing at all
all right knee said okay well this is
one of the things that's new at killing
the company this is tearing us apart
this childish stupid you know us versus
them mentality right this has to stop
this is over you know and clearly that
lasted
so now what's interesting is that there
are kind of Hugh slit eyes from
Microsoft camp right there's there's the
Apple fanboys and there are the Linux
fanboys who also seem to hate microsoft
with a passion of their open source
people right and what's interesting
about linux is you know there are
certain things that just really really
well and there are certain things that
it does really really badly right it
works great for server applications
absolutely wonderful per server
applications like our linux servers
during my web server I've got them in my
apartment I've got a file server kind of
pbx right and yet for whatever reason
linux as a desktop operating system is
still not really a going concern it's
gotten better right but it's still kind
of a bit of a joke right you know you
wouldn't really seriously use Linux at
your desktop OS in a business setting
unless all you ever did was work linux
servers right because all you would ever
really need was the terminal window
right in the really really cool-looking
terminal window and then the thing on
the side that shows you all your all
your system stats the CPUs be in the
temperature and how much RAM you got
left and whatnot right but I mean it's
not really a serious business business
desktop application right and so to kind
of see what people are saying about this
we all we have to do is go to the
world's greatest source of instant
bullshit right
and and see what people are saying right
just just do a search for linux and see
what comes up so you know some
screenshots there's just after I
converted my personal laptop over the
Linux only I found out I might have to
be traveling some for work so I just
loaded windows back right so this guy
obviously understands it's not a going
concern and then there are the people
who you know think oh my gosh linux i
can put linux on anything i can put on a
toaster i can put it on a water glass I
can run my microphone on Linux right and
like like this guy right I'm salvaging
files from a penny in 133 so I can
retire it I can't believe it still
working maybe I can resurrect mayor's
erected with Linux all right i mean it's
not even worth the electricity run that
thing anymore right my telephone for
God's sake is I think 100 times more
powerful than that machine right and
then of course you just get the people
who are very clear lessly just
hopelessly gone like I found this one
this is the guys twitter background by
the way they would put your desktop and
it's it's it's a you know and then you
look at the rest of what he says and
it's all jokes like this it's all
windows bashing yay linux jokes right i
mean nothing else the guy is got a
one-track mind right bit of the penguin
icon and yeah and this is kind of crazy
right why are we obsessing over the tool
what difference does it make what tool
we use as long as the tool allows us to
complete a job right I mean you don't go
around looking at a cab near woodwork
that someone's put together right or
something that someone's nailed to the
wall and look at the nail and say well
this is good but he only used a sears
craftsman hammer to hammer it in yeah
all right a hammer is a hammer it
hammers the nail in and as long as the
hammer does the job it's good right so
why are we so nuts about this right I I
was looking around I was just poking
around on on one day i was looking at
photos of torque on
and i came across across this one we've
all seen this right here's a san diego
convention center on twitter iron on
flickr and some looking through this and
then I thought okay you know it's a
photo and it's from torque on and
there's people commenting on it right
now you're something a little weird
about this do you know something little
worried about this well I look closer
right and on flickr there are these
things called groups where you can put
your photo in a group of similar photos
so like you know photos of cats or
photos of dogs or photos of glasses of
water or whatever your particular fancy
it's right and this one says hi i'm an
admin for a group called nikkor 55
millimeter f / 1.2 AI and we'd love to
have this added to the group because
apparently the metadata somewhere um
it's taken with a nikon camera but it
apparently the metadata somewhere tells
you what lens was used to take the photo
so the guys like hey let's create a
group only of photos taken with one
specific lens I mean come on people is
this guy out of his mind or what right
if this is exactly what we do right we
idolize the tools we say oh my god my
tool is so much better than your tool I
love this tool this tool is awesome this
tool is perfect blah blah blah blah and
we don't really pay attention to like
does the two will actually do something
useful all right it's not it's it's now
it's not a question of this is a nice
photo but it's a question of oh here's a
photo that was taken with this lens all
right it's missing the forest for the
trees it's like saying oh this car has
awesome wheels but ignoring the fact
that it can't actually go anywhere cuz
the engines broken right so where'd this
come from right why do we obsess over
things why do we obsessive over these
things and not of not pay attention to
what people do right I mean like how
many times have you have you picked up a
device or gone to the store and looked
at something that you want to buy some
some electronic toys and do Nikki and
you look at it
and you can't figure out how to do how
to use it right and you look through the
manual and it still makes no sense and
you think yourself probably an engineer
built it right and you know the engineer
like isn't the kind of person in in this
specific case who would have considered
you know how people use the tool right
it's just a matter of you know how can I
make the tool all whiz-bang and and and
happy and whatnot right so where does
this come from right what why are we so
test with the tool and not paying
attention to how people use the tool
well I've got a theory which made as a
disclaimer just be complete bullshit but
here's my theory right think back to a
long long long long long time ago to a
place called high school right how do
you remember this this this place one
person remembers high school wow you
that you're all asleep or you're all
good repressing your memories so wake up
right sorry okay well that's pretty good
right but think back to high school
right how many of you were high school
were the popular kid right accident
there we go right I wasn't I sure wasn't
right and who were the popular kids in
high school right they were the ones who
played sports right which few of us did
they were the ones who were the
cheerleaders which you of us did
they are the ones who threw you know the
really good parties right where everyone
and the everyone came to the party and
God really really wasted you know and
did really stupid things you know and
and did things and did people that they
probably regretted the next day you know
there we go right yeah CCC's now we've
got our own thing what's called def con
which is kind of our reaction to that
right but for most of us that wasn't us
right for a lot of us the way we were in
high school was more like you know this
we're geeks right we're a little
socially awkward right and yeah a lot of
us have gotten a lot better recently but
a lot of us in high school were pretty
socially inept I know I was and you know
some of us have have grown out of it
some of us haven't right but what's
interesting about this right is the way
that people respond to this in their
lives some people will say you know what
god I've got a lot of trouble dealing
with people I should spend more time
with people and learn how to how to
interact with them so that I can be more
social and have fun and have friends
right and some people but for some
people this whole social interaction
thing is way too awkward and way too
painful right so what do we do instead
of you know instead of becoming social
and doing things with other people and
learning about the world at large we
retreat retreat into our little
universes right with with the Commission
in front of us because the machine won't
make us feel bad about ourselves
alright the machine is easier to deal
with than dealing with people we can
control the machine we can program and
we can make it to exactly what we want
instead of dealing with people which are
confusing and an unknown and
unpredictable right and so we retreat
into our own little social clique and
hey here's people who are just like us
who are also socially awkward and who we
can kind of talk with things about talk
about with things that we know about
right we may not know anything about
basketball or baseball but we sure know
a hell of a lot about computers right
because you know that's all we ever
think about you know and they're there
they're kind of becomes this this the
social clicky thing we're now to be the
popular kid in in the computer click
it's not a matter of being the guy who
plays the best basketball or gets the
most girls but the guy who knows the
most programming languages or the guy
who you know knows how to configure a
gentoo box from scratch that's running
on rocks and and you know has cats
pissing on right but something
interesting it started to happen I mean
geeks and nerds have always kind of been
on the outliers of the social universe
for a while until about 15 20 years ago
right when being a geek being a computer
maniac started to become a little bit
cool
right and then 10 years ago when being a
hacker became really cool right and just
as an aside this movie is 10 years old
can we please please please stop making
red pill poop pill jokes already thank
you all right but what's interesting
about this is that this is an image
right this is a lifestyle this is a
manufactured thing right yeah it's all
cool to be the guy with leather coat who
knows how to run nmap but you know
there's a difference there is difference
between the guy between bean guy who
wrote and map and the guy who uses nmap
right there's a difference between being
the person who's known for doing things
right and making things and building
better tools versus being the guy who is
all proud of using those tools right and
I mean yeah that this is a little mean
but it's an interesting contrast right
because we know people who are known for
making tools and then the other people
might we might rise to call the tool
right but what's interesting about this
is that in many geek circles this is
seen as something to strive for right
you it's sort of like you're the cool
person if you've got the Ubuntu shirt
right you're the cool person if you go
if you went to the konig Oliver to AG
you're the cool person if you know you
know how to configure 35 different types
of web web servers right and yet we make
fun of people for listening to certain
kinds of music right or shopping at
specific stores or for buying only
specific kinds of products right and yet
it's the same thing that's going on
right we're building identity around
these things we use and these things we
consume and these things we buy rather
than building our identity around the
way we make the world better right I
mean yeah it's all fine and well to have
set up in you 100 computers for an
office right but how about being proud
that you not only set up 100 computers
for the office but that you figure out
how to make the office function more
efficiently right and rather than just
saying you know oh I set up the
computers but and I'm the kingship
because I set up all the computers and
and that's the end of that right we
build our identity identity around these
tools I mean it's the point where you
know you start talking about your
specific favorite flavor of linux and
then someone next to you who thinks
that's the most evil thing of the
universe because their flavor of linux
is better starts deciding that you are
the most evil person in existence
because you like debian and they like
gin too right this is ridiculous but we
all do it and I guess kind of the
interesting social engineering upshot of
this is that you can use it to your
advantage when you're trying to get
support for linux right because if you
go on to the channel and you say you
know hey you asked politely like the
instructions tell you to and you ask
your well research question you ask
really politely hey I'm having some
trouble with this auto configuration on
older p4 machine you would anyone mind
giving me some assistance what happens
right well that what else happens
nothing right you know you sit there for
an F for three hours and you repeat your
question every 15 minutes or so and
nothing happens but you can if you
insult the product and therefore insult
the people who use it because they built
their identity around this product right
and you rant you say yeah this is a
bunch of crap is totally fucking useless
this auto configuration will work
correctly I was p4 machine I don't know
why I'm raising my time on this garbage
this is something I actually had to do
right I was trying to get this auto
config working I had to resort to this
exact line right and then I got
responses not these actual responses but
I got responses very similar to these
yeah I mean I I made these all up but
but this is very typical of what I saw
right and it's interesting because we're
getting obsessed with tools right simple
tools complex tools but they are in fact
tools that were being obsessed over
right there just means to an end they're
not ends in and of themselves they're
not worth getting all uptight and hot
and bothered over right and yet we're
totally obsessed with these things we
are totally we live our lives based
around these goddamn machines you know
and think about it right there are
machines in all of your garages
apartments cars whatever right machines
that 10 years ago were awesome right I
was at what I was at the swap meet in
Los Angeles recently
and I was poking around and yeah you can
get all sorts of like rip off athletic
shoes and and and fruits of questionable
origin and you know leather wallets and
DVDs and so on but i found a booth where
someone was selling you know old
cordless phones and old computer
equipment i was poking around and hey
there's a palm five just gathering dust
and how many of you still use a palm
five right or any sort of Palm Pilot
right there are things which you're
gathering dust in all of our apartments
with teams of people poured hundreds of
hours of their lives thousands of hours
of their lives into building and
creating and perfecting that none of us
use anymore that are totally obsolete
that don't make a difference anymore
right yeah we learned things from them
and we've built upon them but there are
many things which was dead ends and
there are many things which debt were
dead ends that people got really really
excited about and thought were the
future right I mean I'm sure you can
think of something which people would
think of as a joke in which in
retrospect was a joke right but which
you thought was pretty cool in which you
thought was worth devoting your time and
effort to right so this whole thing is
getting ridiculous because like again
we're getting the point where we were
building things without considering the
people who are gonna have to use those
things I mean for God's sake how many
times have you tried to use some linux
tool that some linux tool wrote right
and you try and do something with it and
you can't figure out how to use it you
can't figure out the error message and
the man page is completely fucking
useless right how how many times have
you done that right i mean look if we
don't understand the people that are
using these tools if we don't understand
why we're building these tools the tools
are gonna become more and more and more
and more useless I mean look already
half your parents can't use a computer
you know me mine have gotten better
certainly I've managed to train them
into
able to use the computer and
troubleshoot things themselves but still
it's tough it's really tough if you
don't grow up around the stuff you
cannot grasp it and the people who are
building these things are young they are
young people like you and I younger than
me younger than you right people who
have grown up around the stuff and love
the technology but don't get how people
work so how do we fix this right how do
we save the world because if we don't
fix this if we don't save this right
things are just gonna get worse and
worse and worse and worse and worse and
more and more and more and more and more
unmanageable until you're trying to
order drinks out of a kind of a drink
dispenser everything has a comes out
tasting almost but not quite entirely
unlike tea right so first off we have to
realize that the technology doesn't
matter anymore right it's not about the
tool it's about what the tool does it's
about how the technology makes our lives
better and more efficient and easier to
live right I mean yeah it's great that I
can now talk to anyone anywhere at any
time right but there's a whole slew of
problems with the phone in general right
there's a whole slew of problems with
the way the phone itself actually works
I mean look my favorite mobile phones
were the ones that just you know you
picked it up you dialed the number and
you called and you talked on the phone
right I mean yeah I like be able to
browse the web and I like being able to
you know SSH from my phone and I like
being able to have my phone connect to
my laptop so I can get online but you
know I don't like the fact that I have
to actually spend time configuring my
phone to get it to work the way I want
it because by default it's a piece of
shit right I'm horrified when I go into
coffee shops now because remember when
people used to go into coffee shops and
talk to each other right and now people
go into coffee shops and plop down the
laptop and open up the laptop and they
sit there and they type in they type in
the type and all you see is this
for 30 minutes on end right you see the
tops of people's heads and no one talks
to each other because they're all
talking to everyone else they're all
talking to their friends in Milwaukee
and South Paulo and Cape Town and
Germany but not the person next to them
right where we're so disconnected from
each other through this technology of
communication right and we're obsessed
with the tools or so the tools are so
over taking our lives now that we are
trying to seek out each other through
the tools because none of us remember
how to deal with each other in person
anymore you know we have discovered you
people are more important the technology
this crap doesn't matter and you know it
doesn't matter and yet we still go crazy
about it right well you have to replace
these things every few years because
they wear out and break because of
design like shit you know we we have we
get into arguments over what tool is
better all right we get into arguments
over what tool does the better job right
and it's not like we get get an
arguments over well you know this pen
writes better than that pen or this
glass is better than that glass you know
we get into arguments over these
complicated tools we've dug ourselves
into this into this hole right because
we're so obsessed with the tool that we
we've forgotten that people have to use
the tools I wait to stop doing this
bullshit where we build our identity
around the tool we use I mean yeah it's
all fine and well to be able to
configure a linux server because that's
a useful skill because you can do
something with it right you can make it
serve web pages that let people get to
information right or you know you build
a really awesome tool it's awesome
because it never goes down right you've
got system set up so that if one fails a
backup system is there so if people can
get to the information or people can
communicate with each other or people
can buy things in their underwear at
home in 24 hours a day right you make it
easy for people to do things
to make the quality of life better right
but not this whole you know this whole
nonsense where you build your identity
around the tool you use and your
identity is depending on that tool I
mean we all know people like this right
we all know people like this who like
for example IT manager at a company or a
network manager at a company right so
let's say you've got a problem with the
network the way the network works and
you go to the network manager and you
say hey I found this problem this
doesn't work for me I think I know how
to make it better for people because
people are having trouble with us right
the network manager who gets that the
network is a tool for people to do
things with will say to you you know
you're right that is a bad way of doing
things why don't we work together on
making it better or tell me what you
want and I'll try and work something out
for you right versus the person who
doesn't get people and the person who
doesn't understand people and the person
who thinks that the tool is the end-all
and be-all will go fuck you and off my
precious network right and you laugh but
you've had this happen to you write and
write even worse you know the person who
comes in you know take over a position
of authority and what do they do they
say well we've got 1,500 servers running
debian but i think we should move them
all to Gentoo because i like gentoo
better right and you laugh put you seen
it happen more times and you want to
admit and really the problems we need to
get away from these damn things more
often you know me to get out we need to
interact with each other and yeah we're
here at a convention and we do interact
with each other and we go out and we we
talk and we we eat together and we we
chat and we have a good time but there
is still the story of the person who
shows up at DEFCON with the laptop and
finds a power outlet in the hallway and
plugs in and sits down on Friday and
doesn't move until the end of sunday
except to maybe go to the toilet and get
something to eat right I mean yeah it's
great that we socialize with each other
but I think we're still too obsessed
with these things right and those of us
who are social yeah we get it but there
are plenty more of us who don't get the
social thing and who are intimidated to
even come to these conferences because
oh my god there are people here and I
have to deal with people in person I
don't have this machine between me and
the person it's kind of sad and we need
to figure out some way of making it
better or if you're still puzzling over
the point and as mattrick's succinctly
suggested fucking get a life because if
we don't if we don't figure out how to
solve this problem if we don't take
steps to try and say hey you know what
let's not promote this whole idea of the
tool being the end-all and be-all
instead let's promote the idea of it
being a lot people one day we're going
to wake up and come to a convention is
going to be full of people who have this
tattoo thank you
do you have any questions comments yeah
you missed um to a point I'm still
burned out on tech um I'm going into
psychology now rather than tech because
I got sick of tech so I don't know i
mean what part what burn me out was the
fact that you know i had to deal with
people like this all the time and i
couldn't deal with people like this
anymore because it was impossible to to
get through to them I mean all they saw
were numbers and and things rather than
the anchors all those numbers my you
know the story the breaking point for me
I think was you know I was working for
and opens a company built around this
idea of open source software and I was
going around giving classes you're
teaching classes teaching people how to
use this stuff and so there were soft
ware and there was hardware to that the
company produced and so for the class we
had to go out and you know part of the
class was she would come and you would
get all this hardware and when I went to
go teach us one class which had like you
know 16 you know 18 people in it that
each paid three thousand dollars to be
there for the week only half the
equipment was there so I called up and I
said you know hey guys um I think
there's been a mistake only half the
equipment's here can you please ship it
soon because you know these people want
to take the course and I can't really
teach the course let's all the stuff
okay sure just a second so I got a
callback we shipped it awesome what's
the tracking number here's the tracking
number thanks I go punch of the track
number 2 day air
right because all they could see was oh
that's too expensive and there was this
whole culture because everything was
linux at the company there's this whole
culture of oh we can build it ourselves
we can do it for cheap the first time
they sent me out to teach a course
rather than sending out you know network
cables they sent a thousand feet of cat5
a bunch of ends and a crimper right
because that was cheaper they were I
wasn't that was that part of the time
wasn't in my contract I learned that
lesson but yeah but yeah but that was so
all they saw were the numbers they
didn't see that hey there are people
here who were getting angry because they
paid a lot of money to take a course and
they're not getting the course so that
was the breaking point for me that's
kind of me we realize that this whole
thing is insane any other questions
accident what picture the first line
I'll get to you later yeah edda so what
are you comment on your thoughts are on
social media and actually using
technology to connect better with people
both across distances but also I think
more importantly who have similar
interests see the social media thing is
really interesting because while yes it
does have that application it winds up
being a tool for self-aggrandizement
right because there yeah there are
people who use it to communicate with
their friends I mean I have a Twitter
account and I use it to stay in touch
with people I know in real life but
there are people on Twitter and I'm sure
you know of them who use Twitter to try
and get as many people to follow them
and sit in and read what they say as
they can and you don't really care but
just use it to say oh look at me I'm
popular now so I mean I think the term
that the center of lexical on a social
media douchebag right
but yeah yeah we laugh but it's true you
know there are people who use the the
tool to just for self a grandma for
self-aggrandizement and so to that end
you know it's just an algorithm the same
problem it's it's taking people who
don't know how to interact with people
giving them a tool to interact with
people and then washing the horribly
knees use the tool in the back you know
this is my coming around Wow hi tech
earlier you spoke about the big hype
over apple and um to be honest both my
parents use Windows machines and I've
tried switching them over to Debian
machines I've been tried switching them
over to Apple machines and for those of
us tools who are still interested in the
tool um but well I I know a great
solution is throw away the computer shut
off your cell phone talk to the person
in front of you instead of eating lunch
with someone while you're on the fucking
cell phone um is is the Linux failure
just a just an issue of designing user
interface because people don't know how
people use the systems or is it
something bigger than that probably a
little column a little column B i would
have to you know i have to do a lot more
research to tell you exactly why that is
I mean I just have my theory my theory
is that you know the people who make
linux software the server stuff is great
because they actually have to use
servers for stuff but the desktop OS
stuff is terrible because they never
actually do any sort of real-world
desktop OS computing so they have no
idea so they make what they think is is
it good is a good product right but in
reality it's it's it's completely
useless out in the real world I mean
openoffice it's gotten better but it's
been a joke for a long long long long
long time and it still is to a degree
very much a joke any other questions
comments so you mentioned that in
technology there's a lot of dead ends
where people spend a lot of time
building something that was delivered in
it just didn't go to work as was a
failure isn't that part of the iterative
process isn't that true in the real
world in our real relationship as well
there are some that are failures or not
so isn't that just sort of an outgrowth
of the way humans interact well of
course yeah I mean in any in any process
were going to be dead ends and things
that go nowhere the the point wasn't
that there are dead ends the point was
that there were dead ends that people
got really excited about and thought
were the future and thought were you
know this is the next big thing and I
can totally see a world where you know
we're all gonna have video phones
doesn't really happen so any thoughts on
how to deal with that the social side of
getting really excited to try and build
a tool for people to use that you watch
the users and then it turns out it's one
of the dead ends because you mentioned
tech bar now and that's one of the
things I'm saying is you get excited
about the thing you're doing and then
it's dead and you invested so much in it
because you thought would be helpful and
then mmm any thoughts on that how to
deal with that I hadn't I hadn't
considered that angle actually um it's
interesting I'd have to think about it
but I'll think about it I'll talk to you
later about yeah change the scenery yeah
often anybody else though actually to
that point something I found after
having done computers for as long as I
have why don't we all have computer jobs
because computers were something we did
as a hobby we got really really into
them we got really good at them
eventually we will realized hey we can
make some cash of this we all went into
it and our hobby is now our job yet a
lot of us then go home and try to go
back to making it our hobby as well and
you end up being surrounded by it I
finish work it I finish work during the
day after having you know screamed to
people about their servers all day long
and I go home and I scream at my own
server so part of that's where the
burnout comes in in some ways you need a
new hobby your hobby is now your
livelihood so you need to go take up
fishing or cross stitching or something
to the something else for you to do as
an aside that does
tie into your data album yeah because
I've seen that a lot as people burn out
over the years it's because all they do
is Computers Computers Computers
Computers to the point where they don't
want to see them anymore yeah that's how
I picked up disc jockey actually I got
sick of the computer and you do
something else to do which was it wasn't
the computer so any other questions
comments all right thank you