alright then Craig Smith this stock is
going beyond
August 14
techniques are not going to go into a
little details of some of the CAN bus
network type things there's plenty of
places to go look at stuff up you can
like we mentioned before there's a
cantankerous handbook to free book I'm
gonna get it will give you all those
kinds of details but we will go through
the process of how you about such a car
I need to expectations on a car what are
your goals and I'm gonna talk about to
neutrals and there are a few overkill
but they're so see if I can get this guy
but never
area
it seems to be working now so we decided
on attack are all cars are different so
depends on your years as a featured you
have present a modification stoit
package you got the tram anh the good
stuff so if you're working on your car
or if you're working on an engagement a
lot of engagement for automotive
companies you know you're gonna be given
certain car and so you basically have to
figure out ok with this car have areas
am I going to attack that's you know
your attack surface you wanna feel your
goals are with threats and risks are
there and then turn the payload you know
what you're going to do once you get on
a car parking cars isn't really the
heart it's pretty simple as a couple
unique pieces that make up the car I
hired to defend the heart attack
let's do it through this live now says
she's on top of everything
so you think about the attack surface
it's more than just know my application
stuff they've never done any application
threat modeling if you like that you
simply looking for inputs these inputs
are things like your form fields there
are a lot of our parts of some kind of
data input your application you busy
just treated car as an application so
your employees become a more varied get
input from other vehicles from sensors
you get them from you keep you get them
from it has wireless or Bluetooth
capabilities have physical inputs as
well you have to see around you may have
USB connectors you know you have the
connector in your car on OBT dongle
those just playin if your steering
column you see in each check both use it
for that and depending on who your
client is physical aspect me out a lot
presence of your client is something
maybe they sell taxi cars or three squad
cars where the wires from the back seat
become very very important so I can get
these network wires from the back seat
you can do a whole lot of damage to
vehicle so don't think just because its
physical it doesn't matter does matter
just starting out and you want to start
with the physical to wireless and you
can identify different on your vehicle
nowadays the comparison become more
common with a means is that used to be
these were like one office each vehicle
have their own kind of thing was kind of
custom built for that vehicle when I
first started in this 2008 the
attendance center that was there also
known as I V eyes but my view I was mad
unit and the process fraught with a
Hitachi a 64 processor and was running
into CEO which you know where
identifiable but processor I didn't
really know a little bit of googling
turns out that was the same processor
using a Dreamcast which is really cool
but didn't know how to write assembly
for Dreamcast but that doesn't take long
to kind of get past month
nowadays on the internet that the new
systems are times are in tow
arm things are pretty comfortable with
their running Linux running you know so
when the CEW Qnexa Green River makes 12
but you're when you're on when these IVI
systems the billing define and execute
isn't super challenging it's actually
the same kind of stuff you would do on a
normal desktop you know your code now
sixty 60 you can test your code and what
you're going to be on your desktop
before use it on when he's not systems
so the only real barrier to entry to
getting all of these attacks just for us
really talked about yesterday about
getting billion test bench do you get a
retirement center you can get one I
recommend one from tyson tyson's nice
because it's open source hardware I
thank them for software as well I P were
using to develop their entertainment
centers this is a no but you can kind of
pick my directly for whatever pieces on
campus as you want it features you want
you just buy it they give you the full
depth studio the same one that the art
of people using it about Devon a lot of
times it's a good one kind of your
bearing on test about breaking anything
I recommend tyson's and then once you're
on which is typical I guess I want you
on the OSU C 00 here is it's as an
access point you know that played some
wifi which is running like used APD life
and asymptomatic into version number
compared to see these these things
really get updated you be kind of
disappointed to not just gonna hard
challenges not simply just mapping
versions then sign ok this is vulnerable
as a known vulnerability for it by now
you've heard what I want to do and this
is going to depend on what you really
want to do or what you been hired to do
your pelo could be that you get on the
IDI you're done maybe you're just there
to listen
on the microphone admits limousine
service and dedication happens in the in
the back a limo is very important to you
to make your games over there in the
context of a Bluetooth connectivity
Bluetooth phone contacts synced
something going for me came with your
cell phone you can liberate the car
companies just on the surface all and
that's going to be working more on the
vehicle's network typically from my
engagements that's using your prefered
concept is going to go from as far away
as possible to working on the car
actually controlling the car the city
controlling like steering it can be
unlocked in the car and driving car way
those kinds of things you walk up to a
car
read the benefit that unlock and started
she's a pretty good demo now is that we
need to go for another possibility is
refreshing the firmware sometimes if
they have it there are a lot of them
don't but if they have these that
sometimes the trusted source on the
network so they may have some validation
you know when it's getting the update
you know over there that ok I got this
piece the update we're gonna push it out
shout to my other hardware components
that are inside my car sometimes there's
no checks between the IVI and the other
former components there is technically
you know these security access codes
they just put in before you can reflash
but the idea is trusted will do it for
you so if your performance trainer
someone who wants to reflash maybe don't
have the key here don't have the money
for the key copy and I V I open may give
you access you want a little complex and
that they're so can we talked yesterday
as the most common when I think
everybody tried before getting into this
bill to start with
that's what the sniffer is available for
CTF challenge the cancer forget john the
CAN bus now controls a lot of things the
other bus is constantly slide
Dennis line when is a very popular ones
a very simple
bus protocol is very cheap and you can
see some they suffer from the seat area
you may not be able to talk directly to
land mines not use exposed gonna come in
say underneath your be done but we can
control it about time space for the seat
warmer let's just say you were to send a
message you can you can send one that
you want to see it goes underneath the
seat itself and then that can versatile
in that actually told the heating in the
warm-up so just because you're not
directly connected you bring up some
kind of wiring diagram you're looking at
it doesn't mean you can't control it it
just means it's going to eventually go
to another protocol and you may view and
a tap into the wire more directly you
may be switching from that can something
else in the screening policy must that's
the kind of the red one of the top now
and I don't worry about too much it's
pretty much just use for high-fidelity
sound and entertainment and stuff
another we might run into a complex
right so expensive I wouldn't start
their scars and hacking stuff goes but
it's good to know they're gonna think
the sides can you come up to speed the
CAN bus that kinda stuff again when I
can go into all the details of this is
another one by one on how to carver say
it's going to be the exploitation of a
focus on so you can look at the pulitzer
your online Cu details of campus itself
to some complications when you're
talking can I that if you have that such
as one of Canada's sale would say does
rpm is going to come off like to say
what every millisecond just going to
don't sharpens its astronaut of course
but it's just going to come out over and
over and over and over and over again so
as an attacker and he zeroed attack that
when you decide you've identified what
the RPM speed this flooding the bus
going to send a bunch of that same
message with maybe a higher speed and
said you can talk faster than the real
messages talking you when they are
coming to go up whatever happened to
still having won the competition is
still having the real system tell it
like 25 and you're like 25 75 height 75
and so
noises of looking like the real controls
the noise in the problem is that because
you can't shut that other guy off your
still gonna have that noise and if the
speed is of the communications quick you
have to be quicker that guy can be a
tough very noisy on the bus
eat up a lot of bandwidth to attack it
that way every make and model is
different so if you find out that ok if
I hope my goal was to unlock a car door
maybe you have a Honda and for your 2013
Hyundai you know this particular packing
a lot card or well not want to slip into
GM's vehicles or you have a BMW it's not
going to work the whole different I D O
different bites with can you don't have
a source and destination you just have
this idea is pretty simple but there are
different for every car that's easily
done to come to give a competing managed
thing I wasn't very that's arguable but
thing is that there are different they
sell the information other people
allowed on a bus and you have to figure
out you know what is going to attack you
may have to be concerned about yes
systems currently vehicles don't have
ideas they're working on the thinking
about it but let's assume their own
eventually be there what would you have
to do to kind of bypass that I think it
through this one thing they can't afford
tool called cannon fingers you can get
passes vehicle detection but taking
advantage of the fact that because he's
making models different you can use that
to your advantage so what you have you
know every card and every year so
oftentimes have slightly from packets on
it you can then use that information to
determine like oh well on this type of
car from this type of car because it's
going to be different so something I was
normally a challenge for getting on and
forget how a vehicle works mention of
you tack you can use that against nice
thing about this is you just do this by
monitoring the wire you're not going to
generate any kind of traffic
traditionally how this is done as you
query the
main ECU and ask for the VIN number and
then you could do something like Ben
decoding your basic look at the first
couple blades and forgetting ok with us
the gym as you know whatever you can
eliminate all that there was an idea
that query don't like queers let me know
squaring the day the element that is if
you happen to be on an IV I i dont like
this because I V I kind of look around
the ABS system very least she's a splash
screen that was a lie condo or something
and that you can plot data that way but
sometimes just not on for AVI sometimes
I like a tome action just smaller model
model it's a little better system so you
can still use cannot finish fourth at
this it will use on the research side he
wouldn't run this on like after an
attack you don't get onto machine and
then run you read this you're developing
an attack this is part of you building
out your exploits and so I apologize for
being too hard to read but he left the
way it works is it would take that
sample said you can't see it too well
here but the first several bites tell
works as these IDs at the top and you'll
see that these counts and so they say
like 98 99 78 99 78 and there's a drop
of how many times it's all those I think
around 400 and something in the drop
again and that's based on their
repeating them out on the bus so how did
they are also takes into consideration
most immersive to certain intervals so
if you take all the ones are said to be
a certain amount shouted miss you group
those the ones signs will call this
common IDs there then we look for as we
look at the packet size that's what some
brackets there the packet sizes up to a
buy on some vehicles this is always
invites they do this by adding about
this particular example there's
something you can see there are two
bites and therefore by it and there was
no padding we call this one dynamic if
its static and eight then we also detect
adding it to the pedal zeros did the
cattle are raised all access all these
things go to make a fingerprint and then
there's some Jason that's the alcove
this
house here normally runs deep of
feelings this is the verbose output we
always get this this Jason Beaubien in
this case the same gonna make model trim
because we've been given a fingerprint
database and then it's kind of saying
you miss out on the common IDs will give
you mean aidid that it thinks is the
best one to use
gives you the mean interval in this case
at the very bottom number it's like 00
died 9 2009 so I used as an attack when
you make a show you want to run on the
system's if you're on the right system
in this case I would listen
02 milliseconds buy seats who are the
main ideas during that point zero two
milliseconds I you know I'm most likely
on it and I don't see it I bailout it
don't make any network traffic I stopped
I can do additional checks during the
because there are patterns out and about
the same time even though the meaning he
doing that point zero two milliseconds
ships in the other comment i'd used as
well as so I can check them off my list
that takes me literally point there two
milliseconds to do this tax is in very
very quick I can really tell without
creating any traffic what kind of system
ought to have two pillows made her way
to unlock a car door on Honda when this
radio is also sold on a call Jim Brown's
I can then have a stake a statement so
at that point there two milliseconds I
can identify what kind of car online and
then jumps the propellant so intriguing
ideas beliefs on the network level to
use the fingerprint database piece you
simply take the Jason Powell you add
information to it and then there's a
function that kind of attitude at a base
in this example code here it's just
giving this is the one that test
directory it takes a sample data base
camp and database of one fingerprint a
federal law that says Honda Civic 2007
not discussing 92 hybrid and there's
information it gives you a confidence
level so how confident that things that
is in that match this one is still just
on the research side
yourself to see if your daddy sorry has
the information reports are different
that you need to know it's the
equivalent of figure out like I had sex
but that works on this version of
Windows what else is at work on its the
same kind of things you would do other
tests feeling ok well it kinda cars can
I make this work on and you make your
expert that was extra bonus feature get
the fuck outta fingers it's a it's a
pattern matching system it's not very
verbose is just kind of added as last
minute but it's kinda fun pattern part
is this be the top it's like a little
lower case the capital be there to speak
of a movie and isn't just bit changes so
this could be off on off on off on or
like and maybe doing locks so that would
be unlocked lock unlock unlock unlock
and lock lock it's a pattern that you're
going to trigger and you're going to
tell kenna fingers a look for this
pattern and all this network traffic is
flowing through your network and the
town of it and as you do those commands
it will pull it out that's what the
example is there a look at the logs
there is serious in this case to make it
easy to see the big changes are between
0 and one can find it anywhere and
they'll say look here's your matches can
find more than one match that would
match this pattern given it and it says
okay with this I D position by position
six over the two days I saw toggle
between a bit state was most cases here
in 10 between 627 whatever this is just
there to save you time this has nothing
two finger printing is just since I was
already analyzing the data less add
something extra and so when you're
trying to figure out things like okay
well well lots of car what controls if
it's a bit I'll call you can control you
can justify a couple seconds just a
little bonus feature
so where I get it from get home if you
check get her back home / Samba Craig
that's my get repository there's a bunch
of can utilities and their conf is the
kind of fingers the Ruby package so if
you have installed you can do a gem
install cos I don't solve the
command-line tools and also the library
so if you want to incorporate this and
some other kind of broader system this
is particularly use on
can so you're gonna use it probably on
Linux don't know if you can use anywhere
else
necessarily for your research stuff but
he's not then stopped at Everett is
called management this is actually
written for reporter for NBC we have
this love-hate relationship the media
need them the kind of get your message
out there and talk to play people but at
least the ones the cameras really went
really sensational stories in logic
don't talk to me unless I have something
demo that's super scary so I hate scary
demasiado I am just not a fun person I
want to go out and talk about fixing
problems outrageous can help people so
it it it's a little tough yeah so I
create this the the store here it's
about that for cars essentially what
this is it so you can set the remote
control model cars at once from anywhere
in the world
way it works is you know what you think
it would work you have a car that goes
up to a web server and polls for actions
he has to be there because the cars
network is always a great can be a
little time so it doesn't pulling a
tribute to what sort of anywhere and
then the attacker was controlling the
vehicle sits on the other side and the
energy commands so when the cars connect
to do the things not that easy to do
what we can do is watch live at the NBC
video did decent job I don't think this
morning too much when I can watch the
whole thing we're gonna watch just let
the democrat the tool works and a little
bit from Josh Corman from my mcalary had
talked about it and then I'll stop it
study released today shows just how
underprepared automakers are to deal
with the threat of cyberattacks that
right now a lot of people are talking
about it but tonight the item is
actually going to do something like
gloria also teamed up with a bona fide
auto hacker and wait until you see what
he was able to do with the vehicle from
thousands of miles away side this garage
on Seattle's South Side our break Smith
is tinkering about 10 bucks for sale by
plugging a wi-fi or cellular dongle
under the steering column of this Mazda
he's replicating a potential security
risk in thousands of cars all brands
that have factory installed wireless
communication using the same signals
that would normally be used by the
vehicle were just now controlling them
from the internet after deciphering the
computer commands that control this
car's headlights and wipers he gave them
to me
3,000 miles away here in New York City
the car is in seattle is the command for
the lights I'm sending it and see if the
lights on the car turned on and the
codes work headlights are on
that's amazing 3,000 miles away I just
turn the lights on in the car and the
switch on the inside the car is off just
to be clear Craig is not behind the
wheel nor is He behind his computer up
in the air like a no hand I'm the one
controlling these lights the lights are
turned on nobody's in a car crash
outside the car lights just turned on
and I control the wipers to this is for
the wipers are good at the wipers are
going and 3,000 miles away and and I
just turn the wipers on software
controls controls your lights and a
player airbag heightened seat belt
Joshua Corman is co-founder of I am the
cavalry dot org a group dedicated to
raising awareness about the vulnerable
software in lots of technology including
cars one person scares me the most is
now there's parking assist teachers and
a lot of these cars as a very powerful
motor on the steering column it's more
powerful than you are
can often be used to rip the steering
wheel out of your hands while you're
driving
Mazda sent the i-team an email stating
the company is aware of the growing
concerns related to the possibility of
vehicle hacking and continually works to
improve the security of our vehicles are
you know I think this is what are the
rules is that you know this is this is a
general general thing that picking on
the car companies and that's one reason
is that special Dongguan major the
reportedly showing me attach a weird as
done with the bottom of the cars it's
like really a problem he modified the
car that was intentional you don't
necessarily have to as I just explained
you put this on the IVI systems or
whatnot but the point was the pic on my
list I bothered us about this but
whatever it is what it is
it could've been worse but you will have
to deal with that if you're going to
Emmas for people this is how the
software works on the details so
whenever you make your relay peace and
so that's the piece is gonna run on
telematics or on your payment or a
little dongle dongle later if you will
but it just goes out the website is a
polling question pass then or any kind
unique lady right now just used to kind
of separate cars from each other I don't
use the code or anything like that kind
of figure out on the server side working
hard as he could think of the method
supported so the response to the first
three is premature what the result will
did you have waivers on off lights on a
flash and then good flight rpm and fuel
just getting a democrat of unit proof of
concept deal and when we went southbound
reporter sat down with her line online
login and check this out he looked at it
so yeah I was just picking up a little
harder doesn't look really about a
correction I think it sucks to contrive
to make it look a little more hackers
ok I had a Kansas and Kansans stop her
from her to Linux can Utilities is the
same syntax for that can man is not
really that commando because it actually
will flood with whatever you get it as
we have two seconds and stopped looking
for a crash have a problem with saying
something else too contrived make it
exactly the way I said to make it kind
of those the definition of contrived but
I can orders but it is easy to use but
it proved that that's what they say it's
Ajax not returnable look like it is
taking on terminal it's just a website
is a test kinda do the terminal
emulation of just a simple PHP back in
as you know some stuff you'd expect the
intermol apparel support you know you
can hit the control you and all that
good stuff those credentials can have
multiple logins from multiple different
people I currently don't really see
people logged into the system I don't
really use the system so that it hasn't
leaked madrick capabilities and basic
scripting capabilities I'm you can
assign the numbers two variables to
group them and see if its tributary
groups said than done yet that part so
it could be a vehicle's it's going to be
kind of like an array gonna work then
save this episode had to assume you're
saving it won't save the to a backhand
service I'd state right now chat log out
if it is just that session or yet but i
think im gonna save on the server side
there that's going to add a some
geolocation stuff so it has the
capability is a feature to say like the
location of the vehicle that would be
kinda grateful to have the DTC
diagnostic trouble codes your engine
light and you know you can have problems
with OnStar which was kind of fun and
scary kind of way so
release this yet and I have been
debating about it I don't think I'm
going to America can't tell you enough
to build it yourself if you really have
a really good reason to get this could
be really convincing you can contact me
we can work on something that isn't a
real solution for this yet so I don't
really know what I'd be getting out of
this time by released in stores up
pressure him to do anything to fix
anything really just for demo and even
if I never did again I did it once and
that was it so I mean if you really want
I'm probably not the only source code to
this so I can be done I mean
unfortunately is not a whole lot that
can be done as individual users we
really have to rely on the auto
manufacturers do a lot of the stuff but
the trash Carmen women do his recovery
little speech there and I really support
I am the Calvary it's a great group it's
just a bunch of security who get
together if you've heard of them to kind
of work with some industries LA Times
internet things kind of people to come
learn the lessons learned from something
or a no sew for manufacturing in server
side stuff just as opposed to reinvent
the wheel on redoing the same problems
we saw before LSU lessons learning and
just jump to the end of the fantastic
they cannot last year this five-star
cyber safety program it was target for
the automotive but really kind of place
and Internet of Things just like safety
by design
evidence capture all that good stuff for
it was releasing any have Internet of
Things device you can't do these five
points you're not production ready when
it's simple you can update over there
you can't help the Modified I mean these
are common sense things we wouldn't
attaching to the Internet like a web
server things and so why are we texting
and the other device
the plane speaker their speaker talking
something else is just controls on cars
coming to your failures on the sky how
their safety standards are males
whatever so please speak was just an
aside for that
easier to understand
gonna get involved where you know some
stuff publicly and openly or with any
kind of group and calorie needs more
than just hackers and with his interests
in the stuff and doing PR whatever it is
you're free to reach out to you the
site's founder garages are supposed to
me about us bringing the book at and has
a Twitter handles for the 2003 that I
can book that's on one side the 2014
crackers and manual it's a little late
on information in my opinion and that's
because story behind it was that this
book was written to go along with a
class at the USCC nice a cyber challenge
class and so is their training manual
but it went with a whole day talk I have
had cars so they get this before so it
seems like it's missing details it's
because it was in the other part I
released it open source for free it in a
setting up my ISP the system and where
we had three thousand dollars in the
first four days and from all over the
world and shut me down and I realize
that people want to do this or they're
really interested I had no idea the
interest until book kind of came out so
I started over another one that can be
done as far as the writing partners and
begin the year but on this expressive
gonna handle this one the first one was
self-publish miss our special and it's a
lot bigger over three pages or something
but it goes up you through all these
little pieces this is like this which
happily out the new one we can go
outside town tax step-by-step how to do
show all that good stuff it will still
be free so also be a free book
negotiations I don't know when I'll be
out I was hoping to be able to Chaka
Khan ago not ready yet I might have some
samples out we'll see so
reason this is mine my questions time
period slide but i wanna have to grant
he's gonna give you information it's
more like to challenge the way on many
factors for the most part work right now
is when they're working on vehicles the
stuff they're working on the new stuff
isn't going to be out for another five
years
their cars are done in 20 the very very
design I'm not my make modifications to
the done so as a security researcher
that obviously is rather frustrating
think that over we're telling them
something the best things about twenty
20 best and I but the current state of
things and so some you have to be aware
of and because of that kind of stuff
because the old traditional way of being
nineteen acted that responded to a
five-year turnaround the time they're
not always not always friendly to you so
it's still at the stage it helps to know
how to get information to them so if you
start doing this research start finding
vulnerabilities and you can become a be
worried about concerned Scherzinger this
research because they want their car sea
antes find something they want it fixed
and that's always are we just want
things fixed so right now it's a go die
mcalary drivers to you find something
let us put you in touch with the
security teams at these other
organizations greetings typically get it
and they typically not have to take this
information in kind of walk it through
the right people and their lawyers after
you enter their help desk it will most
likely go right to the layers but you
get the security help we're working on
getting several factors that have
responsible disclosure policies to the
very least you have an email you can
send to that would be great don't expect
in ninety turnaround time
parties area it would be I don't I don't
think you couldn't shouldn't demand I
need around here but it's just the board
have one yet
down the road I think the absolute
should I thinking on the Internet should
but they're not quite there yet just so
you know I think that is a good goal for
them to get there but they're not there
yet
I would say within the last year is when
they start to take security seriously
and the car from what I've seen plenty
of research in this we've done damage
wirelessly before I'm partially at least
five involved last four years but I said
last year as I can be raised or perhaps
security teens unfortunately they're
doing the same thing that we always the
ramparts we always do when we're
starting out there taking this closed
source group they're attaching it to the
internet icon that we need security
let's move on to other departments and
then your security team and we doing a
situation i mean you're you're you're
just one department onetime mayor the
scary teen
you do have active people looking for
vulnerabilities in your vehicle you
panic attacks do you want to go buy
something you know what to do now and
financial industry where birds eclipsed
by the latest was being thing that
helped me do my job I'm a little
overwhelmed the problem is there isn't a
whole lot things to buy but there's a
lot of companies scrambling to fill that
need and I was at the rather half-baked
at best a lot of the solutions
becomes are seeing money has the same
any signs of people willing to throw
money at the problem and fortune I think
they're gonna probably brought the same
things are very scene they're gonna do
like firewalls IDS systems it's probably
not a good solution and I talked 2013
bypasses 2024 already broken so you know
I think we need a little more work kind
of do lessons learned this is my number
and where we actually higher security
people who can do real testing you can
do it you might have to reach architect
some of the stuff most segregation
that's in there is based on speed we
want this bus got busy we made another
bus based on functionality based on
security the part that connect them just
random but not really you know you can
put files in a missing don't ever do if
I don't ever do intrusion detection just
that's nowhere near the level you need
that's the piece just like you have any
regular network
today it's just there like you know it's
you know so far but it doesn't really do
much so
same thing will happen of course not
gonna do much safer ways of releasing so
far been on the OBD dunkel part so you
can blossom pieces there is not enough
stuff you can do it myself using sensors
have a lot of sensors my personal
opinion is the security pioneers have
you looked at more as we do our human
stuff so you have five senses and it's
easy to clean my senses you know but
it's hard to travel 50 miles and that's
really what you have to do to really
pull me out of my brain off of my senses
cars have a lot of sensors right now you
wanna bust the rest of your pretty easy
just taking over a descending ideas use
other sensors to make intelligent
decisions await your see all right now
hearing that stuff and kinda having a
just of how the industry works seeing
some of the newer kind of tools that can
be used and exploitation I'll take any
questions you guys have
tolerate limiters yes the question
performance training and eliminating
really matters i personnel to the
performance tuning side of open ground
around this is a community that anybody
can join I started initially thinking
the security people can hear that cars
and when I learned from the day one of
the first meeting we had I was scared I
showed up we had a bunch of accounting
show up but reforms to show up at our
people show up you want to do some
Burning Man stuff and i'm looking how
there's a bigger need for like the types
of information that wherever digging
into so I couldn't personally tell you
exactly how to do that but I did we do
it it's typically done at the firmware
level of understanding with the ECU but
again I don't do that please visit the
rumor but there is a prominent changes
and so they need password to do that I
do that part
help with the password to get to the Cu
but then I don't do the printer genius
questions like a CT scanner for security
there's there's actually talk about that
right now I didn't let the video player
way through but there's a senator that
comes on right after that we had a
proposal and it wasn't a bad proposal is
just doesn't having teeth I guess you
would say things in his life
third-party security audit about
statement true but like who's checking
out where the checking for some guys as
web apps in the car does good stamp that
we have to have that listen as a
security group and generally don't have
that we don't have the same class
patients for vehicles that we have a
chance to say oh this is seeking
injection thats this level risk princess
to say if I were to do so it's a
combination of gain entry to a car can
you can you can gain so far as this
level wrist now like if you were tell me
what the expert was I can't tell you how
bad I you it is OK from where this the
unlock the car doors are still something
ok it's here or maybe even amplifier in
the car and I get you down like your
house maybe it's a bit lower water break
through the windshield ok technically
you did it but you know I just and so
like i bug bank problems have a problem
to classify it like you used to say like
over these types of tax will be $20 for
the car were still at the stage like
will I know its security I just ended up
in to rate word label that people in
kind of class other stuff that I think
maybe once we kind of work that I would
reply me soon we might be moving forward
on doing safety rating that stuff for
this in their safety standards for sure
the ISO 2626 to as a think on a stool
standard ASIO but it's really based on a
park fail so I can purchase this part
fails at six miles per hour
how bad is it based on how many people
could die die will do recall how that
works
yeah yeah just a few people died and so
that the change will have to be like one
is that it's not just a part failing
it's the part still working its working
maliciously Picasa pivoting
stuff doesn't come into ISO 10646 to the
starting to look at addressing that now
so I'm safety is only deal with that and
if you have over their updates we don't
really have to do this long-term recall
recall has been stagnant it anyway so
this way if you are to find a
vulnerability and reported maybe we can
shoot for more than 90 day thing where
people have the divers I just tell you
there's a problem seems legit and you
fix it either some there's some
complications for fixing it then you
have to do a lease the same kind of
encryption you do on the phone update be
awesome to do other things you wouldn't
have to do you would have to do an
update for you wouldn't want to do an
update with him is driving you don't
know if they want to make a year or two
ago trying the car to go to work please
wait for an hourly update your
signatures that would say something to
do to make it right but they're easily
overcame we've done it before in other
areas and we have to do it again on cars
so I think once again have those in
place that'll be a little bit better and
then I think we'll get better safety
standards and get them or TV
right well as well as the five surviving
humans can be played anything connected
to the European Plain Dealer medical
device or whatever I mean you can't do
those things you're not production ready
I'm not making speculations of Air
France disappearing before I disappear
think I'll leave that off the table they
ever the same joke made with cars and I
hope was beside the wire wheels on
vehicles and skip the ground and that's
fairly accurate i mean the bases network
on wheels that's what the are you can't
really as an individual right now where
would you put it so like for instance
figure back to the the picture of the
network stuff there is sometimes there's
choke points you know maybe you could
put it choke point depends what you're
trying to protect areas but these are
buses web US workforce so everybody else
is packets if you're on that same bus
segment so difficult and the reason why
hand is this way because it really has
to be very fast very efficient to give
you information so you know you want to
babysit him breaking anyone that
information right away and so it has a
lot of CEP in form of eliminating noise
that you would normally see and i cant
packet but not so much in my life as a
break when it wasn't the brake
controller saying something like that so
if you're going to Fire Island here like
maybe you put down or something plugs in
to prevent like ballet attacks or to
make sure that the preggers progressive
dongle that you put in doesn't get hat
or something like that and you could see
a certain risks segment something I was
honestly it's a knee jerk reaction that
doesn't really solve a greater problem
encryption and I wanna hear a lot like
bullets and bus doesn't help you you
know I'm going to have a much larger
amount of packets being sent to say
you're breaking and it there's nothing
secret about that packet I mean yes I
can forget what breaks you know what
this bite unlock my car door and yes I
use the propellers but personally as
someone who likes to tinker is rather
when I bought my car did you give me
that information
my mind is my car I love to know my car
works without having to do this stuff I
love to have the wiring diagrams
included in my owner's manual and
shouldn't your subscription thing I
don't like those things I like to see
those things fixed I never will be but
you know there's there's movement to get
some thats effects I was involved with
the Copyright Office recently are you
for class 2122 the DMCA exemptions if
they go through it was kinda give you at
least more leniency to be able to talk
about things and share stuff right now
is really questionable a document like
all the packets in a certain vehicle
does are sometimes sold for 125 grand
power to take that one file and publish
it but I but in reverse engineering will
they come out nobody's tried it yet
GMs said they would do something like
that so I believe him but I don't think
I should be able to do it I don't have
knowledge that people should have so I
think we're coming to head never needs
it
this genetic diagnostic kind of piece
that's missing pieces of the OBD
connector is a standard connector thing
to standard diagnostic for the read only
you know it's a read only thing I go
with my current speed or you know how
are things looking but if you wanna do
something complex I see have a pickup
truck and you to carry more weight when
she's out that acts on it you have to
change the firmware on the vehicle so
you can deal with the new partitions
rushers dahmer's gonna be off shipping
is going to be off that's not a read on
the operation and order the stuff you
have to have a single level access so
it's it's coming ahead I think those
exemptions will go through and maybe we
can go a little further on the tinkering
part and open communication piece we're
used to that the software community just
having a communication with me just say
things and you know I couldn't it isn't
attacked it's not horrible and vehicle
but it's not great either of these still
will attack you at the show not totally
cool with working just people on the
street
nevermind I think well you know we don't
know the CPU testing we know we're doing
you shouldn't touch it actually doing a
little bit further and said that in
their case like
the claim that software is copyrightable
all to pieces and I'll be shipped in the
vehicle's round software there's an
implicit copy rate GMM jerk are you
don't do they decide to go ahead and
make a statement and so they're
definitely afraid of course I think for
most people that's news to them at the
page you know thirty thousand plus and
we don't want that car so hopefully
we'll win that by
so the question is there a way to
disable the wifi modem that kinda stuff
there isn't an official ways they do
that i mean I'm seeking cut the wires
and that's what I recommend
be fantastic I mean they don't be
shocked if you disconnect and remove yer
people but it's fine if you remove the
OnStar
call you even for not paying that
service that allows detecting a problem
her car bringing in for free service
jack because they want the answer there
there so you're not paying for it they
they wanted in there so right now
they're definitely not on all search for
it would be nice to have I agree I think
we're projecting while driving is
illegal but I didn't have anything else
that is I don't think it's legal
question
that's changing and I was like 13
processor their update was honored DVDs
and so if you were to buy a mapping DVD
for two hundred and fifty bucks he could
have the ability to put your software on
it that's actually I got in I saw these
deals and stuff and that's remaining
modifications to my splash screen and
bunch of other things actually shooting
get music video entertainment that's my
goal but that's what they used to work
in the honestly didn't use the update
the OS and we had a pretty major to be
on and I think as I get somewhere over
the air and something big of a deal
you'll see more of it on BMW recently
did one where there was a vulnerability
found over the air update which included
not using encryption but did a good job
and it was brought to them by a
third-party researcher who said it and
they had sex I think within the nine
days my memory and and they pushed up
and down the pics the encryption peace
and that's that's why I wanna see that's
fantastic
to some people I think one of the
stories came out of course is the news
and I like BMW had but it right it's
just support me that's going to happen
we're going to find a way you can make
it in there but you do everything right
you have encryption all that stuff i
mean get hurt leader something you
updated on take off work every day to
thrive in their daily needs to a
dealership so my mind there's no other
way to do it attacks are forced to have
a remote update the rewards very
interesting on so I hope to see more
right now I'd say
they asked thanks
I returned I hope so
Tesla doesn't have the texts and the
same kind of development cycle begin
with so they started their friend which
is just kinda cool I guess when you can
be kind of like that when you're like a
startup thing but it will be tough to me
that's a huge mind-set that they have to
change their their machine since I just
keep running making business decisions
and that's the way things have worked
for ever wear them because it was
physical these were closed network
attached the internet you don't have to
worry about but the game changed in the
past them and they attach some ways it
in realizing the United the phone home
systems have an IP on any possible but
unlikely we heard you in the collision
like ours as an IP appealing at least
your wife obviously has it there's
obviously where this was getting into
these systems which puts them on the
same game as the servers as cell phones
and you really do need the same
turnaround times so least those aspects
of software aspects to be shorter than
just happened I don't know if I'll ever
do it for design perspective five years
it'll be a huge change and other
questions
I gotta get well thank you for time play
the CTO get a cancer different a curse