turbo talk during lunch today presented
by fire I my name is Alexis sculpt a
consulting systems engineer for the west
and we're gonna go over to the state of
the landscape and what fire I kind of
doesn't provides a service to all of us
so
liar I approach is an adaptive defense
model and it starts with something that
you're all very familiar with which is
general technology right so we all have
technology trying to detect trying to
alert you are technology of fire I can
detect both known and unknown threats so
it's not a signature-based technology it
covers all vectors of entries so we talk
about vectors that would be ways that
Mauer gets in the organization's web
email data center's web servers mobile
devices USB stick in the parking lot our
technology is founded over 10 years ago
its patented it's a hardened hypervisor
that we built from the ground up and
it's designed around security and
nothing else so I'll go and more into
that technology in a moment but it's
really kind of like a three tier idea
that fire has an approaching today's
cyber security issues and landscape that
technology is its itself there
collecting information it feeds into an
intelligence data bank and that
intelligence data bank is basically
we're looking at roughly fifty billion
objects every day and I don't just mean
files it could be events in a sim it
could be behavior that we see what we're
doing what we call incident response
post breach work we're in the front line
of most of the incidents that you've
read about in the news so without
disclosing anything but any of our
customers you can certainly you probably
know fiery response to most of the major
breaches out there and that also feeds
into this intelligence databank we've
got over a million network censors out
there were deployed on millions of
different endpoints as well
hundreds of malware analysts and until
experts and we've discovered twenty of
the last 30 0 days that are actively
exploited no other security vendor out
there actually can claim any statistic
like that the third silo of what we kind
of do it fire I is the expertise so if
you feel like you might have some
thing in the network and you're not sure
fire I is the kind of company that can
come in do an assessment to see if your
compromise if you're in a specific
vertical let's say its banking and you
read online that a certain bank has
become compromised you want to know if
you have what they have you can contact
us that's one of the things that we do
as far as our experts will also do
incident response as well so if you
already know that you are compromising
you can't get it out of the network on
your own fire Isaac go to for that as
well
the ex expertise that we have the the
responders they also feed into this
intelligence database in this
intelligence database on an hourly basis
fees and all the products all the
endpoints all the network censors the
email sensors all of that so it's a
continuous circle of intellectual
sharing and crowdsourcing what's really
important when we're talking about the
technology that fire has understanding
the attack from beginning to end the
full kill chain today's attacks start
with an exploit typically it's not
normally just a file sometimes it is if
it's an attachment via email but it's
it's an exploit it something that can't
be patched that the the vendor of a
software products has a bug that a
hacker has discovered and they're
utilizing that bug to get into the
network and it cannot be patched it's
not because you didn't apply the latest
TV we have tremendous exploit detection
so that's really kind of how we found
most of those euro days is detecting
that exploit if you do not detect the
exploit the rest of the skill chain
that's on the board right now so from
exploit call back now we're binaries
coming down or mail code coming down
maintaining persistence in the network
and then in a worst-case scenario the
data going out the door the did it
tration if you don't see the exploit the
rest of it can be completely office
created an encrypted in an unseen so
it's it's crucial that you see the thief
when they walk in the door if you don't
see that coming in the door then you're
typically don't see the data going out
the door so
so how does this technology works so
it's we have something we've built an
MDX multi vector virtual execution
environment and what it is it's our own
virtual environment again its
purpose-built for security doesn't do
anything else except look for malware
look for malicious behavior malicious
intent it so hard and hypervisor so you
know absolutely hackers are going to try
to see if they're sitting in a sandbox
absolutely I bring up a V em right now
with VMware and I throw a PDF it came in
my span and open it up in there there's
a good chance has nothing to do with it
because it's gonna check the services
gonna look for certain services running
processes running it might check for
system time moving forward
certain log files being incremented
we've built in anti evasion techniques
over three hundred and this hypervisor
this hypervisors over 10 years old so
this is not something that we just
created actually first to market with
the idea of virtualizing not only
objects when you open them up in an
environment like this but all packet
workflows I'll give you really good
example you go to cnn.com there's ad
space that ad space is what contains the
exploit not cnn.com we're not looking at
one URL we're looking at a hundred
different URLs that are being rendered
and replicating that across multiple
operating systems with multiple versions
of Java Adobe whatever / whenever it's
exploding again that's how we find both
feet the known and the unknown threats
and we cover all the vectors so if your
Android device gets compromised and they
steal all your contacts and they also
steal some of the email that you had
with those contacts they can specially
tailored Spearfish email now let's say
your son or daughter's in a sports
program in the center the sports
schedule looks like it's from the
co-chairman open it up as you trust it
that's a real Spearfish that's actually
something that has happened so we
correlate all the vectors as well it's
not just hey you've got something on
this machine that's bad it's it came
from here it spread laterally there and
and correlating that whole thing so you
can see the full killed chain of what's
happening in your organization
it's also built for high performance and
efficacy so we can bring up hundreds of
GM's in a single moment in time and
replicate your it's your packets across
those at the same moment time of 4
minutes or less determine whether
something is malicious and the really
cool thing about this technology isn't
just determining that it's bad I mean
sure hits bed what we want to know is
what the callback communications gonna
be when this thing is done in its
compromise the system is it gonna go
lateral is it gonna try to set up a
proxy internally and when it's taken
data out the door
let's say it's a keylogger something
very simple where's it gonna send that
data so in at that that's a moment we
actually push the clock forward in time
whether it needs to be ours weeks months
it doesn't matter in this virtual
environment for minutes your real time
will determine that it's malicious
determine what it wants to do its
behavior forensics and also determine
what the callback is once you have the
callback you can share that information
through syslog-ng with other devices
that you have the network where you can
put the fire on line to block it so if I
but FIFA comes in my house takes my TV
takes all the cool stuff that I've got
my drone whatever if they can't get out
of my house I never had anything stolen
so we're looking at about 2 million
objects per hour across network email
mobile file systems data centers and
we're popping those into this and the ex
detonation chamber and that's where
we're discovering the zero-day exploits
that we discover that's also where we're
generating that command and control
information before it actually happens
in real time that's how are able to
actually prevent the reach from being
successful again we're going to
correlate that across everything that
you've got so if it started with an
Android device and then made it to your
email on whatever device you have in the
office but then went out the door on
somebody else's device really cool thing
that we published last month was we
found a hacker actually posting the data
that they wanted to actual trade on
Microsoft TechNet
that's something that all your web
filters allowing right now
communication and post Microsoft TechNet
it was just gibberish and the hacker
picked up that gibberish deleted the
post and put it back together and how
their data so it's not going out the
door necessarily over UDP not going out
the door
the way that you might think it can go
out the door in various different
methods and learning about those methods
in the detonation chamber the MDX is is
pretty much crucial house fire has
gotten most of the brand recognition
that you know as far as far as your
deduction that's the technology piece
but also had up you know the three
pieces technology intelligence and
expertise let's talk about it threat
intelligence what exactly is that is
that I O Si use what's a piece of it
indicators are compromised indicators of
compromise could be a demand could be an
IP but that's that's all signature-based
stuff right once you learn that once you
share that with everybody and everybody
knows that the hackers not going to use
that stuff anymore we're gonna do
something new what we consider threat
intelligence is actually knowing who's
knocking on the door what kind of FIFA's
coming in the house are they sponsored
by a nation state is it regional is it
something that only one state or
location or county is seeing is it
something that is specifically targeting
a specific vector like financial
healthcare retail this year's the year
the healthcare hack right you've heard
that the news you seen at the news they
have to go public with her hacked last
year was the year of the retail hack so
these things change the more fires money
being made and so whenever there's money
being made right actors will will pursue
whatever the lowest hanging fruit news
we've basically got a huge intelligence
database on the tools techniques and
procedures that today's hackers use that
gives us a very unique ability to come
into your network in asset so if you
have something and also be able to
create products and technology to detect
it prevented
so traditional defenses have always been
what what file is bed what Andy five
signatures beds my desktop GV can block
it what URL is bad that I want my
employees going to this fishing site
it's always about what
when it really it's about who you want
to know who's coming in the door so you
know what they're trying to steal so
there who lead you to the what there's a
person behind this keyboard this isn't
just some random thing that happens
because you opened up a spam email these
are highly customized highly tailored
attacks and they're specifically
targeted when they when they decide to
send a piece of code out that they went
through the painful process of figuring
out what the exploit is they're not
going to send to everybody they're going
to tailor it targeted so that its
successful at stealthy and it goes
undetected by other security vendors
user well-funded nation state actors so
the government of China has a building
we came out with a report called the apt
one report your welcome to find on our
site they have a building and they have
no government employees they come in on
a day-to-day basis and hack one of the
interesting statistics that you can get
from something called the AM trends
report which you can find a copy of a
takeaway can get an electronic foresight
Chinese New Years a great time to do
change request controls in your network
because that's the least amount of
activity that we see from our where
they're all on vacation all of them but
not the russians there's still some out
there but China takes a nap during
Chinese New Year their relentless when I
mean relentless even if you have fire I
come in and get them out you better but
they're coming back you know if I'm a
thief and I'm in your house and I'm in
your house for six months or more I know
everything that you do I know on Friday
at three o'clock is when you accept all
your LinkedIn ads I know what sites you
shop at I know who you email the most I
know what time you come in I know what
time you take lunch I know everything
about you your low hanging fruit now
that I have all this data I'm not going
to go when she kicked me out go try
something else I'm gonna try to get back
in the same way that I do
the first place so the intelligence and
expertise come back to that again we're
looking at about fifty billion things
per day of the ring up fifty billion
virtual environments per day were
emulating for web flows opening up
attachments in email clicking links in
email for you and on average in the
statistic continues to grow so and I
apologize it's really hard to keep these
slides up to date because they changed
the frequently these statistics we find
over 400,000 unique pieces of malware
everyday that are only seen once so any
sort of endpoint that you're using that
signature-based any sort of traditional
security that you've been told me know
through PCI compliance and HIPAA
compliance to buy is pretty much
rendered useless because you're not
going to see it more than once they can
go ahead criticized mature and they can
update it but that piece of code that
bad site that's not going to be seen
again but domain that the user
command-and-control that's not going to
exist anymore
on the expertise side last year we
delivered over a hundred thousand hours
of incident response that's a lot that's
a lot of information that we've gathered
by going into organizations that are
compromised either publicly or privately
don't know half of the ones are probably
85 percent of the compromises you're not
even aware of going in there and
figuring out what the tools and
techniques and procedures of these
families are we also look at about one
billion events per day so we have a
security system we have other things
that are looking at events those could
be events from our products is to be
events from our incident response or
assessments could be events from your
Sims again we discovered twenty of the
last 30 actively exploited 0 days is a
lot of CV's read everyday somebody else
finds a common vulnerability this isn't
that I mean these do become CV's when we
discover them but this is basically
something that nobody else can can say
and what an interesting statistic on
this 20 out of 30 eighteen of those
twenty were found by our products that
MDX technology I just discussed this is
about two and a half years worth of 0
days were telling here all found by the
MDX eighteen of those twenty so that's
phenomenal that's not a bunch of people
in a room looking at code that's a
product generating an alert that is on
something that it's never been seen
before in determining through the
behavior of that code or that exploit
that its malicious in determining what
that community control is the other two
that we found was through something
called fire as a service where we goin
in with your network on a regular basis
just to make sure everything is safe
let's talk about email versus web this
is a statistic I got from the
intelligence team it's pretty recent
however we did find another zero day
since I got this data this is about
thirty days old so minus the most recent
02 that we discovered which is called
clandestine wharf 10 in the last 20 days
seven of them came thru drive-by
download that CNN example I gave you its
ad space you just landing on a page in
your getting infected three of them used
email is an injury vector leave it or
not your employees your company are
going to open the attachment we just
need to accept that as fact it can be
the Spearfish I described about the
coach emailing you about your kids
soccer event it could be a purchase
order to the PIO or better yet it could
be something from FedEx I've never had
FedEx proactively contact me via email
but they're gonna open it because it's a
gift for them and it might even have a
password in it to keep it safe so all
the things you might even have
misspellings I mean people are going to
open it you're gonna have a tradition in
your organization you can train them to
your blue in the face but you're gonna
have new hires exiting employees and
you're always going to have this vector
of human error out of those 10 also
seven of them can be directly correlated
to nation state sponsored attacks some
talk about the Russian government Syrian
electronic army really I'm talking about
China but I don't want to be done
too much we follow about five hundred
different thread actor families that
could be from 1 hacktivists an anonymous
to the statement nations to China about
50 of them cause the most problems for
everybody
fourteen of the ones that will most
recently research does about 30 days ago
they're still using spearfishing as a
main vector of injuries or five of them
you spearfishing eight again drive-by
downloads that's just average everyday
surfing and one of them actually use
both techniques now that's interesting
that's where I sent you a link in an
email and you click on it and you get
infected so that's also something we're
not supposed to be doing but we still do
that another statistic I got from
intelligence humor I thought you would
find interesting is that lateral
movement does not mean malware so if my
machine gets infected because I had a
drive-by opened up the email from FedEx
however it got infected it's not going
to call command-and-control necessarily
from my machine it's gonna try to go to
every other machine in the organization
and how it does that is not by pushing
an executable across the line
member I said there's a human behind the
keyboard so they can actually infected
machine and take ownership of it without
actually having an executable they just
elevate their permissions and move
lateral so about 48% of the machines
that we worked on last year that were
compromised you know out of either
incident response for compromise
assessments actually don't have any file
that you could delete say this is the
bed filed as the File menu to make a
signature for make sure it's not the
network kind of a scary thing right
because everybody's moving towards end
points and and trying to figure out
different ways to approach this problem
but the bad guys are going to constantly
morphing change their game is really
about having the experience
intelligence and that and technology to
back that up because you don't have
enough
hours to do everything manually let's
talk about the impact of the traditional
model and explain what I consider to be
the traditional model this is the five
things that you're told the phone in
order to have a secure network firewall
whether to next general not just hopping
on a virus can't have any health
information or personally identifiable
information or credit card information
without a TV spam filtering and then the
other two are iffy you know maybe people
are allowed to go anywhere they want on
the web so web security or proxy up to
you and I D S IPS intrusion detection
intrusion prevention those are the five
things that if we were talking three
years ago I know all of you have budget
for that and that's what you feel like
you buy and that's your protected that's
what you're supposed to be doing that's
not working so the statistics of what
the traditional model does and if you
notice the one that says a hundred
percent of the bottom everybody was up
to date this isn't your fault that this
is happening in the network you can have
the up-to-date firewall course reviews
up today you've you've upgraded
everything you've done everything that
the vendors have told you to do and
you're still getting power in the
network so on average last year two
hundred and five days of the average
that a hacker says resident the network
now that's actually vastly improved 2013
it was two hundred and twenty-nine days
and in 2012 it was 243 days so we've
made some we shift a month and a half
off almost that's still a lot of time to
be in a network and they basically own
everything if I defeat for my house for
that long they've taken not only the
electronics that the taken the kitchen
sink and seeing if they can sell it on
Craigslist while they're still in my
house so it's it's a long time to be in
a network and it's a lot of data that
can be gathered about all of your
behavior just like we're gathering data
about their behavior they're doing the
same about us once you do discover that
some things in your network in and by
the way about seventy percent of the
time it's it's not of your own volition
you have somebody else telling you you
have something in the network whether to
three-letter agency like the CIA the FBI
it could be visa saying
hey we think your compromise because a
lot of credit card transactions from
your location people who have used
credit cards at your location seemed to
be breached so it's going to be a
typically a third party that's gonna
knock on your door in city of our
gonna take about a month to get it out
no matter who you hire that's how long
it takes to get on every single in
points if it's gone lateral see if it's
there because we're not looking for file
remember 48% doesn't use a file doesn't
use a service so we're looking for other
things on the on the system maybe access
access with elevated credentials that
now the average cost of a breach is
different for everybody so this is gonna
be the big guys who lost millions and
millions of dollars down to the little
guys who only a couple hundred thousand
dollars but the average cost last year
was 3.5 million dollars on average
so firearms approach to this it's a
little cut off over there are technology
we use our technology to do two things
prevent what we know absolutely we've
seen this before we've seen the
command-and-control before one block it
but really it's to detect things that
have no signature across multiple
sectors across your organization
leveraging the intelligence that we've
gathered through incident response the
intelligence that we've gathered through
having and points and network censors
out their email sensors out there and of
course any intelligence that's published
I'm so that's the detective prevent
heart that's going to be your technology
piece but being able to respond and
analyzed that and actually make an
intelligent decision wiping the system
that alerts from a fire I doesn't
necessarily get the hacker out when we
have lateral spread in effect so you
want to be able to not only detected and
prevented but when it does come through
when something does come through
you want to be able to contain it
understand the impact of what it did
investigated know everything be able to
reconstruct the whole kill chain and
then get it out of the network as quick
as possible so when someone asked me
like in a quick two minutes or less than
that what what is it that fire I does we
take the average hacker living in a
network at two hundred and five days in
reduce its minutes that's what fire I
does so the whole idea of the spin well
here's to basically use the technology
and use the services that you can
augment your own security team get the
stuff out as soon as you detect that
it's in the network before it has a
chance to take a copy of everything that
you do a document all of your behavior
in your procedures
that's pretty much it