morning everyone times the rock over and
this was work done with my colleagues
here
John Korean Sam so little bit about us
her we're from the MITRE Corporation
we're trusted computing researchers we
basically
our focus is figuring out how we can
make security software that is in crap
and doesn't just
you know have attacker lied to you and
give you a false sense of security
unfortunately basically everything out
there right now is crap
so charm mitre itself if
you probably haven't heard of us because
we're not for profit weirdo make
commercial products and things like that
where research and development center
works for the US government so basically
it's supposed to be a neutral and Eddie
that's you know giving advice
government as opposed to being a
for-profit contractor which is always
giving advice on their own best interest
so if you've heard later if it would
only be first things probably like CV
sticks taxi some standards like that but
even then you probably don't think mitre
CV it's just
CV and might has been around for quite a
while since back in the ARPANET days
so we've been doing a lot of talks over
the last year where
we've been to return by us apart we've
been showing that
as you would expect when people don't
understand and don't look at this
technology
it's riddled with holes so
throughout the last year I'm as we've
been you know describing
exploitable memory conditions in the
BIOS as you've been describing the fact
that
most biases are just a straight up
misconfigured to the bus pender does not
even set the access control bit so
anyone can come along the right to it
we've been basically saying fat
modern UEFI BIOS is are sort of a
double-edged sword
because they help us as defenders the
help us understand the system much more
than was the case with legacy by ASO's
but also at the same time this helps a
attacker understand it in an attacker
can reverse engineer it get to the exact
place that they need to compromise
how much easier so this talk is
basically going to be justification that
we're going to go through you if I a bit
we're going to say okay right here
that's good for us the defenders right
there that's bad for us as defenders
10 so thats that's what this talk is
about
I'm also we've put out tools like to
permit costs which was sort of the first
tool that you can use actually go out
and evaluate your BIOS find out whether
you're vulnerable
don't the BIOS try to integrity check at
that kind of thing and so this will give
you a little bit more context for
if you use copper necklace we have to
practice hasn't
as a script along with it where you can
integrity check you can say here's a
clean copy of the BIOS that it may be
extracted from a BIOS update
here's my bios do they differ if so
yes the well then the if what how do I
understand that and so
that's the other thing that is the point
in this talk to put it all out there
and it's all good well for us to put it
all out there that says hey look you can
now integrity check your BIOS
but the reality is that if you find an
integrity violation or suspected
integrity violation
you're probably not going to know how to
evaluate and find out whether
false-positive so got this is trying to
give you a little bit more
context about that reality it takes much
more than
a single hours worth of discussion to
understand it but
you know we're always willing to to
check to find out whether we have false
positives in Herne our tool so if you
find something that's wrong you don't
understand it you can let us know
alternatively we have an awful two days
with the training on this where
basically we explain okay here's how you
analyze the BIOS to understand you know
here's where the changes made
and and understand it better so this is
basically a whirlwind tour
%uh that so BIOS meaning
legacy BIOS is dead on live you if I
right so it should be a theoretically
dead because
um it's at least dead or dying because
it should be aging out everywhere
because
Microsoft required anything that's going
to ship that has the windows 8 sticker
on it
tres most of your PC is there's very few
things that are
shipping to be Linux Pacific fucked up
relax I suppose
I everything that shipped with Windows 8
requires
UEFI secure boot right near probably
maybe
sure that the stalk you may be familiar
with some other controversy around know
whether secure boot is a
evil conspiracy to destroy the nixon
like you ought to be ashamed
I don't think it is but 0 you can have
that opinion if you are
so theoretically legacy BIOS should be
going away because basically everything
all the vendors are incentivized but
they have to have you if I they have to
have secure boot
in order to actually ship their systems
for Windows 8 this as
but in reality I there's
elements in this which will never die so
at the very beginning a few if I
I'll show the whole who obligatory
diagram in a little bit but at the very
beginning with you if i
it looks exactly the same as bile sits
hand coded assembly
that's a specific to the hardware and
it's required to you know
initialize the hardware as fast as
possible later on once you get past that
stage then you can build up your nice
abstraction layers and you can have
all the niceties you if I but but if you
have a change
that occurs sort of they'll be one file
typically that'll be called the sack
core the security core that's the
encoder some we think so
what I'm saying here is if you go out
news capron case and you do by a stiff
and you find 0
the changes in the sack or I do
understand that well unfortunately
that's a big bobber Pencoed assembly
usually using a lot of PCI access
accessing an approach that you don't
necessarily understand
and so unfortunately that sort of a
lives on
that's the harder and that sort of the
hardest job to analyze
but basically we're gonna talk about all
the call the new interesting
you ship it here so you if I had legacy
BIOS
basically share to common traits so the
entry vector meaning the very first
CPU instruction that CPU ever consumes
that's going to be at the same place on
the flash chip so it
the way the hardware initializes that
reset it always maps to
address ffffff 0 so 4 gigabytes -16
that's always the
memory address where the Cebu try to
access and
the memory hardware at reset is
redirecting that memory access to the
SPI flash chip
so little flash chip down on the SPI bus
so they all start from the same place
and the initial goal and
the overall goal is really it's all
about you know initializing the hardware
it's really
its climbing its getting you to a state
where you can pass off to bootloader
pass off to an operating system
hypervisor
try to get everything initialize he
could have
you know keyboard input video output the
the big difference though the big
difference is that legacy BIOS it was
this big giant proprietary blah boast of
added that plus a whole bunch of other
things you if I is much nicer because
it's now documented that we have a spec
we can understand what the coach trying
to do and trying to understand
did behaving in accordance with that
speck so
also the you if I had as a reference
implementation which is open source and
are available um and so basically
there's a single
reference implementation which Intel put
out there and says hey guys this is how
you're basically supposed to build
something that conforms to the UEFI spec
and then the a.m. eyes Phoenix and to
know inside that the world
they go customize that at their value
add so that they can try to get
other people to buy it because if they
didn't add anything to it and people
would just start from the reference
implementation right
so they out although and gooey niceties
and that kind of stuff
and they sell it to the Dells HP's win
over the world and
the Dells HP's win over the world may go
customize it further
but there's some core initial open
source thing that you can evaluate we
that at Black Hat USA this year we
showed where Corey went and spent a
couple weeks looking at the open source
referring
reference implementation and within a
couple weeks he was able to find you
know to exploitable memory commissions
which then
as I was saying these propagate out all
those other
biases so the point is we can evaluate
the security
much much more readily than we could
with legacy buses
so I've been using the term but I'll
expanded now
if I stands for unified extensible
firmware interface
it was something that originally Intel
made when that they were trying to get
rid of legacy support and
we're all to blame for x86 still having
no legacy thirty years worth of Crofton
it
Intel tried to make a teeny in Maine on
backwards compatible 64-bit architecture
and everyone said net
to 1810 my existing applications to run
so now we have you know 64-bit legacy
Croft
Intel made this you if I reference imply
made this you if I spec when they were
trying to make the I 10 a.m. by us and
they recognized
look we can do all of the legacy stuff
we don't want to do all the legacy stuff
we've had to do for thirty years on the
x86 architecture let's build up
something that's a little nicer
a little more generic and they're trying
to have something that would work for
x86 as well as I tenia
and really can work for peanuts or any
architecture
but but that was originally if I became
you if I when they
finally got by an from everybody hand
they it was no longer just Intel doing
it but they had the UEFI forum which was
watch other companies that bought in and
%uh started doing things with it
so no although there is a
I'm although there is this nice pure you
if I world a lot of the machines that
probably you have unless you bought in
the last couple years they they often
have this thing
built and then there's this you know
backwards compatibility mechanism called
the compatibility support module
and what this is is that basically the
overall system is you if I but
then there's this big globs legacy miles
in there so that you can basically just
run
everything without having the changed
everything so cut
CSM is the is a sorta backwards
compatibility its
it's mostly going away at this point
like if you buy anything new it
hopefully shouldn't be using CSM it
should be sorta pure you if I
but but that's always still occur cause
for concern for a security problems
but the one really interesting property
of you if i four
attackers is that it's getting really
really big
so and actually I don't think I mention
it anywhere else will mention it here
it's also written in high-level
languages
it's written in C I don't think they
support c plus plus but
you've got C code building up this
reference implantation
that is sort of getting giant its 8
twelve sixteen megabytes on a given
flash chip
um and so you know big
high-level language code lots of
opportunities for
I'll typical buffer overflows and so
forth
now if you're not the kinda person who
enjoys reading thousands and thousands
of pages aspects we are we
you know we like doing that that's how
we find stuff that nobody else finds
so if you don't like to do that this is
a good starting point
conference in summer from Intel has you
know he's
integral to the you if I effort and he's
made a book that is basically a
high-level overview
but if you wanna jump right in you can
go download all the specifications
so this is what we're gonna sorta be
working our way through today
a this is everybody who does
buy stocks these days has to put up the
picture this is Intel's sort of fun
description of how emotionally you if I
works you start at the very beginning
security facing
theoretically that's for security is but
in reality that's not when you have
pre if I initialization so you've got
the well
I won't go thru mo will hit them each in
turn so there's
seven phases notionally but in reality
they're not all IOU's
but we're gonna start a little bit lower
than that
and so we're going to start sort of what
things look like on the hardware the
state's
okay so
legacy BIOS you have the SPI flash chip
or
the Intel firmware hub on things
typically older and 2007
and this is basically if you if you
think about your computer architecture
you may be familiar with you may be
heard the term you know Northbridge
Southbridge
to have a CPU he had North Bridge which
handled high-speed proposed menu to
South Bridge which handled slow-speed
purples
the SPI flash chip is hanging off the
South Bridge modern systems the
trucks in the North Bridge in going into
the CPU and
other stuff has gone into South Bridge
now there's just sort of CPU and
platform controller hub
and the flash chip things off the
platform controller hub no
so the legacy by us was basically a big
proprietary blob as I was saying each
vendor had for their own proprietary
formats which
would typically have to be
reverse-engineered I
typically have to be reverse engineered
and people online wouldn't reverse
engineered for various reasons when they
put up tools in order to
in order to a break these things apart
this order for you know analogous to
right this is a bad old days and if you
saw the for word on re:
talk yesterday but still the world they
live in they've got all these
proprietary
compressed unpacked sort of things and
if you go back up
a more than you know six years seven
years this is what you'll still see on
x86 systems
amend typically they were they look like
packed file which means you had
in order to save space on the SPI flash
chip always the vendors were trying to
you know say pinch
pinch a fraction of a penny times
million to machines means
actual money saved so they would use the
smallest possible flash chip may have a
little
a decompression routine at the beginning
so you call into the decompression
routine and expense stuff out into RAM
once RAM is available and that's weird
so nowadays um SPI flash chips
Intel mandates that you have certain
kick I'm
you have certain be are not behaviors
characteristics of flash chips like they
must be able to be rewritten
supply conder dozen times or something
like that so they have certain
requirements that they put on flash
chips
and they require that they support and
this
this notion of a flash descriptor
question scripture is sort of a data
structure that put at the the front of
the flash chip
and that then describes specific regions
within the flash chip so
Gigabit Ethernet region that has sort of
configuration information for Gigabit
Ethernet
platform data that has miscellaneous
stuff management engine if you've heard
of AMT active management technology may
be hurt if the
the talk about attacking that you know
many years ago
that contains information there that is
consumed by
the management engine and then UEFI BIOS
a region
there's sort of a bias region described
by this that's where the actual content
we care about that we want to analyze
our
from so the flesh descriptor can create
new region so this will probably
increase in the future
but for the time being that's what's
there alright
I don't know why I used animations I
think I copied from previous lies in the
use and emissions
so um with what we care about here
within the
by a surgeon in the UEFI BIOS it's going
to be organized according to
for more volumes so what this turns into
is that we have a nice well-defined
well format and firmware file system
ultimately so
I'll spec lays out that there's quite a
quote for more devices which may be real
or physical
the firmware devices are broken into for
more volumes which can be nested
speaking out for more volumes were thin
volumes
I sometimes think I'm the volumes kind
of like folders and then there's going
to be a whole bunch of files from this
folder in there may be a compressed
folder within a folder um
I and and oftentimes we see will will
cover the phases in a second but
just so you know oftentimes will see the
folders or a broken up that
all of the files that run in one phase
both the boot are in one folder and all
the files and another phase are in a
different folder
but ultimately the base unit is a flash
file and so these flash files you know
it has some well-defined structure has
well-defined you know ways that we can
find it parses
but within each file the there are then
actually separate sections
and that's the part that we ultimately
care about those that's the real file
that we care about because
a given section will be for instance I'm
that was called the dependency
expression meaning like yours the other
stuff that needs to load before this
file loads
or a given section will be an actual
portable excusable file
so as I said right here um
I when we did all the way down into this
firmware file system
we find that the different sections can
either be portable excludable former
where they can beatrice excusable format
so PE if you know Windows you know
PE is basically Windows excusable format
likes of former
and TE is the exact same thing but they
basically just collapsed and the
the headers so you know here's the thing
where
both the guy in the bag I say hey how
interesting my bios uses quote-unquote
Windows executors both
right I know how to analyze those so I
as a defender know how to analyze those
if someone modifies them
and eyes an attacker know how to break
them apart analyze them Interbrand
ida and and figure out where I need him
a
insert my hoax or what have you so
there's basically three options that you
have right now for from your filesystem
parsing
there's if I poll which is the thing
that we currently use within
copernicus is a extra scripts but
because this was something that was just
sort of put up by student was the first
one and it was you know at the time that
we started doing this it was
and what was available we didn't have to
we didn't want to make our own certainly
could have but why not use
someone else's code that's out there but
this is not maintained over time and
we've been sort of
getting tired of hiking in the
additional support and fixes and so
forth so the other tools are you if I
tool which also
this is a nice I do anything that will
see in a second here and then
there's a thing called you if I extract
which will basically pull out all of the
files from them off to your
tear filesystem and then there's you if
I from our parser
which was another thing that is being
maintained in being
actively update and and all see that a
little bit later to
so will come back to this later as
as we determine whether we have enough
time but this is basically what you'd
see in you if I too will you go you
don't pay
for more filing hear something to pray
to stumps out something you extract from
a BIOS update file
you don't fit in here it'll slice apart
and say here's the different regions
that the flash descriptor defines
there within the bias region you can
actually expand that out and you can see
all the individual files
cell will like I said we'll come back to
that
but for now this is just to say okay
there's a an easy way to start getting
information out of the cell files
so from both the attacker
and defenders perspective right
standardization is a good thing
right so standardization help the
attacker find that
okay well I can now analyze all bio says
for all vendors and a nice easy way
and that also helps us though as a
defender right so we can now have
generic integrity checking software
breaks everything apart the same way I
and and
gives us more semantically meaningful
information about
okay what was and I don't let just
telling you hey there's three bites
different at offset 2004 and
57 I tell you that within the dot tech
section
a portable executable file that's called
nopee I initialize memory
that is where we find you know i three
by changing table tried to jump
instruction right so
so it works for against just have the
standardization
right but but the real question is who
chose to move faster attackers and
defenders Ryan
field
so
the sec fazer security face is the very
first
notional phase this is a binary blob
love
hardware specific code needs to get the
system
up and running as fast as possible in
just pass off to the a PI faced
notional you can see here it says pre
verifier
hopefully that's somewhat readable pre
verifier should theoretically be
the corridor trust for measurement there
should be an ability from within this
code
to measure the rest of your BIOS and you
know confirm well you're not even bother
with confirm just get a measurement
and store after some trustworthy
location like TPM so that
you can actually say something about is
this code look like I expected to see
to look in reality um
a last year black and we did a talk
talking about you know how these static
route to transfer measurements for a
fundamentally broken
but but there's additional technology
that's going to be coming into place in
that war
improve that but notionally they had
this idea of the sex phases where the
most important security stuff goes down
obviously if you compromise the system
this early if you compromise at the very
beginning if you tomorrow
by the very first instruction that the
CPU ever executes than you
are in you know the most trustworthy
position you can modify
manipulate and make the system lion for
everything else that happens thereafter
but the security phase
hit executes from a flash chips are
actually is like living in the flesh out
there is no RAM initialized
and then it moves along and that's what
I one per
thought I had some where the security
phases and misnomer in reality all the
%um security critical things the
verification of digital signatures the
measurement up for the BIOS
on actual real platforms they don't
actually match that name
they do it much later and that means an
attacker coming in earlier
will always win um
I yep that's where it should go over
that some you know is it's a good thing
purifies another one have many great
examples of how things can be
architecturally correct
and implementation incorrect right so
it's all good to say oh well I see that
they're doing the right thing in the
architecture must be okay
right that's why we have to go in and
actually evaluate things so a
miscellaneous point which i don't wanna
who dwell on too long is just that when
you're building up the system there's
multiple paths that
that this will take depending on the
sleep state it wasn't so if you just
reboot the system
here you know coming from and of stating
you're going to go in
important point which will and the only
reason I mention this
is that which there for a reason
described here is that
there's different when you when you want
to explore the potential for
vulnerabilities on the bio she have to
explore that there's different code past
that'll go down depending on whether you
just went to sleep and woke up for you
want to hibernate you woke up are you
coming from a cold boot
and so the sleep states there
ACPI sleep states um but
as I said they go to different difranco
paths so what we've found in what we'll
be talking about later in the year
we've got a we've got a whole bunch of
all abilities we've already described a
collision on abilities that are still in
for
disclosure we're having the vendors fix
them we found situations where
I you may have a system into practice
may say
0 this system is currently locked its
configured correctly it's protected
that's good
but then you put the system to sleep and
you wake the system up and
the BIOS does not do the right thing
upon wake and it doesn't lock things
down that got on Sat
as a consequence asleep and that means
then you know all it takes is one sleep
in one way can you back to the normal
system which
hun laptops is you know pretty
guaranteed to happen
pretty quickly rent so we'll be talking
about that
later on later in the year comments 0
actually there was a
specific issue and I'll machines that
they patched quite a while back like
last december we just
haven't got around to to the problem is
its
it's not a full conference talk with a
fresh it's just a went to sleep
came up its its got its horrible no
so wherefore adding that in combining
that with some other problems too
to get it to be a full conference talk
with information so
um teletype reparation up a sec phase is
responsible for is configuring the CPU
for cash as RAM
this makes it so that even though the
Rams not actually set up yet
by the time you get into the next phase
the PI phase you can actually have
see code executing in the
in the PI face because if you don't have
a stack if you don't have this ability
to push in pop
then you can expect that normal compiler
generated code will actually work that's
why sec phases Hanko to assembly whether
doing their best to never you know try
to use were you know memory or temporary
space
but once caches RAM is initialized then
you can have fun
compiler generated code running and
then it you know has two activate the
the main CPU
so forth so originally
so in the the full version of this we
would go down like everything and talk
about all the stuff but
but this is just too to speak to you
there's a there's a place in 2008 paper
out there were they talking about
reducing platform boot I'm so
you may know that going along with her
windows 8 secure we are also
requirements such as you must you know
for you must put
this fast well if you put requirements
on the vendors that they must move fast
in the most beautiful early
there they're probably gonna the boot
fast one is the easy one to achieve it
at the expense of the boot securely
help
so this just to say that if you're
interested in that kind of thing there's
a nice Intel
pic white paper out there that you can
look at for reducing
good times that talks through all of the
this can also be used to understand like
what
the bio says there may be doing in each
phase you can say well maybe the vendor
was trying to implement this and they
were
you know this is why the microcode
update is right here this is why the
caches RM is right here
but ultimately when a sec faces down
this is where the niceties of
standardization comes in
there's going to be some hand off to PI
so it's initialized everything its got
a sec faces responsibility is taken care
of and it will now
collect information which it'll pass to
PI that information includes things like
top information about the operating
environment such as where the temporary
RAM is like how much cash israel has it
actually initialized
location of the temporary stack location
of the boot for more volume so this is
basically
a for more volume as we were discussing
before on the flash chip and its tell
you here's the offset to the firmware
volume
so that you can start decompressing or
no just pulling in parsing
the information in order to boot all at
the PE I've Face coat
and her
yeah I'll Lister yeah thats and probably
shouldn't even talk to you
so on the PI face their pre
if I face this a lot of work goes on
here but then ultimately much more work
will go on in the taxi fares
so its job is to initialize permanent
memory so this is where you actually
initialize RAM and you actually get the
system into what you would think I was a
normal
running stay it also then you know what
that initializes memory it has to pass
that off to the next phase and say here
you go next phase you can just assume
that RAM is initialized
it describes there's a a variety of hand
of block serve
Afghan meta data that I must pass on to
the next phase and
and ultimately yeah and its job is to
you once it has executed all the PI
phase hardware initializing modules
then was everything's complete it will
go ahead and pass the next phase
so in the PI phase we have this notion
up im pre if I initialization modules
so panels are the types of things we're
now we've got portable excludable files
well-defined things on some systems
there P e's on some system there TE's
but they're basically this nice modular
format where different chunks
have code handle initialization have
different hardware and
also very interestingly they have a
well-defined structure where
they I'm they create to basically API's
for each other
so they say I'ma p.m. that handles
no status reporting information so I
handle
like writing to a console auger I handle
writing to the flasher dialoguing type
thing
I'm going to register a PIM 2 p.m.
interface and now anyone who wants to
log stuff
they can look up my p.m. 2 p.m.
interface and they can go ahead and call
into me and so
although the a although the binaries are
your portable external files they don't
work the same way as like deals on
Windows they don't like imported the
allow that kind of thing
what they do is they have this
well-defined interface the pink
pp eyes where you look up things that
you care about so when you're writing
the code you say
at some point I'm going to need to call
into this interface that's defined in
the UEFI specification for
here is how I find that the logging code
right so I just to look up
logging code I get back a pointer and
now I have a
data structure that I can use to call
function pointers with an echo
so this is going to be a.m. sorta
interesting and
an analogous thing will happen in the
next phase so
there's the registration the PPIs
there's a PI dispatcher so this is the
thing which is basically going to chew
through the firmware file system it's
gonna say okay
I see that there's a dependency
expression NEC expression says
I can't load this module until these
five other modules are loaded so again
doesn't work exactly the same way that
like an importer dress table
poor names table that kinda stuff in
Windows would work there's these files
on the firmware file system that says
here's the prereq for this file
you the dispatcher must go off and put
all these things and run them and now
you can load this so the dispatcher
asked and the logic for them
home and she know it handles the
firmware volumes and
services such as so this is where
there's some core services
within the PI phase such a so that
each I'm so that each p.m. can have an
expectation that it can
find other ppl as it can find other for
more volumes
so this this again is where
so if I pick up the pace will will get
to see at the very end where
I'll you know how code actually uses the
sort of tables but
um this is a data structure that you can
assume like if your reverse engineering
the code
you can say I will expect that this data
structure will be passed into the main
function are given pin module and so
when I see it off said it when I see it
doing you know
pointer arithmetic and I said going okay
this pointer plus
32 okay now I know that that's whatever
it is
plus 32 anode probably be reinstall PPR
so you can start easily figuring out
this mythic meaning
love I'm you know the code sexy
utilization of ocean porous because what
I'll tell you is that
when when you're looking at the code for
these things it looks very much like c
plus plus code and I mean that in the
most
annoying way so see first post code you
know virtual functions things like that
in direction calls through
calls through function pointer tables
that makes it hard to follow control
flow that makes it difficult to
see you know it cross references on a
given function and see everywhere that
it's used
so that sort of interaction is used
extremely much
in all of the PI phases you're always
going to see things
referencing through the sort a function
pointer tables but
at the end of the day with you know some
appropriate you serve
above idea importing of data structures
you can actually
I
it can actually lead to making very
semantically rich
yup silicone so this is how I should
think I'm the PI phase it starts off
you got the dispatcher and then it used
for all of these pins on the firmware
file system
the polls each of them in excuse the
entry point figures out what the
dependencies are
and and does this nice series ultimately
once it's done with all the payments
then it's responsible for finding the
Dixie I P L initial program load rpm so
this is a PM
but it's only job is to kick off the
next phase that the Dixie face
so and let's get that interest time you
can read it later
so um head of blocks then
as the PI dispatcher finds the
the Dixie I P L its job is to take these
hand of blocks well define data
structures
past them into the next phase and then
I'm
the Dixie phase will know where the
memory is it all know where the firmware
volumes are
and so forth so the Dixie phase is
honestly the most interesting face most
the time because
the lot of the stuff that goes on in the
the pin faces just hardware
initialization it's pretty
I wrote it's just you know if you have
this particular chipset you initialize
in this way
the Dixie phases where all the
interesting sorted for secure boot
things and to set up a system management
mode
all of the I love a good juicy bits are
here so
from a high level view it works in a
very the dispatcher within
up Dixie works the same way as the PI
face so
there's sort of 11 mappings between they
just you know at a high level the
structuring of the Dixie Faizan
PI fazer the same so where is indeed NP
I we had Pimms these PI modules
in Dixie phase they're called XE drivers
PI dispatchers just like that exceed its
dispatcher just
goes through the firmware file system in
fines all the things and load them in
order appropriate according to the
dependency expressions
the PP eyes these p.m. 2 p.m. interface
is a way that you register
for other code to be able to find you
and executing invoke your code
that's called a protocol in the Dixie
face if we talk about a Dixie protocol
were saying here's some Co
that I've registered and I let people
look it up and let people calling and
then just like the
the sack or Dave data to PI PI gives
this world find a to the Hobbs
to I'm to the sexy face so if you take
that exact picture and you fill in
Dixie 4 p.m. and dick CIPO for
boo phase up it'll be the exact same
thing
so I was saying that basically um
the there's all these function pointer
tables which are used I guess I didn't
highlight the the red ones last time but
the ones that we sort of care about from
a security perspective and honestly
that's probably not that visible on
their you there
doors we care about our things like
trust and
process for more volume so there's this
there's this data structure the Dixie
service today structure it's going to be
passed into
the main both the Dixie phase code and
it's going to then
that raises going to use these a this
function pointers in order to call
the sort of core Dixie services the
trust phase
also a process for more volume that's
basically
if I'm a taxi driver I'm going to you
know call process for more volume in
order to find
another from where volume in order to
find some other code that I want to load
potentially
and that processing potentially you know
this is just
stuff which is implemented by the Dixie
core processing you know any time
there's
parsing there's a potential for a
exploitable memory conditions parsing
miss mishaps and so that's you know one
obvious place where %uh vulnerabilities
could happen
these are the things they're just you
know I O space memory space access type
thing
and then trust trust is kinda
interesting because it basically says
I'm going to mark this for more volumes
were three information I'm going to mark
this excusable then unloaded
loading as trustworthy and then I can go
ahead and run that
so fundamentally if I me know you if I
rootkit
I can just you know go ahead and hook
into something and call trust on and
then it's going to
just bypass any other additional
additional checks gonna
bypassing the church X and so forth in
addition to the Dixie services table
there's going to be a whole lot of
a function pointers for use within this
past Thursday Dixie services table
there's the boot services table
this has then the install protocol
interface reinstall protocol interface
on install
a protocol these are the things where if
I wanted to say that someone else should
be able to call into my code I will call
install
protocol interface and then someone else
will
a where is it there should be a lookup
lo que protocol somewhere don't think I
highlighted it
but the National Register notify its all
restaurant was interesting because you
can say
I know that I'm going to me this
protocol and call me back whenever you
get around to loading a
Dixie driver that that actually
implements that so you can have call
backs where
later on it it invokes your code once
the
prerequisite code is actually starter
loan imagine start image those are
basically image in this context
is no portable external files this is
loading
actual execute herbal colon so that
starting up to
and open protocol is call into something
else area
lo que perk up so three pages worth a
fortune quarters just in a booth
services table
but something more interesting than
others and finally then there's some
even more function pointers that
available but this one is especially
interesting
because our in a way that was admitted
again
runtime: services table it's something
that
the Dixie phase has access to but this
is something that persists into the
wrong time %uh the operating system
so it's set up during the Dixie face
there's going to be some core Dixie
driver that handles the
I'm handles the back behind the scenes
code for each of these function pointers
but whereas those other tables boot
services table and Dixie services table
those things are sorta gonna go away
once you get past the bootloader they're
sort of
for buyouts use only and then they're
gonna be recycle their memories can be
recycled when we get past the bootloader
to run time: services table sort of
sticks around forever
and this is meant to be some from this
is meant to be sort of an interface
from which the operating system can call
into code that was provided it
to it by the by the from work and so
this is a potential place where
sort of less privileged coda
an operating system can pass information
for processing to more privileged code
the firmware we called for more
privileged because it sets up things
like system
measure mode which can exist behind the
scenes for ever so
from a black at this year we had shown
how
from from Windows 8 it exposes this
runtime services so
although it's called something else
really you're calling it an API which is
really just a
a front and to set variable and update
capsule
so utilizing these
the ability to call into this function
pointers we can sort of stage
information which the BIOS is going to
consuming process upon Expo
and we'd found these exploitable
conditions where
I we could create this update capsule
that has to do with BIOS updates
essentially so
we can create a fake BIOS update for
love non signs but
memory corrupting information create a
fake update reboot the system the bio
says oh I see that you for
you've part you staged a BIOS update for
me I think I'll go ahead and parse that
and then ultimately in the in the
process a person that it'll
a choke and die and the attack roll game
code execution at the very beginning at
the system to
for the set virtual address map is
cervical you know it interesting for
people like me who do with memory
management things like that
basically like the runtime services
table is sort of left around
but they don't really have relocations
per se
in the same way that normal public
schools are relocations and Windows
so when you first want to access runtime
services table from an operating system
you just sort of scanned through memory
find the table based on the signature
hey what you find that you call into
this set virtual address map and then
it's going to sort of do relocations on
wherever the bio stock this in memory
you the operating system or you the
attacker have mapped to this into memory
at some location you're telling the code
have matching a member at this location
to fix yourself up for me for that
policy here
hardcore in constant turmoil at the
right location so and then
even beyond the exploitable update and
there are other things were just the
ability to access you if I for more
variables has a
has allowed for bypassing set variable
if you may be heard of those cases where
you know they were blaming latex at the
time but really it's a firmware problem
but they were saying
you know people in exon the Samsung
laptop it will
brick your system right I was a case
where basically
I'm the latex was using
the you if I non-volatile variables in
order to save logging information at
some point we just sort of exhaust the
space available for
variables and so they were using a set
variable in just filling it with long
information
and then eventually a a biocide choked
the the Samsung or eventually there is a
Lenovo example as well
last just choked on too many variables
from minute refused to do
so in terms over relative magnitude of
Pimms versus Dixie drivers
you can use these for more parsing tools
and you can see that you know if if
there's 65 pins there's 279
a 678 taxi drivers so there's many many
more
taxi drivers they're all like
registering these protocols and talking
amongst themselves and
you know implementing in a potentially
pretty high level things
on will we'll see here at the end again
if I
move faster will see like the names on
some things from which you can't order
in for that they're doing pretty high
level things to do in graphical things
they're doing
there's I don't think there's going to
be a name specifically that you can
call to that but I know that HP at one
point had this
value-add to to allow you to check your
Outlook mail from
the BIOS so like you know goes Splashtop
operating systems where they said look
takes one second to boot and then
they've got like a browser and you've
got
your email and everything else right so
so that's good from sort of a usability
perspective right you can
group to just something quick but that
means there's all that sorta code being
implemented out by us level
up tough problems can be there
so um I've already made reference to the
UEFI non-volatile very both
I'm just and waved over them for until
now because
um basically in your legacy bio says you
have this notion of CMOS her
NVRAM non-volatile RAM that's already
configuration information but that was a
pretty firm has a very limited
amo
space that by spenders would total bit
there in second trick information
in UEFI you have this well-defined
um will data structures cologne
following variables:
and these are stored actually on the
flash chip so there's gonna be some
amount of code in the flesh up and then
there's going to be this data is not all
variables on
flash chip and those are used for
configuration information
already spoke to that Samsung Lenovo
case where
theoretically just fill up the variables
and you can break the system
home and then also there was
there was a these exploitable conditions
in the past
a was so P I'm a touch the variables a
little bit for instance with this
speak my last update was checking for
the presents were born variable and when
it found it then it and start invoking
last update:
but but typically it's the Dixie face
later which utilize them
so this is just to say what sort of
attributes
unfollow variable can have it all fun
inspect so
non-volatile obviously they can all they
can be
they can be volatile but we care about
non-violence
both services access means that it will
be accessed up through boot and that
it shouldn't be accessed thereafter
runtime: access this is the one that we
sort of
care about a lot this means that it's
going to be accessible
later on when the operating systems
running from within that runtime:
services table
hardware record not that interesting
authenticator write access this is
something that not
this and the time based authentication
these are things where it makes it much
stronger than
in the bad old days with CMOS with CMOS
anyone who's colonel can just go to put
all the bits one-third
reverse-engineered
with authenticated non-volatile
variables
they actually have digital signatures
well they don't have their signatures on
them
the gatekeeper the code which implements
the reading and writing to the variables
it will make it so that you cannot write
to this variable
unless you have provided me a digital
signature that actually is signed by the
key of the platform manufacturer signed
by another key that you betta den
um and so it makes it so that anything
that's important can be stored in these
variables and lock down so that
it can't be manipulated by an attacker
um and yeah
so if something's
both runtime: an authenticated that's
you know where you would put your
typical security information but if you
see wrong time and not authenticated
that means it's open to attack a
manipulation and so in the case of the
set a variable stuff this was something
where I just said that the gatekeeper
is the one who does the you know if
you're okay with this is assigned
variable so someone has to check the
digital signatures like who's gonna
check that
well for most implementations that
someone like system ensures modes when
you're calling into the runtime services
table
that shouting into system management
mode code which is in a protected by
virtue
just being in system and remote but then
if you have a misconfigured buy a house
where anyone can writes the flash chip
that means you can completely do an
end-run around the
the gatekeeper their authenticator of
these variables
and are consequently you can just modify
stuff however you want and that was this
up this chart is art attack that we and
presented earlier in the year
so almost to the interesting
things about the the most the
interesting not all variables most
important authenticated non-volatile
variables
are the keys so the key storage in this
was sort of where the
controversy with the Linux things comes
from their part for manufacturers who
are shipping
Windows 8 certified things they're
obviously going to have
Microsoft Windows 8 key in the I in the
in the within the BIOS as one of the
sickies it'll typically
typically be the platform can so
you've got these notions keys that
platform key there's key exchange scheme
there's signature database information
database so we'll start at the bottom
for been database this is a blacklist
I love you if I modules which have been
found to you know potentially upon
abilities and so they can and a black
list and say
don't ever let that signature database
there's a waitlist where
you can just not even have to care about
keying and you can just say I want to
put a whitelist entry in
for my you know bootloader or whatever
and then you can just put a system so
the whole notion that you know you're
somehow being locked out of your Linex
it was as simple as adding a waitlist
key for a boy who are you didn't even
have to do that
whole thing with you know signing with
the Microsoft hear anything like that
they chose to do that
because they were going for the easiest
most least painful way
in order to make make the system but so
but then you know in reality most buses
they're going to give you an ability to
go in at whatever keys you once a week
you they could have said oh you're going
to add a third or key you're gonna at a
red hat ke
but as if you go back and read the the
articles about that
they're saying we evaluated many
different ways are doing this and we
decided that just signing with Microsoft
key
was the least pain for everyone but it
is absolutely possible that they could
have just done it many other ways where
just manually had to you know said a key
for instant russia's I suppose I should
say it well
I should I'll say it later everyone
bottom
but these these kids themselves their
authenticated variables there
they're sorta written into the flash at
manufacturing time there
sign they were they're marked as
authenticated so that you're not
supposed to be able to touch it unless
you actually are so you know
doing the update with Adele key but
again if you can get around
the signature requirements you can
obviously got my father to
do
I could have already said that
1 miscellaneous thing although we
haven't talk about here
there are other protection mechanisms
within the BIOS things like protected
range registered for the chips that can
say
this region of the flash chip is not
writeable and no one should ever be able
to touch in
the thing is those protecting those
other protection mechanisms can never
really be
applied to the you if I know involve
enables the the variables are always
sort of going to be
a little bit vulnerable more honorable
thing not the code itself
because they can't be marked as pure non
writeable
because if their runtime access variable
they need to be a reliable on the fly
so that's sort of an architectural thing
where I
we can potentially get around it I
already mentioned so
dick scene system as remote or best
friends forever
um system and remote is the most
privileged execution domain
on x86 system I wish I would've put in
sort of a Intel manual picture
but I'm just to remind people or
to inform people who are aware of it
right you have your typical Cebu it
reboots into real mode real motive is
your Platt no protections dos
sorta load anybody can access anything
eventually an operating system
your bootloader moves you into
protective overprotective mode gives you
your
ring 0 your ring 3 gives you paging and
things like that
off to the side there's this notion I
love up
system measure mode and it's the biases
responsibility to put code in to a
location that's called system management
RAM
and then it's going to lock down that
ramp so that basically SMM code
can execute without interference from an
operating system and it sorta execute
upon
just management interrupt so Dixie phase
is the one who's responsible for
actually
instantiating SMM code as some code I
I should put it on here should put a
nice little a people attacker SMM
is almost always to the attackers
benefit over
the defenders benefit because it's an
architectural place you know
think the way it was put is Intel
created SMM to allow for confidentiality
and integrity in those sound like good
things that are nice right
but unfortunately it's not your
confidentiality integrity it's the
platform manufacturers confidentiality
and integrity
so just the way it works is you the
platform manufacture the bias maker they
put code in there
and the Mako gets locked down gets to
run in the background for ever and you
don't get to ever inspected at runtime
so asylum is sort of the ultimate place
to hide
if you look at a black hat like at USA
talk from earlier in the year we showed
you know we just said here's a
proof-of-concept
here's a flag in the ground shares in
SMM attacker here's what they could look
like
and you know security vendors can't find
this then they shouldn't
pretend to be giving a security so SMM a
sort of the
it in the Dixie face so if you break
into the system at the Dixie phase or
before and then
you should be able to compromise as a
man have this code
that invisible running in the background
capable of supporting everything forever
right now both
to boot device selection phase this is
just the sort of very a
short short of intermediate phase it's
going to be a single txt file so when
Dixie passes after the BDS phase it's
going to be some file that
handles selection of are going to boot
from a CD year gonna move from a hard
drive
bootloader the kind of thing and
insides are gonna go for next know it
should be sort of
if this is a boot manager if this is
determining where we're going to boot it
should be clear that
basically by this time a boot file
system access and
you know potentially network access if
your gonna do a network boot
are all set up and so the Dixie face has
created all of these
is nice interface is these abilities all
these obstruction layers
for the BDS doesn't have to know how to
access no
fat verses and tear NTFS or anything
else
this you if i interface get set up and
it is allows you to just call into
I'm call into API's which handle all the
obstruction for you and that's why
they're so many Dixie
drivers they're supposed to set
everything up for eventually the butler
for the one thing I want to highlight in
the picture here is that when we talk
about you if I and it sort of hidden in
this picture
the unified interface is basically a
thing for the bootloader and you know
this other stuff for the next phase
this is the interface by which stuff can
call in
and have all these obstructions pre-made
for it
and the runtime interfaces down here as
well and that will persist forever
where's the
you if i interface will go away
eventually first dip
so trendy load phase this is kinda
interesting because
arm you can have transient OS
absent applications running and so this
is one thing that potentially works well
for us as a security
as a defender you can say okay well I'm
going to do my system and I'm going to
start up an application that actually
you know checks reads into the you if i
interface
does evaluations whether or not though
system calls are hooked on that kind of
thing
arm but even at this phase we have
it to denies unsigned applications so if
you want to do this you either have to
wait list your applications
where you have to sign it with what his
platform keys console
there had been you're extremely lame
talks about you look at me I'm a UEFI
boot kit
except one of the main reasons unifies
even being used as because I've secure
boot pit stop things that are unsigned
yes you can make a bouquet if that
signature verification is off
but that sort of his stupid so there'd
been very stalks there been
typical boot kit third bindle kids
running from you if I
I'll from option runs and things like
that and if this is the general point to
boot kit we know that like
there's a standard methodology for big
kids they start early in the system
but really they can't just live there
they have to sort a bounce their way
down into operating systems corrupted
data structures turn of security that
kind of thing
that's the sort of standard methodology
and you know
this trip transient application North
Africa OS absent application
gives us this ability that we can run
security tools early pre boot
Intl evaluate and assess something about
to the you if I
interface as well as the operating
system now this doesn't help us at all
the tact as a member attackers and
things like that but it does help us to
techno
trivial typical a function pointer
hooking
your typical rootkit type techniques
alright then there's the runtime phase
and basically im
at some point when the bootloader is
done it's going to call exit food
services
that's an API within the you if I
suspect you call that API and it
basically says okay anything that is not
marked as runtime
accessible memory will now be recycled
thrown away and only the runtime
interface should
should maintain then there's a
afterlife race which in reality is one
of those things where they specify they
say maybe someone will use the someday
but as far as we know right now
nothing's using it notionally you could
think a bit like the system's going to
go down you would like to have a
graceful way to maybe
clean up some information that the BIOS
stored in memory alright so where to
secure will come into all this
I'm just but through all those phases
quick so
secure boots job is to basically make it
so that I'm
you know you Yahoo why did Microsoft
require secure right
well because Microsoft is having their
lunch eaten by having both kids
which can turn off all the security
right it should be obvious that like
there's no architectural way that you
can protect any operating system Windows
or Linux or Mac
unless you have some security pre-book
workers if the bootloader
successful the boiler can be overwritten
you can compromise anything in the
operating system
writes what they're trying to do is pull
back the security to earlier make it so
that if you want to attack and you have
to go
as deep as possible and turn we know
that most attackers don't do that
so the point is to pull the signature
checking back so that
you can say this is the bootloader than
expected to run and this is the firmware
that expected to run
and so I'm going to reuse some Intel
group lines because I think they show
that the best way
so the first thing is that
for more signing its evaluated typically
unfortunately it's a value-added knots
or about every Boone up by hardware
not in sort of a architecturally secure
way it's a value added at the time that
you're about to write something to the
flash chip
so maybe the existing bias checks it or
heaven forbid
just you know and application within the
operating system checks in some vendors
have done that
at some point but the idea would be the
existing biases their
it was written it was unknown clean
version at the time it left the plate
the by a spender checks the digital
signature on an update that's about to
be written to the flash chips and then
it just left the entire thing onto the
flash chip
other thing here is if you can get onto
the question because there will be no
subsequent
checks that means you can you know
always subvert the secure boot
right from the very beginning because it
doesn't check it every time just checked
that at the time that it's written
so you know angel here would say well
you know that's unnecessary performance
optimization that kind of thing but
tell it is what it is so then once you
have this
notionally just presume to trusted
content for the flash chip
that code can then actually check if you
have other applications other
bootloaders
other you know option runs that are
signed you can check the digital
signatures on those each time so that
these things coming in from left
trustworthy sources can actually be
evaluated to
to determine whether or not there
manipulated and ultimately Windows 8
secure boot
nests on top of you if I and the then
start
you know checking their operating system
loader itself so the
you if I boot loader is checked by sort
of the the bias itself but then the
bootloader has been checked it's been
confirmed to be signed and then it can
pass to an operating sys
system specific bootloader alright
so the good thing about secure boot is
that as I said it sort of the only way
that you you have to pull the security
checks back to an earlier phase in order
to not have the operating systems P just
architecturally sober double but this
works in attackers benefit as well
because
um you're going to assume that the BIOS
is secure
and then you're going to say well secure
boot protecting me and then I don't need
to go check my by Osram
so like I from running a little late but
fast enough that I can show you
something real here so now we're going
to
pullback look at some of the type of
information that's that's a and
that's put on the firmware file system
and you know give you a sense for now
that we know
these phases and what's in them
that kind of thing I'm know we can
see what kinda stuff is all mixed
together here in the flash chip
bias analysis for the detection advanced
system to version that's our project
I was gonna pick
a random BIOS and that's what happens
when you pick random bus this
mostly whether it works though nope
think the x1 works
no
alright so I'm in a zoo means that
things will actually be visible to you
but right this is some examples above
what kinda stuff we see down at the bus
level just if I'm attacker I'm a
defender
way which one is 10 ago sorry for the
pixelation but there's our dicks remains
that's gonna be the first Co that
actually execute
then we have things like system runtime
Dixie SystemVerilog Dixie
clash verify SMM okay if I'm an attacker
and I want to server SMM maybe if I
subvert the flash verify SMM I'm going
to
just for free be able to get in there
CMOS access Rex
as a man CMOS access from Dixie %uh
system variable
from SMM but I counters so
basically if I'm attacker I go through
here and I say okay what am I trying to
attack today USB
network access keyboard controller and I
just have these nice
well named human-readable names where I
can sort of get
a shortcut to access whatever I want to
compromise
but this works for us as defenders
because when we go out and we do you
know
slice the spice apart do hashing on each
of these for my clean version in my
dirty version
I'm I can tell you specifically that you
know you had a modification in here
I can pull out the specific portable
excusable file and I can partially
tatters and I can
I get additional information so
as expected to be going lower but um
war couple last things sub-zero diyo
I'm not promoting gonna bother for full
screen it in cuz I feel like it's gonna
crash
sub-zero to i/o is a website
where Ted Reed has taken his you if I
for more parser
and he's made it I like this sometimes
when I'm on a machine where
I do want to install the paper I'm
prerequisite to get everything compiled
I just like throw up for something into
subzero that I O and that'll actually
parse the BIOS
it'll pull out some other metadata and
as irv a couple days ago
he's also started taking the matter can
purchase output about whether or not
your biases notable
and he's put that up there as well so
basically we're
we're starting to work with them on the
Site and its gonna be basically way to
crowdsource a determination of okay with
a hundred different people have
submitted a
you know Lenovo x1 carbon at basra
vision 2.56
there can say well 99 if those guys said
that
the hash for this particular thing was
this particular value but
one person is an old iron one person has
a different hashed and everybody else
also
we can start you know pulling some
notion of what's good and what's bad
so you can go check out that site
sub-zero that I O
it has the ability to produce reports up
there as well
in the next day or two will be taking
will be reborn link apprentice with a
little script where you run to purchase
a dumpster by also tells you you know
you're gonna wear not
which can also just the had a little
script that awesome it up so we can
start
getting that crowdsource notion up for
by a screen or not
what sub-zero doubt I O can't do right
now is the bio stuffed up I which comes
with practice the actual integrity
checking up here's a
clean version here's a 30 version they
still have to do that manually
and I figured I wouldn't have enough
time for this but
if you go grab the slide later you can
look at a fifteen minute video where I'm
sort of going through the process and
saying here's my clean version is one
dirty version
run by a staff hey there's a change let
me look at the raw change in by its let
me pull the to ePub files parliament I
to
a you know analyze them and most
importantly use those data structures
that exist and are already well
understood from
the you if I spec very very nice
capability with an idea to import
header files just standard C header
files and then apply those data
structures to
the BIOS and then that makes its that
when you use I X rays in order to
decompile stuff it makes for very human
readable code
for some value human readable so in
conclusion how what you decide who the
with the angel is and who the victim is
here but the angel said unto him
you if I said it to him stop hitting
yourself stop hitting yourself
so you if I brings a improvements for
Bhutan security
so that I you have some ability art
actually to actually get rid of
I'm these booth level attackers who are
just completely subverting
operating systems otherwise um think a
purchase
has made it so that we have a too low
its freely available you can use corn
download it run it
you can start having some notion that
whether or not your system is notable
because for many years people would do
by us attack talks inmates a
well as some members vote a belief this
bit is not set and you ask them what are
you gonna release a tool that checks
that bit so like I know whether or not
they say no no that's so easy you just
do it yourself
welcome prick is now has combined all
the information that is currently known
about bias water bill is whether they're
exploitable vulnerabilities or whether
they're just miss configurations
and it gives us this ability to dump the
BIOS compared against other things so
we know actually have this my
standardize way if we tried to do this
for the legacy by SS
we would run into this whole quagmire of
how do we decompress I love the random
formats
so that's why it only supports you
refine your stuff for now
bone and that's going to be a
so with that I'll take any questions
out to the side have two words let
people get to reflect Speaker I saw the
next talk earlier
so I i think you should check out a
false talk next but
they what else you're free to go thanks
up