so my name's Dhabi outnumber my twitter
handle same as my name it's really long
to prevent people from tweeting too much
I'm the senior director trust at UMC and
I'm gonna talk today about to do
security
so only have a couple introductions
first told about myself
so from 94 to 2004 did a whole bunch a
different security stuff candidates
myself but I've been doing this for
twenty years
ands it was really interesting but I ran
into space on the slide
so in 2004 early start working in a
bunch a different histories
like job now so it was interesting
because they're putting robots on the
planets and had a daughter really cool
stuff with the robot sensing and
the working around data work in
astronomy a bit before that West Marine
was a
a large retail company that with huge
amounts of customer data on protecting
that Yahoo of course we had
billions of devices which a billion
users when I worked there and had to
work I was in charge of security on
mobile devices on digital home
television's
that sort of thing we put in a lot of
data begi maybe her to be GI
a Barclays Global Investors it was the
world's largest trust fund manager two
trillion dollars
I wanna business and the crisis well got
bought turning to Blackrock
after the big mortgage crisis but in the
time I was working there they sucked in
more
ailich dated anybody in the head which a
PhD is that sat in mind
the trends and quantitative analysis to
figure out where the market would go
so all we did was basically build big
did environments for them to
predicts how not to go to business which
didn't work and then
2008 or dark side resin charger
compliance are it so the tools that
allow people to be completed by looking
at all of their
a continuous monitoring data 2009 S one
of my own company called flying penguin
there and after a few years before him
she acquired min 20 13
I'm so there's no is flying penguin
because my company but I'd been running
that for about to
I just almost 20 years since 95 I wrote
a book called securing virtual
environments which may be really
ambitious I thought while I can
a lesser worker their salvation in 99
and so by 2012 I thought I just tell
people what I learned how to make secure
or cloud environments I'm secure how to
make a virtual that environment secure
and I wonder right securing big data
with the ambition
for my first book and Wiley is my
publisher the kinda suggested I continue
on and I realized
pretty soon after starting at that even
though I had a lotta back
round in these Big Data Systems you can
secure big data so the talk is about
today
I'm trying to be a brutally honest
because I feel like a lotta
distributions
I'm being distribution companies they
want to sell you on this technology
the same way PC manufacturers want to
sell you on distributed computing in the
eighties
sore right around like a maturity scale
1988 89 PCs
where he connected to the Internet your
pretty much done so it's their gap thing
at the eighties
we're talking about with Hadoop again
and I want to avoid summer the same
mistakes I'm trying to put in
perspective love
if we're honest about this we can start
to fix some other major issues with
Hadoop
you talk to a distribution company and
I'll tell you pay
we're doing great things which is true
they're making changes but
reality is quite different iight so
this is basically what I do is director
trust people ask you are funny title
what's my job really what I do is try to
help people understand how to create
trusted systems
and for me it's boiled down to three
things after year so
going around the world talking to people
all companies all sizes are trying to
find ways to get more transparency so
people can see
the risks they have a trailer help build
relevant tools
so like my virtualization book was
basically saying a lot of these old
concepts are good but you need new tools
API's are more important than ever
management consoles more important than
ever
so use the right tool for the job fire
also do you much good
if you can see into the networks behind
the virtualization layer saving big data
have a firewall around your big date
environment all the risk is inside it
doesn't matter if I'll
really and the resilience is seems to
matter more than
ever before so people just don't trust
systems that they go down
people expect an always-on always ready
always accessible environment so that's
pretty much what I do
and I always run into this dilemma now
which I call the Sam Jackson audience
dilemma
so basically breaks down to two parts
and you're either a one more time error
or an
option every no talking about alright so
when wertheimer's are
stop talking about big data one more
time I'm sick of hearing about this are
you know everything there is to know
just give me the really hard core
technical details not get out here
the others are Abydos movie this another
sage action movie
are obscure 96 ish
way says he already knows we make an
assumption to make an asset me an option
so the ideas either like don't make any
assumptions tell me everything
explain to me how MapReduce works or I
know everything and it's like hard in
the
Big Data world so how many people here
run Hadoop environments themselves have
set up and run had given by matts
today okay just couple people and how
many people have
successfully entered a Hadoop
environments will set up use did
run a job few people get
so I commit to any assumptions I do have
a ton to slide so I have like a hundred
slides and it does not include how
MapReduce work so as a quick
intro basically with MapReduce does the
way the concept of Hadoop
is just distributed computing its to
make jobs easier
by reducing the load to individual
components
so if each one of these rows for example
was a resource
I would ask the person on the end of the
row to count the number of people on the
road with glasses
that I would go through and say all the
people the into the road give me your
account
that's it so I've now basically map this
whole audience
in two rows and the nasty each had a bro
to give me the count which saves me a
lot of time even better I can ask the
person the for the row
to map although counts from the head of
the line so now I've just got to people
to talk to the give me the results from
this entire audience
make sense that's MapReduce right that's
a dupe
so let me tell you a little bit more
about where it came from so 1996
there there's a guy talking about how he
could take a 24 no bail of cluster
and he could make the equivalent with
sixty thousand dollars
over a ten million dollar supercomputer
this was the genesis of Hadoop this is
where it came from beta of
and was called Babel because in the bear
wolf poem
this old Celtic poem here the poll
actually says
the translation I think its Danish 30
men's have to the grass but his hand
so Mayo of was so powerful he could do
about 30 men's work by himself that's
the whole idea right so it's been
coopted quite a bit by cool and a lot of
other people try to take credit for
what to do biz I'm really by 2006 became
open so that really matter
where it came from but the Genesis is
people trying to do great things with
little bit money
and so today we don't talk about the
same way
a beer at what rate used to mean we're
done
array of inexpensive disks right now its
independent disks because no one cares
they're inexpensive all the stern
expensive
same thing with a dupe its low latency
fault tolerance and scalability
no one talks about how cheap it is
anymore because all distributed
computing is cheap
essentially we've been in a race to the
bottom and commoditization
helps so we're looking for low latency
fault tolerance capability what I'm here
to talk to you about today
is how there's latency there's a lot of
faults and it doesn't really scale well
because I've limitations a lot a risk
like like building premature you build a
castle wall you can scale much
because this is your town is outside the
castle wall yet to build another castle
wall
and another in he cities today up twenty
million people
can't be sustained by the castle model
right so
that's where the problems running into
alright so here's today our data like
definition
we're moving away from big data as a
term in towards data Lake
the ideas you have streams a date all
pooling into this thing and do analysis
I i don't like the 3v definition which
car to keep up with in 2001
mostly cuz I'm not a huge fan to garner
but also because I've been trying to
stick the fourth be in for a couple
years and no one let me
so the 43 for me is more ability and
it just didn't make a lot of sense to
people I was trying to say that if you
have so much data it becomes vulnerable
that then you know you have big data so
now I think it's more popular to be
called re identification
which is a give so much data you can be
ratified then you have big data
so for example you tell people you can't
have a zip code
in your data because that sensitive or
birth date that's for its been proven
that about eighty percent of the time
you can read into by people who have
just one little data point
beyond if you have three total but you
have one that sensitive so you put your
zip code
or your postcode whatever you call it
where you live and
they knew it also have in that data set
the name a doctor
so near the doctor of course is somebody
who works at a parts
particular zip code erred postcode so I
can really identify people bite
figure out where the doctor works right
so now if I know your doctor I can just
simply one step away with another
dataset figure out
the same thing you're trying prevent me
from knowing so I add enough data bases
enough data sources at some point I can
read and if I you
and that's one big data becomes big data
because you have that we had an occasion
issue I called the four R's
I came up with that on Talk Like a
Pirate Day so
that's not just by coincidence so by
prediction is why most people it's gonna
be the norm for data management because
I can't monetization like it's becoming
less expensive a day to Lake its
consolidated who doesn't want
centralized and cheap
by just this is the future of technology
and so let me give you a couple call
examples of this go through this quickly
that I'm working on just give you a
sense
how powerful big date is becoming I'm
working on a clear water projects where
fifth the water and the
in the world the the water that's
freshwater
company Amazon it turns out that a lot
has been polluted by things like
petroleum
and digging so if we could put sensors
out there who can map all the places in
the Amazon that water has been
contaminated and we can monitor and then
restore the quality the water
we can make a huge impact on how do you
do that you have to put sensors in the
jungle
and you have to within 24 hours test the
water cuz the water degradation
and with the port in to keep it safe
because a lot of pressure points for
people to
corrupts the results right people want
to make sure that your results don't say
what you think they should say
so it's an example I'm here's an example
above a group that's trying to reduce
orphanages
I work for the recently not directly but
indirectly
other trying to figure out why there so
many orphans that still have parents
I like at the parents become more
sustainable families and so we need to
put sensors out again very politically
charged
subject so how do I collect data in
remote villages about so orphanages have
volunteers so it's like a distributed
problem above data collection to solve a
major
risk issue and I'm actually interested
in this i love you know you know but a
lot orphans end up doing strange things
like a suicide combat like suicide
bombing missions in the end up getting
recruited into military conflict and
strange things we wanna get
the level of organs down by
understanding why they're so much
conflict
another interesting project I'm working
on United Nations war crimes commission
we had forty nine trials in nuremberg
and tokyo to earn a trial surrounds the
the time at which
post-cold-war with you know we did go so
for example that turns out from 4348
there are about 2,000 trials
that were secretly just been and
uncovered so if we can get that data in
mine it and then provide that resource
to lawyers
then they can actually do with
classification working properly
they can go figure out you know what
would you do if there's a rape would you
do if there's a
genocidal acts because lawyers base
everything on precedents and there's
very little precedent as the point here
but I can generate precedent and so big
data becomes knowledge
teaches people you know how to make
decisions more informed decisions
so here's some more contemporary
examples our traffic
you wanna know where to go and how some
cars now telling you what speed to go in
order to avoid red lights
summer telling telling you how to the
new Volvo tells you how to avoid an
accident
just automatically redirect you every
time there's a traffic incident now this
is an actual architecture built by
pivotal which is a a big party BMC so in
just all the data and then surfaces
these cool graphics
so you can see what traffic looks like
I'm energy out of you know but
you know each turbine sensor has a lot
of sensor so it goes back to the IRT
model
so we're generating up Library of
Congress print collection every month
in terms of data because its 500
gigabytes per day for each blade and you
can see many blades are not typical
turban
may be familiar with his turban seen it
before yeah your place this with a
a big win like you see out here
sometimes they can get as many as 30,000
sensors
why cuz they're reading in it's like
weather forecasting the transportation
it's it's reading in the
directional Aaron or to figure out which
way to turn the blade just like sailing
so you try to figure out the optimal to
get the most energy so
tons a day to be incurred created by all
sorts of sources
this is where you might see the security
conference which is the RC model taking
in all your sensors
and putting it someplace storing it so
you can do analysis to find your attack
vectors
I'm they have one in my not tell you
enough but if you have all of them
it tells you where your threats are
right so I guess you going through these
all day
are couple funny ones here is a social
analysis of tweets
in San Francisco and it's hard to see in
here but basically
the red iPhone green android you see a
pattern or the Android people are on
ferries
that's like the ferry terminal and that
a ferry path across the city and the Red
a scattered evenly across the the bay
which to me says rich Apple yacht owners
verses pour Android
ferry writers right so
instant knowledge I if you look at the
Downtown San Francisco area
you see the BlackBerry users
congregational circle uses for like a
half circle there
even a guess what is going on over here
in San Francisco why so many BlackBerry
users to congregate
but blackberry Office close but not
quite
government User Conference I don't think
about that
no but city hall that was my guess is
also a federal building but that's
actually further left quite a bit for
the left
I to get outta like federal map to map
all the federal building's
I nope they actually turns out to be the
Apple Store
Twitter asked me how I figured this out
by the way after a
a show this to twitter they're like we
get this data
so its public debt I just use the
public's or so here's whether anybody
know this is
this is a weather mapping system it's a
radar system that
track so what kinda storm is this
basically what's happening here let me
know
that insects
so apparently global warming is creating
this insect buoyant so these are
mayflies exploding and their pictures
there to discussing even show you
love towns just covered in insects so
this is an explosion insects one night
picking up on it so it basically tells
you want something strange that when you
have and
a detection system you think about
security detection and you to
false-positive like this
it like throws off your ready I go I
gotta be a huge storm coming out of the
river
which makes no sense alright so quickly
any guesses what this is you know which
side is random
looking at that insects there is a hit
there
how do people say the left side is
random you'll see the right side is
random
as a turn to the left side is random
because the connections
on the right side the insects actively
trying to keep space from each other
and so it actually comes from New
Zealand you can go on the salt or
utica a little boat in like it's a top
at the cave the glow worms
seek get interesting things may look a
lot today to but
are on the same level this is the
bombing map of
London by the germans and if you dig
down actually looks
very like non-random I guess in a way
because it's like we can see even
distribution here but the further you
dig down the more it starts look random
cause our actual very
clear lines and patterns so apparently
the Germans are mapped out exactly where
the bomb every run
mice a live in London so I went lookin
looked at my house it's an interesting
thing to do
in bomb site you can do it live they do
this today actually so this is San
Francisco
this is insurance companies big did
analysis of where the bombs will hit San
Francisco author terrorist attacks
and so they rank them by severity red
obviously most extreme
I'm gonna goes on and on so this is what
a blast looks like this big debt
analysis a blast radius
after terrorist attack like which way
the bomb blasts go into urban versus
rural area
and then this is what smallpox infection
looks like as it spreads through the
middle
the midwest the United States that's
Chicago Illinois I'm
and also Saint Louis and so you can
imagine they're doing this already with
people that we talk about a lot but
actually this insurance companies are
very accurately predicting
these outbreaks or
they spread using big house I could go
through millions examples this is health
care this is the amount of %uh
data that's in each ejaculation of sperm
so 31 petabytes a second updater
which is Google's only processing 20
petabytes a day
so think about that for a second I'm
actually on that point 244 trillion
gigabytes of data in human cells
so you can see why you know talk about
big data analysis and health care gets
into this like while so like
holy grail of way to really understand
everything we do the math
others annable a prediction chart they
were of anybody know why a bowl
predictions are of
is really interesting so it's called the
gödel project is a guy
his very ambitiously trying to suck in
all the information in the world all the
conversations to try to see where
bowlers first any missed it
well as English is an English tool
and a lot of the infections were in
french-speaking countries right so I
miss that
so adding French hopefully the Germans
don't have a disease next
with the bottom line here sort spooky
because if you take this analogy as
you know big data he wants the literally
listen to every single whisper in
every corner every party the globe in
order predict the next disease
verses a distributed model which would
be like a why don't you
have a conversation with somebody and
through are a hierarchy
like the actual detectable with you the
hierarchy so the local
healthcare like a hospital said hey we
have a problem or to the hospital so
that a problem to the government the
governor report tonight
patients rights that a hierarchical
local distributor based system
and this is a top-down like listening to
everything will figure out where it is
first so
he was slower than the distributed
system which ironically
he's running on a Hadoop like
environment which is a distributed
hierarchical system
right so is almost like answer his own
question I'm
is not running a mainframe so here's
2009 dual
said that they detected flew faster and
their flu project was heralded as you
know two weeks ahead heralded as the
future detecting flu
anybody follow this and we see this
every
know that it was wrong for three
consistent years so today we look back
on and go wow they really were way off
but it came out as we can predict faster
and it's because there's a rig
algorithmic accountability has been one
of the problems
it's sort of like a it's a box inside
the box things are happening
and we don't know exactly what's
happening so this is the allegory for
the prom with Hadoop you trust these
systems and then the wrong
a lot of times so here's the audience
operating system
anybody heard that axiom so if you're on
Facebook you're like run an ad you wanna
make sure advertising to real people
with real
needs not just fake bogus accounts and
and facebook says you know they're
keeping down 25 percent fraud or
something which is ridiculously good
versus other systems they're just open
so they have this audience operating
system
type analysis to prove that somebody is
real but then if you go do analysis of
the data
this is a woman who look at our own data
and she challenged in said I can't
possibly be 26 years old
with two children who are 14 and 17 you
think that the system would be able to
detect that because those are simple
numbers it's simple math
it should be able to know itself but it
doesn't right humanistic a look at it
right so biologically impossible
here's a quick quiz on knowledge in the
past
so anybody know the disposable diapers
story by Arthur little
you know you know why we use disposable
diapers instead a cloth diapers
so he was able to manipulate the data
and the news marketing to convince
people is environmentally
better we use less water it's like
better to put into
landfill that it is to use a a a towel
or a diaper that scoff
so it's basically a manipulation at the
marketing data to prove to people
something that
basically isn't true we found since then
the people who go back and look at his
analysis like this makes no sense
there's been a lot of criticism over but
it's too late the market's already
pushed towards disposable diapers
a frozen coke 0 spent too much time on
but basically Burger King had sixty five
million dollars on the line we're gonna
invest
and Coke was saying wow all the students
are buying this
frozen coke you probably wanna have it
never Burger King
and it turned out that somebody was
paying students
at all the local schools to go to Burger
King and buy frozen coke literally
giving them about your
so that would turn up the results so its
wholly bogus results and then finally
bacon my favorite example
one of them I'll at anyone heard of the
beach the company and Edward
bernie is he kinda invented PR invented
manipulation of the media and and
marketing so the reason we bacon today
my argument is and a lot of people say
this
is that the case is he was able to
control the
the consent to the masses to eat bacon
before then there really wasn't much
consumption bacon and the the pork
industry was in decline and Beechnut who
was selling a lot of pork wanted a way
to sell more
so healing a study that said nine outta
10 doctors say a big breakfast is good
for you
to bacon and that every thought leonard
and doctors say bacon is good for you
and then that turn the market diamonds
are other example archaeological apples
were basically
marketing since the turn of the century
has been trying to get data
to turn things into knowledge and the
knowledge becomes like
big big money purchasing decisions so it
was a dupe is really doing
to do is getting people knowledge to
change everything changed people's ideas
elections
so that the scary part there was
security capabilities up the data lakes
are embryonic
as a gardener quote which has gotten a
lot of press but they're basically
saying hey we're still in the early
stages of security
on the system's we need to trust the
most and the model that we see a lot
is if you store everything I like the
CIA quote which is you know you can
connect dots if you don't have dots
so this store all the dots
and so they can connect them and if you
can do the right analysis which could be
trying to convince people to
eat bacon if not bad for them by telling
what's good for them because some doctor
said so in the analysis
that's winning that's winning the
marketplace so you can build the right
tools for the right people
and get them to use it and it's all
based on this idea analysis being like
looking in the rearview mirror
I find that funny because when you look
at the rear view mirror
me know where was invented big hit here
race cars
so the first rear view mirror was the
the Marmon wasp
in 1911 so wasn't as Indy 500 race and
the guy put a rear view mirror on
because I could get rid of his passenger
the other guys to look behind was a
mechanic basically it would look behind
the cars coming
in order win the race you gotta know
where the competitors are so the rear
view mirror was a
a winning tools away just like we're
talking up Hadoop it's a way to win
everything the market but I looks really
at the idea race cars I thought wow okay
so if they do business giant powerful
engine that makes us so much more
powerful
then is there a risk situation like in
race cars
where if you lose control you lose
everything actually turns out to be true
we blow but you can buy me it's pretty
devastating if you put a lot of trust in
it
so there's a real picture guy getting
thrown out of his race car he was only
bruised
but but this art but see built in the
race is eventually
and it would take about 45 years to go
from my rearview mirrors
to seat belt so kinda curious how long
it'll take us to get from this rear view
mirror
Hadoop to the seat belt to dupe great
where we actually protect
data and if I look at the seat belts
it turns out from 1885 to 1970
or early 58 when they first went into
use there's quite a bit I'm
and the the turning points were
criticisms over engineering
so we really need is the equivalent of
criticisms of Engineering in Hadoop
like criticize a dupe and talk about
prevention is the only cure for bad
Hadoop
rates is to you article seem to be that
what people think seat belts are just
because regulators but regulators got
the idea for people pointing out how bad
things were and this turned out to be
doctors
so who are the equivalent today I've up
a new doctors
right these are the things that have
doctors would be saying but you have
immutability by design
so you should be able to change files
but in fact you can go change whatever
you want pretty much anywhere
happens all the time and resiliency is
by design but we're finding outages all
the time
so even
amazon says you have any availability
zone but then the Availability Zone goes
down they say what doesn't mean
availability of its availability zone
it means you have to connect multiple
availability zones if you want a bill
ability in your availability zone
and so we get security mode by design
you can turn on Hadoop security
nominee view security but his security
literally has like us which you can flip
and say ok am in security mode but it's
not actually secure
weird like availability zones and so
traction a complex a ecosystems our
problem and that is not
terribly usable for not very technical
it's a lot of Java in fact a lot of the
tools coming out now which like aP's
essentially
are just so you're at the touch Java so
it's like taps for aP's
because people want to deal with it a
lot other thread assumptions in 2009
that came out the original security
document were based on
no man in the mills it's really hard to
do if you let people into a printer and
they have open access
I gonna stop someone for sending the
middle row that's not protected that it
assumes that users don't have root
very difficult to do because that
standard open fireman
guess everybody root level authority you
have to work really hard to get the
levels down
and then there's no net controls another
assumption which doesn't make sense if
you already have
a somebody with Rick control of course
they can control the neck so
pretty hard at go with those threats
options the ecosystems are pretty
complex
if I was the describe the Duke to you is
a nutshell what it looks like
this is sort of how it works you have a
storage layer which I go to detail after
if you want to know how it works
and then you have a computer where which
is like your PC or any device your
laptop it's like you have
a hard drive and then you have a
processor but that's just distribute
over tens of thousands of systems
so you're trying to basically secure the
way would secure inside your machine
across a wide distribution network and
then on top of that you have your app's
and the app's give database access you
can scripts
on top a bit I you can stream data I get
a couple examples here in a second
and on the far right is the security
model which if this looks familiar
the to the PC model it's because that
would be where the antivirus it's like
after you've built your entire
architecture now you can install
anti-virus
and I'll be this thing they just takes
your lawyer security which turns out to
not really take your security
and twenty years later we realized why
would a cock up that was so
there are a lot of projects which are
worth mentioning here Knox Rhino century
X a secure Falcon also have independent
running on there
own and it's a quagmire over discourse
right now what they really gonna do
so here's an example %uh scoop
is the just like the name za implies
scooping it up
and putting it into the environment so
that's great you know you wanna scoop
like my single database that is also
today to scoop into Hadoop
part make it part of your daily other
original version was ac- alive people in
like command line interface so they made
a
graphical version called scoop to which
is not compatible with security
mode so if you want to use the cooler
newer version you have to turn of
security in your entire Hadoop
environments
so it's pretty big compromise another
example is storm
anybody her storm so if you wanna do
like really fast and all sorts of data
likes a tweet so I see who's following
tweet sandwich URL's are getting really
between the most
you can't just do a scoop because I
would be static data and by the time you
look at it after processing
who knows how many new URL's are being
followed so stream Armin storm is going
to stream that all the time
and every time you get an update its
gonna tell you like oh wow there's an
update
and snowstorms than she does this it has
the spouts and then these bolts
that's what a characteristic of a dupe
is really bad naming and really bad
icons and like graphics
so spouts in Bolton its it's terrible
but anyway
the you use storm and you can get these
real time updates and the really fast
but again it's designed for that
identify me the highlight enough in the
it's designed for scaleable
fault-tolerant
use data right fall color is built in
it's the architecture for fault
tolerance because as multiple
a services running but it turns out that
it actually feels really is really
brittle
and if you do weird things to it is this
one person said it breaks
and a focus for upcoming releases will
be security
so in future or build security into our
fault tolerant system
I'm in fact here's what my favorite
quotes you know what I can get it to
work I just do it are minus RF on the
entire storm directory
and that seems to work to get started
again any
any problems with that in a multi-tenant
environment if you're deleting the
entire storm directory for everybody
yeah he says makes really do this and
developing a bar with the yuan
don't don't ever try to do don't ever
try to fix this is the fix but I'll try
to use this in a production environment
alright so psyched about seven ways to
kill hope for the future an overview
I
will go pretty quickly through these so
first so I believe
you know and this is or using from
capitals model I believe we should look
at it and steps
so you have the in just after pulling
data and you're storing the data
somewhere
with Chad self is a big security issue
you're analyzing the data
which I showed you can be manipulated
into weird results and the new surface
into these visuals which are coarser
suspects security and then you take
action upon it which you upset the map
back to
accurate results and security so my
argument is that we should be able to do
at least six things to protect it
and so I'm reading a book about it and
these are the six things in advocating
in the book
and then the seventh because I forcing a
missed talk seven things to do
would be GRC on top of that which i
think is important but
this is really the best audience for it
so quickly through GRC yeah I loved your
Shiba
you have to be careful we talk to about
it so here's an example zombies versus
terrorism this is an actual honest to
god insurance chart that I pulled from a
big data company
so they're doing over you know with
return period
loss by parallax over 5,000 years the
loss from terrorism
is quite high was the loss from zombies
is quite low we know why
and I guess is songs are predictable
zombies are you there zombies are not
zombies worst terrorists like everywhere
anyone if you could be a terrorist for
different organizations and doing
different things and connections are
very fluid and so the loss from
terrorism can be very very difficult to
like avoid
and very very complicated and this is a
personal to be honest I change the names
that really zombies
but something equivalent is obvious this
is a personal issue mind a lot of people
talk about the zombie
issue in security information security
and I'm like not hard you should the
Rideau there is always a not
it's like the simplest thing ever so for
a GRC mode
going back to my experience with the
guys building robots for Ford planets
right if you have robots to have a
little bit intelligence then they can do
certain things but ultimately the end up
in traffic jams for example
which we do in our cars as the police
predicted with the synchronicity song
it's like you you don't really have
visibility to know they're gonna run
into a traffic jam
unless you're in God note which who
actually uses the word God
and so they're able to look down and say
will route everybody different
directions
so governance risk and compliance is
really about having this
up level view it's like in
Big Data environments really having a
god-like you to know where to turn the
trouble
and so we're trying to move away from
the simple in the theoretical
the chess game essentially into the go
game which is the complex the real
I mention go and just because a lot of
people talk about what's in
and you know chess and how computers
beat humans
adjust Irish by flair that even your
phone can be your chest not very smart
but if you put ago game on your phone
you should not lose to that go game
that they're not very good I still lose
so embarrassed to admit that have not
that great ago but I do play all the
time trying to win cuz theoretically I
should be beating it
and the problem is that there are 130
thousand moos
in the first move in go but the early
400 moves in chess so
a lot of our advertising about how cool
computers are in these big did
environments is directed towards things
we win
not towards things were computers fall
down and every node is Eminem's are
present
suffering out the brown Eminem's even
know van Halen
ever Van Halen used to have his rider
you must separate on my
so this is basically game 3 where he is
like in order to understand my opponent
in order to win this
very complicated exchange i've a
fifty-page like you know we put a bigger
sets and is also supplied shows not
understand whether they're done any that
properly
he had this buried in there and if he
went to his dressing room and found that
they were just
brown Eminem's he knew that they read
the whole thing and probably followed
everything
unless they were gaming him which is
possible but because I was sorta secret
he didn't tell people he assumed that
you know they did or they didn't
and then if he found there was mixed in
you that the whole thing was often he'd
have to let go and check everything
because maybe things would fall you know
so it's it's like the avoiding the
spinal tap outcome
but using game theory with Eminem's
alright so that's your CNN not showing
it high visibility and have like
real threat modeling which we don't do
it to do we don't threaten model
as you can tell you can have roots that
are you know assumption but of course
already has roots also got some policies
like that
but security like as a policy oftentimes
means
access restricted trusted personnel am
and then they try to do this through
three things they do encryption
authentication and authorization or to
enforce
some idea of this policy the problem
being
like authentication as an example we
don't do it very well so security mode
as I mentioned
like if you turn it on you basically
moved from where you use pseudo to run a
command
to re-run k in a tournament you're
familiar with herb ross
you have to get a ticket before you do
something so in pseudo you have to be in
the source file
which is local often scan bureau but
mostly local so he moved to curb ross
you're just asking something else for
authority
and in big large distributed
environments that can be a pain
so it can slow things down so you tend
to put tickets and instead
above caress tickets you give tokens
that are
not expiring we'll talk about the second
but here the point really is that if you
want to destroy an entire directory
you just do but pseudo HDFS as a user
and then the the command are minus RMR
so filesystem mice are mars the same
thing as
are minus are UNIX as our future on can
at UBS consider pseudo say Kate at minus
K
giving Mike up took Mike ticket from the
key tab
which sits on the temp directory by the
way which if your gonna head open
firemen and it starts to have problems
they tend to turn
the temp directory into 777 because
that's a smooth things out
that so things are going to the temp
directors are like the tickets for
authentication
so you see the problems of the compound
but so anyway that's
and other examples MapReduce job kill so
if you want to kill the people's jobs I
say this a lot
you know you just you Canada you wanna
kill it with a a ticket but
anybody know why you wanna kill a job
where jobs were important obviously
so you kill somebody else's job 0 what
they're doing
who cares what they're doing my jobs
report which leads to artifacts for
example so so it might be running a
report and the be like oh my job done
early
all this run these results and wheelbase
are
for cheap purchasing decisions will buy
bacon now because my results show this
because until the job early so and if
you got other conferences like I try to
speak at the Dube summits and stuff
quite a bit
and I find the guys that talk about
security those generally say it's a real
pain in it these are the security
experts on state saying this is how to
secure Hadoop
and they say it's really hard so after I
told you these authentication tips
like turn on curb Ross it's actually
hard so I don't recommend doing it but
it
if somebody comes along like an auditor
a security person says you have security
then you may want to turn it on but
otherwise good luck
alright so here's an example of what I
was talking about anybody seen Blade
Runner
so the concert the blade runner's you
have these replicas these robots and
they go away
do things for you and they come come
back you don't want them to come back to
hire blade runners to kill them
well their living longer they're
supposed to live so
by the fall in Hadoop response to these
jobs at live 24 hours or seven days max
and it's a simple text file that tell
them they can't live longer and so this
is essentially what they were predicting
1968 with
a Blade Runner they're saying you know
eventually those jobs don't wanna die
and I'll try to keep themselves alive
see if to get people give people the job
a fine and killing jobs which is what
i've seen
part it's because you can see the client
would get the curb Ross relationship
so if things everything securing cool
but behind the scenes
your job tracker which member House like
the rose your job jackets figure out how
to count the rose and the sign
roles to for accounting for the down
it's actually give it opens out to
authorize all of the distributed nodes
to do their job
so the more year giving out tokens and
the more you're spawning jobs the more
you're sort of
down the road giving out more and more
authentication capability
and so eventually have jobs running with
tokens for ever you gotta go kill those
guys
so cya monitoring I'm wondering is a
a real problem because the this really
different all these different
products are using right every app is
written by different groups patches got
not doesn't have a centralized system
our way to to keep track everything
and of course everyone's got almost
reliable authority and we recognize this
it's an album cover any guesses I love
hidden stuff in my presentations
this is the roots is obvious
you listen to the roots prohibit now
anyways he ended with a lot of people
having root level authority
you can put in other levels abuser but
ultimately to run the environment
somebody has to have ruined will go in
and make changes and a lot of times I
find a
give that control to several people know
to keep the jobs running I'm
and again it's hard so really it this is
an opportunity for me to go off a little
bit on how modern will change
Amy recognize this as as lines in
gravel could be lines and Sandra for the
beginning I talked about the
the Stingray so can you tell which
direction somebody's walking here
and we do any hunting or tracking
walking to the left
for joining this way
my right
your left
yes this is somebody who's walking steps
that way and then decided group I'm
stepping into a
ok a detection system and then stepped
out and ever look at those old like
Japanese gardens where they like the
sensuous doing as its you know I can
tell
imagine trying to go back and cover your
tracks in the sand pit has lines that
have been
created by Mark has been practicing for
thirty years there's actually setting
honey trap sir the setting
traps for you to step into it so this is
outside National Building in Silicon
Valley
that I was working at nine or so it
stepped into it so take a picture
but the ideas as what we need to get to
you in big data instead of thinking
about in terms of syslog like am I
reading
you know an individual log up individual
system I worked a lot with VMware on
some other
the cloud security we try to move away
and still trying to move away from the
idea that we're just
walking the system the system instead
looking at the overall view in saying
are we seeing steps
in San which gets us to the IO ti world
to so if we can actually pull in
information from lots of sensors we are
not be super accurate anyone sensor we
just pullin
change overall so for example here's a
big did environment where
you have like a web server you have your
sales machines you have your call center
and they start to feed using flume which
is I
kinda the fast equivalent of scoop scoop
you scooper database and flew me just
turned on in like your weblog for
shooting to HDFS
so if you're pulling all your logs
basically out of these
into HDFS then you might use storm right
to sort of capture them in real time
so you can have a web interface I have a
cat but it's basically a user over there
trying to figure out
what's going on at all those things so
that gives you real-time analysis of
what's happening and then inside you
still have things like a
MapReduce which is trying to get results
so it's counting the number people
glasses on
and then pig because people hate using
Java is a scripting language
as a job this morning I suggest that in
a row to rob is
you know Rob Robert No
okay so he was saying that he counted
the number of times the FBI in their
speech said the words like snowed in
or said children because he saying like
if I do a word count
out same thing as me County number
classes in here if I do a word count I
can prove the FBI's being orwellian
so I suggest that we should do this for
all FBI speeches ever and then seeping
into a trend analysis
to see if they're being orwellian
overtime the speech but unless orwellian
then eighty percent the other
rally in speeches that given he's doing
a point I'm analysis a political theory
I wanna do long-term like trend analysis
a political theory
so pig a as getting back to the point is
the scripting language so I suggest we
do a pig word count: being a double
entendre
pig Rekha I good joke so
has a long job so whose he is a
orchestration system that's basically
going to help you manage your MapReduce
your pig because not only is it hard to
write
Java and deal with H base DC right pig
Latin such a call pig latin instead but
then you might get
up tired of doing it by hand so you have
a busy schedule it for you
which is like every time something new
comes in every time the call center
picks up a call
it flags and so is he figures out okay
should run the script to update my
results
tonight in big data analysis in real
time using all these pieces
oh my god how do you like this right you
gotta keep track of everything happening
all over if you're looking for risk
it's like you gotta look all over and on
top of that people start at all
databases to
this is a recent graduate real story
came in was you know fresh off the boat
and said I will have access to the HDFS
environment great you're really smart
so here's a sequel interface and she did
drop table and destroy the entire HDFS
database 296 hours to restore
the data killer so it stayed in the
database and so
Hadoop saves a lot of time unless you
destroy it and then it actually adds a
lot of time
can slow down quite a bit so controls
are important so as a final point what's
happening is your getting these this is
the pivotal distribution what you're
getting is all the green represents
add-on services which is again like 30
antivirus models like after Microsoft
gives your operating system
a topic that you can add stuff so you
have command center you have better
sequel engines
and they have their logging command
center gives you the ability to
like if people come in you can log
keystroke logger all their access
your bill to premature essentially
around your environment by using a
distribution
if it has the right mindset right to
access control
yard authorization is interesting so
yarn is a new version a MapReduce
I'll be no yarn where they are
not the response once I give you a
certificate to Amazon for fifty pounds
we say
have used yarn
okay so I do actually have a couple gift
certificates but we'll get to that later
so the authorization is funny because
the
you see the top level says everyone star
SEO no one is
space right I auditing for space
so I'll little level words as users and
no group so if you want actually
authorize users
and not group you put your username and
a space
but if you become a space that's okay
cause I would your next user
but space means no group right awesome
so groups though users would be space
Man Group
because there's a space before but the
group name then the campy user
but its common space there would be a
user not
not user art so with that in mind
if you go to these environments dubin
virus you'll find a lot of times they
put star in a lot
and the reason they put starring is
because they say you you have to
its is the default setting for stall but
you can't take start up some jobs
because
there the random it's like going to
Gmail or Yahoo Mail
you can't basically access control list
them because everybody has access to
Yahoo Mail's they can get their mail
you can't predict who's gonna come and
check their mail unless you have a and
access control list every user
two billion users not gonna happen so
instead we do %um a secret Atoka
right if I know my secret and getting my
mail account so this is the theory
behind yarn
I for certain jobs they're exploding
tens of thousands of jobs
you have to have tokens distributed
properly but what I said about opens
before
I gets worse alright so also in a little
bit the next section how bad it is
but tokens base we can be delegated or
tokens can be used over again
and they don't die so I'm depending on
access control lists not working star
because I can give tokens that are tied
down
you may see this till the tokens you can
go find things their star access control
you can get in for ever
so other controls really needed I here's
a good example how printers are built
so in this model of access control on
the left is your ad hoc
are your development environment where
you have users with accounts you have
tickets every time so he logs in
they have a ticket and then you get
tickets that expire so
sounds good right on the right is your
production environment where
you give batch account access the
tickets come
key tabs and the auto renew so it's like
the production environment
is built to run for ever and the user
development environment is meant to be
locked down
some backwards right so it's interesting
to me that you see this you just don't
want to slow down production because
you're right you're driving the car in
the race you want the rear view mirror
and you just gonna slow down so you got
everything for
performance scale ability ASI turn off a
lot of controls you might have it was
just like you know your daughter
learning to drive
arts authentication providers get pretty
interesting
if you have your users and then you have
your services assume use but these two
you want to give services
infinite control there a lot of holes
you can poke from the usual air into the
service layer
seeing coming through SSH we were able
to kill tell it off you know
chaos but we weren't able to kill off
HTTP so people can come in through web
HDFS without encryption
you get the password many go through SSH
there's HDFS client goes direct to
storage
there's a MapReduce client basically the
idea here you can get to any
a job tracker or name node name nodes
are going to deal with your storage
so if you wanna get access to storage
your attack that gonna get access to
jobs
you got to the tracker so
the main promoters this is how when we
were trying to deal with it you have
an Active Directory domain in your
company and you build a printer inside a
dupe
so you would lock down the Hadoop
environment and then obviously you would
share
just a little bit of information if you
don't exist inside you can't login
and we're gonna share just that we're
going to create a group that could help
users
but of course people can still SSH
indirectly if they get the credentials
but they know the HDFS username
credential they can just come into
directly
bypassing our perimeter to do work and
so we might put a bastion host in the
way
and enforce these guys to come into the
bastion host which talks the Active
Directory now there's no way for them to
get into the spirit are some pretty cool
that's basically how to deal with it but
it's not differ from the enterprise I
can
let your imagination go wild you can
easily you know that bastion host being
compromised for example
you can collect all the credentials and
I dupont fireman on for all the users
so vulnerability management another fun
section
I'll go quickly there are three CDs
known for Hadoop seems that a shocking
3cds a clutter little special credit
because they have three of their own
so total is overlap there's five total
seabees how many
vulnerability think there are few search
in
the jeera over dupe jurors there but
tracking list
any idea how many bugs there are
vulnerabilities in G roe versus how many
TV's there are I don't know there's so
many
yellow cedar and I do job on it so
here's an example to talk about with a
delegation token this is a real
vulnerability I found in the jeera
so delegation token show up in the URL
the URL gets rental Aug
the oral has your token it this is like
when those mistakes that every church
you know web programmers make where they
put up token right into the URL
is grab it and you can just log in
forever as that person so the obvious
solution is to do whatever and
has been doing which is hide it
somewhere put in the header put it
somewhere it doesn't end up in the logs
put it somewhere it doesn't get shared
like a go to this URL to log into my
head a cluster
and then there are you logged in as you
right there's no authentication required
here's another example
passers and secrets are scattered
throughout a lot other developers alike
i really wanna use encryption but we
don't have a key management tool source
for the key next to the storage
that happens a lot or put in the scripts
you can dig around in this year and
and find exactly where to get the
exploits there's like a million-dollar
abilities in there
I might our classes computer science
students last week
in near Vienna and I told them there
third graduate there a
grades be based on how many CDs they
could file a lot of jeera Sophie will be
a lot more soon
and if not the best students
so I yeah I don't have a ton of time so
just very quickly
the idea that Netflix others have
propagated is that servers are pets
because we're growing them so fast you
shouldn't like hang on to them shouldn't
treat them like
you know this cat your feet cake oh my
server so lovely I really think it's
important special
you should treat them like house instead
but this was I think
created by people who don't know
anything about house I know a little bit
and I grew up around the block house and
so it turns out that house kinda
are like pat's the operative word being
asset right
up pat is an asset because it gives you
affection I guess or whatever people up
at
differ reasons but on an animal that
like a cow that you have a
a rancher gives you milk and money and
cheese whatever so
if you just look at as an asset then you
will protect assets and it turns out we
know a lot more about house we do pets
because they're such valuable assets
so that model in 2012 I spoke about how
to
to deal with cholera this is a store a
lot of time to go through it but
basically
if you look for a source for infection
the way we do in cows now and we can
understand the propagation of the
infection
then we can find the source eliminated
which was developed in eighteen fifties
it was the beginning of germ knowledge
was early big data analysis if you will
using math this is a four night short
approve the people that live next to
water
that was contaminated died that was the
beginning of germ theory
I would also prove that if they drank a
lot a beer and didn't go to that water
pump then they didn't die
so pure save people so I apply this to
technology
and basically the RM is if you can
easily identify problems and have
routine treatment and mineral judgments
then you're on the right path
so we need solutions like aspirin or
ibuprofen are things that we've
identified a really simple
that's how we're gonna do a boner
abilities but the way it works is if we
have on the back and some way of keeping
records
so you identify the problems you store
those records based the big data
analysis piece
so keeping them separate and
understanding where resilience comes
from really helps
motor abilities and so too big did
environment these are examples of
illness
these are all abilities you run into the
HTTP services I
you'll find jobs tickets service
delegation is broken you'll find it an
authority
is too high API's can be easily abused
keras has no definition randomness
people freak out when reading this
issues come up and and hashing tables in
your talk about
those competitions to make sure the
passion is secure in
outside to do but inside to do nobody
talks about it all are
weather out the tickets generate a biker
brosser random enough for secure enough
so passers example where I would look
for illness
in a MapReduce job budget house show up
are to data protection
the important thing to realize here is
that there's really no reason what's
been a
expectation of privacy anymore want to
start talking about massively
distributed systems there's a recent
court case in California which says
if the date is recorded somewhere then
that date is public information
so in that sense are you to protect data
that's considered
public could become sort of weird if
technologies really capturing
information
that you knowingly exposed then it's
basically public information
so becomes a question i've the
expectation of challenging integrity
its are like a civil dissipated
disobedience exercise and so
as a quick example radars trusted I was
implicitly in all the cases
so my brother for example what the
challenge the same court and having been
an astrophysicist he said let me explain
to you the mathematical algorithm
that will show you that you've misfired
a radar gun and
I'll help you improve the integrity via
radar guns if you look at the stake it
and this okay guilty a
so he was like I can map world's like
Whitacre so I got a ticket that was
laser-based I was like how that seem
strange maybe I can show how that's not
gonna work
i'd if we can challenge laser but I can
maybe challenge at the way I know as a
social engineer I can just go pay the
judge
and he let me off so it's what I did
gifts only five bucks to the Sun
a guy who went to law school with the
judge
and magically disappeared but in the
meantime I learned that
a laser is unable to detect moving
objects so even though there's a guy on
the street by a laser saying you were
speeding
I was going really fast and not say I
wasn't speeding but if
they do that and they tell you that
you're guilty it turns out that they can
see you
that blank spot is basically what they
see which is birds
which is cloud anything moving is
invisible to light our guns they're
using to tell you that you're guilty
which is so weird
they can see things like I mean these
they actually use light are quite a bit
for it really interesting to get
analysis
like this is analysis so power lines to
tell if there's a breaker tell you
there's a weakness or something right
up to see the trees can see everything
so this the like this I think this week
old light are
actually honestly and so I read actually
really 20
13 that all laser scanning methods a
basically assume that they object to
stationary
2013 and yeah we've been for years at
least twenty years I think
using lighter to detect moving objects
foot so the idea protections weird
so it actually turns out you know if you
can't kill those viruses with a
medication they should just take a
lawsuit because
other ways if dealing with data
protection errors and sewer
start to see is that issues of trust are
coming around relationships
you protect things based on authority
and relationship to one another
I some people say the sale defeat things
like I sis
if you really understand the complexity
of the relationships so it's not very
promising
but here's a real world example google
has light on top of their
cars right there automobiles I call them
auto autos
because I don't know but automobile the
first time was
automated right mobile automated its or
try again it's like the automated
automated
mobile so the auto auto admits or
failure or auto 2.0
so the light are sitting on top
basically as opposed to the tax stuff
but as I showed you its blind
so I've been thinking about ways that we
can blind paladar effectively and then
blind the GPS by redirecting it so their
cars I gotta control
I'm so and that's a big environment you
have to worry about
whether Google decides to send you off
the road because it detects something
and it thinks that it's right and you
don't think it's right
for example the texas school bus with
children in it and it says I'm gonna
send you off a bridge because I need to
save the school children
and you like there's no school bus and
there's any of the bridge you're giving
control to them so data protection
becomes weird if you give over control
to people who are basing their decisions
on faulty systems
which we knew way back to nineteen
eighty I United States had an operation
in the desert that
went awry because a guy was staring at
us somebody on the ground and use a
helicopter the first start walking
and you couldn't tell because a brownout
conditions so we've been developing
a better technology for years in the
military based on this idea
they were fixing it now some ways
examples of fixing it
with a cumulative which basically means
if you want to compromise the communal
environment
you see this allowed me to pick you love
you can compromise the admin then you
get complete control but you're
basically locked out of the network now
in the storage
it like a real environments our Tahoe is
another example
where same thing if you can get into the
Tahoe gateway which can run local so it
can be hard
but if you can compromise the game
you can get into the environment's
that's the proxy which becomes the focal
point to protecting data
as opposed to the network at the storage
array was our current solutions so
finally
network and system solution there is a
lot over
equaxion to protect the network and the
system's
but it's not well deployed so ask any
Hadoop environment
a where you know how they manage their
certificates
or even as the weather where they do
hardly that's not it not a popular topic
inside a compartment
they really don't have any idea and so
their other more
deeper problems like there's no
exception for JDBC why does that matter
a hive for example sequel anything a
sequel running on top of
a H HDFS so people are trying to use our
job Aquarius into the storage
are often using JDBC with no encryption
you just go intercept other
communication even more so
when they turn on SSL anybody know in
all ciphers are
North Cyprus non ciphers no ciphers
so they turn on SSL but
in the documentation it says attorney
and Alzheimer's that's the only thing
that they support right now
so as you dig into communications that
people are using to talk to get the
storage then you find more and more at
instances up I give an example here JDBC
is what a typical JDBC call
looks like from from higher and there's
there's no a SSL there's no encryption
you're basically doing
cleartext so here's an example recently
I love
a map are in Swat got together did a
demo of how their mining Twitter data
and right away I notice they're doing it
over non SSL connection when I look at
the Netflix security monkey
again no SSL connection security monkey
is the
management tool for security in a large
distributed environment and you're
logging in as an administrator to
environment with no
protection your password so it gets more
and more
complicated as you get to like large
environments there's an example well
RPC calls HDPE never a threat to anyone
it is that has a credential gives you
access any environment you can pretty
much pick and choose where you want to
get in
as you dig deeper alright so that's
basically the whole idea
you have six things that I went through
where there's lots of room for
improvement
and that of course the GRC would serve
see for top-level where things were
breaking
which hopefully for policies are set up
right are monitoring set up right we'd
see oh yeah we have
we doing strange behavior in the
beginning I talked about well
arce solution for example it's really
behavior-based it's not just that
you know there's somebody who's
connecting over report we haven't seen
before
which is useful for example for the past
12 months we've seen these JDBC
connections
and they look like this an hour sinker
GT bck collection that looks different
it's a different every day
its accessing more data than it used to
soviet-built enough data points using
big data analysis you can look at Big
Data Systems
and see unusual behavior and so then you
could say it's comply or not
so the future state essentially very
quickly is
I we've made some progress with some
distributions so
here's I haven't put names on these but
they've come up with their own
this is my fear they call their own
security like as if we've never done
security before
and I know anybody who wants to do in
eighty PV era PA e
compliance check and even use the word
perimeter in there
a model which i think is ridiculous
we're trying to get rid of Realtors and
they're like
you can't build a printer these guys use
encryption in their model
which I also don't like and we have
these other sort of side projects that
are supposed to take her everything
so I think we need to do is build
something like the six and I'll tell you
the truth
I borrow the six from a buncha
compliance standards I looked at and I
thought well this we've done these
before when we just apply these to
Hadoop
and I'll make people happy cuz once
they're done we can just say they're
also comply with HIPAA and PCI
other stuff I'm so here's a quick four
phases are five phases
how you do in the future basically
member the latency argument member all
the argument about how
skill bill you're supposed to work this
is what I used to look like you had a
buncha distributed systems
and you had a checkpoint and that turned
out to be not so secure
so we moved everything into a data
services layer and we have a really fast
network speed so the latency is an issue
so your computer that's distributed
actually comes just memory and ship
there's no storage
on the nodes actually century why is
that cool because if you sent restore
the data
then you can access controls on the data
based on classification
so if you know Bob shouldn't see alice
is home data
the chalet share work data then I can
actually build an access control lists
based on authority
on the data and this is a real
architecture that we're starting to use
which is
every time some inquiries a big did
environment I'd check to see if they
have access to it but I can do that
because I would centralize
if I have
distributed it's literally like asking
everyone to view every time somebody
wants access to data whether that
person's have access to data
it gets really complicated distributed
systems are very difficult to engineer
but I centralize a in a distributed
environment that at least have a stopgap
it's like building a a printer using
fast enough speed and so that I can
provide some least authority
like I talked about Camillo and and laps
that I can provide some way of saying
if I give you access my granted access
isn't just like an ACL
it's not just saying your name gives you
access to your key so every time I give
somebody access it comes with a key
and so when they say I'd like to access
this file: the shop with the token
now you access controls can be opened
because they come with the security
of the token or the ticket and that
actually work so real-world examples
well we can have environment service
layer essentially so when somebody tries
to do Hadoop like stuff
they talk to our proxy they talked or
service layer and we would check to see
if they have access or not to
data and compute resources both are
scaleable and then
in a real real world environment here's
a hospital
so outpatient inpatient care would go to
the service layer to try to query
what's that Asus and then all the stuff
going on like insurance companies
trying to do analysis and Shino defer
part to the hospital doing work
would be feeding into the state a lake
so we create a buffer essentially
and so that's where we are today if you
don't do this then you try to distribute
the security throughout everything and
it's just like Swiss cheese
it's like people can walk through
basically anywhere it shooting fish in a
barrel as we say
so thats basically the whole talk within
hours a lot to cover
adding it to go to its depth but but
again why I'm try to build transparency
sure everybody
where the risks are try to show that the
tools that are relevant SAR difference
than what we've might have done in the
past
and then show the resilience really has
become one the most important pieces cuz
if these systems die
like with that intern killed you know
ninety six hours with the data
the I see all the time executives say
okay I'm done with a dupe
if you can keep this thing up then
forget it does get off to go back to
Oracle or something crazy
so are thanks of your time we'll take
questions
help a fair questions
I would be giving you a book but I
didn't care that you happy I do
sometimes do with the book
the new book will be out in a couple
months hopefully
so which covers all the stuff in more
depth any questions
I would never want to answer for Oracle
but
I can guess so the question is is Oracle
planning to do yeah so true
so my theory is overall we're moving
away from databases because
databases were structured in a way that
was limiting
and people want access to unstructured
so you can do database on the fly
so I believe that the databases will
become a front-end to the actual
data repositories and as people shift to
a new mindset
the move of old database like management
interfaces like I will access my data
through my Oracle Database the move to
direct access
streaming access so for example and the
Twitter
their bodies as Twitter but if you look
at Twitter followers or URL's that are
getting
picked up if you did that a database you
be extracting and dumping
ATT alright you extract you transactions
you load to try to move away from that
and do like real-time query is like
what's the most number followers now
now how many people are following now
how many people are following so
the future is probably getting to real
time but I'm not a database guy honestly
I'm just a
little pen tester so whatever they do
i'm looking for.
clause yeah
there is a gap there because they have
to have access and credentials
and the more you use a an intermediary
that isn't secure the more you open
yourself to people also have access to
the intermediary
the Gateway buying compromise thing in
the middle then I can go and do whatever
you can do
impersonate you affordable secure
gateway where you can get unless we
really test you for
proper credentials ideally would be
back to Mabel example it would be we
don't actually have to build an
all-knowing all-encompassing system
because we have a way
%uh asking people to in a hierarchical
way going to ask people that they know
who ask people they know
and all the things that important get
reported up through the chain so we
don't have to know inside
certain environments and that's when I O
T model if I run engine with 30,000
sensors
I don't want to go and listen to every
engine all the time everywhere
I wanna have engines that are able to
identify flaws report up
just that flooded it's the same argument
as do I wanna have fun
development varmints in information mood
or debug mode or don't have min warning
load
so you wanna turn things in a warning
load but
still have the ability for things inside
to know what's important enough to
report back
it it actually turns into political
science more than computer science
because the privacy issues any other
questions
fifty pounds
that's at I can't pay people for
questioning anything
where to make the suit yes
what's that
how have I seen a security incidents so
I mention one
with the woman who destroyed the data I
what can I say yeah I've seen outages
basically
availability has been the biggest
incidents because we measure that
um act a theft the data we don't even
know yet how to measure that properly
we have some environments that are PCI
compliant we have some that are
hipper complained that are getting there
but honestly the incidents that show up
easiest and most our availability
because they're so easy to measure
if you still consider the part of
security which I do so
yes yet custom computing into
a trusted computing do no not that I
know of
well action to take that back so what
are the things that runs on Hadoop is
like the NSA
and so large intelligence gather
organizations probably do
trusted computers cuz they still have
that stuff sitting around they haven't
migrated of it
but I think more to the point it's a
commodity architecture
and trusted tends to be expensive and so
people are pushing ahead so fast
onto cheap easy they don't wanna put in
place
something trusted however Intel is
I think banking on the fact that they're
gonna make secure chips with crypto
accelerators
and I'm RHS aum's and %ah put those into
every node in a big environment this is
the norm for data management
in a few years so every intel-based node
may have
the ability to be a trusted node so I i
see that coming in the next year two
years will start talking about
how to talk to an HSM on a node it
yeah I didn't say that I have it
yeah somebody has claimed to have a
Hadoop environment as PCI compliant and
the ones i've seen
there you know the scoop flume
relationship there
mostly scooping so they're out-of-date
so they basically scoop
into an environment that's heavily
lockdown that has sensitive data
and that gets out of sync it violates
the idea
real time but it's the only way to lock
it down believe so
so many people and these a bastion host
so if you go in its key large so they
can go backwards in time
yeah so there is compromised nobody that
I know of
a is doing a true wide open and opened
fire at with PCI compliance
I think the closest you get with
accumulate would be okay
I think Tahoe laughs maybe even better
where your
encrypting every cell and encrypting
access
so be pretty heavy complicated
or working on building that as a as an
model
because we have to go the questions
some other question other knife to me
questions who once the certificate
at the fight it out one more question
k gonna ask another question
that
so I've mentioned that the the future of
Internet of Things security is building
these pockets
where things can talk to each other an
early report important enough
information back out
so we need a way of designing a model so
your home for example is your private
barrier
but I can get data out your home that's
relevant to
fixing your system's like a
vulnerability is on your system I we
need to know that you have a system that
needs a patch
I don't need to know that your home
between is ours and that you had a
girlfriend and not your wife at home
with you
ands I don't know you haven't paid your
bills or that a known felon is in your
house
and I find that out by like tracking
them inside your home so they're also
the privacy issues around things
that we need to build pockets and I
don't see a lot of people actively
building those pockets and reporting
ACII
ways of communicating yet so that to me
is the problem a PI should be able to
give us some
privacy in some you know who's actually
leading this is so the sass providers
the sass providers give you the ability
to get services but you can see inside
them
they're hiding a lot they're hiding a
lot a really bad behavior
they're not patching they're not
protecting your data but you can see
that because they create a SASE layer
but your API says my date is my date and
I can see anyone elses date because I'm
using API not because I'm looking at the
actual
access controls on the system's behind
the API so
strangely enough in the model love the
sass if we
use the sass model her home then we this
leaf litter the upside down
Google is our customer where the service
provider where
giving them access to us but they can
see inside they just get what accessed
you know we give them in our API that we
turn on yep that's the challenge I've
Internet of Things it's in the tens of
thousands of nodes
per person not in the the wearable our
discussion is like
89 maybe 15 devices and i'm talking
about tens of thousands of devices
which is the industrial Internet of
Things much more complicated than the
wearables
I thank you