alright I yep very good morning love you
um yeah thanks for coming to our session
and entitled session identifiers of now
possible to favor
our credit could be based at you of for
all the possible adjustments them
is the bus and gonna yeah we're gonna
switch
back and forth you during the talk but
before we start next introduce ourselves
actress Eva question this is something
that kind of get the blood flowing
a early in the morning so I don't fall
asleep during my talk more talk
I'm shorthand who's using Chrome
the browser I figured as much Firefox
km Safari
still operon you like
1 percent I think the internet users and
finally
who use Internet Explorer awesome I
so during this talk already on the
stalking actually go away um
and think about the next door in a way
you have not thought of it before
because it's a
that will show you um yeah later on the
talk
it's actually for our attack scenarios
one of the most secure brothers
but in terms of full disclosure um
I have to be honest okay this is broken
awesome I'm
I was actually in turn with Microsoft
Research until last week the south when
wearing the t-shirt so if I think
anything nice about Internet Explorer
I they still owe me kind of the paycheck
I'm I think so
now that's that's a laugh positive
things to say about it.
okay I quickly to something about us
sorry said mines been damaged or I'm a
security researcher
on pitches in at the University Inn and
Alan in Germany
this is about the case um also PhD
student at University Mall home
and this is joint work with our
colleague martine I'm when you see how
of
down here um he's working for recipe
research
actually all three of us used to at some
point what recipe research in a
your distant past and with to work
together and
collaborate on items get
so about the stalk in this talk we
actually present to you the result of an
analysis of different
browsers so browser-based possum
interest we're not going to talk about
one part but of past but basically about
apostle managers that are the normal
user can use um
such as see a all of you guys just a so
its own hands
um which probably actually use and we
will then
are the bottom with Endemol are ya kinda
this with another as a central
on how bad they re I'm how great I ES in
comparison
um we will then go on with the study of
a footpath put his look on the web look
like on the web
which is also pretty scary on and in the
end we actually after all the scary
parts we say hey this is
to print a cure everything we actually
have a potential solution
what's the problem but before we start
that step a yeah back one step I
and a good was actually one across that
script the i'd get most of you guys know
but have not kept pictures on here so
I so wanted to the flight anyway I'm
the websites principal security policy
is the so-called same origin policy
um and the question is why can't an
attacker
say having the domain to take a dork um
read the visitor's email from
so if somebody that the tackle or why
can't get really really the gmail emails
and this is precisely a the same origin
policy stop
I'm it make sure that resource can only
have get
access to one another if their origins
match an origin
in the sense is defined as the protocol
soap for example aged people with https
I'm the domain but this actually sup 2
may not
not to second level domain as well as
the port saw only these three things
match
then The Exorcist a texas' granted and
this actually
makes the job a little bit harder for an
attacker and make some very sad and also
has a very Sat
kitten in this instance so
cross-site scripting what is the actual
underlying problem um
webapps process data on this is a a very
obvious statement I guess
arm otherwise it would make sense either
way we just have her
kinda the web I'll as invented by by Tim
berners-lee way this half
content you can see it but you can
really interactive web applications
to and the state I somewhat produced or
provided by the way this might be login
credentials that might be
something you post in a in a foreign
anything like this
and basically all that actually reach
the summer by HTTP
which it's basically post for me tonight
get permit us it might even be headers
it might be yeah whatever
however a user can interact with the web
application and when medication then
somewhat process is this the state %uh
it might I the store it
or it might kind of yeah return it back
to regularly
think of a a search query arm where you
enter something into
to a search field and then website at a
youth such for your your query string
and then use also this kind of data not
only to reflect the SPECT you
but also do the search in the background
I'm so the contract with
but actually oMG if you look at this
little snippet update I hope we can you
can read it basically this
script alert one script closing election
update on
but its coat much because the browser it
is something to say this is the
the piece of telescopes someone I'll
yeah executed and open the
box and the important thing is that it's
like reinterpreted by the victim's
browser
in this in the context of his beloved
application
um that means think again about the same
origin policy
if I is an attacker an able to inject my
own code into gmail dot com
than actually I'm running in the
Argentine add a comment I can actually
reach or
you read your emails and yeah the idea
is
for so you try to find a flaw in your
application that allows you as an
attacker
that allows you to a yup put your
argument is called their
own job contest this in your own browser
to begin with
and then you somehow make the victims at
that site that money to buy it be by a
kind of
a clicky are sending them spam I'm
obviously
if you think about affect the profits
cryptic where this is part of the
I'll forget permit or something as you
all might be super long
so it might be very obvious I'm what you
doing but one cannot to do is
for example register a domain like pick
for a quick victory on
um post my cat pictures on it and why
the user is happy that he's watching
cat pictures yet you have been hidden
hidden iframe on the website
um that a kind of contains this URL for
the end users never wear
that in the background while he's
looking at cat pictures action loading
gmail dot com with this
whole bunch of a of misspelled so
basically
in the end we can reach a get emails
okay saw
I
yes but had little or a little bit what
can a cross-site scripting attacker do
so the first and foremost thing you will
always see if you see a proper contact
proof-of-concept sorry for a cross-site
scripting exploit
people open up box and this is like
Wow and obviously kraina
very freaky heck of stuff I'm going on
here but actually
the attack I can do much more than just
open the ballot box he can for example
high-tech session that means he can
force the
the victim's browser to a kinda freaked
the cookie if
that might be involved I'm it might
force the victim to click on a link
for example I don't know a yellow post
something think about
a across the scripting on Twitter um
where you know what i'm talking
you're actually on I said hey that can
pick the dog in the background actually
the kid picks a dog sledding Twitter
plus this a lessen its payload
and then I love you posted a this is an
awesome talk going on here I'm
it can also be used to alter content I
don't actually a
case on the the German Chancellor are
the chances website where r
there was a closet scripting I think
what's on the search field um
which eventually that took some yeah Fe
content namely
a Johnson after resigned because of I
don't know what it was
somebody I think he even made it to the
new arm just because
yeah a it was it was actually on that on
that but
and you can't school blog informs and
but first and foremost and this is also
the
the topic of all talk this something
that typically you there's or
a and research and don't necessarily
think about we can actually utilize
cross-site scripting attacks
to see the possibilities passwords own
yeah so basically just to give you a
quick
quick overview um I think in literature
also in the security community
people typically peak of three different
types of profit script we actually make
a distinction
I kind of been on to excess um
we can either have client-side also a
psycho but call this the issue
and then we can have reflected
cross-site scripting where
kind of the they talked directly echoed
back to the to the user
all weekend of star-crossed script if
you think about a forum post and
except but then again
is a cross-site scripting like a I
hadn't been told especially with the
kind of security policy at the club s
actually it has not been so far last
year CCS
actually conducted a study um that show
that about about 10 percent all the
a top 10 K what sites um carry
a at least one bomb its cost-cutting
liberty this is a tough process good
thing that
has not be resource all that well in the
the previous years um
then again as you might know and all I
am basically all love you are a lot of
you
thought you use Google Chrome week ron
shipp with the cloak walter Chrysler
scripting on its own
but actually tries to detect and ya
block cross-site scripting
on but turns out that yeah basically for
all black hat US talk
a couple of months ago we showed that
about eighty percent of the domains
above these 10 percent all the time
because its complement
um are still vulnerable even if the
croats get the OTA is deployed
so it's not really a Canova yeah good
good way to to block this and this is
also
kinda underlined by be the white hat
security I
security report arm and again says Gaza
Strip hurricanes
the number one spot after being
overtaken by information leakage so
again
last year property was kinda the most
prevalent kind of
one ability on on the web talking and
with this
ok to touch over to the bathroom come
back in a minute
okay now this is working great so
after we now have the the foundations
that we need to understand
the rest of the top I would like to talk
about passwords and password managers
sobel first love about how passwords I
used on the web and then a little bit
how password manager work
and what are the security and features
the password managers have so
if you look at passwords on the web we
have to state that passwords are still
the first and the only for of
authentication on the web so we
basically only use passwords on the web
an well in a perfect world I guess we
would not have passports
we would have something that is more
secure it cannot be stolen that
we do not store in databases and so on
and so forth but
we still have to pass was all over the
place and well in that same I perfect
world where we still have passports
we would have a passport for each site
so
and the passport for for this preach
side should be
sufficiently complex to a wipe route for
staying in touch cracking and so on
but the reality looks a lot different
so here we see is a few statistics that
we've taken from
other researchers from the web and would
be
what we can see is dat so-what there is
such a did
he analyzed password dumps of
of packs that were publicly available
and check what kind possible to people
using
and what we for example see that it's a
five percent of all users
just use the password passport and we
have about 10 percent of the user ID was
password want with 123 456
all one the numbers I want wait and what
we also see is that
a lot of users use the same passport so
we compile a list of the
pop 1000 passports we see that
ninety-one percent of all passwords I
use
from that list so it's pretty easy to
crack passports
and in recent years we hit we saw shift
from
pecan Internet companies 24th more
strict a passport
complexity rules and is illustrated in
this comic so how so
if you look at Facebook and look at
Google we see that those services
require
much more complex pa Sport so we need to
use uppercase letters lower case letters
when YouTube have numbers and and
special chars in your password
and this makes possible very heart to
to remember and this i delete leaks lead
said to have
very in unfortunate situation people are
using passports
and it's not the Saini perfect world
where we have a sufficiently complex
passwords by recite
and one solution that was introduced
lately browse our password managers
so because password managers take the
burden of the user
for remembering the password but the
password manager will do this
and nowadays we see that all the
browsers that Ben presented in the
beginning
have password managers I did you tried
to store password
will see such a dialogue that says well
here would you like me to remember your
password
and with if we look at the
functionalities of such a password
manager
it has basically two
the first one is to store the
credentials on first the mission when
you see them perform
and I think a lot of people have looked
into how this is
going and if there's a secure and if no
work and can extract passport from the
computer and so on and so forth
but not a lot of people have looked at
the second functionality
and the second functionality is
inserting the credentials into a web
page
on a subsequent was it so when you come
back to the website for which is stored
password
it will already be filled into the form
and most of the password manager and you
just need
to click Logan and this had
severe consequences so we would like to
look at the second functionality
and we would like to look at this
situation
in terms of a thinking about cross-eyed
scripting
so here we have a an example so we have
a
simple login form and we have apostle
manager
and the password manager has a password
to start for this loving formal for this
origin
and what he does is simply feels that
porn with passport
and although this is implemented in the
browser
that could be special protections
against attacks such as cross-site
scripting
so we but what we see is that there is
no protection and also the
the way this password is entered into
the form is that the
the password manager just put the
password into the Document Object
went into the DOM took doctor command
object model
and well dollars good running in the
page can access
data that is put into it don't sewed up
the script in the page
is able to excess the email field and
as well as the password field and just
expect the password
and hear the excess comes in so what an
attack against through excess
is execution of JavaScript code in the
origin of the webpage
and hands he's able to extract hectic
repost
etc sorry execute texas ass at
Talisker and therefore is able to access
the password field and extract the
password
so I will demonstrate that shortly its
very thin very straightforward so here I
have a page
it's called login not calm his page not
reloading dot com but it's a page
on my local computer and what we see is
that I start
a password in that password manager and
we see that this is chrome
and if I reload this page chrome at all
will automatically fill in
at my password into the front so let's
have a look at
JavaScript I just opened a JavaScript
console where can execute
jobs to come on site like across sides
Chris
scripting attacker would do and would be
can just do what we can
select the password field so I use just
JavaScript method
its well-known and say well give me all
fields name password
and this gives me a lot note list so I
take the first element
and he I can see the station I could
have the password field
and we do not see the password in the
external but we can just
query the value attribute and here we
see
the Jalisco can access on the password
was
was insert it into the page were
ben says I should soon so that its
more with a bow yes that's a good idea
okay so here we can see at the password
is expected
on in cleartext and this is a very good
thing
if we think about cross-site scripting
and
in order to see what the security
consequences of this features are
I would like to compare two worlds one
world without password manager
and the word with password managers to
tend to your credentials
automatically into for so in a world
without password managers
XSS attacks only work
when the user is authenticated so what
you would like to do in excess attack
it would I do like to conduct state
changing actions in the name of the user
are you would like to steal the session
credentials so the session cookie
to conduct on stage injections in his
name on your computer
so if you conduct an XSS attack you
construct the URL with the
exercise payload and sanded to the
victim to execute
and the attack only works when the you
this authenticated
so it is not authenticated you cannot
conduct any stage in connections
and there's also no session credentials
to steal in a world with password
managers
an exercise to truck just works out of
the box
so the if you with a the page
that password manager will fill in your
password you have JavaScript execution
on the page as an attacker so you can
just Texas the password
and you can still the password and the
consequences of this
are very bad because on though
in in a world without password managers
we can just steal
the session credentials so the session
cookie and the session cookie is
only limited only valid for very limited
amount of time so as soon as the was a
lockout
or a timeout said the session
credentials are not valid anymore
so the attacker cannot conduct any
further actions but if you have a
password
stolen the attacks are limited to
lifetime
of a password and usually people will
not notice that they
they have been accessed and so you have
the password of the user
and the probability that is not changing
this password is this very high
and then another problem comes in so
poss what often reused by users on other
web pages
so an XSS attack on password managers do
not only
affect the side that the users can do
visiting aunt that
is wonderful to access but it will
affect all the sites
that the the password is valid for and
if you look at this we have to state
that well
the current password manager generation
makes acetate
XSS attacks mostly via so it's much hot
much
more easier for an attacker to do
something bad and
we took this as a basis for research
and had look at security mechanisms that
password managers
and as a spoiler we've been found a lot
of them
so but we did we found 5 keep each is a
password managers
so how their inserting credentials into
field and
we see week we will have a look at how
password managers are matching the US
else and performs
that the answer passwords into we will
look at password managers that
require user interaction before filling
in a a passport
and we will also look at at out a
complete attributes let's first
look at your own for matching another
demo
so
here we are in chrome again and I stored
passwords on this website so on
loading dock on flesh login PHP and
on this very same domain I have another
page
which is called search to PHP and such a
PP is a simple
search applications I can just put in
some value and
it it will search something for you
and here obviously there's a cross-site
scripting
so here I had user input which is
reflected in the ghetto meet and
reflected
in the page and I can just enter some
arbitrary
HTML code so for example I can just
could be so that you believe me
so we see that the code that I put into
the URLs
reflected in the page and now the Texas
Board
so let's just try to be a cross-site
scripting attacker and enter
form here so I just at another form
and I give
to input fields to form say just 20
I would like to have a text field and I
give it just an arbitrary name
and now I will add the password field
and just give it another
arbitrary name and then I sent this
and I see it my form and I see well
chrome isn't very intelligent so
just say well I have credentials stored
for long in the comm
here's a form it has a password kid so I
enter credentials
and funny thing is I can't even at
assert before
field just with another name and
crumbled just
enter and the password so chrome has no
matching rules at all
so just source passport and as soon as
it is a password field
it will enter your credentials and as a
cross-site scripting attack and now just
at some arbitrary JavaScript into the
euro and and just extract that password
from that form
as we have seen it before and still your
password
so here we can see a
small overview of brothers doing
matching of your out some forms
and the only browser that really does a
matching is the Internet Explorer
so Internet Explorer only inserts
credentials into the page to distort the
credentials for
and only into that single form and all
the other Bros just
filling password into any form and that
is present on the web page and it has a
password field
the next feature
that we that we noticed this user
interaction
so as we saw in chrome password not just
into
inserted into the page without any
wasn't actions
and that makes it very easy for an XSS
attack a to automate the attack
so just needs to send his cross the
scripting attack and
we received the password so we'll have
another
demo this time been an Internet Explorer
at ABC the same side slugging dot com
slash live in touch keep people and I
start a password on the site
in IE on if I refresh this page
takes away we'll see that
there is no password in the password
field
while what does it take so long
sorry for that
some local host so it should
mom not sure thing
Pittman not still strain lowing but
okay let's just wait us
you second okay
pap kid not sure what's going on
okay to switch to another brother
so adjust its fiery se VC the same side
again
and be with a dude with the fiery we
needed to see that there is
some kind of the pop-up a window
and we first need to click until the
password is entered into for
and if the form is so it can empty it
again circle
if I click so there's some kinda user
interaction about
so im if a cross-site scripting attacker
wants to exploit you it's not that easy
so he'd somehow needs to make you to
click on this thing
and here in Safari BC is he a very good
example
of a a secure using tax in because
this being cannot be hidden by other
things 60
so an attack that he could choose to
overcome this issue is clean checking
so you could try to to make the user
click on this thing and you could
try to height this window from it but in
Safari its
relies very good so this this part that
you see cannot be
the Overlake by any other by any other
side by any
development so that you that you have on
the page I cannot make
be made invisible Bice this
yes
it's not and I can show it I have I have
a short I say it's a very good solution
so in this case
it's not clear checkable so here we can
see it here I have a page that is called
even dot com
which could be used by the attacker and
he framed the the login
but php page from London dot com and he
concede I made a pack
but still so that you can concede and
this thing is still showing a showing up
so people will notice a dent projecting
this this
this very heart
okay let's have a look at the OU again
so
the reason why I wanted show Internet
Explorer's because at a time
when we conduct this research research
Internet Explorer was the only browser
doing that
so before all the brothers just filled
in the passport
and in the last two or three months
opera and also Safari changed it
behavior to show that box
okay
so let's have a look at another feature
so in 1805
we have a new attribute that is called
autocomplete
and here is some tax of the
specification and review
put autocomplete to text feel it s I did
two meanings
so it can I to be used for input fields
that have a particulate Ely sensitive
data
folks under the activation code of a
nuclear weapon says the specification
all you have something dat the user
mystery and top every time he does the
page something like
a for example that in a one-time
password for your banking account
so the autocomplete pot ok to compete at
a good
can be used to opt for a page 2 up out
of storing data in the browser see can
tell the browser
don't safest eight er its sensitive
so we had looked at
different browsers and if they adhere to
decide if you did you put it to the
password field
so if put to the password field brothers
shouldn't store your password
in there so let's have another look
again a chrome
have another page on this domain on is
called
autocomplete aunt
if we look at the password field it is
and here we have the autocomplete
attribute
and be switch it off but well chrome
simply sites well
even ever even if the try to to submit
the form
it will say yes some do you want to
start is Password Manager Pro CS
it will store it and it will
automatically fill
discern application
and there's an interesting %uh example
so we have a Firefox
and here we can see login dot PHP
and the login form will be automatically
felt by your password manager
but if we go to autocomplete we will see
but we're not you thought so it
it somehow tears to do all the complete
field but it still other foods that you
click
so if you if you have the autocomplete
feature in Firefox its
just switch to mode where you require
user interaction
and then it will again on to compete to
feel if you click so it was still stored
password
so let's have a look
at deal for you again so we have chrome
which doesn't adhere to that attributed
all we have Firefox and Safari
day somehow adhere to it because they do
not
out of old the password field but they
still other fill it if you
you click and then offer also does not
just here today tribute and Internet
Explorer
at his trade and does not offer to %ah
to complete the fields at all
so we report this to Google
so we said we we open the bobbin said
well if they are to complete his
present DART cookie attribute we should
not store passwords on
do not autofill the passports so we open
a back
but and put this Google and local
replied well this is intentional and
working as intended
so basically day do not related to
inspect
and does make users on somehow on
exploitable on if you look at all this
feature we see we somehow see a
trade-off between usability and security
so it would be very secure to not feel
the passwords to have
using tax ins where the user has to
click multiple times to white
attacks but I think a lot of browsers
not taking the usability route
so it's very convenient to the password
is in your password for Danny just
compress
the login button that you do not need to
click and I think that the autocomplete
I attribute is also very good example
for that
because if the webpage specifies
autocomplete because of
and your browser does not store the
password for you
users will play in the browser for that
it was a well chrome does not start it
my credentials although I would like to
start on soap
chrome to assess be in order the wish of
the web page do not store this
credentials and with this I would like
to hand over to bed again
call will talk about the state of
password fields on the web
thank you on does 18 issue 2 who
this cunt I actually if both
a bit all seen it in a form I set to
what it could be because of
then they don't storage but the
the notion that that I would have as a
programmer think about the following
have this form that was previously
I yeah the lead with the popular as
previously thought the credentials
and I want the that crimson no longer to
be stored for that field
then I wouldn't ago when the possible to
miss albright I said ought to be to
offer the password which means
as the specs s Europe read your brother
police don't save it
in these cases if a if there's at least
one field
in this form that doesn't have all the
computer to of then chrome stars and
only if
all of you to set to auto because of
which
programmers I think Google think that
programs go ahead and by accident
put autumn people of to a form and
in these cases them to help the
programmer on by a by storing the
password
somebody I can I mean this this blog
reported to be open both
kind of shot down on with this very
interesting other interesting comment
I not really commenting on the fact that
they are violating the
the specification your alright I'm
so enough for Google bashing again
muscle wearing my Microsoft had
and slight be so
another part of the research we did wats
want to then look at
what password protection look a look
like under on the web and
yet this sexually hum was done so we
could gain a better understanding of
house Heights handle these handle forms
so for example
how many sides are actually trying to
actively opt out of
apostle men just storing a during the
past what even if they
not necessary do that um so looking at
kinda feels that at all I have bought a
complete set to OFF
I'm and also I for example look at the
the extra options header which is not a
cricket and has been a
to overcome by a bias he's P directive
an
actually the DX extreme options had a
can be set by website
I'm to tell the browser this this site
should not be
admit to never not ever be framed sorry
so I'm
if we think about the following think
about a yeah
a combination of RA modification I E I
he does not
on feel the form if it's not the exact
righty well so if you think back about
20 to our example we have are such field
the search field see well does not match
beef unblock in for the looking for
forms
you well so what an attacker could do is
he could use this
cross-site scripting on such feel to
inject an iframe
um and then try to yeah a
kind of got yup force the press for the
brother to
I'm to fill out the criminals there I'm
then because they are both this the such
good as well as the
login form they're the same origin the
outcome side can access the iframe in
can then access the password
so we also want to see how many sides
actually make sure that they're looking
for a page cannot be framed
so by by setting the DXM up to um
through that we implemented a very
simple crawl on which basically goals to
weed out some
from the men from this case the
electropop 4k I'm it scans the entry
page
for a look and feel on but death I get
most of you know
and not every webpage necessary has the
the login form
directly on the first page um so bad it
is and look for indicated keywords
um like a log in sign in
Tom on and and such we actually didn't
we only did it for for English
ok for his words so I'm not sure if we
call the Chinese low in points that
might have for
yeah a different than a different URL or
German
it's basically the same and finally a
final piece of the puzzle
wats that this extension that she wraps
excess
to two fields um soul that if JavaScript
actually trying to access the few
because this is a very interesting
things well
I'm we can notice that as well and these
are the results Offerman
the of the study sought in the 4000
what sites we actually found pass with
you it's on 2,143
and this is basically the one percent
your office this relative calm so the
the third column
um so turned on that at with even with
this relatively
simple approach we were able to find
properties on behalf of
of the electropop the 4k site I'm
now for the scary part um so only 38
percent of those actually had the
the form on a GPS page the snot not that
bad yet because
just delivering the form on a cheapy
page on
is well not really an issue because well
then somebody can destroy may be on the
connection
he with UK there's a password field but
he can't really do anything with it and
the thing that
scares me a case miss Kathleen Moore is
the fact that
56 per only 56 percent of the domains we
can talk with you on
actually submit news passwords over
HTTPS so almost every second page
actually use plain HTTP to a yup
transmit your passwords I to it and
if you think about what the boss Antonio
um users typically tend to reuse
passwords quite a lot
so it would be relatively
straightforward and easy onto
get yeah an apartment for a lot of
fights up just by
yeah being in the network and I actually
have a are yeah there's actually a
similar attack a model in which I will
talk about
in in a minute then only thirty .6
percent
on this website actually had the article
pizza to of I think most of them only
had a tattoo of
on the password field so again chrome to
sting of this
um still stores at nevertheless and
the other hand number here three in 25
to May 10th somewhat
summer youth
javascript to access this field I will
talk to you about this
the letter in the talk um but we see
that
this the either means that for example
the most of the sites likely
just wanted to check that the fuel was
not empty missiles altered Austin Texas
which we could detect because we have
this
this rapper and um so is similar to come
out to her
yeah when we did and l3 said they would
pay basically going on
Morrison perot to our research um was
not in the middle a text soul for
for you stick security this year um just
two do not want to go think
I yeah David silver at all actually
conducted
I'm kinda a study similar to ours but
with a different take on a month so they
went ahead
and said okay we will go to a public out
to a cafe
somewhere and offer a free WiFi service
and everybody loves three wife I'm
and typically use this as a free wifi
cool I'll just
click on that and be happy with it but
actually did is
into every HTTP connection they could
hunt so for example the
I could think was a bad example but a
any ATT connections or not
not equipped that in connection they
actually went ahead
intercepted the and the response
injected iframes
into the site up for example to whatever
Google Facebook
and so on and so forth um and similar
to the tech we describe the possum and I
just thought to to the login form sorry
the possibilities with then in these
cases um
fill out the the forms and since we have
a man in the middle attack we can kind
of put arbitrary
paled in this this response from
Facebook or Google
um so they also it kinda put from da
script in there
that waited similar to or attacks waited
for the possum intro to be as kind as to
fill out the forms
and then you get back a to the attack up
and
yet they did that I'm I think they had
like 10
10 I fence or something in Paris each
time user with a different HEB page that
you just can't take the next ten domains
into it
I'm and according to them it's very very
quick to automate I'm
your kind of sweep Rs they call a sweet
attack we just
sweep over the top the top one thousand
domains for example
and try to still have many possible as
possible I'm
but this is No
on that well thats it with no work
um as far as I know they didn't try to
kind of try to force SSL Certificates I
know for similar study where
I'm yep well
am if you think about the following and
if you don't think about an HTTPS
connection HDP basically lied to a
request to HD it through to Facebook com
with a2dp
am and we have a man in the middle
attack up I'm he can modify any headers
he wants to weaken
inject anything you can just injected
directly into the to the page so
sees Peterson doesn't help in these
cases um and there was also similar
study where
some I think a group from from other
dumb University went ahead and open to
open one of these
these public wifi and they said the user
the only prerequisite
and you have to worry this one thing you
have to do so you can use a wifi
please install the certificate which was
actually a root certificates
and basically allowing them to sign
arbitrary certificates
and so I think I'm like 90% continue the
said yes that's I want free wifi
again the free wifi i win for anything
you want from me because I mean also
it's not executed or something but it's
just a certificate 11 why no one
certificate can do
I'm but young so I i kno
I think I are at so
we have these two different types of
Alphatec so we have this
discussed but the attacker and wonders
about to that because it's getting
attacker has
obvious the needs cross-site scripting
availability on that
on the target site however as we've seen
this is not a
yeah that that how to the task actually
I'm because
felt most the website a full somewhat
somewhat insecure um
in contrast one downside of this letter
to take a recess you
clearly pointed out it does not work
with https at least not the way they
presented their work
I'm whereas again didn't the crisis
gripping category have Nexus S on edge
DPS page we can
doesn't go through the password from
there um but
and this is one case where the netbook
Asus the their way more
yet sophisticated and powerful than we
are. he can't just eavesdrop on the
crimson that have been posted to the
website so again
half of all the password fields are
actually submitted
by ATP staff H
guess for some reason I'd don't want to
understand um
so summarizing this actually attacks
against Pablo managers can relative it
can be the ultimate
um so but I love this is
the deep apostle managers and lets that
fear
you're not talk about a year not again
the opossum Angeles
in browsers are not really secure this
might be a different story for for these
these plug-ins like of parts and and and
1password
but we have to think about a although I
guess most of you here
will not necessarily use the built-in
pop-up managers because well you're
your security where up people on the
interrelated
typically are not that security where to
put it mildly for the big and say hey
this is there's a feature on my brother
that
allows me to not remember my password
awesome I'll just use that why should I
buy something or is that something that
I don't have the technical knowledge
actually I text reuse
and in our work we found that yeah we
have
issues related to all kinds of think so
we have this all to finish you
well basically or browse the site you
get it say hey there's password field or
if only I just
a display my password here I'm some of
them ignore autocomplete
on at least partially I'm there is no
verification that it's actually still
the login form so we can use for Mrs
names instead of whatever you send the
password but also for us as an attack a
very easy to
can inject this Alberto reform with two
very generic form into any web site and
want to we want to steal
credentials from so the question is
and this is a not the end of the the
attack part basically
can we come up with something that might
be better solution
that can still be deployed in kind of
quality browsers
um we don't have to report yeah
basically the hope of a miniature
I'm as well as don't have to force the
yeah the the user's the untrained youth
to learn how to tackle the problem into
the data click
and sewn into force okay
so what we've seen in our research is
the the idea of what a possum and should
do is it should
H user an authentication so too store
securely store
the passwords and if they are needed by
the replication he should then kind of
a provide them to the publication so the
user can authenticate
I'm and our notion authentication is the
credentials are being sent to the top
but this is actually
when you authenticate against the server
however as we've seen
and they're somewhat of a mismatch in
this notion and the implementation of it
so be credentialed are at some point
into the summer but
most importantly before that actually
happens they are inserted into forms
and therefore inside to the Document
Object Model and
acceptable by by JavaScript or across
its cryptic pale across the trip the
papal
and we just propose well let's try to
align this implementation how done in in
browsers
with this notion I of York rather than
being sent to the cell
alright so I'm a part of this
the slide it is he the the way
possibilities well-written also
initially we find a login form
than the path a manager comes along
against the page find say that the login
form
so I'll just go ahead and then search my
the username the password that I start
for the side and when the you then click
on sign in
this possible is actually sent to the
server
but so this this this is obviously what
we talked about all this the stock
I'm we now propose the following instead
of the possum in a jar directly
inserting username and password
let's go ahead and enter the username
and inserts
some pseudo-random nonce into this field
with this months
the attack occurred to absolutely
nothing this is just
so that the possum injure has away of
kinda figuring out okay
month XP lost password why and what
actually happens is
if we now click on Submit since we're in
the browser
we see this outgoing request with you
the name in the months
the nonce can be of any format so that
we can actually easily detected in the
in the outgoing request
am and that it can also be there by
accidental just give them something very
long
well the path a manner that does this it
has gone at to pay their season and as
possible at this month's
so let's exchange the nonce with with
the
password there are some contract
constraints this approach
soul potential pitfalls for for this
would be what if in the tech ago the hat
you can use he says cross site scripting
capabilities
he change the forms target so instead of
posting it to
lookin dot com slash lookin PHP he
actually posted to attack outcome
our evil look on a yeah jump PHP arm
another way of going about this would be
for example to
a yep of the two such PHP we've seen
that before
um and think about the following we
still in this this scenario where
um the attacker has XSS on on some site
he has
this iframe on that points to the login
page he just modify its
the I'm the target of the login page
its sent after the the possum out as a
entered the credentials and now this
such PHP reflects back
what it was given right I'm what you can
now do because he still kind of has
control over this parent frame
which is a lot excess because they're on
the same margin to this
to this iframe he can then kinda read
the content of the search page
I which affect the back the password and
could install the past
I'm an attacker could also go ahead and
just change the the method
number is used to post social send the
form sorry from post to get
get means that all the para meterse
although the fuel from the password and
the form sorry
are kinda appended s you get para
meterse
so again he post the form and then just
REITs the
a Bulo of the of the page that was
the has not been a redirected to and
then yes
kinda eight years and I'm Department and
the public at permit and can therefore
expect
so we therefore propose the the
following constraints: there should be a
very strict checking of
the form Parker 20 um so that the techa
cannot
it cannot change this this at all and
also we propose only to exchange these
monsters
and post by Madison ever and get her
meters I'm
we implemented a proof-of-concept
implementation
for for Firefox this is due to the fact
that Firefox I have a very nice
API that allows you to interact with a
possible 100 so you can exchange topic
and each stuff
I'm just from extension so
we still have this this default the I
can kind of them
question and if that you'll be asked do
you want to do you want me to remember
the password this is the first stage
um if you did yes remember the password
this actually go through the password
manager
um and in the parliament we have a call
back that said that kind of
then is called when a new password is
entered and thus a
then cause our extension let me wrote I
with this information for which host for
the torch
for with you that was its already fall
to form a trio I'll I'm and what was the
password
and what we do then is basically we
start this secret password in our
database we generate around months
and Exchange a man exchange the the
credentials they were initially be
stored in the bottom in interest
with our nonce and the learning so
therefore the path we still use the
default password manager but rather than
storing
poss was it not to stores these is
nonsense that we can week and access
later on
arm palaces the tricky treat sorry for
that
um so yeah this is certainly example of
how it then
a goals along 13 arm 13 post
long forms on the apartment for it very
small I'm gonna post login PHP and thus
this month
on is there in the in the daytime so in
the post data
um our extension verify said look at pH
Peets actually
the page that this possible to do that
with this possibles originally Posted to
so it is OK I would exchange that wears
on the lower part which is he opposed to
such PHP which might reflect back this
password
in this case our extensive checks hey
login PHP is month such PHP
so I will not a insert the path with
your
with ended a functional evaluation on
this on his work number 23 and 25 to
main street singer Leo
um that somehow you will start yeah a
Tosca to access the
attacked the public feels sought almost
130 on the cement actually
yet this one had an checked whether
there was some possible are they are not
if you clicked kinda submit or login
without the pop up in there that this is
not putting a you don't have
don't tried to send us this form if you
don't have the password
I'm ninety six domains
hutchison to the password by our X mejor
to be requests rather than posting this
form
I'm and I love those a key 23 to mange
hash the possible before sending it out
you think about
the effectively incident rather than
inserting a possibly be entered this
month's
he has two months we have no way of
seeing it on the on the outgoing request
because big picture don't know what kind
of hash function is being used
um soul in these cases are
implementation breaks because
the pathogens that the nonce announces
hashed and doesn't match the password is
stolen the Somerset
I'm one domain for some reason went
waiting way out of its way to be
super secure and use the bay 64
according
arm or encryption I think they called it
I
again this causes issues if you because
you
value base64 encrypt about the month and
and six domains are those actually send
passwords and get para meterse
its own folder thirty of these two men
to be looked at would break
with our approach which means that 98 96
percent of all the domains we analyze
would work perfectly fine
but what we propose and also more
importantly actually storing passwords
for
for the tex-mex in LA cheapy requests is
currently not
supported by browsers because brothers
wait for a can afford to be submitted to
so basically a post or get request but
that isn't
initiated by this this form submit an
XHR is not a
not a form submit okay then
I concluding what to take away from the
stalk
um so the current generation of
browser-based problem is quite
vulnerable
and even if the most of you and now i
can say this because
and yeah slowly where taking off my my
Microsoft had
I'm not a big fan of IU on for several
reasons
I'm but although most people kind of
hate it and say this is under the really
bad brother
in this instance that actually very very
secure um
then a very shocking nothing that we
found is but almost half of the possible
thanks to post by HCP
arm which is yeah met make the top for
an attacker report ever take it by using
because you can just go ahead and turn
yup read those from that without the
request and at least again to cross the
scripting attack a week and we can do
something so we can
actually patch relatively easy Pet
existing a in browser solutions arm
to allow for these a yet will offer for
defending against East is kind of tax
I'm its hard against never take a what
we can do is
for example enforce the password should
always be are yes and buy a GPS
rather than HDPE but then again we wit
theory break of the
other websites okay and with that I'd
like to thank you very much
for your attention you want to take a
picture I and we're happy to take any
questions you might have
me to put the pac
a picture back on I think we will put
those lights on our domain
which is here cut crack soft the ever
time comes at the end
there's a question
and actually there is so this initial
I research we conducted wall so I think
we did kinda and a fan of last year
and way let me quickly go back to that
slides
lookbook all
I sus screwed up
the this one came on
yes I as an example a this I I think the
initially with Safari 7.7 point all
which
and didn't have your a texan all 7 1/2
human interaction for
for chrome we did the initial a tests
kind of with chrome 31 I think now we're
up to 37 my belief
I'm so they are why the bro this change
um
they actually become somewhat more
secure I can really say for Papa right
now
I don't know that on the top of my head
but I you with all with 11 I
I mean if so weekend
yep
up okay so
okay so so your question is basically
a while we looked at how old how they
behave
a we didn't really with a we didn't we
analyze how they hold securely they
store the passport
because there has been a lot of reset
going on before on into this
I am I could be say I think I know
something about
Firefox I'm but I me by default none
actually have
apostle is that secured a keychain so
you have to accept a
XD know what you doing to add kinda
pasta protected York
to your keychain or are you pop a mentor
passengers database
so there's just nothing there I think
it's also depends on the operating
system for example in in Mac OS
a most of the WebKit browsers used to
keep chain of
of Mac OS so distorted possible securely
in there and by the mother operating
system its
it's different
in Syriac cake
wound
okay so it's all that's what you're
saying is the
a we propose to use this kind of as a
proxy where whisper so this month
but I was too good in theory excess the
outgoing request
but actually this kind of mangling the
is done inside and also after the form
submitted
would ask it has no way of accessing the
page and more so it's
the request is already outgoing and
JavaScript to see the game
might notice there's a request going out
a.m.
but actually have no way of kind of
accessing this mango
request that we that we did so it's it's
a curious
so it's it's currently not possible to
to access the request on the way to the
server for jobs but there's something
that caught service workers weaken
install java script to to request but I
think this happening before
so so we are sitting in the browser much
in on a much deeper level than
been top
me
but only
extensions yep so not not in jobs good
running a web page
I the big sexy extensions are basically
Dallas kept
but they are kinda running as an
extension and the browser back and
rather than
something you can access from the from
the website so there's no excess towards
extensions well this sometimes but
a that he do crack extension to begin
with good