hello everyone good morning I my name's
Ryan Lackey I work for Cloud Player a
cd&e does mitigation company I'm
speaking a black hair Europe 2040
so just a quick disclaimer I my employer
does offer customer two-factor
authentication for website
I we use internally because a PCI much
other reasons
we're not a two-factor authentication
vendor I personally hope you like
consulting in helping out friends people
adopt two factor authentication
and I think it has serious issues but
also very useful tool
I'm just a quick back going to let me
i've I work in startups and and security
for about 20 years now Iran offshore
data here in the North Sea called Haven
co back in
2003 anonymous like gonna catch stuff
before
defense contracting satellite stuff in
Iraq and Afghanistan
and now I have trusted computing startup
for a while they got bought by
Cloud Player earlier this year so the
next 25 minutes we're gonna cover
quite a bit material a quick overview of
what two-factor authentication is
than it should be obvious to everyone
here I strengths and weaknesses were
changed over time
there were some assumptions made when
two factor authentication was first
introduced
that aren't really true anymore and
things have been adopted over the years
our bill is a true
how the threat to all the overtime and
into major weaknesses into factor of the
two-factor authentication and advice
best practice and future goals to do to
best implement this
so what is two factor authentication
former more properly multi-factor
authentication
at choosy two or more independent
factors for authentication chosen from
at least 10
to us at so knowledge factors like
passwords knowledge-based authentication
question things like that
a possession a physical topiary or
effectively a data files protected by
some sort of does control mechanism
or inherent something that user is a
biometric or some other potential it
inherently user
the star has a pretty long history
I'm I'm this stuff before this but
credit cards have a signature
verification
on the under the same time as a mag
stripe I'm extra cards to pay any such
as an ATM card
and then password plus the cloud and the
check so if you're at a checkpoint in
the check your ID plus they ask a word
of the day
that would also be a two-factor form for
the publication to has a long history
has a long history failures I signature
checking for things like credit cards
always been kind of a joke
you can write a line to use for
after-the-fact trend analysis and for
some legal things but
doesn't really protect you from time
abuse attacks almost all cases
the ATM in the same way perhaps it's a
little bit stronger but we have people
who put their pens on the cars we have
scammers all across devices customers
being this is crazy huge industry now
and in documents like you can just show
up with the
pretty much anybody photo of you match
some basic parameters problem maybe
thirty or forty data points
I'm for 30 or 40 a.m. it's a her brother
no more that Miley
like six to 10 better information you
can pass muster as
the clean there's things like us totally
fake authentication credential these are
camouflage passports the people use
better for countries that don't actually
exist you're not carrying like a a
a fraudulent document because it's our
country that never existed
I'm from leo is one other seal and from
for back in the day
but so this is another thing but these
are the physical world versions of these
things
we've had two factor authentication
computer systems for a long time
others ASCII OP the old security tokens
the the offline devices
these probably have seen them since the
early 2000's there are some in the late
90's
the else I think I guess is HP's nothing
so you've had two factor authentication
at least in the enterprise environment
or in the system environment for
for quite a long time the they would
to date rates they were really useful
they were generally disconnected they
were offline
they were physically distinct from the
protected system they weren't on the
same system
and they had some negatives they were
difficult to implement
I you end up with a major problem some
the biggest problem I personally had
with stuff like this we ended up with
like a different to factor of hoping for
every one of your accounts they can be
bank accounts a good basis and accounts
the remote overall accounts at work
agree all such a crazy stuff and you end
up with like a bag for tokens are caring
for tokens which is pretty crazy
the another exciting thing happened
the a little while ago I am
river is a retard one of these tokens
the i-four here this file
for you to review please open to it on
the Rs a security breach
obviously where the sea there was used a
lot it opens was extracted and various
targets were
compromises an attack are the result of
the attack so
yet there's that so this or a motivated
whole shift towards of tokens
a.m. they have a lot of advantages a
cheaper easier than ever basically an
eraser security control the easiest
possible way to implement it is
ultimately you know when
and these were a lot easier to implement
lot easier to manage a lot easier to
reissued in the physical tokens were
I and it's all those problems like
having ten different opens because you
sound different
entries in your girl authenticator your
other authentication ap
I'm which is pretty cool the and about
the same time PC I was pushing people
toward implementing
up to factor for a lot of applications
the
are some issues with how it's been done
but we're just over really quickly PCI
2.0 the me to first after this and
it doesn't really it's not really very
specific about what you want
and it's not really terribly the
thorough so
with this year potentially could have
one or two users verify
use it for certain remote access I so
there's that
3.0 fix this to some extent I requires
effectively a random sample abusers be
verified and
on as a result you end up with with all
users have to be verified
and it's it's a Muse from or
implications
as this but there's still a problem at
all really designer on road access till
I'm not critical systems so if you got
critical systems at work
the the river in scope it on a silly
need for access locally don't need to
have for
two-factor authentication and of course
your Jessica E
difference but the and there's not
really very specific guidance on to
factor I mean PCI generals fairly
in a little about how detailed it is but
I think this is an area where could
do with being a little bit more specific
about the controls that are acceptable
on the type to to factor in the title
applications any protected
and specific I guidance about one dollar
tourism showing should be included
so then also in this to factor of
the softer can land there was a push to
using SMS and call based authentication
because not everyone has smart phones
are not everyone on the
not all especially france for consumer
applications not everyone had a
smartphone and the other applications
were generous carbon-based
so either in addition to or in place
love
a time a cash-based one-time pad
one-time password authentication on the
the sit on the smartphone the providers
provided this SMS or call based
authentication
and there's a problem here it's not
really great photo by Google Voice
allows you to forward your SMS to
voicemail so a lot of configurations
people have this
this kind of thing configurator SMS is
for their services shared
their voicemail shared otherwise
vulnerable so you got done
call forwarding as a vulnerability on a
buncha
normal configuration take things which
are one thing to worry about but then
there's the
the problem both now work now we're all
very very quickly once
a SMS and Email and calls where the
primary means a passing out especially
banking credentials which are used by
large numbers of users especially in
Europe and Asia
a so the
there's been like put a limit on this is
just a short summary of some of the
the attacks on our Design just to still
SMS's and call in addition
Commission for it some more so something
sorta close to me was a
the hit the CEO of my company actually
fell prey to this personal attack before
I joined the company
the collapse had a password recovery
mechanism like therefore different
some security flaws at all chained
together led to his personal Gmail being
compromised which led to a Twitter
account being compromised
which led to a Bulls in prison for some
people so
I'm yeah another
only great two-factor be technique or
technology people using their smart
cards
I exciting news from fighter Alliance
particularly as coming recently but
smart cards especially like the I think
cell phones and the
for me in the enterprise the DOD CAC
card with a common axis credential
were really the the best
the access control type model so this
the
the CAC with the smart card readers was
deployed pretty much across the
DOD and throughout other parts of the
security part the US government
and allows their readers there's real
from blackberry to pair with Bluetooth
there is a
Russia spark our readers on your come
laptop in your keyword everything else
generally will interface with Microsoft
Application actor directory to
to log into systems and was written
reasonably secure the
it unfortunately I don't really help if
is now this whole system doesn't
register now running on the host
being protected because the
authentication happens right there and
the smart card doesn't have any direct
user i/o
so as a result now whereas that was
targeting a specific things
the more so for banking but there have
been
the banking ones are more widely
discussed because they're
consumer-facing and have large numbers
of users so it needs regulatory issues
the enterprise targeted attacks on on
spark arrestor occasionally
are generally not as widely discussed
because they target interest rate is
people in the enterprise
another whole category of course
biometrics a.m.
anything from fingerprint to Iris to
retin-a to hand geometry to
various other things their first got
some issues the readers themselves
usually expensive though this is falling
dramatically I
doesn't really help you when something
is running on the track and host again
and you can't reassure you
the uniting with all the other kinds are
potentials as if something does happen
in your ok you can reassure the
credential
but changing your eyeball outside over
the Total Recall and things like that is
not really a
a viable strategy and has a lot of the
user pushed back so
I there's a problem there on it's
something that that was
very interesting was the touch ID for
the iPhone 5 with
both CCC and when my colleagues mark
Rogers were able to compromise I think
within like a day everything out
and using very simple stuff using some
some
PC board and elmer's glue and
there's that so yeah it's a biometric
sir
a great in a lot of ways but they read
every be deployed in over a secure
system and for consumer website
authentication they're really not a
viable solution
treasury may change this and to make
change over time we have
Apple pay launching soon we should be an
interesting application is this the
consumer space but
think that's pretty much watch the space
and and then there's another
interesting for it to factory that the
the smartphone clients things like
Google authenticator very things like
that
but now you have softer base to that
effect authentication I
freely without the and there's several
other cities
there you to implement is local software
that runs on the host
or they are implemented as the also is
local suffering host but like a browser
extension this case a Chrome extension
um and they effectively implemented TOTP
rejected the client
but it's running on the same
user usually say machine everything else
as the project application
I and as we see all these things
together have throughout
one coming from whether to come problems
is there not independent factors a
compromise the host
you compromise the two-factor
authentication device all the malware
that sits there
am no matter how strong the the director
of mechanism is
if he can impersonate user it it wins
and you end up with really to
root causes this you have data and
authentication that are running on the
same device
you have something like the the TOTP
happening in the same browser that's
running all your other codes at the
browsers averted you lose
order it something unintentional where
you have something like your
multiple devices are paired in different
levels at different places where the
user wasn't expecting repaired
one of the most stunning appealing and
interesting for me
unfortunately wealthy responsible for
everything else um
is paired mobile devices so you have
something like an iPhone pair to your
he to Mac or if you've got an Android
device you have the backups
I you end up basically trusting both
devices at the same level
and trusts or it doesn't go up till it
goes downhill so
you can cialis prix excitingly the
Sienna before device backup sync just
below the money device extract the key
is
and with a.m. with especially the iPhone
we found in Ohio s
haven't tried this yet on how estate but
I was seven before large amounts of the
I'm data and backups was not crafted
this was
doesn't start his work so you can
extract a lot a really interesting data
from the
the backups often are not crippled at
their own local this is well its initial
option
or they're going through the pass for
the store and user I'm caring so I am
is that and some backups to use
knowledge portable storage
and but not all the new and there's also
applications that allow you to do cloud
recovery which
a think sorta breaks the assumption oath
to factor of the two separate vice
the so there's been too much for texting
attacks on this
some so far p I don't really know the
best way to summarize them because
they're actually fairly diverse but
they're all
basically man in the middle the
attacking the device 32 now where
lot of cases out just right now where
that's evolved over time to add
a small SMS catcher component that runs
on mobile
or it's just an hour's been ported a
mobile on
specifically with the goal is health
stealing credentials but
the arm the real problem with that is
that
he used to be have a computer it take
your computer with you wanna multi city
trip or whatever you do work on a
computer you have your phone use that
for your second or occasional vice
but I know a lot of people now the
travel with just a phone or with iPhone
and iPad
and or just with an iPad or whatever
else and there's an
really no difference there's no second
device they can use so
this assumption you have to fully
independent advice is that aren't paired
anyway
is not really a great assumption anymore
us there that will put that aside for a
second
there's another exciting area oath of
compromise the people have been
exploiting since at least
the
2012 publicly and pretty much before
that like it's been an ongoing thing
is that basically this stuff is is
grafted onto existing code a
under existing systems it's not many
many many cases PCI people say
you need to have to factor of the soul
enterprise clients because a PCI
and so somebody has an existing AAA
system and they decided
oh we quickly need to implement
two-factor how can we do the minimum
amount of work
to implement two factors they bolted
onto the front door
leaving all these other unprotected
areas of the application I don't
actually is to factor
a lot of reasons why they do that one it
is quick time to market
and what it is they don't really think
through the consequences of it
thing is there's a lot of cases where
there's a very restricted user interface
from available to the other applications
either because it's somebody else's code
that they're facing with
it's something like the Google
multi-factor that needs to work with the
sixty existing male clients that only
have a feel for password
or some other system like that where
there is no really had an extra
additional steps and they have to
grafted onto the existing stop I
or things where the form factor the
device or the interaction is very
painful to the user implementing
additional codes
it could be a device that doesn't have a
good key or terminal server keyword
display or anything on it
and and also it's really the the things
that people don't look at so much that
they get compromised it's the infrequent
things like account recovery
special users internal users a lot of
internal systems and not going to factor
while the external systems do
the and things like that so so those are
really interesting places to look
and a lot of people looking as areas p
so everyone from
min do it's been incredibly active in a
sealed they're looking at a pellicle
I'm I think they're probably the the
leaders in finding two-factor bypasses
to this particular technique but
there is a teenager who found a
vulnerability in pickles well so
it's not really I'm only the curfew
people are doing it
and these are only people disclosing is
publicly and responsibly there's plenty
of people who have from
is a very cookie-cutter take a taxi can
just go after any API for
I'm lot of services and look at the
features that are
either infrequent like things that need
characteristics are described
I
the things that are either infrequently
used internally is I'm
restricted in what they can where they
can have the passwords things like that
I'm one of the most interesting things
people seen as the
the Google's publications are passwords
or training people to think that there
they're like these passwords are in some
way restricted but therefore casper's
need a full access to the account so
there's sort of a mismatch between user
the
belief about what the system does and
what this system actually
implements I and yet the the duo guys
found the
exciting Pay Pal mobility using this
this is the hope that they look into
so who thought they looked and i saw
they resist this little air
that said that certain is the
application weren't supporting two
factors so
it was a good place to look so if you
look back at them little bit you can
there's a lot of places they're really
innocent
around fortunately there's an
people who believe more in responsible
disclosure and I do that
have encourage me not to do certain
things so your the
so the the what were the consequences
all the stuff I we will reevaluate
whether two factors are actually
independent of each other
and it doesn't do you too much good to
put your on
authentication application in the same
place as you're protected area
I and then there's the home our threat
basically any system that could be on
the road now where
if it's attractive enough is going to be
10 the the most interesting things about
this it's usually banking applications
which usually do vary by country
so for instance I know the US banking
applications for the banks I use
relatively well because there's a part
two of them but I'm not really like the
Indonesian banking system worth their
various
systems out there and I think it's very
unlikely that on
counter malware systems are going to
stay up on all the secondary and
tertiary market
a.m. banking applications in as real
time as people come to the threat so
that's a
constant area to attack and people need
to redesign their system so multi-factor
authentication is inherent in the system
so make sure that every single for
authentication goes to the same
authentication pathway
and don't leave these is like getting
back towards the doctor had rotation
system
there's a lot of things to do work
incredibly well though come
application-specific to factor of
Facebook and Twitter have done a great
job working in both
a.m. where the application itself passes
credentials back and forth
I devices to take multiple inputs is a
really really interesting idea
is that your device actually or you're
protected application is constantly
evaluating
the security printers both on the
environment
which is operating if it see something
abnormal it will require heightened
authentication
purses /a in normal operation mode and a
great example this is on mobile we have
a very restricted user interface
and users want to be able to implement a
rare billion put a very small
pass code each time the user device the
maybe if the device has been unused for
long periods time you want
a more secure past raise it has a
shorter one or
if you are if the device has been put in
a very bagger some very things like that
various indicators that will show if the
device is a heightened state of alert
and Amazon is a great example this they
allow some very low
risk interactions to operate with very
little authentication using like all
cookies and various other things
but if you want to review your account
history or change payment mechanism
something like that they require height
level the publication
the physical of communication devices
that do have direct you I
things that help keep has things that
have the displays for transaction
details it seems especially the vacant
space a big one is really exciting
for a lot of reasons some even if you
don't believe in it as a payment system
anything else
its really the cutting edge out now
where attacking you right now
because he you have like final
settlement on the resort to attack can
you have got an early so the problem
with attacking traditional banking
systems is
is still may go to jail after the fact
and get caught with big when you have
pretty good chances are both doing a
theft without being caught
so or selling pot after the fact so
a a lot of these devices are now showing
your site
but the Tresor device the shows on the
transaction to be details on it
things that have direct user input
direct is our hope that they will show
transaction details that are specific to
the transaction so you don't know where
compromise your machine fully
you can verify that the transaction that
you this happening is the crack
transaction
offer the device in it secured in and
then you have
out a band notifications one other
the really obvious in retrospect but not
really obvious to people in the building
systems is that
a lot of his actions are themselves
reversible especially banking
transactions
so an attacker usually compromises has
been a certain point in time
does not pertain control system for ever
and release the user has some
chance if they they can do something
later so what you do is use and delayed
notifications use and
delayed authentication request things
like that out a band I love you's a
rollback transaction
but one of the most exciting things out
there is actually client OS protected
storage
the as I said earlier the a mobile but
people moving toward mobile platforms is
a serious
risk for this because it eliminates this
potentially use them as a second from a
publication
however um the advantages they actually
have a relatively good security model
compared to most desktop operating
systems
particularly on the harbor protection
from I work in prosecuting for a long
time that's a great
come gold gold how this is russia
meeting on the desktop but I think we're
still a ways away there's some
great work going on there but it's the
compared the iPhone where there's
trusted computing
very much by default on every iPhone the
it a long ways to go
so X Lion on client certs are really
interesting technology that
have been around now for like the twenty
years and
haven't from little less than 20 years
but haven't really
caught on for two reasons browser UI
issues on dust-up
and the lack the protective storage
because it's just a local file your
system
so on mobile that's no longer really
sure you have local project in storage
for things like client certs
and you have browser UI that's actually
pretty good forum
for how it handles them clio for how it
handles these
for sure anything so I would say that in
the case re not going to happen how to
ban device during authentication
we're showing the transaction detail
showing you I'm pen input in everything
else
you can get this essentially all the
advantage of traditional to factor of
using
TOTP HRDP
I'm client everything else just lazing
client certs hmmm
so there's some usability to finish
their so either exciter face
some usability you get the same me a
better security or you
he could have roughly the same a.m.
security and get a lot better usability
them so those are is an interesting
things but yeah unfortunately the
the couple love and areas where one
could poke at certain API's and get some
really interesting stuff are them that I
am in the Middle Earth
and hearty process on so I'll be happy
to questions
if anyone has questions
point B
E
it
ok thank you very much the pics