so ashamed when we speak to you about a
a nation called 06 fail which was the
silly branding we gave it because it
seemed appropriate at the time another
CP configuration management disasters
I'll explain what all that means a
minute so wow the clicker works Who am I
I'm down screwed researcher its life
loss I've been messing with a bad stuff
for years it's kind of been like kind of
got me into security as it was just
getting bad with embedded device and
routers part of it formerly forensic
student pharmaceutical student before
that internet miscreant before that
apparently bad dodgy unprofessional
childish and a bad influence if you
believe certain people's opinions of me
not well liked by some people in the
industry for hilarious reasons mostly in
the vendor side when I disclosed bugs
about their stuff but that's their
problem so be talking about it is so we
talk about the Tarot 64 protocols and
related vulnerabilities the tea rose
exhale 169 protocol related
vulnerability smart miss fortune cookie
and all that hacking ACS servers we can
take over the world and some other
miscellaneous crop in no particular
order you know just stuff thats related
so for weekend I device when you go home
look up there's two talks by a guy
called chart house he worked at
checkpoint Simon think work somewhere
else now once called icons heroes 69
admins and those presenter defqon and
once the misfortune cookie talk that I
happen to see it 31 c 3 it's also worth
reading through the 06 90 64 and all the
other dsl forum specs this bloody loads
them and having a polka disc of yourself
because if you have a router at home
from an isp you have all the equipment
you need to have fun in your own you
know you have the stop play with this so
i guess start what is T or blah blah
blah they're not or exceeds they're not
like 32
p standard because they're not you know
ietf standards their dsl forum
specifications and the dsl forum is like
consortium old people involved in
getting robbed on to your house and they
come up with specifications and
standardized stuff so that they can
interoperate and you know bill you and
get you internet and stuff and to find
all the specifications for how to manage
your broadband networks stuff he can
follow so if we can implement stuff you
can probably ignore there's tons of them
view google broadband forum org i think
it is and then extension PDF and then
tea or dash you'll find is just tons of
the pdfs all defining different specs
cotu we're going to talk about today or
tiro 640 69 there's loads of others and
there's loads of good security research
to be done by hopefully some of you
looking at the other protocols new
clothing because they're all absolutely
disgusting so tiro 64 is landslide dsl
cpe configuration so dsl is a damn slow
lines or you know dsl internet CP is
consumer premise CP box on your network
the consumer premises equipment I hate
these acronyms so theorists for
specification is outlines this silk
based protocols hello configuration of
CP device from the landslide so say when
you got your router off your ISP
sometimes it come with a cd-rom with the
broadband setup software and you put
that into your computer you'd run it
this goes back a while by the way this
is remember doing this in late two
thousand six you click the cd-rom and it
go okay put in your settings and to
configure the router by magic it's not
magic it was taro 64 and that's the link
to the specification there you can
download it you can read it even go
absolutely bloody mad because it's one
of those boring specifications you'll
ever read through basically it allows
you to configure your router for the
landslide 069 is the other end of it
it's the one slide cp1 management
protocol also in cwm p it outlines
protocol for CP advisors being managed
over one or internet by your isp and
silk based its all this disgusting XML
it's actually more than that it involves
so the horribleness that involves done
it involves jabber for some reason when
i was reading through it was like
there's a bunch of stuff in here about
XMPP being used for something I mean
this loads of potential crap there and
it's all xml-based it's disgusting you
could read it it's on amendment 5 is
probably going to be more amendments of
future so firstly to6 4064 allows
managing an e setting on your end point
of on your CP on your router from the
landslide in theory you can manage stuff
like wireless keys you can set the dns
servers you can set the entity servers
you can set whatever you want it's got
full read rice so you know they see SDNS
wireless security and it comes a few
security requirements so this is like
how you manage and set up your router
you can change all the settings you can
fiddle with old stuff yeah it's got
security things so apparently any action
that allows configuration changes to the
cpe must be password protected access to
any password protected action must
require HTTP digest off blah blah blah
not library pass routes you know it
seems pretty solid and this interface
should only be accessible from the
landslide so maybe you know in theory
that's all nice and lovely but in
reality pastor protection nope don't
have time for any of that um you know
nobody's bothered preposterous new
things password seems be entirely
optional actual credentials yeah you can
totally read them they're not actually
obfuscated if they don't return some
blank or null values you get the real
creds back out at the excess flow to the
Internet oh yes this is the core problem
here this thing which was only supposed
to be ever landslide and explicitly say
you know pretty much do not put this on
the internet was putting the internet at
scale by everyone oh and it also has the
implementation sucks so you've got bonus
trivial to my injection vulnerabilities
because why not you know you might as
well take the entire row of top 10
something you know broken access control
clear tax credits like vulnerability
bingo so you know you get old boxes so
obvious outcome of this disaster well
Deutsche Telekom had some problems they
had some quite serious problems and they
were kind of there when this whole
incident kicked off but i'm sure most do
you remember is incident because it's
recent um when this all kicked off their
kind of the first one to have a serious
outage but they weren't alone talk talk
they suffered you know mass scale
outages routers stopping working device
being bricked kind of bricked you know
they didn't work anymore um
credentialing stolen um you know post
office Eircom demon I mean name an ISP
and they probably suffered some issues
because this and it all happened all at
once and this was home user siddeley
going oh no my internet doesn't work
what's going on because the software
vulnerabilities being exploited scale so
you know what happened who did it you
know is there an attribution parody
going on can we all point fingers and
blame somebody well actually we can so
it was great pities you probably can't
read the screenshots of Python code
there that was the Python code used to
do some of the effective phone on a
script kiddies forum and what it does is
it sends a set ntp server request which
tells the routers update your ntp server
which contains these magical back ticks
and you put your commands into the mac
ticks and suddenly they get executed on
the box and everyone has a nice day so
what they were doing was they were
downloading and executing a boss to do
DDoS attacks and stuff and it was a
Mariah variant called Annie and they
were dropping this you know n mass and
the idea was to build a giant DDoS
partner and they
no pocket things do skiddy things what
caused the bricking though I should go
back what caused of bricking is when you
exploit this issue if you do that and
you update the NTP server a bit with a
shell command what happens is the device
no longer knows what time it is and
computers you know if you know things
about computers you know the computer is
really like know what time it is and a
few they can't figure out what time it
is anymore suddenly they go haywire and
just ship breaks and they start working
and certainly no more computer for you
the device is just said to malfunction
you could start to reset them and they
might start working again maybe so you
know this wasn't the first time that the
particular piece of software involved
had issues for tier of sale there was
miss fortune cookie it affects the same
piece of software which is the ROM page
your server on the devices and terrific
fail impacted the tier 0 64 characters
and miss fortune cookie impact the tiro
69 parent miss fortune cookie allowed
all sorts of shenanigans the most
important one was you can access advice
that any authentication because you
could do basically right what where you
can overwrite variables in memory with
other things you could say / write the
check for admin password variable with
halal know who cares about the admin
password or you could change access
controls and stuff really trivially
exploited vulnerabilities this the too
long don't read a bit below is the proof
of concept from a very intelligent chap
by the name of kenzo that exploits an
aircon one what it is is there's a major
on this fossil and the first you've got
key values right in cookies see if key
value so the first one is the key to
some it's you know pointer to something
and second is what we're covering it
with and the same point you know
addressed over rice crapped over writer
with and what that does what this
particular one does it says basically
let people in without a password you
know don't check you know if the common
sense right port let them reconfigure
the device remotely it'll be fine you
send this request the router suddenly
the state of the router changes Bhoomi
ring he was the software is a crock of
rubbish you know just crap software it's
really poorly written and you know that
was you know that was one of the first
you know when people straight going on
we should look at heroes of mine and you
know what is it anyway so as I said
before the dsl forms back it actually
has some security in a material 69
protocol so this would be important
later but it's got a security features
allegedly it's got TLS it's got all it
took elite mass it was designed by
committee you can see big steering wheel
on revision finds that no they keep
bolting crap on and what clearly happens
if somebody goes who I really like this
technology let's implement us as parent
to this protocol which manages crap so
you've got you know bloated rubbish the
ssl/tls is optional I was reading
through this back in it's like oh we you
can use ssl/tls its wrestle or TLS it's
recommended and some setups of it or
really solid where you chew all off you
know you saw my speeds the device they
ship a really good with this respect
where this client slide start on device
in your this mutual authentication it's
really good or you know you can just use
plain text HPD a store um actual off
from CPD JCS is kind of optional so cpt
crc is a basic alarm sort of it doesn't
really in most cases the password is
sometimes important but the username is
normally like a customer ID or something
it's an identifier for the device acs CP
is often as i said the mutual off with a
TLS client search or you can you know be
really crap and use a shared secret
which anyone can leak by just taking
part of their router again the protocol
just like material 641 it's a lot of xml
rubbish are built on stun soap XMPP
those words that you know some horrible
enterprise developers love go here you
know if it's disgusting and a few things
that you know it's out a day
never implemented it's probably going to
be in there the attack surface is
absolutely enormous so you know we know
CP end of this is rubbish we know that
your embedded device you know we knew
this already your little embedded router
in your house I mean there was another
talk earlier today which said the same
thing your router's crap your router has
bugger all security it never will
because the vendors aren't really
inclined to make secure routers yet
there's no market for it they want cheap
they want fearful they want stuff you
can bang out a million of put them in as
they work internet light comes on you
get the wifis it all is fine so you know
we know the cpn you know crap so uh I
see it I please you know they've got you
know business interest in their end of
the things being secured because you
know their end of things have stuff like
money involved like billing and you know
if you go over your usage cap on your
broadband you know they can bill you're
more you know accounting and stuff I
know on some providers you've got like
50 gig a month and then they screw you
if you go over that you know surely
there they've got some rock solid stuff
surely it's good quality enterprise
software you know we all know that you
know enterprise is good um surely can't
be that bad I mean surely they've you
know they've got this sorted they don't
want to lose money so I'm going to go
into second act which is the bigger part
of it in which we have to plan it by
exploiting the ACS end now explain this
very briefly so we want world domination
Denny you remember this cartoon thinking
the brain good so we won't take over the
world right and we want to do it now so
we could you know go after you know take
the more I approached you know hot CP
you know the endpoint device we could
take the more I approach hack loads
routers technically one at a time you
know or with our botnet you know
scanning you know and you know hack
loads and loads and loads routers but
that takes time and effort and money and
we just want them all now
we want them cheap so you know we don't
want to expend actual effort you know
real AZ I mean I used to be somebody who
was on the thread after side of things I
used to do bad things people I used to
hack into shading mess stuff up so I
know that people like me are lazy we
want the easiest way to get stuff done
so we want to hack loads of stuff but we
want to do very little so I thought well
you could hack all the TPS or you can
hack the ACS and in theory hacking an
ACS will be a lot faster because an ACS
can send commands to all the CPUs
attached to it so why not just hacked
the one box instead of hacking millions
box you hack the one box then just run
your script on all the millions of boxes
you get you know an instant wing and the
cool thing is if you go home and play
around with some ACI software you'll
discover that ACN software is amazing
for botnet commanding control because
that's literally what it is it's you've
got like run shell script on device
you've got like deploy binary is to
device you've got like recover passwords
options you've got change dns settings
you've got all sorts of fun you've got
like all these options to you know mess
with you know millions of device solemn
one go you know the world's your oyster
you know you can reflash firmware images
so you could you know create firmer
backdoors upload them and deploy them
all in one go except they're designed
for deployment at scale provisioning
hola you can you know turn that instead
use it as your provisioning server is
now my botnet or whatever arm or you
know you could just you know you could
mean have to think about it you know i
mean i have sat down and gone what could
i do with this and it's just infinitely
it is you go on for days thinking of all
the horrible world domination you could
do like you could just change everyone's
dns settings and one go to redirect them
all to something nasty like you know
shock images or whatever the world's
your oyster fishing you could do fishing
its tail with this see I decided alone
at night AF server or a few ACS servers
and today I'm going to talk about a
particular one which is been around for
quite a while called free ACS and if in
you know it's been slow work because you
know these are horrible horrible
horrible piece
enterprise software you know their
enterprise grade their enterprise
written as in which means they're
completely disgusting the codes a mess
and you know you you know you go mad
looking at us so yeah this free ACS are
about to have a very fun time so before
I start with the explanation of all the
bugs I found here's the disclosure
timeline it's very responsible
disclosure a while ago found boats
between them now weaponized bugs I'm
kind of forgot about them today public
disclosure bugs how I contacted the
people behind free acs know why they
don't deserve it they've written this
absolute you know it's just
probably some of the worst software
about it and I've been doing this for
quite a while you know just it's
disgusting and you know it's like these
people you know they've written this to
be deployed on ISPs to do you know
critical things and you know you think
they put some carrying attention to it
when I look through it it's like you
haven't even tried you know there's
there's just no concept of you know
actually trying to do security all in
free ICS so just figured I'd drop the
bugs and you know let them burn you know
they can deal with it because quite
frankly you know you get really sick a
disclosure like you disclose the crowd
they don't fix it for six months and
you're like do i drop it joy sit in it
do i leave them and i figure if I burn
free ACS some of the other ACS vendors
might perk up and start securing their
stuff so I'm sorry that one person who
probably is responsible for maintaining
this project but we've been used to
worst example in the world so it's been
around a while I actually think it's
maintained by one person I was having a
look at it and it seems that you know
it's either a very small group or one
guy who writes it it uses Tomcat on my
sequel so it's written disgusting Java
which made me hate it even more I refuse
to program in Java and I normally refuse
to look at soft words written in Java
because just know I like to go outside I
like to not go insane the only job I
want my life is you know coffee
not this you know weird object
orientated crop of absolute rubbish you
know just know so immediately you know
just kind of felt this just taste you
know when I looked at it so it's the
most complete hero 6 9 acs available for
free under the MIT license most complete
means most attack surface um I think we
can all agree on that if you stuck on a
million of one features that's a million
and one bits of attack surface and in my
auditing I don't think of even scratched
the attack surface all that much I think
there is way more there there are tons
of bugs in it to be found so if they
ever actually patch the bug that I
disclosed and their next release you can
just go find more and then you can go
back to hacking ACS servers you know
taking over the world and you know
preferably get yourself a nice cat to
stroke while you're doing it and demand
a billion dollars so um this is this is
the first thing I saw when I went to the
free ACF site looked up how to install
it yeah so they said do this on an
abundant 14.04 LTS server which is you
know that's a pretty old version of on
do I think we run like 16 or 17 or you
know we're on one that's a bigger number
than that anyways I'm not in a bun to
user ID go download this old is 0 which
isn't available you know to go to the
mirror you know that you know go back in
time find the download and then I was
like right now how do i install it on
this you know already outdated box and
it goes do this and nope you know you
see some problems here right go to your
home directory w get this shell script
from a non ssl/tls site um so download a
shell script over plain text make it
executable and then running as root you
know his secure deployment practice and
all that and then read on in chapter 4
to complete the remaining ten percent of
the installation weeks we couldn't pop
it into a crop shell script because you
know reasons and all the remaining
surely running a couple of shell
commands I could send them a patch for
their shell script which it means that
you don't have to do the other ten
percent but they'd still be serving a
shell script over you know HP on a
server that's probably trivially
compromised with hey um so the lowest
hanging fruit I found was the default
login creds I've main XA PS do people
change this do people ever change
default passwords I mean you know that's
a that's a question that answers itself
you can find a bunch of them and
Showtime I just put in the query you'll
need to be logged in to show down to do
a title search but just put in title 3
acs or you can find a couple of them on
google's is like five on google in tight
little free acs web web because when you
go to the login page for some absurd
reason it says free acs web web logging
because you know if the login for the
web or the web web login or maybe we
should put an extra w in there you know
I should send them a patch that's like
free ACS web web web login you can find
them on census you can find them you
know via Bing search by n you know
whatever way you want or you could you
scan the internet to HT title grab you
can come up with your own way of finding
these things they're pretty easily
finger printable and for some reason
they're connect to the internet or get
onto there's a little side note not in a
couple minutes but yeah you can find
them and they probably have admin XA PS
as the login and another note about the
login but why is that and I thought this
is really interesting when is going
through the log in when I was testing it
when I burp suite open those like right
we're going to find some bugs and i'll
type in the admin and then i type in X
aps and i hit enter and i look to where
the password shows up in the data being
sent from my browser to the server and
it turns out that it seems to hash it
does a shower one of the password before
sending it to the server and the sha-1
is just a shell on the password which is
also from
the database so there's some weirdness
there you know there's something odd
like it's literally passing a hash to do
off instead of sending the password in
plain no idea why but you know it
doesn't matter because you can just
capture that and just ship it across so
there's you know some weird smelly stuff
here and I'm just wondering why are they
doing that it hints at something weird
so after I logged in the ACS server
realized that it was actually made of
access it was like an XSS test website
instead of an ACS so I'm pretty much any
parameter you can imagine will reflect
you know will reflect back some input
it's post also carries the most of a
reflected exercise but some of them are
persistent some of them stick around and
because I was an idiot when I was
testing this and every time i go back to
reach has to to make the same mistake
and I don't differentiate between which
you know which payload for which
parameter when i'm spamming in my access
requests one of them just keeps coming
back and I'm like I'm not sure where
you're coming from I know where all the
other ones are coming from book that
alert box that just won't go away you
know it's following me around the ACS
offer you know I click on random bits
from the alert box I'm like whoa hang on
where do you come from you know it's
like it's literally like damn vulnerable
web app except you know it's got
optional you know commanding control for
a whole fleet of cpe devices built in
which is not you know premium features
so I've got some screenshots of the
excess bugs because everyone loves the
lair boxes and here is the first one and
get from you can see it's like the
lowest of the low of like finding XSS
would just spam something in see what
comes out and yes another box pops what
do you do and another one this one in a
post request to somewhere oh that that's
the that's the bloody one the kept
popping up I think that's the one I'd
know where that one comes from but it
just keeps coming back we've got more I
started numbering them at this point I
started each request I'd records request
and I go okay I'm putting a number in
for each one so they can uniquely
identify my cross-site scripting
vulnerable
yes so you know we've got XSS posts off
but that's not quite what we're here for
what we want for world domination and
following demands we wanted to be pre
old we don't want have to crack a login
we don't have to rely on default creds
we want a pre auth exploit that's no
knowledge required of Krebs it needs to
be remote we don't want any of this
local nonsense we need to be able to
fire it at something and it just bloody
works so needs to be exploitable over
the internet and we need a pre off now
that's already pretty much crossed off
all that post salt softer we found we
also wants to give us privileged access
as in an admin role in the ACS server
except we're after we want control the
ACM server so we want admin on it um we
also want to be easy because you know we
won't do this cheaply we don't want to
spend weeks and weeks and weeks
developing some absurd memory corruption
exploit that works you know if I present
the time because he players and ASL or
and all that no we want something that
just works reliably easily cheaply and
we can you know build and weaponize in
like five minutes and deploy where we
can just ship it the minimum viable
world domination plan pinky and stuff so
that's what we want you know and that
seems like we've set you know pretty
high bar you know because you don't
often find these things all in one
basket you know you know some of these
seem to be often quite you know
sometimes you've got three or four you
know sometimes you get to you normally
don't get all four and one go this time
we did this time you know we hit the
jackpot with what's coming up next with
the actual jackpot so preauth attack
surf is actually using a huge lights
like the wall and trumped and all that
you know it's not it's like bigger than
its hands so it's huge the pre-op attack
surface is literally enormous so because
it has to interface for tier 069 clients
you've got a whole client-server model
there you've got as well as like the
admin doing
admins door from the ACS you also fatir
all 69 clients CPS have to communicate
with it and do stuff at the same time so
I was looking at it and the first thing
that CP device sends when it's talking
to an ACS is the cwp notify of yes hi
I'm here and I stayed looking at and I
found it was surprisingly difficult to
find a good sample one these eventually
I found one um and it's xml and it's
disgusting and I won't oh no oh no no no
no I just xml know some found a demo see
wmp client and this is the nonsense that
it sends and there's just loads of
parameters and loads of fields and just
loads and loads and loads of attack
surface to play with their it just
enormous so we've got all of this to
play with and I hate XML xml Java you
know we're an enterprise land here so at
first I tried closing the XML you know I
tried messing about with the trying
stuff that had caused you know cause
server to hang I got it to cease
responding i got just fall over and die
with various loops and stuff in the XML
I got bored looks like Hayes XML so said
okay I want to do something with the cwp
notify that doesn't involve having to
write any XML at all or deal with this
XML parser so immediately said the XML
is out of scope so look for something
else I could attack so yeah there's the
XML but I hate XML you don't want to
play with it you know I just know I want
to do other things with my life that
example that I that example there is
missing a header missing the base of
golf header so don't they use basic odds
to identify the devices and do stuff
yeah okay let's see let's see where we
got here you know this possibly some fun
here so basically in 03 MP notify
messages is used for the passwords
optional some people require
password some implementations require
passwords you can pass so only you know
proper clients can talk to the ACS but
ever the username is actually used by
the ACS identify the device in some
fields for some circus quite often
that's like a customer number of
something is the username in a few
device would take an apparent so the
user name parameter is it's put into
stuffs and it smashed with then it gets
terraced and it gets handled so you know
this there could be something there and
also when I looked at the speck of you
know what face of goth is you know what
stopped you can put into a username
field in it it's really loose you can
stick them over the hell you want so
long as you know it doesn't mangle hv
headers so we straight to play around
and we found something really quick when
I stuck in a quote we found the sequins
action bug which disappointingly I
haven't been able to reliably exploit
something useful yet but that's fine you
know that's fine because that doesn't
matter you know we'll find other books
there's a lengthy sequel query which
when the device registers it gets
inserted and then later on when the
admin does something and it queries that
table the input the single quote you've
jammed in gets stuck into another sequel
query and because it's coming from the
database it's seen as trusted it ends up
somewhere it ends up somewhere else and
ends up coming out breaking something
else along the way this is horrible
chain of disgustingness that leads to
your entire race their server is going
nope no theater says nope not doing it
can't do it and the problem is if you
screw up with your sequel injection
attempt you brick the ACS it starts
working so you got one shot so it's like
let's let's not do that let's find
something easier because I'm lazy and
I'm sick of reimaging this VM every you
know reverting snapshot going up bricked
it again revert snapshot sit there and
wait while the computer chokes along for
a bit and eventually goes okay we can
test it again and another one oak broke
back to the start so there was you know
we didn't get lucky there but hey we
found something else username
completely unsanitized as I mentioned it
also shows up in the UI bunch signs from
the admin sighs so new login to the a
CSS I've min to do your acs admin things
you know to cut off that BTW customer
hasn't paid the bills at six months to
you know check usage deploy a firmware
update to fix some nasty bugs whatever
the user name field pops up and
surrendered in HTML well once another
box in there exceeds made of excess and
I thought yeah maybe we can do that
justjust full deployed I normally hate
cross-site scripting right I think the
cross-site scripting normally is was
useless thing in the world until I
started doing this this is the first
time of may cross site scripting
actually useful and fun because what we
do next will shock you probably not but
anyway that's a click they titled
trivially exploitable excess happens so
it worked from the username that we send
we stick our script alert whatever in
and then when the admin logs in later on
weeks later whatever suddenly in our box
so like okay so from an unauthenticated
somewhere off on the internet land we
can get an alert box into the admin
session you can see where this is going
now you know some limitations you know
we've got Caroline it's in it gets
passed through a bunch of sequel
statements as well as we don't want to
break anything so we've really really
really careful with it kind of not
really you know we have some
restrictions but they're not that
serious and this is a screenshot of it
works you know we got the alert box yay
you know we login as admin um it pops up
and success and I was like okay because
he's the Carolyn the character length
limit in there we can't fit like an
entire big blob a jay s and they're sooo
fun thing this is like can we load a
script from somewhere remote and if he's
a short enough domain name like say x SS
IO or something you know just get one
the three-letter ones on the two-letter
tlds is loathsome available it's get
some short yes you can
can easily get your script in got a
remote script executing it just
magically worked we had you know loading
in remote jazz which made testing stuff
way easier because now what I could do
is I could just start changing the jazz
and the remote side re log in and see
what was going on so we started to get
you know we're getting somewhere with
this so if we can check remote cast into
the admin session one the ovens logged
in we can probably take over the ACS
right you know we could probably do
something so it's all about little bit i
started looking you is there any file
upload book so i can trivially exploit
and i was like a effort you know or i
could deploy some threat i'll just add a
user so i had to sit down write some
javascript but because it's been lazy i
copy and paste it from Stack Overflow
because I had this little rule in my
head we're being the lazy world
domination type so as much copypasta as
we can to write the exploit you know as
much as laziness as much you know 14
year old from hack forums as we can get
with this you know low-hanging fruit
deserves you know low complexity
exploits so there's no CSRF tokens or
excess protections or any of that fancy
governance that you hear about in the
OAuth security guides because this is
enterprise software written in Java and
it's crap so we must send a post request
to the endpoint that let us add a user
so sat down copied and pasted the
example of sender post request in
JavaScript from the first hit and
Google's doc overflow went select all
copy paste right edited a little bits do
need to do and see if it works because
again we wanted low effort and right in
this exploit oh yeah it works so this is
a this is the test this is this is the
most disgusting piece of pie that I've
ever written it's actually probably the
worst piece of code of ever written but
it works you can take over an ACS an ACS
system with like so leopard so we inject
or excess payload in and we get a
response going you're you know cool
your device cool everything's fine you
just get this blob of crop back and then
we wait we spin off our server serving
our malicious JavaScript and we sit
there and we wait and then we wait for
the admin login so admin logs in you
know we get a kind the oven logs into
the ACS the admin then loads the script
from our web server you know standard
soft and runs the script and magic
happens and what's really useful because
as a slight problem of okay so you've
got your whole thing set up how do you
know which ones you've owned so in the
headers there is the referer header and
the refer tells you the URL of the ACS
you've just added an admin user to in a
later version the exploit added a
function to parse that out and check if
the credentials we've out of work but
yeah it works we can now add nap and
user remotely by sending one post
request to be a CS and then just
listening and waiting for once and Lee
boom we've got madman and this is what
it looks like added a nice alert dialog
for debugging purposes so the admin
would definitely know they've been
hacked and we use the very unsubtle
username pass through of hacker hacker
you know just just to be polite you know
so when acs admin logs in they go who's
this user named hunter you know if you
won't be more stealthy you could change
it's like totally legit or if you want
to have a bit of fun you could change is
like GCHQ or something and feel free to
you know feel free to do what you like
so you know we've we've now got a pin
user objectives and it's been added and
we're in the admin group boom worked
magic so you know success by the way all
the code the exploit code will be
released once i'm done um it'll be on on
online on Twitter and stuff so I'll
tweet it with like the PSI Denver a
hashtag so yeah so what do you know
we're taking over the world here so
we've got our
nice that a nasty we scanned the
internet will use showdown census Google
we find all the free ACS servers we
blast out our excess you know one post
request to each you know that'll take I
mean just a couple of hours you script
it let it run boom then we wait a couple
days we may be released in advisory
about free ACS to acs admins have to go
log in to acs servers and i check for
updates hypothetically payloads fire
hack the planet and then yeah we've
we've got everything so we've got hacked
ACS servers now we just reconfigure all
the settings change the dns paypal calm
is now ours or maybe you know for all
them clients or we redirect them to you
know lemon party or something take your
pick of all the chalk images in the
internet we can reflash member and all
the devices so we could do for cystic
mass route kitten all in one go you know
suddenly you've got a bunch of firmware
flash infected devices good luck have
fun imagines cleanup costs allah or
weekend massive billings provision new
devices we could migrate all of them
over to our acs so the isp totally loses
control of them forever you know it's we
can do whatever we want regard now we've
take that ice that is p is now us we are
the isp we're like these guys who by the
way of the most badass logos all the
intelligence things like yes you know
with nothing you can you can start
reaching into people's home networks
corporate networks grabbing data you can
like you could tell the AC the CP device
start sniffing packets and send your
back logs you've got basically mass
surveillance in a box here or global
domination yeah that's pretty much it
have fun take over the world and thanks
to all of these people the organizers
yourselves various people have helped
along the way and software vendors to
keep me in a job if you want to get in
touch contact details i generally ignore
email
because I keep forgetting answer it
because I just saw goody know Jabbar a
more reach belong Twitter or this weird
and you mastered on thing I managed to
black myself a three-letter user name on
one of the instances but it'll probably
fall over in a few days base in the user
account yeah
[Applause]
Thanks that's who it is that's causing
this crop unless this market pressure
honestly I think we need to just burn
them the entire thing start from scratch
like I've been reading through the specs
and stuff for quite a while like I think
the first time I heard tiras Klein which
when I was like 17 years old has
chatting to one of my uncle's is a
network engineer and he was randy was
going on about it he was saying that you
know he was explained to me that's how
the ISP was able to log into my router
remotely and you know fix my internet
basically and he was like you know it's
basically a huge back door and I was
like oh I should look up this but the 17
year old doesn't read like me at least
no 17 early I didn't have the patience
to read through the massive bloody PDF
of the spec and make sense of it it was
only a while later when cherez hull said
doing his work on it but I got
interested in getting I went oh that's
the stuff that i was going to mess with
ages ago but got really bored and soft
you know it was made interesting and
I've realized that it's screwed is too
much crap in it we could reimplement the
whole thing from scratch way better
using modern technology that's not
rubbish like you could do it with JSON
set of XML and that removes all the XML
parser issues which are never going away
you could you know how
proper mutual all proper crypto it does
it's not going to happen and so some of
those will have this stuff enabled on
them and the ifc ones are pre-configured
the IST settings I know with some they
know at least the micro tech one that I
have at home my tub you know if I wanted
to allow the ISPs do provisioning I'd
have to input the stuff myself and let
them have access to my advice which
would end in furs lolno mostly is ist
supplied stuff but you'll find that a
lot of people do configure it or auto
configures in the setup you know set up
the connection nonsense it's you know
it's pretty much ubiquitous like
everywhere there is the spec to that I
think it's 111 yes yeah it's in the
hundreds the spec for those yeah free to
the skate escape some questions
[Applause]