thank you yeah just introduced myself
I've been there elation herbal tea for
27 years quite a later time with my
degrees in mechanical engineering so as
total mechanical things away back kind
of move through networking programming
no one ethical hacking probably this
somebody's I get bored every couple
years and want to kind of go do
something else everybody who is we are
thankful being the program chatter art
party for their to go up in degree so
smug in swing and what are they but
basically a couple tools that I've
created for using were classes in
Alberta first one susceptible web
application generator slug codenames
slug I was thinking damn vulnerable a
little bit overused in hacking so I
moved it away from their second one
susceptible windows network generator
swing so the docs base with all about
what are they why I created them and
we're out the going there's a hell of a
lot future what can these applications
ethical have been Albert a well I always
advertise ourselves as we are vocational
we're trying to aim at the job market
make things as real as we possibly can
however teaching security testing web
application testing or infrastructure
testing it can be difficult it's
additional where that have done it and
some of some of you who've been an
opportune before a recognized a few
faces will recognize those that
essentially what i do is a clear at some
kind of target whether it's web
applications on a network and hand out
the same target to everyone and what
happens is students will collaborate
somebody will find a trick some deal
find an administrative password then
they go in the pub and kill the mix and
it takes away a lot of the challenge and
so it's pretty easy to do that it's much
harder to make a general to make it very
challenging and it's also topic of
students practice and feedback all my
students want to be fantastical so they
want to test a network find out what
this should have found and then try
another one try another once again
you know what was a different destiny I
also try and challenge security that
students in and security as much as a
possibly can it brings more than just
the technical skills and I think Agatha
is more about other things than just the
technical skills things like exposure to
methodologies project management skills
experimentation skills I think a problem
when people have more things by getting
them wrong then getting them right the
first time so as Native students the
environment where they have to test
things they can break things and get it
wrong and then hopefully get it right
but the other thing is think outside the
box and so many people said thing is you
can't teach think outside the box skills
and they may or may not be a right but
you can certainly put students in the
situation that they have to think
outside the box 22 when so that's really
what I want to do so walking it swag
this good slug version one its kind of
this was conceived last July and corfu I
had 18 18 nights in corfu and I way by
the pool in the morning and I drunk lots
of alcohol and afternoon but in the
meantime you know when the Sun was the
hottest I spent to it I wish there was
every day right in this application not
sure my partner was too enamored me gone
and holiday and walk in but once the
geek fall was a geek so looking at web
application security testing and a lot
you'll recognize these applications
brilliant applications done vulnerable
web app written by Ryan Durst known for
years great application mythology abhi
walk and also web caught the fantastic
trade and applications as a lot of
challenges and them growing it however
they're not really will stick web
applications so you cannot perform a
methodology against damn vulnerable
Weber that's not its design it's not its
function so it's not vocational with
anyway because someone getting a job at
the end of this would be a fine a
methodology to your website reporting
the findings so it's but that's just not
end there also second with solutions are
out there
students are like the rest of us will
take a shortcut so if you can go online
find the solutions then students i'll do
that and a lot little clip well i would
have found it anyway but the method out
the experimentation skills that they're
getting it wrong kind of skills that you
that your lamb and also once you've done
DV wa it's done you can chuck it into
been basic one so here's the desire
sensory so know what classes or 40 50
students i want an individual and
real-life website as much as possible
for each student or several for each
student and the one them to form a fill
test using the methodology and then do
the further here the documentation at
the park at the end every student hates
doing that but tough the sweat so we'll
both you must document in the real life
or real world so a one would realize
that application students can attack and
it won't lots of them and I want them to
be vulnerable in different ways I don't
really want them to be tied down when
you're rather than any anything like
this if you get something that's tied
down it's really good an object
quadrants you're not really 11 very much
so want them to be very vulnerable
rather than under long haul so what I
did on the balcony in corfu was I
googled for applications so that will
tell you factually MySQL PHP
applications and see what's out there
and there's lots of websites free
student projects com which I take it our
student projects that you can download
and submit as a course look don't ever
do that because same thing of a
technical term for these applications
but I could only think of shite the
person they are absolutely awful you're
terrible applications Phil voges Philip
Boyes and in many cases the filter genes
as well also be incredibly careful of
using any of these and the documentation
is just they fail a document with it
many of them no don't do that so anyway
I started downloading them I did most of
these applications that have died
avoided I fight to fix the code that's
number one I'd to make it work what's
the functional it wasn't there I've also
kind of
turn them into a lot of things you see
home what school which is I think it's
very relevant to this building I feel
like them you know I feel that any of
the magic wand in this building isn't
bad but anyway so these are the
applications of data wouldn't use so
we've got school manager system we've
got them a jeweler store in here which
have some din to recast Feliz jewel
jewelry store online career guidance and
they've also got a medical service
specialist whether promoted to the
castle to a doctor I've got a student
information system a clinic our web poll
manager and of course no student can
survive without pizza so I thought I'd
being a pizza or the system as well so
these are basically what I would like
them the contrabass applications eight
of them the coded in different styles
which is great so it definitely could in
styles most of her endless each of these
applications has also got lots of
different inherent vulnerabilities
cross-site scripting there's probably
that cane in each of them which is which
is fine no has what we want there's
still not enough you know so I needed to
do a little better scripting so give me
a good excuse to learn about a Python so
here's here's that the very first
version use this for student assessment
so you see it generates random websites
for student assessments but just go
through each of the parts individually
in here you can see we've got a student
what's all six names in an eight it's
created a copy of the jewelry website
for that student copy of food website
for that student so creates a copy of
one of them at random then injects
random vulnerable both its end to that
student way back and then all the
injected volumes of all stays involved
for me so when I'm marking I can see
what each student was facing but also as
part of feedback I can send them the
bread and say here's what you should
have found so a nice a little bit of
feedback for them and I think feedback
is really important in this this case
here's the current injected vulnerable
face I have not injected cross-site
scripting because they've been so many
so many of the men they're pointless
likes nice little a believe it but
things like super when Jackson proxy
request forgery a lot of what is in the
some that been injected after your folks
so things like director drive-ins out of
there or it's not there some are random
will create some or less so for example
each of the Advocate applications have
got an odd mineral game as well as the
standard user login so for the admin log
n I've created a password based on
actually txt file some are random so for
example with super injection
countermeasures there these are these
are a very basic one a lot more now so
it's going to pick one of these you see
that this one is it says we just felt
about when it was one or select on union
in there so that's all done at random
just a little bit of detail how I've
done this it's really not rocket science
all I've done is going through the PHP
cool in certain places and normalized it
so for example anything that I login
I've used dollar username and password
in the PHP and then I put an include
file underneath so the cancer measures
the sequel injection there are from that
file and my script basically creates
that file so it's not really rocket
science there's also a look within the
code we're putting tags so my script dog
steps through from the tags and replace
the tags with whatever I wanted random
on this was the feedback that was
created for a student's pretty basic tip
again where I must have known as much
better now but you can see in here that
got hidden source codes messages user
enumerations possible admin password is
service in this case so you can see a
useful feedback but what the student
should have found when you put them are
going through it so use them 10 14
assessment what reasonably well probably
too many vulnerabilities but I've got a
lot of good feedback from the students
in there and kind of also dealt a little
bit now but given students of practice
platform is not this is not really
fulfilling what I want to do here I
would I would like some kind of
self-contained application where
students can create things and instant
will get feedback and maybe a little
better training in there as well so smug
version 2 i'll give you a little demo
this in a minute but very very simple
web
interface why is the student to create a
vulnerable web app with definitely
different types of all of the most days
then taste it I get feedback on it so I
have a nice day today my laptop fried at
eleven o'clock this morning thanks to
mari anything Rudy for your laptop so
let's hope that this works so I've got
this running if I Salim rise to get it
running in a tiny core virtual machines
so the entire thing is rained about 250
Meg ceux qui tam it quite amusing screen
here will be the truth right so this is
essential here you see all those you
create a random vulnerable web app for
testing purposes pretty straightforward
if I create a new web up and I've done
it with a kind of base I can see all
vulnerable is a rare no vulnerable is
present or run the vulnerabilities so
I'll just do once they run the
vulnerabilities but in here I want to
make sure that a definitely of sequel
injection in there so I can make sure
that these are definitely on or I could
have said no sequel injection yeah so
can do that create the web app that's
the robot generated there's a little bit
of information is the bottom you've been
given a user account hot club is the
username password and sat Bob your task
is to test it so you can call the web up
I'm able go so that's that one you can
log in here and do a full test of it
well back a bit at the end and then go
into the injections and this is a less
than that one that's been injected just
all getting some of them there's a
cookie that can be reversed that's the
way it's been created directly frozen
zone a volt going a bit simple injection
there's a countermeasure is used as a
bit forcible admin passwords this is not
an easy one but that's obviously in the
debt ceiling that I've used so next a
nice and simple we're black we create
another one all vulnerabilities robot
this is my hope random kind of comes in
oh yeah you just knew it was run the
balloon of creating seen one so yeah
that's created another one so it's a web
file manager in there can be used on as
we see each point if you go back and see
what was injected so I it basically
means that student can sit in practice
and practice and practice and practice
and also individual vulnerable is so
someone wants to become an ex gotten
sequel injection they're nikka just
create site after site with different
countermeasures one what's the things we
doing this ten ton of things to do is
immoral think about it there are more
things to do number one outcome the
shooting the force that are about to
come in see what their phone and trying
to make it better more based web apps
I've got that another sex that I've
downloaded that I could fit in fairly
easily I've medium wall so the saints
currently very very vulnerable more
vulnerabilities we're talking to a
number of people at security and live
suggested vulnerable is that could be
two ends or I'll put their own web
server configuration vulnerable is
there's no reason that I can't add in
the environment as well I've also got an
honors project student David who's done
a great job start the year I told him
this is what I'm going to do here's your
possible is he disappeared that I hadn't
seen him for a bit for months and he
came Barton when he showed me all these
things is implemented so there's lots of
things when they're like passwords
throttling and so many things he's
actually got a training system in near
as well so I will be incorporating the
house stuff into this as well before
releasing it swing kind of ribbon rather
the world alone the same kind of thing
infrastructure been testing classes I
give out a network latissimus you all
the same all these things about same
network they collaborate so how to make
this more challenging I had the idea
let's try and create a random Network
generator done it in pyro Cheryl power
is absolutely fabulous you go online
most most of my code is joining together
routines that I find
light it really has a copy and paste job
I feel like a student just going online
copy and paste a couple lines in between
it but there are two routines for
creating a domain controller you know a
simple routine you should download and
call it you know so that's my code I
feel that virus but whatever but this
was invited application a definite
vulnerable network for every student
2008 server and 127 so the general have
to share rose and cue clients it's
multistage partial application but the
batch files in there all we do is really
control thanks so I mean in a minute the
reason it has to be multi stage is
because you know what windows like you
trying to steal anything properly then
you must reboot your machine so it's a
bit of a pain so it's hard to be multi
stage so a state essentially for the
windows 2008 server four stages stage 1
2 3 and 4 stage 1 and this way values
and that's things like tons off the
firewall on UAC just the mixture of the
scripts runs run okay sets IP address
and the windows have you ever set the
machine name then you must be bit you've
got new options so that's stage one and
then reboots and run stage to set the
opposite to be in control stage three
starts to do a bit more positive things
like adding and users look we know a lot
more detail in a minute also as in
computers dns and still somewhere when
the services as many as i can get away
with without asking me to reboot and
then install some patches reboots stage
for the stalls some more windows
services configures the services and
also install some third-party software
so going to go through each of these
part exactly to these parts and any file
controls also i've gotten any file with
everything in here for example the
domain name uat you ad target com also
things like organizing organization
details and they've also good things
like the department's for groups within
the network and things like usernames
that being random were created I know
so once that I'm going to use for
passwords for creating for users so
adamant random users see any other in
random users I've got minimum possible
paths or the length of maximum but I've
been a percentage of users with
dictionary words passports so in here
I've got forty percent that can be
controlled I've also got users with
dictionary force numbers so forty
percent the users addiction for numbers
and I've said twenty percent I'm going
to have good passwords that are very
random and then creates each of the
groups so but human resources legal
finance engineering sales etc and if
there's users who are in the admin group
that I've got good passwords these are
up there admin users were pretty much
uncrackable passwords and also three
users in here that being created they
have in administrative group that got
crackable passwords and here I've got I
think of their it's 102 102 users have
created and it dumps all this their file
so that i can I can take it away when
I'm marking here's a deal in the random
users exceeded anything that's happened
that any of the number one our dog
Athena was created with a dictionary
password the next one is additionally
fast word for a number down he ever got
a very difficult possible to crack but
also we've got an admin with a bad
password n here n da lamp whose password
as in the dictionary and that one's
there's an admin was a difficult
passport so it just kind of goes through
that hchildress through that and also i
got pageant patches up to a random day
or specified date so i can say patch the
server up to a year ago or if it'll do
it randomly and the way i did this was i
used the third part of packaging that
they knows all these patches as msu
files and it's very nice that means i
can do this nore stopped because again
windows when you do in a patch what
should we start with some so the very
last one restarts okay also installs
when the services using powershell and
creatively easy to install windows
services
so you see the kind of thing Sutton's
install and dhcp tftp smtp just however
many services i can do end there at the
end of all this is that kind of sample
output that you see in the windows 2008
server that we've got all the groups
have created in here that will use HR
and IT legal whole pile of computers the
near of dummies computers if you're
looking each of the groups we've got
users that have been created in there
and also the administrator as you can
see there's a number of a menace it has
been created in there as well configure
the services what I try to do for each
of the services I've created one PI
Rochelle file that sets up the service
secure and one insecure so for example
in there I've got dns this one allows is
doing transfer which is not good so
that's that's a vulnerable one evident
key sort of SNMP we've got a public
greed Illinois and there as well so
there's 2i or side my program i can set
to run the moist select one of them or
always making vulnerable depends on how
we want to configure it I didn't flip
out the applications find this package
am called up deploy quite often own
internet as free up before it's been
around for years and years but it still
works really really well I've only got a
think I've got to FTP servers in here
that my application users but allows you
to please snap short system so you
snapshot the system and by that I mean
services registry files the kind of
things a snapshot or not then you
install what you want and it may be
apache web server with a website and all
the configuration in there and then you
post snapshot it and it creates an msf
file of everything that you've done that
changed so i can set up say apache
server in 20 different vulnerable ways
with a different msi file for each of
them and then see it at random choose
that one or choose that one or choose
that one so so brilliant a lot of
application it's about 15 years old i've
got's quite shocked you're still works
but it's a little bit slow but hey once
it's created is created
yes and what fine is really to create
different categories in there so every
student will have an ftp server a vision
or the intersection party web server or
different types of services in there so
anti procedure on a little bit
complicated a little bit complicated i'm
using a vm run command comes with vmware
the syntax is a little bit awkward but
once you crack for syntax then it's
answer and creatively easy to use it
allows you to run a vm revert to
snapshot it allows you to create shared
folders to copy things over to the vm
allows you to run things on the vm as
well as you know from a kind of single
command on your base operating system so
this is a century of what this create
net what script does I've created for
kind of beer bones operating system vm
server one beer points nothing done to
at all so this is unclear as a nap short
called booted so all over the initial
part that might smell does just built up
to four VMs and the signal or happy then
copy everything over on to vm server one
in a folder then a copy batch files onto
each of the virtual machines and run all
these bad spells in each p.m. now
explain why you need to do that in a
minute but this is my situation we've
got to service to clients we've got go
runnin on them and what Gordon that does
essentially it sets the IP address now
if you set the IP address then we can
communicate with all four of them can
communicate with each other and in this
case I'm using server one as a
controller okay so that's essentially
what it does is certain way and then the
first controller will go through my four
stages of creating that the link and for
all the users with all the services etc
etc once it's finished at the very end
okapis required files to the secondary
controller and each of the clients and
then the cause we've got fixed IP
addresses we can pierce exec enter them
and say no checking action and
essentially what happens
is the secondary controller will be set
up sets opposite to be in control none
of that so it does all that as well the
client will join the domain logon is a
certain user and the same with a client
to so reasonably complicated procedure
but you know it will straightforward
paint on a future work in this again
number one Clinton network traffic with
an idea that I've got that I think it
would be nice if we could see every five
minutes get the user to do something or
specify beforehand and from a random
10-point get a user to click on the link
go get always use a cop in an email and
settle in thentis and use something like
respond on or something and you know
harshest ugly so what of it areas in
there more windows services and each
other and want more configurations in
Windows tweaks lots of them as well more
third-party applications so whatwhat's
of them to do and of course then you
start thinking well i can add in virtual
rules as well so we're going to we're
gonna add in look the whole wall I don't
virtual Ritter ever you said you haven't
got a linux server organ are there no
one except so obvious thing that all
certainly possible the time to do it is
we're going to take a while but lots and
lots of things ender combining the two
of them this was canet an idea what HUD
I've got a module done in fort here
called been tested where the students in
traditionally have been given some kind
of target that the op the attack and
again we've all got the same target so
had the idea what combine all this but
not creating four different virtual
machines pre create everything in there
so all the usernames all the services
everything required for each student so
student one will have this set up
student to go of the set up students
will have all these and the way I'm
doing at the moment you built up the
first vm which has a web server you
choose your name from their head submit
and it's set up the environment for you
and the veggie way so it means that
every single student has got a different
web application they've got different
usernames and passwords and services at
students are working on this current
like some of you in front of me I'm
working on a common one it'll be really
interesting to see the feedback that
will get from this so I can kind of
change it again more and more father
work involved in here I was thinking
that we could of the same set of the M
so you built before the MS let's em
office to swag you can see I want to
create a network with two hundred users
ten percent as more crap parcels native
percent than the good passwords I want
numerous services and then heck goal so
it's very very similar front end and it
will go away and generate it and then
the kind of injected that the volume of
office the solutions are there as well
so students if you want to practice
there you go you know help yourself I
like the instant feedback of that I
think is is the real good 11-point
honest so something up certainly find of
useful utilities I will be releasing
them as soon as i get time to get my
arse in gear and do it properly if I
said we want to add in the honest
projects stuff in prove there's a lot a
bit stuff in there but future what goal
or you know any of you are partly
students in subject or norse projects
core in this anyway thank you
for what was then a rattle sit very
quick all over Martin's instructions
that we all need to go to the pub
[Applause]
that's got a 25 minute for questions
will help you beverly hospital seen it
yes yes a whole you know that's again
another future what there could possibly
be done and i am thinking again that
would make a great on this project for
somebody doing that you know one of the
big issues would stop this about one of
the big issues i know someone else at
another university who's trying to do
the same kind of thing and they are
trying to set this fantastic framework
saying as i haven't seen any out group
from that it doesn't watch it and
there's two years down the line there's
nothing there so my idea was definitely
a let's make it work number one and then
let's get clever with that number two so
yeah I totally agree can't be done it
would be excellent anyone wants to do an
honest project I'd be delighted if you
did that but yeah just a quick quick
little look at this is this is
essentially a spring running to begin
mer it's all running a single virtual
machine i'll just briefly show you this
is the syntax in here for the vm run
command see it's awkwar-- awkward-- if
your vm run without the snapshot vm run
start an evil shared folders and you see
underneath forgot I'd share folder set
share folder state etc then underneath
that is basically like a copy of an oval
one so sent does it all but awkward but
keep going through
from there is visit we just kind of
create network the whole phone takes a
bit 45 minutes to run so I certainly
don't want to show you them all up but
you can see it's run vmware it will then
restore the snapshot then the files are
all copied over so you can see all the
files copied up so that's all done from
the single batch file which has made my
life pretty much pretty easy most of it
but that's nice essentially the vehicles
through sorry i want to show you that as
well since I point it is more certainly
an issue at windows 2008 server from
import and passwords etc has a secure
string in there which is Midwife a bit
easier because my application doesn't
import text passwords imports a strength
like this and I'm hoping that I can
Kenna it's going to make it difficult
you give hacking students a challenge
like this the new reverse engineer it
right enough so I've got an issue in
there well I'm trying as much as I can
to try and hide that and if I can think
of a bit an idea they know will but as
it is yeah it's difficult however I mean
would you really go through that process
of you know do the digital forensics is
your boredom virtual machine you cracker
absolutely in a pen testament good yeah
yes Decker yeah you're the Hawkins
student alia thang thang in all the ways
that you can submit that's good I'm not
saying that's about like I said there's
a good thing you know that's thinking
outside the box yeah you're definitely
right however I still think a lot of
these things a student spent that when's
the time doing that then just crack are
doing the paint test you know
oh you're right you're right but I still
think you be quicker to advantest you
know well i'm doing the digital forensic
job of doing something really incredible
cause i'll just good point i do pain
test so I've got to tell you the answers
to your coupons well don't we reason
you're here cheese I was expecting
operative graduates to told me because I
was still got jobs garda you guys you've
got the right to told me you've got a
job they've got a lion Viet an example
[Music]
yeah which is very possible absolutely
setting a vegetarian what the idea is
diff infection the company with a lot of
colleges it should be a walk with us but
hey that's not really the testator this
is to be one the traditional application
I'd like to take all these e
applications and find on the run on
water and educate me quite a while
because the code is not really exactly
which is fine no yeah
yeah I'm not a victim if ago we invented
on on your documentation that's all
wrong but that's awesome yeah procedure
palace you know it soon as we just
certainly where people to project
regeneration a set yourself before and
you don't example 11 another wonderful
people don't get also solo material
contact three that accompanies people
who are budgets and puppies who said
they chose it will give you suggestions
and see a bit better because but my
number one I get that is education but
number two are great for whatever
company HTC and we're ever take care and
use other people to stop me if I could
said at the nigga said well and you're
going to you immediately I want and take
works often and your baby LOL
application center yes yeah I said most
of you can't yes yeah so if you want a
copy give me show you this in today to
do it I find a wiggle in your walk dog
don't use your Lots as always it
everything plays it all the Western a
50p yeah you're right i guess i could
imagine wantin more papers
I foundation heads up to this weather is
correct youtube or I keep my fav future
what I mean if I can get 20 people to
deal with mr. Jackson a or nests
that would be fun fantastic good there
are so many things to be done with it
you know oh yeah good yeah I've been
that would be really nice then again I
think that shows what Martin's go to a
company because I want my students the
base weapon you know so affiliate
happens the end it's going to kill them
we've done this in the past is that we
were asked before there would you like
our students to test your website and
the people with math websites will say
no the person whose website has put it
down secure as the person is going to
all Yelp it low to be able to give you
so behind as the students and there's no
vulnerable and then it like handing over
all the bodies in it and it's all
destroyed for the students to start off
with that they're not fighting an
innocent so yeah I can see there's been
kicking on by a company and then doing
that yeah definitely Jeff one okay
that's a hopeful winter a week something
hopeful people good well you know we
would outfit and do do do anything with
it because I don't think us that there
are people who've got this idea out
there but I've not seen any results you
know great up with an idea and twine on
it for three years that no I want
something to watch so thank you
[Applause]
you