hello everyone thank sir I got stand
next to this thing done can you hear me
if I walk away thanks for coming to my
[Music]
wife's go then check that out yet to
cancel then I wanted to talk about a way
I think that maybe we can we can fight
this problem will loop back around to
some more complaining then we'll have
some open discussion some question and
answer which officially a little aston a
few minutes unofficially it's going to
last the rest of my life that I ruined
everybody on board already miss to talk
cool this is not like a dense
informational II you know intensive talk
it's me up here talking about this idea
I had for like a half hour and then we
go and have some snacks problem so
mighty news replication difference I'm a
penetration tester a member of the red
team is secured and like a lot of
penetration testers I have a compulsive
need to tell you that I'm a penetration
tester and then talk about penetration
testing for a while so let's do that how
did I get here how did I get to be up
here complaining about user apathy and
indifference penetration testing it's
one of the things that there's always
some debate about how to define it what
it really means same thing with red team
testing but essentially I'm a fake
criminal for hire I test security I test
things by trying to break the rules it's
the best job there is this the best job
out there I don't know what your job is
but sorry mine's better
with most penetration test they are
focused on a specific area of an
organization security I but that's the
internal network with that external
network wireless is it good lots of
different stuff each can provide value
to the organization they can identify
weaknesses but they are inherently
restrained they're restricted to
whatever is being tested an external
penetration test is only going to test
the external network with with a red
team test we get to take the gloves off
of it we get to get a bit more into the
role and it's really pretty simple I'm a
bad guy you have something that I want
to steal I don't know what it is maybe
its credit card information maybe it's
personal health names business secrets
whatever it is I want it so I'm coming
for you now I don't want to go to jail
so I'm going to try to choose a text
that well and I think they're effective
they follow through my level of
acceptable risk they're not going to be
noticed they're not going to be caught
awesome I hold it lazy I don't want to
work too hard stealing your stuff sue
and yourself at the business for me I'm
not looking to waste resources I got
bill cheap and effective for me the
attacks is going to trump something
that's flashing expensive and and
finally I don't feel any real need to
play by your rule I don't feel need to
just stick to just the external or just
a wide line everything is in scope and
as has your bad guy i'm going to use
whatever works so what we know works
with with a disturbing degree of
reliability is attacks against the user
social engineering USB key drops
aiding in the building's fishing the
user is a week p week users a weak point
in your defenses and that that's
something that will exploit that's
something we'll take advantage it we
will find someone at your organization
having a bad security day and will
leverage that in pursuit of stealing all
your stuff and yeah that's a lot of fun
but I'm not really a bad guy and you're
not paying me to just break in a call
smogon American I need to provide some
sort of like actual response some sort
of recommendations on how you can stop
whatever attacks were successful during
this test and traditionally the
recommendations that we provide tend to
fall into a couple of different groups
I've wandered away from the podium and
Jey flies and I have the thing that lets
me change slides as I carried around I'm
going to keep leaving it here the person
which is well I think of us as
technological solutions and we like me
these are comfortable user employee
allowed tailgating in the building you
should buy and install a turnstile for
your honors fishing was effective thises
secure email gateway 9000 plugging to
your network something bad happened by
this thing it'll make it better we like
these beasts as technology enthusiast
these fall in line with our way of
trying to solve problems yeah they can
be expensive but it's something we can
control the problem is that for a large
part we're doing here is treating the
symptoms we're putting some band-aids on
some bullet wounds we have here yes they
work they do you know stuff they do what
they're pretty much supposed to do the
best they can but
they often end up being more of a speed
bump to an attacker rather than that
that brick wall that we're all hoping
for all right what else do you recommend
user education I love this will say
provide your users with information
security awareness training information
security awareness training I die just a
little bit inside secret honest it and I
say it's white I don't know what but
information security awareness training
undeniably it's a good idea it's
critically important that we can't you
can't afford lycra mass ignorance of the
topic but everyone hates it everyone
even we as security professionals don't
like security awareness training so much
so that in a lot of places what have we
done we've taken the whole thing and we
shut it over to the human resources
department that here you deal with it
information security awareness training
has turned into a 40-minute PowerPoint
slides egg that you click through as
fast as you can it's next to the ethics
training and the annual harassment
training this is what we've done with
them and sadly I guess it's working as
intended let's talk about not here the
human resources department at your
organization exists to protect the
company from the employee so in that
regard the information security
awareness training doing exactly what
they wanted to do because when what if
these users inevitably after receiving
training clicks a link in an email well
now you can you can reprimand them you
can yell okay so do a live demo of how
that light though yell meow scary
well dad gore pointing right at you much
that like can you help me out that night
ah so in this scenario a user who's
click pumping I've come dealing Eric off
amen he clicked the link in that
phishing email why why did you do that
who told you remember eight months ago
you took that training to said hey don't
do that promise alright well I mean the
CFO click the same link so try not to
move again all right yeah that's it
thank you that's essentially what is
coming down to its a way that that we
can get people in a little bit of
trouble if they don't follow the rules
so we're fighting a battle here how does
look like we're doing do we have
technological solutions are they
expensive and do they annoy our users
yeah that's how we know they're working
we have user education is it boring yeah
that's tough how we know it's
educational right the user they're
informed they know but they don't care
they don't care enough to act and some
of the problem is that we as information
security professionals we're not good at
making people care about me Computers
Computers are still tricky but getting
juven very actual people to care about
something it's a bit outside our core
skills
we need to approach this problem in a
different way clearly what we're trying
yeah it's working you know what it
suppose to do but it's going to continue
to be a problem we can get back a bit
what we have is a nice probably
relatively simple idea something that
our users could do do that would make a
security better everybody needs the
magic don't click every link in the
email with you get choose a complex
password and user where trainees we've
tried to logging Lee gently force them
to do it with the technological
solutions we have it trying to sell it
there's like that's gonna get burned the
Nexus showing this to them once in a
while but it's this message out there
kid it engraved it so that they can't
stop thinking about dead stopped working
about it squeezing this muffin fair to
Gloucester doll we might be we should
you invest the help of marketing
professionals to sell security to our
users marking professional marketing is
telling people about an idea and then
giving them to act I that's like exactly
what we want and all right yeah it's not
it's not a completely new novel idea
people look on the internet to find
references to it going back for years
but it doesn't seem to be either widely
implemented or well in connected but
that doesn't mean it's not a good idea
you can see how you might hear about it
and say use marketing for sale security
users if they call it that makes sense
but online marketing is not what I do
and then the ideas sighs when we head
outside there we go when you head
outside I see advertisements billboards
logos everywhere you watch television
there's commercial product placement you
go on the internet and you're not using
an adblocker some region advertisement
score when you head into the office that
is that with advertising pretty much
drops off hopefully penny will work and
what we have is more of a blank slate
this is where we could target our reach
our target audience this is where we
have an opportunity on every blank wall
and every screen on every internal
website to get this idea this simple
security idea where in front of the
users not not look here during training
you can in front of them every deck and
marketing marketing can help ensure that
this message is communicated defensively
effective communication we'll talk more
about that in just a minute after these
messages yeah that's a commercial break
in my talk at the time you guys try this
one this is this is a pretty good son I
can't get it back in the States but
I'm hoping to get a sponsorship deal all
right fine maybe I should not define
it's not actually intermission going no
one get up and leave can hardly look at
me I've had too much sugar as it is I
possibly too much caffeine today what do
we got all right let's say for the sake
of argument that you don't think I'm
crazy you like this idea maybe you think
well how can we possibly get it going in
my organization I've been thinking about
that too we have so much in common we
should hang out how can we do this of
what option make looking we can do it
internally it's quite likely that that
wherever you're working has some sort of
marketing personnel already working
there maybe you could look them illicit
their health and developing an internal
information security marketing campaign
they understand your corporate culture
they know what resources you have
available maybe a good working
relationship anything happen place all
of that I'm not disappear saying like
everything's great clear problems
possibly coming up primarily is that
working on your security campaign is
probably not their job they have their
own marketing stuff to do that's
presumably making the company money what
else is going to cost a certain amount
of Maya do this who's paying for this I
who was this idea who hates this idea
who's fighting with the people who love
or hate this idea corporate politics
always fun to feel it it's something
where you'll need to have done your
homework try to find someone on the
marketing team where you can you know
get there by an idea come at it from two
directions find a champion in marketing
that seems to be done needed to get
anything done in in a large organization
heavier no arguments ready as to why
this is going to help solve a problem
that your company is having okay well
look we hired an outside consultant to
do this work speaking as a consultant
hiring a consultant is often an
excellent idea the Eclipse you could
contract the company fine company that
has the experience in both marketing and
security to come in and help identify
problems and weaknesses it and build
that information security marketing
campaign you could maybe try to fly past
some of the internal politics you don't
need to pull from your marketing team
they're still obviously some problems
potentially consultants at the very
least cost money I don't know I didn't
do the math but there's not a line item
to the budget who's going to pay for
this Oh decisions need to be made we're
back at politics so I think consulting
is a pretty good idea and you may be
thinking this guy work secure work
Brandon Ellis lies is he about to stand
up here and say that secure words has a
brand new service offering where we come
in and do marketing no no we're not
going on sighs I'm pushing for it maybe
we'll all someday but we'll see how
convincing my arguments are to the
bonkers finally a third way thinking
about this what I think that has was a
good deal merit couch college interns
college school sydney university
students happen to be here sweet not
here marketing students doesn't what we
need we can bring in a marketing intern
and for that semester of whatever you
have here they would be more than just
bringing the marketing department some
coffee and doughnuts they would work to
develop an internal marketing security
campaign if right now you've got nothing
literally anything these students do
would be better than nothing that you
have your team could provide what you
want them to sell as well as various
health and resources the marketing
department could help out providing
guidance and direction this benefit the
organ
station because they get some kind of
security campaign it benefits the intern
who would get some unique experience
fairly up-and-coming line of work it
would benefit you if your users just
stop clicking on things for five seconds
while they're looking at whatever this
kid made and then helping us out of the
day they are so right now it should be
fairly obvious to you that I'm just some
hackers standing up here saying like hey
I got a good idea and go forth go out
there and and talk to marking and good
things will happen i promise i'm going
to stay safe over here in my consultant
problem not talk to strangers because
they're scary yeah I didn't want to be
completely hypocritical coming up here
talking about that so I tried to myself
I went out to a member of our own
security marketing team I went out to
local colleges in the Chicago area where
I lived and hunted down Murphy
professors I wanted to get their
professional input I wanted to say may I
have this idea do you think it has an
area what potential problems you think
we may have and trying to pull this off
if we were to try it what what potential
issues what can we do to maybe make it
more successful there could be big
problems I would just have no idea cuz
I'm I'm not in marketing i spending go
school for it's never been my job I'm
standing up here saying it's a great
thing I also wanted to do this so i
would have the experience I think I
didn't know you guys I didn't have
introductions never met them before I
wanted to look like 22 approaching
strangers with an ID I had and say you
know how would it be to try to interact
with anything and get their involvement
so I came to make his questions and they
said larger now instead
I get that along they said either
overwhelming on each one I spoke to was
interested they thought the idea had
merit they they offered their inputs or
recommendations and perhaps even even
funny they were expressed an interest in
continuing to work with me in the future
developed appeared to say like a good
idea to get out of here I mean I'm 40 so
they're not going to call me okay but
still it was right to the madam and it's
something that's that really inspired me
to Achilles this isn't just me Daniel
you're saying hey I think this is a good
idea it's me and also a couple guys over
in America that you don't know and I'm
coming over here to back me up what can
you do so not as if a critical as I
would have been otherwise that's what
loop back around to effective
communication by possible that this idea
of marketing security is already a play
in your organization being used to try
to fight off this user apathy and
indifference i get 2 i'm lucky enough i
get to visit a lot of companies and see
what they got going on in security watch
sometimes they even knowing they're
doing that but I've seen a few things
and some stuff I like and some stuff I
don't like one of the things that that I
found people doing more and more it
seems pretty cool is the gamification of
fishing detention this is where anyone
please you this any one company yeah all
right good um hopefully you don't like
completely disagree with me as I
continue to talk so this is where users
are encouraged to report suspicious
emails not just because that training
said you should totally do that but
because there's some sort of competition
this some sort of contest they can
possibly win some sort of prize and what
if presented to the users it's not it's
not a footnote on a PowerPoint slide
deck it comes out a little bit of
excitement it gets to users thinking
like hey I could win some maybe not too
shabby prize by just reading my emails
and complaining about stuff redeem and
complaining about this is pretty much
all of you anyway so but various people
i talk about that has been deployed it's
in your organization the texts attention
analogously rave but it's definitely
they've seen certain benefits of it and
it's a example of a security idea that
has been marketed better you know we've
already told them like reports that this
officious suspicious email and they
weren't really doing it but it took that
instead lows let's work with the human
condition a little bit let's work and
find a way to try to get people to you
know actually act actually move on this
simple idea that we want to do it and
review concept is not working yes is
there is there any reward both rom
matters is just something where there's
like
oh they feel ya okay the history of the
program is different and I've heard
about programs where they people win
amazon gift cards if your if your team
is your group it reports the most
suspicious emails and they're even maybe
ranked like like these were no obvious
dishes that these were actually like
scary stuff and you did good job
pointing out on your team could could
win prizes keep the party I don't know
whatever people that who have real jobs
like so it's something that i steam it
I'm like that that is we need more of
that or at least that kind of thinking
to say like what we're trying right now
by just telling them to do it isn't
hitting the job done on the other end of
the spectrum and there's probably more
people with with this they have a the
bulletin board somewhere in your office
in the break room a hallway there's a
bulletin board and on that bulletin
board wedged between parking regulations
or just wedge between the parking
regulations and whatever else is up
there is a piece of paper and maybe says
like security at the top with my
keyboard ID and then it says although we
don't really know it says maybe it says
report suspicious visitors or don't
click phishing email sorry lady maybe it
says who knows no no one it might as
well be camouflaged I mean we all we all
know that it's there but it's
ineffective communication this is the
kind of stuff that that left to our own
the voice devices i think we come up
with like we need to tell people about
security things all right when we won't
fit open up word and change the color to
red as Reds important it is it's up
there and nobody knows what it says yes
that's not true that nobody knows what
it does
I don't know I know what what your sign
says because when I break into your
organization when I break into your
office and I'm creeping around the place
looking the seal saw or attached up your
network I work for these could they make
me smile outlook for them any when I see
them I take a picture of that or
sometimes I'll take a selfie with them
yeah so I'm cater behind you says if you
see something say something nobody's
there I told that dangled in front of
people it was delicious still nobody
says anything we motivating people to do
any sort of action this is what you're
fighting it is so you can do this I mean
you can find a way to make your
communication more effective to use
marketing to work with them to make
security better talk to Marge mean most
known pretty good people run on keep
your guard up a little bit you shouldn't
feel the need in this battle you
shouldn't feel like you have to be
constrained to whatever comfortable
solutions we've you know past and
working before whatever duct tape half
measures that you've tried the past it's
clearly you know not working well enough
or we wouldn't have jobs feel free to
take a page from our bad guy play ball
you guys should use whatever world so
that's pretty much it short talk if you
have fun with that I don't care but I
appreciate everyone showing up I preach
thanks besides for letting me come and
talk hopefully you're not going to just
be super mad at me
okay at this point discussion if you
have questions I will pretend to try to
answer them while desperately thinking
of a way to get out of the situation if
you want to talk about penetration
testing clearly I cannot shut up about
that if you want to talk about the
person who's currently the American
president I can't because I haven't been
drinking heavily but is there any
questions you guys hated date me oh yeah
and that's what we got we have secured
in a stick potentially i mean it could
just be the stake but who wants to work
with the place where it's just this
thick hopefully there's also some
carrots we should do saying accuses
aspect of the gamification like you know
if you're consistently not playing the
game you're failing every every fishing
test if you're becoming almost a
liability company because you suddenly
don't care it's punishment in order oh
I've never liked the negative
reinforcement again I don't have to deal
with it but at a personal level I'm like
now let's not punish people it in D
motivates them I think rather than
motivate some zzz's
ok I see ok so like pushing the problem
off on foot down so like they bring
their own like vices I I'm always really
they're like either bring their phone in
and then connect your corporate laptop
their phone and bypass that needed
restrictions next thing you know that
corporate laptops popped and yeah
actually I like from that happens this
is me doing it thank you I the other Oh
Becca now you have you all right I
didn't want to have to do this what I'm
sorry I couldn't understand you yeah oh
yeah I'm definitely there's a I'm sorry
I'm not pushing certainly different
different and I think any congestion
consultants full backing up in this on
certain businesses or in certain fields
you get a test for and it's like ours
this is going to be fun healthcare you
really hope that that health care
companies would have stuff locked down
and you have my health information know
some of the Skerries contest that that
I've done are at a hospital and I was
seriously considering trying to steal a
baby because that was the level of
access that I again
other organizations I've seen you know
certain financial places they they know
what their issues are they done a good
job of segmenting things off and locking
them down so that it makes a little bit
more challenging for the tester really
large organizations frequently have some
things that they're doing quite well and
then and you're worried as a tester for
a little bit that it's going to be hard
and then you find the fact that they're
huge means they're screwing up a whole
bunch other stuff and can attack that
yeah definitely certain organizations
are certain certain feel a little bit
more lockdown in others but it's not a
hard and fast rule there's been this
surprising the crafting security pretty
much everywhere you go so kiss me yeah
the airport it's I mean it's an airport
security yeah we have we all know that a
security theater same with your
organization the people's it does I mean
to a certain degree like you're wearing
your your badge on a lanyard around your
neck through all the people in your
organization wear them on their hips
damn I clip there or is it where your
lanyard around your neck and that's okay
what if the attacks that we use a lot in
physical penetration testing when we
spend the
I mentioned tailgating or following
people in the building we've actually
moved are moving away from that because
so because it is too easy because of the
problems like this like how do you tell
how do I tell you how to stop that
that's not like tell people not to do
that or put a turnstile in your already
you know telling you want to do that in
turn styles are expensive will do an
attack that involves badge money you
have you know that keen on the editors
we have long-range Badgerys proxmark you
invite that badge so we target people
coming in heading out at the coffee shop
and steal the badge and make a clone and
walk in and when I'm asked on nine how
do we how do we stop that I can talk
about some more technological solutions
which are going to be like oh maybe move
I class readers are a different bag to
put numbered pads on the doors so that
when people need to punch an echo in the
changes Elise in the sensitive areas but
something else Falls Rahman is have your
folks where their badges on the lanyard
around their map as opposed to on your
side because mine because it's hard for
me to get a read my holding that up to
your chest and steal your badge that way
it's not perfect solution but it makes
my job a little bit harder also you have
badge discipline had your badge always
on display while you're walking around
the facility but when you leave when you
go outside put it away put it in your
bag so I don't know that someone sitting
out GM dash he's really worked there I
don't know that's kind of I talked to
Wallace we have to feed her question I'm
like I'll talk about other stuff and
make okay that's not good okay hyster
security theater of I'm not fan
professionally but in regardless will it
help us with what we're trying to do as
far as committee people that they they
need to do whatever security action that
we really want me to do to a certain
degree i think it might be okay if you
can do something like oh we've talked
about scenario we're like tailgating
happens you need to like scare anyone
for a week by having like really insane
entry and exit procedures and maybe
don't give them all the information but
lets the rumor mill vela circulate that
there's a security problem so um you
know exactly what happened but you've
raised everyone's awareness by causing
some hats on their life i don't know i
wish i may be a curie office and they
had made up of mock movie posters of
current it's like movies and then they
had swapped out like the curious it was
like the new Mission Impossible movie
but you know is I don't want their like
mission impossible not clicking links
and fish Neil but it was instead of that
boring piece of paper it looked like you
know the legit movie posters that that
they had up and complaceme also had like
hand out free book for these I side I
stole a couple cuz they're pretty cool
but
exactly but you know most often think I
think the Cure works probably had
something else in our breakroom Jane
like don't give out information over the
phone and we test their people on that
and most part yeah we don't give out
information of a song which is annoying
if you're calling in as an employee
trying to get information out of them so
yeah it does happen but I I doubt in
that case that it was just the security
person coming up with that on her own it
was more likely that she teamed up with
someone in that in the movie studio to
like hey Camille he was already working
on the idea without ever having the joy
of listening to me talk for however long
I've been time I uh well then I'll stop
I leave you all to go about your day
thank you so much for coming out and
listening to me talk on my Twitter dress
up there feel free to ignore that
because I hadn't logged in and months
but I mean via check it out if you like
um I work for security I don't want to
plug them too much but there's lots of
you know security options out there
we're also one of them so check out
thank you so much