right thank you can talk and they will
do me okay we'll start right who am i
near lines in pen tester evolving it in
a range of security areas social
engineering is my favorite we're going
to touch on a lot today apart team neta
tude to be mind seeing the other
confidence to smoke out last year quick
backgrounds I'm interested in sort of
nation-state friends and I'm interested
in what the media have to say about it
and on to like reading about it 2016 and
Russia China Iran and North Korea
regarded as the most instance or threats
to the west a quick I have a few boring
slides like that I swear to play quotes
but it starts flying cyber-espionage
basically stealing stuff that's not
yours government laid attacks nicking
other countries information this was an
interesting quote I will slow down in a
minute I will go for this most loads
very quickly I warn you now Michael
Daniel which has the form of us special
assistant said you'll never be able to
prevent them all everything to spend it
revolting eventually I think that's
accurate and I liked it and i think it
was good at some of that level and they
did that publicly right so what are our
targets and just good like doing this
any ideas for it out there to anyone
what sort of things will nation state to
be doubtful they kick thank you anything
else breathes stuff and after things of
Finance things of worth and paint
actually aren't they all watched
affinity recently and thereafter to
paint patents they like to know how
things are made and they lied to them
replicate it these are the areas they're
targeting most transport manufacturing
retail energy companies financial
companies medical companies right to get
zero day start thinking Daisy right I'm
sure you're all aware of the term Daisy
right but the idea of taking a power
station down
switching off the power and causing
complete chaos this is something that
scares the hell out a lot of people and
it's quite an interesting area bit of a
thing after the power went out what
happened and this suit from the media
and it was last Sunday and it just
caught my eye basically saying that
hackers potentially tried to bypass a
nuclear power station defenses last week
and it was called and stopped this is
another interesting thing from the media
apparently to have 7700 present active
professional hackers working for him
which I think that odd statistic I don't
know if it's true or not that the vision
of people have enough career is they're
quite limited and they don't have much
yeah they do a lot of bad things but
theoretically they've got seven thousand
seven hundred people now doing it
full-time this concept we are at war we
are being attacked all the time and
we're also attacking other people all
the time back and forwards back and
forward it something that's overlooked
because there's never been an official
you know we're in just act but we are
this is an interesting statement that i
read to date there has not been a single
cyber crime that's regarded bad enough
to be an act of war yet okay so think
nation-state cyber attacks are the fetes
what do you think ARF right outfit on
again and nation-state anyone what do
you think what person comes to your head
so I was that thank you very very good
one and i'll get back to a bit anything
else there's think more basically what
do you think the nation-state costly
expensive you know really advanced
incredible entre not to swear
sophisticated exactly why i said i'll
come back to that that ticks all those
boxes it's expensive it's sophisticated
who's my slide saying that and i have my
suspicions this isn't official that I
have my suspicions that they're not
sophisticated as you think and I think
the reality is that they could be done
by a non nation-state it can be done by
an individual right let's look at an
example of what was regarded as a no
state and the reason why what about show
is regarded as a nation state attack was
because it was connected back to North
Korea now it was never proven and you're
probably all read information on it and
let me go that far into it and you
probably watched documentaries is that
this one here in Vice did anyone watch
it it was very very good soluble on
viruses brilliant there are about 25
minutes long the straight to the point
and a front of lots of security experts
saying things like we're at war and i
find it amusing I'm quite interested in
media and those words around things
they're really excited about it they're
really selling that's the sexy sell but
the reality is well this is what
happened right so guardians of peace I
see my notes on November the 24th 2014 a
hacker group identified themselves as
guardians of the peace are broke into
hacked so late media now to get it right
what was taken personal information
about Sony employees emails between
employees embarrassing stuff very
embarrassing you released emails salary
information and unreleased Sony films
which is obviously connected to finance
there's money involved in that their
dimension massive lots over those films
being released right what do the
guardians of peace though now this is
what interests me and this is my tools
gonna start changing a little bit they
got remote access internal network they
exploited internal misconfigurations
they hunted out users of interest and
exploited domain admin at that point I
lit up I thought what they did what they
got the main event and they stole data
there's my things of interest it started
me thinking what is the difference
between what they've done is hot
regardless highly sophisticate by the
media this is like the most scary people
in the world ever that the media patrol
and what a general good pentester does
so we don't steal data but on a good
pain tears a good remote social
engineering engagement we will get
access from the outside to the internal
network we will exploit internal
misconfigurations will elevate or attack
misconfigurations common
misconfigurations and we'll book will
exploit to become the main admin so it
got me interested apprentices were doing
that how sophisticated really are
so-called bad guys that nation-states
right boilerplate snack time you all
know this but I'm just going to put it
in any way for the record generally it
takes 98 days for financial firms and
197 days for retail to detect a breach
so how long did it take to get accessing
now this is an interesting stat thats
related to death last year at Def Con
2016 eighty-eight percent of hackers who
are asked said that basically it took 12
hours so go back to that not yet 897
days we takes them on average 12 hours
to get in I'll put a little bit of a fly
comment at the bottom 12 hours i think a
long time I've enough quite generous
that actually can access from the
outside to the internal organization and
get complete compromise to domain admin
level right out there if they all wants
to have a direct Lisa saying that so now
otherwise I'll carry on right so it got
me thinking could a single person
accomplish the Sony hack what is
sophisticated and what would the cost
they well basically is the price of the
laptop theoretically I think it could be
done by anyone at home with a laptop so
how to write from remotes internal site
for getting zero days because they're
costly and they don't often come
weaponized so you have to know kind of
what know what you're doing with them
start thinking what I'm sort of thinking
is replaceable that which are macros o
LED HD OS even I'll put it on a lure
that from my slide to get picked up all
the time all year in C now been all
summer talked last year and now i'm very
interested in you and say I'm
interesting functionality I'm interested
exploiting what is there what can we do
with it what will not get picked up by
ivy what can slip past battle i'm
interested in writing the start off with
video at this point I'm like look around
i pre-warn now fellow right here we've
got is a macro now the users click
enable macro for it to work while
clicking it makes a call back to the
fracturing over here which is callo now
as you can see I've got a session from
that machine from clicking know how the
session remote internet machine at this
point I drop into she'll just so you can
see here what can you do well there we
are on the cali box
connecting back to the Machine the
windows box here so that gives you full
access as that standard user to that
machine just from the second it's enable
on the macro i'm not going to show you
how to create macros at this point i've
released it all on my blog which I'll
tell you what about again so you can see
exactly how this is all done not too
fast forward a bit these videos
the next one I'm going to show there's
no la now i relieved are starting by the
been exploited for the last couple years
and it does a link now when you
double-click it there's shortcut it
opens up power shell which runs a
command back for the Kelly box and that
point you get a shell off the box you
saw judge from the use of
double-clicking that you've got remote
access to that machine I personally
think our label to the odd and if I
receive a word document or a powerful
document or any kind of document with
another document embedded in it I
wouldn't click on it but from tests that
we do work and I've done myself and
other people do and I know it works
macros no l8r very very successful right
the next one is urine circuit responder
going just hoping the word document
we've received their the machine navels
that may know when to get domain
connected but also the username and the
password hash what happens is is when
you open you and see it makes an SMB
request back to the machine which ops ii
responds a response back to it and it
goes great have a username have my
password hash so what I'm going to show
you their freeways which the third way
doesn't give you direct access into an
internal network but the first to do now
what I find what I find is a lot of
places after you get hash value reverse
the hash I don't about emissions is now
so we'll do a talk and they still have
ssl vpns on the outside or citrix boxes
with single factor authentication so
just getting creds can give you a pivot
into the network I do it all the time so
it's carried a macro is probably
ultimately in and that without
credentials it's not that useful which
I'll get back into later right you and
see it interests me these are never very
quick demo of it so there's a cloned web
site of the famous dating website now
just from viewing the sites a refreshing
the browser right just from refreshing
the browsers and not putting any
credentials in whatsoever would get
impressed so we get a hash just
doing it now what I'll show you in this
video is I look at the source code and
if you zoom in right above them there's
a request now I'm going to zoom in on
that because you not about to see that
from there so that's if you can all see
that but literally is just as a file
share a request to a fictional image
that's not really there but mob stuff
it's legitimate functionality Microsoft
is no difference it just make the
request out and it's 445 outbound is
open on your firewall and you're using
Internet Explorer that's going to happen
it does happen a lot on tests right so
quickly talking about you and say
cracking hashes now I'm not going to
sell this it's free anyway but I'm not
here to promote this today that released
the dictionary called rock tastic
there's got a billion unique
combinations cracking hashes isn't
really a problem a lot of people will
say oh I don't use rells and I do usuals
these rules with it but I would try the
dictionary first and then old news rules
is required rules don't add football
teams that don't have town so then add
CT names that don't add the top thousand
male and female names to it they are
also incredibly slow now I heard people
say I don't really care about being slow
because I've got releasing at home well
personally I haven't got a ten grand we
got home I used purely for cracking
hashes i wish i had but my wife is not
going to let me buy one of those the
reality is that's what I've got and it's
here now lenovo laptop and a lot of us
have corporate laptops they're hideous
what would happen and this is what we
have right final point before I talk
about the internal side to it insane
products you've all got any way that
we've now got from the outside to the
inside at this point when we've got
creds with the hashes and you could do
it ugly as hell this is and anybody on
that show you a more pretty-looking
email but the reality is you can add
microcode an hour late and again see all
into the same word document so you can
really really weaponize these things now
that's a more prettily document as a
sort one that will be used on engagement
and the reason why i say i use this on
engagements is because i know this has
been used in the wild this is the sort
of thing the media has
on their blog so that this is what
happened and this is what we have looked
on what we've received so it's just ways
of enticing people to hit macro this is
a good example of la la and it's a
recruitment word document so you just
put an email open the document for more
information and just right they'll
speech there about how underneath these
are all the individual jobs and each one
would be its own ola they do work they
work very well have any questions about
that one going along this is good it's
good we'll go through quick and make you
quite short right so we've gone from the
outside and on the inside now this is
gonna be a bit painful for PowerShell
people here and I recently discovered a
love the PowerShell I'm quite slow and
i'm quite set in my ways I've been using
metasploit for a long time and I didn't
want to move over to the house I had a
process that works mean it does work and
still worked that I'm starting to change
it now more to powershell uses less of
metasploit the one that show you now is
the metasploit and process that i have
done flight last two or three years so
we've got crazy and we've got a remote
shell on some internal box now let's get
those pretend here here's the shell and
what would you do once you've got access
to a shell where the first thing you
want to start looking for is Miss
configurations for this I think they're
typically would use SMD login with the
credentials now start running this
apologize offensive a basic flavor
warfare that we go to the whole process
so you add the user name that we got to
add the password
and at the subnet I'm always interested
in pomo jewel scripts that allow you to
set the our hosts I like the idea of
similar ization the fatty you can just
spray it out against an interface subnet
I wasn't asked very very interesting
right I hate run now what we're looking
for we're looking for any user with
local administrative access local
administrative access is gold bust and
allows you to use basic set against box
it also means it got a good chance
against system when you're on pace exec
on that box and ecosystem health of this
happen well if I get creds and won it
I've coming outside to the internal side
it's common it's common that you'll find
is spray / / 24 it's commonly you'll
find one or two boxes where that user
has been given the local admin rights
why are they think even local admin
rights on that box there's lots of
reasons it's just miss configuration for
one and the fact that maybe they have
rights to install something on that box
or later they were developer and they
need it for a certain reason it's just
incredibly common on finding right so
once you access to it you can use person
correct and I'm gonna talk about like
basically executive Chris exactly is a
lot of you here will know bit on the
slide and that power didn't know how to
that's how you can figure pit except
this exact also quickly it's like Talia
gives you access to the machine now the
reason why you want access that machines
because that uses that crowed you've got
has got local admin rights on that
machine so that's why those of instant
interest to you now this video here very
quickly let me show you snowfox for an
option on here it's just me using Pierce
exec just in case anyone didn't haven't
seen it before and at this exact what I
can say is about a year and a half ago
two years ago changed it from using
dropping a shell to the box to
powershell which is fantastic because it
automated bypasses antivirus before this
is to use so called feel ya feel or
shelter to make a payload that would
slip past antivirus but now it just
automatically slips past antivirus which
is which is great overpressure
this is very interesting up notes when
it's lost its power shell when you run
it I'd say twenty percent of the time
you don't get a session back immediately
now what found is if it like some green
like a Christmas clothes off so just run
it again and what you find is down the
second attempt you will get a shell or
sitting on the access right gate system
is not an exploit is an attempt to
personate a security context or system
right to this work you get system I have
to remind myself of that because I'm
quite capable of saying it is an exploit
and course it's not but what happens
when you run get system and it doesn't
work now it's a bit when i start to get
rid of upset i like it makes it easy and
fifty percent the towing it is 50 at a
time is not now it's probably more
interesting but it's not easy so when it
doesn't work professor professor prove
esque as people keep telling me and i'm
getting a lot stronger at these are
typical ways of privacy ms 16 s 0 2 is
these regards quite successful and UAC
exploits is another one user access
control and will stop you from getting
system and it is very good i recommend
to people they turn it on is that no
anything that pops up and says are you
sure you want to do this i would
recommend having it because it's one of
the things that stops us from getting
system harm joyce power up is also
another good way now i'm going to talk
about some powershell sort of a trick in
a bit later and not at the moment right
so pretending one of those are just
worth of my free videos for everything
and how cash is now writes a quick
update we've accessed from the Intel
from the outside to the inside we've
exploited internal miss configuration
share files with local administrative
rights and we've got hashes what can we
do now okay there's time to start
sending out the domain admin the DA okay
if it just casing that doesn't know here
what is a DI basically if the keys to
the castle is a high schoolish level of
a single domain is access to fall domain
joined resources it just gives you
access to a defendant on the domain
right the first thing you want to do
when you're hunting at domain admin is
intimately logout Nessus if you tempted
to use it uninstall it must
personal opinion start to listen to
traffic no your tools I call this the
clones it's incorrect that some hash is
the actual official term now why does
Microsoft not sold passwords I'll get to
the reason why pastor hashing words is
because they don't salt password so if
you have a password hash from one box at
the local administrative hash it and
they've cloned that logs over and over
and over again that same password hash
is going to be on all the other boxes
now the reason why they don't salt has
hashes is because backward compatibility
they just can't do it would break it and
that is why still today they're not
doing it they're fully capable of doing
it they just don't for compatibility
reasons so Microsoft engineer comes
along built along she really liked it
clones that machine over and over and
over again and then on the final day
he's off sick and someone else comes
down doesn't know he cloned actually
build his own machine so what happens is
we come along with hashes and we can
access that machine that machine that
machine that machine not that one
because he was off that day that we can
access that machine with that same hash
and people will keep saying as the hash
is dead it's not a key scene on test it
just keeps coming up and up and up it to
the point where I would believe if any
nation state was going to do it they can
just use this it's going to work and why
would you not do something that works
yes it's noisy some of you might be
thinking this is nauseated not it is
noisy and I find a lot of people don't
log problem or they don't have a scene
that have no way of having alerted
messages so a lot of tackers know this
if you were trying to attack someone who
made paint let's just say it's an
example what's the likelihood that
they're going to think a nation states
going to attack them and secondly what's
the likelihood because they're not down
at Alicia I compliance they don't have
to be government any of their kind of
compliancy from that what's the likely
that they going to have logging it's
cross then also criminals are starting
to catch up worth noting 2016 has been
reports a lot of a ransomware on
somewhere and somewhere and it affect a
single box well noticed on geez pass the
hash now so they clicked one in fifty
files in one box I'll then come to all
you ever boxes if they can't using this
exact process and they'll encrypt all of
your boxes which is really scary
also pen testers use it all time right
this is fantastic tool that idea squat
long time S&T sm assembly exact what if
some big that allows used to do is stick
the username in would password hash you
don't have to reverse the password hash
and elector you check your system admins
who don't very useless it's brilliant
those albany thing for long times are
really really good what I'll do it it'll
spray out those hashes against the
entire network your subnets that you
have defined and it will log into all
those machines using the hash that we've
given it where it can log into and it
will run a command looking for domain
admins officers what is for and then it
will give you back mr. a list of all the
IP addresses where the domain admins are
and their name now if it can do that
basic set can get on to that box so
after running it i siad means everywhere
domaine happens everywhere and it's
quite scary and every test after test I
do from the outside getting to the
inside and you just think why are you
all logged in as the main admin it can
be very no ranging from two to four
years is right about 20 of their IT team
it's just like there seems to be this
broken idea that if you're an
administrator on an either a Windows
domain you have to have two main admin
rights to administer it and you don't so
when should have domain the a account
the use i was going to throw this
question to you by i think it said and
but a lot of people say like password
resets installing software this is all
all incorrect your goose delegation of
permissions have to output a delegation
of rights and always get it wrong and
then Microsoft delegation of permissions
and you can say that that admin has
rights to install this software that
admin has was to change passwords that I
mean can change passwords and install
software tell they have the main admin
rights hell no I'm not gonna trust them
with that that's the key sucursal domain
admin and I ask someone a lot smarter
than me about this and said went with
the heb use he said simple when you set
up your domain and when it absolutely
hits the fan that's when you squeeze my
nothing sorry I'll fill up and preachy
so you found two main admin how to
exploit it so you've used SMB exec
you've spotted where they all hidden you
use purse except to those boxes
and you've got remote access to those
boxes and then you've got this
incredible tool many cats northagen know
that mimic cats but just in case i watch
our video right so we're on the box is
exactly that may not have been sitting
and I'm going to use the post exploit of
limit cats in metasploit and run it and
they go voted to Main Avenue at the
bottom now this works at the 2009 server
and windows 7 and it always makes me
excited when I thirty thousand nine box
of the day I on it comes straight to
that box i'm running this now and i'll
use a SMB version and i'll double check
the machine and if it says like 2,000 on
a 2012-2016 as a lot of crap but i'm
gonna get to know in a minute so people
started have windows 10 and i'm finally
a lot of people surfaces i'm turning up
to sort of offices now is there to do an
internal or through the remote and you
check what machine ET fondue i suspect
as a surface and it has the fall flat
windows 10 on it now we don't attend and
windows 2012 onwards they change the
registry settings in microsoft that will
not allow you to instantly request in
memory what the pros would be affected
users password its and in the cast
doesn't work but what you can use and I
found that very recently by fluke some
feta cheese quedado now the key logger
pivots metasploit will instantly pick up
antivirus and then Google their names
like look out here like that it's worked
brilliantly place module run it and it
waits 142nd to believe it counts down so
it's not instant it doesn't instantly
not let me show you waits for an idle
period of one hundred and thirty seconds
and then it automatically what de tends
to lock their screen and when they lock
bag it is a log back in you see their
credentials and thank you worked so
old-school tricks are working against
new school boxes it's quite interesting
there is also to result in a little bit
called prophecy to which my friend
developed is sitting there probably
annoyed when we now for 20 him out
create proper which is the same kind of
principle is exempt songs right so come
across word choices for domain admin so
where the main avenues you what would
you expect with the original password
tools for the main
me something complex a lot of characters
passphrase really good password I CeeLo
2 passwords 2015 retested next year 2016
it's just it's like much of complexity
says uppercase lowercase and a special
character or a number i just sit all the
time really really weak passwords so the
keys mimic act anyway but the figure 2
views they simply log in you're gonna
with just a weak password and Sprite out
against the subnet the chances are you
probably get two main admin as well
because the choice of two main admin
passwords that I've scenes last 23 years
is shocking right quick recap some guy
existing outside wrongly inside we
exploited misconfigurations we're now
two main admin what to do next this is
the bit where I point on certain domain
controllers now that I postal module
spirits in metasploit to do this and
lots of scripts to do this but those
lights quickly do an ipconfig all and i
look at the dns server and i was told
this by apprentice two years ago
basically when you're particularly
active directory or if it's NEX NEX NEX
is next or DC promo then lexisnexis then
next what happens is one of the
configurations do now asks you what's
the IP adresses if you do DSO that
automatically if you just present
actually all allow you to have back as
the dns server now some also said i know
this is true the DC theoretically has to
be in doing this box but thank you your
usual agree they don't suit has to be so
this is why when you do not click
configure it's a very lightly bite your
dns box I will be DC and often you'll
see two now at this point you can rdp to
it because you've got the Khmer napping
happy no credit you can add a patriot or
totally you can pierce executive it
Pierce exacting gate is fantastic now
this is the bit that I absolutely
deserve this thing gets me of the time
when you do a hash dump our would pause
this but I'll doing and also explain it
the crunchy pause it was in this mode
but if I don't have to jump now I
thought it's like the frequent showing
is dropping you've got the jam top here
we go Thank goes on and on and on and on
now some of those smart might be able to
spot that they've actually
that's because this is a large box in my
house I'm not going to show you any
client stuff there but it's also
interesting because i had the same
password for every user and if you
looked at the hashes in a minute minutes
tops they're all the same there's again
I'll read for smoke shop doesn't sell
passwords now an interesting comment so
that is why it's still talking into
intravenous an attacker wouldn't do this
they just do it don't care but I always
ask a client at this point you have
multiple DC's I can see to hear that you
have anymore is there anyone you're a
particularly preference that I do this
one out so they'll replicates it's the
same day two on each one the reason why
i asked them that is because in my
experience of doing this twice this has
made a DC bounce just from running have
stopped so i was pre-award that it is
low risk but there is a potential risk
mostly it's always worth noting is
people right so you've got the hashes
you can craft all those with your chosen
dictionary are you fantastic what do you
then do looking at share folders is
always a good point now if you can find
an organization chart quite often put on
their websites or somewhere you can find
it generally in a share folder you can
access to everything at this point yes
the main act domain admin gives you
access to everything there's not going
to target individual people we've got
the hashes and lots of the lancaster
house and all you can crack it so you
can start taking to co you can start
targeting i know human resources is
always great one reading the earth
emails there you're going to find a few
documents that's exactly what guardians
of peace wanted to do with silent okay
so on average this is what I found to
get from nothing from sending an email
in it takes between 30 to 4 30 minutes
24 hours so that's quite I think white
relatively short amount of time that's
why I did that as a start why does it
take something mocked a bit the phytate
takes 12 hours and I'd like to take 12
hours personally right that was the old
process and if I had rewritten this I
start this talk writing about six months
ago if I know what I know today I would
have written it very differently there's
a lot quicker ways I knew this
previously polite and group sex male and
groups XML if you any standard
user can mount a share on the domain
control that's how these work normally
they can by default they can now if a
standard users to mount the domain
mounted share on the DC if you couldn't
afraid there that's the locations and
policies directory if you look the group
xml or schedule tasks xml or services
xml they're great they're encrypted ave
s that the passwords are in this
document is it contains the username and
password now quite often it is the
domain admin in those documents
alternatively it's a local admin even so
it's of high level value can attacker
and much loft encrypted the key I have
the exact date to one here now I don't
at some point they released this week
I'm not sure if you can see there that's
the key they released the cave my
friends last week to the war we've got
the key so we can now reverse them I'm
sure someone got a kick that day from
Microsoft for that once it's released
without there's nothing you can do about
it so we're all go the standard user
which remount these directories we can
download a copy of the group X and
mouthwashes word document a text
document should say and it looks they're
yellow what is highlighted is username
and the password hash and underneath I'm
using a tool built into cali which is
just one of the Ruby script going to the
metasploit framework and you literally
just run that command and it reverses
the document for you the hash in the
document to reverse it for you and you
can see there they go the press what is
let's get acting takes about two minutes
to run every time I run it I was
thinking that you can I work in a work
is going to work into what course is
going to work into something every time
they got to but he always takes a few
minutes right kv 296 2486 does rolls off
the tongue now what I've made a tattoo
of it prevents new credentials for being
placed in the group's policy preference
so you group sex and our files if you
run that update you can no longer do
that it doesn't let you but what it
doesn't do this is the catcher it
doesn't go back and delete them because
if you believe them services and stopped
working so a lot of people will run this
update thinking outs fixed end but the
reality it hasn't so any standard user
on your network now can mount that
directory they can rip those files back
they can reverse the password is
microsoft released okay and they can use
whatever level of privileges that
account
that is what I think is one of more
rapid ways to get into my nubbin once
you land on the box this is the new one
and it is one of blew my mind and clin
major revealed Kerberos ting to the
world has been implemented into a lot of
frameworks already now Club roasting
every user has the right to request
service account information from the
domain control including the password
hash that is it doesn't roll off the
tongue and that's scary as hell but any
standard user can do this it's just
functionality now it used to be complex
we're talking about its earlier Nomar
friends where it used to be like four
step process to doing is complex it'll
probably break and you get frustrated
and had but the world and give up and
think it's too complex lights been made
ibly simple now but before I explain the
reason why we made simple I've been
asked Todd this slide Kerberos provides
secure user authentication with an
industry standard that permits into
compatibility basically win2k was
implemented a wintry k and it's the
blackest cluster to do they're going to
use it and they're going to keep using
it and using it and using it and there's
nothing you can do about it now the only
real fix for those is to make sure that
your service accounts have really really
strong passwords now it's worth
mentioning a service account nine times
out of ten do not have the passwords set
through the spot every spire to run out
and secondly they were often configured
years and years and years and years ago
well before complexities have been
forced in a corporate environment and
for that reason they're often shockingly
weak passwords and so this is one of the
few exceptions where crashes and either
the rock tastic dictionary don't work
because that's all that complexity where
these is one of a rocky one them and
really restocking put my password
password all lower case and services and
the password is services if things like
acting really bad they're often also the
divine admin group so within I went on
with expand right hash cat has included
support now for crafting these and this
is what the new frameworks that come up
and I think is brilliant and is proceed
to has created on my friend Ben Turner
and David harder the Twitter there
Iran's interest in following him it's
the what was implemented into that was
this
underneath you say all you do is
literally get access to a machine get
shell on it using possède so is the
same thing the mac user macro attic
access to machines in cortecito then all
you have to do is run invoke Kerberos
output format Prescott select object
they don't and he go and wait about
second to later and it's word to get
your hashes back and go quick explosion
and how to do it and this is quite scary
she can send an email in run that and
their domain admin without doing
anything just from seeing iron with a
minute right so took a look back this is
the reason why I am getting really
really into using PowerShell and in a
year's time if you hopefully come soon
as a talk no I do it'll be basically
just about powershell but right I took a
look back over the last few months and
statistic wise here and confront I did
14 internal of the structure test seven
remotes social engineering tests and I'm
not lazy also do web apps and everything
else is thrown at me on top of that 2170
of them are got the main happening and
its really comment why do you not get
demain happening generally if it's a
cliche test and it's just not red hat
boxes and it's a Windows domain nine
times out of ten you're going to get it
if it's a remote one and you got a
social engineering engagement you're
going to get in you're going to get it
ok so this bit when it gets more
interesting alarms time I've got left so
let's thank you when it fails and you
might start considering if your nation
state you're going to think i'm going to
go i'm going to tom's travel stops going
on aeroplanes it's the third time living
my life up in on an airplane to get here
today and right why risk it for a
biscuit is my daughter said if you don't
want to try and instantly rother put
their site and get access in if you
don't need to so what are some of the
possible better ways of doing this more
savvy ways of doing it and it's just
something that I was toying with last
year and not spoke about to anyone
really so far and while doing a lot of
internal testing announced that people
use wireless ops ii guess wallets is
very very close I guess wireless now
it's often segmented correctly from the
internal wireless which is great it's
all done properly and
so what's the danger well generally
guest wireless networks i just opened or
if you have a police case of weak word
like Hello 2017 off some line at all and
in wanted anything or as a four-digit
pin order your pins you can brute force
would burp and there's no lock outs on
the cisco and has no lock down so you
just literally run through about four
seconds of bantering and if segmented
correctly where is the risk well it's
going to find corporate users on the
guests which is insane but it happens so
you can be sitting outside and it can be
looking at the water network and you'll
see corporate users actually connected
to the guest network all the time now
why do they do that well if you ever
turn up to site on your Thursday a lot
of likely people put you on it just for
ease of use it's quick related to you
sometimes she has had direct internet
access outs and people like that to the
restrictions on their marks office
forgets if it's ever connected it will
always try and connect back to it when
it sees it now people so but they don't
broadcast profile was the problem well
I'll started researching it and i was
looking at this these pub pollack group
24d bi directional antennas they've
actually said and quit and you can plug
in straight into what is alpha tardes
these are pretty scary stuff about to
show you the amount of distance this
thing can see an SSID from now instantly
it's worth and it was a bit of a laugh
off it now i looked at my wall but
that's pretty scary and that instantly
anyone who does was the term ago was
rubbish because you can't broadcast back
now you're right you can see it that
they won't have the power probably too
broad to us back to you but it's still
interesting that you could just be
sitting moles late and start doing a bit
of recon on these people start to see
what they've got and you're going to see
corporate users on it you know if it's
worth doing on up and what would be more
realistic would be one of these which I
pringle can things now you big nut it's
two miles wide really she just sit
across the road and parched you know few
minutes down the road especially London
to be realistic and an eclectic any
plugs into an alpha card so corporate
users run the guest Wi-Fi what I would
do and what I have done to prove this
actually does work is connect to the
guest wireless foret responder which is
incredible you get hash ears Rock tastic
to cracker and then I use first in
now our picked up first in it's not two
years ago and I'm that's really cool a
company who hadn't used it for years
it's just a stupid tools that we should
be using all the time we sometimes just
ignore but first a nurse is fantastic
you put the domain name in and a second
or two later I'll pop out the sslvpn an
overview I although office 365 potential
to maintain now what's interesting is
you've got Craig's so you've just
connected to their corporate and their
guest network and you now know that it's
doorways to self AP a domain name is
this and they wrote of you a domain name
is this so you just connect to it using
those creds so you just literally
sitting in a park across the road and
you've got access to internal data the
VPN things are really common for the
earlier single factor authentication on
big plans it's a scary common right when
it just doesn't work this is the thing I
do a lot of internal SD as well and if
it all fails and you've got a walkie
interrogating at court five in the
morning when we got the cram down we saw
a load of offices from the air force or
later would pass the load of corporate
offices and I could see for the door to
went past no turnstiles people walking
in hell they're just absolutely queues
of people courts and I'm walking in
instantly I just knew you can walk
strange their strength 11 straight
upstairs and the this just happens over
and over again so Reds get stopped
actually for trying to access into a
physical building there's exceptions
that even the most extreme places can be
going to turn style is hindrance but
what someone suggested to me is to save
her a new pad getting food going at
lunchtime the yo works you could just
walk in it with a bit shifty in a bit
and being a rush on your mobile phone
you can't including you in your hand and
so I can't my enough a personal best
good let me in there if that's for you
it just happens all the time anybody
doesn't focus where the front door
wouldn't allow late so just quickly run
down the back I'm gonna run back door
and said this much the same thing too
yeah yeah fine let Liam rights your
on-site find a place to hide and I just
sit in a middle of an office I don't I
used to when I first got notice we've
got shifties or don't hide in a really
small little place now to sit right amid
I start talking to people quite happily
people don't expect that person they've
been cleaning who is it the cocky person
but they don't generally think your
malicious right map drives called
broadcast
cause broadcast the seat that you're
saving a lot of Borg access to until the
network or a fedora of internal testing
on this screen here you can see
responder and here I've got windows 7
machine starting up which is an exact
replica of a kind of dimension now just
been starting up the windows machine you
can see a hash so just from being on the
same network and that machine starting
you've got a house and I'll explain the
reason why you've got another one again
with it just going to the desktop you've
got a hash now in a minute I'm going to
go to my documents we did you get a hash
and you see where I'm going with it
taking on document again you get a hatch
now this machine is broadcasting out all
the Ptolemies filthy it's going where
are you where I'm here respond to this
thing on here on here certainly your
authentication to connect me no reason
why it's doing is I'm at share if you
look there you won't see it very well
but that's share their highlight a
little bit he's always broadcasting out
now loads of people have mad shares it's
just what we do map shows of course
broadcast broadcast can be responded to
responded ends up with you going creds
right when responder doesn't work and
you're on the internal physical side
what do you do or this is when it kind
of gets a bit of a challenge it's
actually quite enjoyable though because
it's different it gives you a chance to
fig cold boot attacks really really
common people don't encrypt pcs they
encrypt laptops not pieces I've got five
minutes to go does anyone have questions
which always quickly carry aren't very
quickly go for it move some questions
rigid and right so soft Callie go to the
conflict directory your copy the sermon
the system file use pw dump you got the
hash this is great and sometimes people
put bias protections on i've done this
once i'm not gonna have done this
hundreds of times until it once on NSE
test of cracked open the box and middle
of an office and i've had my phone out
googling how to reset the bios settings
on this machine and i've done it in the
middle of an office with people walking
past me we've been colleagues and any
word no one stop me now on something now
I'm six foot six got ginger hair I stand
out it's like non-stop me right grabbing
tramp bypasses doing that grabbing
straight to the local administrative
accounts what you're grabbing from that
box there's a clue that bypasses the
requirement to responder domain user
password cracking domain use of share
rides and does feel slightly like to
that's just fun right that all fails you
can finally reinstall meses and fire it
up are there any questions come on play
someone a question maybe it's that was
most insane thing I've ever seen then
most scary cool oh sorry well I believe
the Christmas what would you recommend
an enterprise does to stop these kind of
attacks mmm well think we just always
historically say it's about training of
employees in you know training employees
to spot suspicious things I do agree I
agree that is a level of that you should
people should be told if anything
unusual report it don't forward it to
the entire company which is what I found
a lot of the time people are do put you
in say image into an email and send it
into an environment and via their smtp
price that service on the outside to the
flies come from an internal source
outlook will automatically accept it and
just open that image and send the
request now someone forwarded that
definitely the business and I went from
having up rehashes to having like 1500
and it is just going to that note delete
and the message a very simple sational
delete it now I think we need to have
appliances and email proxies and
firewalls I'm not here to talk about
vendors but there is firewalls out their
applications they are checking which
will stop any reverse connection vacuums
not from a browser now we're discussing
this earlier is wait around it you've
got to start being pretty clever to get
round these things and a lot of like the
kind of nation state ones wouldn't get
round this initially they'll find a way
around eventually I realized was
blocking it but I think you should have
it layers of hardening physical devices
that do this and have good trained
employees to actually configure them as
well as internal training is very
quickly to blame people go you clicked
on it to your fault and that's wrong
it's not it's also your fault for having
an infrastructure that allowed them to
get to the point where it got to them
with ease and secondly they're not
having good training internal to so this
isn't right if you receive any email
that you don't think he's right you
should question it you should the
ventline open it recruitment emails i
use those all the times and people open
it and those really people like to be
someone said to me people like to be
made to feel
special they like to be made to feel
wanted important if you tick those boxes
and I feel a bit of pain as I say it if
you take them boxes people will do it
and they will open it you need to tell
people that you're a word don't you
opening stuff from the prison people in
my place that's not normal again you
have devices female props an email
protection I don't want to mention the
name but it's a big couple of vendors
who have this sort of detection and also
far walk and application layer firewalls
are any more questions for I haven't and
I just do sa testing I'm not part of
their I don't do red teaming I was
discussing this earlier and we do do
retro music business we do a lot of it I
just doing what i call quick and dirty
grabs and get in within half an hour
domain admin put in a report that's what
I do I haven't had any I've had a few of
good challenges and they've got email
protection they've got props you know
the email I don't say no do you know I'm
getting yet another application their
firewalls they give me the amount of the
biggest amount growth and but there's
ways around them there is the it's not
the trivial to do that eventually has to
pick up with our own episode and start
talking to people which we really don't
like doing that and any other questions
thank you very much just before i go to
see adverse there's my twitter kind of
almost send me any questions at any
point i do reply and i have a blog as
well which is my exploit 2600 which my
YouTube blog and that has all the videos
I've shown you now and I show you how to
make them all and if I was interested in
making them thank you