hey folks chris sanders here and i'm
very disappointed that i cannot be there
with all of you in person today but the
show must go on and i'm glad we're able
to make that happen with josh and i
recording this presentation for you i
think a lot of people in the audience
will be really excited to see some of
the stuff we've got to share again if
you don't know me my name is chris
sanders i run a company called applied
network defense where we focus on
accessible information security training
for practitioners and i run a nonprofit
called the rural technology fund where
we work with teachers and communities
in rural and disadvantaged areas give
them the things they need to teach kids
about computers engineering stem and
their related career fields i've written
a few books over the course of my career
the most recent of which is called
intrusion detection honey pots which is
going to be pretty relevant for today's
presentation
hey there josh brauer here i've been in
it just under 20 years and just under 15
years in security
for the vast majority of that time i've
been involved in the international
nonprofit community
where i focused on network and endpoint
detection
deployed security onion for many years
in those environments and actually
joined security onion solutions about
two years ago
where i work on further development of
the platform as well as training
i've also
developed a couple classes with applied
network events over the years one
focused on os query for security
analysis and the other one on writing
sigma rules
you can catch me on twitter at defense
of depth we'd love to chat about it
security uh d d or even coffee
so i think most folks in the audience
have probably at least heard of a honey
pod and maybe even have a basic idea of
what one is
formally we define a honeypot as a
security resource whose value lies and
being probed attacked or compromised
and maybe a little bit more
simplistically it's basically something
fake that we hope attackers will
interact with for some sort of benefit
to the network defender there are lots
of types of honeypots but they
ultimately have four things in common
they are deceptive so they pretend to be
something that they're not they're
discoverable which means an attacker can
find them somehow they're interactive
which means the attacker can exchange
some sort of data with them or provide a
stimulus and cause some sort of effect
and because they're interactive we can
monitor that interaction through either
logging or alerting
now chances are when you think of a
honeypot you probably think of what i
would call an attack research honeypot
and these are honeypots that are used
primarily to observe attacker or malware
behavior
out on the public internet so
you generally would place these outside
your firewall or just anywhere where
they're accessible on the internet with
no real access to the internal network
and then you have some type of system
there or service that's listening for
some specific type of interaction either
just for general educational purposes or
at least primarily for threat
researchers folks are really concerned
with malware worm proliferation the
proliferation of specific attacks and
how certain things might be uh exploited
things of that nature
so again the key thing is that these are
placed outside the firewall visible to
the internet they're generally going to
generate log data because you're going
to go look at this but you're not
necessarily going to be notified of when
these interactions occur because the
internet's noisy and you're going to see
a lot of them so that's what we think of
when we think of an attack research
honey pot and i mentioned that because i
want you to kind of bracket that to the
side because that's not the type of
honey pot we're here to talk about today
we're going to talk about an intrusion
detection honey pot which is
you know certainly has all the same four
characteristics of honey pots that i
discussed a moment ago but they manifest
in very different ways an intrusion
detection honey pot is basically a form
of intrusion detection system just like
circada is signature-based intrusion
detection and we have anomaly-based
intrusion detection systems and idh is
another form of that sort of thing
it's generally in this case going to be
used by blue teamers so the folks who
are actually building detection doing
detection engineering and the analysts
who would investigate the alerts from
those things
there are a couple of main
characteristics that really
differentiate and idh from other forms
of honeypot one of those is that they
are almost always placed inside the
network so the idea is that an attacker
who has already compromised your network
will stumble across one of these
honeypots now you may ask yourself well
well if that point if the attacker is
already in there then what's the point
and i think the thing to fall back on
here is that
just because an attacker has a foothold
on your network does not mean that they
have won
they have not really won until it
becomes a breach until they've stolen
something or caused some sort of
sort of negative impact uh on your
network in some way so we still want to
try
very aggressively to detect them even
after they've got that initial foothold
and certainly that's a viable thing to
do so we're placing those inside the
network these are generally going to
generate alerts they're not going to be
very noisy because they're inside the
network and nobody should communicate
with them legitimately because they're
not legitimate assets so they're going
to generate alerts along with log data
and these can manifest in a lot of
different ways
generally either as services or tokens
and we'll talk about
those things here in just a little bit
so
a couple of other key things i just want
you to keep in mind as it pertains to
idh and what really makes idh work first
nobody should ever interact with an
intrusion detection
scanners or something like that that
might hit it but you can very simply
allow list these things and make sure
you're not generating alerts from those
things so you should get very few false
positives and if you do they're very
easy to investigate and tune out
attackers are very unlikely to discover
that something is an idh and even if
they do it doesn't really matter a whole
lot because you already know that they
are there so you can respond quickly
that's essential
and finally there are lots of
opportunities for deception with idh so
you can lure attackers into an idh in a
number of different ways you can get
insanely creative with these techniques
and that's one of the reasons i like it
it lets me really flex my creative
muscles and do some unique things that i
wouldn't be able to do with the
limitations of signature-based ideas and
even a lot of anomaly-based ids things
so with that said let's talk about some
of these use cases
and i want to start with
this scenario and lots of scenarios we
know that an attacker has to gain an
initial foothold onto a victim system
before they can really further their
attack so there's a lot of ways that
might happen
let's consider the scenario where an
attacker sends a malicious email with
either an attachment or a link to a
victim the victim then clicks that link
runs a file ultimately leads to some
sort of code execution and the attacker
has access to that victim machine and is
therefore in control of it
now there's a lot of things that could
happen at this point an attacker with
that full access can do really anything
they want but they're obviously trying
to achieve some sort of goal and what i
generally notice is that attackers will
you know kind of early on do
at least one of three
major things um in some sequence in some
order that i've seen from my time as a
defender and from doing these things
myself as a little bit of time as a red
teamer um too so you know one of those
things really the first thing i would
consider that an attacker might do and
these are in no specific order is they
might pillage for files right so the
attacker controls the system and they're
going to go digging around for files
that are relevant to the attacker's goal
so something that either has sensitive
information that's useful to them or
something that
could help them expand or compromise on
the network they're going to look for
those sort of things
so if you imagine an attacker is
browsing around the network and they
grab a bunch of these files and they're
opening them or they're downloading them
and then opening them wherever they are
one of the things we can do here is hide
a honey file right and this is a pretty
cool thing it's the idea that we create
a file that is fake it has no real value
but it looks interesting in name
and the attacker opens it let's say
maybe it's a spreadsheet what we can do
is embed what we call web bug into that
which is a reference to an image on an
external web server so when someone
opens that file it tries to go out and
get that external image from the web
server but in our case the image doesn't
actually exist the reference to it is
hidden in the document there's a lot of
neat ways to do that and when it goes
out it hits that web server well we
control that web server and it is going
to generate logs those logs are going to
tell us the ip address that came from
and we can tie a couple other
interesting things into that as well so
in this case we would know when the
document is open because we would get an
alert when those logs are generated now
that we're going to know where it was
open from which could be our victim
machine which could be the the you know
the foothold into the network or if the
attacker pulled it back to their system
we might actually get their ip address
which could be pretty neat you might
think attackers are too smart to allow
that thing to happen
i think you might be surprised on that
so this is this notion of pillaging for
files this is what we would call a honey
token where we're mimicking legitimate
data and we can do that in lots of
different ways
so the second scenario which i think is
pretty common is dumping credentials
it's fairly obvious why attackers would
want credentials they can use those to
further their compromise and
you know get into other systems so in
this case there are a number of
techniques that attacker can use to dump
credentials uh one of the more popular
is using a tool like many cats that
don't from lsas or lsa secrets or any
other number of other locations
what we can do in this case is actually
embed fake credentials alongside these
locations since we know where the
attacker is looking we can make sure the
attacker will receive these fake
credentials in this case we're talking
basically honey credentials they mimic
legitimate data they look like a
username and password but they're not
they will not actually allow the
attacker to authenticate anywhere but we
can monitor for this if it is a fake
username and nobody should ever use it
we can very easily create detection
signatures that tell us anytime someone
does try to use it if someone does try
to use it we know where they stole it
from because it only exists in specific
places so you can leverage lots of these
and lots of different places on your
networks to do some really cool things
it can be a clear text password it can
be a password hash ssh keys any other
form of authentication
token or credential is pretty valid for
this use case now let's talk about this
third thing an attacker might do and
this is the one i want to focus on
because it's specifically relevant to
the demo that josh is about to show you
in this case the attacker has
compromised the victim and they're very
interested in learning about the network
they want to learn maybe where they are
in the network what type of organization
it is if it's not specifically targeted
or maybe they just want to figure out
where they can move next look for other
vulnerable services or places where they
can leverage previously stolen
credentials so they're probably scanning
in this case it may be using a custom
tool maybe something that we could all
use a public source available it could
be a very wide scan it could be a very
targeted scan
but the thing that the attacker is not
going to know is that when they are
scanning host is that one of the hosts
we have placed out there is you guessed
it it's a honey pot it's a honey service
and it is basically out there for no
other purpose than to listen to probe
requests and if someone sends a probe to
it on whatever service we have out there
ftp ssh anything
it is going to let us know because we're
going to log that data and we will alert
an analyst that that occurred because
nobody should ever be communicating with
this system
some like potential for false positives
but very easy to sort out once you allow
this again things like your internal
vulnerability scanners things that
normally generate broadcast traffic on
specific network segments very trivial
to do
once you set one of these up so
this is kind of the scenario we're
looking at here with the honey service
where we're mimicking the interaction of
a specific software or protocol function
in this case listening on on the network
and we've got lots and lots of uh of
options for this
so these are really the three main ways
i see attackers um you know generally
they're not going to do all these things
sometimes they may may do them in
varying orders but at some point with
that initial foothold usually you're
going to see one of these three things
so we cover a lot of use cases with
intrusion detection honeypots so
hopefully now you kind of get some of
the the value proposition of idh for
detection so i think the question then
turns to deploying idx and how we do
that in a way that's that's pretty easy
and there's a lot of ground to cover
here we're going to focus on on one
specific technique here with with honey
services i will say that many honey
tokens and honey credentials can be
created from existing os functionality
and tools so you've probably heard of
law bins living off the land binaries
that attackers will use i like to think
of this as law idh living off the land
idh because we're using existing
operating system functionality and so on
i think that's pretty cool
honey services are a little bit trickier
you can certainly use legitimate
services so if you want to set up a fake
web server you can use real web server
software and just really restrict it i
find that a little bit time consuming in
most cases and you can potentially
expose some attack service you don't
want to accidentally so i really like to
use pre-built services that are
specifically for honey pots
for a lot of reasons
certainly the one i just mentioned but
also because the logging is really
designed around that specific
use case for these purpose-built tools a
lot of tools available for this the one
that's most relevant for us today is a
tool called open canary it's made by the
folks at thinxx who also make a
commercial honeypot tool which i find
to be pretty useful and pretty good but
opencanary is free it's open source
it basically it's very simple it's
python and it has a configuration file
you would edit the configuration file
say what services you want to run and um
and basically launch the python script
and it will run those and you can use
those 490h as you can see in my list on
the screen there are lots of different
options and they all provide some level
of interactivity so it's just not just
advertising that the http port is
available
it will allow an attacker actually
browse a website a fake website that you
allow it to host it will not simply say
ssh is available it will allow the
attacker to attempt to log in and you
can collect the credentials they use
and maybe if they're stolen credentials
you know where the attacker might have
been on your network so a lot of
flexibility there i really like
opencanary is a good
starting point for hunting services and
with that in mind i think um i think one
of the big lingering questions here is
well you know i want to i want to deploy
um something like open canary but it's a
lot of work maybe sometimes to integrate
that into our security monitoring stack
so
you know i guess now if only there were
some sort of platform
a platform whose goals was to simplify
the deployment and management of
security monitoring infrastructure
we're at security onion con right so
this is where we're going to show you
some some cool stuff that
particularly josh has developed and
something really called the idh node
right we have these nodes and security
onions so
josh and i are really excited to share
with you a new capability that allows
you to turn a security onion forward
node into an idh node running open
canary this allows you to deploy a honey
service in such a way that its alerts
and logs go straight into your security
engine monitoring pipeline and it really
just simple makes it all simplifies and
automates a whole lot of useful things
so with that said i know you're excited
to see it i'm going to turn things over
to josh
all right thanks chris
uh i want to take just a minute and demo
for you a new integration that i put
together that allows you to
integrate a intrusion detection honeypot
into security onion
it takes a forward node that you already
have installed in your grid and converts
it over to an idh node
so to start off we have to be running a
distributed grid in security onion
you'll see that i have
so manager which is our manager search
node
and two forward nodes
all right so that's the first
requirement because what we're going to
do is we're going to take this forward
node and convert it over
to a
to a idh node
so from there
let's go over to the github repo the
link will be available for you this is
the so-idh repo we're going to get clone
this
on to
the manager
all right so you can see that i am ssh
into the manager
so i'll get clone that repo
and then all cd into it
and we'll see there are a few files
we have this idh
setup.sh script
so uh we're going to go ahead and run
that script with sudo
and it's going to do a couple things
it's going to first check to make sure
that
we're on a manager the script has to be
run on a manager
then checks the version of security
engine running the minimum version
needed is 2.3.80
to make sure this works correctly
and then there's a message here no input
found so the actual usage is the script
name
and then the forward node host name that
you are targeting and the script uh
hopefully lists a couple or all of the
available forward nodes you can see we
have two right here
so we'll go ahead and copy and paste
this one
rerun this but this time we're going to
select
uh sensor o5 to be targeted it's going
to rerun our manager and version checks
it found the forward node and it is up
and responding
so we get a final warning here
this experimental script will convert a
forward node into an intrusion detection
honeypot node it is experimental and a
work in progress
warning exclamation point exclamation
point this script will stop all sensor
services on the following forward node
and convert it to an idh node
this is what we are targeting so do we
want to continue yes
so it's going to do a few things that's
going to disable the sensor services on
the forward node like zeke and cyricada
and steno
it's then going to copy down a salt
state and apply that and that can
certainly take some time on the node
depending on the environment and how you
know what kind of system resources that
that forward node has
that salt state will build the open
canary docker container uh configure
file beat to make sure that um it sends
over the logs over to the the manager
as well as some other pieces of
configuration
you can see that we do have idh setup
complete
doesn't look like any errors
if the script runs into errors
it will say so and it will also uh list
out where you can find the log with the
errors that it ran into
now we see that the setup completed on
our sensor
and we have a default idh configuration
we have the
ssh and vnc uh honey services
um accessible on tcp 222 and 5900 and
accessible from all networks from a from
a firewall perspective
so to be clear here the firewall
configuration was applied only to this
forward node
this firewall configuration is not
set for any other node on the grid just
the idh node that we were targeting
so this is the case we should be able to
access ssh
on this port
so let's go ahead and copy and paste
this
we'll say ssh dash p
for port 2 2 2 2
and ip address
and run that and we do get a an accepted
connection
so i'll put in my super secret password
of tour and of course it's not going to
work this is a honey service
we don't have that set up
so uh looks like i was able to
successfully connect to the ssh honey
service
if that's the case logs were generated
of this attempt and we should be able to
see those logs over in security onion so
let's pivot back over to
security onion
and check it out
if i go over to the hunt interface
we'll see that uh my currently i'm
grouping all my logs by event.module
event.dataset so if i scroll down i see
lots of z logs i'm going to go ahead and
filter those out
and then i do actually see open canary
logs
and i'll filter specifically for that
now there are different types of open
canary logs uh generated
there's kind of the the
you know the logs generated about the
service itself it just
simply says it added the service
right so kind of metadata about the
service and what's running
and then finally we have actual access
logs
um so we have logs generated from my
local system
which we which i just used to access the
honey service on port 2 2 2 2.
now if i drill down
we'll see a lot more information
our destination host port
time uh file log the file path you can
see we have the
password that is that i sent and the
username
and then this is the raw log that came
from open canary
so this is looking pretty good but um if
you recall idh is one of the key
parts to an idh is that it should be low
volume and if you know any events coming
in
from probing and accessing the services
are pretty high
uh quality events events that we want to
get alerted for so rather than having to
make you hunt through all this data on a
regular basis we also create a playbook
uh alert for it
now um i do have two created here
because i was testing this just a couple
minutes ago
but as part of the setup process we do
create and activate a playbook play
around ssh
if you're not familiar with security
onion playbook it's a tool that allows
you to write sigma rules and import them
as detection plays and then make that
play active which will use a last alert
in the back end to generate any alerts
that it finds based on your play that
you wrote all right
so we have one again built for
when ssh is accessed and the objective
is
detects when the ssh service on a so idh
node has been probed
so if this is the case we should have
gotten an alert
over in the alerts interface
for uh when ssh was accessed
let me filter out the cirricata alerts
and uh there we go right there playbook
so so dash or excuse me so idh ssh was
accessed
all right so we could drill down into
this and get more detail about the alert
but this alert was based off of that
data that we saw in hunt just a minute
ago which was generated by open canary
which was generated because i probed or
i tried to connect to the
the ssh service on our idh node
it's a pretty great stuff
but again going back to the cons the
concepts behind idh is that it has to be
customized for your environment you
don't want to just use the default
configuration that we've set up for you
so i want to show you how to edit the
default configuration of your idh node
and apply that configuration
let's go back to our terminal
and if we come over to the summary here
we saw this we didn't read it though so
open canary config is on the idh node in
this
folder right here
and then you can run this command on the
manager to apply any configuration
changes so you're going to make
configuration changes
in the configuration file here
and
apply running this command on the
manager
so first we'll ssh into
our idh node
ssh sysadmin at
login
and
we need to open up our configuration
file
a sudo a vi
it should be open
canary.conf
if you're not familiar with opencanary
configuration no worries it's a fairly
simple we have a bunch of canary
services
or honeypot services that we can enable
like git and ftp and http
we can enable them with a line like this
and then we have options so with like
port options or banner options
all right
so for right now i'm just going to
enable ftp
change this to true i'm going to leave
the port as 21 and the banner
as it is the default right now
so i'll go ahead and save that
and we're going to come over to the
manager
and we're going to run this command on
the manager
now one of the other pieces to this
command is if we
are changing configuration that requires
a new open port on the idh node we just
list the port number as a parameter and
that will take it in and add the
necessary firewall configuration
so let's go ahead and run this
oop
yep
let's try that again
it shouldn't take too long it's going to
restart the idh shocker container
and open up that port that we specified
all right so now if everything worked i
should be able to go over to my
local terminal say ftp
mypagers port 21
and check that out it's trying to
connect to the ftp server
put in my
oh yeah whatever password required for
tor tortor that's fine
sorry authentication failed so i'll quit
out of that
and again we should be able to pop open
hunt
and see the alerts for ftp
inside i may need to give it just a
second here
yeah we'll give it a second here
oh there it is right there
all right so source ip is my local host
and destination port is 21
and if we scroll down we'll see that we
have my password and username as tor
all right so that is how you customize
your idh or the open canary
configuration for idh
and that's about it for this demo
hopefully that's making sense so we
started out with a distributed grid uh
inside security onion we downloaded the
the repo and we ran the shell script
which uh converted our forward node into
an idh node we tested uh and verified
that the ssh
traffic was generating logs
uh with open canary we can see them and
hunt it generated an alert because of
playbook and then when then we went and
actually edited our open canary
configuration
and tested that as well for ftp
so uh let me know if you have any issues
or run in any problems um this link for
this repo will be available feel free to
drop in a question either on twitter at
defense of depth or under the issue
section here
thanks josh that was awesome i'm really
excited to see it there's a lot of
things to love about this integration in
this tool it's certainly extensible
whether it's through open canary itself
or through
applying python skills if you want to do
something the native tool can't do it's
also obviously open source which is
pretty neat it's automated through the
magic of security onion you get all your
alerts right there alongside everything
else and you can investigate it
alongside other relevant data so i think
that's absolutely fantastic and there's
a lot of room to extend this with the
integration with playbook which
obviously relies on sigma rule so
there's a lot to be done there
obviously there's a lot we couldn't
cover in the short timeframe surrounding
things like idh deployment best
practices and so on if you want to learn
more about that then i think the next
best place to turn is my book intrusion
detection honey pots or the associated
course you'll see a link to that here in
just a moment it probably also is worth
saying that this is a new feature this
new script so it's
not officially supported as of now
by security onion it's it's an
individual effort here mostly by josh
it is beta and it's fairly bare bones i
think there's a lot that can be done
with it a lot of ways to take this and
really improve on it or leverage other
sorts of honey pots so the key thing is
if you really like the idea download the
script uh convert one converter forward
node that uh
into an intrusion detection honeypot
test it and tell us what you think and
if you've got some cool ideas for what
to do next uh let joshua know and i
think there's a lot of
great things that can come of that
with that said that's going to wrap it
up for josh and i here in a moment again
i'll put a link or a slide on the screen
with links to download the script as
well as some additional information
including my josh's contact information
thank you all so much for coming enjoy
the rest of your conference
hear me
i got you
all right all right all right
so i think we're just doing a uh live q
a right now chris
so um by the way good to have you here
in person
um
as in person as i could be it just just
one second before we get started there's
something i need to do but i just want
to make sure i don't forget it because
i'm really bad with my to-do list and my
goals so i just want to
sounds good
that's all the trolling you got chris
that's it
it's
it you know it's a crazy year
that's true
it's true
all right
uh any questions comments or snide
remarks if you had snide remarks we'll
hand those off to chris at this point
any questions or comments
yes sir would you mind
yes push to talk thank you
yeah so the question was uh that script
turns looks like it turns the idh node
excuse me the forward node into an idh
node could you actually do both at the
same time
it specifically disables the sensor
services so you could technically turn
them back on
but one of the big things with idh is
try to running running minimal services
as much as possible as well as
just from an attack service perspective
just trying to run it as minimally as
possible
but you certainly could run both and
that from a technical perspective i
don't see why you couldn't do that
you could certainly do that
i would still recommend just from my
background is
one um
you know one
uh function per node is really what i
would recommend and i don't know chris
if you have any any comments on that
uh no i pretty much agree with what you
said i would keep those questions um
yes yeah great question so
if we're going to be minimizing the
amount of resources anyways then the
assumption is is the resources would be
pretty minimal yeah so
because we're setting up a the idh node
after
it's already been set up as a forward
node
initially you might have to bump up the
resources just to kind of get it running
but you could certainly reduce them and
just run it as a vm i mean the doc
excuse me the docker container for
open canary is really really minimal um
so you really will not need much
resources to run that
yep great question
any other questions or comments
yeah go ahead go ahead
yes
yeah so again the question is is
ultimately long-term you would want to
have multiple idh nodes because you're
going to customize it for your
environment you may have different
environments different facilities
because this is more of experimental
proof of concept
it was really for standing up you know
one shot but you could certainly
you know have multiple
idh nodes in different locations and
to reapply the configuration you may
have to do some tweaks because right now
it's just targeting kind of any idh note
out there uh honestly i'd be happy to
chat with you afterwards and maybe we
can get some ideas on how to make it
more specific
oh no i totally agree and that's that's
why i felt like after working through
chris's book last year and with my
background and running security gunning
i can definitely see the power of an idh
node internally and then deploying it
with security guiding if i'm already
deploying sensors in all my sites and
let's throw a couple more idh nodes out
there for just another another type of
detection so right there with you
yes sir
oh my god
yeah yeah so i believe the question i
heard
most of it i believe the question was is
essentially
there's more attack surface you you're
you're adding a new uh type of node to
your environment specifically to your
security ending grid what's the risk and
what are the concerns of adding this
functionality connect you know if it
gets compromised can they come back to
the security ending grid is that the
basic idea
okay
sure
sure yeah so the the
the idea is that anytime we add new
functionality there is certainly going
to be an increase in attack surface
right and so um
the difference here or the
the idea is that the open canary and the
way it's set up is that it's very low
interaction and so the risk is much
decreased
unlike like chris mentioned you could
certainly set up your own web server and
kind of try to lock it down that would
be much more difficult to make more
secure than just simply starting out
with like open canary
secondly open conair is running as a
docker container it only binds um it's
like read only bind to configuration
file on the host of the secured union
host and it has read write to the
nsm logs folder so it can output its
logs and that's it so again it's just
running a docker container and then
there's some other kind of technical
limitations in play and so
chris and i have talked about this that
there's certainly risk anytime you add
additional functionality however we feel
like the risk is is pretty small from
that perspective
you have anything to add to that chris
yeah ultimately i certainly agree with
everything that you said there um you
know this is one of the reasons i really
like purpose-built cleaning pot tools
like open canary there are certainly use
cases where you might deploy you know a
real service for a honeypot so maybe you
actually deploy a system running ssh to
serve as an ssh cleaning plot but then
you get all the attacks that comes along
with that
and that that can be a little problem to
manage and something you have to think
through uh quite a bit uh with something
like this it's really not designed to
take a lot of complex input it's going
to be incredibly simple and when you
decrease the amount of input that
something can take you ultimately you're
decreasing the attack surface to a large
degree so
that's one of the reasons why like open
canary in tools like it's one reason we
chose that for this initial integration
it just really limits that attack
service very very dramatically when
these tools are built with honeypot use
in mind
good questions yes mr mike
yeah that's a great question mike so the
the question is is um should we deploy
this on like the public internet on uh
you know on a cloud provider and it's
like publicly accessible that's not it
goes back to what chris was talking
about early on in the presentation is
this is something that you're deploying
internally
you're not putting out on the public
internet right chris anything to add to
that
um i did not hear the question but it
sounds like we're talking internal
versus external deployment where where's
the best place to deploy something like
this
yeah so certainly inside the network
it's going to you know with opengl you
can have it mimic lots of different
things uh there's a lot that goes into
them certainly more than we can give you
here just now about how you and where
you choose to choose to deploy these
things but generally you're going to
mimic something you're either going to
try to
blend in with other things so that when
an attacker you know scans the whole
subnet they're going to they're going to
hit this or when they you know try to
log into a systems via rdp they're going
to see that this is one of many rdp
systems they might try to log into it
that way so that's blending in
the other opportunity here is really
standing out so take taking something
and creating a system that really just
stands out amongst everything else so
that an attacker will see that and think
it may be of interest or value so if
there are a lot
of window systems you know putting an
ssh honeypot out there if there
are a lot of linux systems putting on
rdp honeypot out there you can based on
systems service i'm just finding some
way to make it stand out beyond
the things that it's going to share or
be adjacent to on the network so those
are really kind of the big guiding
principles
that i use when i'm trying to figure out
where to deploy these things and what to
mimic
thanks chris thanks mike
one more question one a final final
question it's got to be a good one
yes all the way up there
there we go
is
yeah so i think the question was is um
from a network performance perspective
um is there any concerns if someone's
like trying to do brute forcing against
a service or something like that um so
to be clear
this forward node this converted forward
node is just simply sending the
logs from open canary so it's not
sending any pcap or anything like that
to the manager so it's just sending logs
so you're not going to get anything from
that perspective and if someone's brute
forcing this service
then they're certainly going to be
trying to brute force other services in
your environment better to brute force
this one so that you get alerts and you
know about it right that's kind of the
thought process there i think that was
hopefully that answers your question
yeah i would agree with that i mean the
the whole thing is someone trying to
force it we're going to know that
they're there right you're going to know
someone's doing that and then you can
investigate it so that's
that's that's one of the great things
about these approaches is if an attacker
wants to do something bad to this
honeypot beyond what it's supposed to do
or even within the scope of what it's
supposed to do they have to interact
with it and once they do that very first
interaction
which usually when you're probing it not
necessarily trying to do anything else
we're going to know that they're there
and we can investigate it and
i'm not going to say it's game over but
it's certainly the first step on the way
to game over for the bad guy
all right i think that's it thank you
all very much thanks chris um bill
anything to
okay
thank you