all right thank you I really think Sam I
mean he like the question this is
exactly the perfect setup for this this
is ongoing work I mean not ongoing I
mean it's gonna be presented at CCS it's
on ePrint it's exactly to tackle some of
the problems or the issues that were
brought up and all the points that he
pointed out clearly has a lot of
experience actually digging deeper into
these protocols and implementing them I
claim that hopefully what you get out of
this talk that you would be forced to do
these things if you use an interactive
sea improver or computer-aided
verification for your protocols all
right so what this talk is not about
there are no new protocols no hardness
assumptions or I'm not also talking
about you see yet we're doing game based
verification sort of modeling also and
we're also not what I'm not talking
about having the computer find the
protocol or proof for you this is
basically if you have a specific
protocol and a proof for it and you want
to get high confidence in it and also
what I wanna hopefully you get out of
this talk is that if you've been through
the trouble of actually verifying it in
a formal model I'm like a fear improver
you have to do a little bit of work and
you will get an executable out of it
that is correctly constructed okay just
a the Katori slide on MPC protocol that
allows a bunch of mistrusting parties
typically software to compute a function
under private input historically semi
honest passive honest but curious the
model that cares more about privacy and
the act of one or the malicious one is
where you basically can have cheating
and arbitrary deviation from the
protocol I'm not gonna go through this I
mean this crowd doesn't need it but the
reason why I just want if anybody
doesn't know secret sharing is you
have the share and reconstruct protocol
is because I want to show you actually
formalizing it easy crypt and show you
what I want you to walk away to
basically the message is that this is
possible like MPC I consider it as a
advanced cryptographic protocol and
primitive and it's not that
straightforward to implement especially
once you get to the malicious and active
and also adaptive adversaries one more
thing I'm going to talk about is okay
over long period of time if you have
things our secret chair then mobile
adversary can basically collect all
shares this has been handled in the
literature before in the proactive
setting where you basically are going to
move sort of your you're moving the
polynomials that you're sharing with
over time so that somebody that is
comparing to compromise and get all the
shares over times you're resetting
parties and starting them from scratch
they need to recover their shares from
the existing polynomial so you cannot
stitch things together I mean this is
very basic I just wanna you to be aware
of this because I will show you
formalism that actually implements this
stuff all right
okay so the reason what I'm saying NPC
starts to become much more complex is
once you start to worry about dynamic
groups and things like proactive
security very quickly you'll find that
your MPC protocol has seven eight or
nine sub protocols and that's why you
see and composability is very important
but that's at the protocol design what
about the software this is non-trivial
so just when you refresh shares the
standard trick is if you basically had
multiple shares on a polynomial
everybody gets the evaluation of the
polynomial so a simple way to refresh it
is ver sorry to refresh is generate a
polynomial that evaluates to zeros
that's the green one ad where the
secrets are share it again everybody
deletes their own CH they're all chairs
so basically what you get is a new
sharing of the same secret when you
recover share is basically when a party
leaves the protocol and comes up again
you need to give it doesn't have any
state you need to give it existing
shares so this is very basic MPC has
been known since 88 bgw is one of the
most fundamental protocol this is an
interesting fact there wants no fully
specified proof till 2011 and once you
get and I highly I mean this is very
appreciated that the work that our share
of and lindo go through to specify
everything in detail and have a
foolproof that's a long time okay and
when you look at that paper that's like
an
eighty-seven page paper eighty-four
pages of it is about passive and static
static active when you start to get into
adaptive malicious adversaries and also
composability there's a lot of other
papers that you need to refer to and
theorems this is highly non-trivial so
actually even implementing something for
adaptive active adversity is I don't
know if anybody did it but it's whatever
happened is none trip so basically why
worry about verifying NPC because one it
provides an existent proof that you can
tackle in computer data verification
complex protocols and then people now
are talking about zero knowledge who
morphic encryption I think we're ready
to actually verify these in interactive
to your improvers they're becoming
increasingly relied event in blockchain
settings and not only that honestly if
you were at the talk yesterday the
blockchain Dalya Malky mentioned this
protocol this is a consensus protocol
ziva that was written in 2007 and ten
years later they found that the liveness
and safety conditions were violated in
very simple scenarios ten years to do
that and this is something that doesn't
even worry about confidentiality and
privacy of inputs MPC is way more
complicated so I'm not saying that the
implicit protocols have issues in them
I'm saying this is like higher
confidence level of confidence that's
just not there yet and if we if we go
there to build infrastructure that
should last for decades I think this is
the best way to go to get that level of
confidence
all right there's already been some
workshops and people talking there's
some funding programs about so there is
interest in the community of sort of
merging cryptography and the PL
community and get formal verification
it's just that so far they talk I've
been to that workshop it was very useful
different languages and it's it's
unclear how soon we can sort of sort of
merge both and hopefully this work
provides evidence that it's gonna happen
soon and people can build on it all
right so my opinion is that and just
gonna mention here and this is the end
of the fluffy stuff it's all gonna be
more technical from now is that when you
talk about formal verification
don't only talk about the specification
of the protocol might as well get
executable software that is correctly
constructed because what you but I
learned in the last year going through
that exercise is that you're almost 80%
of the way through when you use one of
these theorem provers to actually
formalize any protocol all right so easy
Krypton are not sure if you haven't
heard about it it's an interactive
theorem prover that basically allows you
it has a probabilistic language that
allows you to describe a lot of the
primitives and the constructions we use
in papers so that you can sample from
random distribution can be hooked to
interact with your improver and SMT this
is satisfiable modulo Theory solvers to
automate the proofs this is following
the construction of it architecture is
following some work from bellari
that basically is proposing to verify
crypto protocol as gos code based sort
of objects typically you would describe
a construction or a protocol as a module
some some global variables and
procedures and definitions and then
there's multiple levels at which you
would verify something like this so for
instance like take L gamma a text book
ill gamma I mean if you write an easy
crip as you would write it in your paper
you have three function three procedures
or algorithms key generation encrypt and
decrypt and they have already operators
to sample randomly from let's say a
group of a specific order so this is not
far away from how you would write in
tech your your protocol so what I'm
advocating is if you write this first
and then extract from attack which is
actually possible I think that's the
right way to do it so what we did in
this paper which we presented at CCS is
we did the following we defined abstract
definition for a lot of the primitives
that you would have an NPC not ot I mean
I think that should be done but what we
did is we did secret sharing a lot of
variations of secret chain your standard
Shamir one by some polynomial additive
gradual we did MPC an abstract
definition and then we proved some
compositions theorem at that abstract
level then basically what you do is for
each abstract primitive you need to have
a instantiation of it which is like
Engineers case basically you select a
polynomial of a specific degree over a
field and then you prove equivalence of
the abstract definition and the actual
instantiation of the primitive and then
basically you would prove security
that's equivalent you can extract from
the specification you have a security
game also and then you basically prove
you have to specify the proof in Easy
Clip and I'll show you examples of this
it's not gonna stay that high level it's
just I want you to walk away with the
overall sort of mental map of what
happens so we have game based security
definition for each of the primitives we
code the actual proofs and verify them
an easy crypt but that's only half the
story or like two-thirds of the story
the interesting thing that we observed
is the language of easy crypt is very
close to a language called yml which you
can automatically extract from it Oh
camel which is executable in a verified
way exactly the question that was raised
before before I walked on the stage I
think this is possible and I think this
is how things should be done because
expecting software developers to learn
cryptography the cryptographers also are
not going to write the code so it's much
easier if the protocol designer uses a
tool like this and then you get the
whole thing automated and again in a
verifiable way all right so this is not
happening in vacuum I mean in the last
several years have been a lot of
interesting efforts sort of slowly
making progress towards this but till
this paper nobody has verified a generic
MPC protocol for n parties for the act
of setting active adversaries and had
the whole proof in easy crypt and also
nobody had extracted software from that
proof specification or that formalism
that is actually executable and that's
what we have in in our paper previous
work has looked at like the SV 17
private count retrieval that's a
protocol for three parties that is
basically counting the number of records
that match a certain query in a database
and they only did it for the passive
model
in ccs 17 they did it for Yahoo
two-party computation horrible circuits
but also only for passive and they did
extract executable software and then
finally in 18h K+ they did it for a
protocol by only Maurer that's very
simple the beauty of that protocol is
it's not only for threshold adversary
structures for general adversary
structures but there's a catch here that
the protocol they didn't have the whole
proof actually formalized in easy crypt
if you read the paper carefully you find
that they did at some point prove that
the protocol satisfies some properties
and then they have a manual step where
they say oh if these properties are
satisfied there in protocol then you
have a simulator but it was never really
coded an easy crypt I think it's doable
they just didn't and they also didn't
bother extracting executable software
from the formalism and easy crypt so
okay so I've been talking now about
these abstract definitions so this would
be for instance an example of an
abstract definition of secret share okay
the same way you would define it in a
paper right when you start writing about
let's say I'm going to use secret
sharing you define have a definition
that says secret sharing which is
essentially what matters is what's in
the red box there are two algorithms
share and reconstruct takes an input
some randomness a secret and output some
shares and the reconstruct takes the
shares and outputs some I mean all this
code is in the paper and we have it on
also on github so I mean the link I'm
happy to turn it or see people taking
pictures it's all open source so
basically this is you're not really
specifying how you're going to share or
reconstruct so you do this once the the
good thing about this working at the
abstract level is you do it once and
then later on every time you instantiate
it using a different I know mathematical
structure I know you can do additive
sharing or using polynomials it doesn't
matter it still will satisfy these two
conditions sorry I mean these two
definitions then you can also do it I
mean we did it all this code is
therefore verifiable secret sharing now
similar the way you would implement in
C++ or any other object oriented
language where you inherit a class and
then overload
for instance some of the members we're
doing here the same thing now the the
share and reconstruct operations are a
little bit more involved because it's
verifiable but you can do the same thing
for this is now not this is not the
abstract definition anymore now that we
have the abstract definition this is the
concrete implementation of secret
sharing that's following Shamir
basically what this map says is
basically saying you take some
randomness and a secret of type secret T
which you define up there and then you
evaluate a polynomial using that secret
as the free term and the randomness I
mean if you were here on the talk before
I think it was who was it was talking
about the IETF standardization process
BLS signatures at some point he said you
might make the the sampling of the the
the keys I think make it deterministic
and pass it a random randomness and
don't verify
I mean don't don't sort of explicitly
say how that randomness it should be
chosen this issue actually encountered
that when we're trying to formalize this
we realize that it's easier to pass the
randomness as sort of like the
polynomial typically when you write a
secret sharing sort of like on paper so
you you say okay I'm going to select
random coefficients and then put the
secret and the free term and that
determines the polynomial here what I'm
saying is the randomness you're gonna
pass me is going to be a random
polynomial with a zero free term and I'm
done adding to it the actual secret so
that it's in the free term and then
share it what I found is when you try to
formalize things there are multiple ways
to do to do the formalism and each one
can make your life later on easier or
harder there's no right answer it's
really up to your experience and your
taste so we have the same thing for
instance this would be additive secret
sharing a concrete implementation of it
that satisfies that abstract definition
and then we have the same thing
commitment scheme Peterson and Feldman
and then what we have in the paper is at
the abstract level where we're proving
that if you combine a primitive that
satisfies the honest but curious
definition for basically that the shares
are in
and of the secret and then with a
commitment scheme then you get the
revival secret chair again this is
proven at the abstract level and this
framework basically anytime you
instantiate any of these primitive using
a concrete mathematical structure their
protocol will inherit the composition
proofs that you did at the abstract
level so that's actually very useful
because these compositions you prove
once that mean this is not you see
composition this is composition in
series so we did the same thing for MPC
just this is an abstract definition of
what could be an MPC protocol I mean
again this is very high-level it's like
you have inputs you have players you
have IDs of players you have phases you
have an output phase doesn't say
anything and we think of this as sort of
the ideal function out but then you have
to instantiate this actually using
concrete protocols and and we have also
because we're initially when we started
were very ambitious we wanted to
actually do a proactive protocol for
dynamic groups and dishonest majority
that didn't happen we settle for just
honest majority and proactive but no
dynamic groups yet so we have some some
composition theorems on in the proactive
settings that are formalized at the
abstract level all right this for
instance would be the recover protocol
that I tried briefly to describe earlier
in using just curves for MPC when you
have proactive MPC when you have
basically a party that has been reset
and it's trying to join the MPC again
and it needs to get a the shares how do
you give it the shares what I showed you
before that every party would generate a
random polynomial with 0 at that index
of that chair this this basically is the
protocol how you'd implemented in
easy-grip all right so so far I'm
talking only about abstract definitions
and concrete instantiations then there's
the proof how does a proof in easy crypt
look like well I mean the proof script
will basically be a bunch of definitions
at the beginning you're importing the
modules the abstract definitions you
want to satisfy in the concrete
instantiation x' and then you're
defining the type of the adversary we're
defining here an Oracle because in the
security game you have to allow the
adversary to query the share
functionality with
the secrets that it wants and the game
that you're the security game that you
have is basically similar to how you
would define security of an encryption
scheme is come up with two messages and
then encrypt them and you should
distinguish we're doing the same thing
here for the semi honest model what
secret sharing it just doesn't fit here
so this is how it looked like basically
you generate two secrets or it could be
two lists of Secrets
you have the adversary choose one flip a
bit you send them the shares of one of
them the adversity can then query an
Oracle on sharing on any any secret they
want to get the shares for and at the
end they should have guessed a bit and
you basically in easy crap because you
can compare two probabilistic
distributions you compare if the two
bits are similarly distributed or not I
mean depending on if you want to have a
statistical lis secure or perfect
security or computational you can do all
this in easy crypt so we've done all of
this for this is the list of primitives
and proofs we had so there's like 30
files was was a lot of definitions in
the semi honest and the malicious use
cases alright so as I said this is only
half the story that you basically wrote
the abstract definitions and the
concrete installations an easy crypt and
you wrote the proofs and verified them
the interesting thing is that we found
that the easy craft language is very
similar to yml and I think this is not
an accident I think why am L is a a
framework used for the deductive
verification and I think the easy crap
people when they developed it they were
inspired by or affected by that language
so it turns out that you can actually
easily translate from easy crypt to IML
and then if I know if you've heard about
Oh camel or not before it's a language
that's been around for a while it's very
heavily used in the verification and PL
community and it's really designed for
safety so what we basically did is we
wrote a small tool that translates from
an easy crypt specification of a
protocol to a yml specification of that
protocol and then once you're in yml you
have the all the
power of the y3 framework there's a lot
of tools that can verify yml code and
that can also extract code from yml to
other languages so there's already work
that extracts Oh camel that the tool is
verified like a verify tool that would
translate yml to oh camel and Oh camel
is already executable there's also some
tools online that claim to translate
from yml to see I haven't tried I mean
we tried them but they didn't work
they're also not claimed to be verified
PVS is the proof verification system
which is the interactive the improver of
SRO it's been around for 20 years the
language in PPS is very close to I ml so
you can easily translate from why ml we
haven't done it yet to PVS and my
colleagues have a PVS to see translator
so so i think it's it's very plausible
that in the next year or so somebody can
write a tool that translates from yml to
C and or like we will maybe do it from
PVS and then you can get a C
implementation so now the interesting
thing when we did this oh this is just
showing you how closely similar I mean
like the languages also and the right
here would be the easy crypt I mean part
of these a crypt code for additive
gradual sharing sorry gradual sharing is
basically you take a secret you share it
additively and then take each of the
summons the additive share and share it
using schmear sharing the reason why we
use that is because it's used in some
protocols for mixed adversaries that
basically if you were the talk yesterday
from Dalia you can have these trade offs
between how many passive party how many
parties are corrupt passively and
actively and it's sort of a dial so you
look at the protocols that do this they
use the notion of gradual sharing with a
different polynomial degree of
polynomials for the different shares the
additive shares so on the left this is
the easy crypt code for a gradual
sharing scheme and on the middle that's
the YAML code and on the right the Oh
camel code they're very similar if a
human if you can see sort of a bunch of
variables and then let for instance here
you're defining and yml a function when
you say let very similar to easy crypt
in oh camel it's a little bit different
so I mean basically when I want to show
you that
not for and that's why we have verified
tools to translate from each to the
other so then the question is that code
that you extract which is executable how
bad is the performance so I think it's a
little bit unfair to expect that you
would compare this against sort of an
optimized tool so what we do is we take
charm which is a Python based framework
and we it has its own secret chair in
class so we compare against what's there
for different field sizes different
number of parties and it's not that bad
I mean listen it's this is something
that you get within a minute once you
write things easy crypt people spend
months and years optimizing
implementations so I think it's it's
it's premature to say we expect the same
level of performance but there's nothing
that precludes us from also implementing
a lot of the optimizations that people
do in easy crypt and getting similar
performance so in some of the cases
actually one thing I'm gonna point out
is when you look at charm sharing and
reconstructing and then our extracted
code so it be constructing in charm for
15 parties sorry there's about the
second row and extracted that should be
15 15 party it takes two millisecond to
reconstruct it took us six millisecond
and to share 23 and 1/2 the reason why
we were faster in sharing and not to be
constructing is because we actually
needed to implement an easy crypt a
library for evaluating polynomials and
doing the interpolation and that's what
we're actually synthesizing in Oh camel
and that's what we're using for
interpolate if you take that part out
and let's say replace it by NTL a
sea-based implementation for has a lot
of algorithms that you would need it
would be much faster the point is that
ntl is not verified whereas the Oh camel
code here is is formally verified
because the tool is formally verified
that extracted so so there's area
there's a lot of research to be done
here on optimizing I think there is hope
I mean in the next five years even if
you have I think 20 percent 30 percent
overhead it might be worth it for the
increased confidence you have in the
correctness of the software
anyway what's missing what we haven't
done and yeah we're working on some of
this but please if you're interested in
this area be glad to see people work in
it is adaptive active adversaries you
see verifying the underlying broadcast
protocol for instance nobody has done
this before the underlying
implementations of field groups and all
these things nobody has done a verified
implementation of this as far as I know
recently there's been some project like
project Everest or ever crypt using this
as the underlying parameters for an
extracted NPC code would be would be an
interesting Avenue nobody has done this
before comparing against sort of more
optimized protocols and implementations
I think if you start to look now at
optimizing what we have implemented an
easy crypt you might that would be a
fair comparison but but so far it was
really all the basic stuff just wasn't
there
so it took us a lot of time to implement
the very basic libraries and building
blocks and then translating to see Oh
camels performance is not bad I
personally think I mean you're not gonna
get much more out of C but the memory
footprint of a camel is bad because oh
camel doesn't release memory so it's not
gonna scale at some point so there is
need to also work in C um I think anyway
and obviously the future work is
basically addressing these things and
there are other interactive theorem
provers other than easy crypt easy crypt
is really focused for cryptography so
like things like Isabel and PVS if
you now want to start also reasoning
about like this MPC software it's gonna
be sitting either in a virtual machine
or like container or something like that
I mean if you people are starting to
talk about not starting it's been around
for a while
verified microkernel if you've ever
heard of SEL for I mean ultimately what
you want to verify everything end-to-end
then so SEL for instance is verified in
Isabel if you want to verify the
composition of both of those two things
you need to do the work we've done like
an easy crypt in Isabel and it's in
principle doable it's it's just X was
gonna take a lot of effort which is good
I mean there's a lot of research
to be done anyway whenever I talk to
people about this kind of work and this
sort of approach these are the questions
I or objections I often get and I just
want to put it out there because
honestly I don't think these are valid
objections it's like oh what if your
security definition or abstract
definition of implementation is wrong I
mean you have the same issue as papers
there's nothing different yeah I just
took it and implemented it just a little
bit more rigorous formalism what if the
computer checked proof has a problem
it's exactly the same as you have it in
a paper you can always if you find the
bug if it's nothing fundamental you can
fix it and within a couple of minutes of
worst case hours you verify the whole
pipeline what if there's a bug in the
verification or synthesis tool chain
easy crypt an easy crypt is a big
computer trust a computer based at your
trusted code base that you're trusting
fair enough but easy crypt has been
around for 10 years a lot of people are
using it eventually I think bugs will be
discovered and if you really want to go
there you can the same way you in a
programming language when you design a
programming language or the first ones
you bootstrap a compiler you can do the
same thing like I can imagine a verified
interactive theorem provers like easy
crypt that is you start with a very
small kernel that you have enough
confidence in it manually and you
bootstrap things and that's how people
did things was compilers and what if the
use tool I've had that discussion
actually I just added this today because
I hadn't a discussion in the morning
what if I spend if I'm a student I spent
six months nine months learning easy
crypt and that goes away after two years
I mean first of all I am not involved at
all in easy crypt I am NOT I have zero
interest in easier but I think they did
a great job and it has matured a lot
over the last 10 years I think anybody
if you told anybody ten years ago I'm
going to verify something like bgw for
active adversaries with a computer they
probably would have dismissed it we've
done it ok there's no reason not to take
this approach moving forward because as
things get more complicated and more
automated we need we need that level of
rigor it takes time yes but it's
and also if in my experience same thing
was programming languages the first one
you learn will take you longer but then
once you've learned it the second and
the third one will be much much quicker
if you learn one of these theorem
provers and sort of use it as an extra
verification step in your work if for
some reason you need to switch to
another one it's not gonna be that much
time to learn and pick up the other one
and if you're a student that's starting
and expecting to have a 30 40 year
career in design in cross the
cryptographer I think it's worth it
because you might not use it on every
paper but every once in a while you need
that anyway I'll leave you hopefully
with these conclusions that one
computer-aided verification and
automated verified synthesis of software
for cryptographic protocols complex ones
is achievable today and I think they go
hand-in-hand
I mean verification by itself is
important but if you've done 85% of the
work why don't you just do that X report
and it's reasonably low performance now
- given that it's automatically
synthesized code and that is you have a
much higher degree of confidence in its
correctness and there's a lot more
research to be done and yeah was that
I'm happy to take any questions I hope I
hope that this is something I expose you
to something new today
a couple quick things I might have
misunderstood but I think maybe on slide
1450 it's something about um there's no
formally verified fuel implementations I
didn't say I said we didn't use whoa I
see I see
because certainly there's a bunch in our
work no no okay I know there is just no
I was just trying to focus yeah the
actual question I have is this in a lot
of these it seems like I've been
following this work and related work
because it's extremely interesting um it
seems like there's on the one hand
getting correct by construction software
is excellent on the other hand one of
the reasons when we implement something
in C for example one of the reasons that
we do that is not just because we want
it to be fast but because in some sense
like maybe the compiler gets out of the
way a little more than the old camel
compiler does which I mean kind of
sounds like a joke because of course you
always fight the C compiler when you try
to write code in it but specifically
look if I'm trying to write constant
time code I have basically no prayer as
far as I can tell of doing that in oh
camel I could probably get that done or
at least you know if I know what
compiler I'm targeting I could probably
get that done at C so it seems like
maybe there's a little gap right between
on the one hand correct software but
it's a little camel and on the other
hand what I maybe want is really like
software in C that's constant time and
maybe I can examine the you know in the
IR or the assembly afterwards how do you
see how will we close that gap fair
enough are you worried because of
leakage resilience and in constant time
for example yes I think if you want to
do that I don't think easy crypt in its
current format has to do that I think
you would need to move to something like
or Isabel and I'm not very familiar
with that that area of research some of
my colleagues actually have been working
on sort of these constant time
implementations I don't have an aunt I
haven't looked at it I don't think there
is we require a lot of work it would
require probably like I can't imagine it
as I said if you move to PVS which is
very close to yml you can
extract sea from it and PVS is based on
hire or law it's very generic you can
start reasoning about these constant
time it's just nobody has done it yet
okay thank you I'll tell you what we did
honestly we did oke ammo because at some
point it was just two of us it's a lot
of work and this is this is excellent
it's it's great it's just like of course
as you said there's there's tons more
work to do and I'm worried about one
thing I'm sure everyone else is right
about you know ten other things but yeah
so this is a good answer I really
appreciate it thank you thank you it's
more common on the question dust now so
I mean you mentioned ever Crypt I mean
one of their motivations is to get
software down all the way down
has it even have one very fine the
Assembly level so there is other works
in high assurance cryptographic
engineering so it just has to interface
somehow question to you you might need a
whole bunch of shinier things and I see
like sharing and we sharing and well
reconstruction but it's your protocol
taking into account that you don't
actually have to reconstruct it I mean
do you have for instance the
diffie-hellman where you never recon we
construct the share but you just apply
it using the shares I'm sorry so I mean
like when you when you do secret sharing
and you want to run different allman
okay you don't have to recover the
secret we can just apply the dish
yeah we're recovering is I mean you it's
up to you when you want to recover
I mean we're composing these I mean you
can just share and just open are you
asking I mean but I mean do you have the
functionality do diffie-hellman without
ever reconstructing we don't we haven't
implemented anything in the fam I think
other people implemented the fear
because I mean that's that's what would
really interest me because I mean once
you have recovered the share it's gone I
mean if if you're malicious member gets
the the combined share or you assume
that the combination takes place
somewhere else
I mean India model are you assume we're
we're doing NPCs overtake everyone would
be would share their inputs and your
computing a circuit as additions or
multiplications you can leave the the
result chip secret shared without
reconstructing so you can leave it
without reconstruct I mean so when you
say we construct you reconstructing the
result of the computation yeah you're
not saying you've reconstructing the
Shamy see no no no sorry yes we can
suppose might result of the computation
[Applause]