thank you everyone for joining we have
the opportunity and I'm very honored to
be sitting in this table right now with
these amazing cryptographers and people
[Music]
so I'm not gonna introduce them because
I'm going to ask them to introduce
themselves but you probably know most of
them if not all of them so thank you the
fur to the five of you to be here we had
this idea of having all this day going
going to talks and learning about what
the different standard efforts are doing
and so on and we thought you know what
what is the best way to conclude the day
well we can't get everybody here to
start working on standards because there
is too little time and too many topics
so we thought you know let's have a
conversation and see what is the what
are the kind of hardest part of creating
a standard and so on so we offered you
know just ask to have a couple of
minutes each to introduce yourself and
tell us a bit what's your encounter with
the standardization and if you have any
anecdote that you find is worth maybe
bringing up one stack ok google'
krafchick I'd consider one with a lot of
experience in standards I've been
involved with with the IDF since mid
nineties you guys were there and I
wasn't in his talk so I don't know what
version of I think that's he talk but in
the 90s it was very hard to work in the
IDF for someone that was talking about
rules
and definitions stuff like that so it
was not an easy time but I'm a stubborn
person and somehow then the h mark came
at a time in which md5 it was started
breaking md5 and what's the name TT TT a
German researcher that people hear too
young but he he had the first words on
basically breaking or showing some
weaknesses of md5 and so the time that
we were trying to promote H mark he he
came with his work and I so I sent him
emails saying do you think that you can
break H much with md5 under your attacks
the answer was no I have no idea I'm
fickle can do that so I asked him can I
send this to the IPSec said yes and I
think that was the most important part
in getting these accepted but the reason
I'm telling this is because actually the
fact that there was a proof in H mark
became an important point in in this
history of trying really to move crypto
in practice clip the practice into more
theoretical of well-founded science one
did say that you were pushing for the
security part of the of the standard
like that yeah he said that he mentioned
my friend bill Simpson he has he had the
famous sentence saying that he doesn't
talk to self or self-proclaimed
cryptographers anyway that's about an
agreement
so hi I'm Dolly monkey and currently
from Makkah Libra and definitely not
that photographer so I think that means
I'm a person was actually why I am on
this boundary between so I have interest
in secure systems I'm kind of a boundary
whenever there's a Byzantine failure I'm
interested in it and that means I'm
touching on crypto cryptography
cryptocurrencies and I guess I have a
series of life anecdotes that keeps
dragging me into flight crypto at least
or security side of things so it starts
with my postdoc I joined the AT&T Labs
and mic writer at the time who came from
Cornell really wanted me to join that he
was working in a security group so I
joined the security group I was the only
non applied cryptography they're the
only person the only person the only
person then I assume the faculty
position at the Hebrew University after
and again distributed systems person but
there was nobody to teach the intro to
cryptography and the advanced of course
in cryptography at the time because
every witness of left for sabbatical and
Michael was doing quantum computing
every time and Michael Robin was
spending all this time at Harvard so
they asked me to teach the courses I had
to teach the security courses and then
while I was there is complexity theorist
and later
game theory nothing today with
photography and me nothing to do with
cryptography either our daughters took
swimming lessons together so we would
sit by the pool no no I mean I'm
watching them swimming and chatting
about computer science and at some point
they we the girls started pulling each
other underwater and you know I'm jumped
and save them and all that and somehow
out of that came Fairplay you know the
system that says isn't it time to to
actually see if we can practically
implement secure multi-party computation
and just how expensive that is
so so that's how I get into that area
and I can continue but this is you know
this is very personal my story I kept
being dragged
I'm around Romer I'm a professor of
computer science at Tel Aviv University
and the research scientist at Columbia
University let me share my origin story
how I got my powers was the spider so I
used to be person so I was working I was
already on this slippery slope to become
a cryptographer working on side-channel
attacks and cache attacks in the search
I got wondering it was this theory about
your knowledge proof impossibility
results for complexity that's what's
that good for
well maybe it's good for proving the
integrity of computation as it was
envisioned before it became theoretical
complexity theory tool and maybe the
kind of verifying integrity of
computation that your knowledge groups
can do can be a way to mitigate the
attacks that we were studying
if you cannot trust the computing
platform because of various physical
attacks maybe you can just make it prove
to you that it operated correctly and
maybe you can actually implement this by
building on if they were any company's
nodes so that's kind of cool so I was at
MIT any time we took it to the NSF we
submitted the proposal and the response
came back that nope no way this will
ever work but you know what in this
every date work it would be kind of
useful so here are a few dollars don't
spend them all in one place they have a
sugar program for exploratory research
keeps you just above the water actually
started picking pace he teamed up with
to actually use the cutting edge PCB
techniques to build it even further and
to get some prototypes one thing led to
another and we actually showed various
way by which you know which boots can
actually work and we say great so now
the problem is solved all this saved we
can go back to our Batcave or whatever
and do theoretical research because
everybody will just pick up these zero
knowledge and use it well nothing
happened in that regard and so we
started looking for applications or self
is starting bitching around and we heard
about that new thing Bitcoin that sort
of had privacy but didn't and if we only
use your knowledge proves maybe we could
make it have real privacy so we teamed
up with people working on that and we
published a zero cash paper which was
one of the first plausibly real all-news
applications of your knowledge proofs
and we said ok now surely everybody will
use it and we can go back to the lab and
do our stuff because blockchain right
and not even heaven either
because no one knew what is that what
the way they call it the moon math of
the old knowledge proves how can you
ever trust it no one would ever use it
wait
so we had to roll up our sleeves and
create a new company to actually do the
engineering to deploy this it became the
second script of currency which is alive
and well and there's a whole bunch of
other cryptocurrencies that forked off
for this and many other projects that
were inspired by it to use your
knowledge proves in numerous other
applications whether blockchain or other
Daniel is from Canada company that
commercializes these applications in the
enterprise context for disclosure right
like them and there are many others and
this is why I'm sitting here because
those your knowledge proves that no
never work but if they did might
actually be useful I have become useful
I've seen many application and we would
like to make sure that the using it
right
hello everyone my name is Luis Brando I
guess if the time to talk is
proportional to the experience I'll have
just a little bit of time I'm I haven't
been around for that long I finished my
PhD in 2016 as a cryptographer I gave my
my core area is secured two-party
computation as I was doing my PhD I did
I
I'm originally from Portugal I did a PhD
between Lisbon Portugal and Pittsburgh
Pennsylvania in the West and while I was
in the u.s. I had the opportunity to do
a short summer visit at NIST and that's
where I met Renee who who I mostly work
with now we match very well in terms of
interests related to privacy and while I
was still doing my PhD Renee came with a
problem where basically the government
is trying to implement a system of
brokered identification where
it's gonna make everything easier
because you can have now citizens
identifying to relying parties with the
help of identity providers but because
there's a privacy constraint where the
identity provider should not know where
the where the person is going to the
government is trying to solve that by
putting some entity in the middle that
is gonna mediate everything so that now
that interpreters don't know where the
citizens are going and it's like we look
at this okay sure but was the was the
person in the middle and it would be a
government controlled entity and so that
will ended up actually being quite an
interesting problem to look at from the
perspective of privacy were actually
skew computation ended up providing
quite an interesting result showing that
okay even if you have to have a that
person in the middle because of it's
very well justified you can actually
make sure that it's not going to learn
anything about the transactions that are
going to happen anyway this is how I got
connected to NIST and Rene and then once
I finished my my PhD I kind of this
looks a nice place to to try out and so
here I am for the for the past two years
just to try maybe a little bit of
anecdote this was just a few months ago
and this just to mention something about
I mean I think it's something always
present mainly in conference is the
aspect of NIST like oh you're working at
NIST like are you one of the good guys
or one of the bad guys interestingly an
interesting interaction a few months ago
at a conference in Europe you know just
coffee time saying hello to people and I
say hello to this person and then kind
of just showing the name oh and the
person just in oh you're at NIST I'm so
sorry for you
and I'm like oh really why is that oh
because nist sabotaging standards etc
etc and actually I had it quite a quick
answer I just occurred to me to say oh
well then I guess I'm glad I'm there to
make sure that doesn't happen anymore or
at least that I can help that not happen
so it does it does feel to me that
actually being at NIST is is an
interesting place to be to indeed bring
in some interest for privacy and really
making sure that we're doing good
standards but of course don't trust my
words but but that's what it is that's
what I'm trying to do and it does look
like very as I was saying in the
presentation earlier this morning even
though I may not have a large enough
historical perspective of things I do
think I bring a fresh perspective for
some things and I do
I really feel excited about looking that
this is the time where some of these
things what we're calling advanced
cryptography is coming about in terms of
standardisation so it's it's a cool time
to be here alright so my name is Tonya
Langer from the universe Tecna
University in Eindhoven unlike my course
because I don't know why I'm here but
since I have the board anyway I might
tell smilin toads so growing up in
Europe in cryptography we've always been
looking at the standards ie
missus - and as a standards as something
which is probably there in order to be
against us so we've been always looking
at those things as something were okay
figure out what it's like we always knew
there'd be a little bit paranoid but
well it was not the good feeling hey
this is something sanitized it's good it
was more like hmm are they trying to
shove something down our throats which
is helping them spy on us well and then
some years later Snowden came around and
well at least there were some which were
made to be well looking well not in
order to make us more secure but in
order to make it possible for them
whoever they them are to look at what
we're doing and get information they
were not supposed to do now my first
step at that point was do a lot of
archaeology
so I spent a long time digging through
all the FOIA requests about dual EC so
if you want to learn more about the
history how it was possible that these
things happened if you saw the project
will run releases then there's like the
NSA bragging about an exercise in
finesse and you go like yeah okay fine
show me what it is I mean this is their
annual report and when you tell your
boss hey I did well please give me a
race you will also say hey it wasn't
exercising finesse but actually Wars now
digging through all the details is that
the way that these standards work in a
particular thing that I saw is somebody
has to write this document and then
magic somebody is willing to take it
over and do all the work and so what
happened at that point was that the US
representative says well look you just
got another 40 pages of feedback with
lots of nitpicky remarks and the Germans
don't like this definition and the
French and the British and they're all
complaining how about this he is our new
and shiny and nice is written and we
already did the work of formatting it
the right way in Izu style which is not
the way you would write your things but
it looks like I just saw how about this
I know but I said oh yeah sure that's an
exercise in finesse just preying on the
laziness of people okay so it was a
little funny I could give some talks
about it I could show how this is a
backdoor we showed how the backdoor
could be exploited in in real life
because direct out there and it's a was
going like well I'll buy your beer if
you can show that this actually is
usable you never fold up on that but
then it's fun but it doesn't get you
anywhere it doesn't make the world safer
and so eventually I was like fine I
probably have to roll up my sleeves and
actually go to those meetings and yep
it's still the same if anybody is
willing to do something they get a
shitload of work so well please join and
help so that the next thing that's a
better and please join only if your name
tag doesn't say NSA or know that you
can't say that but
we need more eyes on this we need more
people who actually have the background
because normally people who have time to
go to standardization bodies I don't
really have time to go there and I can't
go to all of them and it's so easy to
slip some and when you look at ISO for
instance I've now been to other meetings
there are now a bunch of cartographers
in the room at the SC 2712 JTC 1/sc 27
working group 2 which is meant to be the
one for doing crypto standards and
there's a good number of people with
different interests and I'm happy to see
the NSA there and happy to see the
Russians there and the Chinese and so on
and a whole bunch of free world
cryptographers and we are all keeping
each other in check and reviewing things
but even this is one working group there
is a huge flood of documents I can't
possibly keep up on all of them maybe
together we can but then there are other
eyes working groups so there is the ISO
working group on financial standards so
the financial system has their own
crypto things there is something on
small devices there's something on this
and this and this and it turns out that
if your crypto can't get into the SC 27
working group - you can just go to
working group 3 for instance qkd which
several of us have some loath against
didn't manage to get into working group
- and so now they're trying to get into
working group 3 which is actually there
once there is a standard that they
determine how to qualify and how to
measure this well they skip in the
standard part and they just go into
three and probably every customer will
just say oh stand ISO standardized check
that's fine so it's a huge time sink but
if each of us maybe does a little bit we
can do it now the reason why I'm saying
I have no idea why I'm on this panel is
that my normal work is low level or trip
- trying to get signatures encryption
stuff right I dabbled a little bit in
higher level protocols have done some
pairings and such during most oppose
qualms these days
so I can't really help much with the
fancy stuff but then again the lessons
learned on being on those
standardization meetings is probably
similar to what we encounter elsewhere
and well maybe if each of us does a
little bit it can work so just to kind
of address these
I don't know why I'm here like I think
you're behind somebody I'm really
answering your own question like we want
to bring all these people from different
walks of life right I think Louis was
sorry Ron Ron was mentioning this this
morning that it's important to bring you
know people from theory from from there
are developing open sores people from
advanced cryptography not advanced
cryptography people that work in Stan
there's people that don't work in
standards and all all walks of life in
some sense but but these also kind of
brings me to to think a bit in retro
actively as to the difference that I at
least seen in some sense from the past
way of doing standardized
standardization at least in cryptography
and the new way and I think I want to
ask you like what why are Standards
important if at all right I mean there
is in some instances where they may not
be important there may be taken
advantage of and others that not so if I
ask you all that question our standards
important when are they important you
want us an order or okay so if anybody
wants to answer please just it depends
so I would say if you need something
where multiple people do something has
to be interoperable it helps to have a
standard if you just need something for
yourself for your own product be it open
source software be a commercial product
and you have the expertise to select
something you don't actually need a
standard and standards will get in your
way in the sense of speed of product
development whatever there is another
place where standards can help namely if
you want to have some certification or
some form of verification at the end of
it there are a bunch of companies which
are well set up to test things that are
in these standards and if something is a
newfangled protocol or newfangled
cryptographic primitives they don't have
the expertise I'm not saying that all of
those things help well I think they help
I'm not saying that all of those things
work we have seen for instance open SSL
v certified had a sec Fault in something
which should have been tested and
working but there were probably other
things that recording the certification
so some things it helps and some other
things well couldn't be bothered
I guess maybe as a compliment
I think a standard is a reference that
people can refer to and in good use
cases there's there will certainly be
bad use cases robbery in good use cases
they can potentially serve to to be a
reference for best practices so for
example taking the example of threshold
schemes through cryptographic primitives
where one of the goals is to have a way
of enhancing certain security properties
such as for example better resilience
against key leakage so if there are
scenarios where it's likely that a key
is under attack there's some adversary
trying to reach a key then maybe at some
point in the development of these
schemes one can say okay maybe some
threshold schemes would be a best
practice to protect high-value target
keys and so once we have that preference
that's a reference of comparison if
somebody loses a key and was not using
that maybe it's an indication well it
should have been using that possibly
another thing that I think can be a
benefit maybe it's a secondary benefit
but I think it's also relevant related
to Samuels conversation talk today is a
standard may also indeed constitute a
period of higher peer review of a
particular method or operation and it
will probably lead to a better
specification of a particular technique
and that may have its own benefit I
guess
so in general things products that the
different manufacturers companies
generate underneath we work with each
other
require standards so in the case of
cryptography most cryptography really
requires standard in that sense because
you don't want just one company to be
able to produce the products even
different vendors and to interoperate so
in that sense there is this operational
reason for four four standards but
beyond that in cryptography we want to
educate the world not to invent their
own crypto if you don't want these
companies to invent their own crypto you
need to give them the solutions and this
is one fundamental reason for first
standards in these in this area and then
there is the question of base the issue
of best practices which is also somehow
determined by the standards I'm not
saying that all standards actually
standardize on the best practices it's
not necessarily the case but if we want
this to be the case we can help being
involved with these things one example
of best practice is that so best
practices also in this area are
important for regulations so you know
when we people have regulations on
privacy or security related stuff then
the standards also are a guide for for
regulators and Wow I always you know
that now people work on search and
encrypted data for example and there are
different methods one one of them for
range queries is deterministic
order preserving encryption which is an
urbanist encryption and therefore not a
great encryption so the question is when
when when a regulation or a law says
that data needs to be encrypted it
doesn't send into encrypted with
semantic security right so the word
encrypted is not sufficiently
descriptive if there is a standard to
cite with in relation to that then then
you get a much more more information on
what really is needed are meant
I think another consideration is
lowering the barriers to adoption
especially for technology we need
standards for the same role that we put
guarding grazin handholds hiking trails
right they may save some experienced
hikers from falling to their death but
also they will encourage less
experienced hikers to take the train in
the first place and with the very
complex and nuanced graphic primitives
that we are dealing with here there are
many people who are cognizant of the
dangers of doing it wrong and so with
only start denying if they feel that
it's well one marked another's that we
will say from certain death they try to
just wing it and this discussion is
important because it shows that there
are different considerations for the
different phases of the evolution of the
standards the initial ones we are the
informational aspect is crucial whereas
later on it's the normative one that's
essential for interoperability that I
believe takes over maybe if I can just
kind of follow up on that it's a great
it's a great point for the next question
but also like when you mean lower the
barriers for adoption it's also in some
sense lower the barriers for entry right
the fact that when you can give this
tool or the standard to someone that is
not doesn't have the money to implement
this stuff maybe we can just take the
standard implement
having to go through a long process
right but so in terms of adoption right
we have this kind of question of where
or these tension I would say where in
some cases technology is just being
adopted by companies and that's when
sometimes the motivation to create a
standard comes into place
in other cases you have write an open
source for example projects that sort of
create an ad-hoc standard right so what
really goes first like standard or
adoption right this is a big a question
that may resonate with some of you but I
do want to say one of the advantages but
also where I would see a need for you
know some drawbacks or some cons for
this is you know fundamentally I agree
with everything with advanced crypto
message that fundamentally are
addressing decentralized trust so
bringing distrusting parties to automate
the processes in the interaction between
them so how can I bring somebody that
doesn't trust me if we don't even agree
on the formats or the standards are the
primitives clearly there's that need
there's also need to consider the
societal impact of the technologies that
we create and if you just let open
source ad hoc or even product great fact
you know adhoc standards you might not
have the responsibility and the
protection of regulatory oversight and
generally you know even economists or
advice as to how to best create
technology that we can be accountable
for and that takes into consideration
all these aspects related to that is the
issue of transparency that's one of the
things that you want to provide as much
as you can to we we have examples of
NIST is a perfect case of extreme
non-transparency and extreme
transparency the non transparency with
the famous great transparency in all
these competitions so you mean the
period of NIST pre Lewis and post Lewis
I think that anyway in general the issue
of transparency and even in cases where
standards are developed in some chaotic
way but with transparency that's that's
really some level of assurance no
guarantee of something right but at
least assurance that things were so I
think guidance is wonderful and
definitely desirable but when I see of
standard I think of something which is
unique there's these standards for doing
something whereas when I hear guidance
or something new then I think okay fine
a it doesn't mean that we have to
selected which of those it's just like
everybody who does something should also
give guidance and how to implement it
properly
and how to take him to current whatever
sit considerations belong to this
protocol but that to me is not a
standard who go since you just mentioned
the pseudo-random generators I mean
that's the one with the dual EC is in
this was in some sense an open process
they had two conferences where people
could give feedback but it was not a
competition it was something were missed
posted this thing as died post I don't
know 20 or 30 things per year send them
and you can be on the mailing list you
get a notification hey there is a draft
please comment on it but to me this is
more like a denial of service attack I
don't have time to look at all of those
and so in the end I go like yep fine and
the same happens with I so they say
heavens ITF there's too many things and
if we now say won't have even more
standards that means we're spreading
even more thinly and so that's what I'm
thinking let's hold back on things let's
do community focus on a few things that
we can actually handle and I'm happy to
see miss during post quantum happy to
see miss doom lightweight I'm happy to
see Miss doing advanced crypto but does
NIST and does the community actually
have enough manpower or cryptographer
person power to handle all of those or
are we losing focus on things and yes I
do see that you would like to have some
advanced things it would be nice to have
a standard on zero knowledge but you
also want other people to to have
reviewed it and where do they come from
because they're kinda busy with the
other standards well first sometimes yes
for example with quantum there is no
substantial
notion of photography but we all
understand that it needs to happen ASAP
and it needs to be highly interoperable
but even for things that are much faster
like your launch proves its while it's
definitely too early to have normally
standards for specific calibrations as
everyone should use there are already
fragments that are very useful to
standardize like interoperability lower
levels of the stack benchmarks
conventions and terminology because they
enable the conversation and even this
conversation is useful for the
practitioners who can already use these
components crucial it's also useful for
the researchers in academia or building
these components because they can talk
to each other more effectively they can
fairly compare things in their
performance using common conventions for
benchmarking and often conversation also
raises new research problems for example
the work that Tron kinetic resented
earlier about you see modeling emerged
from the first Zika personalization
workshop and the need recognized there
to better capture these properties so I
think we should not overreach and not
become rigid and it's too soon or aim to
solve the very difficult problem of
whose scheme is best but we should look
for the places where meaningful impact
can be made
[Music]
since in which standardization conflicts
with specialization optimization there's
certainly conflict there especially with
very rich functionality where for
example performance depends drastically
on the application domain they approach
it we taking to the significally
proselytization effort at this point is
the descriptive rather than prescriptive
one we are trying to comprehensively
describe the different approaches and
the main trade-offs to help
practitioners place themselves in the
large engineering landscape of possible
approaches I assume that this will
eventually converge into a smaller
distilled choice of concrete algorithms
and parameter choices okay I think that
we just have a different idea of what
sound is of what cinemas Asian means to
me it's like a standardization body says
something worse what you're saying is
the community working on this gets
together and comes up with hey how do we
decide to write these things down and
it's not a selection of an algorithm
it's a selection of a presentation way
of a evaluation way and so on that's
this is the component that I stressed so
far it certainly goes beyond that for
example in the proof security track that
deals with algorithms and security
definitions there is a ever-evolving
survey of the specific algorithms and
approaches not know just the conventions
used to designate them in the
implementation part there is a detailed
discussion of the modules best practices
for implementations and involving
taxonomy of existing implementations and
the properties so there's
a lot to do that is just it it is
descriptive level and and yet is
substantial so one note that I think
address is what Tonya was saying with
respect to the denial of service problem
which I think it's it's a real problem
and in the aspect of the of the right
time for standardization I think another
element that we can look at is not
necessarily whether it's the right time
to standardize but whether it's the
right time to have a standardization
process and so then we can what we can
tune is the speed at which the process
goes and so I think if we if we realize
that we have a potential for denial of
service because there's not a lot of
people we can potentially go slower
until we actually I mean whoever's
leading a standardization effort can can
be aware of that and can make sure look
guys we're only going to advance if we
actually have collaboration so at least
from the perspective of we I mean the
privacy enhancing cryptography team is
having at NIST now with respect let's
say with with your notes proofs is that
we're emphasizing this aspect of
developing reference material and and
positioning I mean you even put it as a
disclaimer when we made our initial
comments that were not this doesn't mean
an endorsement for standards was really
because we feel that that process is
important so the process of building
reference material is a time during
which we are getting informed we're also
putting our contribution and so I think
that aspect of speed not only of so
basically not looking at a particular
time for standardization to act to have
a standard but a time to have the
standardization process I think that
gives us more flexibility to have a more
secure process
right now there is a call for proposals
by DARPA when they see program for
building zero knowledge proof systems
it's going to be funded by many tens of
millions of dollars and consist of
multiple teams constructed into several
tiers and there's ta one which deals
with specific applications for your
knowledge and ta two that deals with
creating the backends that actually runs
to get a busy launch protocols and
here's the thing it will be performers
dozens of researchers funded by DARPA
and some will be building these
applications and some will be building
these backends and they need to talk to
each other and some groups most of them
probably will be will only be building
the higher part or the lower part so how
do we make any of these talk to any of
those right so this is essential for a
project the US government has been
essential for national security then it
requires yes specifically for these and
similar applications we're developing
the SDK interface standard as part of
the personalization effort that aims to
make to achieve interoperability at the
level of conveying statements to be
proven into your knowledge between the
application layer in the cryptographic
layer so we've seen this kind of
concrete engineering means already it is
very early deployment if in research
stage so maybe I won't even take it a
bit of a step back when when both of you
were also answering at the beginning of
this class question you were mentioning
a lot of this idea of right as a
responsibility and accountability and
transparency and I think maybe even
going back to what Tonya was also saying
before this idea that there is a kind of
very little involvement from academia
because usually you're traditionally
industry has been driving with standards
or standard bodies have been driving
standards for industry but now we're
kind of seeing and I hope that this is
the case that maybe standards is a way
to bridge academia and Industry right
and this is a way to bring
accountability because there is sort of
in
currently different interests from both
both sides so my question I guess is is
twofold one is is standardization the
only way to bridge academia and industry
and the other question is is more on the
lines of I guess what is what is the
best what is the better way to
standardize through standard bodies or
through community efforts right so
well I think that yeah there many ways
different ways of having this community
efforts the industry academia
partnerships standards one one way it
depends a lot whether the the interests
of the academia they happen at the same
time when I mentioned the mid-90s when
you know when I was working in the IDF
there are very very few cryptographers
involved with that even though things
were very important things were
happening because you know these things
would happen at the beginning it's a
very hard to hard to change them later
but there was no awareness in the
academic community that actually
something is happening in the world and
we are not participating
so definitely standards is one one way
of doing it depends on the type of
standards some standards that no
academician will be able to work because
they are boring and they are
bureaucratic they are closed there are
different constellations but right now I
mean when these things happen together
is the best now in in the last year's we
saw for the development of TLS 1.3 an
amazing
joint work of the industry of the
experts and TLS from the industry side
cryptographers and security people and
formal methods people having really a
huge collaboration and hopefully in the
years to come but the truth is that
there is very good track record that
when cryptography is done with
professional cryptographers the result
I'm not saying that they will be perfect
but they stand time much better yeah so
I won't say that there is one model that
always works better than the others but
the point is that the weakest link are
they are us the researchers because we
like to work only on what we like to
work and if something requires too much
involvement with details of stuff like
that then many of us we will not do that
so it's really a responsibility we
cannot wait for the industry to can say
please please help us this is a very
very important point right I mean I
don't want to stop anybody else from
answering the question but how do we
incentivize researchers right
cryptographers to be in these things
this is kind of going back to what are
they interested was who I was saying
look do you know of anyone know of
anybody who made tenure because of their
contribution to standards there's just
academia the traditional age does not
have the recognition or the resources to
invest
this really really important noble holy
work and it's not a work of you know one
month it's a lot a lot of investment and
it is grudge work and talking to people
and things that scientists are not to do
in the reason you're now seeing you know
some convergence is because academia is
becoming much much more industry
friendly anyway everybody has business
incentives so now there is the resources
and the incentives advanced you know
prominent scientists to participate in
this work but my providing your answer
is unless you have the business reward
and credits to do that
[Music]
the coppersmith sure but I mean the
academic systems not the Deming system
is not set up to reward you for wasting
your time on standards I don't it money
to do I don't have time to go it's
against publications whether so I mean
I'm doing it because for the good of the
world but I'm a totally it did for doing
it so so I think that when you say and
talk about working standards and when I
say working standards I think we have a
different different feeling about this I
wrote many papers
thanks to my involvement
that people were defining things and I
was documenting talking about developing
the Torah fee inventing defining proving
so this is part of our research world
it's true that you have to spend time
interacting with the engineers
interacting with industry which I
usually find but also a great
educational experience and a great
source of problems to work I think
there's one big difference between what
I'm talking about what you're talking
about you talk about standardizing your
own algorithms so you're mentioning AES
mentions r3 so you have an inherent
motivation to see these things getting
used and yes then it's totally
worthwhile to invest a little bit extra
or a large cut extra to push this into
standardization what is you motivated to
go for the year or two years Wallace is
in discussion what I'm talking about is
that there are a lot of standards which
are being written which are being pushed
by industry for their own interest and
they have the same idea hey look we have
this thing one of our designers did this
we now would like to have a stamp of
approval of you ITF I saw Etsy what have
you not and spending time on reviewing
and cleaning up the mess that is there
that is not very rewarding but it's also
necessary to do because we see those
things getting used in products and if
you were yesterday at work every single
paper was showing a really fatal flaw in
real-world deployed things and
essentially everything was based
understanding where the standard was
just flawed because we as a community
don't have enough time to review all of
those and I'm not talking about a s or
sha-3 that was lots of community
involved I'm talking about all these
other things which fly by and say hey do
you want to give a comment on this whole
standard
heavy weights or processes but also in a
community driven once where a lot of day
for it is a bit of like a potluck party
everybody comes along with their
thoughts and pet peeves and you need to
somehow call this all of these together
into something coherent and the most
effective ways to leverage those pet
peeves into you know what if you're so
pissed about that why don't you write
that chapter and sometimes work often it
doesn't often they have the full intent
to do it but once they fly back and have
their teaching obligations and their
deadlines in their grant reports then
the energy dissipates and I think we
still learning the ropes of how to
create just a common standard i I
conceive that the notion of standard
does include the case where people wanna
standardize their own things just for
the sake of standardization it becomes a
reference so I think the where the issue
may be is how do people recognize
standards and which standardization
bodies with particular missions
recognize particular standards so this
was actually a question posed in a
previous presentation where I mean I
post this question about okay if maybe
one of the benefits of standardization
is that it goes under a better peer
review and better specification okay if
that's the only thing that that standard
is achieving then if people know that
then it's not a problem it's it's
basically a paper so to a certain extent
I guess depending on the application
sometimes what we need are actual meta
standards which are standard saying
these are the approved standards
actually to a certain extent NIST does
that in in particular settings it says
these are the particular standards that
we accept for signatures etc etcetera
and that particular vendors need to use
if they do business with the government
for example
so yeah I think I mean I I felt this
even while I was preparing the
presentation for this workshop the
question of what is the standard comes
back and forth and usually we're talking
about standards and we have a an
implicit mindset so maybe sometimes it's
better that with this disambiguate what
we're talking about okay thanks I think
we're good we spoke a lot about like the
origins of standards like worried where
the standards originate how what is the
best way to proceed with us what are the
incentives and so on
now I want to ask like okay now we
assume that we have some standard for
example there is this tension right we
kind of are all aware maybe maybe
secretly aware that standards can
somehow stop innovation right so right
companies can adopt some standard
implemented they put it in their product
they integrate it and everything's good
and then you know a few years later
suddenly it's broken or there is a
better standard right our researchers
motivated to look into this new this
direction one now there is a standard
and you know that maybe it's not gonna
be adopted what's the tension here how
do we form standards so that we don't
stop innovation right I will talk about
good standards or bad standards well I
think the the quality of being good or
bad can actually be it's it's a
contextual property it can change over
time I think I mean I think the answer
can go both ways so if we develop a good
standards in a particular good point in
time that can promote adoption can
promote innovation can be a good
reference for people to do more research
and innovation along that line now if we
have a context where compliance with the
standard is required and the standard
becomes obsolete and the standardization
context is not able to
revised the standard retired we draw the
standard we'll replace it by some
something else then that's a problem
again I think in a big part that may be
an issue not with the standard because I
mean at least in this use case the
standard may have been good when it was
designed it may be a problem with the
structure that holds the standard so
let's say that yes I think it's a great
standard it is it went through a good
process it's holding fine let's say that
next year it's broken can we change it
immediately if we can then we have a
problem but is it because the standard
was bad well it was bad now we know it
but previously it was a good standard
but correct me if I'm wrong you're
talking about more like the process
right there on one hand you have the
process on the other hand you have the
adoption part so talking for example TLS
I think this could be a good example a
new standard was created for a tails 1.3
but how many companies are how many
right services adopted TRS 1.3 at this
point that's that's mainly because once
the browser
very fast so that's relatively first but
standards like TLS I mean this that they
are not a block cipher not basic
primitives but protocols or modes of
operations they should be built in some
flexible world so that at least the
components of it can be can be replaced
so that's a very important consideration
to have in mind when you develop a
standard there is a tension between
making flexible and making it too
flexible standards that have too many
options problems of interoperability or
complexity so so you need to find some
balance but definitely there needs to be
an element of flexibility agility in
which you can change the components
anyway when when standard is finalized
the interests of the designers goes down
but the interests of the Kryptonite
because now you can write the paper I
broke their list 1.3 and so a lot of
standards not just in photography where
the standard sometimes it's just a
de-facto technology standard has some
limitations or constraints and there's a
whole ecosystem and research field born
just around dealing with the constraints
that the technology is created and
overcoming if anything I would be
concerned about
all this energy channel that's breaking
dealing with I hope I hope we can't read
it so maybe maybe a bit more
I don't like technical question but
along these lines of having a standard
already set in place like the question
is really like we're talking about
advanced cryptographic standards but
really to be honest all these advanced
cryptography actually uses use
primitives that are not so advanced
whatever we define as advanced right and
what do we do with these standards right
these are common like if I put this
specific example of threshold
cryptography homomorphic encryption is
your knowledge right at somewhere
another you're using some commitment
scheme or at point you're gonna be using
some signature maybe not all of these
are standardized are we too early
standardizing advanced cryptography and
and what do we do about these common
primitive do we all standardize them
individually for different applications
we human race not we specifically we're
standardizing what we care about but
there are many simpler primitives that
aren't fully standardized things that
are much better understood in fact three
years ago
Nigel smart and several of his
associates wrote a letter to NIST
asking for a more attention to
standardization of cryptographic tools
that are pretty well understood for
example your knowledge proofs but not
the fancy general ones that we dealing
with now but rather things
sigmund protocol for discrete log and
Peterson commitments and the properties
opening this transfer garbage circuits
pushing it and these are things that
especially the first few have converted
nicely they are building blocks in many
existing protocols in industry as well
as the protocols that we are dealing
with here and it would have been nice to
have those covered by the way with the
with the soon to be approval of EDSA
essentially contains the KP of the
spirit board embedded in it just just
one shot so I think as we move further
into the future and assuming that we
will be standardizing more generic SMP
see I think there will be a point indeed
where it will make sense to have a good
reference definition slash reference
some something that we can reference if
not an actual standard of some things
like maybe garbled circuits oblivious
transfer some commitment schemes but
going immediately to those without
knowing what is it that we're going to
want to do with them might not be the
best option if there's a possibility
that when actually we go for the more
advanced things then we actually need a
little tweak of the commitment scheme
now having said this I actually think
that special cryptography is in a kind
of a sweet spot in the following sense
it does require let's say for the
multi-party setting it does require
exercising some SNP see in certain cases
but the actual scope of threshold
cryptography I mean if you look at it
from the point of view of threshold
schemes for approved cryptographic
primitives it actually has a very
well-defined scope so even though we
might be looking at maybe we can call it
a large number of possible
standardization elements it still it it
it comes down from a small number of
primitives let's say we may want to do
threshold RS a threshold ECDSA
threshold at the SAS reference condom
although the post quantum is still in
the evaluations it may take a little bit
more time the point I wanted to make is
the following if we say that what we
want let's say in the next one or two
years is a threshold version of ECDSA or
RSA key gen and we know that we're going
to have to use let's say an oblivious
transfer there then we're talking about
one standard that is gonna use one
primitive so maybe the actual exercise
of doing the full standardization is
what we need to actually be fine within
their own standard one implementation of
one let's say oblivious transfer and I
think that's a good exercise without
having to commit that we've standardized
oblivious transfer because now when we
go for the next maybe more advanced SN
PC protocol that also requires double
use transfer then we can analyze okay
can we use the one that we already used
and then if you can we can just refer to
it we can even if we want at that point
actually remove it to a standalone
document but then we also retained the
possibility of saying you know what for
this primitive it was a good exercise to
have done that oblivious transfer but
now we want a slightly tweaked version
so I guess the summary of what I'm
saying is while we have a small scope
where we're just going for one or two
advanced concrete protocols I don't see
it as a big deal to actually embed in
the standard the primitives that we're
using and then when we start defining
three four or five advanced protocols
then we can we can by then we have
learned with the experience
one fourth Thanks
so I want to kind of ask a question but
I think it's a very interesting one
we're going back to the tension between
academia and industry and interest in
the industry we have kind of a legal
framework for processes and for
applications and things they're already
established right almost trust models
but also like a legal punishment it for
behavior for malicious behavior let's
call it right so can we justify
the effort from from let's say our
ciphers researches to write ensure or
enforce non-malicious active behavior in
these cryptographic protocols when we
know that whenever there is gonna be a
cheater there's gonna be a kind of a
breach of contract and legal consequence
right and and and attached to this
question is kind of the idea
SOCAN standards kind of help to define
regulatory and legal frameworks
so in some sense cryptography can
enforce behavior or can catch behavior
exactly and that's right so we have
scenarios where people are not
associated with robust identities and
are not accountable in the standard
world of legal enforcement and maybe the
clearest one is blockchain right you are
respecting transactions that were posted
by unknown people and the only way to
make this work is by not assuming that
there is any recourse other than a
cryptographic one to ensuring the
correct behavior there are other
scenarios where there might be fall back
alternatives using society's legacy ways
of enforcing correct behavior but those
are very expensive it's true that
humanity has spent in the last few maybe
tens of thousands of years building
civilization aka a way to enforce norms
but it has many costs it has
in Liberty in resources in performance
of these systems and to the extent that
we can replace norms enforced the Google
way with real-time cryptographic
protocols often there is a benefit to
that and it's these places that I think
are being monetized by many of the names
you'll see on the sponsor list of this
workshop to understand so dealing with
regulations right it's it's a big deal
and we have to work in that direction
even if it works very slowly it's a very
important aspect
Peter Van Valkenburg
talked yesterday morning about basic
constitutional rights of modern society
is she committed a crime you will not
get punishment so I think there's a very
dangerous slippery slope in automated
punishment systems and concerta social
rating
yeah I I think I do have some concern
with the premise of of the question
which is well assuming that we can catch
people and I mean even if you even if we
catch people misbehaving that does not
necessarily mean that we can enforce
some some punishment and and I guess a
full answer to the question would also
have to be parameterised with what is
the cost of being caught versus the cost
of actually achieving whatever we were
trying to get with the malicious
behavior but one next two extra thoughts
one is one potential problem of
standardizing let's say semi honest
secure passively secure protocols that
completely break down in an active in a
with an active adversary is is the
problem of misuse so now you have a
protocol that is stamped this has been
zero knowledge proof for SNP C in the
semi honest case and then for the people
are not cryptography so we're using a
secure system therefore we can just do
whatever you want right so it's the it's
the problem of the false sense of
security and I think the I mean in
general the problem of misuse of
protocols of devices and all that it's
it's a huge problem in in cryptography
so I would tend to say if we can do
maliciously secure actively secure or
secure against malicious adversaries
then I think we should go for it at
least in the SMBC arena the there has
been a convergence with respect to the
costs previously it was like 40 let's
say 40 times difference and then you
know a lot of settings those the factor
of difference has decreased a lot just a
final note is that at least in the SMP C
area we we actually have I mean a good
characterization between semi honest
malicious and then we have the covert
adversaries or the covert adversary
model where which exactly
exactly measures the case we're
adversaries behave based on the
probability that they can they can be
caught and so fundamentally creating
very very serious if you give a false
sense of security because we are experts
and probably what we created is secure
the responsibility and the
accountability is on us so we should aim
for the but we're just one extra
technicality in this I mean it's one one
technical aspect where it's kind of it
would be an analogous question to which
I have more education in answering is
the case of adaptive adversaries versus
static adversaries where in secure
multi-party computation at least there's
a lot of cases where we we can do the
proof for static adversaries we can't we
don't have the protocol for adaptive
adversaries but at the same time we
don't know of a real practical attack
that would break down the system and so
in those cases it's a little harder to
say and so I guess what I want to say is
I would be inclined to accept a static
malicious so a protocol securing a
static malicious model if I don't know
of any practical attack in an adaptive
scenario and I don't know any protocol
that is efficient at least in an
adaptive scenario where is for the semi
honest versus malicious case it's a much
easier answer like go for the
maliciously
because we know how to do that right and
it also boils down to what Aaron was
saying before that we need a lot of user
guidance that it's actually less
important to have like the concrete
scheme but it's important to see to say
on the annotations what does is achieve
what we expect and what can you expect
I mean we have more questions but
there's basically like 15 20 minutes
left and I want to open it for for Q&A
so if you have any questions you want to
come to one of the microphones and ask
anything you're interested in here to
ask which is about for more metal
missiles and how do you think this
technology may be used in the
photography or standard weather is it
like usable right now or a sterilization
main processes or is it does it needs to
be improved
right so Hoover already mentioned the
role that follow methods played in the
definition of chile's 1.3 I think that's
a great achievement at the same time
what is the rather lame end user I would
like to see is that I can actually use
this on things that I'm kind of
prototyping or something and so yes I
think more has to happen has to be
easier for me to tries but yes please be
involved and you saw that the previous
talk was easier being used on anok on
the case I think this is helpful and
if they are candidate solutions it would
be nice to get them formally verified or
shown to be not verifiable which case
they should be fixed
analysis of traffic corridors are
improved amazingly in the last year's I
don't think that there is any excuse to
have something a standard or unimportant
component there is no excuse not to to
be analyzed through these tools you know
I'm not sure about the completeness of
these tools but they are great debuggers
1.3 is an excellent example where people
have been working in running these tools
you know they found problems they found
issues they give you guidance on the
design so problem with a bootstrapping
problem you know I mean really I think
that we should be analyzing stuff as
much as we can we're using the which
will keep improving thank you
thank you very much for this discussion
I found it really interesting and I
appreciated the balance of say like the
positives of standards efforts and some
of the things to be concerned with I
guess I have to interrupt you and say
that your talk really well just wait
till what I was I have big big questions
kind of about how to you know know like
what are the things to watch out for
like what would it mean for a standard
to be bad or to go wrong that there
might be pitfalls to learn from it but I
wanted to phrase it as a more maybe
hopefully interesting question like do
you have any horror stories or like
anecdotes of standards gone wrong maybe
like the second worst standard to the
dual EC one that we might learn from as
a counterexample every single talk
yesterday at work wreck the workshop
yesterday workshop on attacks in crypto
essentially everything was standardised
and broken so there was Bluetooth there
was WPA three very new standard and also
broken so these are the last two talks
at my head everything before that as
well what is there to learn from those
though like is there so some of those I
would say are closed community no
feedback from the outside kind of
standards and I think this is kind of a
warning flag for me by now it would be
much more surprising to me if something
which had gotten a lot of community
feedback and review I mean like for
instance you mentioned follow methods if
there has been pieces now with just 1.3
with all the praise it's still not in
one model as deep everything together so
there still are some little cracks where
things could go wrong but I would be
much more surprise for things
that going wrong then was something
which was cobbled together because
somebody needed something and nobody
ever looked at it and capstone including
chip manufacturing was broken within
less than I don't know 60 days Matt
glaze among other people at ATT loves
showed how to break that but basically
this was supposed to be the only way you
encrypt audio turn you know audio signal
transmission by a government standard
and luckily cryptography record analysts
in this case broke it so we kind of died
a peaceful inside' and death that was a
horror I think another cesspool of
horrible standards is blockchain what we
have is many block change projects out
there who are building what are de facto
standards because they are actually
executed interoperable Network
consisting of many thousands of nodes so
they may not use the S word but that's
what they're building and somehow they
think it's fine to do so without even
having a specification for the protocol
let alone any form of analysis or review
process and because it's ternary rather
than binary then it must be fine
for example there is one thing that we
need to stomp out is this the comfort
that those fractions of the
cryptographic community broadly
construed have with just putting random
Beach operations together or some field
elements and propellants because they
cannot type match of you can typecast
them and then they type match and
calling this a cryptographic protocol
that people are actually entrusting with
many millions perhaps billions of
dollars this is the elephant in the room
right some of these people are probably
fine but many of our colleagues
colleagues those who would have been our
colleagues are actually out there right
now doing very evil stuff I think
knowingly or by incompetence
I mean do you think militias together
with the best
well if you're so why don't you write
that chapter okay so since you asked the
question like how can you recognize a
bad standard what does it smell like so
find some standardization body where the
membership fees are high the excess fees
are high and the they charge for
attending meetings right if you take all
three of those fairly lightly not gotten
any review
and they randomly pick people from
different countries yeah this I wanted
to you use the term bad or good I would
like you to look at standards as
something living with a lifecycle as any
asset the enterprise has got a lifecycle
and one thing that I would recommend in
any of the work is put a version it's
you consider it as a block or an asset
of cryptographic thinking on board all
over the world put it aversion to it and
look at it
my experience is 25 years of running a
pro services I don't build them I use
them and I have to replace I said one
with three and that's what I do guys try
to think of it as is yes you have a very
good tool as a version and but twenty
years I'll have to replace it I'm sorry
so please look at it as something that
is a living architecture that we have to
maintain in some way the fact that
things like knowledge not much - maybe
and advantage because you're less likely
to you know to put something very hard
it already already has a version 0.1 is
also proving useful for the research
that we lead to the consolidation of the
standard for example it allows us to
plug and play with different approaches
to schemes and compare them in terms of
performance because it was built in the
first place to allow you to change the
backend in a very convenient way even if
you use a different representation that
is the ideal that we striving for it
adds a que interface makes some headway
towards so to the extent that standards
are intended to foster this competition
and collaboration and putting the DA 1
minute here that plays very well also
with the fluidity thank you
so before before kind of wrapping it up
completely I just wanted to kind of say
a couple of conclusions that I got from
this and thank you all for sharing your
experience and your views it seems like
you know cryptography is still at a very
early stage right like we really started
you know 50 years ago right 60 years ago
or something with computers and advanced
in some sense and now we're at a point
where we see that really academics are
getting more involved with industry
whether it's because the industry is
asking for it or because there is more
incentives in the industry than there is
in academia right and hopefully now
we're gonna see this trend where
adoption is done in the right way right
like if you think about how like I don't
know physics and engineering right came
up to be and and how it transfer
knowledge transferred from academia to
the industry right people wouldn't have
thought to put people into a rocket and
shoot him outer space if it wasn't with
the proper set of physicists and
validation of techniques right
this is kind of the analogy that we need
to get that we wouldn't deploy secure
systems where billions of dollars are
based on without the correct processes
and correct very validations so in this
sense I guess either we need to change
the incentives that exist in academia or
we need to make sure that you the
industry can counter that by by asking
and providing those incentives right so
in general I would just say if if you're
in the industry and you're building
something then make sure you involve
academics and if you're in the academia
and you want to stand up standardize
something because you think it's useful
make sure it's useful before right it
kind of goes both ways if there is any
more questions otherwise any more
comments on your end maybe some
conclusion remarks that you also want to
share so maybe let's thank the speakers
and the panelists
[Applause]