[Applause]
okay so good afternoon everybody
I will speak about drones and their
possible attack vectors I want to say
thank you to all the people that helped
me with my research and they spend a lot
of time with me on the field trip to
test all the attack scenario that I will
show you later
so let me introduce myself I'm Paulo
Stagner I'm better known on internet as
void sack and since the beginning of my
career I mainly deal to with penetration
test and red team while now in doyon
sack I'm moving towards the application
security and vulnerability research I
also a blog that is called voice check
comm where I publish my articles
research and vulnerabilities so I'm
sorry I know that some of you were
expecting like this but I will not speak
about
Allah the tolls is divided in well three
main blocks the first one about
vulnerability research on that topics
the reverse engineering part and the
forensics so first the since the first
introduction in the consumer market
drone were used by different type of
sectors like the law enforcement for you
know border control patrolling and so on
and another project where drone were
used as a portable defibrillator and
also by you know checking place where
there are art to to get by a human and
also in 2017 in Syria they were used to
drop some explosive projectiles on the
battlefield and personally I use drone
in red team engagement to map Wi-Fi
hotspot in the area and later to
generate a map of the Wi-Fi hotspots
so in this panorama a Chinese company
named DJI quickly gained the fame
reputation as the most stable aerial
platform for shooting and video and
photos and this is the phantom tree
model and this is the product on which
all my research and this talk is based
on it took me something like one year of
research working in my spare time night
time and so as you can see from the
slide you can see the main body of the
aircraft and its controller and some
other equipment so these are some key
points of this specific model speaking
about its weight its weight 1.2
kilograms and this is able to fly with
another 400 grams of payload it can fly
for 20-25 minutes really depending on
the weather condition and its maximum
speed is a 16 meter per second or 50
seven kilometer per hour and as I
mention it earlier it is an excellent
platform for its stability
now I'm joking this is the video
feedback of a race drone while yeah this
is the video feedback the video footage
of a day on the sea there was a bit of
wind but is really stable if you pay
special attention you can also see a
seagull passing by at one point I don't
know where yeah okay never mind
okay and this is our old photos in
different type of weather Sun and wine
condition the left corner is a Piazza
Vittorio entering my own town while the
two photos in the middle are from UK and
right corner and is again Turin and
superg so speaking about the Phantom 3
model and this is all the drone
architecture that I analyzed basically
the drone which is flight controller and
some other models like the GPS models
and compounds gyroscopes and so on
and their ground controller that is a
radio model for communicating flight
command to the drone and the optional
basically module that is the application
that you can mount on the mobile phone
and you can retrieve back the video
feedback and some media while you
shooting photos from the drone and
despite all these technological
components the drone doesn't have any
system to detect obstacle so you can
only fly the drone in line-of-sight
basically so the first thing that I did
was to try to understand its network
schema and the drone is basically acting
as a well the ground controller is
acting as an access point for the drone
and the camera there are two different
components probably because they don't
want the video feedback to interfere
with the flight controller
as I said before optional is the usage
of the mobile application on the phone
so as you can see this is the list of
all the exposed services within the
network and that they show you before so
I'm basically having flying FTP server
and the interesting services like SSH
and turn it all filtered so I cannot
connect while the FTP is always
reachable and in the case of the camera
you can login with the anonymous
anonymous combination while port 76 78
is used by the Android iOS application
and this is the nmap scan of the last
version of the fear where we can see
that they are trying to improve and
there are denying the service that they
are exposing so they only left the core
services and they left the FTP because
it's used for loading the new firmware
update and retrieve some flight logs and
media and the port used by the mobile
application so this hardening was due to
the contrast the illegal market of mod
that were allowing people to change you
know maximum altitude and also remove
some no-fly zone limitation from from
the from the drone so regarding the
communication between the aircraft and
the controller a Wi-Fi connection in is
established between the remote
controller and the drone and is used for
both the transport of flight data and
the video feedback so this model does
not use the light bridge protocol that
is a protocol proprietary for long
distance streaming and it has some
greater stability and fluidity of
long-range communication and is mounted
on more professional drone of the GI and
the fouled SSID is derived from the MAC
address of the ground control
and it has the following format is
phantom3
underscore the last six digits of the
MAC address of the ground controller
while the password is the Evergreen
strong password one two three four one
two three four and this is the default
one so you can change it but it comes
with that posture
so obviously drone are not exempt from
the most common Wi-Fi attacks so we have
some predefined behaviors in the case of
the authentication attack so if we
basically disconnect the phone from the
graph from the ground controller nothing
happened
well if we disconnect the ground
controller from the drone it will
trigger the return to home and the
return to home is basically the drone
flying up to 30 meter of altitude and
after that going back in a straight line
where the last GPS point was recorded as
a home point so this can be only used in
where we have GPS fix and if we try to
add a new device to an existent Network
they are cruft maintain a queue of
device so does the live in priority to
the first connected phone and when the
connection to the first connected phone
drop and you can now connect the second
one and if you are trying to issue
command with the mobile phone and the
ground controller at the same time the
ground controllers did maintain a kind
of priority but it makes all the system
a lot less manageable and Wi-Fi attacks
again you cannot downgrade the settings
to WEP or UPS because it does not have
that kind of support while the boopie r2
is vulnerable to the stander four-way
and shake brute force and since as we
will see later the system is based on
open word tea and DJI never leads the
film where update of after the crack
advisory it is also vulnerable to
truck and this is an example of the
four-way and shake brute force I was
using fluke seein and a good dictionary
and is just a matter of some minutes to
recover the pressure head password okay
from here I started my my journey into
getting a shell on the aircraft system
because at the moment I have some filter
services for which I do not have any
password and so the first things that
come to my mind was to explore the
application that DJI provide for video
feedback and some other cities assisted
control ok here a small digression the
Phantom 3 and later models comes with a
dispensing system or an inbuilt no-fly
zone list and no-fly zone are as shown
by the image some virtual fences with a
specific diameter which the drone cannot
fly in so this make possible to exclude
some location like the airport from
drone flights and the GI also has a map
you can see country by country or the
no-fly zone in the area and there are
three different type of no-fly zone the
first one is a warning zone in green
where user will be just prompt with a
warning message and the second zone is
in yellow and this is an authorization
zone so you will need to have a verified
DJI account and internet connection and
you will got a prompt on your mobile
phone and you can unlock the desire for
the flight while in red there is the
restricted zone so there are zone where
you cannot fly and the flight is
forbidden so if you try to turn on the
drone it will refuse to start so main
problem is that no fly zone system is
only able when GPS coverage is present
so if the drone is not aware of its
position you can fly inside no-fly zone
while if you trick if you try to trick
the drone putting it in attitude mode
while it is still having the GPS fix it
will refuse to fly and this is an
example because DJI want to update
no-fly zone like including temporary
no-fly zone for specific events or
location so it is able to push some new
no-fly zone during the mobile app
updates and in this example this is the
example of a no-fly zone file in blue
you can see the position and radius of
the no-fly zone while you read the type
of the no-fly zone so this is a stadium
and the flight is not permitted in
violet you can also see the date where
the no-fly zone were inserted and also
if it's temporary when it begins and
when it ends
while in green the name and the city
were the no-fly zone it is present so
main problem is that these resources are
not signed so you can edit them and
basically invalidate all the
introduction of this know of this new
no-fly zone and searching inside the
application I also found this
configuration file with the root
password for the aircraft and you know
the password is big China is a Chinese
product and they're also trying to
improve because in the previous model it
was only digits so they are trying at
least okay so perfect now I have the
password but SSH and telnet are still
filtered and FTP service is restricted
to a single folder so I cannot navigate
the file system yeah damn so I tried
some simple finger replacement but the
funeral's as some kind of checksum
mechanism that prevent me to replace it
and since doing the full finger analysis
would have been a long process and I'm
lazy I prefer to
you know perform some preliminary
analysis as an example I try to just
grab for some simple keywords and I was
able to extract some other ashes that I
cracked so now I'm full of user and
password but I cannot log in anywhere
because the services are filtered so I
also told that some of the
countermeasure of the field where we're
you know introduced in later updates so
if even if it's not documented I found
that if you keep pressed the three small
line in the application basically a new
menu will pop out and from this menu you
can downgrade the failure so I
downgraded the failure and downgrading
the field where the FTP service was not
longer limited so as a root account I
was able to access the entire file
system which I copy and I started the
analysis again so the specific system
that DGI
is using for this drone is a fork of
open word tea that is called barrier
breaker and it's also full of some
custom binary for from DJI so I also
found that the following script are
running at boot time and they are
holding some network configuration for
the Wi-Fi settings and stuff so I had
this command and I was able to
reactivate the telnet and that was a
result so I was finally able to get root
on the aircraft that's fine but it's not
everything because until now I basically
ignored some of the three big chunks
that DJI provide and that third big
chunks is the SDK SDK here I have some
sad story for you the first time that I
try to compile it I got back something
like eleven
our message but at the end I was made it
to work
you know with some hammering technique
so the main idea of sdk attack was to
isolate some specific instruction sent
to the drone and while monitoring you
know the network traffic with were shark
or whatever and I would like to
implement some custom application that
could sense specific command to the
drone like the association to another
Wi-Fi network in order to get a full
drone takeover so SDK has also an unlock
mechanism this required to again DJI
account and request an API but
fortunately in the LA in the version
that is prior to the last one and it was
enough to modify the Java bytecode and
set the variable as you know unlocked
SDK like setting the variable to number
two if I remember correct yeah and so
you you don't need the AP key anymore
and you don't need a DGI account and
also this is the communication flow
between the application and the drone I
filtered out all the UDP traffic because
it's only video feedback so I also
started to do some reverse engineering
of the DJI sdk packets and DJI use a
proprietary TCP based protocol for
flight control so I started to do some
reverse engineering and it's very
similar to the protocol that was used by
the previous version of the Phantom so
some fields were already been identified
by the community and this is one example
of a DJI packet it has an either of four
bytes and the payload of variable length
for the either the first byte is
protocol magic number and the second
bite is the packet length so the either
plus the payload after that there is the
version of the SDK and the last bite is
a custom DGI cersei which I derived from
our coded values inside the SDK while
this is the payload structure so we have
the source type in our case is the
application speaking with the remote
controller after that we have an
incremental sequence ID a flag a field
that I don't know for which it's used
and the command that is being issued to
the drone so in this case is a remote
controller common set another ID and
after that the meaning of the field so
we are setting some kind of specific
instruction of the remote controller of
the drone and that lead me to GPS attack
GPS attack was the attack vector on
which I focused mostly and mainly
because it does not require you know to
be in the same network as the drone and
it's full remote and furthermore is the
most common technique to hijack a civil
drone since
civil GPS is not encrypted and speaking
about GPS attack the most common way was
the replay attack where basically a
previously recorded final is sent back
to the device and as a setup is used the
arc RF which is kind of cheap is 300
euro but if you compare it to other
devices is cheap so they occur F also
has some small problem with its internal
clock because it's not precise enough to
run a GPS replying so you need to buy an
external clock in order to make it work
for GPS attack and to in order to
generate or signal we need to download
some basic data and this basic data are
called FM
data and they are containing some
information about the location as far as
was able to understand the location the
current location and the future location
of a satellite and they are used by the
receiver to calculate the estimated
position on on earth and this is the
result of GPS spoofing attack the device
now thinking that I'm in Turkey and I
would also like to point out that also
the time information is contained in the
spoofing sign on so we can spoof time
and space and this is the result the
drone was in Italy but I was proofing
the location of the White House that
surprisingly is also a no-fly zone and
if I try to fly I got this error message
back so funny things DJ I think that the
White House it's a nuclear power plant I
don't know maybe we are missing
something but if we spoof the no-fly
zone and the drone cannot take off and
while if the drone is inside a no-fly
zone and we are spoofing another
location and the drone will be unlocked
and free to fly and this is what happens
when we are spoofing a no-fly zone and
the drone is flying with my setup it
will require something like 10 minutes
or more to complete these attacks so the
video is speeded up and the drone is
first landing if we basically create on
demand no-fly zone while is flying and
this is the schema that we can use with
the right hardware equipment to perform
a complete takeover basically the real
drone is on the green marker and in at
the same time two different attacks are
performed the first one that is the
authentication attack so we are
triggering the return to home
functionality in order to get the drone
flying back home and at the same time we
are also performing the GPS spoofer TAC
so now the drone things to be on red
marker and try to fly home while
basically the drone is fly on the
opposite direction far more away from
the on point so we can capture it or do
whatever we want
so I also try to think oh we can detect
some GPS attack with my stop basically
we can have this three option we can
validate the GPS subframe as you can see
from the image a real GPS signal as
subframe with some data while a GPS
poofed signal as subframe with all-zero
so if we are receiving a GPS packet with
all zero data in its subframe we can
refuse the packets and we are kind of
safe from GPS spoofing attack at least
with my setup and also we can try to
validate the time that we have set on
device with the time that we are
receiving from GPS signal and we can
also try to check the speed or validate
the time spent travelling between two
different points so if the drone is here
in sweden and after one second its
location is changed to China and is
impossible to fly from Sweden to China
in just one second we should refuse you
know the new location so that's pretty
much lead to the last block the forensic
part which basically I thought that
could be interesting to understand where
we can retrieve forensic artifact from
this model and later so on the phantom
tree there are three locations from
which we can recover artifacts the first
one is the gimbal the camera on the
gimbal so we can recover some media
files like the images video and so on
and there is a now also another location
that is the mobile phone on which the
app is installed and there are some txt
file
on the mobile application and also there
is a third location that is again is not
documented but there is this memory that
is all in that file that is present on
the motherboard of the drone and is
acting like a real aircraft black box or
flight recorder so did you I again used
a proprietary file type for that file
and since there is already available a
tool that is called drop drone open
source parser that is able to parse that
file every three information I will not
spend too much time on that but as you
can see from the structure again the
first byte is starting like the magic
number magic protocol number from the
SDK and again we are having you know the
the sensor that is issuing a message and
the content of the message and I would
also like to know that when the memory
is full the oldest data will be
overwritten but not only like you know
deleting the file pointers and well the
precedes location of the file that will
be overwritten will be zeroed out so
this will reduce the forensic chance of
recovering file and it is also possible
and I was a bit upset when I discovered
that and to fly the drone without the
memory on the motherboard so find the
drone without this memory will not
record anything and this can be used as
an anti forensics technique and if we
try to well these are all the data that
can be extracted from you know about
that file and txt file and if we
aggregate all these information we can
get something like that so we can show
the fly path of of the drone with some
statistics about the maximum altitude
speed and distance from the arm point
and we can also get
the entire sensor signals that we had
during a flight so in this specific
example the signal lost signal is shown
and this is the list of all the events
that are occurred in a specific time
frame so you can see that every events
all are also holding the altitude and
distance from the on point and some
other information and if we intersect
basically all the information that we
have so gimbal data with flight data and
the events were photos or video were
taken it is also possible to reconstruct
what the operator of the drone was able
to see and photograph so we can be
better than CSA and also if for that
file they will stay on the memory that
is on board of the drone the same things
cannot be said for the txt file txt file
on mobile phone will be uploaded to DJI
server because they will be used to feed
the DJI pilot accounts so with all these
details is not difficult to understand
why us in 2017 banned DJI products from
army so basically they cannot use the GI
products inside the army this probably
was the reason because you know you will
fly the drone and after that your mobile
phone will upload all data on DJI and so
Chinese server okay some things that I
forgot to say the video feedback on the
drone does not have any type of checksum
so we can potentially show on screen any
type of image and another things is the
drone is very sensitive to
electromagnetic field so it has a
compass system and it require
calibration before the first flight and
I can tell you from experience that if
you trying to turn on the drone near a
fridge or some
really large metal masses the compass
will go crazy and will require a
recalibration so I think that should
have some mins left and these are all
the countermeasures that come up for
trying to defend against drone some of
them are pretty straightforward like
shooting down the drone with a normal
gun and the other are you know some more
fancy kind of defences and none of them
is working against very tiny drone or
some drones worms so where you have you
know hundreds of drones flying all
together basically none of them is
working and this is an example of a
drone that was developed to capture and
neutralize another drone and after that
they started trying goals
so yeah the problem with Eagles is that
the average life of an eagle is twenty
years but they can only spend ten years
doing this kind of mission so after you
both won and you spent probably years
training them you will left with
probably a best friends I don't know
because they're quite useless after ten
years so no no way to bow them and well
yeah confetti gun can also be effective
or jetski so yeah you can feel the pain
of the drone operator is four thousand
euro knock it down and all this fancy
you know counter misery when that's what
happened new reality so they each drone
with three million-dollar missiles yeah
I don't know why okay so further work
maybe in the future I will try to look
into two different things as I said
before the system is full of custom
binary so I can try to
reverse engineering them and trying to
find some cool exploit for this binary
and also I can try to do the full
Network protocol analysis so I can try
to build ground station that is speaking
through the SDK directly with a drone or
maybe playing with something that is
more complex than that
okay here I have some references and
useful links for later and that's all
Thanks that's uh that's fun okay we're
running a bit ahead of schedule which is
just nice yeah but they also means that
the coffee is not gonna be ready yet
when we're done here so I'm gonna get
questions from the audience but yeah
first thing I'm really curious is
anybody making a better firmware for
this well I don't think so I mean they
released some other version later so I
don't think that the model tree will be
upgraded anyway all right because I mean
this it's an obvious attack thing with
the geofencing yeah to convince it that
it's in somewhere where it shouldn't be
to make it land right so that's
something that you would want to remove
as a user yeah so someone should be
making a firmware that you could replace
they should make yeah all right take the
microphone are you are you aware of
Kevin Finisterre and the work that he's
done no so there's a website DJI dot
retro roms dot info okay I'd be
hyphenated but Kevin finished his Nick
on Twitter is dot slash d0 TSLA SH okay
so they are upgrading different work but
these quality version like yeah so like
I brought my Mavic okay and then it's
got the controller is patched mm-hm the
aircraft is patched and the Android app
is patched and they've moved everything
like it's a proper like it's a it's like
a dirt bike now it's great so like if
you're unaware of yeah so they've
removed all the geofencing that we've
moved like the entire left-hand side of
the application which just Scrolls with
errors and whining and complaining they
removed 100 of the GPS restrictions all
the altitude and distance restrictions
they've let you make it make it go four
times faster hilarious aside is that one
of the exploits they used on the
aircraft which runs Android by the way
yeah maybe is the dirty cow exploit
works because because of course it does
but yeah if you're unaware of Kevin
Finisterra and the work that he's done
it sounds like a whole bunch of the
stuff that you're looking for is already
done and there's a wiki and there's
firmwares yeah so it's pretty rad you
should check it out yeah I would thank
you
interesting but and the is there
somewhere some some mitigation you can
do
the GPS hijacking thingy well there'd be
some things that are unreasonable right
if you move it really quickly like the
drone cap move that quickly yeah but it
would be you know performance issue
checking on the packets coming through
like I'm not sure that the aircraft
cares about where it is in GPS if you're
using the sticks to control it if you've
programmed a path yeah if you program
that yeah yeah there's nothing much you
can do because it's radio and unless you
can like somehow manufacture a Faraday
cage to go around your aircraft as its
flying into places it's not supposed to
fly like if it can be any more
conspicuous like maybe it shoots
fireworks at the same time yeah well the
main attack with GPS will be the
authentication the ground controller
from the drone and spoofing the GPS data
the GPS signal in order to steal the
drone so yeah yeah so basically problems
and deal with it
yeah it'll kill you with I'll return
home if you lose like if you really want
to ruin somebody's day you spray the
transmitter with 2.4 gig and you you Jam
the transmitter and when the aircraft
loses communications or the transmitter
it goes to return to home mode and the
aircraft goes oh I better I guess I
better go to my last known GPS location
and then in that condition you can just
conveniently send it out into the ocean
never to be seen again
or something or into a building or into
wherever but yeah if you control if you
can tell it where it thinks it is via
GPS and then you can create a condition
whereby it goes return to home then you
can absolutely exploit it that way yeah
and there's basically no defense so but
you made some tools for this so you were
creating some tools when you were doing
this I mean the only tool that is
already available is the parser for that
files while for the SDK I honestly
didn't build anything yeah it was just a
trial and error approach so I was just
recording a lot of packets from the
mobile application sent to the drone and
looking at the values of the packets in
order to trying to understand what was
changing so if you know
stick the common to make it fly
what buys change and whatever so yeah
it's just all right fair enough
do you have questions for the audience
there's a hand over there we got a
microphone
I think you've almost answered this
already but if you wanted to steal the
drone so you can jam the Wi-Fi on or
going to go home
are there any commercial drones that
don't do that like if they get their
Wi-Fi jammed out a sitting place or just
immediately go down to the ground I'm
sorry if you so if you Jam data 2.11
calif I though it'll go on to return
home mode and at that point you can
potentially spoof the GPS to get it to
come to you yeah so are there any
commercial drones that don't do return
to home if they lose their Wi-Fi link or
do they all do that
honestly I only tested DJI products so
DGI products is making the return to
home when you lose connection to their
own controller but I don't know for
other thanks more hands no
all right that pay Thank You Paolo
[Applause]