okay uh we're going to start start now
and we we have a couple of panelists who
will who will also join in a couple of
moments uh
my name is de souza and i'm a
postdoctoral researcher at tilburg
university and the panel this afternoon
is on regulating tech
sector transgressions in the eu before
we begin uh i wanted to mention that
that while while the panel speaks and
the panel title speaks about the eu the
conversation we're going to have today
is actually much broader and we have a
really
a wonderful set of speakers who come
from different parts of the world and
also with different expertise
but as we begin the conversation today i
want to say a little bit about the
project that we're working on at the
global data justice project which is on
sector transgressions the idea behind
sector transgressions
is to be able to track how firms that
establish themselves in one particular
sector use their computational
infrastructure to be able to
creep as well as pivot into a new kind
of sector uh we started the project
drawing from the work of tamashiron and
over the last year have been trying to
explore how these transgressions are not
one-off events but instead are events
that take place
over a period of time and end up
crowding out expertise of one of the
things that has struck us
in the past year is that
sector transgressions are different from
regular types of growth for businesses
different from innovation and what has
emerged is this idea that one it's a
context of the pandemic and the context
of timing
secondly
it's also a question of of how these
transgressions have taken place is it a
question of government invitation is it
a question of
companies being given legitimacy through
political connections and it's also a
question of how companies have used
their market to abuse uh positions of
dominance so
what we have uh today is
as a conversation which we hope will be
able to to understand the sec this
phenomena of sector transgressions
and and to see whether this phenomena
exists in different jurisdictions and
i'm really happy today to have uh
with us
uh
mariana really who is the general
project manager
at data privacy brazil uh i have urjdan
sabha who's a lecturer at the university
of amsterdam
i have aaron martin who works with me at
the global data justice project as well
as scott skinner thompson
who is an associate professor at the
university of colorado
uh law school and usha ramanathan who i
think will join us shortly who is an
independent research and human rights
activist in india
so what we hope today is to also look at
the question of what does sector
transgressions do in terms of the
dependencies it creates we're interested
in dependencies in terms of economic and
functional dependencies uh which results
in
how sort of power
concentrating emerges in in particular
spheres in terms of creating
infrastructures we're looking at ethics
transgressions where companies who do
not have the expertise are ending up
dominating how public sector questions
are sort of emerging for instance in the
question of public health we're also
looking at questions of political
dependencies and civic dependencies and
how we would like to structure the
conversation today is
around a series of questions we will
begin
by
and i would like to invite uh
mariana and then urjdan aaron and scott
uh
to reflect firstly on on how they see
the concept of sector transgressions in
their own work and in their own regions
and if they can do so by by starting
with an example of a case that they see
for instance in our work so far
uh which has been supported by the uai
fund one aspect that has emerged
repeatedly has been the ways in which
public health the public health sector
has been transgressed by security firms
such as palantir but also transgressions
taking place in edtech
transgressions that are also taking
place
in logistics and it's and these are some
of the sectors that we've been looking
at across nine countries in the eu and
we would also like this conversation to
to explore how
uh
similar similar transgressions are
taking place in different parts of the
world
so uh as we begin i'll invite mariana uh
to start
again over to you
hi can you guys hear me
hi um
good afternoon for me it's morning still
uh it's very good to be here thank you
for the invitation
and uh i'm like you have already
introduced me uh thanks for that but i'm
maria nahiali i work at a daily privacy
brazil
research association and
over the last few um
maybe a little over a year
we have been conducting research on the
it's hard to use the word legacy of
kovid because it's not over yet
but the idea
and the the the general initial idea of
this research
was to investigate how
government in brazil at all levels so
not just a federal government but also
at the state level and
the
municipal level um
has
adopted different types of data personal
data based technology to
fight covet uh 19
and we didn't really start with the idea
or with the concept of sector
transgression like in terms of our
methodology this was not something that
was necessarily in the picture
but
as the research progressed we
um
we had some
indications some
results
that are pointed in this direction and
we have actually engaged with the global
data justice project and with some of
you we have had conversations and even
inputs
into our research so to answer the
question i think in brazil this is
huge because
historically um
basically every social thought book
brazilian book
will say that the public in brazil is
private
and of course this doesn't have to do
necessarily with
companies but more with the dynamics of
these
players and how
these relationships developed over time
uh but
so so there are many possible examples
and i will keep to our own research
because this is where i think i have
more to contribute which is the
like i said the public health um sector
and we found that um
nearly 60 percent of all suppliers of
technology
to government like i said at all levels
are on the private sector mostly
technology companies
actually there is one company that
accounts for almost 20 percent of all
initiatives that we
were able to
map
and
um
we
we are still not i think at a point
where we can
say that um
there has been other there is there is
an actual transgression because we
haven't looked at the
the history perhaps and the journey of
these companies like
in their different sectors but we have
some um like i said indications
that this may be happening
um
and
these are
this is what has been moving us
towards continuing this research
and basically uh what we found was that
um
[Music]
the the three most uh common uh
functionalities because we maps
different functionalities so we're not
looking just at like contact tracing
we were looking at the broader uh
scenario and the three most common were
socialized isolation
monitoring
was the first one then uh tyler medicine
and
third was um
the
monitoring of a temperature temperature
use of thermal cameras
and there are big differences between
those three because the third one i
think it's very interesting that the
companies that are responsible are not
brazilian while the others are mostly
brazilian companies and in the case of
thermal technology and facial
recognition technology the companies are
mostly chinese
um
but
the thing that we noticed
was that the the
the arrangements the the contracts were
mostly
at no cost for the public entities and
this is something that appears a lot in
research
how these companies provide these
solutions without costs at first
and we are not at the point where we can
affirm that this will change but this is
also an indication of something that may
be happening and we are following this
closely so i think i'll stop here just
to
say that we are working on the public
health sector and of course another one
that is very important in brazil is
public security and we may
go into that
later but i'll start i was up here thank
you
thanks a lot mariana uh rajdan maybe if
i could ask you if if if you'd like to
also reflect on the phenomena of sector
transgressions and perhaps also connect
to uh as mariana mentioned the idea that
do you see this question of the public
being private also
in the regions that you've been looking
at
yeah so
thank you first of all thank you for
having me on this panel it's been very
interesting to
hear
marianna's reflection on the concept of
sector transgression because i can also
see some similarities there
with the global data justice associates
project which i'm working on which is
sector trans question in east africa
just a brief introduction there so in
partnership with uh data for change
this project looks at
cases of transgressive technologies in
ethiopia kenya and uganda and i was
humbled to work with kinfeilma
who are experts on law and tech and who
examine these cases and i think one
important thing is when we
make the concepts of sector
transcription go global
we also have to understand the position
of these visions in this highly
connected society
and what the researchers brought really
broadened the concept in two ways so
first of all it really put to the
forefront the
it did not only focus on tech firms but
also on this complex relation between
telecom and tech there was one one side
of it and the other side of it is that
it emphasized the role of development
agencies and tech philanthropy which
which is something that might not be as
visible if we look at that sector trans
question only from a high income country
perspective so one example there would
be that in ethiopia there is a project
called john snow which is a health
information system and it led the
pandemic response in many ways so they
monitored you know health sanitizers
availability tracked
health checks of
travelers entering ethiopia they
provided information about the the head
education through whatsapp helpline
and what's interesting here is that they
were brokered through usaid and they
worked closely with the bill and melinda
gates foundation
and
above all this this jon snow uh
firm
did not start with the pandemic it
predated the pandemic started in
2015 uh
under the under the you know
the idea of providing a health
information system in ethiopia and
because ethiopia has this long-standing
relationship with international partners
and it was not framed in terms of you
know pandemic response back then but it
was framed in terms of digital inclusion
and in terms of you know economic
development so that is to say that you
know when we look at sector
transgression we also see that it's
continuation
of things that have been happening in
the past
thanks a lot
i think you bring up an important
distinction with with also how the
project has has been framed in the in
the eu with the focus on the pandemic
and and the changes that have taken
place there but to sort of speak to a
longer a longer narrative and and i
think this is also a good opportunity to
bring in usher ramanathan um
we've been talking about how in
different regions of the world the the
phenomena of sector transgressions
manifests in different ways and also
manifests at different points in time
and i was wondering if you could share
uh
from india uh how do you see this uh
this phenomena emerging is it something
that has been around for a while and
when have you seen any sort of important
examples in the last couple of years
during the pandemic that that have been
different from from the past
we can't hear you
there's a speaker right at the bottom of
the screen
and now yes perfect yeah
okay
okay i'm a little uh
nervous about
entering this conversation because i'm
not sure i've understood
uh
sectoral transgression correctly
so let's just say i'm giving another
take on it yeah so
uh
if it is about
see one of the things we i think we
spoke about it the last time too that
technology persons and technology and
people who are
leveraging technology for their business
are
not satisfied with finding an area where
they can be they are very keen to
take as much as they can because tech
now is not about any sector it's about
data
and data from any sector is exciting
for them so there is there are no
boundaries in this
second thing in india it's
i'm sure there are other countries like
this where the relationship between uh
tech com you know tech interests i won't
call them companies they are tech
interests and
the government
uh
it's very close so there are things that
take uh you know the tech interest
promises the state and you know promises
the government and the government
uh
creates a good ambiance for
take for the tech interest to do
whatever it is that they want to do
in india it is represented most darkly
and most clearly in this thing called
the iceberg
which is the
uh
it's an industry roundtable it's like we
had the nashcom which was made up of or
you know it was a association of all the
big tech companies
and then they decided that you know some
of the smaller guys needed to come in
and it you know it shouldn't be just
amazon and facebook and google and what
have you so they thought that they would
create other products
so the whole thing became about creating
products for the first one when they
first began and then it got hijacked by
the id project that we had
and creating what they called were
stacks
so these stacks are not these stacks are
applications and they can and the idea
was that we'll create a platform
and
the the and it'll create the
infrastructure and anybody can use it
to create any kind of business that they
want so actually i'm not sure therefore
that they really
that the companies have been necessarily
looking at it as something that is
sectoral but the state has been looking
to bring everything on to these so that
data can be collected from everywhere
it's using the muscle power of the state
to be able to collect data from so if i
was just to give a few illustrative
things it's now in agriculture
it's in finance it's the fintech and but
it's not only fintech it's also the
whole welfare state is done only through
this
it's in fast tag which is the toll
collection
it is in registration of driving
licenses and in registration of vehicles
which are which data by the way is what
they've told them in parliament that
they're selling this data for a certain
sum
most recently they've been saying they
want to link up the voter id
with the id database
it's in
the corvin app which is supposed to be
holding all the information
on uh
you know you can only get yourself
vaccinated if you go through the
covenant or whoever vaccinates you will
have to put you on the covenant and
there is a set of information that's
held there which then converts itself
into a
health id if you give your uid along and
if you give the id along with it
there's a social security quote which
says that all unorganized sector people
have to get themselves onto this
database with a whole range of
information including the tax
information and
you know the id information and the
telephone number and all the rest of it
if they are to get anything at all if
the state at any time decides that they
want to help them through a time of
distress
so this is just a continued distress has
provided an opportunity to speed these
things up and to use more coercion
and to threaten exclusion but this is a
pattern that we've been seeing over the
past
past 10 years
just two things that were that seemed
pretty interesting one is that you know
we have this id system the uid system
which was done
like a
joint kind of thing between private
industry by bringing in a marketing
honcho from within
tech industry and the government and
they
the whole project was run through this
now it's about 11 years 12 yeah it's
about 12 years since the project began
and they had in november
a meeting where
two of the guys who are i mean all of
them spoke but in one session which was
on digital economy
you had
the two people who were from government
and who had worked on this id project
speaking there and saying
that
this project had actually been promoted
saying that this is so that the poor can
have an identity and they should be able
to get their whatever they've been you
know whatever is due to them
so you have them now saying that listen
this was never about the state it was
never for the government
it was for creating a digital economy
and it's got hijacked by the state and
they are holding it captive
so there is a there is a way in which
they saying that the state's job was
just to create these databases so that
we can create businesses out of it so
that the general gdp will go up and this
is not the first time they are doing it
this it happened earlier when they said
that privacy is not a fundamental right
it's not a right at all
because if it's going to be a right it's
going to be a problem
so just uh one
uh
one thing therefore is that the i think
the place where we are seeing
a large number of players come in and
there is a certain amount of anxiety
which we can see around us now
apart from the fact of being in all
these various databases and having to
identify yourself through them and be
watched by somebody else who you don't
know
apart from all of that the fintech
explosion particularly
is causing an enormous amount of anxiety
because various people are getting onto
it i mean we tech people are getting on
to the fintech revolution which
basically they're looking at banks and
their legacy data and wanting to use the
data and make what they believe it
they've created a
money movement
agency which is outside of government
and outside most regulations so that and
the government has been
the prime mover i mean the prime
marketer of that and the prime minister
has been the prime marketer
so
and in this in each of these especially
in the fintech sector you find that
amazon and google and facebook and
everybody has walked in
so while the intention apparently is to
say that you know we need our own we
need to make our own businesses and we
can't
rely on advertising because we don't
have that kind of budgets here
but we do need all these databases and
they should be ours which means the
indian tech interest
ours is not the people of india and is
the indian tech interest and therefore
you know we need to fight off all these
amazons and googles and whoever else
actually they're creating you know
various scenarios where those guys come
and do the
major part of the business
so this is the kind of semi-complex
scene that we are in now and i'm not
sure if this is what you meant but this
is i think obsessing my head so i just
said it
thanks a lot i think i i i think you
also raise a question and and and maybe
aaron you can come in here but about how
useful uh the idea of sectors is to
think about uh transgressions as you say
so maybe that's one thing aaron that you
can begin with but also the second
aspect that you raise about about the
question of state capture
and the capture of state institutions
and what this actually means for the
dependency of
of of the public sector
um aaron perhaps if you could share from
uh
from the work that is being done in the
eu if if you see similar questions in
margin sure
thank you siddharth can you hear me
yeah
no so it's actually a great time for me
to sort of react to the conversation so
far and indeed one of the questions
we're grappling with in the eu focus
component of the of the research is
whether it still makes sense to talk
about the tech sector as a sort of
distinct area
of innovation um
sort of business growth
weather you know over the past sort of
ten years and in particular during the
pandemic uh we've seen the sort of tech
sector invade pretty much any every
other sector
um that matters uh especially from a
regulatory perspective and i don't think
we've sort of come to a sort of final
answer on this we're still debating
internally whether
um
there's value and still
holding on to this notion of a
distinct tech sector in particular
because
um at least for me at least i have a
fear that one when we kind of say that
the tech sector is everywhere that the
amazons of the world that the googles of
the world are basically like uh they're
no longer tech firms that they're sort
of you know um
these these monsters that that operate
across sectors that we we kind of lose
side we can can can can sort of sharpen
our our hooks in terms of regulation um
there's a lot of regulatory activity in
europe in particular around as we
discussed today digital services digital
markets
the governance of data of different
kinds
and i think it helps at the starting
point for a lot of those conversations
is this collective understanding that
that the tech sector is a thing right
that it's not uh that it's not a sort of
uh a figment of of of the past um and
that we can identify actors within
both the sort of regulatory community
but i think more broadly civil society
that can uh help to rein in uh
particularly transgressive behavior by
by tech companies right even though they
operate in for example finance um
education
agriculture increasingly and so forth so
um i think this notion of you know
what is the tech sector still and does
it make sense to
um to conceive of some of these issues
as being sort of tech driven uh is an
important one but also want to react to
something that mariana said and i think
this is where this question of sort of
what can be done and what's the role of
sort of civil society and other
actors is quite important so she
mentioned that
in brazil a lot of the innovation during
the pandemic
um was by sort of firms uh
using sort of chinese sort of
innovations of different kinds and i
find this sort of this question of like
the the geopolitical interests
um and and sort of suspicions or
concerns around uh the
sort of the
national homes of certain tech companies
important because at least in europe we
see that there's still this push against
american and silicon valley in
particular uh
interests although the problems are much
broader but i think elsewhere in the
world there is this concern around china
india as well um and i think where
where we can use some of those um
national interests or or concerns around
the geopolitics of technology in order
to resist this the sort of expansion of
um
dare i say illegitimate technology or or
technology that perhaps uh has been
developed
a vacuum
during during the pandemic um where
perhaps you know we haven't
uh followed all the procurement
procedures for different reasons where
we still have an answer to some
questions around accountability
um
exclusion
so forth it's sometimes nice to have the
geopolitical card to play right where we
can at least use that as a way to to
push back certain kinds of
um behavior by by the sector as it were
and just one final point if i may said
arts
this um this question of no cost
contracts i think is really
just a brazilian phenomenon it's
something we've seen in europe as well
um and this is actually where it becomes
a lot harder to understand what's
happening
in terms of government procurement of
systems because
uh
at least when you know there's
contracting in place where governments
are paying for for systems and services
we have the paper trail we have the the
due diligence that's required um for for
government spend and where things are
being offered for free we see this a lot
in the humanitarian sector as well that
makes it much harder to understand um
you know the sort of the the terms of
agreements uh there's a lot of see
because things are offered for free um
and i'm i'm sort of hoping that we can
think further about what does it mean to
offer sort of a
a platform or a stage uh during an
emergency context in an emergency
context rather
even for a temporary period uh at no
cost
and then you know what what that sort of
allows for
push back
um transparency
uh and resistance uh by by range of
actors so i hope that helps in terms of
reaction to the points made so far
thanks aaron and and scott maybe i'd
like to bring you here to also react to
a point that aaron made towards the end
of this idea of of illegitimate
technology uh whether it's to do with
questions of procurement whether it's to
do with the ways in which uh
accountability is sort of these
organizations and i was wondering in in
your uh reflections on on on tech
expansion during the pandemic um how
would you sort of distinguish
transgressions from from from from
innovative activities from business as
usual and what is an effective counter
to this understanding that that the ways
in which
text
companies are actually moving into new
areas of business is is part and parcel
of their business model
uh thanks thanks so much uh
siddhartha and thanks to to everybody um
it's really uh great to be part of this
conversation and i believe we're on at
least four different continents at the
moment which is uh
um
which is pretty exciting uh
i i the the conversation's really
interesting i think i think that my um
[Music]
my initial reactions and this is not to
suggest that that government
surveillance is indeed um
better than this privatized capitalist
surveillance that we're seeing um grow
with and accelerate because of the
conditions of the pandemic but i do
think that one background condition um
that has enabled this
uh
privatized um surveillance creep or
transgressions is is the the
is the the norm of neoliberalism and the
the the failure of uh um
governments to be in the business of
providing services anymore and so i i
think that that background condition is
one that we need to
bear in mind because it is the one you
know
all of these different examples and
there are some really good ones
are enabled by the the failure of
government uh to to do its job edtech is
a good example
schools do not have the resources to
serve children so google comes in and
says here's a chromebook you know and
and
and and start surveilling our our
children um
and this is true in any of the exam any
of the you know if we're talking about
contract tracing whatever um
it's the failure of government
which has been primed
which which
exists in part because of the tech
company's ethos of deregulation of
privatization not just tech companies
but obviously corporations across the
board that has
created uh this this gap in governance
and services which is in turn um allow
these transgressions uh to accelerate
with uh
you know dramatic fashion um
and so i think that that is important
which is you know i i think we have to
attack these uh you know attack but um
call out and and combat these symptoms
but i do think it's important to to to
realize this is part of a broader
phenomenon of
neoliberalism and privatization um and i
think this relates very closely and and
and is potentially you know one
solution
building off of um aaron's point about
geopolitics and i think we have to be
careful here not to be
i'm not suggesting this is where aaron
was headed but but be careful not to be
you know sort of nativist in our
approach to
to these discussions but at the same
time to the extent that there is an
opportunity to suggest to countries okay
if you care about your sovereignty right
then one way in which to protect that
sovereignty is to be in the position in
the business of providing um government
services yourself so that when there is
a crisis you do not have to depend on
either
private or public goods from uh another
country um whether whether that be you
know
my you know
my neighbors to the west in in silicon
valley or um uh uh china um
and so i think that that's that's a
potential uh uh you know
helpful linking of those um
issues so
those are sort of my initial uh thoughts
um
i i do think the concept is
is really helpful from a descriptive
standpoint
to help understand
the degree to which um
you know companies and and again to
other people's points not just tech
companies but many companies now are
surveillance capitalists and um the the
commodity is um
information and surveillance i would i
in terms of you know shaping norms right
we've allowed ourselves to be shaped by
some of these companies
and and i think we need to
resist some of the nomenclature that
they've imposed on us um at turns and so
even you know the idea that these are no
cost no cost contracts or free it is
just it's just inaccurate from from a
descriptive standpoint like that
you know the old saying is nothing in
life is free right and it's not free
right there's a huge cost and so i think
we need to um
be sure when we're labeling them to say
you know they're they're the ones that
want this right and that's because they
are
um extraction in industries extracting
information and um
so what what do they need to provide in
exchange for that um extraction um
so those are my initial thoughts but i
really i'm really happy to be part of
the conversation and look forward to
learning more thank you
thanks a lot uh scott um mariana if i
can bring you back into the conversation
and
maybe to also speak to the to to one of
the points that that's got made in terms
of of thinking about institutional and
public sector responses particularly as
as he describes when when when
government capacity is is
is is non-existent in in in certain
domains uh in in in brazil and in the
work that that that you're doing
what role do you see
for us for civil society and for for
regulators to be able to
to respond both it and in times of a
pandemic but also uh in terms of a
longer or
a longer sort of more embedded response
to the fact that institutional
capacities need to be strengthened
thanks um
okay so
lots of things that i want to react to
and i will try
uh to do my best
i think this this issue of uh the
public sector um inability or lack of
resource
to provide i'm sorry there's a noise
here please let me know if you can hear
me i will
try to move closer
and
there is the this issue in brazil now
that um the government is active
actively trying to
kill the population so
it's not just the lack of resource or
lack of capacity there's also a
political project and the pandemic
showed how
the government was actually trying to
divert attention and to not
uh
act in any
reasonable way
so it's kind of hard like right now
to understand how all these um
many um
issues play out but
what i was i think going to say and like
kind of trying to answer your question
about civil society
um the main problem the main um
limits the main difficulty that we faced
with this research was
a transparency one both public and
private transparency because we were
researching um
technologies that had been acquired
by governments and that even though we
are in a pandemic and there have been
some um there is some level of
flexibilization in terms of
um
the the
public procurement uh
the the the thing is that after
a year of research and over
600 uh freedom of information
act requests and lots of other um
attempts to gather information
and together uh
these contracts disagreements at the end
we were able to um
acquire only half of all the
the initiatives that we know that took
place because there there was uh talk in
the media or even by government
officials but we were never able to
locate
uh the
so it's not just the no cost
uh issue and the inability to
have this paper trail but like we
it's it's before we couldn't even access
like the basic um outline of the of this
agreements and this is a huge problem
because we can't say that it's something
that the private sector is uh
responsible for or or the public sector
is re actually the public sector is
responsible for in this case um and so
what we what we thought was more um
useful and perhaps as a strategy to
engage civil society and other
organizations around this issue was to
talk about transparency
because uh
people were more um
impressed and and the impact was a
greater when we said look we know their
things are happening but we don't know
exactly
what they are because we can have access
to like
like the basics something that should be
public and we can't access that and this
has garnered more attention and then we
were able to go further into the
discussions of
um
of the the actual numbers and the
sectors that are involved and issues of
privacy data protection surveillance we
started with the transparency thing
because this is something that brazilian
civil society
in the
last i don't know 10 years maybe has
been
very um
has been following very closely
so i don't know this is just an example
of something that we use to
garner attention and to engage people uh
around this subject because
like in a scenario in brazil where
civil society is faced with and
not just brazil everywhere but with so
many
problems and the government itself is
always trying to divert attention and
show
it's very hard sometimes to
make people care about these things
especially when there's this um
framing of um
innovation and of something that can
actually be good and people don't
understand the implications
so
i don't know i i just thought it would
be useful to bring this experience to
the table and
uh but it's something that is very uh we
still have a lot of work to do
so thanks this is really helpful both in
terms of how you articulate the
challenges of actually trying to do a
monitoring and
uh
accounting off of government and
government in departments but also the
framing of
of such responses in terms of
transparency
uh in order to build solidarity amongst
different organizations
would this be something that you also
see
in terms of civil society responses or
have there been other ways in which
civil society responses have been framed
in response to
tech expansionism
[Music]
yeah so um i can recognize the problem
of opacity as something that we also see
in our research so
yeah advocating for transparency and
making sure that the problem is there to
the public eye
is important so i'll talk as a
researcher on academic i think also
extending the scope and making it global
and going beyond fragments of privacy
and ethics can also help in this
scenario because it allows us to make
visible these other actors and also
identify when we can take actionable
tasks and i think
another thing because this sector
transgression happened in the in the
perceived emergency and
uh they they they
rise from a pandemic we could also um
pay attention to where this rhetoric has
been used before so in um
yeah in regions where digital
humanitarians and flourish so zones of
conflict places that are considered as
perhaps economically or politically
unstable or
border zones and then we can learn from
uh grassroots movements there on how
they were directly impacted by these
transgressive uh technologies
and uh learn from their experience and
see how perhaps they resisted or
subverted um
subverted these trends and i think this
is particularly important because we i
feel like we're going to be heading
toward a lot of other emergencies and
with the with the with the with the
problems that we will be facing with
climate change so i think
to have a more robust institutional
response is to also listen to to
grassroots movement and learn from from
their activities yeah
thank you uh usha you want to also come
in here and
on the point of civil society responses
both in terms of challenges of of of how
to respond and also what possible
framings could be
yeah
it's actually a little complex here i
think i mean differently complex it's
not any more or less complex it's
terribly complex everywhere but
i think it's a little different in the
sense that
when we address
the tech issues here we are addressing
the state much more than we are
addressing the companies
because the companies are acting through
the state
and the
what the these the obvious surveillance
is being done by the state with the help
of these
technology companies and i was thinking
when you know on the question of
sovereignty for instance i think our and
you said this
i was thinking that actually it's very
difficult here because you know even in
our
even in some of the major state projects
that they have which is which are
surveillance projects
they're not able to find the state is
not able to find
uh people who will join the state i mean
join a take up a job with the state
to
for instance be a security officer who
will make sure that data security is
maintained so they have to then
you know give this work out it's all
about startup
and
you know giving the work out to
everybody else
so it's not about establishing systems
as much as being opportunistic and
that's the way we are now so the
the way to do it is
in a short time get as much as you can
put it all together because the
unfortunately it's like a
rush to the bottom
so it's also saying it's also a
competition with the really bad guys i
mean you're talking about training in
the power of all these big corporations
and if you're competing to say okay i
can't have that kind of power so i'll
find another kind of power that will
compete with
with this power then you know it's so
for civil society the
uh when you're addressing the state and
the state doesn't listen and the state
has the power to coerce to mandate to do
whatever it wants it's one kind of
problem that we are faced with but i
think the good thing that i'm seeing now
and i think i hear it in many of the
meetings is that there is a greater
awareness
that these are problems earlier it was
you know seeing tech as a problem
because it seemed so obscure
it was hidden it wasn't that clear but
increasingly we are hearing people
saying listen we do need to do you know
we can't just walk into this with our
eyes shut
so that's been one good thing and then
there are groups that have formed over
this you know over the past 10 years
which are making legal cases out of many
of these and they are really working at
uh pushing back they're working at uh
you know getting
the courts and judges to understand and
that's a huge problem because you know
we go through so many discussions to
understand what we are
faced with and judges just have to hear
it from lawyers who themselves have no
clue and you have to be training them on
you know what needs to be so it's a real
uh
it's not a happy place to be but
people are working at it and lawyers are
getting trained in understanding
technology the younger lord
and that's a huge help so there's more
discussion
but uh
the unfortunate thing and i think
sometimes we might need to make this
linked to and i mean i'm sure we have it
i'm saying that between philanthropy
you know who are the richest guys today
who is giving the money and what are
they giving the money for and what what
do they ask in return
i think that's clearing the pitch quite
a lot and i think we you know we need to
figure out what to do about that because
if you look there is a recent article
where
the chap has written about
all the things that have happened on
this india stack kind of thing which is
what all these applications are that are
being created all of them all of them
are being done by a tech baron who's got
pots of money and who's therefore
get you know getting people on to do
this create all these products and then
he has access to the state and he what
his in his language he evangelizes it to
the state
so
then we are stuck with
you know
and there is a huge crackdown in india
on people getting funds
so it's like it's a lot of things coming
together therefore when you say trans
you know in intersector when it's really
like superbly intersect
so one last one word if i my just as a
thing because i'm very curious about
this thing of innovation
and the idea that
you know we are all
rights activists in in many ways
but the idea that therefore the
corporate entity should have more rights
than all of us should have and that they
will have the right not just to innovate
but to roll it out in our midst without
any kind of
uh you know without
asking us without
you know figuring out how it matters no
moratorium no licensing no nothing
anything goes
i think this uh
you know i idealizing of
innovation maybe we need to
juggle that a bit and see what it really
means
it's not the individual it's about power
[Music]
thanks thanks for bringing that point up
and maybe this is something that scott
you'd like to respond to and the
question of
of innovation as power and it was it
also links to the questions that you
spoke of before about government
capacity
well thanks yeah i think it's a really
important point um
and i
i
i i do think that there is an inertia
um
both rhetorically and and in terms of um
all sorts of structures in in favor
that
compel innovation uh sometimes for the
sake of innovation without um any sort
of uh deliberation
um
or democratic input on
on whether that innovation is harmful or
not um
the the as issue was was talking the key
example that came to my mind from the
american context was
the rapid
proliferation of um policeworn body
cameras that we've seen in the united
states over just a really short period
of time
and right and in that
context you know civil rights groups are
are are not of one mind on whether or
not this is a
a an important check on
um
uh
you know
state power and racism or or not
but um what we've seen is
you know
pilot programs um
and uh you know they're sort of rolled
out
in fast
at a fast pace um sometimes civil
society is galvanized to work with the
state um to legitimize that
um
and
um you know the the response is is bit
more nuanced than the state uh might
lead us to believe in so one example is
that in new york city where the when
they were um
a few years ago rolling out their body
camera
pilot program which of course is is is a
product of
partnering with the private sector and
companies like palantir and
axios
they they surveyed a bunch of new
yorkers and you know the new yorkers
including new yorkers from from diverse
uh backgrounds and their their responses
to
you know the conditions under which this
technology should be uh deployed we're
were very nuanced right you know they
had strong views about um when the
cameras should be
activated and when not and access to uh
the videos after the fact and who who
you know when officers should be able to
review the uh videos um and so it wasn't
a sort of blank check right that the the
civil society and the public gave to the
deployment of this
this innovation
but new york city ran with the top-line
response which was uh you know people
approve of body cameras okay
the conditions under which they approved
of them were extremely multi-faceted
and the conditions in under which new
york city deployed them were not
in alignment with those nuanced
perspectives right and so the top line
was taken legitimized the innovation and
then the innovation was deployed and now
of course you know are there examples
where police body cameras have um
captured police brutality
and um been used to uh you know at least
momentarily garner some measure of
accountability for individual officers
yes there are examples of that are there
also examples where this is
being used as a as a you know
innovative surveillance tool which is
further subjugating marginalized
communities
of course
and so um you know i think sometimes the
unit we see the innovation as a quick
fix to the problem oh
how do we deal with police brutality
well let's get this video camera out
well the background question is we have
structural racism oppression and a video
camera is not going to fix those
conditions right but we we just latch on
to the innovation as usual suggestion
uh suggesting as as a quick fix to
long-standing structural problems and
then we use
civil society and you know quick
basically crowdsourcing of public input
to legitimize that innovation when in
reality the public response to that
innovation is is far more complex
than than we may be led to believe
thanks a lot scott i think those
examples are uh are really compelling
also to sort of problematize this whole
idea of of innovation since we're almost
at time uh i'd like to do a one round of
uh
final reactions uh from our panel and
maybe i can start with you aaron
thank you siddharth and just to to
reiterate scott's points uh around sort
of the
um
this this idea that sort of text will
tech will solve all of our problems i
agree 100
i mean i think we all agree here that
it's uh it's quite easy and dare i say
lazy sometimes to rely on technology or
to expect technology to
solve deep or structural uh problems i
mean his previous point around um the
context in which you know some of these
uh sort of pandemic related technologies
were being deployed in the u.s
um really points to like for example the
need to
to address tax policy right like and to
to ask hard questions about the
availability of public sector funding to
uh
to to respond to emergencies like uh
coped 19 but of course those are
uh not only harder sort of uh problems
to solve but i dare say sort of
politicize in in different ways um and
so technology certainly isn't the
solution to most of our problems if any
of them i will also just sort of uh
close by reflecting on
i think
related to the politics of this question
of innovation and resistance innovation
uh in the context of the pandemic i'm
reminded that we often find ourselves
among strange bedfellows uh just last
weekend
was a big protest in brussels against uh
in particular sort of use of digital
vaccination
certificates
for accessing restaurants and and bars
and so forth and while i think many of
us here would probably have you know
questions around for example um
the
sort of legitimacy of certain
technological interventions uh questions
of you know the sort of the providers of
the the platforms that are being used
for vaccination certificates in
different countries um
i imagine most of so generally be sort
of um in favor of the use of you know
certain sorts of technological measures
to manage public health uh to reduce
risk of coronavirus et cetera so i think
it's it's uh
what i'm trying to say is it's it's not
that we're anti-tech or anti-innovation
in our line of thinking in this project
but we're asking questions about
you know when does innovation become it
and what makes a technological
innovation in particular one
that's provided exclusively by the
private sector uh legitimate or not um
so i hope that's helpful thank you very
much
thanks a lot aaron uh mariana would you
like to
add some concluding thoughts
yes so i think i would just like to
thank you all and say that
in one hour i have a lot of questions
and
a lot of
things that uh i want to reflect on and
also at the privacy brazil we will keep
working on them and we hope that we will
be able to
continue this conversation for example
on the
um
on whether we should um make this this
distinction of the tech sector i think
this is
a very hard question that made me think
a lot during the webinar and i have some
thoughts on that and i think we at data
privacy as well uh considering the
brazilian scenario and we would of
course like to continue this
conversation thank you very much
to all
what's done
so some concluding remarks i wanna well
i wanna thank you for this insightful
conversation i think this made us all
reflect on
um what was known as perhaps techno
solutionism and how it progressed and
how we we see this you know tech firms
gaining more
power and control here and
and yeah i'm looking forward to to
to carrying on this conversation with
you all thanks
thank you uh russia would you like to go
next
just two things if i can come back to
one is like is a kind of response to
what adam said
uh on the
on this uh vaccination
uh database
i actually have not defensive at all
about opposing a global database on
vaccination and asking that we should be
showing this wherever we go
because i don't see the agenda as being
vaccination and health safety at all
i think it's an opportunity that's being
created because actually we don't know
enough about the virus we don't know
enough about the vaccination i think
science should focus on that
and not allow
tech czars to want us on
a global database and i mean i can give
you illustrations earlier of how they've
actually spoken about this ambition of
having everyone on the global database i
really think i mean i'm really not
defensive at all about it i think
such a database should not exist
and the second slight thing is that it's
on disruption
uh it's actually quite interesting to
see what happens here you know
disruption
was meant to disrupt morrigan systems
but they've actually become like burning
the boats so you burn your boat so that
you have to get on to the system that i
am providing for you now whether it
works for you or not and whether it
destroys all your rights or not so i
think the just like we interrogate the
idea of innovation maybe we need to
interrogate the idea of deception also
thank you
oh and finally scott
oh gosh well it was a great conversation
i don't have uh much further to add i
azusha
you know this this final
point about the vaccine um
uh databases i uh
something i
need to give more thought about but i i
will say
one you know
again the impulse to track right like oh
we need to verify who has a vaccine or
not
part of the
issue is that our social fat the reason
why we think we need that or why some
people think we need that
is is because we the social fabric
in many contexts certainly in the united
states context
is so um
so sprayed
that there's an incredible lack of trust
among
people among communities
between among each other and between the
people and and the government that we
think that um that sort of command and
control approach is the only thing
to the extent that my remarks have a
theme is that there's this background
problem
um
that i think are so closely related to
the surveillance issues um
uh that um and i don't have solutions
for them but i think that they are are
are influencing the conversation in
important ways but thank you again
um of you learned a great uh deal
[Music]
yes thank you so much everyone i think
this is this is a a very quick one hour
but it i think we covered a lot of
ground i think there's several questions
that you've raised in your final remarks
starting from the question of whether
uh tech is a sector
the question of of whether sector is
actually a useful way of of discussing
such transgressions the ways in which we
can problematize innovation problematize
uh disruption and also think about what
are the ways and and what are the
challenges that actually emerge when we
are creating a public sector
dependencies and also
enhancing obesity through the ways in
which
this ecosystem around
having private sector
offer public services um creates so
thank you so much and thank you so much
to the organizers at privacy cam for
giving us this opportunity and uh yeah
we're going to post a link to our work
in case you are interested
and would like to follow it we will have
a report coming out in a couple of
months
thank you again
you