good morning everybody thank you so much
jen for this introduction and welcome to
the first session of this privacy camp
i'm gonna call to join me on the virtual
stage the speakers of to this final
noemie levant from la cuadra batter
rena tangens from digital garage and
patrick vaya
a member of the european parliament
the time to join i'm gonna introduce a
little bit what we're gonna talk in this
room uh today uh
it's not a session where we're gonna
analyze what has been going on on data
retention um on the political and
legislative stages so to say there's
been already quite a few events about
like thinking what has been done in the
past years in terms of case law
in terms of litigation
by civil society groups now here we what
we want to do is really to focus on
action mobilization what can be done in
the next stages
and in the next years as civil society
to combat new initiative
uh new
laws at national and eu levels that will
be proposed uh to maintain either data
retention regime that exists
or to propose new type of
mass surveillance
type of regimes
like in many eu countries now
the idea is that we collectively
brainstorm about
the next step or how civil society also
said he can mobilize uh people against
their attention
um it's still like a big
challenge when we think about data
retention uh and explain it to a
lay person on the street how it can
impact her or him
and this is something we need to
collectively think about because the
story is not
at the end unfortunately although we
thought it would
after the the last uh court of justice
uh
case law uh and case
um and for that we will reflect uh with
our speaker about the state of play
um we will think about what are the
current challenges what has changed in
the past 10 years or maybe 20 years on
this topic
how can we approach it from a different
perspective maybe to be more effective
um and for that maybe it's a good idea
that with our speakers we reflect on the
past
uh what we have done in the past that
has worked what has worked less uh how
we can improve things
and we can also start like brainstorming
collectively what what about what can we
be
doing in the future in the coming years
um
so for that
i will be accompanied by
patrick breyer
if he's here
i hope i have my speakers
rena hangins you can all like switch
uh maybe while the technical issues are
being sold guillermo can i
ask the public who they are maybe
like
are the polling questions ready
few seconds
yeah i just i just would like to invite
the people
to the stage
hi
hello
i had some issue with my camera and i'm
here it's okay it's the first
session look at my face
it's still the morning
thank you hi rena
hi
and while we're waiting for patrick i
think patrick is joining us
as well
um
i wanted to ask a little bit who we have
in the
in the public to see like
what kind of like people are following
us this morning and whether they can
participate uh in the brainstorm
um so i prepared some questions to you
if it's possible to share them in the
chat um
i directed myself to the yeah exactly
have you ever worked on their attention
yes or no
ah so uh
a third
approximately of the people of the
viewers have already worked on it
uh two two-third actually not
um
the next question then is dependent on
the first question so i'm addressing the
the the one-third um
who already worked on data retention
with the second question i wanted to
know
like
how for how long have you worked on it
like is it like less than three five
years yeah you're
oh only one person could actually answer
this is too bad
that was too fast
sorry
no problem
this is the testing session
you haven't been told
too early in the morning exactly
so for those of you who already worked
on it
for how long have you been working on it
is interesting the the interest we have
is that because the in this question is
that
some of our speakers have really long
term experience i'm looking at you rena
and
some maybe less
and it's interesting because you're
coming from different perspective
different goals
okay uh among the people who said they
worked on it um
some of them
worked less than five years
uh
and more than ten years so we have like
the two extreme
uh it's not super representative
obviously but uh still interesting to
know and the last question for me was to
know
from which angle did you approach this
topic
um like was it mainly
like artistic engagement or was it like
more advocacy so if the
the last question could be asked hi
patrick
yeah everybody is here now
cool i'm just asking the last question
to
the people in the public who had the
chance to worked on data retention
before
[Music]
yeah so
what i wanted to know is
from those of you who worked on it and
it's fine if you didn't in the past
there's still a chance to catch up and
we need all the energy possible on this
topic but from those of you who worked
on that our attention before was it
where did you started working on it like
mainly advocacy working towards
legislative change mainly research maybe
in academia
mainly tech self-defense let's say like
finding solutions to
work against
the retention of your personal data
or mainly campaign you organize protests
on the streets again like on this topic
um or any other and if you have like
where you've done something other than
that
um please share it in this in the chat
i really encourage like all of you all
the viewers to
use the chat during the session to share
your experience and share maybe if even
if you haven't worked on data retention
but you've been
campaigning or working on a specific
topic related to surveillance
do not hesitate to to share it
uh once the results are in on the chat
uh i'll consult them and the speakers as
well but i think this is good for the
speakers to know who uh he's following
us
we could i i'm gonna actually head and
give the floor uh to patrick um because
the in the first stage i just wanted we
just wanted to
uh remind everybody what the state of
play is so we actually shared the same
level of knowledge about what has been
going on on data retention in the past
years
um so
i think it's good that we go over
uh
what happened uh we thought we won on it
we thought we had a big case we we
almost did it
uh and now actually it's starting all
over again why is
this topic still important today patrick
and could you
summarize for us the latest
political
steps we saw
of course good morning thank you for
organizing this panel and i'm glad that
we have
activists among our listeners so many
who have been engaged in in this fight
for so long as i can tell
from the poll so it's wonderful to be
having this panel and wonderful
panelists and um it's a good time to to
discuss data retention
just to remind you
what's so special about
data retention in comparison to storage
of other kinds of data it is just simply
information that reflects our daily
communications
and our daily movements
and also the ip addresses that we use on
the internet that can be used to
reconstruct our online activities
so
unlike with other data it is very
comprehensive it
exposes your social network it exposes
um
our personal connections and and
problems and possibly
um it allows
forecast your behavior to deduce
patterns movements etc so it's extremely
sensitive data and it's being retained
without any business need or any other
necessity to do so
so that's why
the european court of justice decided in
a landmark
decision a digital rights island
that it is
sorry i think we lost the image is it
better now
yeah and i think you worked out for a
few seconds just the last sentence where
okay
the the eu court of justice decided it's
not proportionate to
retain and and collect information about
the communications and locations of the
entire population
that are completely unconnected to any
crime whatsoever
just because they might be of interest
in the future
and that was really
a landmark decision but it was never
really implemented
except maybe in those countries where
the specific decision was taken but not
even there so in ireland for example
they still have indescribable data
retention in place
and um
so basically member states refused to
to heed it to implement it and the
commission refuses to enforce it because
the commission is of a different view
itself in fact even the european data
protection supervisor in those court
proceedings argued something along the
lines that
the retention is not the problem it's
about the axis which is not true because
the it's the retention that has the
chilling effect
the knowledge that
your communications your behavior could
be used against you that is what has the
chilling effect
and yet um member states ignored it and
challenged it
and
what happened was that they did actually
manage
that the court um watch it down
um it's just prudence in its case law
and in the latest decision
allowed for a measure of
of um
data retention
where in case of a threat to national
security
um which is used by france for example
to argue well we have a permanent threat
to our national security and so we'll
just retain everything all the time and
of course we'll allow prosecutors to use
it for prosecuting crime as well
they have allowed for the so-called
targeted data retention so you can
retain data in certain areas
and that is being used
by member states such as denmark or
belgium
um to have basically um you know 80
percent or 90 of the country covered
um with some reasons above average crime
rate that there are railway stations
whatever you have it
and
basically it means that in those
countries
um
people are nearly as exposed to having
the data retained as
according to the indiscriminate
and
also they allowed for indiscriminate
retention of ip addresses even so that
allows for reconstruction of um
of the online activities in combination
with the log files that are being kept
and
what happened last last year what was
revealed was that the commission
already released a paper to propose to
member states how they could bring back
data retention
in line with the court requirements by
interpreting them very extensively
and
the only reason why member states are
not enthusiastic about it is that they
basically would prefer to ignore the
code rulings altogether and go along
with the existing law indiscriminate and
for all data types
and
so there is a threat that despite some
positive developments such as in the
german coalition
treaty and agreement
that this data retention will be imposed
by way of the eu level on all member
states and that's why it's a really good
time to act now because this is at early
stages
the commission has collected feedback
from member states they are waiting for
a court decision on germany's data
retention regime that's coming up in the
next few months
and then they will act and it is clear
that the commission will propose
a maximum measure possible they actually
consider extending data retention to ott
services which would for the first time
include messaging services
possibly video a conferencing services
internet email etc
they could actually mandate
identification
so um
it could eliminate anonymous accounts
and that's all that is a real thread
that needs addressing so it's very
timely to be having this panel today
thank you so much patrick for the very
good summarize uh so we hear it well i
think what the commission is planning is
still very unknown and i'm not sure they
have a good idea themselves what they
want to do actually
but this is our to our advantage because
we can come and be prepared when
the proposal comes out
and in any case we need some
mobilization currently at national level
where member state are pushing
more or less for a renewed regime on
data retention
in their domestic laws
um before maybe we like
think about uh future action and what
can be done and learn a little bit from
la quadrature du net uh case i wanted to
turn to reyna rena you are an activist
like a really long-term activist in data
protection
you co-founded digital courage which had
a different name at the time um
and i'm not gonna try to pronounce
you funded the big brother awards uh and
you were also using arts at the time
to um
to fight against a surveillance issue in
germany and i wanted to learn and i
think a lot of people in in the public
could learn from your experience and all
your uh
past mobilization um could you tell us a
little bit more how you became active on
the topic what did you do it was in the
2000 if i'm not mistaken um can you tell
us a little bit more how did you
organize how did you find partners uh
what did you do and
what do you think were your main
victories
hey yes
sure it's a pleasure
actually we started back in 1987
and
that was
the decade where um
the
big census in germany
uh should have happened which
then led to the constitutional court
ruling for
informational self-determination which
is a really important ruling
and everything else
relies on that
in terms of data protection law
so that was the time when a lot of
people were active on this and we had
demonstrations and so on in the in the
80s against the census
um
well um
um i should mention that i'm not doing
artwork to make something pretty
uh and have a
cool
uh thing to show
for uh for demonstrations but
um
our concept of art is different we um
we rely actually on the french composer
eric certi
uh his music was not meant to listen to
but to have it in the background and
create a good atmosphere so everyone
feels comfortable
and
it's
actually the music
tries to be boring
so you are not distracted but you come
to the point where you want to be active
yourself
so
this in very short the artistic concept
um we applied also to political
uh and legal situations
which also create a room where you find
yourself comfortable
and wanting to to uh
[Music]
to contribute something
or you think you should rather
stay quiet and don't do anything that
attracts attention
and we think in a democracy we need uh
people to to feel comfortable to to
to feel
confident uh to participate in in in in
the democratic process
and people can't do that when they feel
under surveillance all the time
so that in very short is the artistic
background of what we do
um
well about data so we worked for
data protection privacy already since 87
but
on data retention this started in
december 2005.
um
there the directive
came into place and
we had a first meeting
different people from different
organizations and also individuals at
the chaos communication congress this is
the the biggest uh
hacker
meeting
and that was taking place in um
i'm not sure was it hamburg or berlin
already i'm not sure
maybe it was berlin
um and um
they're very different people came from
the
critical
people against globalization of attack
there were people of the hackers from
the chaos computer club
and there were data protection officials
actually taking were taking part
and
some activists and this group decided
we have to do something on data
retention because this has the potential
to be really threatening for everybody
as you can
[Music]
you can figure out what someone is doing
because you can follow them their
location
all their social networks as patrick
explained already
so
um
there was a mailing list was created
and we decided we have to work together
and that was great because
more organizations and more individuals
joined in
and the interesting thing is
that
we were successful to
uh to make people understand that
everybody is really
[Music]
is affected
so we had um
uh groups uh joining in
uh you would not expect there by like uh
doctors
uh journalists lawyers
also therapists and
we had the
um aids hiv counseling the telephone
counseling of the protestant church in
germany and so on because they all saw
that
it has a chilling effect when people
can't call
a counseling line like like this
um
when they think this is all recorded uh
that the fact that they have been
calling there allows
the um
that you think
they might be ill or something or have a
psychological problem
so i think one of the secrets of the
success was that we
actually
were
successful to attract a lot of different
organizations that were opposing data
retention for different reasons
and
we started
organizing demonstrations
the
the really big demonstration that was
taking place
several years
was called freiheit state angst
in german and
this is
where the uh freedom not fear
slogan the motto of our annual meeting
of act european activists in brussels
comes from
um
freedom not fear um
[Music]
freyja angst means
we don't want to be protected don't uh
make us fearful
and pretend you want to protect us
we think democracy and freedom is
more to protect we we protect it and
keep away from us
and um we actually
um were successful to bring people of
very different political backgrounds
together
we had um
[Music]
people from the left the greens the
pirate party
um and uh the liberals uh the free
democrats of germany
uh at the same time there were the
anti-capitalist block there and uh
uh
a block of doctors that came in white in
their white coats and uh
so it was very colorful and a lot of
creative action of people who protested
and people
founded local groups
and
that organized events in their town and
made info stands in the pedestrian areas
and
so there was a lot of engagement
um
also because we had a common uh goal for
uh
in the first place to stop uh data
retention
uh by the way of the constitutional
complaint
uh patrick
really earns the uh the credits for this
because i think he wrote most of the uh
text of the constitutional complaint in
cooperation with meiner sterostic our
lawyer
which sadly died uh some years ago uh he
was a fantastic person and he he was
always engaged in
defending freedom
and civil rights yeah that was you see
patrick in one of the early
demonstrations
uh making a talk next to paduloon of the
guitar coverage
and
we started with 250 people at the
demonstration at the next
there was something like 500 and then
more than 1 000 and then we have at
fifteen thousand and uh then at some
time um we had uh
um we had uh fifty thousand and uh that
was just a fantastic
experience to see that here you see
people of um abbey sky swordstart
that's a free group with no
it's no association
in the leader sense but it was a free
association of people the local groups
uh always called themselves awaits
foreign or berlin or whatever and we had
a lot of them
uh yeah we had uh uh quite a number of
demonstrations that is also in berlin
um
and
but um
a lot of local
initiatives um
uh who did things
i would not have recommended i would
have thought as as an experienced
activist this does not work
for instance people
carried a coffin
around
and said
to to show we bury democracy we bury
fundamental riots
and we thought this is so boring people
have done that in the 70s you know but
most people don't remember this so um
it actually worked to attract attention
and this coffin was carried around
hamburg i think that was
and so a lot of creativity and and
actions and uh to to activate people
happened and that was that was great and
um
of course um
collecting signatures um
for the um
complaint was a big thing
as people saw they can
actually have an impact
when they support this constitutional
complaint and we collected these
signatures not like these organizations
who do that online but people gave their
real-life signature on paper
as
[Music]
it's
i don't know the the term the exact term
to give the lawyer uh um
uh the um
uh
um
the authority to to uh
to apply in
in their name at the court so
uh and this this was the biggest mass uh
constitutional complaint we had almost
35 000 people
who signed this and
so we have been uh bringing um uh
really
a lot of paper to the constitutional
court for who were the plaintiffs
uh at this court and um no please go
back in the picture frank
um
look at this uh this is potsdamer platz
in berlin you can see how many people uh
attended these demonstrations
and
the speaker there is tilo weihert who is
a
data protection officer
of schleswig-holstein
and
there were masses of people and it was a
great feeling for everybody to see we
are not alone and i think this is the
main learning uh to see we can actually
move something we can have an impact we
can change things
and
a demonstration does not only show this
to other people to politicians but also
to
any people who are active to see they
are not alone this is a very important
function also of a
demonstration um
well if we uh
jump on to the next picture frank
that
that was in
at the
european court
and i have been attending
this in 2013.
i traveled there and the german
television was there with me that was
quite fun
and i wanted comments on this
this was the the ruling against the
directive on data retention and
i could not believe how
um
how harsh
the judges
were dealing with these government
officials and
trying to get information from them
why do you have
data retention why do you think it's
useful
and as an example of the austrian
government said we had 1 000 no no we
had 120 cases
more or less um we had we have used data
retention on we couldn't have solved
them otherwise
and the judges
asked
what was the uh what were the crimes
and uh the guy of the austrian
government said well it was uh
let me see um it was fraud uh dealing
with stolen goods drug trafficking and
insulting other people
and the judge said
did you have any terrorism
cases
and the austrian guy said
no i can't see any and the um then the
judge said and you have used data
retention on cases of insult
uh really
and the austrian guy said yes because we
had the data
anyway
so we just used it and so
i could not believe that he actually
said that because he couldn't have given
us a better
uh
argument on that
um there of the function creep then when
when the data has been collected it will
be used um because it's there and uh
people organizations and also
corporations might get hold of the data
as soon as it's collected
something like this will happen
so um
yeah um
[Music]
i was astonished how they
the judges were
there dealing with the government
officials and
other activists said oh this does not
mean anything
they will
they will not do anything important in
the end but i was very happy to learn
afterwards that they actually decided uh
that the the european directive was not
um uh in terms with the european charter
of fundamental rights yes um
a very positive outcome in the end of
the of your campaign so maybe yeah
this picture is uh showing uh us also
you can see patrick again
we are on the went mainarch touristic is
the guy with the orange scarf uh our
lawyer and we are on the way um uh the
second time to the constitutional court
because uh
the
data retention
is in place now again
and just one point i want to make
is
[Music]
that in the first ruling of the
constitutional court the court said it's
unconstitutional and void the german law
on data retention but they did not say
data retention can't be done
as such
so under certain conditions it could be
uh there could be a law for data
retention
but they said um there have been them
there are certain conditions you can't
rule the um the data retention law just
um
as such you have to look at the context
are there other laws in place
and when there is more surveillance in
place then citizens will feel under
surveillance all the time and this is
not uh possible in a democracy
so um
the the term that was coined then is uh
uh
this means uh
overall account of current surveillance
laws uh
so uh the politicians have to uh take an
um in account
that uh
how
how many other laws are there uh for
surveillance and can't decide for
another law adding surveillance to this
and what we have done is we made a list
uh uh
of all the laws that
were added on this since 2010
this is when the constitutional court
said no it's uh it's unconstitutional
and
this was a tedious work but
in the end
the liberal party
foundation took up the work and
this ended up in the german coalition
contract so
in germany when new laws are
decided on
they
the
german bundestag must take in into
account
uh what the total accounting of
surveillance laws is
and uh it's mentioned in the coalition
contract and i think this is a big
success
okay i think i am
make a point here
and you can ask anything indeed
of course you can ask any question to
rena and patrick already uh thank you so
much for this rendition of all the work
you've done since uh
the late 90s actually and i think this
is already shows a lot of great uh
lessons or takeaway we can do for this
session
like i understand that it was a
combination of different action of
different types of action it was
advocacy with the list you just
mentioned showcasing how many
surveillance laws were already in place
it was about litigation bringing
actually the case in front of courts
uh asking for a review of the legality
of those laws but in the end also
showcasing
uh your power by bringing people to the
streets in numbers
and that is very impressive
as well as actually bringing different
people
around the table and
um
highlighting their voice bringing their
voice to the table those who we don't
think at first might be affected but are
in direct line so that's already very
inspiring i think for the
for how we could design uh our own next
uh action in this field i want to turn
to nuemi who has more uh recent
experience knowing me is member of la
cuadro dinet another edgary member so
such as uh dikital kuraj
this is our member in france and now
naomi is also the legal advisor i would
uh translate it this way
in english of la guaracher
recently joined the team and we are very
happy to have her this morning and she
also was part of the litigation team at
la cuaracho
when the case uh the french law was
brought
uh to just well in front of courts and
it ended up in this uh
uh now famous landmark ruling i would
say at the court of justice
uh obviously the aftermath was very
disappointing for you guys um i wanted
to know
that the reason for that is the
constitution actually circumvented the
whole kind of conclusion from the court
of justice and i wanted to know how like
when ratio
lived through this journey uh what did
you learn guys what was the positive
aspect what was the
kind of the defeat or the the negative
things you wouldn't done it wouldn't
have done again
and what are for you the the next step
after this disappointment how you pass
that feeling and how are you going to
continue
working on this topic
well hello thank you for the invitation
first
uh well actually yes with quadrature we
we challenged this topic only on a
litigation aspect uh
and to resume it was long it was a long
fight
and i think what we can say now it's
we have a big a very
uh
sensitive example of how politics and
law and litigation can interfere because
when we first
went before the judge i actually the
starting point was the digital right
island decision that patrick brayer uh
talked about and for us it was
really great it was a material and
substantial argument to to
show the judge to
to challenge the legality of such of
such retention and access
of data and so we went uh on
first time before the judge we were
actually ruled out because
we were actually the council of states
say that we were misinterpreted
the digital island decision so we had to
wait for the td2 ruling to go back
and then it was long because why i say
we there are interference with politics
is that at the same time there was
negotiation on the e-privacy regulation
in brazil and
so we know that friends have had a big
part on it so
in our action before the judge at that
time really stopped during two or three
years because the council of state knew
that there was some interest
in resells and
so
we had to wait until 2018
to have our preliminary ruling uh
transmitted to the court but again we
saw that the council state didn't do
this
just to enforce the law the the way of
turning the question the way of drafting
the preliminary ruling really asked the
court to
change its position so
all that time we were quite happy of
course with that little ruling but we
were all we knew also that there was so
much interest there that this topic is
so sensitive when you talk about police
and terrorism so
so we we were really waiting for this
decision
and
actually when uh the goal of justin's
decision uh
came out in 2020
we had kind of mixed feelings because as
patrick brewer said it was
creating exemptions
so it was for us kind of weaker a weaker
decision weaker position than the td2
ruling but we also believed at the time
that france
french law was going to change because
it didn't comply with this decision and
so as you said the council of sale so
which is actually for those who don't
know the french higher administrative
court
will
interpreted it in a way that nothing
changed so it twisted the exception to
make
uh
the retention and access actually
permanent and as petroglyphs said the
exemption of threat to national security
was used to say that we are in a
permanent threat a permanent state of
emergency and so that the police and the
intelligence services
should
access should should have the same power
than before so
what our feelings of of course who were
disappointed but we were also facing the
limit of litigation as
the the countryside didn't actually
enforce the load didn't enforce what we
have been doing for decades which is uh
make prevail european law on french law
and so
it's more than a disappointment it's
also a loss of faith in this institution
even i don't know if we had too much
faith but now we don't have
any more and how
actually
the police and the intelligence services
can have so much influence and maybe
it's
very specific also to
how friends works because i think it can
be different in in different member
states because in france this concealer
state is not uh
made of classical uh judge the judge
came out from a school that trained also
the higher executives that go into
ministries so it's the same people that
actually
judge our case and that also advise the
politics so it's a few hundred of people
who are in the higher uh position of all
institutions so
i think what we
after all this year
all this year sorry what we
uh
recall and what we were in face of is
that really something cannot ever change
and this institution has hundreds of
years
exit have existed for a hundred years
have very prestigious and historical
past and so we believe that with our
legal argument with our european law we
could make
the makes things change and actually
we could not
and that's how that's why we were
disappointed and actually
like almost a year later
we still don't know what we're gonna do
we we
know that litigation cannot be used
maybe to such
big subjects we will still use it for
smaller case or individual case but
that's also what's sad is that we were
trying to
to make uh to defend a collective
subject the collective cause and maybe
now we have to go back to more
individual protection
uh
to
tell people how they can protect their
privacy or maybe to go do litigation on
specific criminal individual case we
were still thinking about it
uh because
it has been i think it was six years
fight and we went to the highest it's
the highest body in the european union
so we
at least maybe we could go before the
european court of human rights but there
are also a lot of limitations to go
before this this judge we could uh there
are also the option
of
asking the commission to prosecute
friends but where we cannot do it
ourselves and that's
that's a shame in european law because
we depend on a political body to
to uh
to to do this action
of failure
so
actually we are making maybe a pose
on the
on litigation and that was really
interesting to see reyna reyna's
history of activism because we are also
thinking
maybe of doing a mix between litigation
and then going on the street or may or
or doing some as i said training
or also tell people and
the people that they make them aware of
uh
of where their data is going because now
that we lose that we lost sorry
well you have to be aware that if you
have a phone you have always you're
always
tracked with your location so
yeah maybe sometimes
not take it and it's a shame to go this
far but today we cannot
well the fight for the law is lost so we
have to go back to individual protection
and so that that's some stuff we we were
thinking about also maybe
uh before the french decision we were we
were
pushing to
to entertune
and force uh european law
instead of a french so for example in
we have some social network we host some
social network and we're saying we only
keep the logs and the data a few weeks
because we have that little ruling and
we want to enforce this decision but now
that the french flow is clear well we
can
maybe still do it but we we put
ourselves at risk but it's also a way of
activism to
to
actually not applies at all but
with of course all the limits it has so
we're thinking about all this doing a
mix
of uh of the of all the square of
activism
and if we i actually if we had to do it
all again
all over
today
uh i don't know if we knew that it was
going to end this way i think we will
not go
because uh
because we were thinking that french law
will would apply and enforce european
law so
actually it's it's a very difficult
question uh
maybe we we would do
more specifically maybe we will do all
of the same again because
that also may shed light on this topic
in france and uh
we are waiting to see how this decision
is going to be teached in law school
because there were a lot of noise and
fuss about about it
here so
we still have mixed feelings uh we are
happy to
that we went all through this journey
but uh but it's very difficult and as
you said in the beginning of the of the
talk we have to do it all over again we
had we thought we won and then
maybe we have to to
see and observe what was what was going
on in every member state in the in the
few years what the commission is going
to propose
but uh it's not
as
as it did is also kind of an attack to
european union law and it has done
quite the same uh twice in the last year
i think that's why i said at the
beginning there are a lot of politics
and there are there is a tension right
now between france and european
union well that's what we saw so of
course maybe we have to have this in
mind
and wait until it pass or wait until we
have some more idea or wait until we
know how to attack it but of course we
won't give up it's just that
uh such such a big
big event like like we had
uh makes as a as activists questions of
where of are going to a subject and we
made all our efforts all of our energy
into litigation and maybe
we just have to wait and put our energy
into something else before before coming
back but thank you very much for
for the cheering
in the
arrangement absolutely deserved uh
there is a question about exactly maybe
knowing me you want to just respond
directly um there's a que another
question from freedom and about like
whether what do you think the court of
justice will do when it sees that
there's such a
almost wrong
reaction to its own uh court case uh
what do you think the reaction would be
and louisa also had a question um to
which uh patrick archery answered in the
chat
about italy as well uh
um
obliging retention of metadata for over
four or six years i think and the
commission is not still taking action so
we are pointing again to the same
direction of there is the commission and
this is a deadlock it refuses to do its
role under the treaty uh like as a
guardian of the treaty um is there
is this a point where we need to focus
on um i'm asking to all the speakers and
we have five minutes left so please be
brief
i can start quickly on freezing
questions uh actually it's something
we're looking at and it's interesting to
see that in the latest uh general
advocates conclusion on a segment
on the same topic saying that it's okay
we know we know where the case law is
stop asking questions so maybe the court
is going to
to go
on and on are saying the same position
and that could uh weaken uh member
states like friends who are who has a
very narrow interpretation so
uh what's going to be interesting too is
to see if the commission do something to
enforce this position
uh if
if the commission is going to wait to uh
citizens to seize it or
or if it's going to do some action for
failure by itself so i think it's uh as
i said there is a moment of tension
right now maybe in european union about
enforcing law and uh it's only the
beginning so we have a part parts
to play
in there
any final word
from patrick organa
before we close the session it's too
short
yeah
that's what i was going to say uh we can
tell that we are running out of time
before we've had
the opportunity to discuss everything
and talk with our
audience and so i think it will make
sense to um to keep in touch and
have
more meetings and um
continue the the networking to
see
internationally what are the
developments and how can we challenge
there's a great thing listed andrea i'm
sure clearly we'll go into that and um
we will also
continue our work and try to bring
people on this and um
let's as lena said let's be really uh
persistent and a pain in the neck
very great words of conclusion yes
indeed if you want to support
a network a
transnational civil society mobilization
as louisa put it in the chat you can
join uh as you remember
um the members in germany like digital
courage are working on those topics uh
la cuatro as well in france you can go
to at your website edri.org and check
the map of members and maybe join
them and support our efforts and you can
also support obviously us
at european level uh we'll continue
monitoring what the commission has in
mind for the next year
we have a mailing list that is open to
external
beside members
you can drop an email to me you'll find
my email address on the website as well
and i'm gladly uh will add you if you
want to take part in the mobilization
i take the few seconds left i have to
thank my dear speakers thank you so much
for the great insight i was super
reinvigorated for this morning after the
stocks and and i will do our best
uh to fight against that our attention
for the years to come
thank you
much