so we had a good talk coming up for you
we have
legal practices as infrastructure tax
and I leave the gym I like gonna
per I'd like to present out much %ah
I love the stock I get this ever so
often and I'm modified it I promise I'm
it actually a little bit updated cuz you
know the law changes
I'll change tell but right is my passion
for fashion
okay why am I giving the stock on cuz
your information and really it's not
just your information is information
that you may have been cast
to defend as a part of your job as a
partner
whatever you have to do with an
organization
and its vulnerable things that you might
not get
we all get our lives I've I'd lock down
my box
could save the date her its are gonna go
to where
the people who are authorized happen and
we think about those things we think
about is a cocaine all corralled
all safe the problems are other
processes legal process ease
that would crack you open like a walnut
this all stems from a
really really drunken conversation had
time on a hacker con
now this very rarely happen and on
I discovered people talk about how
secure the boxes were under said look
you know what in 10 minutes I could have
you
i cant all the information I want your
systems and the best part is
I will make you help me find it her
in someone's like had to talk again some
so your your impressions farmer
two processes you are familiar with and
it's being handled by people who don't
think like we do
who soon well it has a password
therefore it's safe are no one
understands that system
so therefore the data safe on and we you
know we bristle
constantly too bad but Knollwood much
has been audited or less I know exactly
how else to word
it's not safe it's not safe until I say
it isn't even then I'm still paranoid
arm the promise that this babe gets
handed off to other people willy nilly
what I'm hoping to do with the stock
explain roughly have the legal system
works
this will be your date on show you how
to prepare for these
as best you can so
standard disclaimer I am an attorney
just not your
that can be remedied
on this field have large influx that's
my standard disclaimer because well
things change
arm the law is whatever a bunch of
people in black robes say it is
that's a nice way of saying I may be
wrong
cell kinds of attacks kinds approaches
that
legal people like me can take to try to
get you
to give us your data first 17
this is for civil lawsuits anbe wish to
sue one another about something
and you have to perhaps to to get
someone to crack open their
crack open their systems we've got civil
discovery and you've got a subpoena
then you've got criminal search warrants
and related warrants
wiretap Warren stored Communications Act
Barnes and
third-party I want to talk about that
separate makers it's been kinda for
why I updated the stock cell
one is discovery it's the middle phase
obligation
for started something we call a
complaint in answer which is
kind of like I when we
when known we solve problems with
violence
and the way you would start a fight as
you would show up and smacked the other
person in the face with a glove
well the legal approach to that is a
complaint I'm suing you for the
following reasons:
and the answer which is oh yeah your
mama
discovery it's a
this usually so it's in class here on
discoveries the middle step and this is
that this is the 1i wanna talk about
its information and gathering and
sorting
from both sides each side has two
bombing of a certain amount of relevant
information
to give the other side because you're
trying to figure out
want can we can actually show in the
complaint an answer is true
so therefore a judge can rule on it and
say your douchebag you are the other
side a lot of money
are you don't know the other side a lot
of money and gets also I
information-gathering from both sides
and other third parties in the second
and third step the last step is
presentation in San on so trial
arbitration arm you show the other side
but you had and they decide
Wow I'm be kinda prove their case and
we've got nothing
and you go to your client if your lawyer
in same now we gotta settle this
com cats and mice you wanna continue
paying me money
I usually actually say things like that
kinda shock
so discovery process at the start each
party to the litigation
has to identify and disclose the sources
are potentially responsible yes I year
size electronically stored information
bets the Federal Rules Civil Procedure
bad is broad as hell
electronically stored information is not
just emails in Word documents and
PowerPoint decks
is potentially raw data I have seen
cases
where the real lawsuits quiver randomly
generated data for signal casting
perper I'm sorry for circuit testing and
one side soon for its like
it was randomly generated data that went
to the circuit and then went to death
now
and we want that big random
you know I can give you a lot helping
Deb random it'll be
roughly the same know we want the ones
that use like
deleted years ago we never thought we
would need to keep better
so each party has two tell the other
side here's what we have
you have to get nationally hand or the
information you had to say these are the
sources been for mation
and you have to preserve it you have to
prevent all that bad
once you know the litigation starting
either you've been sued
you've gotten a letter from the opposing
side saying we have a problem
we are going to we're going to
contemplate legal action
something it says old there's a problem
are something really really obvious like
arm that been rebuilt
exploded for no apparent reason be a
think this might end in litigation
yeah at that point matter now prevent
any event
any the relevant information you hold
from getting destroyed
I'm I will talk about that
so first year to preserving then you
have to compile compile it and put in
some kinda
format that human beings can look at
Ingo
is this actually useful to the
litigation is this
gonna help us are hurdles with another
side need to see that state to
figure out what actually happened this
sometimes gets really complicated
because
I would often get asked what I have
heard I the database file how do I make
this
in a review before Matt and sometimes
the nest blow it to a printer
see you have a nineteen thousand page
document that's just the wrong
database file I'm
kinda interesting what I do with that
I'm billing by the hour
I review every page because I'm paid to
do them
RI I don't do that anymore thank God but
I've seen people
clicking through and it's really amazing
like
I have a person a human being with a
high IQ
who is looking at pages and pages and
pages
up little cracker and yet don't bill
four-acre to think about that when we
talk about costs
okay so we have to compile our we to
sort through it
to find responses stuff this is stuff
that
happens to be related to the stuff we're
suing
for to see for example two companies
AMB have a contract to license should
maybe do a cross-licensing
intellectual property Basu would render
everything that A&B have about that
intellectual property
is responsive everything they have to
they have to talk about
about the contract what their agreements
that's responsive
everything they've talked about about
the contract to each other
is responsive it may not represented in
court it's a much broader definition
it's really really wide
its anything that may lead to this is
stuff like
information about a meeting member gonna
sit down and talk about what we're gonna
give the other
the the the other party response of
endure sorting through it also findings
are privileged things
bad while they may be responsive you
don't necessarily have to divulge
like attorney-client privilege some
trade secret to protect the ball
arm try think other examples in a can of
the top my head
but your sorting through these giant
giant China datasets
looking for stuff but you have to get to
the other side
and your also when you're doing this
you're looking through stuff
that proves your side skates while
you're handing out at all the crap they
get
winners anything we have that we want to
leave around at a deposition or trial in
arbitration says
this proves we are right
so you're looking for that matter
seller discovery if experts say massive
exfiltration updater Republican gigs and
gigs and gigs threes what's next for
transient data
is you were handing the stuff of
to third party vendors to handle
for example arm one of my subcontractors
his job is to go when a litigation is
filed show up with a stack
I'll I'm USB hard drives and
forensically capture the entire hard
drives
are people at companies
he now holds their baby daughter he's
I he's a nice enough guy is he might be
bonded but
you're handing all had stopover to some
guy
who is a good one step up from wearing a
sham pressured says like your company's
computer guy
and the best part is he is going to hand
it off to a vendor
will be cont'd discovering vendor who's
going to confer
all the documents there into kips RPD
apps
everything every email every Word
document
every text file and if they don't parse
it right I've seen people take the
entire contents have hard drives
and you're reading Java classes that
have been turned into PDF's
in your looking for going this is a Java
class why did make pars for this
to go might be responsible no we're not
suing sign
it's not useful how do you know like
I its please trust me yeltsin
and going through and M usually the one
you're doing these giant giant
but beta Sox you get to read through
you get a seat all M you get to see all
the stuff that's on this user's PC
now think all the Croft that is on your
on your machine
guiding bore the crap that's on my
niggas you do what I did buy new machine
and you copy everything that was on all
the hard drive
will hurt your new home directory again
and again and again
and sometimes into a copy just look at
the Barnes go
ok she is this at all that porn when
sorry I'm best for those client file
sweater
but then conferred computer users if
those have you were
in in like customer-facing ID thing to
behold the stop you found and users PCs
that could suck down and don't to
e-discovery vendor who takes all that
stuff and blows the PDF
so all that Jay peg and give porn is now
convert the PDF
in a searchable for for for text if
there is text in it
at some cost but it's handed off to a
third party
and how do we select that third-party
answer the lowest bidder
so it's cool its three guys with with a
pirated copy of law 5.0
to convert this crap in the PDS for
searching
awesome you don't even know you is your
intersect people
generally don't know who that provider
is because legal shows up and says
this guy who
has given three fingers on one hand has
used be a shop teacher
but he understands how in case works
good in of
that he is going to go to your CFR oh
and take the entire contents of the hard
drive
how scary is that
not that scary okay I'm I'm never having
this conversation sitting at someone's
desk it was a CFL for a
for bike a fortune 1000 company Mike
you know I showed up
I'm wearing a suit I have a hard drive
and I showed you a business card why why
would not be a problem I
I'll if there's a empezar person with a
with a hundred feet
and if I just said that like yeah how do
we that you might have a business card
because that would prove me
you know but I pursued I'm clearly trust
your trustable right I missed you're
taking all your data
it's okay and ago when you steal
anything on your must be on anything
you're right all but all the pencils and
pens there in spirit they are
Creek are by the way sorry I need the
password to get into your Lotus Notes
file XXI need to be cryptic
are located the your
completely trust more why would you do
that but
I hot this is such a such a security
hole
because I sent him from the legal
department all the sudden you trust me
sober other exultation data the exhibits
the documents that you pick out of this
hmmm II giant data stream
sometimes become public documents this
is sometimes really embarrassing there's
a case
are coupled it came up couple weeks ago
where
someone put a bunch of trade secrets
inadvertently
in a motion which then
went on to pacer which is the docking
system for the entire federal court
pacer documents our public you don't
have to be an attorney to have a log on
you can to say I wanna log on and you
can search through these and sometimes
you find really ridiculous stop
because someone didn't think well that's
not publicly yes
it's absolutely public many people
tackled on pacer and The Miz make a
Google
because it's easier than using the
search function MP Sir
ants all house at you at this is all
secret
no then again I'm also a decline was
like oh you can't show this complaint
anybody like
its public well we want to keep it
secure
its public like your
download it see it's not a secret
anymore
who knows about this like every on
practices in the federal courts we have
to go
sour exhibits are public documents and
sometimes a really embarrassing once
other downside if are other affected
discoveries it's expensive to do
our explain why go through
and peak the entire contents have your
hard drive
maybe that's $250 to $500 thousand
documents
now imagine we've converted them to PDF
and you read each document to figure out
what it is
who was reading that document an
attorney
billing 14 to 16 hours a day
reading through those documents how
expensive now is that one terabyte hard
drive
arm it's amazing how Washburn raids
other million dollars a month on a
mid-size litigation
and wanna when is the kind gonna go we
got a saddle
cuz bring were bombing money in each
other I realized like Mitch
mosser big size civil litigation is like
playing chicken except you just have
bundles a hundred-dollar bills and set
them on fire
only at I got 21 fire pigeons
and and initially I i look at that and
go
my god this is awful but then again like
I get some
fat like mine my job is like okay at
your job to burn hundred-dollar bills
but you can take a few of the top of the
stack okay you should burns more men
can I can occur when the disk right now
on but I'm not here but I'm not a guy
not yet like
and it's amazing as you get someone
who's angry you get some CEOs like
I'm going to litigate this to the
Supreme Court like and and there's a
public this is ridiculous and the other
hand I have a mortgage
and I've student months might get you
large should take that all the way to
the Supreme Court
and I'll do it but you money wasted
accepted I get some of it
cell hah but I'm by Esther
so it's time consuming to collect and
assemble
this takes time it's grueling and you're
reviewing: it by attorneys
who are sitting im
dank airless rooms angry because their
job is to review these documents
it's really expensive I didn't make that
clear
sour discovery defense how do you
protect yours
your organization from this awful awful
attack
and rescue a mess with the sound the
legal once you understand what the
lawyers are doing or not doing
and then what you can do in the ITN in
for a sec departments
up your organization so legal approach
is what the what we innocently call a
document retention policy
how many view just kinda felt that your
soul left your body when I sent that
this is actually amps I'm writing peace
now
and there are actually a lot of fun but
for me i'd
I'm your abt the advantages
the document that doesn't exist cannot
buy
UMES
as Brad said earlier what if the
documents get lost
what if you are allowed to destroy them
sell that one where someone wrote in
email about
and think about all the embarrassing
things your users
day any now
all the really ridiculous things
teaching catch the rack
on that the new associate on the key be
ditcher now oh my god
you know we completely mangled that
project call by the revolution reinforce
the bumper
can tell I mean it's only a nickel yet
use
people buying ridiculous things are born
with a Geisha House
on on those a software litigation
and one person admitted you know we've
never done this before
we should pop we should stop the sales
people from saying we've with these
out successfully ok
and i'm looking guy who did on one hand
CE mi I found the I found the big
glaring document the promises of
are crying to send that to
well we found a really interesting
document the problem is kinda visit nail
in their coffin
on the other hand it's better that you
know about it now than I was just
clicking through in handing the other
side the other side is like blind siding
you with that
at a deposition at four in the afternoon
you like did you know that only I
decided
what does completely screwed the pooch
we fuck them over me
a circle local term from upstate New
York it means are we look forward to
doing business with you
you would WordPress been there before
habits but
reading this insight so
if you can destroy the document legally
it's a nice thing to do
so if you write a document retention
policies says any document were certain
be
unless litigations filed can be
destroyed
so that way you know what to put the bed
also once litigation is hard sometimes
you can negotiate down the scope of the
data because the
the each side is also looking at this
and they don't want the massive data
dump to be handed over to them
because like I said the analogy with
burning hundred-dollar bills the
end okay we found 1.2 million documents
American handy your lawyers and they're
gonna look through them
the burning continues because now they
gotta go through all your
you know the other side got a good for
all your shit /img /url
is this useful now now now now
and given your users how many times how
many times have you seen
users download the same attachment
Woburn Woburn Woburn
over and over again I have we cease 18
copies in the same document
someone reviewed all 8 p.m.
so bad document that bad that one-page
document about
you know did number appropriately
funding the coffee fund
cost like eighteen thousand dollars
because so many attorneys had to look
through that again and again and again
so negotiates go camping hiking this
stuff isn't relevant this stuff isn't
these people we don't need to scour
their hard drives
arm if you can argue that some things
just like your
your command is ridiculous let's shoot
what's narrow the scope of it
awesome and also you can say things like
a lot of the day you want
is not readily accessible it is in some
kind of hard to get
form like its obsolete
you know and sometimes this is my job
which is
turns out bad the company used
clarice works as their because it was
cheaper
and you like how we blow to the PDF Mike
let me get back here now we're going to
i'm going to like it
old-school Mac shop like yeah I need a
magazine requires works
really yeah Kadam
but and in five ok
and it's also because I could and I used
to play with that's not so much like on
email calling up olds is a min to get
get me eight-millimeter game drives
why do you have any surer
up to hire more from your has a bigger
one work
I'm settings up like it means I don't
have to review those documents in a
month
a while dork out with some ancient
technology
and at the end it's like yeah I'm energy
converters clarice work documents
PR you know again Mac exchange 2.0 from
into a text file that you can now review
the Cure G music no its side
all good trivia from like old Mac shops
you like and you get like it you know I
remember getting a staggered 800
I'm $800k Mac lobbies Mike I know how to
do this
and and and in a sense taking an hour
nap
and I'm baylon I'm end up going for him
reading this and said
anarchy how did you know I do that like
I'm diaper
yet Mac I remembered that stuff but
again like crazy said I love them like
how was more because as more fun than
actually being a lawyer I got a problem
now
that no one can fault me because I took
a different path has like no one else is
gonna
touch that god damn day your doesn't
really fun when you call a Mac shopping
go I
actually need abort from a Mac SC
because mine just fried
and its actually like real money but no
its not economic
Dutson into it's a it's a twenty-two
million dollar
litigation I need a Mac SC I will pay in
the current one
like how much I don't know how much
haven't have a hundred dollars a day
really be yeah ugh some I'm its clients
money
arrangement I've been tonight if you can
guarantee the soccer works
because at the end but I get actually
useful data
and bad I do that that was some agassi
woodworking not in LC
like okay so
not really you can say we don't need
Alex to be dicking around with Mac junk
to get those few pieces a bid to say
they don't exist anymore
there they are effectively gone the
technical approach
mention that you can have this legal
consequence document retention policies
as
every document were ninety days gets
deleted no matter what
so that way you can say we only have 90
days worth the beta
you soon as today we going right have to
go back a quarter
we don't have to talk about stuff
previous the problem is
is that you get eight people document
that says
all baidoa over 90 days you shouldn't
have
how many of your users are going to
follow this your
in okay both of them
may all out knowing your users
that means but documents get printed and
put in a binder somewhere
I've done i've seen that remember one
one company like over so smart with a
30-day docking retention policy inside
you know that's about as dumb as
requiring you know
epic ECA epic pass power sign I would so
secure it now I just need some
fucking posted now you know it's the
same a pro-taliban 30 David which means
you have stacks and stacks and stacks of
paper documents that were printed
and that means you've just tripled your
cost because now
instead of having an easily incredible
electronic document you will be printed
document
that some schmuck has to step up on a
scanner
and OC harder and their little twitchy
bad NCR comes out as you know coverup
not going to pick as the old I was
snoring
don't snore horribly wrong which means
you have some were other Shin ok
some point we're going I'm think it's
perhaps I was to take me a long time
they're blowing it up it's like
so it took you 45 minutes to read
that clarice works documented some
asshole printed five years ago when it
if he just kept electronic with them and
grab it nope
not the main actor next but now someone
had to get ready
but technical approach if you can
actually make it happen
sorry but by for that document as
passive stockman pension policy
but go bye-bye really really useful
it's also the home wanted these the
technical department has to look after
how many people have a basement in their
shop
that has old or missions
all the deal what's on those all
admissions
good will actually answers
I'm home stop why do you keep 'em
I might need the park is comparable good
your own only needed three eighty six
cuz I'm not part do it but we might need
and I get you out here on this episode
Amy's warders technology addiction them
we go to bob bob is a UNIX sysadmin the
forefoot beard
there can be good sports you shouldn't
compare me to him
and DL home I'd say that cuz I may have
a spark station in my basement
said did might be needed just don't have
the beard anymore
om so that I actually think that the
doctor tension policies also old
machines
and sometimes you can convince well
I've tried to convince some people that
the best way to get rid of
all beta is to actually physically
destroy the drive
and on the best way to destroy drivers
with all well know is that most in the
gutter
argue like American stuff too I'm not
you know
yes it's cheaper ok
on okay also though the other way you
can reduce costs and protect your
your your company is the building to
preserve identify in search of the stuff
arm it's amazing I'm 1.high started
talking to people about doing project
management for these big litigation
because I was a
so also a tech geek was what tools you
using a mic
grab new ones I wanna spend a lotta shit
grab but with a better other tools grab
ok my cock I'm that works right
you know like L other industrial tools
that do that better
it's a text file writer at some get a
bunch a text files in a directory like
I'm sure there are tools that much
graphic interfaces but
for one user you know but I haven't
needed to yet
when when you don't like I'll play with
them but
mobile I want to just use that like a
site not ever hit in hebron need
something else
and I am bats like a magic to like
regular orders like
so you can search over multiple
directories ok
yeah on wait a minute but we have
multiple systems we've got these
mix boxes and we've got these I'm these
Windows servers and his Mac servers like
Ivan I was conducted mount oldest grab
what to do they had
Matt directories all the documents it
had those repeat those search terms like
how do you know Mike our
and am selling have real to keep on
repeating I'd grab
& like Mike had some a magical talisman
but
trust me ads that's how we're cool one
uses other tools like they wouldn't work
on the Mac on my desk
it had at work I can you are there's
burn it to a DVD take that
ever discover you need done I'm gonna go
we don't go home now
arm but the ability to do that to go to
say the and
here's your stuff that you needed done I
certified
of course I was a litigation that I also
attended a search against of our
I index faster backups and I sign this
affidavit says like I promise to give
you my first born my soul and my last
night if i'm wrong.
I've signed a
this is before I became a lawyer send
that often like me I'm done that
litigation
thing I get to go do another project and
some guy
wearing cover all shows up a two run two
crates for DL
tease says I heard you're looking for
stuff and there's nothing on a sinking
feeling like
I can certified like I'm not that I
searched all the detail
what the fuck these McReynolds Adobe
aunties
but have been is like blue bag up three
and that's like new scheme that I know
what I've been working for two years
like
I had no idea what the shares and
I I've never been so thankful when I
founded
they were stored in bed storage bed
storage at the pharma companies that was
above in panama machine which is a big
MRI household its her
go like
I am gardens drug however
a good 700 cals her God for
to me murders yes for
there's nothing on the sinking feeling
is that open these crazy homestead
I'm gonna be racking games from two
months after I explained to corporate
counsel I'm back affidavit
arm to bacall why no
I'm bought I didn't know about these
happen have a card in store that
memory controller she's a girl you've
done your
Dept and just delivered on the
Cumberland take those away
where com care hips
com like I wrote another affidavit said
all the
anything else was destroyed per the
document retention policy
Houska also came back and didn't budge
knowingly if you think about user access
rules
no which employees have access to what
because
imagine you've got some litigation where
they named fifteen people about have
access to the data that is important in
this litigation you want to know where
they might have stored
now of course because they've moved
around
and we've all found that one server that
one workgroup used
and you find it like I did once where is
behind a panel she Brock
because he lectures Watson goes it's got
a Mac it's got an apple logo a must be
yours and the police she block away and
there's a
have a workgroup server my
hot it's been sitting there for like by
from three years since she brought this
office
can still live and the worst part is
that
transceiver the AAU why transceivers
blinking said some things hitting this
Mike
I have no idea what the hell the
senate's so of course
I did what you're supposed to do in this
case you on plugging leaks on a Boeing
com go
I'm gonna on your machine
Salaam members access to what because I
don't have to be that guy now is the way
to go in
going in growing IT guy but what about
you know is a in a possibly know and
then having them go
all there's this theirs is p2
that has a drive I don't know what's on
it
where is it hides in a shed but an
internet cable strong two-way
of how the notes to live like its
blinking something setin
I don't know why what could be on it I
don't know but it's kind of like
I one sec who's working part man you
know it's like the same generators a
lost art
I don't know it's on the could be the
document that sings the entire
litigation you find after Discovery's
closed
soap had it not been able to say very
quickly what informational actually
holds you don't have to worry about what
about bad thing up
there's back I can search through all of
our data
and anything that doesn't mean the net
searchable zone
is gone how do you know I pounded the
hard drive
flat with a hammer it spendy doused
I shot into space separate will worship
but that wouldn't say
all the data we have on this point is
right here
there is no other source yea and you go
in go back to your job you don't have to
worry about that really really nice
because the turny
wants to also say cuz the attorneys
going to sign of their evidence as
you can freaking disbarment your I'm
lying
kinda scary to see if they wanna they
won't have the reassurance from you say
everything in bed that we have on point
is here
everything that may have held a day
before
was destroyed as per the doctor
retention policy of
okay so I talk about this and why it's
important
but the rule is what you don't have may
not hurt you
more there was the emails
that might proof that often case
against you if it's legally gone if you
are allowed to destroy it
you sell con the doctor attention party
doing stuff not but the doctor tension
policy
gets you in shed cell
destruction usually okay
if you don't have some other requirement
to keep that getting a
you don't have some regulatory mood says
you have to hold all this data for two
years
arm one of my clients I love them for
public transit authority
they're almost twenty years
good 20 years some this is paper
documents
and they decided well we still hold onto
a pass the doctor pension policy
so we went to the warehouse and it's a
warehouse
filled with document boxes filled with
more room
rats n and good
mom I don't know yet but mimeographed
files remembered your barber
on white paper burger this is not this
case was 1953 Yomi come back to us
everyone involved is dead
I'm we can shred it yet
the only downer has now is that some
poor schmuck who's got became really
weird train fetish
may want to know about some dough on a
trolley
when Eisenhower was president did
okay so usually okay if you don't have a
plan to keep
you have to keep it if litigation been
filed on this point
are you think it might happen others
regulatory scheme generally that's okay
there's one case
thats different where r may be running
I don't go too much into a purse
basically complaints about
rifles firing when he didn't pull the
trigger
kinda group them
if you turn the safe be it would fire
which I think that makes the time safety
ugh really YUM
really bad irony that save proud
now it's safe I'm but they had
complaints people britain said I had
this problem with your otherwise fine
firearm
and what they did was be read it and
shredded them
so when other people you know went when
it's not a hold that was really scary
when the right for one of the bullish on
handsets like
group I ever close pointing at
someone who wasn't dearer you know how
my wife
dressed as a UPS delivery man with white
gloves or something
I'm and they said but we want all the
other complaints in Remington said we
don't have any
not been getting we don't have any cuz
we describe the matter doctor
prevention policy we get them with them
fraud 30 days nourish read them it said
wait a minute how many complaints again
we don't know have you had them other
people coming and we're going i
here's a copy the letter I sent my see
you hadn't noticed that this was a
problem
going back to the 70s yes but we don't
have the doc because we destroyed them
as per doctor country bars in the course
I'd well
lady Mirlande you should've known dead
you want to destroy needs
sour the other thing you wanna think
about a special electronic scheme
is never create the document in the
first place
I'm thinking about what anonymity if you
want to protect your users
you create a log file about what they've
done and then deleted
that's potentially a problem if you
remember
log information in the first place
that may be beneficial cuz then you can
say when you get sued
I don't have that data because I'm never
how did
anyway I didn't destroy it I'm never put
it down
I think you can argue that that's
transitory know if it was never really a
document was just weren't there
you needed to prevent transaction but it
went away
I think once you create the document has
invited to desk
in such a way that you need looked at it
especially given how did for anyone
the time and by one per gallon thinkin
human terms
a week a month here then we have a
problem
if it's designed to be in the system in
such a way that its only used for debt
transaction
10 seconds a millisecond whatever broke
a
generally so unnecessary logging
retention
now spoliation this is that this is a a
legal term for
you destroyed staff you shouldn't
perhaps
and we do nasty things to people we
catch doing this
me in this ranges from a sanction as in
you know how to bring the opposing side
is allowed to bring this up in court
that offend them kept the stockings but
the screen is they're trying to hide
something from his you make the
had you're allowed to bring up the
adverse inference that says
I eager the defendant says
they've never had any of these documents
but I have proof that they did
which means they must be hiding
something I can bring that up now
too nice it's a nice hard because all
the sand %um the fact that you have no
case
is actually beneficial you get to do the
conspiracy theory
thing i've seen others where cases have
been
dismissed but only I'm suing the sky but
I destroyed all my documents from guess
one
dismissed gone you like ho in did get
clients like worry me
I have no claim now at Gap as you
describe you destroy the necessary
documents
this isn't an idea to hold everything
but like the relevant documents once
litigations value then destroyed them
you can get spanked for that it usually
depends on how much bad faith is obvious
in a burden destruction like I hope the
evidence
I'll try a car accident more action is
great rock one
on dad truck was all over they believe
it was bad maintenance
the problem is is that later the the
warehouse the truck is stored in burns
down
destroying the evidence and that the
truck manufactured tries to argue to the
owner the truck like what you destroy
the evidence
therefore we should not turn said I was
really bad because you have no control
over the warehouse
warehouses held by a third party not bad
faith
other stuff but the destruction of the
complaint letters to running 10
is in bad faith and Remington got
spanked for after
sanctions okay subpoenas
this is a this is kinda but this is more
interesting is this is that where you
can go to a third party
and say I'm suing be a is suing be
but I want information from CE
about be senior with third party in fine
stuff
you can get its issued by court
sometimes my grand jury are violent
again
tops our pain response information same
things we talked about for discovery
it's a major discovery order you can
depend on similar grounds this is
overly burdensome its too much it cost
me too much to give you this data
narrow the scope of
ok yes guess they can't but of course
you bill what your rates so i've seen
that's what I guess we demand this
information fine I built two hundred
fifty dollars an hour to do this work
and you before sometimes ago know we
think that date is actually worth it
were paid near like okay well printer
I'm issues have standing down here's
where things get really really fun
you subscribe to a service
bad holds your data
I can go after you I can sue you for
that day your
I can go on for your service sometimes
you may not be able to step in separate
embargo after the serbs that holds your
data and you say no no no that's mine
data
there are cases where the quarter said
no it's not
its beta about you but it is not your
data so therefore you had no standing
to file a lawsuit to protect but Batum
so warrants on this is a criminal this
is kinda related I throw this in cuz I
like this park is
I find this is something valuable to
hackers
cross probable cause to be items seized
container are
evidence for instance from counties are
contraband
usually ninety-five percent the time you
do this
has an IP person we're looking for child
porn
out it seems to me there's a that wasn't
the case is I do this is most cases I
red may because people will litigate
child porn stuff
om this is a different standard than
what you need for discovery were
discovered or just there's litigation
filed yet reactor
yet to show that there's some prove
there's some evidence that the data we
want
were looking for is out there
and you happen wiretap want this allows
you to put a sniper on a system
probable cause and no alternative mad
science like a higher standard than it
had been a warrant
ok extra Communications Act same thing
its
I same thing is just a regular warrant
you don't have to show that there is no
better alternative
so dealing with warrants this is
something you may have to do special if
you run a data center or the like
her to approach its I like to call them
hopeful
are silent if you are a large
institution say for example
a well you mentioned one person does not
show up to a around say we have a
warrant
it back said because a Wells responses
that looks like a war that sealed okay
how do you want the data DVD thumb drive
good
here you go helpful
the silent helpful so you get the nice
officers what they've won
for so they don't take everything
if they have a blunt they can take
everything that they believe they have
Republic cause
is contraband fruits
evidence are contraband so they could
sell
we're taking everything that stores data
in the data center
most if you want holy shit that despite
my uptime
ok node where's the data center in a
truck
and I've read why I bred want to make a
can stop I didn't thought I didn't think
how better
like I'm not gonna arm anything
electronic like
they took the alarm clock call I'm
because the
89 fine shown at you just clear now
and I'm I've I've heard about this I had
not seen it but I've heard rumors that
don't send like the biggest mean as cops
who packed
Dom but okay man get these boxes and the
only tool we have is a para bolt cutters
and that night well well well what do
you wanna I'll play
I'll stop being you know sergeant
douchebag them
the problem is when you're hopeful you
are now betting
when to call you all this stuff haha
second I'll get it for you
you just admitted pigeonhole was there
I want to come to your house others like
you know
%um now you can sell that wasn't my
night how'd you know I was there
Walt said cocaine on the front ok
the sign would approach I don't know
nothin about nothin
take it all good you can claim the bad
stuff isn't yours
they may go to prove it another way but
you're not admitting to it
the problem has nothing Sears can take
everything
and the fun part is what happens in
other people store their stuff on your
boxes
when they take the boxer can search the
box not just the target out the original
search warrant
to think about that for a second so want
offenses
legal file suppression motion baton the
warrant was a legal
you gonna take it away after the fact
you can follow suit give us that stuff
back when you're done
please are in civil rights action in
1983 action
technical offsite backups
in a different jurisdiction so you can
go live eventually
mirror sites season go live when you
click when you switch over be an ass
in crowded campaigners so you can say I
didn't know was there all of my clients
bits our customers happen but the
container I don't have and
I don't have the key so you can take I
can be proud I can be mister finally
nope
here's the incredible container that is
the target of that search for him
have been bad but also said that way you
can say
don't take our other stuff I would ban
as how poor as I can be
of I pictured cat
cuz I wanna have to like here's you know
here's here's the nice passive approach
I couldn't find it
picture became being angry Southam
promise I don't have to take a picture
I'm
a transitive trust think about who you
trust
and who they trust and so on the idea is
this
sometimes information attacker once is
involved with places
so where do you go got good soft target
of course
less interest in protecting me film I
has weaker security
same them you maybe
are in Crescent you our wiki leaks see
him
have a spec you have a bunch attorneys
jon benet just to fuck with the system
and back with the man to defend miss far
I am going to have someone is some
if given the same data is on some small
cloud provider that's like
I have got a realist I know where
somewhere
fine don't have the data over they'll
give it up
soda hard armored target the angry one
is gonna it fine the same date as in
another box
sober example one
subpoena card providers have an account
holder the cloud provider
may just give you one it's faster easier
may not even alert the data holder
and as an example people be Harris I
don't wanna go into it
arm but no expectation privacy and we'd
public trough
tweets and the tweets for twenty years
not be on
not create or so therefore you have no
privacy rights and ad
I example number two this is a new
medication
Tucson two companies get into either a
merger and acquisition deal or
litigation
their peak each Olympics debate in hands
of 20 discovery provider that may have
shit secured
I'll as the attacker don't go after the
company with the big InfoSec Department
I don't have to be discovering vendor
which may not even have good physical
security I walk under the
I walk into the the floor grab the data
I've worked when he discovered a vendor
we had no security
you could have walked in and cake and
rights they were DNA evidence bad but
I've noticed this
evidence bags Rep really easy I can grab
the Gator
I'm all that I P walks out the door are
a few people buy stock at the bright
time
however it's going to be okay
soothing picture macadam
what can you do learn how to speak to
the lawyers
in your organization about these
problems how do you want to approach
them so that when you're being proactive
you like what
I think about the security staff more
than you do.
and I would like hope you do your job so
we both protect the organization
educate them about security don't talk
down to them
be their peers to convince them that
this doesn't need to be
outsourced we want someone to be on his
way to hire an outside vendor to search
our stuff
fuck I can do that I can do that cheaper
and better and more securely than you
can then you're outside vendor can
design a while the stuff it's
I will happily handle that for you
bratter
what tony has grabbed work what can you
do continued
discovery on its this is we go to
integrate who has
access to what and where the systems are
does that sound familiar
I did he discover a vendor I did he
discover the audits and slide
this could be tapped on the regular
security on
in fact it should be because it's the
same damn thing but because I'm an
attorney I get the bill
some notable because I said it simply
discovery audit not
a regular Security Auditor the ability
to backup everything has the ability to
preserve everything
you don't need a necessary by a special
e-discovery package
which are usually crappy you can just
say I need to grab stuff
I can grab stuff help but the vendors
figure out if they can protect your shit
any questions are kinda card
we have two minutes of be quick moon
so you talked about grad and in the
discovery process
a friend of mine works for the
Department of Justice
antitrust division and in addition to
looking for a tax documents yes
thousands and thousands about wiretaps
from so he has a lot of the enzyme
you know China discovery so what are you
think
is possible when would you like to see
poor on time's cover beetle so we can
stop burning these back some money
am i doing then it's not because my mind
isn't bad I'm
anything it just lets you search
thinking it's just been a
and we think about how to search beat-up
all the time in ways that the
e-discovery vendors
don't what if you miss something
i fuck up every day
now I'm gonna be serious you're not
going to get killed for fucking up
occasionally as long as you meet a
best-effort
of one minute I'll take one more
question
on what about us documents that
need to have longer life spans like
research methods
who are product documentation or being
hold on to it as long as you need to
you have to be able to give it was over
when you've got it and you have to know
that you've got it
I'm it's more that if you're following a
their attention thing that you have to
destroy it
only been I don't think I'm under same
question many
if you entered a retention policy that
says if it's all in the nineteen is
reduced rates
okay and you have this docking in my
cock
notes on a program that you're you prime
need to refer to:
a year down the line when you're
updating at on
have do you can write granular
dis you can write granular I'll passes
policies words like this we hold for a
long time this we don't
okay thank you thanks thank you
next way