up security for drinking water because I
come up a background as a
water Commissioner for thirteen years in
Massachusetts
are my day job is %uh
is doing it. tech support and so on in
mine non day job the
with be nice to turn to a gay jobs is
security research quote-unquote
I was a former lobbyist for in violation
see an environmental
a group up a beginning talks at here
and a duck on black cat in the churros
on the road this is my seventh talk this
year god help me
are speaking yeah spoke on drinking
water infrastructure security at three
locations God a wireless water meter up
at two locations talk a virtually tap
konnen
like at last year and a given earlier
version of this talk a thought Khan in
Chicago but this is the much improved
version
arm and I've written some articles based
upon my water department experience
I'll in the journal throwing the Water
Works Association
and my black cat I'll white paper
on wireless water meters actually the
part of it that was on
general drinking water arm a security
was published in the book weapons of
mass destruction terrorism
a second edition om which came out
earlier this year
which is used as a text book a universal
all I think also at West Point
are so I'm trying to and developing my
expertise in
writing on these matters so just talk
actually came outta my research
originally talk to someone earlier I
give a talk at Def Con 2010 on general
drinking water infrastructure security
and
that led to my talk last year on white
water meter security
or lack thereof and and hack ability
while its water meters when they become
prevalent and that led to this talk
which is
should have a further fine-grained way
finding out how to use water
in your home another activities in your
home arm
so arm the outline basically is
I have to mention at I did some research
on the tele screen now I look for a
picture from the original show
this is sort of an IA out adj inside
joke to the prisoner
it's Patrick McGoohan playing a former
secret agent for those who don't know
who when he resigned she should have
kidnapped and brought to
the village which is beautiful little
town in an island or
somewhere no one really knows where it
is and it's like a gilded cage is
beautiful everyone's dressed nicely this
was an activities but this 24-hour
around-the-clock
total surveillance just like right now
in the US arm and but his I try to find
a follow this but this artist was the
only thing they had it so
so for his private residence
quote-unquote it says private which a
corset isn't
because they can see and hear everything
he does and everything
you know in and everything he you know
and everyone else
so that was sort of just the inside joke
arm
number six I'm not a number I'm a free
man
et cetera so arm before get the
more infrastructure mediated sensing the
actual topic
up the talk I wanted to give some brief
introduction privacy
I'll all warn you that that's what is so
to take over because
the slaughter by the talks that might be
go into more detail
over threats to privacy these days but
I'm it hit a couple key things
to look at outside the home what privacy
do we have in what threats there are
and I'll talk about this technology
which is inside the home
so the tele screen this is from the
movie
wars peace freedom is slavery ignorance
is strength
%uh as you may know from the book and
the movie detail screen is a two-way
video %uh that it really explain the
book with technology was it didn't
really matter
arm work which can see everything in
with the Smiths homebody found this
little corner worst part
where he thought they couldn't see a man
here he found out later course that they
course are things going so
the tele screen has been developed I
Apple has a patent for art
I want read every slide I a course %uh
by: how's it different than a a video
screen on a laptop with the
with camera well it's the real video
screen so they've got the
the view the view a bowl know that the
video receiver
is integrated in with the the output so
so you don't know there's a camera with
these and
up my understanding is that sharp %uh is
coming out with some
some that are similar to that as well so
are I could find information that Apple
was actually coming over that we know
the Apple TV
might be coming are I don't know whether
it's the same thing
so that the point is that ap you know
from George Orwell sorta
coming up with to it as a without trying
to design deter actually say would
happen
it was a device in the book arm it's
it's something that
is is on its way it's not here already
answer privacy is under attack so here's
number six being chased by Rover
so in the village where those cameras
everywhere in in
and microphones everywhere whenever you
do something that you're not supposed to
rover appears out of nowhere in that
I'll explain what rover is but it is big
which weather balloon competent has a
life of its own its is alive or is it
I mean what is it president charge than
a smothers you wake up in a real jail
cell and god knows you know than
than they really start to work on you so
arm and there's another
was on again there's a lot of talks this
conference about privacy some blood to
add to that
total weight above discussion on it and
that hit some things
and the high points before I get to the
main topic to talk
but who was watching who wasn't watching
is is a good question
so while I just throughout this new
speak definition
course in the news big dictionary there
would be no word privacy the last one
number five
arm but it's interesting you read
privacidade the
disclosures on some web sites and it
summer them there's some some of them
actually say that includes collecting
data on you
or your your you're agreeing that data
will be collected
arm so arm d
the definition a privacy that
institutions and businesses
are are coming up with is certainly
could be different than what
most people think it our cameras I was
in Chicago for talk on a few months ago
and I didn't see
lots of cameras but according to our
study
by ACLU they've 10,000 or they're
working on getting ten thousand that RB
wall the wall to the city arm
and the objective is to cover city from
one end to the other
up so that's up so above
that this is a generic pictures on the
internet up for surveillance cameras
and this is want the cameras at the in
the village
are numbered I'm gonna be pop the
village references be popping in and out
here
on my favorite soda analogy to work I
mean
were we all over the bill it right arm
so
is many other cities that are are
covering a cameras wall to wall and kick
almost anywhere without a surveillance
camera run to 711 or school or
institution or police station
on in urine a private facilities in the
camera
and arts OECD its on public in in in
popular movies you see a lot of places
where they hack into the camera and they
find you when they can follow you around
arm which probably could happen but but
the point is all those
this visual information is being
collected and some other may
right over the information or or not
stored but
some a drones
now this is this is really something
some on looking at outside your home
what's the
threats to privacy so I
this a lot of activity coming out on the
web about drones
that there are a number facilities being
about
conceptualized in the US proposed for
drone bases
and it could either be the sum big
drones
for these baby drones
and some really small ones are coming
out there like fireflies
they're hard to see arm and then the US
Army has blimps a course
so anything a real and %uh some hackers
have developed their own versions
been presented black hat and DEFCON last
year
arm but a there's a possibility so a lot
of governments
and local a large force min can nom
can apply to use drones and they've
declared to the FAA
but drones arm becoming more pervasive
your car so I believe the so a bill
in congress I don't know if it's passed
to our require
a black boxes like an airplane to be in
your car
a lot a car still have them have now
this the Nash
so that that records data on where you
travel
of faster going things like that which
is very useful in an accident
investigation
com so beautiful tune of that car
driving has a black box
the national vehicle locator service
keeps a database
up pictures I love love license plates
on so that when the government to the
DEA or the or the FBI's looking for
someone like
that's 11 the sources they can tap into
to
to try to locate someone are GPS
locators
I think it was a up a the circuit court
decision
which may or may not be nationwide but
that was a decision saying you can't be
place without a permit
don't worry they'll find try to find a
way around that
and personal ads and geolocation like in
minority report
I was gonna do with the move what movie
or Ian but its it's hard to say they
also overlap
but in my report he's walking through
with the fake ice from
from that from the the FAA's eyes
replaced
and they're responding to the retinal
scan and they're giving a personalized
ads based upon who
with the eyes usually you used to belong
to arm
and those are under development are
immersive laps
beds cameras and displays and there are
some a retail locations now that our
up have networks where they the they
find your cell phone
to get your Mac address: and they can we
get to who you are
om and then give you personalized ads
based upon a database of where you been
and in your shopping and French
billboards
I'm told call your cell phone time I try
to get dumped a lot of the things that
the point is
some there's a lot of things chipping
away on
it's for the government its marketers
try sell you something
I its its all the above
secret code in color printers age had to
mention this I I learned about this by
it
watching me cook Nicole hi Colin kanan
in the TED Talks up he said in you know
for example in nineteen eighties during
the Cold War
ish in Germany every whatever type array
had to register it so that the
government could find out
you know and then give us ample so he
wrote something critical the government
or something that in like they could to
find out who typed it well deff and I
think marcia happens here
she's here now but effect this year as
done a study where they try to document
the secret codes that are now in laser
printers
for many laser printers on so that the
government
can do the same thing now now maybe not
to
suppressed free speech of course why
would they do that
on but the if they want to identify Word
document came from
it's possible with the secret codes that
are in like light colored yellow or
green or
something you can obviously see arm to
check the EF F website
forum documentation on on and some other
codes have been able to decode
arm so me going to stalk
he was surprised said people should know
about this he surprised how many people
don't know this
and I didn't know it so I figured I'd
throw it in because that's a serious
invasion of privacy
type something up be printed out you
make copies and
somebody you the cover someone else who
knows the code can figure out
which machine it was and maybe track
back to you so
it's it's this really know when to this
sort of chipping away at
doing something privately warrantless
eavesdropping
again I will read everything but its
you know started with portion Obama's
been keeping keeping it going
on but don't worry selection on a
terrace you nothing to worry about
so a it's only international they sure
so international naval
listen to anyone who's point not talking
about something with a foreign
foreign address but we shall should be
worried because again it's
its thousands or millions have phone
calls and data
%uh that's being collected
a people cell phones so again others
its ourselves so there's people
everywhere taking a picture
or video a Google Glasses
if they takeoff on that a picture right
there
I'll was a threat there well it's again
it's developing data
so you walk around cool glasses and its
ability database
Google which course remembers everything
they have service going back to
beginning have Google the record
everything that
you know and every search ever done any
anything that anyone's ever done
on their pages saw an add to that total
database to courses for useful to
marketers
and maybe maybe other parties arm
and a I ran into an interesting web page
it's a joke
or maybe side a joke saying hey the
government really succeeded in getting
people to voluntarily disclose what
they're doing
which is what lot of people do want
Facebook Twitter
a LinkedIn
MySpace and off thats all around arm but
a lot of people
a the I think mostly teenagers and high
school students
up just tell people everything you're
doing and then they're shocked
shocked that people ur you know talking
about what they do
and Jeff auction aka to reporters here
they did a story on early this year
on it is also a threat though even if
you're not on Facebook
people can talk about what you doing on
Facebook any information about you can
still leak out
so long and a course Facebook is
monetize at into the billions
and been so it's a useful tool with but
this millions a
appoint a data being collected for
marketers and God knows who else
soldiers arm so it's ourselves Pogo you
know
we've seen the enemy its ourselves and a
course I just saw this
a couple days ago I am so airports
I invasion of privacy is we enter on you
note
get on a flight there are a new laser
scanners
per which 50 meters awaken see
everything
10 million times faster 1,000,000 times
more sensitive than the current
available system
and you have to be in line again it
course they're talking about it for
airports but
why not anywhere else you know arm
so that's the headline from Gizmodo so
the stories and Gizmodo
on or give credit to the judge in a a
Jenny a that a photonics kiko
second programmable laser scanner
can look at you and fight so
sorry right at the bottom there to Jan
jin et a today a
so on this is not into this is not
intend to be a thorough discussion
love erosion a privacy outside the home
but its it cover to cover some
some major issues that I've seen so far
so the big question is do the walls have
a home protect privacy anymore
so Chris Desmond a master's thesis
candidate
on looking at on some use a law school
in Canada I believe are looked at this
question
and had in this great quote the walls
and maintain the privacy the man's
appears a thousand years have been made
obsolete by stacking logical advances
so wasn't that long ago that you know
you're inside your home
and you're safe from private from being
so gone
arm across such a real class home i'd of
family lives in it
but its the conceptual design by an
Italian a design team
to somebody well-known technologies as
tempers attack
%uh outside the home can read electronic
a signature
a electronic emissions from me monitor
literacy are key are I presume also from
an LCD but I'm not sure
arm and and there's a way to read what
you're typing on the on the monitor
keep your viewing can be read revealed a
smart electric meter there's a paper
that came out in Germany
last year I'll like in Chorley com
sort of are the timing up when they know
that the keys on
and they can detect the channel arm you
just match it up with the schedule and
you can find what someone's watching
are electric meter signal sousa a talk
at Def Con last year
on I think David Kennedy on how a few
the electric meter
just to get a reading the fluctuations
in in New
electric use you can determine are
what's going on inside the house
from electric arm I activity not
comes close to 1 I'll be talking about
in the poker the talk
course tapping in in eavesdropping on on
computers is no no mystery on and your
Internet activity
are but we're were going going to it
another level
are in the stalk on that so
course a smart grid so I gave a talk
last year action early this year twice
and Lasher like at DEFCON on are smart
water meters
Wireless water meters and on
when I did the research I didn't realize
at the beginning that the major concern
to be privacy
so are right now your water department
presumably is
has a mechanical meter hit most place
the US
that is red quarterly because they have
to pay someone to go out
knock on the door called on the basement
read the meter on
you said that about seven percent of US
homes have
up have smart meters to go beyond that
that are
well wireless meters anyway that sent a
signal up
on in the venture sending a signal out
or having received for summer driving by
the home
or received a central facility for
billing is that
you can change the frequency such you
don't have to pay for people to go out
and arm read the meters you can you
can't you can check on the frequency of
water use
every our everyday every five minutes
which is very useful to the water
department to determine leaks determined
people using water on that supposed to
are but it also gives you a very
fine-grained art detailed information
water use to you can use to determine
what's going on home
so this is I am just one piece for my
talk
on Wiles water meters where are from a a
online newspaper called the Carrie
watchman are from Cary North Carolina
that the right to be concerned about the
information our private lives
the town self able to collect from the
acostar AM I water meter system
is is is implemented om and they give a
call from a technology futurist keynote
speaker at ok
conference on they can tell when to take
a shower when taken
messages from the water meter I'll get
into techniques that are even
more useful than that too funny what you
doing
are I gave up my wireless wattmeter talk
in madison wisconsin yesterday
and after I gave the talk I talk to some
people from the University
wisconsin where I give the talk in the
city we found out that
that the city Madison Wisconsin just
bought aka
pit wall to sign a contract to install
you know tens of thousands while
swatting Israel the city
and like most in the got a cryptid the
you something called frequency hopping
spread spectrum
which you know is thought it was
encrypted in which came into war to
it's a but its obscurity so every packet
is sent out
%uh with the different frequency that
presumably only the sender and the
receiver now
the trouble is it's not really
encryption and there are
fairly easy ways to to break that arm
but in any event up whether or not the
water department is going to be sinister
and use the information
on somehow based upon what your home
I don't think as a former water
Commissioner I'd I really doubt the law
going to do that missus a personal thing
going on in some
some in the water department wants to
get someone who based upon the data
the trouble is the date is created in
Atlas forever
and was gonna go so privacy is the
biggest
a question you see out there mostly for
the smart grid for electricity
for gas in for water
okay here we go infrastructure mediated
single point sensing like
having a long technical term arm
infrastructure sensing is my shorthand
for
on so its use a existing-home
infrastructure
so this is a way without having to chip
you which upon you
or or a or a transmitter or already
a microphone or have cameras in the home
find what you doing in the home
now getting to you white anybody would
want to do that in a
good sense arm the contactor the term in
human activity
I'll so eliminate the need for sensors
or or
chips I'll work with other such a device
and methods
this is not the same thing is a smart
home which
we've been reading about in science
fiction for many years but
still hasn't come to fruition on Iran
arc on the smart home a while ago when
the main reason maybe people why people
why would you need it
though there are applications out there
that arse are similar to the smart home
where you have a home area network we
can help settle control over
appliances which is good for rum you
know
controlling I'll electricity use if you
want lower your electric bill
arm sold most this these devices in this
research comes primarily at the
ubiquitous computing research lab
Ubicomp
at the University of Washington are its
copper basic computing
are ubiquitous computing bigness means
everywhere
arm these are not in production yet but
there's a lotta research in a number
papers on the web
about this so sustainability to reduce
yousef natural resources like water
get natural gas on fossil fuels for the
most part
that power electricity anna's use for
arm health something
and so these are some other purposes at
the propose
for are so hiker sets this is how I got
into it and looking at
I'll Wireless water meters read about
hyder cents
in this is very tech technically this is
very absurdist cated
but very simple so arm so you wanna find
out
are what so with this device on the back
up with this device
you that's very simple small device it
doesn't cost much
your cash into any pizza plumbing in the
house
and after being calibrated as a little
whiles
transceiver on it I have to be
calibrated you can tell
which fixture was turned on or off in a
particular time
and how much water is used and you can
develop a very
precise database up water use
so toilet faucet shower
tub kitchen on
I mean everywhere on and in it uses
something called
police cells law were a which I won't
read
arm but these craft give you the idea
apart works is that the
the open event when you when you I know
from experience in
in water you know when you open to close
a valve you create a water hammer
which creates a sound or in a vibration
and so this read it and I can tell the
difference between an open to close
arm so strong device
a miss a change in pressure on its up to
wireless
and there are on so there's less its
battery-powered
but there's a but the really been
working on it as one that actually
powers itself from the water
going the vibrational water going to the
pipe %uh
so there there there's there's a lot of
development work going on this these are
not a production yet
not the ones that I'm talking about an
hour in production yet but
they may I'll talk about why gas sense
so this is attached to where the gas
enters the house
are are and it uses sound
toward it so it listens to the sound of
the gas
natural gas ensuring the house she's a
hot water heating Stouffer's fireplace
clothes dryers
so those things don't muscles don't use
water solar covers
are are some different bases
arm so they're a couple studies that I
quoted from here
are so calibrated by turning gas
appliances on our offer recording sounds
so saw that these are can be put in
surreptitiously
on and suddenly figure these things out
although
I'm sure some could figure that out but
at this point you have to put it on
so this it's a lot still being studied
you put it on you do the calibration
any good the same thing that you with
Tiger sent you determine what's been
turned on or off
and how much gas is used arm so
so that so the the the the successes
that helps provide a complete picture
whole-home human activity know what you
doing in the house along with water use
new Eagle feedback to buy still Peters
monitor perhaps reduce our natural gas
usage
so that's a beneficial use right to
reduce use natural gas
you get the same benefit as natural gas
by using lesson you're paying less
so that's good right elector cents
so arm so the switch mode power supplies
will turn
most appliances a.m. is a high-frequency
electromagnetic
I on pulse and
I it as a signature specific to a device
and a defect but electricity is easy in
that sense com P
Kors so i cant so that's everything else
in the house as electrical
location sensing and this is just a part
picture
so they could there are devices you can
put it if you've got a a
up air conditioning system a check
system
in the house or building on most houses
may not have that
in New England anywhere I live in the
eastern US but maybe
other parts the country doing a course
apartments condos
are government facilities private
facilities have them as well
arm so a single sensor
just can detect the disruption in air
flow last 35 eighty percent accurate can
determine
wheres that you know one or two people
where they're going what what their
activities are in the house
are smart for such an easy way to do it
so the pressure sensors
in a grid in the house and you can
calibrated so you know who's walking and
who in where they're walking
and and and in get a database of the
exactly what's going on there
powerline positioning this this means
you have to have something on you
like a a chip or met re: microphone or
something
arm so the so so you got water
gas-electric om location
so they can find out what you doing in
the house
and again these are that the I'm not
saying this is done surreptitiously
someone's installing select knowing it
would be very hard in most cities
but that's not what the ideas arm
so the the the acronym is ATL activities
of daily life
so who went where who did what up here
automation
so this is a um try to find some more
examples for this but this is the best
one so it so you get a pattern
from these different answers and this
pattern set out there having breakfast
on so looks at what this i think is
primarily water but you get water and
gas
and a location there in the kitchen the
kitchen faucet on
are still arm you know there's enough
water to put key in the cattle or
or make make make a copy so to having
breakfast
others a different pattern for for
dinner might be some lower
different pattern for going to bed
different at different pattern for
other things you're doing so you even a
replication sensors they can find out
from the water and gas electricity what
rooms people are doing things in
in the more sense as you add are the
more information you get
are behavior automation health status
that's one the beneficial uses in a.m.
and correlate with other information are
so they're a lot of studies on this
arm the massive studies I'll were
actually that the researchers trying to
find out now
so if we put all the sensors in on
there in a couple problems like running
out electrical outlets for someone like
me
need power on their own you run into
electrical interference from one set
you several frequencies so the working
that out up don't worry
to working that out and and and so it's
ok to be easier and simpler
to build the house or condo or
government facility
were they can track everything you doing
I mean why not okay so health monitoring
in the home
I'll elderly in assisted living
facilities
those are two so the similar things so
looking at water use
mom mobility %uh
it you can get help indications on
and there's a lot of fine-grained
analysis but done
for many years said elderly home elderly
in assisted living facilities where you
know
a there's an 80 in the home or visit the
home or their camera switch
is intrusive so we so the way doing
without cameras
so you can see a reduction in mobility
%uh the toilet it uses much
other not drawing water the night doing
something
that that's a health issue arm that's
the easy one to figure out there are
many others
that a years love assisted living
research I can correlate with some of
these things to look at
help so that's a good thing so you have
assisted living facility
in a city paying for it an aide to be in
each with the person all the time or
visit us
you probably wanna visit once a while
you can set these things up
and set up on the computer and you know
have a flag go off if certain things
happen
so that's that a a positive intent ovett
arm resource in water conservation
are soul which can help people who want
to conserve
resources water gas electricity
cuz they can get fine-grained
information on their use
so if they want to reduce our electric
bill they can get report daily
weekly monthly annually whatever
to say okay you this is your bill this
is what you used
during this time and so you voluntarily
the positive so far you can voluntarily
say oh yeah I don't really need to use
that as much I'll
or reduce that and all the bill save
money same thing with water
don't leave the for you know don't leave
the faucet running on
take a shot take a bath and separate
shower usership you know
there there's is also still rules you
can follow this is a way of helping you
of all those rules to on achieve micro
sustainability meaning free a little
home arm
to be sustainable in terms of are
conserving natural resources
and improve their lives so what's wrong
with improve your life right
home health monitoring so there's a lot
of stuff on this that's not what I'm
talking about specifically but there's
wearable matter medical sensors
embedded medical sensors that the whole
all the talk
arm they can't be hacked right course
they can
on the slaughter research in that as
well on packing pacemakers
and the implantable defibrillators
because they're Wireless and they're not
a cryptid
in most cases arm but again up
so there's a lot of arm by to find
monitoring
motion analysis I mentioned earlier
parkinson's disease is one application
where you can look at
mobility our actions and correlated with
some
you know health are early detection
arm in his first responder prove like
quality
so the lot there's a lot of good
research on this community where home
resurgence
initiative in Georgia kak they have like
a a model home setup
where they experiment with these things
and again the intent is positive in
terms of
how do we make home health monitoring so
someone is in
put into a home but there in their home
but I T set these things up so that
someone hill to the contract from
outside can keep track at the sayings
and get a top or something
say it's of the fall on the floor or
there's a the there's a
episode this information can get
electronically sent to the
to the caregiver all the monitor and
and respond arm so there's a whole
buncha technology in addition to what
I'm talking about
that that works on this in this field as
well
so assisted livings I've mentioned a few
times a
alarm at University Virginia smart
medical home
aware home Georgia Tech again so they're
looking at
arm so this is mortars stuff but again
on
sort along the same idea I'll see you
get something on on the person
so I can check their heart P the blood
pressure
on but in addition to the other a a
infrastructure mediated technologies I
gives you a richer picture
up what the activity is to help are
protect the health of the person
us a resource conservation I'll soul
reduce unnecessary use of scarce
resources
on reducing violent missions reduced
cover for put all the good stuff
the term is Microcenter bility on
so we get detail information on your
water use
you can review that yourself voluntarily
ever issues are
so if your municipality your state has
water conservation
requirements or recommendations it helps
you fall that
say that for natural gas and electric
use
on and so does their papers written
about this sis
sippy in goals arm life improvement
goals
so improve health fitness so again if
you had these in your home
you could so instead of writing that
down what your activities are which is a
good wave
above feedback for yourself arm you can
this'll give you you know how often to
drop their figure air hole how much is
use the water
arm if you have the four sensors are the
effects such as you can
you can check in your movements in the
house arm
saw can capture all the info are make
use that information by Traci
performance
and a as a whole our school of thought
research on am and up terrible affinity
Asian for some reason today
mean the name center architecture
on wary it did it further develops data
that's collected
through these infrastructure mediated
sensing to
to the track
talking a rock nothing right I mean
that's a favor hacker question so I
research the things I look at
you know like most you well this is what
they intended to be four
but you know wenis what if something
ever use just for what's intended
I'll see if data leakage and arm
but also are I think that the problem is
less that the government
god forbid is gonna require some %uh
these things should say water
conservation
to be the biggest application but it
might be your landlord
or your next landlord where are the
condo association
are all the you know are who says so
they're under pressure
wall get to that arm so the wireless
sensors such as could be hacked
collected Turkish isley I increase the
reach surveillance into the home
arm the the evidence could be
falsified could abuse in a criminal case
I'll could be inaccurate maybe softballs
if I did just wrong
but some attacks apart so this is a
laundry list div
some things that could go wrong so let's
look at them
will the data leak out no course not arm
I started a catalog this her just the
list is too long
and in and it had everyday read about
more
on laptops being left at to airports
with the health data
or 50,000 social security numbers on
someone hacked a database in his
password the username
that happens every day om credit card
numbers
a health information and I read
somewhere that Steve's will pay ten
times more personal health information
for credit cards
I don't know why maybe someone here
knows why but that's that's the
information available find credit cards
actually at work that much because
on there there the
the theft has detected in there they're
closed they're they're close up pretty
quickly apparently
arm but you get it you got social
security number well that's that's a
fake identity
as identity theft which is rampant arm
now Pachuca %uh which is now quite a lot
bien
ours an online database know it's a good
thing where people
accumulate the data from monitoring
various things
I am from from building monitoring
systems from
Wireless data so I'm not saying it's a
bad thing
but again here's more and more data up
this type that's on the Internet
that builds a pattern builds a database
up thanks
so it's an iPhone app which you know
could be hacked are so so there's more
more information
I try to lookup are how much information
is there in the world
ended keeps increasing a exponentially
or more
arm and how much information and
personal behavior
is there in the world and that's
increasing exponentially
so that's a whole nother talk right
there because that these technologies in
Pachuca
and people monitoring themselves for the
for good purposes
and these a health monitoring up
data probably never goes away and as it
accumulates
it it did it creates problems
perhaps in the future for houses day
going to use like Tim
gigantic database that Google has on all
of us
%uh course the government could get it
very easily
up from whoever the second third parties
that get the information
work they sell the information on
so data data leaks out
it's it's a rule elector camp I just
read about
arm so up for the Internet of Things is
another topic
is another word for what we're talking
about to the Internet of Things
everything
but with ipv6 taking off finally
everything's good have an IP address
and get the on internet almost
automatically so you can control or
monitor it from anywhere
with your iPhone years your Android or
or whatever
%uh so this is another way of putting it
on the Internet
arm any you can save resources so you
can
with with elector camp or many other
applications like this in
their ads now on on on on TV in in the
media
for monitoring your home to your
smartphone which is a great idea
you know so but the data get screwed
gets created
so it's not as much at the that that
summer's gonna hack into your smartphone
in
and control your home or check your
video
without you knowing it which course will
occur but on top of that all this data
is being collected
and and and um and accumulated
so this is from %uh this is a quote from
their web page
arm it's just another way a farm
you know a database being created from
these type devices
and I'm I tried I'm not saying and being
fucked exhaustive in the type devices
that use infrastructure mediated sensing
arm
a lot of people use different terms for
similar things
so the Internet of Things as you pick it
was ubiquitous computing
pervasive computing I everything's
becoming Wireless with an IP address
being on the Internet
and many of them track what you do in
your home
what you do anywhere else and it's gonna
be hard to escape from that
if it is already intercourse under CISPA
I try to look at the recent this the big
love news about this earlier in the year
and I try to find the latest in as far
as I know it's
stills passed by the House Obama this
does people saying that Obama's will
sign it
if it passed the Senate but maybe FF
explain what's going on the senate I
couldn't find the latest information
but done the biggest problem for what
we're talking about
notwithstanding any other provision of
law which has very broad term meaning
this you can do it companies may share
information
including federal government so like in
the while Wireless while a cat
wiretapping the
the telcos were just giving information
to the federal government
well any any these entities that collect
this type information
can just give it to the federal
government on request without you
knowing about it
you need a search warrant you don't need
a subpoena arm
you don't get a wiretap you don't need
up his mother
a secret court it's just out there
so that's another way that information
this information will be go
so Google could be watching I'm sorry
is watching I am
so so it gets worse so Google is right
on top is a course
there there there in the cutting-edge so
they're talking about
actually getting a stated themselves
surprise surprise
I mean the Google number has an update a
so they wanna home activity recognition
I'm reading a some saying
the sounds familiar that's what we're
talking about to track people's
activities are home network interactions
so they talk about the home area network
re electric lectric you
your electric appliances well I think
that's what the talking about
among other things your home area
network which were electric appliances
are networked
and you get a central control center
that you can access to your smartphone
most likely
where you can turn things on or off
remotely or in your home which is very
useful
course its wireless it on the internet
so Google wants
what to do with that information they're
gonna just do to protect your right
arm so to remind you to work take
medication
so they know medication you're taking
well that's not that's good that's very
helpful
cogent act more safely member I Robot
you know the Three Laws of Robotics
so they can help you act more safely
so I can prevent you from doing things
that could hurt you
that's a good thing right what I
recommend changes in behavior
I'm not liking this very much so far on
so using UPnP n product discovery
protocol which is fairly universal
grace into stable operation so there
this is still under development
I guess but don't worry they get the
money they'll figure out how to do it
so this is independent of what I was
talking about the city but
could be integrated with it very easily
on so his
your I'm stealing stuff from one other
what are their web pages or a discussion
about this
something about this leaked out and then
a Google someone from Google denied it
but then
the there's a paper with a talk about it
arm
SQL database all those can't be hacked
uses
event notification technology was forced
out as control variables at us
comin home network device like computers
phones and TVs game consoles
booking 7 include other types sensors
nice
cut off I stop Cup stop calling it so
yeah Google with the Google Glasses and
your Google web page in your Google
gmail and everything Google
arm so the that ups the ante a little
I think and bat attack okay so let's say
for the infrastructure mediated sensing
and this comes from the same researchers
at University Washington right but said
the crypt
they know that the privacy issue okay
I'm not saying they don't know that
they do this privacy issue so they're
working on a crippling it so one the
researchers said well what if
what is a cryptid can you still find out
what's going on in the house and the
answer is
yes to a fingerprint and timing based
snooping attack tek-tips /a side-channel
attack
so you don't need to read the
transmissions from the individual
infrastructure sensing devices
you just have to know when the signals
come out
so they say so they put motion sensors
so the basic research
without actually reading the signals
they were still able to read the terms
they acted as a
activities a daily life such a sleeping
bathroom kitchen visits bathroom
activities
catch activities and high-level health
information
it's very sophisticated so you don't
have to read the signal you not to
decode it
you just have to know when the signal
occurred and where it came from
see if you look at the fingerprint you
have to know what motion sensor or
device it came from
so that mean look at okay how do we
protect against that which is good
so it's nice research being done this
and that they're looking at
the attack and the defense the question
will be when these things actually gone
production
will these helpful to have these are not
so so the protectionist signal
signal attenuators say send the signal
out
not when the activity occurs but sup
some random time after that
rain delays are attenuated you reduce
the
I'm sorry that's when you reduce the M
how far the signal goes
periodic transmission so you don't so
you time it so incentive
sending the signal when the activity
Kors you you time into every 15 minutes
for every 20 minutes or whatever
goes out so you can't %uh a used without
attack to
correlate the timing of it with the
activity fingerprint masking
again arm I don't know if the only to UN
NP um identify run of the mac address
some other yep that you have to know
what devices coming from obviously
so you you you you mask it somehow
or you put in Fig transmissions so the
good news is he's
these people art evil who are coming up
with things they are trying to do it for
beneficial reasons
they are thinking about some love the
negative uses ovett
this a course doesn't protect against
the fact that the data is actually
collected anyway and it's in a database
somewhere by
their company or another company and the
day to cancel the actual traded
were stolen or given to the government
or taken by the government
but at this at least protects you from
someone scooping from outside the house
if they put these in place
but who would want this information so
the site after this from a discussion
on now electric Smart Meters I'll go to
the whole thing
not all the supply I couldn't give a
story for each of these
on but across utility some talking to a
smart meter
are but lot the still apply see
so you get arm so soul for
for water conservation what if up the
a company that sells water conservation
devices or elector conservation are
Natural Gas Conservation they get the
database and they figure out that
here's a list to people in the city who
who are complying with the
conservation requirements or that they
know want to conserve
gas or electricity use or water more
and they get a database initially signed
a marketing email or
or mailing if they still use a lil our
law enforcers
arm again there have been some cases
arm where water use has been the
that the FBI goes to the water utility
in fines owed excessive water use
and says she may be there maybe they're
growing marijuana
or maybe there cooking math because they
also higher
electric use arm so this gives you more
fine-grained information
but what if are you think someone's
holding someone hostage ur kidnapping
that's a good thing but you can't take
it for major bear how many people in the
house
by looking at the water use electrocuted
cetera
arm so there's a whole bunch love
potential uses
that I couldn't pick up but it's
probably here somewhere
and arts NCCA vices are to the market
yet it's hard to see
and Ivan examples actually happening but
the bad news is that
this information is collected even if we
can't think right now
how could be used badly don't worry
somebody will
okay so a bad way I'm in favor aye I
used to be work for environmental
agencies and environmental groups ol
water conservation is a good thing
general because even if you have plenty
water quote-unquote
any miss appellee it's not going to last
forever spot with population in business
increasing so Walker fish is a good
thing however should be make people do
it
well a lot Cup sometimes you have to
make people do it
I have to have a law how do you enforce
a law very hard
so are some examples our San Francisco
LA architects is a lead certification
I don't member the acronym stands for
but we're a building is is energy
and environmentally efficient and and
and conservation wise
so what if arm the building its pockets
X s now regular part putting in a
building is these water meter
what hyder sense and lighter sentence on
I'll wanna throughout the building codes
because it's now a community
our priority to reduce use arm
what I think the biggest threat would be
probably that dot is first in california
which is under strict
requirements to reduce water use 20
percent by 2020
which is very hard to do once you've
eliminated watering lawns if you can
and are easy thanks arm
it looks like a a natural for me that
California would require
municipalities to meet the requirement
miss a palace to meet it would say
okay landlord congo owner I am building
superintendents
you have to require your tenants to put
these things in so you can monitor
are the water use and then slap their
hands or required to do things to meet
the requirement
i think thats for the most likely are
the way this will be applied
but again these are the market yet so
we'll see force better living
okay I my favorite movie for this is a
course on
demolition man course and %uh
there there there's a lot pasan in
middle on Massachusetts to
to prohibit public swearing now they
don't have these
had a little devices that they listen to
you and give you a fine
and it's very its what
yes that's right so that's very useful
device for us serve us for their
I so worried running outta time now so I
read all this but done
%uh so there are there are regulations
out there that look at
the intrusive to what you do in your
home to protect people
and this could be way doing at use a
large force meant
okay Minority Report pre crime well
obviously we're not gonna have three
cocks doing this but the FBI is looking
at using big data
to look at activity outside the home but
maybe the keys inside the home
you put the day together and you can
figure out things
that may or may not be accurate for
example target there's a big story out
no well those that I caught target has
figured out a way
target up stores that sell other things
but when a woman is pregnant based upon
if they buy she buys a few things
they know before she does or husband
anyway that she's pregnant
and it was accurate this in one case
which was created the story
that's the only example I know where you
could put all this data together and
suddenly
bomb so sure the FBI's I get GetData
crackers working on that right now
a good and very quickly here I apologize
that the conclusions
okay this this number six again
beginning at the show
are and there's Tom Cruise a course arm
so there are benefits from these nothing
that they're not
are but like anything else hall
you know what could go wrong and there
are serious privacy issues that could
result
I'll and security again if somebody
knows what's going home
arm and you know they're doing it they
could take offense to that
and is a privately Richter scale it's
not really a 9.5 because is not here yet
%uh the utility manufacture Belkin it
bought the higher sense so that may be
coming on the market soon
and finally I don't think we're gonna
get 1984 but
double will be like the prisoner with
cameras and and monitors everywhere
be seeing you thank you