touching on the first commercially
available modular robotic systems in the
world
actually for adults it's the only one
there are a few other ones fun for kids
just love to see them so I don't have
those with me today
I guess to roll and there is another
system coming but
is ready a for for I
so my name is her for and I'm from
Sweden little
about might the time I talk to see their
and you pronounce my name like to
prepare your spot all
and that might be good if you wanna talk
to me later during hope
and I don't want to do that Picasa test
the Roberts out
I've got everything favor them just for
the whole
two days remain I
we're talking about self reconfiguring
of
and the name isn't very good
called other things that other time like
program
utility for you might have heard of Sep
what exactly has one thing going and
it describes well what it's all about a
start with modular in my robotics week
bill
what we want from standardized rips
modules
and that's simply the Madras the better
because it's more generally a pliable
can be used in more situations
so young then versus custom we go
general way and then reassemble what we
need from and
this week and compass in there and solar
a model only includes
enough functionality to contribute this
functionality decide
in the insol that's why the see here
that house G degrees of freedom and it's
a very very capable mod
most only have well I because that's the
smallest number you can have %uh
and you see the the lose LEGO pieces of
course
that the one that fits them and song
axiom best
because you could build the other two
from from the rock and
shows actually quite clearly that's
actually what they've done
the bill looked at the LEGO pieces from
from LEGO pieces
and you can of course use small one
startling
pieces to build a woman them if you
wanted
a let me come to sell
reconfiguring a and this is say that
instead a new building
assembling them and I i should point out
that what you're holding your hand is
not set that's a more general
the connector for something this picking
system
very hard so we haven't really quite
that
a self configuring
want to make spouses assembling the
modules
I it's also worth mentioning that the
not only can the rearrange themselves
amongst other
but they can also change the properties
this is what that one can do
they can be longer they can hold onto
each other and angles that to change the
color or
or stuff like that this gives very very
wide Scopus chain you can adjust
ourselves a fraction of an inch
or we could turn ourselves from a a a
sofa to the table
depending on what we want to do so the
want to mention
and modularity put together I mean
nobody can deny
the significance of automation or model
I'd
it's basically the the foundation for
our society today
%uh put together we get something really
exciting
you get universal physical machine at
to to join a
analogy there is to say that at the
computer will
we just call it the computer but it is
actually a general
comp computing machine capable of
simulating
any a dedicated comp
computing machine the ones we had before
the gulf
what we call the computer and even
further by backed them that they were
actually people
it was a joke title to be a computer you
did temptation by hand so what would be
yeah if you could create this amazing
working selfie configuring
of Texas a and
22 of 22 to to do talk about that I'd
like to also you a question which I
paraphrase
from from saying apart and its from his
presentation
usually referred to as the mother of all
the most if you haven't seen that one
online you should definitely check it
out
percent something that is a mix of
Twitter or
Windows all this put together and it's
like 40 years old
shows us how it could work so he says
if you have a system no cost
environmentally friendly
virtually unbreakable but for many
fiscal structures
perform any costs what value could you
drive from
and that's what I hope to
to talk about I shows the title known
no natural resources were assembling the
sofa
because bomb it's naturally a paraphrase
line you sometimes most of the season
and the movies
a no no animals were harmed in the
making of this motion picture
I'll so I shows this title
because one of the things that's up
terrible this would allow us to do
is the drastically change our
relationship raw materials
the stuff that the world around us is
made of
I'll
because when assembling one thing
in in a separate robotic system
as we do in the computer we use only and
I mean when we note another software of
used
another software use only energy the
computer stays the same
and it's the same thing with the modulus
said beginning
robotic system the model stays the same
and we use them for different things
me out a little bit too many do that
allows them to sell be configured
and then we've got table so share a bad
whatever
and of course we can do that time and
time again
and this could
drastically slowed down the rate its raw
materials
close to our society the way us today
goes from natural resources
products and then to waste basically
landfill we try to recycling there but
it's quite hard
because we get this huge mix of
everything so in the bin
hard to know what what's actually in
there and recycling the best way
so you use
only what you need right now Chris
whatever
you since you could always assemble
watching it at any given time you only
have
a what you need right now
this could seem simple but what you
don't
it's not there because when you need it
with the same
a and this is significant
think about how efficiently actually
Jews most the stuff we have
it's been reported that life his life
average power real issues 14 the rest of
the time
1528 just sits there shell a
so that's the fact that we have
but don't have don't is very sick
but it doesn't actually and their
there are a number of other features
that changes our relationship through
material
instinct as a part of said thinking
optics
I I'm gonna
talk about a few of them if you wanna
talk about this more I'm here all
all although the conference but I'm
gonna mention a few of them
via the more important thing is that we
could use the module for its
entire service life until it simply
isn't usable
and very few things I guess that party
lists thrown away
long before it's worn out have a hard
time seeing you worrying about in 40
minutes
I am you can use it for the phone
service life
and even if its not up to a hundred
percent specification
there's always many situations rates
capabilities are more than enough to be
use
and
when d'amato breaks I mean they're gonna
break they're gonna be
so only don't use them anymore we can
actually since we do a few types a
modulus
we could actually bring them back into
the factory and disassemble them
and reuse the components within them to
say that something is broken
is very likely that most the park's in
whatever is broken
are perfectly alright it's just one or
two parts that are broken
here since we have few types but many of
them
we can bring them back into the factory
disassemble the mall you
and use the parts that are okay again
and of course we could do this again and
again and again until
that particular part is not use
one I'll and
even if its when we decide to more jobs
where they move for instance or
how they use their war but since we know
kinda where they are
warned and how we can have we can handle
that
in another way save me disassemble the
module beget apart out
it isn't really up to spec but it's not
too far out suspect so we can rework the
model
may be answered your washer way it moves
a little bit thick you water them use
the first time
and that could actually use the mobile
again maybe in a module at in only
the park in a model that is only at acid
lower specification but it still usable
for some
most the time I and
soon related the park is not gonna be
useful it's going to be our respect it's
gonna be old
we don't want in but since we know
exactly what
the material is made out of its we can
actually recycled raw material heart
more efficient than we do today X you
know exactly what we have
we know exactly how to treat it to
recycling the most efficient way
this actually one of the bigger problems
in recycling today
know exactly what you go that and and
to substances mixed together that's the
the two hard issues
up but to come back to the the beginning
where we actually make the module
since the surface or whatever reassemble
and the internal structure
are two separate parts I we
I guess we wouldn't build the bad doubt
that the model I just passed around
kinda hard would probably be very
uncomfortable I
then we could a.m. that
that the fact that the surface and the
internals are two
separate things which means we could
actually use recycled raw materials to
make
that ninety percent of the internal
structure
and just use new materials for the
surface and what you see and interact
so not only can we recycle much more
efficiently
we can also use recycled material that
is available
in a way that is not possible today
on behind
so
sad to say this is not all for free this
is Modena robotics has many issues
and some other Mar not sole some other
Mar kinda soul
and others we're working on right now
overhead the modularity
is one of the challenges we face a
because
a dedicated custom component can always
be
perfectly adapted to a
the situation it's supposed to work
practically that's rarely so
because we cannot have bomb tuneful
bonds on each tossed
them need and infinite number tools so
although the the
the custom argument there is
valid and interesting in practice it's
not ass
a significant as one might think I am
I'll
and also in a
selfie configuring modern robotic system
we could
at that the amount of overhead being
corporate in the system I depending on
what we want for the system
so we could France to say that we we
want the system to be very responsive
you wanted to be able to transform
fast and and then be
have to accept that the risk higher
overhead than for a system that doesn't
have to be able
to task to transform ass rapid at
Francis this is
a we could actually turn it from Siro up
to
a some former maxwell we could build a
brick wall with a system like this and
then we can save the wall is not much
change for a very long time
I so let's just remove the rover that
built the so
10 needs at that time it's not longer a
sub reconfiguring
system it's just their I and in another
solution we might want to change it
faster
and then we say okay in there is certain
overhead for this but we're gonna keep a
number these
reconfiguring units in the system
but can also than change so when it
comes to the argument though
overhead a model I T I usually say that
it is the lowest form
the lowest level overhead that should be
compared
to a custom-made parts because and
anything more than the lowest level s
is a feature not a not a cost it's a bug
it's a feature not a bug
I so
that argument can be quite well handed
especially if you then consider the fact
that the recent
and overhead of on modularity or
non-local ITT
to support you have to make that custom
component a
and that's much harder making just more
of the same thing you already know how
to do
I to make this system where
we use the models we need at a specific
time
were a the best we can we need to prune
are more and we need to draw more deals
from approved when we need them
and return them to the pool when we go
basically like our share
this though is a is both a %uh an
opportunity and a problem because
the the pool will be a common thing and
this many ships around privacy security
access to more deals a and what you can
actually do with them I mean if you want
to do something that is likely to
to destroy them on yours are you allowed
to and
stuff like that so pooling is an issue
it's a it's it's a it's a
opportunity but it's also an issue
septic nothing more than a robotics is
gonna
address many things basically in the end
we see that everything fiscal around you
that you can touch
will be built by systems thats
far off in the future but even if we
just do 10 percent democracy around
which is certainly possible especially
orchid in
I can mention architecture we're making
great headway in architecture house
I business this is gonna
upset a lot of people I mean spent so
much changes
and there are way some arguing for the
fact that it's going to be a very rapid
change I
the only solution I have there is to be
open
allow everybody access to the system's
I to allow education about this system's
for everyone free I and of course
as and as a level playing field as
possible so that
everyone can participate and do stuff
with the news
with this new technology so what does
this mean for for for the hockey
community we hear that hope I mean
most of us like to do stuff tinker with
things and and
to to just not consume it also
kinda produce I
there are many things that that that I
think that that the hacker community
with dull with modern robotics I markets
are reasonably cheap ass
competitive to custom parts that are
made in small series or
or are stuff like that these can be made
you serious
and with them drop in price and of
course you only pay for them and you
actually use them
so you don't have to buy them in the
same way you do
to do with general components that it's
hard to know somebody wants them
when you're done I
and it's also so that since the or so
general if you wanted to develop it work
with the software Park which is probably
ninety percent what we're talking about
the hardware modding robotics is very
hard but you only have to do it
wats when somebody interconnected that
works OK
we've done that I mean just make more
but the Soccer Park is gonna be
shoot work I and venue Jan
you can start with developing used to
simulate to YouTube Aug you've got your
system working
okay but you have to test it on the
fiscal motives to see
if it works in in real life and I can
tell you there's a very big step between
those two
not a modern a robotic system works
great in simulation
very few works warm in reality
I but since they're all the same it
would be very easy for somebody and I'm
actually working with something to try
to do that
to provide the more deals for testing
purposes virtually
remotely so you do simulation work to do
development you go on to this website
you can test them against the models and
see whether they were
get feedback from what doesn't work and
and and
do do it that way and that means that
you'd only pay for the little bit of
time
at which is this going to be
ridiculously she
just like web hosting today or all the
things we take
take for granted in in the web world %ah
as I experimentation cost next to
nothing
the margins are cheap and you just get
them when you need them
I'll another factor is that when you
when you want to start doing something
montana robotics I here you get the
advantage of
not being custom components I'll because
it's going to be leveraged in and us ice
icy
see waz at the first waiver wave forces
you have this eco-system all the modules
that somebody ever did
and you can just use the Leveson it
ceases to to
I incorporates what somebody did because
the module the connector works ass a
black box interface basically
if somebody's margin work it's just take
it and
and run with it how up
the second thing that the I find to be a
big leverage
this is I am that
somebody's probably have the same
problem with it wanted to work with the
something similar to what you want to do
and since the modern parts are general
you could probably
East more easily build on what they did
than if they
build it out custom components from
scratch every time
is this going to be this small nagging
freeware the issues that makes it
impossible for
for you too to use what they did and of
course when you're done and you got
something working
Jorma we going to the pool and everybody
could just use that
and they could use it as it is so they
can modify
a and course you could just share this
with the world and
win great Carmo you could selling if you
want
to embarrassed or I would like to come
back to this
question again this time I
I'm gonna just say that if you had this
system
this no cost environmentally friendly
virtually unbreakable at the margins are
placed themselves if they break
theirself reconfiguring at perform any
fiscal structures performance of
what value could you drive from I hope
that
that got put some ideas in your head and
that you think that
the critical to try this and I i out
because its very easy
we could tryout many many different
things here
just during the two days ago I and
because it's basically free we don't
when
when we leave here the models will be
exactly the same as when I
and ira so there's no cost associated
except the little friend I guess
somewhere somewhere out someone at the
pay for them
I I would really like for you to
to to help me you know this bringing
this out into the real world it's just
about to come there this one you see is
made with rapid growth
rapid prototyping but it is commercially
available the fun for kids is
also commercially available and more
its solid systems where you could build
restructures
the snack together and that's great but
there is systems coming out that you
could build I
been these share sodomy city on this
table is I
and they're still active still have
motors are sensors and
operating system so you can also program
I'm looking forward to building
go karts other those when I get them
which is sad enough
probably towards the winter which means
I'll have the students that the Sullivan
sweet so that would be a modular ski-doo
up there are a few
a open source projects that you can
contribute to that you can
use at No love them ourselves become
thinking I'm sorry to say
they are modular I'll I'm working on a
project
that would probably hopefully and make
it possible
to create a open source free for
everyone
ok 3s in speech and beer I guess
except for the modules I but assess if
they can be
pagey I embed it more important than
free maybe open you will have a pillar
rights with access to them
and you will have a set the
responsibilities and
the community as a whole would work with
setting those rights
and obligations I'll be putting up some
things to these
I open source projects on my long I
tomorrow and also a number a video where
you can see
the Senate reconfiguring systems in
action because they actually do work
quite nicely in the lab which of course
is like saying they don't
you want but its still cool to see them
transform from a snake
to at four a told basically you can see
them
coming walking along SSF four legged
creature
protecting that the slope is too high
for them to do that
and then they become a snake in them do
the incline as a snake
and then they realize that now this
background then they go over to walking
like to talk again so
Thessalonica videos out there I'm also
gonna
put up some resources a I
where you can find more information it's
very heavily researched
space as most for this development the
stunning the university environment
right now
but I think it is ready to come out into
the
its garage readies what I'd like to say
you can actually think about this
in your garage and you could do it
tomorrow
and anchor continue his 222 to the pool
and
everything is grows exponentially I'll
so
any questions I said yeah
yeah
actually scaling up from the chair is
what we think is
it's not easy the requirements list for
the connector which of course is what
hi no is like 50 different fire
I am it wouldn't use the same
because satisfying all those
fifteen-month connected just
dick impossible but say that we would
use the same connector but we could use
one connector for the chair and then one
connector for the house
%uh and yes there are
alternatives both to make a really
really small connector is actually hard
%uh one that could become sup million
each year and we could do
not only each working share but a
beautiful on that
we can look at and see K looks like
share a
yeah not one
that's the Holy Grail basically to make
one connector that not only scales
from from the really small the really
big but that this cancels
compatible so that you could at touched
something that was ten percent smaller
to something
and then something that ten percent
smaller than that and then some you go
all the way down to
a mister fineman levels they spent a
room at the bottom
yes but yeah that's a very good question
but yes
theoretically and practically going up
from
that share not a not an issue any other
yeah
did
yet what we call that is basically more
what we're doing today
we if we would want to do robotic
architecture we wouldn't start building
the whole house what we would do is
for instance these these walls that are
behind me is actually a a modular system
i mean
now we can have one big room we can have
to small room so we can adapt our
environment so
doing what you say is that the them
coexisting of regular
technology with this absolutely that's
certainly something that would be would
be where we would start
I use basically what you build a house
like this you build the
source and you build the walls but you
need everything open I have an ex awful
there that s
if you did that to your apartment it
would be more significant the sink set
say that you had all the space
just in one open open space and then you
had a a
then there is that this simple popular
vote this up because the modern robotic
system
event able to put up walls but if you do
this point I want
all there and in civil there say that
you have this apartment
I and since you could use the space
for whatever your wall at you don't have
to buy as much
she'd actually afford to buy an
apartment in that good neighborhood that
you always wanted
but you couldn't because it's very
expensive I but
since you now can adapt your space to
whatever you need
that's no problem say that you buy your
gonna live there with your
significant other you by I guess is
crappy I don't know forty
sixties 40 square meters maybe and you
want to have a dinner party this is the
example on running so
you gonna have a dinner party you need a
big kitchen to prepare the food
so you have a big tits to prepare the
food and after that the food is done
it's Ian
bodice name this is reasonably big pitch
in the SIR
don't usually have a that size fits
peace advocacy
you having just like that need a lot of
food you need two bathrooms
you gonna take a shower I
guest starts to ride you need one big
space for
for for just socializing and you want to
just two toilets no charge just two
toilets or uniform because you don't
want
lines 24 I then you need to a table so
that everybody can sit down
you get a table I and when the dinner's
over a couple your friends party
spend the night because you gonna go
shopping or whatever tomorrow
I and then your question better
San and within this space you could do
all that space flies
but it would be very expensive to have
although these just standing
waiting for you to use so if we could
juice
our whole space all of the time it be
very fish
but as ice yeah that's definitely what
we're going to do even allow them to
coexist any other questions
yes the sisters house Ltd
the morning himself probably not be self
healing but the solution
the whole George if your share
contained a broken module transfers the
checkered have a feature that
detective left for the person sitting on
the chair and adapting
so that even if you're if you're for to
use it comfortably if you're
6-foot-4 you sit comfortably because she
had a tax on all your not thats
I and of course
then had a broken module that would you
could be automatically replaced
and and and then I guess what
automatically return to the factory
and there you have to take a decision
rather to reuse the park's recycling
in the park but the models themselves
were probably not be
the same feeling on on that level this
is actually also
yep know that's also the difference
between
that the cell-free producing machine a
this could become a selfie producing
system
because there's nothing stopping you
from building a %uh mining truck
or or any kind of system needed the
to make the modulus themselves so
it's not a selfie producing machine but
it's a selfie producing system yeah
architects are very skeptical about this
as they tried before and it very hard to
get it to work
yeah
I'm here for two day
yeah yeah
I'd like to say that that learn in
Norman amount from me because that's who
say that
we are some be configured more durable
everyone to view the pictures something
completely modular robot
your well rover nothing but yourself
camping anyway and you're definitely
some feeling which is very nice
otherwise we love you would be me to use
the smallest cop killers immediately be
oneself
I so I'd say is that the father
I think it was the first question was
that have yeah be known and Norma some
out from
from nature I how to control these
Darch group of almost uses very hard
it's not you can't just not right
line code say do this do that its
becomes impossible immediately
I they use for remote control basically
like ants control the
that the hive other the and I'm a
they also use I actually one of them
architecture project stateville houses
with the same
or what we think is the same algorithms
ass at termites build their nests
termites are not her smart features but
they build fantastic nests
they maintain them very nicely and they
can growth in S
wild investors in News so say that
that be like moving into a one bedroom
apartment and living there
while the construction workers made it a
two bedroom apart and of course
fix the roof or whatever yeah awake you
had a second question
and can you do that again
talked about it being related to 3d
printing
at you can't do them all to see you yeah
you can't do it CDP it but it's not
necessarily I think it is actually
a maybe I shouldn't say this here many
thanks be competing with T
pic-a-state if anything is I I know that
they're trying to make it to a full
circle
thing where where they where they think
and then granulate the past again and we
do it again but
week Alice that step at they can do
very nice of the clinton like very nice
position
but they have to go through the printer
weekend
yes reassemble them on you and without
going through the fence
yeah
I got the perfect also for you right
here yeah
I again be learned from nature I dream
long be tried to do self-organizing
systems for a long time 22 uphold
solutions to our problems the way we
have the old
from from from the environment armenian
basically but it's very hard to do
when when I components are too large so
this actually two professors in Japan
but just published a book on this
it's called cell-free reorganize
self-organizing robots it's a fantastic
read
surprisingly reasonable for
book of that nature actually and more
they
talk about 22 they talk about a lot of
stuff in the book but what they
talk about is that instead of saying I
want to
to watch EXTRA exactly like this behave
exactly like that
I define a set a ruse and then I prefer
be started simulation by holding
something that looks
reasonably close to what I wall and then
of course I can put it out there
in the real world and allow the
components
to evolve a chair that fits my needs
this is also very important because self
because self healing comes from
the self-organizing because it simply
that takes its not fulfilling that goal
and any that that and we've seen that in
simulation also to a certain degree in
hardware the connectors still playing
house the bad connectors we have are
still a very hard problem
I but in simulation BC that I
gates for instance how robots walk whole
very nicely
and many other things just a bowl if you
allowing if you give it the
the eco-system to do so we can a former
the products we do so yeah this sinus
fantastic important and
with a more something on your system
under
system we could do to sign in a
fundamentally different way
but I definitely like talk to more
serious
I'm outside when I'm done I'm gonna be
here tomorrow and
Sunday to and I'm gonna have the robots
here for you too
to try different set up yeah
yeah
yeah yeah the yeah Center
on a comp this area draw some some
having names and this
you mentioned the seller cellular
automaton which is fun moments where
and he actually he just the fall there
this work with us alert
cellular phone the sucking easy died
before you finish that work died
very John I think it was 56 there is
speculation that he was exposed to
radiation during the Manhattan Project
which
course worked on I but you have to send
it on atomic Tom is
the basis for our research for right
about now then comes
a a Penrose
the mathematician important for I
and the modern version of
this research was started by a man
should have called up
when he was working on a the CNC machine
with interchangeable tools
so he was working on making the robot a
the machine collected to let real love a
second I mention
use it for a while return it to the
storage pick up another to do something
and he said instead of you doing it just
for the two
why can't I do it for the whole machine
i mean sometimes I need a strong but
reason to slow n and the motor and other
times I need a very fast but not
necessarily that strong
motor and if I could put the strong
motor back in the pool when I don't need
it
somebody else like so he started the the
the work
and this post lay 80s and
Upton I would say I to 2000's
progress was very academic very heavy on
math by
tried to read the cellular automaton
papers and just impossible to understand
for me
I IIT I i feel now
there are commercial projects the basic
fundamental law
algorithms stuff are reasonably good so
I think that
five years from now this is garage ready
five years from now
everybody can tinker with this and
they're all and and you could start
already now
because it's actually much easier to
build the module and then build the
check out the models
than it is to build the chair from star
special somebody else
the marginal
yes yeah and at this point not only I
mean this actually worse guys than the
commercial guys because you can deal
with those
you give the money they're nice to you
but but it but if the government does
that to you
and your government isn't nice I'd don't
want to live in a world where
where about government-controlled these
things yeah others
definitely privacy issues there's so
many issues are on safety and security
and and your control over your
environment yes absolutely
I I don't see this aspect call
pic MCUs even though we're going for
high-resolution
unit a hatreds homogeneous system that's
way way off in the future I so I think
that actually
I'm working on a project a where we
gonna set up an environment where you
can send your the signs for modulation
and we make it for you so you don't have
to be an expert in machining or
a few depending on whatever you just
have to be
somebody that wants to to view it and we
take care the biggest that's a challenge
in modern politics
when you do a prototype younger you do
one or two
but to do anything significant you have
that Penn
15 or even a thousand and when you do a
thousand or something
your you do too many of them to be
done by hand and you too few of them to
do with them
in dusty so that's a big challenge but
yeah there's
definitely many issues around privacy
security I don't think that the
commercial guy so the big problem
we can develop but but governments are
certain your problem I
but I think this this an opportunity
to do it's better this time than
and then we did maybe with computers
because we all are out here and we're
doing stuff it's not done by
dogs institutions and the government we
could do this together
and then of course we will also need so
yeah yeah
jet yeah I had the pleasure of
interviewing the guy from ipod cost who
worked on those they are just amazing
should I introduced permanent magnet and
then you can go on
you know about the regular Mac nothing
we know about the a.m electromagnet and
and making my
magnetic effect that turn power on it
because
medic and and return to power of its not
like that
that's a terrible singer doing it
because that's all thanks a lot of power
all those bad things and the permanent
mounting the can of course use
can turn it off but he mentions elector
permanent magnets
and day are a former magnet that when
you give them the pulse of energy
they talk in the state between magnetic
and not so you
a store first the power it becomes like
that short burst the power
it's not like that anymore its like
magic yes and
yeah so now everybody knows what a
permanent electromagnet this
a which I guess someone you love you
know so on the question
yeah if you remove the micro from the
name it's already here
yeah and I'm it. in Boston they've got
if he works on the elect a man is that's
where the use it is called the wrong
with Pavel
its 11 millimetres cue and Leo
stochastic a
said set/sets per family so what you do
is you
don't have remodeled with with amid a
schematic it's not
it's complicated but that's not going to
that right now you
put them in a bag to shake them and the
Maldives hit
and okay this is correct this is not
correct the sample
so then you could pull your because I'm
you can also use a just assemble them
into 21 think not
and it says every model decides whether
on the park to the
the solution of if I'm not part of the
solution i turn my Mac is often I follow
so from a from a do you get a dog bite
noting the shape of the dog into the
cuban everybody else just says
when I go back to the pool call me when
you need so yes certainly they elect a
pack
and they are very nice because this came
with size we talked about size with you
before
and they get better and better the
smaller they are
I I should actually I I'll I'll talk to
the people that no one put it on my blog
but
yeah but I understand is that yes it's
not that
far-off they didn't them 11 me let me
take you because that's what they could
do in the lab again they had to do a lot
of them
this another project you know what
impresses of this
the one you do on on the tipper
I am I like actors you figure that out
myself I don't have to give you an idea
about any other
did that's the test program in France
now it shows you that all the
degrees from work I don't don't get your
Fingaz past because it's reasonably
strong I'll
I yet you know the press box
you do it from head over to the
toothbrush you put it vibrating motor on
there any
runs around on your table I a guy
decided to do
a thousand 24 robles so one single PhD
students
bill akin about the row that's a
big project right so he had to look at
all love these parts and
he's previous work was the algorithms
the mathematics behind it but he decided
I'm going to bed
2024 over and that's what he did there
15 bucks a pop
spent fifteen thousand but he actually
had the building by hot
and I was saying to him that you very
Amos like saying all this so hard to
build the house know them and I said
Jordan
lucky guy just the next PhD student just
about the
the megabyte the robot semester to be a
pain in the ass out ther
so yeah scale I is very hard but they're
working on it ap
mine view lately has been that
we're not gonna as he's talked about the
Chevy not have the same connector and
within the house Aspen rebuild the chair
or when we build the
something really small we're not gonna
have the same process
up getting the item I but
the system as a whole is gonna be
complete a selfie configuring
press the send that we want to have a
really smooth and curved surface or
something
we could actually have an assembly unit
within the solution
that makes component out the really
really small parts
and then pass them along at a higher
scale
at something that could become a bigger
biggest Dec
yeah
it has to be done that way I i think
if we only have like five or ten to
twenty thousand units we could probably
centrally controlled them
but when we come down to doing something
in there really
view high resolution we get trillion
some units that's the only way
there's no way you can centrally control
them because timing issues Miami
it simply practically impossible
yeah
yeah I guess probably probably be more
efficient to use the clout than but yeah
but who knows I mean 50 to say what you
can't do
with the scent be configured modern
robotic system says it is universal
fiscal machine
it's basically impossible is a what can
you do with the computer
well that depends on average a
programmer you are more than anything
else so
yeah any other questions
how I recruited you to the
said be competing mother robotics
project you like being nice to the
environment a new
do cool stuff for free and I i mean
I mean if we do this right i mean we
learned a lot from how computers and the
internet was introduced if we do it
right this time
it could be free ass in beer and speech
and this thing that actually costs of
could be very very very very very very
cheap for us that's
according to have but there's a couple
billion people in the world that
it would be essential for purse that
aspect back
we have the and interesting twenty years
ahead on the site so
yeah
%uh sorry I didn't see their the lights
No
yeah March other I had the pleasure
interviewing
in hong kong recently yeah he said
big balled up though he's a big motor I
can tell you yeah
I think that we probably aiming for what
you say that that the analog systems
they have to be very very small investor
I mean the sea views when you do a
thousand of them and they have to BSA
microscale
we don't have a lot of computer power
each bomb so
I'm thinking that and I think market
than being bought searching me
advocate for that point-of-view and and
I think that's valid
I don't think you really know and I
think that in my own way we can come
back to that with different connectors a
different scale
maybe some systems and some parts
assistance might want to use one of them
and other system or other part 7 a
system
more want to use both of them we can
also dynamically adjusts
where we use each because 3 don't build
each and every looks like that if yeah
we could just adapt ourselves continues
it could even
perceive you do that itself to evolve
a system for eighty percent is done one
way in 20 sent the other way
if the text that the situation has
changed and another
itself
anymore I'm here for two days so
you don't have to ask knocking on I
don't know the time maybe the next
speaker wants to come in
what's the time okay space