morning mmm the afternoon hours in it it
is
okay will stamp your breakfast buffet
love
low bit art our money's distance got
mind is going to use these two fine
gentleman are they are will explain
everything about it they are scions of
the
the 8-bit seen on your right is Jeremiah
Johnson
also known as North sleep he's a he's
one of the best musicians up his genre
in all of time so you're lucky you
already won
if Casey wanting we were supposed to go
today and hope you already won
but but what the Christmas CD that comes
along with the may now be you have no
carrier
ok who performs and
makes Nintendo do things that was never
meant to do every time he gets on stage
Miyamoto actually starts to shake a
little bit at his desk in Japan
because he knows what that the
abomination is about to occur
for your entertainment so they're gonna
talk to you a little bit about the
project Diva
decided to take on this year and the
magical things they've done with it so
please give it up
for these two wonderful gentleman no
sleep no carrier
thank you thanks
and and now you know why we ask Jason
Scott and producers
from selling by
as jason said we're going to be talking
about this project ivars called 0 they
aren't we started
just about a year ago
and this this is the talk and that we're
doing for you guys here and herb called
dead in a pool of blood in millions of
dollars
manner and so let's
let's just talk for Easter about a
little about who we are
am interns have this project so
by at its heart what we are is
pirate software group for for Internet
art and for digital art so we've got bad
you know there are
there are groups that pirate everything
from movies to TV shows to music to
software
from internet art is just another typeof
software another type of media that's
distributed
over over the web and over
over the network's so from why isn't
anyone
taking this in making sure that it's
spread and
is intuitive subject to
and abuse these false
am structures have scarcity that
are sometimes imposed on digital works
and digital media
by outside forces in most cases were
talking about
for instance the MPAA in in the a.m
when we're talking about movie piracy or
from
or software companies themselves
enforcing their copyright
one software aspire to in this case and
it sometimes am galleries that are
trying to you
some to take works offline for
are collectors after they're sold or ads
arts organizations that are trying and
two your approach
I'm the monetization met-art and a
certain way
and so we thought this was an an
interesting project to explore this idea
yeah so mom again I will talk more about
Anna your chin this term in a moment but
we're known is your day are
and I'm our motto is pretty simple and
it's that we put in our back on the net
and on again deterred look at this term
0 yards
and think about am where this comes from
have to look at I'm kind in history at
the scene
and also on getting to know exactly what
his neck are
so I'm site we can really just simply
talk about where's
and wear something and maybe everyone
hears from her with and on
it you know refers as a germ I said to
works there are
copyrighted and distributed without fees
or royalties
and out where's group arm that exist
kinda globally referred to as the where
seen were as
on you know just largely the scene and
i'd this term can be use a number ways
are one way you can use from where's is
to say something like I downloaded 10
gigabytes have where's yesterday
this is a very common type thinking
about it has that
and use that as AI noun but arm
less of them because be used as you know
the new windows was where's
a month before Microsoft officially
released it this is a term that I V
don't use now you know how to use it
and I you can go forth and I do so and I
had a long
and adaware scene has a long long
history and I'm he grew up in the 80's
news bulletin boards and then moved onto
the internet
and I chances are you've probably been
familiar where's for
a long time and I we can trace the
origins at the scene
armory leave on your back to that time
yeah and so and sue what would group
started doing is when the
cracked a PC software and they
distributed
they would start I'm tagging the
software with these
interest screens am and so here you see
an example
via an Activision product that weighs
pirated
and this is that the group that it
started giving their greets and is
letting you know that your
you're able to to you I'm run the
software beakers
and they're the ones that were able to
crack it am
and now when we talk about where is the
terms your day and your day are
and is is sort of a reference to the
time
and in which it takes I'm from the
release date you they're releasing the
pirated version so
if you're able to you I'm to get your
hands on a copy
love piece of software or in our case
we're talking about
works have avnet ardor digital art and
release it within the same
within the same day or before the actual
official release date as bad
about work then I your you're talking
about as you're owed a release
from so yeah I guess you wanna pick up
from there in
and continue on with their yeah I am I
think gets and that that's pretty much
where all
we could say about their day so for this
term if you're unfamiliar that when we
come up with their de Arte
arm you know this was actually go that
we I'm have achieved i think im
israeli's are tried
really hard including our first one
which is will talk about more
is that yes 01 something releases we
feverishly
hap to you on get together to really sit
within 24 hours
and on you know I'm primarily I mean
not historically I distribution center
so where's look something like this:
and down and here you can see that at
there's tons the CDs and duplication us
software
I mean hardware do I get stuff out there
and I am
along with our along with a zero-day
releases on what we saw here earlier
this activation screen that I am
jamas talking about here there's some
things that this this kind of evolved
trade for CC things are going to the
hallmark of
later cracked roseanne intros easy
things like thanks so they're thanking
people
rate you also see arm people's names
mentioned
arm which would come to be known as
greets and US had this idea that this
that it's not just
Activision bringing this to you it
actually Activision and the racketeers
so it actually people that are coming
and creditors
it's not just the people that are
bringing you there are creating
the media or the arc for the game but
it's our city but are cracking and there
have a part in bringing this to you
so a crack show arm you know is an intro
I'm introduction to a game like you'd
see their but on
at the same time a accompanies a crack
and this just shows who was responsible
for it
and on who brought this to you may greet
your friends you might
on fuck off to your enemies and it was
really made to impress people and let
people know who is responsible so good
to go
look at arm some crack shows one cracked
row here that would have existed
on back and I think this is like the 80s
she's
these
a
the
all right that is a comer 64 on and how
many have you
mom recognize that from the opening
notes but um
the so that the cracker still exist
today so it may be downloaded on pirated
software 1.0 and seen
and execute well that you're probably
afraid to click on and died I was
accompanied with the
aware that you downloaded and then we
open up your eyes snap are the software
but here's the song
it might be actually accompanying the
key generator they came with your
software
and all this has a history I'm going
back to crack chose to happen you know
in a comment on a meager days
and the scene really can spread out from
there and I'm again this is from the
computer article on the scene
so it started out really gotta as you
know the where seen but then people
diversified ready had people that made
music for keygens and for cracked rose
you also had people that would make the
visual art and eventually
on you know people got more interested
in that side of things and you had this
kind of splintering
on there from the where scene into
despair groups like their demo seen
where people make these little intros in
them or more complex
arm works of art that stand alone so
it's no longer just a piece
a cracked that is before Pisapia
download but something you download to
watch
and to listen and it's a real time
demonstration love
graphics and in music and really again
a.m. to highlight the palace in the
coding ability I love the people
involved
so on there has been this evolution we
show quick demo in this is from mom
years later
and it's much different than than the
common or that we just looked after
well the
the
well
well the
the alright so
here you can see something that again is
much more
evolved and then something is on the
Commodore 64 in this is because again
people are just
on who making a quick crack shower intro
to accompany
the multiple releases and where's group
but this is something that is maybe
the demos are months or even years at
work that people put together teams are
people
and in order to release the Sabre love
minute normally non-interactive but real
time
demonstrations love on cutting ability
and artistic skill
and I'm you know when you eat we think
about what we're doing most up
the net or that we look at camp has its
roots are some people pay homage to this
and I am this is kinda my background
when we talk about zero day
and never gonna move on and talk really
about where the art side of things comes
in
yeah and just an intern and a little bit
am
this is something that's and been
interesting to die and I'm because ive
and the background entries and spoke a
little bit about the fact that
from I'm in on the electronic musician
working with
typically old video game hardware early
home computing systems
and on is a visual artist doing the same
thing and
song want are what r artistic practice
is really about is almost it's a it's
almost a deconstruction irv I'm real
time demo is because
I'm greeting and greeting sir to the
soundtrack and when
Don and I perform together he's is
creating
live visuals better from better being
played
and real-time usually from software that
is written himself for a min
Nintendo Entertainment System more Sega
Genesis or
other consoles and so this is something
that was interesting to us because its
order
wake I am packets or even continuing
evolution in this this lineage this
thread that's run through
their computer art scene and soon now
talking about men aren't which is
something that sort of non
and its its related in some ways to you
and two demo seen culture but it is it
at definitely as: a separate thread its
own am
this term is really and was was first
coined
in there early to mid nineties for a
group of artists
they're working at the time but I N and
more generally and can refer to you
from and basically anyone working with
the
an the Internet as a medium for their
art
so part that is am inherently tied
and into the media more aware of the
medium and
the advantages that the system dish
distribution gives you were at the sort
of context and it provides for the works
some and so we're going to just talk
about are
a few examples of artists and better and
better working with the internet as a
medium
I'm starting from some a barrel earlier
generation and then moving into more
contemporary ones
right I'm so under how many if you've
seen this business and
work from 1998 and I'm it's called
traitor
and its arms to online today in
something by done by Martyn a beer
and shredder and then you can go check
it out a potato land at work
shredder the idea here is that um you
know
in it in the nineteen nineties of course
arm many of us probably I started me
experimenting with web technologies and
it was especially important
you know to understand that it's it the
web was open in a way that it
is different and some software that you
have access to and that their source
code behind everything that you see
and shredder is um a kind anti browser
of sorts where you
watch this window you put in a location
there is also number bookmarks and if
you check out some the bookmarks listed
at my speech to the time that this was
released
but I'm for instance I'm the screenshots
maynes it still works
arm and you opening ya who and i'd the
world the out
the output is something like this so
in it condemned literally just shreds
and you can see combinations are the
images arm overlaid as well as some I
love the
HTML the CSS and on the
hyperlinks as well on this web page and
you can scroll and you kind of get the
feeling that
your you know your you're not really
seen bit I'll
the web page as intended but it's kinda
makes up the source code
and the on the images and everything
that actually makes up the web sites
again this is released on back in 1998
and B sample public am I talking about
as you know kind of more
on classical or net art and there's a
nother
duo named jodie
and down this is an insulation love
there's and I'm this is
job untitled game which was one of 12
variations up the quake
engine that they did I'm so if you
familiar um
with the game Quake the modified it in
numerous ways and on this was
summer these recently shown on the New
York at the museum and moving image
and I'm its kinda interesting on to see
these
um you know this is one way could be
shown was also installed as this year's
projections
and I'm some the games have all the
graphics removes lawyers like the
screaming monsters as you navigate to
the space blindly
which you can see how you can guess how
well that would work great
other ones have the debug information
streaming over top
I love arm over top of all I love the
graphics
so there's a pretty constructions I love
on that the game that day
most people now but you experience in
different ways I'm another one of theirs
which may or may not recognize here is
our Wolfenstein 3d
dad I'm is is with all the graphics
completely removed
so arm you know they're really kind of
%uh play with this idea
love arm you know games and and but also
looking at you know
I'm kinda bring to light what is our
behind on what you're actually looking
at
and then and moving on to some other
more contemporary and earn an artist's
and this is a an animated gif by the
artist Nicholas s Union
use air Canadian artist am and most of
his works are
often presented in animated GIF format
and obviously this is
and this is assertive from a choice
presentation that is very tired today
onto the internet impaired to GIF format
being such a popular way of displaying
moving images
from back I even from that sorta early
internet is when
netscape first started adopting its
usage
um and so many of his works are
concerned with
landscape answer nerve architecture
architectural forms so he's his
this is from a series that is done call
Lance studies which is an arm
be sorted mountainous
am pieces have to rein better
intersected
by these blocks of color and he's done
many of these some that that where the
blocks of color sorter
mentor evoke a very minimalist am
structure and
have housing units or I'm some type of
serve
am cyberpunk sort of condominiums
am and that and then moving on to you
from friends while gamma this is an eye
this is an artist who's based in
am in Spain Anna and his
are again a lot of his work is done in
animated GIF format and he's
and he's very concerned with and the
body
um and the body not just as a sort of
physical
am the physical bodies that we inhabit
but bodies
as at the avatars that we inhabit and
in virtual space and how those to you
arm
are at odds with one another and how
they collide with one another
come how their malleable and from
and what this hors d'oeuvres with this
makes us question about our our physical
bodies as we move move move into
spending more and more time
in in virtual spaces am
the next artist is
Michael Manning he's also from again
working very often with animated GIF
format I'm answer your YouTube can
probably
pick up on the trend here in as far as
contemporary internet artist Sam
begin freezes and then incredibly
popular format and
Michael from is is based here in the
United States
and he he's very interested in
am certain elements of popular culture
fashion
from corporate brands and things like
this so
we have another work we're gonna pop out
to show I'm called my
my spirit is lost from Michael and this
is their
aware where browser-based work
had to forgive me
at the forgiveness here navigations
little bit hard in the second screens
and first for stabbing a your area
sue in this one you'll see and this is
SC reserved from have certain stock
photo images that you found and created
an assertive
and was like a stream of consciousness
in color based gradient
and bad P just sort of search through
the stock photo sides
and found things that tied into one
another and then you created this
incredibly long image
embed you're sort of able to traverse
just by
looking at your browser and I am and
serve
the browser becoming the frame for the
work rather than it being
framed and hung on a wall you're you're
sitting at your computer and your
experience in this work
and Justin whatever space your ad am
so now we're gonna we're gonna move on &
Dunn's gonna talk a little bit about
and assertive beginnings 02 Aaron I am
and and where where we are
taking it so far alright yeah so back to
my commanding in fact actually
om he had a.m. show that was it carried
it last year
at highbeam that's a in New York City
and Chelsea if you're
from the area and dished shows called
Street show the things between us
in yet so
and the end in the concept for a strip
show is
some bad and I i our earning your view
from earlier with the US being dead
drops
anyone out there as if we know system
and soon
so dead drops arm are USB sticks that
have been embedded in
and buildings or other physical
sculpture Anna
physical structures in public spaces and
the idea is that you can
go up to these dead robson merit several
places where
their aggregated unmapped and you can
see an example here this is the one at
IBM I believe so your
and and so you can take your laptop up
to them
whole you know hold your laptop against
the wall you can see what files are on
these things
pull them all sometimes people we've
interesting things there you can we have
interesting things there for other
people
you can leave malicious things there for
other people
um so the idea behind the street show
that Michael had ways
there is this conversation going on at
the time
a ballot am taking works offline sue
collectors could have been locally
when referring to Internet are 10 and
there is a lot of controversy around
this idea
because when you take care and and
a worker bee Internet are of the
Internet did
it is its use to you have the same power
than it did before
and still with the idea that he came up
with
as assertive critique on this and and a
way to continue the conversation wise
to curate this show am invite a bunch of
net artists to create
Anna original work specifically for the
show
and to give him the only copies of those
works and then he went and installed the
this show on a dead drop and that was
the only place that these works existed
from so and this is this is something
that weighs
ways a little bit am frightening and
kids in
the as among the hardest purchases
participating
because this is something and you put
your time into creating a new work and
then
you're giving the only copy away and
then there there are many possibilities
of what could happen at that point
someone could come and basically plug in
their computer and just trash on the
works just
do with them someone could take all the
works often have the only copies in
an accord them for themselves someone
could go into the source code and some
other works for example web-based
works am and and modify them and then
release them as if those were the
original works but they're actually
modified versions
and so at the time done whereas I'm was
actually a resident and IBM
and down he's gonna pick up from where
we went with this
yet so it was interesting oMG is that
the day it was installed I was working
there
and ives when a wide watching the
Twitter feed owners like people talking
about the show one interesting thing
that I don't think
on he German mention that is it was
actually true that these
will you couldn't get this stuff on the
Internet right which was pretty
interesting is that its net art and
their net art is that a lot of people
no lot of people follow everybody's
tweeting about the show
but the only people that have access to
these works a bit better physically
going to go to IBM so it's very similar
to
you know where you think the traditional
gallery show you have to show up at the
at the strange thing is that it was not
our
so yet anything could happen here could
have been corrupted on
people could have skewed simply taken
off the works to be nothing left behind
what actually happened is that
um we've hired at the mall and a that
was the start
the 0 de Arte so throughout the day we
are texting back and forth and talking
about
what's going on here and I'm at lunch
and one out and omg my computer up
copied all the works
got home and arm we launch this website
so arm we do this we had this idea and
we we
talk to all day but what we gonna do and
then we realize that you know the best
thing to do would be to
tired all the stuff from a coworker we
know what are we gonna call this well
you know its net art
and comet 0 day because the gallery show
just launched that day
so armagh we had twenty-four hours arm
and in this time we gave ourselves a
limit up till midnight
to figure out a way to do everything so
I think it was like 10:30 at night we
got started for some Galleria area is
you recently reviewed 30 Blake we sort
of joke about it at the beginning today
and I am at which it I should also
mention
I had asserted personal an interest in
this because I was one of the artists
included in the show
so I really didn't want my work to just
disappear after having
put the time in on and um
but we we really did feel like this
where is from
assertive
we were taking a stance on work on on
our
on on the conversation that was going on
and we wanted to say like
yes this is this is you know
an interesting way to continue the
conversation by having mystery Joanne
this is what we think should happen we
think that these works should be put
back on line and they should be
reviewable by the widest audience
impossible
and they shouldn't be and their they're
sort of power shouldn't be neutered by
the fact that
they're being taken offline so I'm we
joked about in the morning
and same yeah I think done throughout
the term like 0 they aren't and
and saying like yeah we should just like
pirate pirate this net art
and we laughed about it and then like we
were like well actually we should do
that
and I am but we both had a lot of stuff
going on that day
and we can get together and chill the
evening and then
we just yeah I mean either Andrew
together this
this sorta ask your template we we
polled there
as some definitions is your day in and
I'm
and assertive as Lucifer definition and
art as we could come up with their and
then
some and then reduced and put up there
we we went from to the torrent file
on The Pirate Bay and you can yeah we
can go back to their
Aquino sure and yes oh and yes for an
hour and a half we got the domain name
got the hosting that website up in a
Twitter account
and we had a torn up on the Pirate Bay
so is a really busy evening
but arm you know by midnight I am we
really didn't know what was going to
happen but we had everything in place we
started tweeting about it and the people
had
been following the show all day and
talking about it in curious about the
works now had
a place that they could go and get
everything so
you know our there is no way of knowing
when Michael started this show what was
going to happen
but on that you know we took in a way
that was unexpected
and down this was really beginnings
absurd AR so
arm when issuing interesting thing about
0d art is that
like um a lot of wares is there any
where's ends up on places like The
Pirate Bay eventually
and on we've actually had to you
arm not consciously but on come up with
are very similar om roles arm in have
people to help us
just like you might find in the later
seen so we actually have
people that arm for various releases and
again on you can see our website at the
ready are dotnet
we've had suppliers on and this is a
term that of course
I if you're familiar with nowhere see
that you see maybe an info files before
and again i'm for files again files that
accompany pirated software they give you
information about me how to install what
the serial number is
and a general information about the pot
the software
we have people that supply and again
suppliers people that would actually
give us the
I give us the software in this case the
art we have rivers as well because this
arm again this the stuff
exists online so it isn't always the
easiest and
come to get all the files of the
Internet on anywhere from movies to
pictures to texts
and we've dealt with various works nom
and in various formats
we also need people to help seed do and
down cedars again in if you're
unfamiliar with bit torrent web it when
it works is that you are
have a file somewhere up like on The
Pirate Bay Nova torrent file which is
simply
you know now man index it is not the
file is not the information itself but
it's really an index of all
files and a link to connect you to other
people that are seeders and leechers
over peer to peer network over a peer to
peer network in the Cedars people have
complete copies of the software
and on the in the season appears our
people there are also
you know are downloading rape and om and
we've had people actually help us see
this
and Dom which is very basic work on that
first night love our friends from across
the street was over
use in different apartment at different
internet connections there were used as
and utilize the sneaker net serum get
the data over to him
and the sneaker net if you're not
familiar is taking the date and walking
over to someone else
am so we we put this first release the
bars on a USB key
and we brought it over to him so that he
could spell by seed
from and get this and these files in the
this show distributed more quickly which
bring this to you
I'm how you guys can help um downstairs
in the
art space on the mezzanine level we have
kiosks n/a
am you might have noticed if used nephew
taking a walk to remember
incidences order old CRT monitor
displaying
NFL files and from and with 2400 2400
baud rate
from and the easier than a profiles for
the releases we put out so far in
connected to the monitor are two USB and
sticks then have all of the releases
we've put out so far
me along yeah I'm well they did when we
first put them
but the installation there from and
along with the income per
accompanying torrent files so
if you were so inclined you could go go
down there
grab all these releases grab a torrent
files and
load them into your BitTorrent clients
and help us see the releases
from we're gonna talk and done going to
talk a little bit about
10 var releases the most recent 1i think
actually I by an artist named Sarah wise
and this one was actually
little bit of a different scenario for
why we ended up taking
tignan on and releasing in 30 yard
me and this is an example when the info
files that we have and again
here we see that on just like %uh Norman
for filing the size the format the OS
the curator the show now it's a little
bit different in a traditional where's
info file
as well as the location release name the
date
you-know-who package it who supplied it
and then the URL to the show so we try
to give all the in from
information on when we release this and
this again is Sarah's project called
internet is
and I am this is and image on
that is related to the show in this is
really the reason we ended up taking
this on
so arm I guess it's best to show the
show
everything first and then we can on talk
about some love the reasons why
we decided to release this
gonna show here is actually home
when I release voters I'm so what
happens like if u
if you check out arm whenever releases
what you'll see so
again trying to view from over here but
if you go into
yes we have our mall love our folders on
me over files in here
and some of them are on the info file
we have I'm Sanjay pegs that where a
company company the show but then in the
actual folder itself
we have a do a directly Rep her website
where the show was hosted
and we try to be faithful to the on my
work that we we have
that we wrap and that's why we have this
index HTML but we also have one with
relative links
so the index HTML isn't actually gonna
work because of where every all
love the hyperlinks point to the
different files
so when we release it we in in addition
to doing straight rip up the side
and I the art that accompanies it we
also
on at the gym out that way can be
beautiful offline when you download it
and any additional information that
you'll need is included in the info file
so we had to be pretty on them pretty
comprehensive about everything so you
can actually
in on enjoy the do a two piece but also
if you want to see
on everything arm you know the way it
was we don't wanna gonna spoil it
and I believe that in in the case ive
and this work someone actually
am downloaded this and after
she took the site down someone actually
downloaded and is your day rallies and
put the site back up
using me index relative relative index
HTML file
so is it was put back online again
yet so am this shit and we'll just talk
a little bit about what is actual
work was and why it ended up being taken
down by the artist
from with Sarah Sarah participated in a
show
and that was good curated at in
pennsylvania called what is
internet and the artists were
tasked with creating a original works
responding to this and would whichever
way they
and they chose sushi boosted the AM
a job listing on the air aside for
voice actors and she asked she said that
she wanted as many people
and to respond to this posting is as
they liked but with the understanding
that only one of them would be selected
am for it actual payment for the job
and did the voice actors were supposed
to
tell tell her in their own words what
the internet meant to them
from so what she ended up doing was she
put put together a website where she
linked all abuse auditions from the
voice actors
with streaming streaming examples above
the audio that they
and performed am and then
she weighs going to allow the public to
vote on which was there
which one was the best and that was the
one that was going to be paid for the
job
unfortunately am the company
the boy voices on com the company that
weighs am
representing all of these voice artists
and took
issue with with the project and said
that it was a violation and their terms
of service
answer before she was able to even have
a public voting period
and the center a cease and desist letter
and Astor
and to take down beside from she
contemplated sorted keeping an open and
fighting it am legally because she felt
that the way that she worded
and the job posting was within their
terms of service
from but eventually she decided bad and
she really didn't didn't have that the
time
or on the front via the legal backing to
get into your
something like this and so we approached
her and said that we would be happy to
help
make make sure that the work and then
she created lived on
and and weighs Anna and would be
continued
to to would continue to circulate on
their on the Internet we can listen to a
couple these now
it's a very large it's a very
interesting project yet there's a
there's a lot of them and
I'd encourage you guys this is really
one worth checking out because it's
pretty amazing to hear what
an wake all the ways that these voice
actors present themselves and all the
things that they've been kept the
Internet is
years for a couple real quick hey this
is Lauren holiday here is your ID Shin
the internet is not a transcendental
ideation
in deceptive AutoCAD Excel Derek
redaction
nor and I get make individuality have
mobilised digress is nor spontaneously
race made it into homogeneous
individuality for Pete's sake
alright their I forgot how could someone
you know we might just listen to me for
the restaurant are actually
and there's no questions later will
display for sarah b rate let within
couple more
I don't know I they're so great internet
is
the beginning the future and the year
yesterday
alright script
this is Jean have Rico which internet is
my window to the world
on it when it's a good and on something
good
in communities the world for me mean for
the world
only when I want it at mindspeed
as a very little fuel cost are
I see if you're interested in this we're
giving have to download it
again damn you can check out are kiosk
downstairs and you can grab all over
releases this is on here and I am going
to take a look at it
right alright so again this is on this
internet is by Sarah waz
your so now I we're gonna
we're gonna sort of go back in time a
little bit and talk about another
project that weighs called aren't micro
patronage
which ended up being a target does your
day are
and them and then it played out in a
sort of an interesting way
over over the course of six months so
art micro patronage
is the side and that trying to create a
mano
Korea is is trying to create a model for
micropayments to
artists have internet art some so what
they're doing is they're
approaching curator's asking them to to
select a group of artists and then
they're presenting them
as they're presenting the Shari's on
their side
art mag her patronage downward um you
can click through the shows and as you
click through
and you the individual works your you're
given
assertive am navigation bar on the
bottom
that the window that allows you to
donate some small amounts of money to
their to the artist
from in doing so
you I you ensure that you have continued
access to these works even after the end
of the show
or so at as at their their model is
basically
like Iraq becoming a patron of the arts
you have continued access to these works
if you don't donate them after the run
have one month
bed show goes offline and it's not
it's no longer view more to you inserted
hitting up tell me that the people that
have dominated
so the first show that they and
that they put down boys won by Sarah
Klein it was called material motion
and we saw this as an opportunity
in 402 yards assertive step in and
archive these works and distribute them
again through
and through bitter networks in the
Pirate Bay and make sure that they
continued had to be accessible to
everyone you wanna
talk a little bit about the process im
sorry ive from
something that like made the different
media formats and how we were able to do
that yes this was
arm one where we needed some help
basically because it was alone with
their
interesting thing again about is your
day project is that once this release is
we'd understand if we hear about a show
what's going to look like what's gonna
have
on as a party that what'd media until
the day it comes out
and down we can always afford to take
off work everyday shows going to be
released some as the time it has eyes
as shows release in it germ-line I talk
there things during the day and at night
we're working hard to get
take everything and get it together so
the show was particularly interesting
because again
on has a rather complex arm on that
rather come back but it's a little more
complicated because over the
the frames and the payments and there
where streaming movies as well as
animated gifts
and entire web sites that word that were
shown
so you know the collection works it was
just one so
we've chatted you know safe able to am
you know archiving everything but as
well as working around somebody's
challenges
so we actually had om we had i
XR x two rivers here's where the for
shows where we had I'm jugar help us out
with getting on some love these files
that we needed of
love mom though as some in some the
streaming formats
and I and now we have we had a
reaction right away from art maker
patronage and A&M
basically and the the reacted and two
to the release of the show because I
think we had
we aren't we did something out from our
Twitter account there was a screenshot
of the Google search results for
I am for art micro patronage and the
first results were
on the Pirate Bay links to our door and
I'll
and my fingers like the first five or
six rebounds and then after that was
their website with the show on a
am so we said like don't like curator's
artists like don't say we never you
never did anything for you like that
we're increasing your visit visibility
and and so in
so as time went on am basically
the this was the first show and they did
a six-month season and by the last
shown this season an which was entitled
cream
curated by when the Howard whose
currently a curatorial fellow at IBM so
being sorted by come full circle
am we were actually invited you
be included in 10 are Tiger patronage
whose
shoes and so for 14 cream
an we we actually ripped every single
am show in the entire season 0
and the art micro patronage side so
there is sick shows including all of the
works within cream itself
and then we package that as a mega pack
from
chevon & Art and then released and on
the Pirate Bay
I am along with bad we created
an intro and we're gonna we're gonna
sure you are
the inter real quick that am so this is
that this is sort of like
we're some yeah hold on
its
bring the Browns are winning over what
is it like
so bad really not that good users
actually
okay now your new york than forward
slash
and the nation's from slashing
MP capitals you
and so you can see this your name
typical
troops home
Andrew Bolger its role tax am greets
our logo representing their and then
this with music that I produced word
donde recording running through and
Weezer nerve
really is there were you see we're sorry
like hearing in evolution
I am a crack in culture in the demo seen
culture and bringing this back
into the net art scene in seeing and how
how be used to use order similar by
but separate when you use can inform one
another
so
from through I had to read this
purchase participation in the cream show
at art micro patronage we actually ended
up becoming
the most funded project in the entire
season
over some I'm shows that they did
and Sue now what we ended up doing with
the money that was donated was we split
it between the Creative Commons the FF
in the Pirate Bay
and we just took Graham because we felt
like we were
we didn't really want to take this money
for ourselves for our first of all it
wasn't
it was in the a huge amount of money but
it also was
from a way that we wanted to show served
their organizations that we support
from and who we felt were related to
what we were doing
and we will are since our release ways
they were was actually
assertive compilation and the work have
many artists we felt that this was a
more reasonable
something to do them
%um yeah I think we're just gonna I
think we only have about five minutes
left so we're just gonna
from rather than and talking anymore
we're basically at the end of everything
we wanted to say we want to open it up
to questions and also just
from any suggestions people have were
we're really interested in getting more
people involved with the group
if this is something that sounds
interesting to you we'd love to get some
more people that are really
knowledgeable
in in terms of computer security and
from and think about other ways that we
conservative grow this project so any
questions feedback suggestions
if you could turn out the light a little
bit so we can see on
who is asking questions and who's trying
to leave her
yeah thanks and can I it's quick
question
your so I think a lot of this a yes we
allow this to me you know
at this is certainly an important part
in this is political obviously
and economic sense for americans a man
we live by the dollar
so when this all happened Michael
Manning at Eyebeam
I'm I know that there's a bit of a lot
of back and forth on that and someone
was public and someone probably wasn't
but do you guys how important was the
sole aspect love
artists being able to make a living and
what was what your work was how it was
affecting mad
I'm your obviously it's a very loaded
question but dis no I mean
obviously both the bus being artists in
addition to participants in this
in this group I'm you know I would love
to be able to live off my art when I
don't think is reasonable
is to you expect to be able to live off
my art
based on a system where you're imposing
an artificial scarcity on digital works
and trying to treat them like physical
objects
and that can be sold in the same way so
it's
I think to to you to try and approach on
the Salam
have internet aren't or digital art in
that way your
basically creating an unsustainable
situation which is
obvious based on what we've seen with
them and the movie industries and their
this hors d'oeuvres from and the music
industry's and so
their different dear part of what we
really wanted to do with this is say
like you can't
like take works offline that's not a
valid
approach to to solving this problem you
have to do it you
you have to think about other ways
monetizing these works
that are going to be sustainable and are
actually going to work and are actually
going
to allow the works to continue to
circulate through networks
this is
media overly artificial question but to
what degree do
CC with a are net
itself an art project more than a
political project
aka
I M obviously many there is there
it is it's a very open question and it's
something that we've talked a lot about
but
um I do you see it as
assertive art project in itself I think
that its assertive
am its to exist heard about the
intersection and wake
on hacktivism like open culture from
from conceptual art from
and and and and it is something where
we're trying to you from okay we have
two minutes we're trying a
basically am create conversation around
this but we're also
I in some ways we're curator's because
we're deciding which
shoes that we work we won our represent
thriller
through the side obviously we're not
going to release everything that follows
under their on relevant earn an ardent
susceptible to being taken offline
so its yeah it's something that is sort
of an ongoing evolution a
for us and we're not we're not exactly
sure where the project is going to grab
a wrap into that
yeah oh definitely open we won and he
said with one of the reasons being here
hope is really to make connections to
more people and talk to other people
they may have interestingly really do
want to hear from you
but we're definitely looking to kind of
go beyond I'd the
model just releasing works arm out that
other shows and looking how you know we
can actually help support
artists and I am through all I love the
kinda Press
and attention we've gotten through this
project so yeah we have kinda varied
future plans
and om and I and everyone hear from you
yeah so I think we I don't think we have
any more time for questions please if
you have any suggestions or questions
come up to us afterwards
also you can hit us up by on Twitter at
at 0 they are you can also
go to the web site WWW dot there they
are done and
and if you want to be my last its distro
d I asked you are 0 at zero d'Artagnan
thanks everyone for coming thank you