which is a you now signing protocol
I it's frequently used Wii
week he's so I'm gonna show you
break those and a I'm trying to get my
presentation software
running
I swear this was working fine 15 minutes
ago
okay
so de Cannes is an email saying protocol
it's different from a signature
protocols may be familiar with
like GP GP TP you or estline
GPG is a user-based signing
protocol it's based on the weather trust
model
so user a asserts user be is who they
say they are
and you get for whole bunch more people
doing at
and that's a valid the signatures
and tough I'm sorry
I s mine is
a lot more like SSL you have certificate
authorities
issuing certificates to users
and
really sorry you can't hear
I don't have my sights on that
okay but Deacon is different its
domain level signing see your mail
server is doing all of the signing
for you its
the goals are very different most in the
users using it for deliverability
that means they
want to make sure they're you know
doesn't cut get caught by spam filters
so consequently if it works ship it
is exactly what happens with it whereas
stuff like cheap uggs mine usually
its hurt to get it insecure
the defaults are all saying
and
okay these are not my way this is site
is a good friend of mine
device like the plan to stop okay
you can internet stalk on my own and not
necessarily those
voices in my head or anybody else don't
be a jerk
and Michael here tonight
is to raise awareness and get some
problems fixed
I
as everybody knows email is really easy
to forage
its on the level love writing
ally in return address on a postcard
I its
organization all so you don't have
individual users claiming responsibility
for messages you have the organization
asserting that they did send it ants
its use with white Mustang techniques so
you have reputation tight sealing secure
IP address
your domain name in a way that is not
really forged
I okay curies terrible acronyms
slide I I'll let you read that
real quick and move on interesting
things I
I sputtered you missed it this part
already
but everything I didn't mention is
there's SMTP s which is
SMTP with SSL and SMTP we start TLS
which is that's where
your communications airplane tax and
then you upgrade the session SSL
those things are used for encryption
over the wire
only it does not protect the message
contact from anything other than
eavesdropping
I 30
but this third parties are often trusted
with Deakin keys for domain names I'll
usually busy email marketing companies
the other interesting
thing is your email provider maybe
signing your e-mail for you I'll think
I know Google does its I
actually know some people they had a
ni harassing and the email and it got to
the point where they called the cops
on court got involved and
the guy was claiming oh i din can't
prove I sent those emails
will Google signs of your outgoing email
with the cam
from it's right there
that's something to be aware of at
right
so if you want to set up the cam the
first thing you need
is an RCT pair then you choose what's
known as a selector
this is just an arbitrary string it's a
label for years
then you set up your DNS records
I'm gonna show you how that works in a
few minutes you configure the
and mail server with that's like trying
private key: civic
it can properly market messages up I'm
not gonna cover that
because it's different for every mail
server and it's not really interesting
and if you're doing
large-scale outsourcing with
a email parking company they will take
your
email server setup for you because it's
their mail server and others give you a
key thing in putting your DNS
receivers verification is pretty trivial
there's a header in the message that you
look for parse it verify the signature
nothing super fancy their the
header is composed of a series tags:
their key value pairs you have if
version
which is just gonna be one have a
signature algorithm it's either Rs a
shot water ice 1856
guy I there's
a hash the message body in there which
is
a 64 incurred and along with the raw
signature data
there's your domain name here: selector
and you get high a list header fields
you require
so but the standard talks
about the selection at the
hair fields that you include being
non-obvious the only one that's actually
required is the from address that the
only one you
include is the from address and you're
signing your e-mail like that and
somebody can just take that signature
header
and as long as the from address is the
same signature remains valid
obviously you don't want that so
generally running through your message
body your day your subjects
your to lying miscellaneous other
headers
the other thing you can do is list and
your head or less headers that are not
present that asserts
absence that header you could do that to
you
stay insure that somebody doesn't add a
auto reply suppression hair
or something like that to your message
in re send it
you can also last the same header more
than once
in there which can prevent additional
headers from being appended
if you only included once you can add
more haters at the safety
same pipe only the first one will be
considered but if you have and plus
one you
your hash will include a value that
says you know I try to hash this twice
the second time was
absent and there will be no
this is an example signature better
the swine covers headers from to
subject dates the mine headers
that stuff I think super interesting
there but that's fine
what looks like
the text records just like
email headers are tag-based you have
again
key/value pairs most of them are
optional and rarely present
the really interesting wines are the
likes the old on there are some other
values the day
I'm not mentioning in there but
never use them but the test like is
interesting
the test flight specifies the you're
just testing he can
and anybody processing your mail
must not treat those messages
differently from unsigned male
that'll be interesting here in a minute
got a public key data
obviously and
mean you can read my site there's
nothing else terribly interesting here
here is one wakes you create a key pair
offices using open SSL
which is my preferred tool for
doing such things there are other tools
having
looked into that into too much detail
what's out there what the defaults for
them are
but that there's an example
DNS record up there that one has the
version
the key type and the public key data
once you've done that here in your
configuring your mail server
that information
there is another protocol called of a
game and signing
practices which never really got off the
ground
the idea ways a domain name could
specify a
what they're signing practices are for
email using teakamp
you can say I don't know if my mail is
going to be signed
you can say I sign all of my mail
and you can say I sign all of my mail
and not only that
if you see anything I didn't sign fees
threw it on the floor
that knowledge
the author the standard now advocates
instead of this standard
you should passed around privately s
the email
have domain names that actually know
what they're doing
on for example I found
that the of you has an 80 S P discard
record set
which means you should throw away all
their emailed its on-site
they also use test he's in production
so all of their male is set out to the
key that said you
says you should not treat this
differently from unsigned male
and their signing practices policy says
that they want everybody to throw that
email
on the floor so if your mail server
accepts mail from them and
isn't many standard
yes ya who was one of the authors and
that he can't stand it this one other
engineers is
listed in the standards and they still
got it wrong
%uh that will be a theme tonight the so
there's nothing inherently broken
that he can it's just that getting it
right is part
and its getting it right is the
exception
basically the only organization the day
seen
that I would consider to not be doing
anything silly is Facebook
I'm not really a fan on Facebook but
somebody call them out on their blog
that screwing it up and they stop
screwing up gay Facebook
for something I key rotation
is something that specified in the
standard
because smaller keyser often use
so they say oh well it's okay if you use
smaller keys because they don't need a
long lifetime
you can you can exchange key every
couple of months
a
yeah expecting people to do things
after they've got something set up and
working
you're gonna lose that every single time
third-party mailer mailing services
mentioned earlier of and provide keys to
customers customers
don't audit those keys they don't check
to see whether that mailing service has
used that he adds
fifty other customers for example
and the protocol
is described as not particularly the
security sensitive
but because it's used for whitelisting
and reputation techniques
a lot a trusted domain names
30 came signs the spam filters will let
anything through
as long as he's got a valid Deacon
signature that's a lot of fun
I even if I and if anybody's familiar
with
spf its it allows you to you
the text record and your domain name
that says what IP addresses are going to
use to send mail
so you can say so I only use this IP
address to send mail
and if you see anything from a different
IP address its a forgery and you should
drop it on the floor
but I have
seen a couple services which will take
Deakin signature as over right for that
and
for them a long anyway site
right the even if the even if the SPF
policy is heart fail
the D Kim will work anyway so how we
curry
kids 384 big he is which anybody who
uses they should be punched in the face
really his hi
think the first time somebody broke a
384 bit he was one of the RS a challenge
numbers
RCA the company you
was started by the guys who invented
this algorithm they released a major
challenge numbers to test the security
of our Sadies to be prize money
catch to it back in nineteen ninety 92
or 94
somebody broke 384 be
in a couple months with if you can
Gators I
that was a big deal at the time but it's
almost
two decades later why is anybody still
using
512 vicki's and
thousand-dollar PC
I am high and core i7
will will cut through these and 3-4
weeks
an interesting thing and that the
algorithms necessary
to you break RCA is that that the
algorithm depends only on the site at
the key
so there's no getting lucky and getting
it fast or getting i'm looking getting
it slow
pretty much every key at the same size
will take very close to the same amount
of time to break
512 ickies I
based on my own back at the and look
calculations online
how much it took to you breaky on ec2
I'm guessing you could spend one to two
million dollars
to break EN 8768 bikini
NEC to bit is not a lot of people using
is pretty cam
but 1024 bikinis
one of the guys who invented arce
that paper talking about the cost a
cracking those
in 2003 he was estimating
with custom hardware you could do it for
about
ten million dollars in hardware costs
plus twenty million dollars and design
costs but this is almost a decade ago
a lot has changed an manufacturing since
that
on the for numbers here
the RecA 768 challenge number which was
cracked I think about him
years ago they spent 15,000 core years
on it but
a large botnet can be 30,000
hosts 2768
vicki's either yes
yet honest says the you should not be
using
she's smaller than 2048 bit for anything
now
I am I'm getting sick that
on the slide so
why would people use the shitty keys
DNS
has been around since the dawn of the
Internet pretty much
it's a 30-year-old protocol dial-up was
the norm when it was invented
and dial-up had a maximum transmission
unit
576 bytes see you had your IP header
your YouTube he had her and then your
DNS response metal had to finish .500
76 bytes to work well so
there and it down to five minutes of
bytes thats E maximum size
the DNS packet ever you P I
a 2048 picky because the
the base64 encoding overhead
the S&OP one including overhead
all of that stuff and not only do you
have to include
the raw module is there's also a public
exponent you have to include
you get really close to that limit with
even a 2048 picky
and a 4096 pick you up to so
people when they were reading at the
standard they worried about that
that's one of the reasons smaller he's a
comment in fact the standard is not
even require verifiers to support keys
larger than 2048
I CA's I think in the last couple years
view given this year's a lot of shit but
at least 80 keep most people from doing
painfully stupid things they have some
news
and week he's a faster if you are
sending
outs an email to you
every single one of your customers kinda
knowing
bit you also want that to go fast
smokey's
cute faster people like
fast email delivery and the other
standard was designed with modest
security because nobody really cares
about this and as long as my email is
going through all of my customers I
don't care yeah
so what have we gotten the wild ebookers
they mentioned about Facebook
the link is up there if you want to read
it I
this guy span seventy days trying to
crack their fight for Vicky
gave up posted on his blog about it
they fixed it there was a follow-up blog
article for somebody's Cisco
Osisko by IronPort systems a few years
back
which is a spam filter planes companies
so they've got
alleged test data that's
tests that some in the wild data from
the systems they have
but it's two years old I unfortunately
not have access to you
mail servers that process email for
thousands of people are tens of
thousands of people so
made it is not as good but I read it to
a party can scrape
which will connect when I am that
mailbox and pull all the
BT cam headers out its I'm I did this
against my gmail account and
gmail account a couple friends and I
found some interesting things
anybody heard of a company called
epsilon interactive I
early last year they were the ones who
had a massive
email preach they had email lists for
many customers stolen and
those have been actively used for spam I
A
there were a lot of notifications that
went out to affected customers some
companies didn't notify their customers
cases you don't have to
but now
I would wager most in the people in this
room
our customer at a company that was
affected by this speech I
currently they have moved out their
customers to 1024 picky
and I the its unique per customer i cant
recall at the moment
but the old 384 bikini
is still there they were notified about
this nine months ago
didn't fix it cell I'm calling them out
on that
I yeah
their customers include several very
large
banks several brokerages luxury hotel
chains
those are some enticing targets for
somebody who wants to run a phishing
campaign
is also a large dial up by asking the
united states that uses the same
384 bit key for every ISP's domain name
that they've ever bought which is well
over a hundred
I am NOT mistake which one
but I think there's few
possibilities left I
you can help out where some %uh the ones
that were pushing
this standard because by if you get on
the internet a while
you're a member at that there was lots
of fishing for
you gain hey pal because pic mail
accounts
well they had money they're attached
bank accounts the train them and I need
a
you could cell something that you don't
actually have
get paid ran off with the money and but
I'm anybody it's wise to wait you're
long gone
so both of them have accounts that are
very valuable I
I A through my
deacons great program kinda 512 dickey's
thats there no longer using
but they have not removed it for DNS I
and II emailed them two months ago
to point this out to them didn't remove
it I cracked it
X fun so
that key the other interesting thing
about it is
that was a test key I remember what I
said earlier that s keys
there to be treated at any email signed
with a test key is to be treated as if
it was unsigned Eve and paper how r
about the only companies that are
Whiteley
actually
where the actual practices to you drop
an email from them that is unsigned
so this happened
I got that 32 my a gmail account
there's a nice little is a in Google
Labs there's an option
you can go that will nice little key
icon
next to you budget in an email that he
signed with the cam
this only works for you can take power
right now so its
it's really fun that I got it and
that that doesn't really that looks like
you is actually from the date nako
totally Vijay okay but here's a little
more
gmail see you I if you if you click the
little
Info button it all say signed by datacom
on this went straight into my inbox and
was Mark's as important
very important very important
opportunity to
for natural male enhancement okay
so thats
thats a showing off how do we crack keys
so for stuff going to take a few minutes
to you talk about
arce works this is really basic
the Wikipedia article has a lot more
detail if you're interested in how it
works
but the relevant stuff for this talk
first of it's an asymmetric algorithm
which means there's a public and private
key
give everybody the public key that's
cool long as you keep your private key
private
the public he is made up a two numbers
and which is called
the Model S and E which is the public
exponent
the private key has three additional
numbers P&Q
which are two large primes
that are approximately the the square
root but the modulars
the model is generated by multiplying
the Aztecs numbers together
and d on
is equation up there d
can be a ripe derived from E
P&Q if you have those three numbers
there is an algorithm that will
efficiently determine d
if you have the restive the numbers I am
NOT going to get into it
peco's open SSL
has that built in if you want to make
you a custom parameters
so that leaves us with P&Q as the two
important numbers that we would need to
find
and we can do this by factoring in much
less
now 512 the keys that a hundred and
fifty five digit number
that is a lot of work to factor as I
mentioned earlier it said
my PC 22 days to find it
so how do we do this there's an
everythin called the general number
field sieve
I A have to admit here iight don't
really understand how it works
I one of my friends told me that I was a
map script kiddie and he's right
bytes that's okay I think everybody with
a script kiddie something one day
and I'm trying to learn more there's a
venture open source tools
that do bits and pieces at this out for
them various
a bunch of stages to it it's really
complicated
some people there was a perl script that
was written while ago
with mostly works somebody way better
python script
it automates running all the tools
necessary to you perform the Outrigger
key conversion is still tedious going
from an RS a public key
getting my Julius out a bit takes a bit
of work
the open SSL tools that you can use to
pull the module is that a public key
you hacks you have to feed it to these
tools and ethanol
and then even more tedious is to turn
the factors
into a private key I could not actually
find a program to do this
I a for a very small perl script but
I am I'll see that in a bit
if you 12 try fact himself
there is a great tutorial on using the
Python script
there's a bench dependencies to set up
but if you can follow a how-to
and you have a Linux box it's pretty
easy I think the Indian people
Windows binaries if you wanna do that
and that is how you would convert eighty
can text record
to a much less except for the step where
you turn it into de small
I N they look funny oh now
I don't think so so
I am when I ways testing this out
Iran's commands like that I ate pops
nigel is in the pipeline
and hacks which happens to do a great
job of converting our checks a decimal
numbers into regular decimal numbers
if Icahn you save it to you file called
she got and
and year and out as a type on my side
okay you're in. seconds I
with the the word file name is a
parameter and of it goes and then you
wait a while
I played around with doing this on ec2
BK's
I A had a nother key that I wanted to
crack
this presentation and it wasn't going to
finish in time
the the set up for that is fairly simple
you can run the polynomial selection
phase of the algorithm
thats it's the first phase polynomial
selection
the CFA's news
some post-processing where you build up
a huge matrix
relations found in the city Phase and
you news when I saw her on that
and so read that on my PC
uploaded the polynomial that came out of
that phase
to you an ec2 instance
heights are never mentioned cluster
compute spot instances
I and a half million people are with
ec2 they have a system where you can bid
on spare capacity in the system
which will let you get a resource that
normally costs
250 an hour for 25 cents an hour as long
is
you don't mind having its shut down on
announced if somebody wants to pay more
than you
for this that's fine so
you get one note that all the master
were
the computation an image slave nodes I
did this for 16 instances
the city phase took about six hours I N
cost me about a hundred dollars
hundred dollars is totally worth it if
you're going to be doing a phishing
campaign
I you do have to kind of the 88 I A
didn't see a way to get it so I'm
actually stop my extra instances
thanks sensors are costing me several
dollars an hour I A
we did around in shutting off and then
you got your post processing
that takes a while by
at least at that point the
post-processing only runs on one
computer
I couldn't find a way to make it run on
multiple computers faster
i think thats limitation at the tools
so read a few programs to
to do stuff the person I wrote was
a program that will take a factorization
and convert it to a private key
given the public key I you can also
easily extract the public key from a
certificate if you're
say I down there was the TI calculator
signing keys that were
cracked a while ago that was a
certificate now to rob public key
public easy enough to extract
so you get this to all either the log
file
Tron fact himself or
the raw factor you just one of the
factors is fine
is used by the models by factory get one
it generates about private key file that
you can use
i reprogram called D can scan which
is almost to the level is being in
denial of service tool
packed I A
took the list the selectors I saw from
scraping
a few male schools and compiled a word
list with major rules
I've gets an example rules up there
essentially what it does is it can take
forward at a plain weird last and
scandal at those entries but there's
also a couple expansions the you can do
they say numeric range expansion which
can be used
either with or without leading zeros
there and because I read in for all
the numeric range expansion operator
also works on letters
really okay I'll
a typo nice here
anyway the other funding
is there's an expansion rule that will
take the domain name that you're
currently looking at
and slice and dice the parts at that I
saw
a fair number domains that use the
domain name again
as the selector that a fine at get
d came down which given a domain name
and a selector will give you get it up
the public eats up there
I this is a test that I set up
this is a 256-bit key
I have not seen any keys that small
actually used in the wilds
but that would be terrible this is like
the test uses a slightly older version
it might well then
the current one will actually list out
whether it's like this tester
it's ready for production that's what
the public he looks like
and also got a fingerprint shield their
which is shot one of the public key you
can use that
to tell which domain names
are using same public keys if for
example they're using the same marketing
company or
their bench domain names and by the same
company and
they don't care I'm we have D can crack
which is not fun once you get
fact insist that up all you have to do
is
gifty can crack the domain name and the
selector and it does everything
it will pull the public yet at the Andaz
extract the module s save it to
configure file
perfect and SIV run fact MC give you a
big estimate how long it's going to
take.
and automatically construct the private
key I A
have a demo that tonight in fact
and then there's D can spoof which will
take that private key
and a well format it email message
animal at Deakin header to that email
message
so that you can use it without setting
up your mail server to you
said okay let's see if my laptop still
hates me
area
I kits to pick
I can everybody read that
I so here's that testimony showed you
out
route
I can fix that
that's what I get for
not testing this part of the demo
well
on benefited ec2 is that their packaging
areas are very very fast
Palace
see if I got any other paints
hit
thank you
sorry I'm absolutely terrible typist
okay I will do a different demo than
get up on stage in any every single type
a possible
and my computer spends first 10 minutes
not working
okay
that one
affiliates let's see if it works
try this one more time and I will to
another company that actually works
okay great so what this would do
if I hadn't been too stupid to set up
all
dependencies ahead of time because I had
been testing is on a different system
I is it will rand
run in Civ this key is Canada rigged lol
because
256-bit key takes about three minutes to
crack
but it'll out the private key
I so I did already to you
a key I anybody familiar with the
black hat security conference it's in
Vegas in about a week
on they
they use an outsource provider to you
hands all
sending out their marketing messages and
these five in each of the key
and this was the key that I cracked on
ec21 about eight days
up there we go if you've already cracked
it
it will just poll the factors out at the
log file
and give you the private key directly so
there we have a private key
and let's see if
I am liked my gmail
excellent
okay this is sending it without the
signature
I should get mice
am order ever go
so this went to my spam folder cuz a
shaker in a second
ion spf failed
I in fact at heart failed because
they specify if they don't quite was the
white
IP address its peak I
so
per pair
and that limits my inbox and
I ago
I %uh the second time
I ate use D can spew with that Breivik
what
oh I'm sorry I didn't show original on
ass you're right
so it's got a valid became signature
here on
somewhere in there which I can't see
right now because reasons
it says that he can it should say in
there somewhere that the Deacon
signature is
valid I'll okay
thank you I still can't see it I don't
know why I'm
I'm sorry that I had some technical
difficulties with my talk I have a few
minutes for questions
because deaconess a
and trusted huge trusted yet
people screw up SPF all the freaking
time so
I quickly a few other things that I'd
like to do
I been working on some tools to track
key usage over time by monitoring male
schools
see when people read take their keys
when they changed he cited stuff like
that
I at some database supports my tools
integrate DNS service with email servers
so that yet idiot first irritation and
as to how not to screw this up at
use 2048 he's possible
if you can't because they want this 1536
wreck a quarterly should be safe I if
you get screwed doing that it's not my
fault though
but make sure you delete the old keys
make sure you check to see
when your third party mailer is doing
and
if you've got a third-party mailer you
can
CNAME the D can record so that
if the need to retain it for whatever
reason targets of the compromise they
can just delete it
okay I have time for maybe one more
question 0
I I didn't say that it was about a
hundred and twenty dollars
yet they will be up I and my get account
which
is its get have duck pond slash
Qube are seven slash t- can keep WN
I any turkey that again its get have
docked on
slash to you the ER seven slash
D can pwn