good morning whom I am
iron by the rescue bid I was up really
late last I got to bed around 7:30 this
morning
so I got a couple three hours sleep arm
I wanna thank you for getting up so
early company this topic that's really
important
I am I'll talk about this talk I mean I
joined a couple mountains pronouncements
first
on in addition to talk to you on that we
do a lot of work shops here too
I'm gonna hardware hacking area
the the mezzanine level and in at nine
in hackers base village area on and also
on the six floor
there's two rooms known as the Paris
room in Budapest room
and a it's been really blinded good
hands-on workshops going on there
this morning there are two on
one-inch called morning healing really
not about hockey with the hacking your
own
your and physiological are being
on so any malcolm she is teaching that
and it's a basically two its internal
well-being type of thing senate really
good at nine needed after last night I'm
that's a 10 o'clock
on the six floor and also this morning
from 10 a.m. all the way to 1 p.m.
its whatever floating thing come in when
you want but I don't show up after 12
is there FCC amateur radio
examinations I ham radio stuff we have a
station set up on the 64
a special cause an issue to it by the
Federal Communications Commission
and nine each for this event with the
plan
this past week and we've communicated
with the in 15 or 20 but nearly fifteen
a
other countries with about with just a
few want to power
I'll Mosby data communications on
cuba Czech Republic Russia Costa Rica
Argentina much more are those be great
medications
using no infrastructure between
morning point B pretty interesting on
sale show up
you big thank you have no chance and
help pass in this thing
but you'd be surprised to get a count on
these tests a few years ago
for in a mine anybody can believe it so
where
go down there and give it a shot after
this talk good and they're
six more is fifteen dollars which in fcc
v
and take the bank got nothing to lose
and is the closest thing we have to
to government-sponsored hacking I think
a ham radio how brazen the hacking the
radio spectrum for
over a century its it's a really awesome
community into a lot with it when all
each other communications made sales
this works so on turned right on about
that but it's a it's important part of
our community
I'm decided to park is about avoiding
you bakeries surveillance being or
becoming aware there
and what you can do to avoid everywhere
you go
in hotel Pennsylvania out in the streets
on there are
racially countless forms have
surveillance technology
or pointed at us Anna you now have my
money the records
is there one out when everybody had to
get your paranoia is just good thinking
doctor don t be heard if you care be on
severn
I always remember that when I get when I
see Perry's rise and communications in a
in public areas so out without further
ado annie cruz said
great Kante and Lisa Shea are both have
been with West Point for about a decade
teaching about this stuff they both
academics be really know their topic we
had lease on off the hook on the radio
show last week talking about her
week before last was in year and
but two days ago and Adam she really
year she really AM
explained a lot about what we should
beware if I wasn't aware
so had a great time thanks thanks very
much bernie & I just as a side note
Gregoire both ham radio operators
for but that's where I'm
so as as bernie mentioned we are both
instructors at West Point we are blessed
with academic freedom we
we teach at West Point on but these are
our own personal view is that we're
giving you their not
necessarily the views have West Point
the DOD Department the army
United government ernie any other formal
entity on
and and context matters somebody's
things that were going to tell you about
may not be legal to do in all places so
on common sense prevails were not out
here to get
anybody in trouble especially ourselves
arm we're not lawyers either
we're were computer scientist analytical
engineers and ham radio operators
so but we really want you to get on this
talk
are basically three things one that
network surveillance systems
are out there there's lots of them were
under them
even as we speak now are big can
threaten our privacy and our way of life
there
that we enjoy individuals can and should
take steps to protect yourselves
some its common sense movements more
than common sense
but especially in this audience with
olive you
this community has the opportunity the
knowledge the status
the networking specialist social
networking to do more than just protect
yourselves
you can deflect the trajectory this
surveilled future
serving
so is a burning wood burning mentioned
you have to be blind at least in our
community you have to be blind not to
see this
the sensors that are popping up at
virtually every facet of our lives and
some
then we invite into our homes some them
are invited to tour
you know in our societies burnt or
communities for us if you've driven
across the George Washington Bridge
or any other such Lee checkpoints coming
in onto the island
you're well aware solo what we did
is taken you know I'm sending a pic the
counter measures by looking at what are
the trends that may cause concern that
we need countermeasures in the first
place
well just as an example the government
India
is the planning on tracking its
citizenry using a biometric
identification system
on the order of 1.2 billion people and
kinda the first
generation this there's
research right now only think about
parts of your wives are currently 0 peak
to various sensors are various people
who'd like to separate you from your
money
or to keep by your respective nations
save
and examples you know review your living
room
very orwellian Arbor TVs and watch you
are currently under under development in
the idea that they can tell people are
sitting in front
better targeted advertising and all
sorts of other
potential uses in the same thing
communities in
in this is just an example that their
one group building a billion-dollar
scientific ghost town
to be sweet instrument the whole
community and you know largely these are
for
business schemes not forward on the
surveillance society in the future
but if it not good privacy is not built
in with proper
safeguards them we risk doing just that
and then there's also applications what
do people do with these new data streams
or
environments and I thought this is just
one example well if they can count
emperor penguins from space
when also I can they do with that type
of technology in
in not just a one-off instance as we
sexy technology evolved
know this type of activity really could
occur in real time
and we see other applications
an often a trend for military technology
being used in
say law enforcement or commercial use
and in this just example the police
drone
you know anything on the website very
Skynet like photo that flying over
metropolis
and you there are technical challenges
and one of them being power
we see research into better power for
these mobile
worse fix sensor systems an example just
nuclear-powered redrawn research trying
to go from D's
two months to on time on station lot of
investment behind it just
one example many many many examples
is minneapolis-saint Paul launching a
twenty million dollar
HD surveillance cam camera project and
for those
live in Manhattan your I think you're
well where are the surveillance has put
a system being put in place post-9/11
in also increased capability another use
love the generator stator what do you do
with it how do you
how can I be applied how can be mined in
the capability is getting better and
better
now I to me a great example SoundHound
you hold that up because the sample the
song
and I can tell you what the song was and
if just had
imagine how powerful that is and then
very it's what variance to that could be
used for
same thing official recognition
capabilities
were really good idea identifying people
based on their physical appearance for
other biometric
attributes trying to get to the unique
identity per person
and again getting much better active
area for research
and when technology alone won't work
we're seeing hybrid solutions that
happened what humans are good at and
what machines are good at and this just
as an example
was a Google using capture to help
humans decode street view addresses
sensors are getting better and better
on on a daily basis and just right now
in this basically terrifies me
the idea sensor your real time video
through solid walls
so your home's are you know dne aren't
necessarily secure
I know it's not the best view on the
right hand side but it's there and it's
a merging technology
behind much of this or incentives
incentives for government incentives for
businesses incentives for individuals
to employ and use these the sensor
systems
and just your people like their money
and you know this was just an example
that is GPS being used for driver
discounts
and may have seen various marketing for
free on that trying to commit to put
these in their cars
in return for a discount
and then in general the justification
typically is to improve your
you know your online experience shopping
experience
key component of this is tying into some
to some records from database
tells who you are because you have to
stay to you wanted Associated
in with some person or group of people
and you see various
the Thames coercive disclosure identity
and I think you can look at
Google+ you know it first came out the
real-name policy trying to talk to real
name
being just one example money so in this
case but the idea that you can't was
people's arms
and he that your billing records cell
phone numbers or idea that the other
means
be able to hide those the that those
data flows
at reason those data flows to people you
have you ever tried to get an anonymous
EZ Pass if I know how
now difficult or essentially impossible
that is
and what this picture a puppy is is so
if you go on the Google you're looking
for vulnerability
this is this is the closest I could come
to you out upon our ability
the soft underbelly above the suit
systems
ok I try I try to be what is
vulnerability
are so Google Images is beautiful for
things like that
but the systems themselves often
partners linked to attack by third
parties and then they can get the people
can get in
am and use the systems that we're
building so this is a
legal uses illegal use and other
examples and Tom prosecute a great talk
and black hat DC
that explains some some the ways it
could be time
and then you see a lot of concerning
blue sky ideas
the for example the idea of using US
postal trucks
as a fleet sensor platforms right you
think about that
driving peered community constant sensor
sensors in every
I censored you're monitoring the
community via the US Postal System
so not this is being implemented by it
sure does make one nervous
the end result of all this is the
potential for misuse
is high we build it for arguably well
intentioned reasons
but the potential for misuse either
through a slippery slope above
you know which emit legal uses war
heard were illegal use do for building
this infrastructure that could certainly
abuse and in negative ways very very
negative words
but will lower work and we're focused on
the physical world here
world live online surveillance for
another talk
these
so there is a Dr Chinese
general name sons who who lived about
2500 years ago
and what we're trying to to educate you
about on
is actually has ancient roots on Sun
soon
said many many things is his book is
often quoted they are 24
but one of the things that he said was
if you know your enemy
and you know yourself than a hundred
panels you need not fear the outcome
and dachau we're trying to get at here
we're gonna look at deconstructing a
surveillance system
and Greg and I and some colleagues at
West Point have
have developed a surveillance system
model and as I talk through the
different component to the model
think about what are the vulnerability
is what it was the soft underbelly
over each of these components until its
start out with the censors its a sensor
system it has sensors
we look at sensors in as an electrical
engineer
inserted two broad categories sensors
can be passive
Witcher what's down the bottom left
corner the receive energy
from the environment and that's
fundamentally wanna sensor does is it
it detects energy of some sort
you could have an active sensors well
think other police radar gun
active sensors omit some form of energy
and then measure weren't returned
all these sensors fundamentally measure
analog quantities pressure
lying he'd something like that on but
all these computer systems that we work
with transmitted and stored digital
information
so the sensors generally convert the
analog to digital
and then there's usually a local
processing and local storage that's
that's conducted two probes do feature
extraction identify
those on those identities perhaps our
the key
characteristics I and then often that
data is stored locally
what we're most concerned about are
these network
surveillance systems or network sensor
systems
because data that stored locally you
have to go there to hack it it's its
it's more difficult to to compromise but
most
many systems nowadays transmit data
across
a network and I don't have to tell this
community happy how many vulnerabilities
there are when you start doing that
and the data is then aggregated and
stored perhaps in the cloud is stored
somewhere remotely
and again that has all sorts of
vulnerabilities
finally none of this would really be a
concern have never looked at it
but were concerned about who has access
to this data
who are the legitimate users and what
are they using it for
and then of course as greg mentioned
these systems can be
can be accessed by illegal third parties
and thats
of course a concerned us um in addition
the systems don't have to action
miss only be accessed by real people one
sensor system can talk to another sensor
system
or two just another network computer
think I've greg mentioned EZ Pass I I
love easy pass it makes
Mike Gillis commute much easier I like
not having to stop
every bridge toll and fork over well
known to buck 50
arm why live upstate here's where
marjorie
yeah no idea his pace and outrageous fee
but yeah I have a cheaper commit
so it's nice to be able to just drive
through the toll booth
but that EZ Pass system connects to you
the credit card system because every
couple months the doc
25 or 35 bucks off my credit card so the
system's time to other systems and then
you wonder about the secondary
security about other system so these are
all
definitely areas of concern
so now that we've we've known a little
bit about the the system as a whole
let's look and technologically based
countermeasures so first off start we
started with looking at the sensor
let's look at the center only bonus if
you gonna
counter and two system you have to
understand what characteristics are
Jo Brand has done some great talks on
hardware hacking
including one on DEFCON 17 and smart
parking meters
if you know what the hardware consists
love you can figure out how to reverse
engineer it
and potentially on avoid
being subject to it home
ultimately you would like to denied a
greater defeat the sensors
first you have to know where they are so
this is a really clever
car radar detector from a company in
Japan
not sold in the US that I can find it
combines a GPS with the radar detector
on showed an and other online services
can be a great source for finding
Sony's networked sensor systems if
they're visible online
you can use online tools to find them
and then then you know if your
if and when you're being surveilled
sometimes
the people who put the systems in the
place tell you about them
Washington DC among some other local
governments tell you where the traffic
cameras are these are designed to help
commuters
so you can avoid rush hour rush hour
traffic jams
sometimes community organizations band
together
and develop on databases and where the
sensors are
you have to understand where the sensors
are whether engines
what they're covering and then
potentially might be just easy to bypass
them
home maybe with a little bit of work
maybe a maybe have to get any is doing
arm but certainly if you can bypasses
sensor
thats that easy countermeasure others if
you know the more technical than about
the sensor
if you know its sampling returned
sensitivity you can did
defeated that way Mythbusters has done
some great episodes on this especially
episode 59 the looked at a number
sensor systems that were defeated in
movies and of course that know the Huron
the movie
that blows a a little bit album powder
and you see this this network to rave
lasers all around and they can
they can just step over instep under and
crawl around them
if only it were that easy may the Boston
a number of things that were shown in
the movies
not everything in the movies is true I'm
I'm but we we tested a couple use our
cells we have
in are electro engineering program a
flutie i 55 thermal imager and were able
to verify that yes indeed glass does
block
in for a on this is a a picture person
who's standing partly behind a glass
door
and you can only see the party the
person that's not behind the glass door
now granted that's maybe not the most
practical countermeasure walking around
New York City carrying a pena classism
probably not recommend in arm went for a
lighter re
more durable alternative try acrylic
plexiglass
works just as well much lighter doesn't
break you have no drop it
however you might wanna put handles on
the backside
causes you're holding the plexiglas it
will heat up and then you can see
through it again
other types is electromagnetic your
other times ive
energy that you might want to shield
against
0 electromagnetic energy there's RFID
blocking wallets
there's this really interesting product
to wifi shielding wallpaper that
reagan I wanted to test it's not yet
available we sign on a
on a website should be on I think this
fall the neat thing about it was it
alleges that it will block your WiFi
signals from getting high your house
so people can snoop in and non use your
use your WiFi network but it will allow
cell phone signals into your house
which is an auto engineering I'm pretty
fascinating because
cell phone ban goes up to 1.9 gigahertz
and WiFi
here to 11 BG and is it 2.4 gigahertz so
how it can have that sharper filter I
think is pretty fascinating
where maybe Maybin doesn't work so well
happy Easter
by if you want to block visible light
you could you could do something like
put on these laptop copy Bunny Sox
it will prevent people from seeing what
you doing I wouldn't want help for those
people that can detect your typing
simply by listening to you
on and it may actually attract some
attention
but it's a technique home and that
ultimately if
if you're not connected to a network you
have to work on air gap
if your computer only is connected to
your printer
using a cable and it's in your house
then
then you're protected to a much greater
extent
hard to surf the internet that way but
sometimes these trade-offs
other forms shielding and sim
residents have Tempe Arizona had
in some issues with cameras that were
posted in their neighborhoods
and so around christmastime Santa Claus
gave those present
those those cameras present in
you may have heard in the news lately
stories about graphene
making invisibility cloaks did not
entirely science fiction there's
electromagnetic properties of graphene
that will allow it to deflect
electromagnetic radiation these are
still lab tests
sorts of things but it could be coming
to you to a theater near you
the military of course is interested in
these are two things
the navy's interested in ultraviolet
cloaking
we have a variety of systems and chaff
where you can
disperse material to prevent radar from
on to Broome your your visibility here
to rate or
I'm and they're looking at being able to
do that in other specter
or instead I've deflecting radiation
maybe he just want to absorb that
radiation if best answer
doesn't detect the reflection then it
doesn't detect you
so there are eight arms Irving materials
and potentially
other types have absorbing materials
we're finally
arm another opportunity would be to jam
that sensor
send bank more energy than it's
expecting to receive
its we live in just a cool world you can
search on the internet
for green laser pointer webcam and yet
just dozens of cool pictures like this
non-destructive at least you miss you
doing a liner close range
or the really high power laser on but
its you know it's it certainly effective
at blocking the image
or you could try and destroy it with
much more intense radiation
again nothing that you can find
searching the internet high-energy
RF guns these however you want to care
ok you can kill yourself happen
these these are dangerous if you point
these it targets you really want to make
sure that you own the target your point
because you can you can do some serious
damage to
people who work with mint lower te quise
disabling might be something as simple
as when black people over lands
war for disabling audio sensors
potentially a microphone plug
that greg has is this cool picture the
the microphone plug com it
isn't something that he found but he
hasn't actually found a real source for
anybody knows weakened by members cool
low-profile climbs
please litmus now I'd like to buy couple
thousand of them
and I mean I can go to Mauser digikey
and and
and get clothes but they're not they're
not that cool low-profile time
so you refuse if you see one that is now
arm soon
so what we would get so far is largely
energy-based
with the you know the energy being
omitted heavy block it disperses and so
forth
with the sectional look as little bit
higher level I had more than information
model
and how denied to feed her degree that
in the process associated processing
one come strategy is that it's proving
that you're generating something to me
that
books to be one thing that is actually
something else and
there exist you interesting that you can
go back and look forward to operation
bodyguard they had
mock-ups a very is viewed vehicles used
for Battlefield the section
and then today you see circuit on the
Russian inflatable weapons but the idea
is
similarly camouflage circle World War
two
doesn't camouflage used to in some cases
Hyderabad are camouflaged being used to
hide a blend into the background
but also to defeat being able to be
locked on her divert the I so when they
gonna refuting a
had a target they would be would divert
them away from the sensitive areas
doubt and then there's example dazzle
camouflage circa 1917
in interestingly dazzle camouflage circa
I and its makeup and makeup
you know techniques for defeating
several things one is
daschle detection so it a
the the computer algorithm can't
necessarily detected faces there
effectively making you invisible to the
algorithm war
defeating it defeating the
malcolm's ability to form facial
recognition and there's a great talk on
on the right on the right hand side the
dazzle camouflage
official recognition facts and fiction
and
other from DEFCON 18:
also the idea a degree in Information
quality in
inserting spurious activity if Europe
and the Prisoner your college the it's
your funeral
episode where people would deliberately
in certain ways you know tryin ads
fool people into thinking they were
going to take some action which they
never did
eventually lowering the threshold to the
point they the
powers-that-be the serbia was not their
harm us
and than they could strike
and also to overcoming the processing
altogether absurdly powerful
if you're looking at human base
processing
and just I'm not advocating this but one
example Arab New York Times just earlier
this year
was the idea if you want to crash the
justice system just go to trial
beyond the be high-level information
degradation type activities it's very
useful think it just
collection intentions towards and wipes
p.m.
of course there's encryption for data at
rest were delayed
in transit but there's other activities
or other
means to lower the a century billy club
data
for example you may have seen privacy
glass is that type of thing did
only you can see what's on screen and
to let me just say it's a great time to
be alive when they learned Austral
shredders that you can put a Volkswagen
bug
into in trader should all be an
important part of our lives
maybe not that big but
there's also the idea because uRS and
the idea
basically we need a plan to destroy our
data sometimes that's built into
companies because the word about
discovery
update on being able to get you get
pulled out into a court of law which
maybe and senator a bit in general the
idea we need a plan for a stronger data
personally
and in the people we deal with
in avoiding generating data in the first
place I'm
sometimes we have a choice sometimes we
don't
we need to use a common sense to make
sure that when we have a choice we're
not doing
disclosing something that we should and
I was up for less rather than more
however are becoming a Leo Leone low
tides
and attempting to live in the 21st
century I can be very difficult
thing I I'd like to live in the 21st
century don't want to live in a cabin in
montana
but you I think there are times in our
lives we have a choice
or companies have a try sometimes their
governments have a choice
sensors themselves apart up sensor
systems you often
with command control
there are opportunities good and bad for
sensors to be controlled
this is an example love the ability to
turn off cameras
I was packed boat remote cameras by
sending certain signal to the camera
personally I find that concerning the by
certain entities could turn off my
camera against my will
but nonetheless there are perhaps
mechanisms for controlling the sensors
but in there also I mean using the
online example we
have the police control use and privacy
settings how much
information we share to the public and
tubers group
however and oftentimes that
you've seen that it wasn't your Facebook
there's a constant sirs articles how
their
privacy settings which shall we say
artwork all that intuitive
and we're set with the faults that were
all there be protected from privacy
I'm but beyond that be weird delusion up
control
so you can set your privacy settings all
day for who you share information with
under social networking site
but you should not forget that Homer
data
every conceivably spinner actually
likely resides forever
on the servers up the company that
you're dealing with so but beware the
illusion of control
people see bob also
denial of service and I i think now
service particularly interesting when
you look at the human
in the communications channel aspects
period since systems and I thought this
was a great example
are good but whites if I could see you I
would say
with the show him who's received robo
calls that they haven't that into their
lives that they haven't
okay I can see him I could see a test
I'm
so one enterprising company decided to
build a reverse robo call our
so let's say a given government leader
decided to call you invite you to vote
for him or her in their campaign
this company would allow you to dial
that person back repeatedly
expressing your personal interest it not
being on there
on their list anymore are it no
I went back later in the company's is
now not offering the service
I'm not sure exactly what happened but I
thought it was a great track
and then be on the nightly so good get
into this larger context minute
but was so we've talked about the the
censor themselves energy flowing
than information but we also need to
understand actors because really they're
the people building
sharing allowing these things to take
place
so with that altruism
so the monoline I talked about a little
bit ago
is is a technologically focused mono and
and that's important because thats
that's who we is technologist my own
to to tinker and we have the expertise
to to exploit
but even more important is
the ability d to understand how that
model
fits into the real world because
technological solutions
aren't always the the most permanent if
you can get a system removed entirely
then then that's better than having
defeated
honor an angel sent to prison term basis
so let's look at the world that these
that the sensor systems resign in for
star
the sensors have targets and often
that's that's us
and and as users and as citizens we
should be concerned
and understand what these with the
systems are and then think about
how we how we want to interact with them
we're
or perhaps not interact with them at all
I'm all these systems
or in place for a purpose who uses the
data
who has legal and says who is illegal
access
what are they using the data for and
can we strike a compromise with them
that they can get
some or most to the benefit in that
system
with down unduly affecting our privacy
all the systems have enablers and by
that we mean
corporations companies individuals that
the design-build more kid these systems
they have a financial incentive in these
systems
but can they also be persuaded to build
in security building in privacy
so that their system is still profitable
them
but nyse: owners to us
and then all of the systems that are in
place are in place by
some organizations some collection of
people BNA
a company were a government or
no whether to local municipality or a
national government
and the whose owners have a vested
interest in getting some benefit from
the system's
but again perhaps there could be a
compromise struck
that they still retain some poster all
the benefit
without being detrimental to our way of
life
on and then finally already in the
system regulated
should they be regulated can they be
regulated who might best
regulate them so that we can
continue the way of life that we enjoy
without
arm without suffering the harm thats
the second-order effects from so many
systems so
or though we as technologist
always tend to turn first words a a
technological solution
its is often most effective to
to look at this broader context so
influencing
the policy in policymakers can be a very
powerful way
counteracting systems on and in
in many countries in the world including
this one we can do that through the
ballot box
and I encourage all a beauty to use your
right to vote
in a way then I'm that
you know did exercise your right to vote
we also as as technologist have a unique
ability to educate
educator friends educator neighbors in
our communities
about the system's but then also educate
the decision-makers
and if if we want to influence policy
and we wanna have laws
that protect privacy the policy makers
need to understand the issues
perhaps on the best ways to educate is
through the mass media
and so Stephen cans given in excellent
are on how to talk to the mainstream
media
to the or voices become heard
more broadly I'm and and we can learn
from history
visited other my students sometimes
think that the the only important
inventions incurred in the last five
years
that's not always the case look to
history and learn from it
mass media can be influenced on
this research a really cool billboard
that we found you can educate people
in in some way unobtrusive ways and
again
if if it's just one or two people
speaking out
nobody hears you but if you really
support in get
thousands tens of thousands hundreds of
thousands on your side
you can make main impact we all remember
what happened in January when
when Wikipedia and major online
companies
work on the Internet yeah I'm and add
that when your parents
our grandparents are asking about what's
open is we've succeeded
yes I'm and even on a local scale
the state of pennsylvania ran and for
tax amnesty that had
these were really implications and it
was used way over the top
on when and say things like
was in time we can make this easy in a
satellite video
on his zooming in on a picture about
house
and presumably in pennsylvania my he to
be the person actually own that house
when I feel paranoid om so
so this was an and that was that was
just kind of egregious
and the local community protested
recently we went back to the site we saw
that video
and and it wasn't there cell
sometimes sometimes you can effect
change
they even took the head on
URL and some under enterprising up
enterprising entrepreneur repurposed it
for his a his or her own benefit
I'm but it's important to communicate
these issues effectively
when you speak to you be felon
technologist
you might speak differently than you do
to the mass media or than you do to
decision-makers
into you have to communicate these
issues effectively
on Daniel solove had very powerful
example talking about privacy and
and just how sticky a concept that is
when those things that we we know when
we see it but how do we actually define
talk about it art can be a powerful we
communicate
and and again sometimes sometimes that
works
science fiction is well-known were
communicating in raising issues and
I've technological problems long before
they
they actually are instantiated you
can often be affected if you highlight
cost-benefit analyses
on the TSA has drawn much attention for
for ways that its surveilled us on
and in sometimes in very harmful way is
and as you draw attention
to you health risks were costs
the effectiveness the user's and the
owners are these systems
are continually doing a cost-benefit
analysis if the cost is too high
compared to the benefit
they can be persuaded to change change
the reference
so I'm when
when TSA breaks someone's ten thousand
dollar insulin pump
that's a serious problem yes there's a
legitimate security interests
fun not when its comes at the cost is
I'm actually harming the citizens
so you can you can effect change
transparency we believe is always a good
thing disclosure
love where the sensors are and what
they're doing is is important
sometimes it can be embarrassing not
everybody who uses sensor systems
uses them for beneficial purposes but
transparency does help keep people
honest
and as researchers we advocate
conducting in sharing
admissible research admissible meaning
invisible in the legal context if
if research is done well he can be
introduced in some manners
this court case is that going to lead to
earlier
we can influence laws in policy makers
to the court system
if if we do our research well
and you can on take these issues to
congress maybe not you personally
but people organizations can be called
to testify in front of Congress
and other we give congress sometimes a
hard time for
for some laws are the things they do or
don't do here's an example
love are a congressional panel doing PSA
oversight
and when Cubs when your congressional
report it says the work hard two
committees
has documented a recurring pattern
mismanagement ways to the TSA
and listen unending string and video
clips photographs and news reports about
inappropriate clumsy and even all
logical surges in screenings by TSA
agents
innocent but some pretty damning
commentary about
in other branch of government so
sometimes congress does get
and we do have multiple branches of
government
you can work through the legislative
arena possibly through the judicial
arena
we've I think probably all heard about
the the reason brown case on
GPS on and even the white house has
taken notice with their
prime see below blind right it's just
been
been drawn up so
is anyone here a citizen I've seen em
obscene and the city but I can see but I
if there are but bid in number they were
advocating these more extreme measures
but for cock to big comprehensive inner
now something certainly people used over
the server
centuries the idea of non-violent civil
disobedience
some people started their own countries
I certainly hacktivism people start on
political parties
and in there's been and other ways
populism form folks that they weren't
they were displeased
so there are other merch three measures
of course we're not advocating them
for for less extreme Andrews you can do
things like support your primes the
champion's choice
on things like the the Electronic
Frontier Foundation which has many
speakers here
at this conference were you can join a
professional societies such as the the
IEEE the ACM
that also help communicate to the media
and advocate to you
to our legislature bodies on
but as always common sense should
prevail
along little bit of common sense can go
a long way towards
counteracting some unease measures but
also
arm common sense just in your in your
daily lives and
and common sense in how you go about
employing some these countermeasures
Greg
so some parting thoughts to to wrap this
up
this is a I was looking for picture an
expert urban and mood
I'm bud I'm best I could find was a good
picture above
a finance but the idea is when you're
dealing with governments you have to
expect lumbering bureaucracy
and and find ways either to hack the
system by finding the appropriate people
that will
help you or understand the process easy
you can use the most effective way
but don't be surprised if you run into
bureaucracy you're trying to import
sperms
and also is as much as we like to be
smart dogs
myself included about to use and
countermeasures
beware counter countermeasures and and
this is a picture of someone who was
be videotaping police as they shot up a
car in Miami
I'm and I don't know the details are you
know how that panned out I do know that
there's a video on youtube
above the individual at gunpoint where
the police officers expressing
displeasure
about being videotaped I'm it's very
compelling
and when he will release the slides if
you get a chance to see this
a highly recommended and don't be put
off by naysayers
I'm not those you America academia works
you submit a paper to a conference you
get reviews back from various people
and they give you great in a few the
great time of you getting
arm so reason I were writing a paper on
gonna subject very close to this
where I may have mentioned something
about I'm
had total Information Awareness being a
bad thing
and and I I i think i touched a nerve
one of the reviewers
and the be sleep before making baseless
assessments implications
and was one of the quotes and it sounds
more like a political manifesto so I may
have gone a little too far
but nonetheless we were put off by this
right we okay we took the feedback
I touched a nerve and got into an even
better conference
about a month later so you just can't be
put off by naysayers
you found us with privacy and security
be
yes ultimate writer thank you
ok okay
were one up so we should be good serb
but edge as you trying to do the things
you find that you can
take you can teach people about privacy
is important for privacy
terrible me a given rate and the others
less so far you can take people down the
rabbit hole
first wash so just beware don't be put
off by
naysayers his
I'm not the one seen thus far it's what
Slashdot a while back
but it's a beautiful thing it was a fire
talking about communities against
terrorism
potential indicators are terrorist
activities related to internet cafes
and the suspicious activities which I
precluded
proposes be great countermeasures and
things we should be doing just to
protect our own privacy
on included overly concerned about
privacy
always paying in cash using anonymizer
to shield IP address
using encryption and finally downloading
information
about electronics bud
so actually I was gonna hand out these
flyers today but I thought I'd be going
perhaps a little too far and ideas we
need to inform
folks there well often well-intentioned
overworked
and in a and I'm to be fair I pulled out
these because they're
but there are others in their their
arguably our a good thing
but we need to inform folks so that it
will get better
better results from leaders also
seek actionable changes don't you know
trying to her cancer overnight
i think im we know what can be done what
can you go to a decision maker with the
actually can have the power to do
it may be still compasses the in-state
with maybe less
issues regarding privacy in a few on the
left have you seen the
initial obscure a TSA scanners 0 the
Riviere invasive showing sensual any
good people
causing an uproar and incremental
positive change perhaps is the idea if
you have this more cartoonish person
that doesn't
that still compasses the objective
without naked pictures
under shopping store dinner government
database summer
and as you employ countermeasures beware
the risk
love uniqueness make yourself more
unique because you're employing the
countermeasure
in some way am the affected a really
project coping of the clicking what you
did is you visit with the browser
and based on information browser past
the server through mobile interactions
they were able to uniquely identified
millions and millions are browsers
in there's a really wonderful talk on
Def Con at Def Con that came out after
this
but just idea here's be where is your
employees countermeasures that you're
making yourself more unique and more
perhaps a target so in conclusion
I really believe is a look and see
everywhere once you're tuned into this
everywhere you look you'll see more and
more sensors in our lives will see more
and more
information flows aggregating this data
more and more use in a minimum
we'd should beware us and sensitive to
this
and we should Canon we should protect
ourselves but in particular the
community this community like
we have here in the audience today you
got special powers
special skills that are that are and
special insights
that allow you to you to understand
what's going on
and help inform and shape the debates on
going now through technology and policy
and we can deflect the trajectory of the
servile
future because gonna have to live with
otherwise
so for more information we'll have this
on slide that we share for the whole
body psych
we do this and I'm and some colleagues
have done some work in the space
including some on automated law
enforcement because if you think about
the surveillance future
a natural extension that is who will
help to enforce the laws better that way
so everyone we driving 55 on the
on the beltway around DC
so with that are there any questions
on my
him yes I won't let me let me ask that
there is a microphone here
that's the preferred method I'm
otherwise that we have to remember Peter
questions
Cup programs
and Christian up so often
opener the other the other bus line
do can yes go ahead please
do any thoughts on the proliferation by
magic cameras such as the makers of
connect
I'm primeSense I'm
mean know comes at two sons was getting
better right
and we're inviting them into our homes
and we're collecting data with them
and then it comes down to the controls
up to date as the d-league team
is a being shared in is it even if it's
not being shared freely with the company
that did not aware of
is it being is doesn't reside such that
a corner other
you could come in handy in access to it
words that system secure so
me I think in general it in us you know
that's just one of many sensors were
invited into our lives
and those are the questions you ask
where's the deal is being shared
immediately
is the system secure in could be does
reside
in my system such that saw a third party
together perhaps a remark or
so to the network nature this most
insane yeah I mean if its network
arian its even more of an issue right
thank you sure yes
I don't know I have a question on I'm
from Philadelphia and in Philly we have
a a
a volunteer I have a camera program
where
your private webcam has plenty on the
street let the police know on any
basically register you have you looked
into
legalities behind NAT or at the senior
examples event in the city's
so what you're saying is you got in
philadelphia you have people that
identify cameras and then make sure that
there's like surveillance cameras
watching the the public spaces
and those are the concerns from central
registry year like if you have a webcam
and you just went even on your problem
has to be playing outside didn't tell
the you'll
precinct hey i've a web camera is at
this address and then they
no debt so there's a crime then they can
basically go to you
%uh and as a private citizen you can
hand it over ABC and the examples that
was Billy just unique and everything
else
here I haven't heard that
and I mean what I mean into this is
brother the the discussion we have to
think about your private citizens with
censorship governments were sensors
having a central registry of their on
one hand is good I mean
I think generally transparencies good
but some
also makes me nervous for where can't
really figure
thanks very much sure thank you
in yeah
yesterday do during Stephen ROM bombs
presentation
we were shown customs lines have people
with ski masks on
we could see their eyes and maybe their
skin right below their eyes
and according to mister fromm bomb on
secure lemme facialed our recognition
only needs about five percent of
someone's face yet
in your slides you had something
different we're maybe the dead the face
was being disguised
so could you talk about are what
actually can disguise visual rock
avoid facial recognition and 129 your
I mean it depends don't have them keep
believe the software in the San surgery
can they get enough for the sample that
unique enough to to perform
identification that they wish
the the was drawn from for that's why I
was based on the dot com park but I
referenced
arm so I mean in in that aren't they
you're talking about and demonstrated
that in certain common algorithms
that that official %uh that make up
those hair designs
would prevent facial detection the first
place for prostrate
official recognition however absolutely
i mean
that wasn't Stevens talks in the
wonderful
are I could if your eyes are there
you know usually rest were just pens
down what technology up against re
what time the database doesn't have
behind so okay so we're really down to
two minutes
I i think we'll go ahead and and wrap up
at this time
and what these my will be on hallway
will be around so we will talk about
this and thank you for your time
beer tent way