talk a little bit about how you can
connect to your car
release that's the goal mom so what
what I really do little bit introduction
by myself is a
I read bytes from the can-bus and your
vehicle how many people have cameras in
their vehicle anybody know if they don't
want it
alright so I'm excited to be very it's
gonna be ready tactical talk
arm but it does have any questions
always you know
feel free go to my website on campus had
to calm
other go love my website really asserted
a couple years ago with the goal was to
just order introduce people to how to
get to their car how to get
data from their car or interact with a
car
is just a blog it's God's just has just
tax
you know just redid sids it's kinda
funny sometimes
so Iron Man and my twitter is I don't
weeks cuz I don't
and you can gather post in this
presentation yet but I will
I'll probably buy it tonight this will
be you the the URL for its campus
acecomm
hope worker I and I'm a talk a little
bit about
some a program that I so little bit
about my background
I've been work I work for the company
for about five years
that was called in traffic control
systems
they make tools to connect a vehicle at
work so that's where I got my sister
and I'm a talk a bit about their their
software I don't work for them anymore
work myself but I still really believe
in their software
they get excellent I am they have free
demo versions you can use to get started
thus it's really a high cost of entry to
get into a lot of stuff I'll be honest
with you
but I think there's ways to get around
that there's ways to find
the you can find a way to get in into it
on
just a starred hacking on your own car
so little introduction is a little
overview on talk about how to how to
connect to the vehicle
what's in the car will 2moro beatrice by
itself I am and looking at vs at the
communications more
more not this offer but the
communication what they look like some
other physical layers of the vehicle
arms is JT fifties are going back to
little bears what some people still have
the 250 in their car
Lynn on my my talked about land but that
we talk about can-bus
the different players again bus and the
devices that use to connect to it
but the physical air on the frame
I had a good guy had a demo but I'd I
didn't bring with me so I apologize
understand the data on the diagnostics
purses normal messages which is really
important once we get into it
um a little demo hope we can reverse
engineering we have time
I know I'm at a run through these things
pretty fast cuz I have a whole bunch of
them
I diagnostic protocols if I can touch on
it
obd2 a lot of people no love vehicle
network says obd2
but there's so much more that's really
just scratching the surface I'm a little
bit about Tom Summer Bird other
diagnostic protocols
arms some called I saw ninety I so 14
tooth 229 I supported
30 will be by Jim Landers GM and
diagnostics
on diagnostic messages commanders at
such-and-such an ASM Q&A at the end
so that sometime so I little bit history
how I started on RBN I sent out by
taking my
Compaq PC and then putting it into my
civic
courses wasn't it side on this wish
I heard and I you know I this is really
USA so this is my high school year in
high school a lot of us
out here been working on it but these
things are well so I put computer
in a car but the computer didn't talk
the car and that was really all tonight
my goal so I got into a website and a
brace from a with this website excellent
on website for you know trying to figure
out how to what tools to get mp3 car to
comment start a long time ago on their
goals to merge
computers and cars stuff like that and
that's how you can really get into
if you haven't been to their website
their forms they have a
section just I'm diagnostics and two
controllers and different rosanna
connectors excellent resources well
com little bit about this is really
where it all starts and love you seen
this
everybody wears 1996 or newer vehicle
has is in her car
this is the DLC obd2 connector able to:
slotted names that goes by
but every car in the meet me they're
sold in the United States and a lot of
European cars as well
have this connector are you can find it
underneath the dash just
the old darkened that you had an eighth
where your steering wheel is
and look for this car sometimes there's
a port where and this is
the only two connector and it's designed
primarily to be an interface for
scandals so when you're
take your car to get serviced through
every that the diagnostic
dar were you in a performance
diagnostics nowadays all these controls
on their those plugs thing in an hour
but it's so much more now they use this
also the engineers who are developing
the car
uses connectors well so a lot of the
diagnostic data is there but almost
never really there's a lot more
information besides diagnostic
so go to this go to this connector find
it and that's where you gonna start
on what you will notice is that not all
the Pens are populated so 16 pins on the
connector
just an effective but not all populated
so this actually gives you a lot of
information about what networks
are under car so if you see that pins
into was populated and you know that you
have
if you look at europe into is the G 1850
in
are you know you have to 1850 on there
so you know you need a tool which 1850
if you peace
see pins a 16 14 yr there
you know you have high speed can-bus see
you know you can get a campus tour
plug it in and size be care now there
are other pins with her
call discretionary pins like pin wind up
in 311 or something like that
is all discretionary pencil the audience
get whatever they wanna he spins
their GM which had been one they put
their single where can
101 so they can do whatever they want
with these discretionary pins they can
put
you know obtain another power output
they can put
no vehicle speed sensor like a pollster
something like that they can do whatever
they want
I'm you can also get the spin-out from
pinouts are you very good resource for
denounced
ever been around I so this is a really
this is the most important part arm but
given that you have you may have more
networks on your card then what's an
this connector this connectors for
diagnostics
and some manufactures decide that you
are certain networks don't need to be
put out here
and the reason is there's a couple
reasons one is they don't want
deal people like us to connect to the
network they wanna make a difficult
little more difficult
but mainly the reason is they
don't there's no tool that needs a
cactus or wire on route the wire
all the way to hear you know there's no
reason for so they just
they don't waste the time spent time
there move on so
you may have to go to other web sites to
try to find
you know body control module swear your
body control module was located in your
car and find the body networks cuz
typically there are two networks in your
car and
if you have a newer car and the body meh
the body controller has
almost all of them on there so try to
find a product or so little bit about
what's
what is in the car like on little bit
about
how the CAN bus and why the campus
really exists
so you may find that the air conditioner
module Missy position module on the
transmission and a controller all
connected via can-bus
see have all the systems connected and
they're all controllers so they have a
lot of bio
connected and actually actuating the
engine you know the timing on the engine
to transmission and when it ships
all these controller sitting here and
they're all connected to a single
network is typically the campus
in the reason why the use the canvas is
because it's a very well
but not very fast but relatively fast
compared to other technologies that are
out there
today they are moving away a little bit
French control systems
from can bust because they're coming up
with the faster newer systems
but campuses very much prevalent and in
cars today
and I do I think it's gonna be there for
a long time just because its nature now
talk love or about
why that is a little bit later
so I miss you a little bit so I'm I love
what can bust might look like so I'll
bring up vehicles by
here so this is the
vehicle spices offer that I use pretty
much done a daily basis
and just to give you an idea this its
you know a lot of first use proper use
like
Wireshark and the system similar concept
it shows the actual drawing information
on the
on the bus arm and I'll show you exited
in a
mrow a hex so
if we look at this we can see like this
is actually a reflash event that
occurred on my vehicle i reflash the
transmission controller in on this is
the fuel control module so we can see
even even when we're looking at this
data we can see that
that you know we have of rain this is
what a frame missus editor
identify your and then a bike today to
thats can-bus
data fire at a bite to data could be
less could be more
but that's it really short succinct
messages they go out so it's rather
I mean if we compare this to like
Ethernet ther anything like that these
messages are very simple very concise
and the idea is we're trying diff hair
have like very short messages that live
very quickly
but there's a lot of data an updated
contained inside a tease
on tell these messages so that it can
your do whatever it is you like okay the
temperature the engine is this
book done just to buy today to one by
today that's all you need
there now you now everybody on the
network has an information we can move
on to the next
next thing on this is a gallery flash
events are going to see a lot more data
here
but you see id very simple
very simple to use very easy to
understand not super complicated
but there's a lot of different formats
these messages as well
on if you look at the date it actually
can go by pretty cool
course year you know it's gonna happen a
hacer
I was gonna say yeah going by a little
bit making a run past but of course it's
gonna fail
on so let's see
its again can-bus communications
originally originally designed
you know more to decrease the wearing
size imagine that you wanted to share
the engine speed with other controllers
you know
you have this this a radio
and you know I like people have this
feature on their car you driving on the
road the radio source
divall you increases as you're driving
is bad maybe your vehicle speed or
something like that
and these are the types of features that
they stay at it in before the head
I your vehicle networks is really
cumbersome because they run a vehicle
speed-sensitive
every every can't every controller
radioed the
the engine that all these different
things had to know what the vehicle
speed was
well they took that concept obviously
put on a canvas and said hey we're gonna
distribute this data now across that now
we can use that information
and we can record bigsby now weather for
whatever reason we want people to be we
can have it now
but of course there's two ways to get
the day not talked a bit about that
those later so subtle about the physical
layers themselves there's the old
the old in the new solicitor 1850 I us
more
talk a little bit about canvas canvas
hack but JT fifties really where it all
began please the US
on there's two different versions as
variables with the balls with modulation
there's Lynn we have this is a newer
network I saw 9141
there's can talk about different flavors
newer
I am a newer type of fun serial data
network is them
most certainly oriented serial transfers
really use for
media as you can imagine Canada's ironic
name for bird
use for me complex rate which is a new
very much faster and I see faster it's
really only up till like
5 make per second but her just a lot
a lot faster for vehicle data there's
argues that in some more European
vehicles already
B&W on and then there's been which is
Toyota still uses their all archaic
network
I did 50 has to wear differential
signaling
I'm its on pins to Anna to in 10 if
you're
take a look at your body to connect urge
take a look at it say oh I have been so
intense
you're on a Ford vehicle of course
because the port is only one that uses
the
PWM to 250 it's also known as
SEP I M
it's really old and no longer in use you
won't find
you'll find 1850 PWM on any vehicles
then
I there's bbw which uses just as in
words
GM is the really the the main user
a crisis you use it as well it's just
something to so if you take a look at
you just have been to
there no in ten your honor GM or
Chrysler vehicle has a 250 so take a
look
can you confided arm
now we talked a bit about canvas I
defined by Bausch
so very large privately held company did
hadn't had the new original need
they made it they make educate roles
typically so because they make these
high-speed
they need this high-speed data that's
very reliable
so they decided that they were going to
come up with their own
system and fortunately did because it's
actually very very good
there are two types there's a two
versions such as a
2.08 we'll be and there are two types
the monikers are usually
2.0 days of of to refer to the lavender
and then there's 29 did
and this is really refers to the
arbitration ID on which is the
identifiers every frame
God back here this is the identify
rehear the center column
this'll be there 11 but I D so free book
but how many bits there were
rigid there's a lot bits am some the
some vehicles very rarely have 29 did
ID's larger ID's
you can do a little more ID's are as far
as like segmenting and
the messages that you send our
I am it's really good for real time
systems
some very low latency I you just you
send the message out
if you're talking about most vehicles
are we are running about five hundred
kilobits per second
really super fast leasing you know 500
and but you know these messages if you
think about on a bike frame
goes out if I would kill bits per second
it only takes about 280
microseconds for to be on the bus and
then it's gonna next one
has time so if you think about all the
information you back into two hundred
makes its really fast really quick
and then you have this you know all
these other controllers concert was
really close to real time
very useful there are there are three
different physical layers in this is
really I think probably the most
important thing for somebody who's new
trying to understand aggressor grasp the
concept canvas
is there's three different types are
single where can faltan can and do work
and
do work and is really the one everybody
knows when they're
when if you raise your hand earlier as
if you were cameras as you know about
your can probably is rooted
but there's actually two other flavors I
think they're just as much fun
I'm excess you get an air card to try to
hack anyone I like
figured out but the problem is there's
just no good hardware out there for the
other two
the do work and 80-90 percent involved
can tools that you use can bust
can device that you can buy offline on
minor whatever
am any the Arduino shields that you may
find they're all using this to work and
which is
I'll talk about all over later a little
remorse specifics
but I'm they're seeing where 10
really only a couple tools I can't think
Ive not use that
actually interface with their and arm
lost people Tarkan as well which is this
more European I you see Chrysler
VW Mercedes and some in the new york
years
are using this this network but this is
these two are really designed for body
networks are much lower
but they're very they're just as much
fun if not more salt october bouncing
work against
because everybody's religious center so
a develop a GM
on it's found you know really I N
your even some older hunters as well
sorry GM has in some the older honda's
have seen work and GM you if you have a
gf General Motors car take a look at
your already to connector
if you have something in pin 1 on a
connector you have seen where can
ice time to go find a tool that texting
work and as you so much
so much stuff Johnson work energy a
Honda has it as well
on I replaced JT 50
its limit faster it's arm its
really known as the body bus really you
only have body control functions on it
very low cost center but much lower rate
as you can see is 33 killed it
33.3 33 actually kilobits per second
on JT 50 I'm serious
as a respect GE 2411
has up to 60 meters in length typically
is your Bible
a signaling level so if you are using
like a logic analyzer
to look at the data arm you can use a
standard logic analyzer
was your but was too much to handle the
revival some problem
I'm does have a high voltage mode pretty
quick
so it any logic analyzer wouldn't win
her
on and very much the most fun networks
that you can act really because there's
just so much
information on there is so much control
or your car on
fault-tolerant I still suspect 11e 1190
dash 3 body at work again on is a
two-word network
laos for the loss one a least one other
number
one of the wires that's why they call it
a fault on a network so you can come on
where it still works
this is really good if you're trying to
like you know figure out how to hack are
you just need to find one wire insulator
to
you wanna packet from the outside I am
to moderates there they are am and its
practically never almost nearly never
found on the obd2 port so this is one of
those networks that if you really wanted
to connect to it
really gotta find it you gonna head
start again through wiring diagrams et
cetera
and you can look for an average you
won't find an image works ever on the
Fiat 500 which I found it there
very strange whisper on
do where can on my soul 11.08.09 a dish
to you also known as G true to me
for so if you want to look up the specs
because it was really expects are most
prevalent version like this message
before them can-bus
on this decade it technically will
support up to when the whole megabyte
per second
I'm I know 'em but you'll really find it
around 500 kilobits per seconds
and the reason for that is you know they
just don't need to set it a lot actually
just add another
can that work if they need more
bandwidth on the figures easier and
1 megabit the really have tested a
little bit on some vehicles and
an extra capacity in san n course
anytime you talking about speed you have
that
distance trade off so they want to make
the the can-bus
longer well they can make it as long the
faster they make it so we have a little
bit
it is a differential I'm so if you're
looking up like an oscilloscope
something like that you can switch it to
different shimon
on it does shield against him I just
like your
fun internet on fun in 1614
so that's where you look when you're
ready to connect a reminder for 1614 s
gonna be where high-speed canopies
there may also be another one on 311 so
look there as well
Tom Ford asserted use that it's been 11
so you can work
you can take in its the same physical
layer as
as you'll find in 614 so the same tool
that you use to collect it
you know 614 you can order 311 the work
they may be different bader its lead
player on a little better
it will that work arm really just
typically a powertrain
applications typically so that's where
you where you're going to find their
20 arms a little bit about that so
summer devices you could use
arm I have an old one but here it is my
old
a Arduino shield from escape paying
than the new ones a spark on 1x every
picture a little bit later
use legislator I M so she looks like but
they do have a Arduino shield for its
150 bucks
just supports again to work and so if
you're working with that you can work on
some of the cool ones
a.m. that and the nearby rebel you can
this is the the companies to work for in
her control systems
this is very expensive as you can see by
1200 two thousand dollars
extremely high you know for it for this
guy but the valley cans a little bit
more reasonable there are can USB
ease and stuff like that out there a
cheaper but you don't get the advantage
of the software
which you can get like a demo version as
well heard
even a free version detective retrievers
as well is really helpful
mom and your engineering tool really
that's really where they sell
their their their tools for the engineer
so
you gets the same two lawyers engineers
the guys I G and the guys aggressors
archer
the more costly and then of course
there's a company called down
that makes the makes a tools for scan
tools
whose here's the home known chipset them
sports all the obd2 protocols yes
disorder
you know make your own as the chip
itself here too you know cobble together
your own
devices buds AT commands I am
it will cost lead for high you know
high-volume implementations
but they're the good news is respond a
little clones out there as well to that
so it's a very defective standard for
creating
and talking to you know you can bust so
there's lots of her out there that's
based off the on protocol as well
so you can you know get this free
applications that can talk to your own
around based devices well back to have
one with me know
show it to anybody want to see
afterwards on
so little bit about the physical layer
itself cuz girl but she keeps
so we love we were physical layer on its
twisted pair some reason
am it does and this is probably if you
are making if your gonna go home you
wanna make your own campus network
assess
from sure everybody's gonna do after
this is gonna make the engine was a word
you will have to make sure that the most
important thing you can do is
put 120 ohm resistor between can I am no
I and by the end of your campus so to
make a long string
this is the the number one thing I hear
about from everybody talks talks measly
I get a cut in all up it's perfect
I've had my own campus on my desk and of
course
input resistors therein and nothing
worked because
you know the you made it two antennas
now they're just they're just too big
antennas know but there is a stunner so
you gotta put in there now you have a
bus
differential signal and can have up to
two 2 30 notes
just wires is to copper wires is run
yacht with them if you want to don't was
with you don't want to its up to you
iron remember but the %uh the length is
really
up the baud rate versus like the problem
so yet as everyone's radar
so don't make it too long but you know
if it's ten meters is going to be a
problem
for even the best scam a city can sell
it to you
so you know it's pretty simple I a
little bit about the data frame itself
actually gave a better
used here so that the middle one is
obviously an oscilloscope you
above can frame you notices
its it's not like just bite bite bite
know here's one by
is not a break because nobody saw
stacked next to each other it's actually
really well engineered to support all
the requirements for campus as we fast
reliable
and all those must you'll be able to
read
the data as well so you look here in I
think we have a starter frame and banner
arbitration field gotta control fielder
tells us the
did a link that such her on Buford
data bytes girls in their test CRC is
pretty good
robust here see 15 bids you know
considering the size of the day the
mondale you can put in it 15 bids as
significant an act field any under frame
%uh so it's its really simple
easy to understand that a lot now very
convoluted you know just have a few
things you learn once you learn them
you know you're in good shape stars
trying to figure out that so again I
told Germany's talk a little about their
to reno shield being guess parkrun on
again don't forget those resistors if
you can make your own
network the good news is if you connect
to a vehicle
there are there already there the right
way but it's a fully functional
on campus so that's better
IRS the nearby to show you a bit earlier
does have an obd2 cable is connected to
the obd2 port
arm diagnostics personal messages so
win when I talk to a lot of my
Mike my customers and I work with what
on a daily basis the the really it this
is the most
this is the thing that educate more
people on anything
is the difference between diagnostic
information
been get from the vehicle verses what's
called normal messages which is the
information it just flows from
controller to control
controller you have to do anything it's
just as good stream data
now with Diagnostics is a strict
protocol on
being in what's what's interesting about
it is its strict to
the particular OEM typically so GM will
have their diagnostic protocol price
/url bears
they're all really based upon the scene
thing that's like it's like a
thing about %uh Latin based you know
there's a scene this is one unifying
document that
that was created first then everybody to
spy on their own
I am diagnostic protocol base after that
they're all really somewhere once you
learn one to learn the other is very
very simple
but it's very strict I am L you know the
arbitration Eddie means this
the date first day to buy it means this
the second intimate means this
so that's very strict protocol and its
you know if you go to work
Geo 2000 chrysler to a 2012 Chrysler
that protocol so same hasn't changed and
you know you can
bingo you may be a couple years before
that hasn't changed it's always the same
on it's used by the schedules rate so
they have this
their Williams make their own each a Wii
and has our own scant
that's for that REM answer all your
specific skin to all the other ships
have one
I'm anybody wants to work on a car that
you know has the money
as well as the as well so because in
that they don't wanna change the
software that often so they keep very
strict protocols
very tight and they don't change things
much less they need to change like
obviously there's gotta be something
different on a hybrid vehicle that you
don't need to get on a regular
in on hybrid so you know they might add
things for that but
other than that everything is really
backwards compatible as best as they can
so once you learn one thing and one
vehicle probably the same like
on the other vehicles no much difference
so as a command in response
as well so that means is the scan tool
sends out a message
to the car and then the car response
back that simple
and every message that as diagnostics it
always works in that same flow
the skin to request information the car
response get to request a response
request/response so I am you don't we
we have we can ask for you know what's
this data value was a very what's a
stated value
what is it and then it responds and if
you know the scaling is there's a lot of
when as a returns back issues
access most of the talking engines beers
in like that you have to rescale it
if you are scaling a bet you can do
yourself from your own trials
you know I can mimic the scan tool
exactly what it's doing
on whereas we take that in contrast with
normal messages are
are no messages really are just these
messages that are just being sent
no engine speed is gonna be sent the
throttle position the temperature
maybe twerk requests things like that
for one controller its broadcast it out
to the other controllers but
the only reason why ever have to
broadcast it out because somebody else's
listing
so if you think about it like why would
the
engine arenas started not everything
about this way but while the engine need
to share information about its mass air
flow
right so because it does need to share
that information second senator
so the only way to get it through
diagrams the requests using a scan tool
or something like that
so even if so there's something that you
wanted like mass air flow or some sort
of parameter that really
only needs to be stuck inside and one
controller handles itself internally
nobody needs to be
have that information it's going to be
only accessible through diagnostic
message
messages if you're lucky most the time
it is but it's only gonna be there so
when you plug a tool in like this new
buyer this
this year either one of these devices
you put them in I'm your biggest remove
data that's gonna come across these are
normal messages
you're gonna get that information but
the only thing that's in there is going
to be
information that needs to be shared
monks controllers
with that also means is as the vehicles
change in as information that needs to
be shared changes
that information changes so it's not
going to be consistent throughout the
years
effect probably every two to three years
are going to find its can be completely
different
so normal messages also have things like
are but this is really where the fun is
a normal messages cuz that's really
where the controls are
so that's like your lawn lock in your
lock ours if you have a key fob persons
like their locker I'm like that's really
where you can find that
to get information is to know messages
you may be able to find it a diagnostic
information but is really rare
that some fun things like that
lock/unlock may be there
so you know understanding the
differences between diagnostics in
normal communications is really cheat if
you're gonna get out there and have
you know from here so reverse
engineering normal messages
again we just gotta look for a pattern
you know anybody who's worked with
reverse engineering knows it
1c establish a pattern like you had the
key fob
every time I do it a this message shows
up chances are that's a key but that
sherlach message read
are you open the door on the car he
every time I do that this bit flips
goes from 0 to 10 21 a it's a pattern so
to salvage a pattern
I'm attempt to change the vehicles
import and then use filtering
a lot of data there you know it's not
yours look at it
is always did a changing your not
opening the door looking for the door
message got ok for the door you don't
they open the door
it's not there try to filter it out use
whatever methods you can to filter out
all that extra data
a little bit about the diagnostic
protocols already to
are on board diagnostics a little too
I'm is really probably the most common
thing you go to Wikipedia you can look
up
the entire spell a pretty much the
entire spec
I'm especially the messages themselves
so I recommend their
on are many here
millions have their own labor
diagnostics
Islanders Ice a 42-30 also known as you
yes for universal diagnostic system
that's used in for your Ford started
really a doubt that's more european
effort to try to unify diagnostics
arm used used to be I saw a 14 to 29
that's where the old one you know i mix
those two up
UBS access to $42.9 cutest as
4230 doesn't make any sense her the
numbers are
river Tiber as a forty-two 29 is
exceeded
one that everybody's moving to from 4230
and then there's GM lawn on gym when is
made by
Jim order our general motors and
its specification you can download for
free an app for free but for like 50
bucks from my HS global
comets GNW 3110 so it's a really really
useful spec
if you want to learn about your give a
GM vehicle on
all these are all it is by 16 a property
too often referred to enhance
as enhanced diagnostics so when you're
you know where you're looking for like I
want enhanced
kids or something like that it's easier
in the enhanced level
it's really everything that outside
everybody to and just to give you idea
why this exists is really only two is
really only their
war I am you to understand how the
emissions
work on the vehicle its to do emissions
test matter
you know every state has our own at
every single other states have their own
emissions
requirements and if you go on a girl
like a local emissions
you know irony and we'll have a Michigan
so I don't worry about it
if you wanna go to get your missions
check to whatever they'll plug in their
own style scan tool
and that's ready to use for and that's
it so if it's if it's outside the realm
other missions
it's all on its own hands so it's not
required by nado yams
to enhance so some room wall you know
have
you know this summer their own
parameters there are some have
you know from Wrexham library why annex
it's up to them
what they're gonna support with enhanced
diagnostics we can't really be
I'll became really understand the
differences between the two so
enhanced diagnostics I'm you have to
really get to scan tool that offers
enhanced a massacre in fact one the ones
I use is called
auto ingenuity they make a very good I'm
relatively low-cost
scan tool that offers you a lot of good
enhanced
ability as well on on in
if you're going to learn anything about
diagnostic protocol
I recommend starting with I saw 15 765
I'm specifically I cities as excited as
to you or just going over to campus
acecomm and then are reading my blog
entry and I cities and 65 this is really
the décor all diagnostic protocol so
you gonna start
they are interpreting diagnostic
information yourself that's really where
should start
a little bit about 14 to 29 TDs word and
230 there are many overlapping functions
on
the combine to make a buck eighty
percent followed I'm asking you
so if you learn just wander to these
really very similar
documents if you learn just one or two
them
you really be ready to interpret any
scan tool data that get senator now by a
scan tool
on it allows for all your specific
functions and
crane responses and they're also use for
real reading TT seizing control albert's
every last drop some if you could you
make your car
goal over slower because
you wanted to send a command out as a a
turn off
you know by joining our own turn off a
you know so under 12 it's pretty fun
you know have done it
the so you can do it you know just
that's that's there was a fun things
have you wondered if you drive your
friend
your computer next to you and you wanted
to lock the doors
honk the horn our driving you do it
through diagnostics
I'm it's fun honk the horn is
7 a good idea a
now occasion be in the back seat
hi Tim GM General Motors diagnostic
protocol Jim W 3110
a started over there the old sabes
9-3 start with him Lancer so really from
2005 and newer GM
move to GM ran it's that it's really it
it's really ubiquitous term if you look
at a few research on is what people
don't really have a grasp on what GM
land really is just the specification
for TMW 110
so any car that follows a specification
is a GM land vehicle
I am love people refer to GM land as the
saying Where Can
on the done the vehicle that Sajan when
it's love more encompassing the man
I'm a large you for reading and writing
data just like connie other diagnostics
backs and soul and GM obviously but is
really similar to all the other darkness
protocols is a lot of overlap there's
ruined them change too much
I'm nobody to on
died in 1986 a new are also known as as
a DJ 1979
so if you're looking up specifications
CNN's to the nine
they've replacing it 79 with 15 765
but you'll see that this saudi and
Syrian is a good spec to realtor
attended promotes on redefined
a again my missions related own me
so of its not emissions related it's
really not going to be there
this is the reason for on mod-01
they often refer to their services or
functions as modes
I am some old one is how you can read
data by parameter ID your hid and this
is probably the
the term that a lot of people working
for these periods primarily use a system
single ID that defines you know engines
the
vehicles the arm bildt and maybe engine
coolant temperature sensor
again you can go to Wikipedia and you
can look up that every single one other
kids what they'd what they do and bla
bla how they are interpreted as there's
the response comes back on
and really represents really a very
small fraction of all the diagnostics
that exist on the vehicle network so
what's a good place to start there
really is this once you get your you
just get your feet wet with nobody to
because there's so many tools
you know for like two hundred dollars
you can go even cheaper you can collect
Autozone or something i buy a scan tool
you know and really simple spaghetti and
it'll send diagnostic information are
you going to put you in your car you can
plug it into your
you know your drina and see what it's
doing
on it'll send out a message in it so you
know how to respond to that message
which pier my with my blog et cetera you
ken
you could start to learn how to had a
formulate those responses
arm then you don't even need a car
anymore
you know a few you live in New York City
probably don't have a car so
you need a car can just you don't just
do on a bench
and Jonathan ok
dynastic comedians I am
canvas so was a turn a sister I'm
with her diagnostics you know we are at
the mercy the control software
this is one thing I people understand is
a while I just wanna know you know
as wanna make the trunk open and close
to
you know you don't have it do not have
no clothes strong but you wanted me to
close by sending data
you are at the mercy the software so if
your software can do it if it says no I
can't do it
well then you have to change software me
easy you know just modifier that's a
whole different class
a but but you know just if you wanted to
if you wanna send data to the car you
absolutely can't you can send it all say
thank you for the data no will not do
them
it will it does it all the time I try
and try and try
but that's kinda funny no check having
it say no and then making it say yes
eventually
a you know just trickling in I'm
and once you start learning any
combining those normal messages with the
diagnostic information if you can
combine those two
by could I i give you a great example
have a problem where I'm trying to you
make the fuel control Marshall turn on
us what's this
three if you look too much on trimming
the few good role model turned on and it
has no after
thirty-seconds no I won't turn a well
I figured out a way using a combination
or messages
and diagnostic messages to maybe see yes
it actually I don't have to change the
software
was looking into it I needed to do but
them
know there's a weighted to bypass some
others summers off for restrictions
another good example access to problems
two times where
20 amps trying to turn the children
Michael on another one
it said okay no I won't turn off your
charm I join I said well then reset
software
okay now gonna okay no problem so you're
using diagnostic messages to tell it to
reset maybe have to take a different
way around it city also has a lot of
different services
and maybe you're not using them for
their intended for that's the other
thing is really important
don't use necessarily have to use them
for their intended for
I you know but for your own will which
is kinda
numbers were arm
so I the commands that we use the so you
can do things like
you know locking or unlocking the doors
engine idle speed is really common mine
rumored only diagnostics so so
really I think about okay what with it
with the
the diagnostic technician need to do to
solve a problem on this vehicle
well then we could probably do it
ourselves so we can send their arguments
um is always a sequence in order to them
again to be in response sometimes as a
sequence of them
you know you have to set it up say okay
I want to start agnostics now
now I'll now that I've started a mass
text I wanna do this area
on and that's better
okay and the normal messages the third
again we're going back to
this is the kum these are the messages
between them between two controllers
on so is typically a little bit harder
to find his commands
as you can imagine there's no format you
can just tell us can to let a
send this command get a look for you
have to actually be a press the key fob
open the door open to trying ca
you know drive the car down the road if
you need to find
the XP or something like that these
things it is day to this is normally
going out there
and and with the prom with can-bus is
you know if your have a controller that
sending that message but you wanna send
it instead
well i controllers not going to stop
sending that message has cuz you want
senator
so you have to find a way I really
creative intuitive ways later
to make that message disappears best as
possible or to send
your message immediately after it so
that you can send your own version it so
these are things but
then of course there's always
consequences to you send in your own
version of it
obviously so you have to be aware that
if you're driving down the road
and you turn off you know later
traction control or something like that
you know that's gone it's gone for a
while in you have to have yet to learn
how to dance and I guess the commands
to cleared any information that you may
have cost like I still have that airbag
light on my car I gotta get better there
so you not have health I don't know
where day's work will find a
up so kid you know
so you have to be you know be aware that
with you know when you're working with
with these messages you still have all
these physical layer constraints they
have to deal with
you know the canvas messages going out
from the other controllers if you need
to send your virginity
it to find a way to shut up now you
could physically poll
module obviously that's not a good idea
in like cases specially integral
just won't drive but you could pull like
fuses or
there are other diagnostic commands to
make it work but you know it's you
really have to get in there and you know
put because these little bit figure out
how to other disable some real a normal
communications
buttons in cases some communications
then we have been one-time
their events you know their mock
commands or something like that
you can send your version unlocked
emitted the current box
greater works and lock in a car lock so
it's pretty fun
on uttered
tomb see security systems
so a lot of people were if they're gonna
get into the car they're gonna
wanna know a little bit more about the
security in them so
so the OEM's worse Martin is said hey
listen what if somebody else wanted to
like change the firmware
on this would that be a bad thing or
good things that's a bad thing so let's
sit
that secure or somebody else wanted
changes primers here that parameter
there
put a new key you know like a I got the
ski but I and then learn a new key to my
car
so I answered like we should probably
protect that
information a little better make a
little bit harder for them so they don't
work almost every actually
every every Windows this the they
secured using something on the 27 yr
service 27
on and how it works is your request a
seed
from the cars eighty gimme a seed
problem happen here
could be matures soon like
it is so bill hey gimme a seed 02 2701
that's it commute see dennis is OK user
seed
6701 1983 that's that 1983 sweet angels
we apply it to some algorithm and I know
you know it's a standard
hash algorithm of some sort and then
later down actually thats
one your tweezer ok
times okay there's a response so says
okay here's your
here's a key so i SAT 85cm forever
so your standard you know hey there's a
here's their haz response let's see on
now it is OK I agree we both carotid the
same value so
is now unlocked good news is its
unlocked now I A
don't have to know the algorithm some
other two on the algorithm
now it open I can do whatever one now
right
it open I can changes grammer's added
let me change before I can
reflash much pack that's what I'm doing
right now reynosa whole reflux and
letting another tool to do it but it
took it and actually unlock the
controller for me what's really
interesting is GM
they don't have a very dynamic a cdkey
so
they'd only ever sends the single seat
so I know now
on a marquis comer 85 85cm I'm not gonna
tell you which cars my number but
it's there and you can now unlock this
controller and
now looking I really do I mean I can
reflash
I can to lead the firmware for sure
release you know
it will you know you can it doesn't
break commercial issues you do voters
are really good you can still
communicate with their
but on you know it's really starting to
wake up in your engine controller
doesn't have sovereign
so it's possible it's possible you know
you never know
so you can unlock these controllers
either another controller can do that or
you can so I you know you can crack you
know if you crack it
he could be profitable I've heard of
people paying good money for that
so you know the security systems are
pretty basic you know you're my kid
and sometimes is a dual security system
I've definitely seen that before you
know you are a year on odometer to the
car
don't know why anyone do that to
increase your miles nigga you didn't get
my agenda
so I am so let's say you want to change
or dahmer a lot of them will have this
standard
security really simple and I have a
second layer security that
in order to rewrite the road honor
because that's a very valid
application rewriting the odometer
because if you're odometers replaced
you know you need to write the new value
to it so
they could be you know could be very
useful %um
so a and that exceed agree to secure a
so I
we have about 10 minutes so I have time
for Kenny there's they said there's
Mikes up there so if anyone has any
questions
internal ate up a little bit think peace
time to do it and we have space is going
ok
think when there's a company called ross
tack in a minute a
vag-com is the sovereignty USB down one
dollar
and I was like about a hundred dollars
getting internet
minute are they like an anomaly or do
other people have that kind of
fanaticism support for different makes
models
um I've actually never use the vag-com
thing but I
I think like I said I do ingenuity has a
tool but that is cheap
I am I don't know who has other
there's like ALM tools you can buy
things like that
a I don't really know yes I think there
is a
add her to bed but I I don't know but
that's just for this I tell you now
yeah every odd vector
bags through would ask you what does the
arbitration on the bus how does how does
he
all know arbitrary and I'm ready to talk
give yeah
okay so let's use my hands
okay we have to wear two controllers say
this is a typical everybody who works
were sealed their networks
understands what about this but the two
controllers the ball the bus is free any
both controllers could talk at the same
time
the posts are talking clearly occlusions
gonna happen
in the case the Internet it detects the
collision starts resets rate everybody
know that but
with even with can-bus only wearable
or normal stop so we'll both both nodes
will start sending
a starter frame ago
and then a server their application ID
Iranian to deter
and then but one of them will say it
will go higher with an arbitration
eighty and one below
well Loewen straight because it sets a
lower number
essentially that's how it works solo
wins and
as your strength vinyasa listed at the
same time
see you realize he the bus went low but
I didn't want to go
that angered that means I'm being
arbitrated out there is somebody else is
sending
a an arbitration frame at the same time
I was the whole time we've been
in sync with each other and how to sync
I'm listening now I go to receive your
ice I back off and then that the
transmitter
whose children have no idea that I was
everyone talking on the bus because as
far as he's concerned that wave
you look at the wave and the bus you
would never know so that
that it says are gamma I'm arbitrated
our
move on to the next one in the idea is
the ideal modular
the idea is really just a concept rate
the ID really means
alright this is the data thats is stored
here
in Amin this is ID 111 means
every time when 11 comes out I have this
data
in this frame in this former its rulers
for it doesn't really
necessarily mean something in a case
diagnostics $70,000 et cetera
but doesn't really mean anything in the
case enormous messages
themselves thanks better under
a mess around with the sleep words after
the forwarder
ideas IDSs home given archive can't
really as a duet Chinese one gated it
cheaper to build a monster had to get up
and fix a few things
I you know you pay for that's fine and
yes exactly
um no 0 the softer though that comes
with it seems to be
it's a it so bad I don't mind
it was any Israeli thing else to go on
with the
hasn't been I like but I'd only one I
don't represent the company in our by
Rep Ritter
recommend the auto engineering towards
really different and stuff like just
enhance bids just hence can't control
live very good we want to do something
that's not it like
only four technicians should be able you
the idea is to really only gone fortune
from happens like the next layer neither
I haven't been willing to put in my card
scares me just think it crashes does
once a month things i was looking at
this is it will be fine
he'll be fine Miller plug it in a lower
longer needed
chances are hurting a little nah that's
why I got the republican member
electronic warranty in the you know I'm
here talking about this on top dog
yeah I don't know a Hallowe'en I don't
like in their it wasn't an Akai Hana
that technicians a my house all major
no but like the others a lot lead
systems this thing was like you know
collision avoidance lot supposed okay
begin you're weird like is the stuff
documented anywhere look at those
midgets super close but which protocol
the using in can I communicate
closer to the IDS if you wanna
like simulate a car you need to learn 14
to 29
women or 14 to 30 band which car you
have company borden transition away from
fourteen to do
230 arm but if I if I look at the the
idea software
they will be speaking this internally
cracked in an intern on
it'll talk to it to the controller today
I don't know how much is handle on the
hardware itself versus the software
got two guys I don't know that the
interaction is is no what's output from
the
from controller in its thats him ok
assistance was
Switzerland on things wasn't yeah it's
like three points got a point but no one
knows yet
may I dunno yeah because I don't know
business a minute if no one knows I'll
take a look and yes it could look like
yeah that better
have have you messed around with
motorcycles at all II I used to work
with our little bits but they just were
starting in a CAN bus
at the time so I am both to Kody
and BMW use you some more stuff and get
actually
some guy did a thesis on his pieces for
school
on a reverse engineering the whole to
cart he thinks her you buy so I'm to
cutting board
yeah they're talking about that I never
really read above it all to cutting diet
diet it's really interesting if you can
do
all kinds of stuff like do that we do
the fuel maps n yes for sale that's a
huge business
you know redo a few metzger debut the
tuner knows about re doing but it's
really not
that's that's really high-level
application ovett I had two minutes ago
I'll thanks never to carry
yet again Jim know with the
transition towards a I'll EPS sir
electric power steering is that the only
put on
these buses the room no no no no no no
so you won't be a lunar but you'll be
able to happen unless obviously but done
though they were put on the buses but
the controllers are there so this offer
is there
right um what there are two private
canvases
as well between two controllers like a
lot of good ABS controllers and two
controllers
by their own private can network had to
tap into those
so they have some physical security
after augment
which is good actually that thats reply
gap is good however
the controllers they're still
controllers that are on the CAN bus so
if we find a way to modify software
clearly we can reflash it
over can-bus me we have a potential
arm for you notes during into knows
schoolchildren
Jeter I mean it's bad don't do that kids
so so don't know that didn't but
fortunately there's
little bit smart and they think will
will set it aside
and they won't do it and that's good on
but the software although they're
getting better risking software
God that's good ThinkCentre
you recommend any particular can stock
on how like as far as the can stacks for
diagnostics or can stacks for just
general like
I'd like I'm gonna make my own
controller wanna throw canseco grandma
to try and let your mind cancel
yeah it did some more many years ago
when Pan Bus
can stack Medina why I mean it had used
a handful love them
only you by proxy release you some
electric the guys
and so I can really recommend anybody
good they're just really expensive
that's all I know
they are yeah 102 here
than to everyone you can stick I don't
know how much time I have a make good
I don't I can see the signs so 70 K
leveling I think that when I can
and came back well