you are you're about to see Scott and
healthy exploitation and
disclosure I present to you Tiffany rad
take Newman and Mike Mary thank you very
much it's great to be back here at hope
this is my fourth hope am attending and
I think the third which I'm presenting
and
today we're doing a presentation
different than the others I've done i
jus security research and also attorney
what you're gonna see today is just a
technical
paper presentation were doing I have
from a group with independent security
researchers have done stuff a SCADA
and Mike worries her talk about what
he's done with skaters well with his
company man security
and I you'll be seeing the three of us
here and never gonna have Terry McCorkle
inbuilt Billy Rios
are talking with you via Skype am so
they don't they'll be up online they can
hear everything that we're saying we'll
be able
if you ask us questions at the end or
keep them they'll be able to hear those
the purpose of this panel to talk about
the research that we did last year we're
gonna give us
show two videos makes you do
international what he does
with mad we're gonna show a video that
was done by sixty minutes bob
featuring mining team's research never
gonna show a video that actually from
Derby Conn
and it's going to be a Terry McCorkle
Emily Rios and it's only a very short
introduction to this is the table work
that we've done with SCADA
so home let's start there
sixty minutes overtime
this is part of the actual Stuxnet
go that's correct this week on 60
minutes
steve Kroft reports on a mysterious
computer virus
known as Stuxnet which was used to
attack a nuclear facility
in Iran in fact it turned out to be the
most sophisticated cyber weapon ever
invented
no one knows for sure who did it but we
do know where you can find the code
on the Internet producer Graham masik
right now the Stuxnet code exist on some
hacking sites I was able
to actually get a copy it wasn't super
easy but it took me about a week
unlike most computer viruses and worms
Stuxnet doesn't attack other computers
in attacks
things there in the physical world
things like pipes and valves
electrical systems that key is in attack
something called a PLC
programmable logic controller there in
all sorts have
industrial devices they run conveyor
belts there on elevators there and
traffic lights
and if you can get control over one of
these you can do all sorts of mischief
there are many hackers now who are
trying to emulate per copy
Stuxnet basic attack so our
what if someone wrote a warmer a virus
and the perfect correctional facilities
that was our main question and
one hacker Tiffany rad just showed how
she could hack im
to the computer systems that control
prison doors and open all the doors
simultaneously close all the doors
simultaneously trick
the operators in the thinking the doors
were all out the closed when they were
really open
your own creativity is the only limit on
what you can do
as you can see our PLC that we we
purchase on eBay and everything is up
here on the table
if they're not hackers and kids in in
the in the basement and I'm their
pajamas just doing
miss malicious things as professionals
who work for companies
and look for vulnerabilities
specifically to
mitigate them to fix them miss chanute
mention Stuxnet earlier that Sean McGurk
was a really interesting guy he was
until recently
at the Department of Homeland Security
he was in charge protecting
the nation's critical infrastructure
from cyberattacks we know there's a guy
in Austin Dillon Beresford
Yeah Yeahs yes yes we've communicated
with on many occasions he shared a lot
of his research with us
I don't know where stocks I came from
and no I didn't have anything to do with
that site but
I just want to say one thing don't
underestimate the power the dark side
and there are a lot of people who are
out there were looking for ways to
attack us and we here looking for ways
to attack
our adversaries it's important how this
information out there
so that we can make thing safer for
everyone he's a
very I energetic an enthusiastic
individual that found
that if you with with actually no
industrial control experience initially
that if he started looking and probing
at these devices he could identify
vulnerabilities
he's just interested in this yes it was
an academic research project on his part
and he had the time in the capability to
actually
look at the devices in procurement
programme continuously
I'm not here to freak anybody out but I
will tell you one thing
and what he said as if he were able to
take over certain PLC's
for 24 hours he could cause explosions
my cuz pressure to build up inside a
pipe and cause an explosion it goes back
and blows up an entire plant
this act was was done by a 29 year old
kid with a tattoo on his neck
working from his living we want to take
it a step further we can get other PLC's
villains hack have these PLC's was so
extensive
that the Department Homeland Security
and Siemens the maker the PLC's asked
him
to hold back on his talk that he was
about to give about this and he
voluntarily
agreed to do so to get Siemens more of a
chance to patch these
these holes was there a moment that
really made you step back and think
I'll this could be bad in this story the
thing that scared me the most
was the fact that this can be cheaply
done relatively cheaply down
a small country a failed state terrorist
group
if it had a couple million dollars could
go out and hire people to recapped
and let me tell you what was incorrect
about this video
it's not gonna take a couple million
dollars or nation-state it took a
literally a a bunch of us in the
basement for twenty five hundred dollars
on our project doing it
I'm doing this had the security research
we did another correction
it was not just me on the team it was
unfortunate that so it was betrayed
Teague Newman I was also on this project
my father John Strokes whose physical
security i engineer designer he was also
working on this with us
as well as Dora SK to explore he was our
exploit writer who our
didn't want his name released so he's
Dora a so that's those are the
differences that we had from this video
but we want to give you an induction
what even I did
and now let me add turn this over to
Mike Michael talk to you about the work
that he did
yes I've got a very different experience
and wanted this
on Tiffany antique in the other guys are
all independent researchers and I demos
my research
on with under the guise other companies
and
and for corporations so I think from a
disclosure perspective in a lot of those
conversations I have
a very different perspective than
everybody else in the POW and
you'll hear that perspective as we go
through this that's a a bit about me
I'm I've been doing on research since
the 90's and have
made with skate & PLC's and not getting
might not be all season
and everything in between cell hopefully
I bring in a different perspective to
that
okay so
right now what we have is we have a
video for billion Terry
appear this is i just give you can intro
what they did
their goal was to find 100 bucks in 100
days
and so will play a few minutes at their
presentation they did
Derby Conn last year see get to just do
that
and we also have an article that I just
dropped for a second
on the guys actually had The Washington
Post public
publish an article about when the
particular vulnerabilities that they
found
and I'll let them tell you about that
moment but for now
play their video
Solis we set out to find some bugs and
we ask ourselves how we gonna do this
right make will we be able to just find
bugs in
were fresher
they found a lot a bug's basically
all summarize it out what they did is
billion Terry when out
and they they took a look at
specifically pretty well HM I software
and everything they got was demo
versions are open source
and their goal was to find a hundred
bucks in a hundred days and so they
start looking at all this through
a couple various buzzing techniques and
I'm
your you'll hear from them that the
actually found quite a bit more then
100 bucks all actually flip it over to
them right now
and us if you can hear them via Skype
at Terry's the the bug can you guys it's
not coming through
okay well they're doing that let me tell
you a little bit about one of the things
we wanted to discuss here today as when
you do this type the security research
where there's some implications really
critical infrastructure
how you handle this information how you
do this disclosure
in particular when it's a government
assets like we were talking about things
relating to nuclear power plants
data centers and correctional facilities
the reason that we chose correctional
facilities was that and
my father was one of the the writers for
sneakers and he does a lot of
and at assessments of ethical our
federal buildings
and he knew that PLC's were used for
different kinds of things everything
from climate control and data centers to
you
to jails how the doors open with the
PLC's so we've kinda put this together I
was doing some research on now
on Stuxnet at my university and I'm
professor Ashton professor the
University of Southern Maine computer
science department and we were talking
about
well this the Stuxnet exists will that
affect
correctional facilities will it affect
nuclear power plants in this was very
early
about April of last year then I found
out the do wonders for was doing similar
research we found out by reading an
article
and in the newspaper that DHS had asked
Dylan please don't present about your
research
I he was gonna present takedown con and
they asked him to hold off on that
presentation
until they were ready for him to release
information publicly
so that's one of the ways that Dylan had
a handle the disclosure I mean how do
you tell the public about your research
I'm I think we're OK nothing for ready
that's at but area and Billy talk about
their work and then we'll get back to
the a discussion about how to disclose
the step information
remember up her
in great so
is a term for all basically with you
like like the ghost and we set out fine
some bugs are
essentially we had a goal by 100 and
I think that day ordered over a thousand
58s
her ice yes sir and
the main reason we went to rise yes sir
or disclosure process would be
the you vendors is pretty or and the
you know you never know we're gonna
response you its so went through
ICS third but and or the disparate
benders unit at between running back and
to help validate
impacted or anything like that that they
were row
I'm and I will at Billys it worked there
about the Washington Post article that
got this order
everyone can you hear me this is very
perfect I'm yeah but the Washington Post
article word
it details a early that we found in the
tritium Niagara for more
and I'm it's it's pretty that barbara
Lee and I want to get into technical
details consider
this quarter panel but you know we're
kinda shocking that we reached out at
DHS
and I we reached out to the vendor they
basically didn't want to accept
responsibility for fixing the bug
right so I'm we try to present a case
just
let them know what the risks were and
how prevail in bisbee systems were on
basing and facing the Internet and I'm
and even after that you know seems like
a really didn't care concern in this
wasn't the first time we are encountered
such
such attitudes you know it's like they
have this culture within the industrial
control systems world were
are times I just say you know what
that's not my problem that the customer
problem
arm been configured properly or we
provide guidance that prevents
you know explications a business type 2
bugs and it kinda puts the
responsibility on to the customer
to secure a good is poor design so you
know after many many months
you know we decided enough is enough so
we decide to you know go public with
summers information and and and
that's where we see the Washington Post
article article drop so that kinda bar
perspective one
the whole disclosure process and
industrial control system
one interesting thing that I'd like to
point out
is it when you look across the board
here all
us you know dawn who couldn't be here
when it comes down to is
worthy original things that the vendors
were sane is it would take a
nation-state to do this
and I think that you know realistically
Iran of who is Dylan or denies group
but we probably spent the most money and
we're talking a few thousand dollars
so like a Terry and Billy you
Adam
yeah okay asset they had to spend
anything at all
now we actually did he disbanded the a
or the research it I think the biggest
thing was
are and everywhere to you
but you married I'd airplanes in a jobs
and we just found are nights you can't
you
yeah i i just want to echo workers are
arm and back
we made it a point not to take any
sponsorship
are not to take any work time to do this
research
at the end of the day we want people to
know that but anyone can do this
rhetoric
anyone can be this right are they don't
have any kind sponsorship whatsoever
dont have a kinda morning
I'm all they have to have as a
willingness and some time to look into
the star
and no prescrip line what we found the
scary thing though is if you actually
did put some money too
you know i mean weird tho we see the
resultant
stuff like this and I've worked on
projects that actually did have funding
and you know that with that were and in
some cases vendor sponsored in some
cases other people's months ago when you
actually put some money in some real
time in some
you know we're not just skirt around is
in our basement in the of hours
on it's it's scary it gets very real
fast
yeah I can imagine and the work that we
did
add me antique it was on we did this
after hours
a and I have to say to that we have with
some of us work for large companies
I'm including my Terry and believe this
is not at all other
the reflection of our work 'em employers
we did this on our own
so it something that didn't take up a
lot of time to do
and I what has this question actually
two billion Terry in Mt no answer how we
did to you maybe make you can talk about
it but
how was your experience Terry Billy with
them dealing with on the ICS group
which it stands for industrial control
systems
yeah I can speak to that and so I'm
really pushed all about bugs 30
industrial control system sir team
which is odd which is an art the DHS
writer art department alright security
and the reason we get back it's because
the control systems were over still very
old school
you know and the last thing we want to
do your wires as independent security
researchers we don't want to stand
and email to these vendors from our
gmail account
arm and get a response that basically
says hey thanks a lot better lawyer up
right like that's the last thing we
wanted
so are we did or decide to do just route
everything through dhis
now where we have this kinda like a
neutral third party that can do the
interfacing for vendors for us
error in fact when we first started we
said hey you know what
we're not talking directly to any
vendors if you want to talk to us
you need to talk to DHS first and your
chest wall
get the communications to us cerro now
and that gives us a little bit of a
proper
so we can figure out you know which
companies are security researcher
primary
and which ones are not right so and the
second piece to that airs
are following up on this stuff when you
have a thousand different blogs that
spread across hundreds of different
vendors
following up in keeping track at the
stop it's actually a large after
and we don't want to do that right last
thing we want to respect our weekends
and nights
managing spreadsheet about when you to
follow up with and whether or not
someone responder weather gonna issue a
patch
and so we kinda through all that work at
DHS insider who
you keep track of this stuff we're not
gonna keep track of this stuff right
American trucker or that we find
interesting weather across a thousand
barger 100 her vendors
it's just really difficult right we
don't we don't want to get into that
error i think is for that role girls
they did a really good job
you know arm I I do think they had her
hands tied
in in a couple instances nowhere like
the vendors not respond to every day no
one accepts responsibility for the buck
you know what you do then right and I'm
and I don't know or if we
entirely figured that out yet but are
you know that the initial
I think use for DHS nice yessir I think
I was mad
wonderfully you know they manage all the
tracking
they did all that but ping you know
every couple weeks whatever
they gave a status I'm and and I was
pretty good I really enjoy that
ida I'd like to point out one thing also
with the
regards to Terry in billy's work so you
may have heard that term
that's been freshly cleaned because this
for everday bugs
a billy Terry what are you guys when you
guys pick that you just described
that loss in area right there with
regards to those
Search Server Brevard a buddy actually
was originally Korean ever first time
we've heard it we're actually help
smokers cigars on about me
at the SP or conference in Miami and
there is is actually re wat min that
said
he said is preferably bugs are eaten so
when I had the opportunity talking to
somebody
I'm they're basically like I started
using that term because
really it tennis sums up what happens a
lot of vendors are never gonna fix these
issues
and those in our Customer Advisory their
literally like a year
wish your application program and you're
never going to have a patch where
in a I don't know I mean its
it's frustrating for for researcher
that's turned
you know get things fixed have them come
back to back in response and
basically put it on a customer saying
you know you're always going to have
this issue
we taken I handle this a little bit of a
different way we didn't go directly
through
ICS sir that reason being is up what
we're looking at work correctional
facilities so we reached out to therapy
or prisons didn't get much RAM
a response back at that time so we talk
to some contacts to you know both are in
the Washington DC area
and we wanted to tell the US government
about this this is one of these things
where
if we didn't a and we we felt like if it
came out in the press in like the wrong
light
and the government didn't know about it
we have some some problems
so a meeting was set up in Washington DC
and an agency and we said hey this is
what we've done
we're gonna go public with it is that
okay
it was really wanted these things were
all of us walked into the meeting
thinking okay if they're going in
if they're gonna tell us we're not ready
we knew that happen did Ellen
a about two months earlier we're going
away
but they actually said you know what go
ahead and talk about it
a which which give us a lot of like
relief that we could go to
Def Con and out not feel like we're
gonna get a cease and desist order
it was like a little bit the back of our
minds are alike are a date think that'll
be fine
on and wonder if they are you can talk
about Mike how the government can handle
some other work that you do actually
before
before that I taxes that same gel a
small the gas
because on the first time I reported one
is both the vendors 2004
and so I'm and can in some ways the old
guy the group but
on things like I see a certain stuff
like that them
we didn't have any in that so I i do
these vendors and and somebody I
it was in a military earlier mentioned
something about the attitude you get
from a lot of these vendors
and I know a bunch have quote-unquote
for everyday bugs that have existed
since 2004 2005
bed I think me in the vendor the only
ones that know about the net
right and and they have no intention
ever fixing it never well
and to the point that was made earlier
I'm bound by the NDA's irv
my company's at the time I can talk
about them
and the vendor never well so nobody's
gonna know that until somebody down
and and their attitudes back then I mean
people at least opening up into the sea
busy bee a the 60 minutes report this
their wall street journal her
Wall Street Journal coverage the
Washington Post governor is covering it
now
hmmm back then these guys their attitude
was just
hey you know with if you are putting
this thing on the internet unity it
and you while I might agree with that
doesn't stop customers from doing
wanted the interesting things that he
can I found after we did our research
is at conferences are usually shy say
after conferences were on our way out
someone to stop us and say hey I can't
tell you who I am on my work for
but I just wanna tell you I'm really
glad some independent security
researcher such as your group would you
don't have NDA's
you can go out and tell people about
this morning I'm can
customers consumers because he said I've
known about this for so many years just
like Mike saying I couldn't tell anyone
now we get into this interesting debate
about know is security through obscurity
working I believe that I love us
talking here on this this panel would
say it's not working
for ICS and in fact when you have
something such as very important
critical infrastructure up
and its I it's more important we believe
to get the word out these are
vulnerabilities
because from what we found a lease in a
correctional institute said we talk to
you
and to some government agencies here and
these and manage these
a lot of them sort of had an idea with
SCADA was didn't know was in their
facilities and in particular the people
that were working in a correctional
facilities when we get it got it or have
one of them
in the United States they were checking
email and Twitter from the control
computer for the PLC's
that's not a big no no yet those types
of things are
easy to fix in the sense that you tell
people back computer
there's a reason that this acceptable
use policy exists
follow it or you can have all the
prisoners xscape in and got a real big
problem
they they got that so telling them you
have these vulnerabilities
really was was rewarding for us as a
group for the research we did
that it looks like some changes are
being made you know it violates
can change the culture mean I at war
story for a second on
to give you guys an idea of how
ridiculous some other stuff is and
especially in the control systems are
opening
you guys kinda been a funny noise when
they talked about to
check email but at let me give you a
story from 2005
I was they had a vulnerability research
for scanning vendor and we did a lot of
stuff we would
drop the scanning tools into
environments in just
certified you know set it and forget it
and and start knocking stuff over
and I went to any major vendor and who
was dealing with
who had a control system in a major
hospital to control the budget
medical devices we were just destroying
these things like you know you turn on
the scanning tool
and all these medical devices with a
shot of with no idea what was going on
and sitting with the had architect this
and he said you don't connect to port
10000 do you
and I said yeah any he said
while you can't do that I and I say why
not
and he said that's the shutdown poor
I kid you not I i couldn't make this up
if you if you open a TCP connection to
port 10000 the entire system shutdown
that's the kinda stuff that these guys
were doing is like why would you ever do
that
and and so that bid that this kind
research comes out actually change the
culture a whole lot they can't be that
stupid anymore
that's not really stopping them but
that's not the point
they can try though big exactly
you know it's interesting to is morrow
to be United's research
you know after Stuxnet everyone pretty
well herded you know SCADA
ICS power plants water treatment
et cetera et cetera and wanna bar things
was want to see where else
was that people probably wouldn't expect
in wind up taking a look at prisons
on a note in the videos show uterine
billy's
Terry talks about a lot of things like
alright Budweiser plant
uses it cell I mean this stuff is
literally
everywhere it's in manufacturing
stranded here sharing City
yeah it's its its everywhere amusement
parks I mean
there was a lot of places you know that
I'll think people would have guessed
that it was initially
cell those common interesting thing to
see over the course the past year all
the different places they
the stars become public where actually
is located two
so think I think also arm
I wanna things that I'll a lot up normal
companies don't
consider themselves babbit system very
and
they were other things that I went out
as data center
you have HB act and yet building
management
in the water the and it and these storms
EMA systems made by the same manufacture
run though it that goes down think about
the ramifications without having your
datacenter
you know a while are hip if you have
porn
you can run your machine though exits
were things that I was trying to hit on
me is
that way people understand that this
isn't just
in a conveyor belt systems are some
automated system error its
new systems are running like building
management
and its it's pretty per
yeah absolutely in where the things if
you take a look at aryan please
presentation
Terry talks about that in there that was
a Terry the average
time to shut down once a date is a loser
schooling is like
three minutes 29 seconds does that sound
right yeah there's a report that I read
they had that in there
and their I i've actually been in a data
center where their
wrench set there are and you see people
running around frantically trying to
turn off machines before the overtly
its it's an interesting in Norwalk or
are and that was a related to my
researcher or where
are they getting shut it down but you
know her
a so yeah just is something did to keep
in mind it
Burgos for the people that are like I
don't have been
I I think most companies have real in
their in their environment
may just don't really like that last
summer
with all busted this type independent
security research
a.m. about ten to twelve months ago when
a lot of it became public for the first
time
I wanted to ask and I'll talk about how
our research may have changed some
things bed
Terry and Billy did you find that some
changes have been made
I'm as a result of your research like
you do with the vendors are the
government
I mean do you have any comments about
that
yeah I could take that there are some
changes actually
I'm there some policy changes from
various government agencies some other
summer which will actually made public I
think you're in the next couple weeks
which is awesome
I'm some other vendors I respect the
read operation some changes in attitude
I'm especially after you know they they
have their dirty laundry aired
in a public you know in the mean you're
somewhere or something like that
but I'm I think what are the things that
we're most proud are theirs
when you take a look at that number
researchers that are working at
industrial control systems
HM I am a stalker that's associated with
that it just dramatically increased over
last year
you know our I know what I was looking
at the ice yessir
your marquee monitor and a they have
recognition for various researchers
you know at the time it was like by
people now
I'm and now if you look at it it's like
burying people or forty people were some
nice pretty people
and so on and i'm happy to see that you
know I hope more people continue to
shine a light
underscore industry you know and get
them to where they need to be
are light years behind modern ha
particular your light years behind
modern
your security practices what you see in
other places
cerro are we still got a long ways to go
you know but I think we're making some
progress I just hope it's
it's fast enough one nurse P for a
second half
Dylan who unfortunately couldn't make it
on
I know I was speaking on the phone with
him on
my about two weeks ago now we're just
discussing some
exploit in general and I know that he'd
said a lot of the stuff he found last
year still hasn't been patched
and actually if you check his Twitter
feed I believe like two days ago he jus
are released the whole buncha Metasploit
modules for some other stuff that he did
last year
I think may be potentially to urge the
patches along
did yes gonna say some very good pen
testing tools to come out so if you're
in that industry during penetration
testing and doing
large facility tests are you a lot more
tools now to do it
so where from bird perspective that this
have some models and Metis when what not
to help us do our job to make things
safer
so when people do somebody's releases on
we enter able to turn that
their tools and make things up make
things better and we we found after our
research
is that a the correctional facilities
have actually
up some of their and some other funding
that they have
for information technology when the
things that he looked at as
with the networks is how things are
connected within the prison like you
should not be able to get from the
commissary like I'm computers they're
like for ordering food
into the PLC computers we we did see
that I'm so you
that shouldn't be connected %uh so
they're looking right now at how things
are set up with eighty
and they're doing more for convergence
to with physical security also with
electronic and computer security
that these you can't just say the
physical security is something else and
compare securities here
there together especially when you have
you know a close circuit TV that's on
the same type of system
so they're really looking at more
Bahamas to give you how these facilities
are set up so we're glad that
have a lot of states and clean when we
did our tour were able to get some more
funding
and we're not we're never suggesting rip
out the PLC is because we we know that
right now
the vendors I don't really have a lot of
fixes for them I came from what we've
heard they're working on it but we're
not quite there hit
but until then physical security might
be
and training might be the way to kinda
patch in some way
above the vulnerabilities we have now
let your people know the guards were
working in the control booth
what you know don't check your email on
their computer ever don't bring in USB
you know just just don't do it and then
also the physical security
we personally in some way it actually
should have been in that control center
either we were just security researchers
on it or
so I'm walking down where you have like
switches for trains and trams in like
new york city
knowing where these are and making sure
you're better physical security are
kinda patch summer that where
not Patchett bed kinda make the gaps
kinda come closer together
DNA testing thing just generically with
what we size
10 things we did see was some extremely
poor never segmentation and
you know obviously you can always throw
money at a problem to fix it the
sometimes you can start to do other
things that don't cost a lot like
you are restricting physical access to
use a particular machine the controls
your jail cell doors
is probably a lot cheaper then hiring
someone in
to you know to redesign the entire
network and segmented properly implied
by new routing gear
who knows you know but there's there are
his
the typical air defenses the answer and
you just implement
as much as you can when you have the
opportunity yet sometimes it's actually
it's
is the easy stuff it's the physical
security stuff that that's actually the
simplest I mean there's a story
two years ago now about a kid and I
don't remember the exact details on it
that you have to google it but
some kid i think is in Denmark who
crashed a light rail train
you get his turn crash the light rail
train in his
in his City on by reprogramming his VCR
remote
out and outside his house the light rail
train had and inner and infrared
interface
for signaling and I mean literally this
kids like oh look I completed my VCR
remote I can do stuff and eventually
figured out how to change the switch
with his VCR his TV remote
and crash the train it was bizarre but
to that point I mean I I was on a TRB
panel
about six months ago into to the point
about the research finally getting out
there
people are starting actually understand
that this is a problem you know when
kids are crashing trains with television
around like
0 or we can open all the doors in the
prisoner or what whatever like
ol may be really should check my email
and and I'm starting to get some
some play and we can actually start to
get some leverage in
and hopefully make some changes yeah
absolutely
and give me the commentary and daily
about that animal I will open it up to
questions
yeah I do have one last thing on it's
probably the one thing them
probably the most disappointing about
when it comes to like the border daily
disclosures
stuff that we did and you know we we did
push everything to DHS and the vendors
are notified but
does it always seem like the people that
really need to fix this kinda stuff
AK the implementer building that had to
stop in their buildings
in order to PLT the guys who actually
implement our have a PLT running
somewhere
they were like the last to know right so
on the government new
you know the vendors definitely near and
then it became this argument ass like
when and how you know that your like
tell the public
and it's like well honestly those guys
are probably the first to know
right because they're the ones that are
running the standard or interact
accepting all this pressure
I'm but it always seems like it's there
the last 10
you know and I hope like in the near
future we can solve that problem where
the people that actually really need to
know this stuff for personnel tractor
they can take the right steps to
protect themselves or protect whatever
is that they're they're running
you know
and the cable I will take some questions
and if you can hear terry Billy Wilder
keep them for you
actually will repeat them make sure
everyone does hear them some years ago I
didn't says MANOVA badge access control
system
and I discovered that it was listening
on 22 ports
its its root password was over 00 T
documented in the manual
the firm advised that the dialup modem
that was attached to the computer always
be on for better maintainability of the
system
in this was in use in use at all the
British airports
at prisons are consulates at the library
of congress
at the US House of Representatives
Senate I'm
and I started calling inspector
general's inspectors general various
agencies in
got them to recognize the problem but
the vendor of course was in
great denial was used that prison's and
of course you could open all the prison
doors
using this thing elevate your badge you
could
create events that we're not locked
because the misplaced right 0
the system was open source not not for
any
political technical reason but just
because they wanted to if def
in features since the system so there
was you know if death
embassy if death Heathrow if Jeff names
our customers and their code
so we can actually find bugs in a in the
system
including misplaced right curly brackets
which prevented certain events from
being logged
I'm you can create still badges it was
really just terrible
ended up in the New York Times but the
vendor was in complete denial
I that was a great story but I don't
think use our surprise any the faces
appear
yeah I said I realize that museum
it is amusing and that is a a tough
thing is when your security researcher
for any view other her doing his work
how do you do who you tell under some
security researchers that use ICS sir
then there's some security researchers
in this that independent security
researchers we've met him said they've
said well
wanna were kinda made them annoyed
summer with ICS certain is that there
was something that was
a bug but they called it a future and it
was
something that they're like they're not
gonna release that is a warning no I
forgot to mention the back door that was
in every implementation
if you typed the right magic function at
the date
into the any other attach terminals it
would
Openreach shell for you and this was
undocumented but we found in the source
code
who is amazing I S
out great great show as lovely I am
were all akers we appreciate all the
stuff you give us for information but
when you present to
organizations and groups do they ever
try to kinda
who says a pure terror sort their
TribLocal issue like that
and has happened tease security
researchers yes
and especially when you're when that
when the assets are
over the I wanna was a target because
that would make a see my tears but
when the asset is a you know transit in
New Yorker DC
or when we were talking about some of
the country's greatest liabilities which
are
in a maximum-security prisons it's kinda
hard I'm
it was challenging the day took it took
some a a lot of preparation
and we wanted to tell them because
they're really the only ones who can
somewhat
fix there you know get aware that this
problem
and government try to fix this and get
the vendors to patch
I think that we were lucky in our
experience
you know his we we approach them
directly you know we said we want to
talk about this boldly
by you guys make the call and they were
pretty
you know pretty good with does nobody
tried to pass out bagay knows my thank
you for telling us we're glad
I would appreciate if you didn't release
it publicly I fine
but day we had a pleasant experience
I yeah I think that's actually that's
part of that is just the timing on what
you guys have done
you know like I said in 2004 2005 2006
people weren't nearly as
aware up the kinda problems you guys
have been bringing up and and
they haven't heard have you know don't
researching your research and things
like that
you guys are have the benefit have
everybody's kinda coming out the same
time
you know several years ago absolutely it
was like wire why are you doing this
while looking at this what's your
problem would you trying to
trouble-maker
yeah no know your stuff broken
make fix it but but yeah I think I think
that that
there are industry groups like I see a
certain stuff like that makes it easier
to have those conversations in the same
way
do you think you've got a friend Adrian
you as a irrational and organizations
that really does
a.m. don't go pink your rights yessir
agree we had organizations though
you gotta realize this of course made
around the world graders not just
american companies unit I means im
interview
company international but they're big
enough that they can have a process
began over
we actually had some firms over in my
Israel
they were nice yessir want to talk to
them
new date they basically gave them who
are you
and we're gonna do all background check
to make sure your legit
or even talk who alright because
their alter paranoid about no these
hackers bringing
about their bright Anna those are the
sort of things that we didn't want to
have to deal with
but you have to realize that this
software is
it crosses a lot of borders air there
when you talk about being
but and summer stopper any backers out
there like will get them with partners
like that
okay thank you thank you thanks
hey there it and so with what are the
things that
I was thinking why you giving the speech
is just the general age
love this equipment is is not really
taking into consideration in the
information that year
betraying and simply because you know
a lot of these factory PLC's were
designed
before you know Ethernet interfaces were
even on the equipment
so you've not got a you know
second-generation engineers
attaching a Ethan and interfaces to
analog interface is right
so Unisa two things to consider
you know while we're busy you're
slamming Siemens in these guys for not
considering the stuff
is that yet they they've been designed
the the device
initially to be on internet on anything
face
it's not just being connected to one via
some third party in some cases
and you know and secondly you know a lot
of the times these devices
in a we you wouldn't find any other
manufacturer the marks of or Apple
support devices that are
gardeners on the years old you know yeah
I know that
that absolutely is is true in certain
cases
I am and that was one of the things that
we found out
as well so some home like cocaine
in ICS we found that very often
availability was a greatest priority and
so sometimes when
the patches cycle could be a place six
years so
you are looking you know I handled by
snatt is correct
but it doesn't make it any less of a
problem is this so widely deployed in so
that there's gotta be stuff
in between you know the implementation
I'll
the next gen and what we have now to
make it
better and safer as yeah I think to your
point
yarn about the the physical segmentation
those networks is probably far more
important than
most is a topics now that was one of the
things did
we really like the whole way long we're
going through like okay this is the
immune idea by there's no way it's gonna
work out
we like it's going to be a rig after its
gonna be this game that we got in there
in
rightly sign some Ailsa thought
when he useful in a while
betraying your statistics was the
I guess that the character other
statistics because
you could take any level of code and
you know well thousands of potential
security problems
but you know I you know when you're
reporting statistics like you know
100000 bugs are you talking about on
a like external vendor firmware buns or
you talking about
bugs that are exposed due to the
implementation of
love the way that the device is being
used
is that those as programming languages
are you know that its
it's up to every engineer and and and
the engineering this factory
is far more concerned about whether the
cause gonna fall off the conveyor belt
then
with some connection getting to the bus
yeah I heard the question I actually
want to talk about the first point that
you brought up
where you say you know some other stuff
was designed in it in an age before
they realize they were spying to be
connected to the Internet basing the
entire world right like a
we understand that no but at the same
time
you can't let the vendors of the right
so if you give them the opportunity to
say hey you know what
I'm we never designed to do that I'm
sorry like they'll
builders take that standing just report
right armor and
you can't let them do that right the
world has changed world to change around
their software
and your hardware and you they have to
adapt right
and if you don't force them to add up a
wall or just keep doing the same things
that they're doing
and we've seen that right like something
your software that surlis
by a lot other better i'm talking like
within the last couple years
it shares the same design principle the
same code laws
the same error that they have near the
same block that they've had like twenty
years ago
right and that's not acceptable you know
they have to adapt to the world
I'm they can just pretend like they're
sheltered and like no one ever gonna
figure this stuff out as a its you know
obscure
right so I'm it separate you a street i
think im retarded understand that
some other stuff probably isn't as
robust at Purcell person
makes it out to be right and at the same
time the vendors
need to get with the real world right
her room when they look outside and see
everything is connected to the Internet
and
people were connected directly to the
internet and such and understand that
their environment
and they need to change their path
accordingly you know and I hope that
that's being done
so but as for the bug that went down
farmers about that we reported they're
not configuration issues
right like we don't want to bring the
customer years there merge the back that
we reported their strengths of her body
right there bud where their vendor needs
to go back
and Murray change a couple and the code
to fix the issue
and and thats I would say probably like
95 99 percent about that were reported
sir so much yeah and I think to your
other point
the all the software we looked at was
the software
you most here with no base on
we weren't looking at physical hardware
no physical hardware as
the same to order issued bill and
research shows that what they're like
other guys they're doing
great research in that area are related
a.m. the issues across the board
so software and hardware or
firmware know it's a so the I was under
the impression that the the level but
you're talking about were
all exposed via the PLC hardware itself
no is are all a Hemi
or other pieces software
are support system I'll yes Oteri in
Billy
the primarily to teach my systems I'll
we looked at the PLC in the PLC software
directly
there the large for them this from the
gym by I think my everything about be
systems is that they are so complex
and and I think one of the things we
need to keep you know just as an aside
keep the pressure on the vendors for is
that wouldn't be cool factor
you know you design this thing in 1978
to do one function and then somebody
comes along
this year thanks only because we put it
on the internet we did
connected to the Internet I acted to
hear that spectrum and was
he was manager from his iPad right yeah
but was denied that happen is that
yeah NF if we can keep the pressure on
the vendors to not fall prey to that I
think that would be a good thing for all
of us
I i just think we should published the
statistics in a more
accurate yes I'll be addressed the right
areas love the problem
but thank you as Stephanie with paying
attention to it although
at I think we got two minutes left so
one more question
against ties in a bid to his arm how
much
successive you had in getting the
vendors to think security first
I did a master's thesis in SCADA back in
and there is just basically a very brief
overview of the
security picture in the environment and
I we hearing about things like
the controlling to no remote power
plants I would be over an unencrypted
radio link not not even like open wifi
just long distance radio with known
Chris Shino
authentication know anything at all show
you don't even need to find
just needed turn on the radio skin
yeah that's still the case in other
places yeah
just fine glaring designs nobody's even
thought about security and
yeah that's why we would we did as wave
with our group we brought awareness to
directly to the government agencies that
we thought would be the ones
would be most interested in trying to
make some changes so
we political more question real quick if
you if you have them freely
you know I'd actually like to add
something to that like how do you bring
you know someone is awareness I think
you know maybe it will
above the first after to let these
vendors know that security is not magic
right like there's definitely some
science behind it and fixing bugs is
literally a matter
adding a couple and the Karrimor cases
right it
sometimes it's not very complicated to
pick certain issues arm design issues
you have course
it requires a lot more but promoters
that that we encounter
it doesn't take very much for them to
pick you
breedlove we're gonna more question or a
a term be quick
am I work in a similar industry none
exactly the same
but a it seems like you're very
antagonistic towards the people you've
been dealing with
not everybody but you mean sometimes
those two those relationships may
develop that way
and a.m.
it's a like fixing two lines code is
really easy
but that's not the expensive part its
testing
and delivering an you know they don't
work for you they work for their
customers
so I mean you mentioned in your talk it
seems like the the
culture at the people who are
implementing the systems using them
might be a very important kinda vector
to get in
because you know the they're not gonna
spend money just because someone calls
months is your problem
so I just wanted to kinda bring that
aspect and
in there yeah I think you're absolutely
right
in the thats were things that it is all
your help we're very
return cuz customers don't know where
you know
at their disposal they don't know task
they are we born herbal right
and so I think the culture aspect does
need to change but I think
that's where the awareness helped very
it's difficult to change it
people don't even no because the
company's not gonna tell them
okay thank you thank you very much her
brother time baghdad
thanks very much how