Nations Security and of course as anyone
recognize the internet is for porn
right okay so Avenue Q right
so that they are that's a Broadway play
just a few blocks up from here with the
offeree Muppets and I'll light-hearted
Dom I jack to a release arm but of
course I'd the Internet
brings up a lot of other notions a lot
of odd notions of censorship a lot of
our
emotions in some people and on
I and i think that's part of why the
speaker selection
group was very happy to have this be one
the topic this tops is covered in horse
the
on our relevance as you see in the long
Ten title
is I is very obvious to Tucson topics
you care about here
so on like to extend a
very special reading to any our
representatives members or hangers-on at
toda la firma Baker & McKenzie I'd also
like to
recognize and I welcome are many friends
from the Electronic Frontier Foundation
to the stock country and out what we
have is its
extra special treat is on a
not only Chris kaback a who is our
speaker are we also have I J right
home who is our ghost speaker and so
with
now without further ado I introduce you
to the internet is for porn
hello my name is Chris cue back
an armchair com this presentation how
high heels and fishnet have driven
innovation in information security
a is the focus 7 is
basically the slippery slope censorship
starting out with pornography
and we just might have a good time
please feel free to ask questions and we
would just like to give you some
are favorite views a the internet is for
porn
hopefully you all at sea mas
bring our Dr more poor
only for or no
or week or go out I other people in the
world
for all of my money
and turn on more people and Fernandes
more people
driving thinking on that was born
more important totaled
higher me %uh
I have to read this this presentation is
solely the opinion up the presenters and
not necessarily shared by any claims
current or subsequent employers up the
presenters
and who the hell and high
because I'm not on the program one JK 47
currently working as a professional
services engineer
for many the storage in databases that
you might be using today
and I focus on databases virtualization
structure actually started when I was a
teenager making web sites for porn
companies and multi-level marketing
companies
I did that because I couldn't be sued
were arrested
like other people were so I also worked
at
Air Force Base man 21st Carling work all
that fun stuff
and in my time at work I'll I made one
of the largest
porn databases with some special search
in
features for finding 1i 1n I can't hide
anything cell skin color noble science
an this was when like aid I first came
out you could actually do streaming
video and audio stream from the database
I was in and then alright so
questions and feedback we have a mic
setup here if you have any questions
please come up and ask us
will also set aside time at the very end
four questions but
Stoppers at the up something pressing or
if you have a question about material
craske
case a few questions for the audience a
show of hands
her two friends using the internet to
search for
over I excellent are
how many have never actually had to
investigate pornography incident I am
has anyone ever think that they were
ever exposed to illegal pornography
K why on earth as legal pornography
running a really depends on your country
but not everywhere can get
porn likely there's Wikipedia who knew
it was so sexy right
a little shape send a little a
at some other top searches on Wikipedia
yes so what is legal pornography
in the united states are some very
specific definitions
this country is rather unusual in the
fact that computer-generated
a child pornography is also illegal
like this said the the definition of
Legal Porn
changes from jurisdiction to
jurisdiction
a erotic materials are not considered
obscene
there is a definition above scene and
there's a definition
erotica and pornography their different
a so
and different countries and different
states
there are differences and the definition
of actually what they consider obscene
as well
handout yes exactly
a but the actual definition a what is
obscene was from 1968 Supreme Court
ruling
Jacob else purses Ohio at the Supreme
Court Justice said
I know it when I see it sir and this
is not it he was referring to a movie
operator who was fined twenty five
hundred dollars for showing basically
what week
we consider a soft porn a maybe soft
porn
a movie that involved some ladies and so
forth but to
it went all the way up to the Supreme
Court and now we have an actual
definition
what is obscene and what is not now
pornography is actually brought us a lot
great advance
advancements both in internet and
hardware
now first porn online services were in
the eighties
like most about us we had a really slow
systems
I know if someone in Diego Garcia who
looked at it over 75 by
teletype line have patience yes
so Usenet a gray an event innovation for
porn
and that's all I gotta say about that I
know the web usage
ru at an amazing amount especially with
in college years
because a pornography and
dot com burn what would have been
without pornography
so more the technical advancements
were in the cortex used the biggest was
probably actually jeep ad push
video because it allowed video streaming
with
our plugins cuz plugin sock
who he remembers RealPlayer
yeah yeah I think that up one of my
favorites when I was a teenager is
called
see you see me oh yeah yeah
cell I mean from that we got the more
advanced kodak's
many are used today like H 323 for way
in those services also MP force came out
of that
because and give its because im a all of
the different licensing restrictions on
the kodak's
we also got major advances
in online payment systems up
world pay in CC bill before pornography
in the push for
identification people's agers
they were just doing in abstract modem
transfers things like that but because
im
porn web sites needed a reliable payment
system
so there's a clear trend and OneWorld
pain CC bill
first came out released their online
processing systems
and pornography burn and of course pay
pal
it how such and also got
Paris Hilton yet nevermind for
and Chocolate Rain and who the fuck is
that guy
railing I have no idea alright
we also got a lot of hardware advance
without it global load balancers
you don't want your viewers on your porn
going to slow website across the country
Cisco came out with some the bass global
load balancers
nowadays we have many other companies in
that space and sis goes back in now
we also got wind accelerators
river bed now 5 they'd prolly be nowhere
without pornography
I mean they built from the most
sophisticated
TCP stacks decides what comes out a BSD
at any around we also got
SSL accelerators before sign in a couple
other companies
started pushing in thousand dollars to
sell accelerators
I mean you take an entire server farm to
host
one small porn website i no one in my
sights in
ninety 6 to a thousand servers
and then we dropped into signs with
ourselves our readers
to replace them so that was an
incredible
advancement it was on-chip
encryption and decryption for the masses
I mean back when I did the the
consulting to the government were you
seen
million dollar walking crafters kg
enforce
game 7's those were just not possible
for pornography and it made it
popular we also got advances in digital
cams
anywhere would your day DSLR be today
if the money wasn't there from webcam
sales before like attack
before those companies came out these
are things that we
touch every day so to speak and week
yeah we've we wouldn't know
that they were advances because a
pornography we don't think art
why did most people via webcam in the
nineties
seriously yeah and
low-cost high quality recording mediums
and there's been some security-related
incidents that have brought
a is security innovation
into play for example the Melissa virus
crashed email servers around the world
when it occurred
so did the in a corner cover virus when
it came about again
from some of these a security-related
incidents
we have gotten email filtration
web filtration at when Twitter was hit
with
porn spam they switched over to TLS
instead up area instead over
SSL we now have in addition to that
a browsers
in private mode or otherwise call porn
mo
had another poem exactly
a digital ID's to make sure that age
verification could occur
private bpm using proxies to make sure
that nobody could see all the
interesting little bit supporting that
we're looking at
who uses tore I hear
there you go and nowadays
funny in a and it is safer to Sir a porn
site than it is to read a plot to visit
a company site or to visit
a religious site in semantic study is
religious web sites are three times more
likely to contain viruses from porn
sites
Braden
now the economics internet porn
so there's a lot of revenue that has
been generated from pornography you're
talking about
at the various filtration you're talking
about the monitoring employees you're
talking about
on the back and litigation and legal
fees
and what other ways can anyone think Oh
anymore
a webcam site housewives congressman
money
it's a homegrown business nowadays
anything else
they don't think I've welcome on
payment clearing house payment clearing
houses in
Houston
yeah site sites for amateur porn
yeah blame me there's more sites like
that
and I'll tell you afterwards a
fared better her the hell no
yes ballet x hamster
chatroulette video yeah
or penis roulette so
P brings in a lot of money a
also taxable as well so it's a
revenue generation for many governments
around the world
I it's quite amazing that although the
United States a seems to have a very
interesting viewing pornography
a it brings in more money
a in this country then all up the
organized a sports franchises put
together
I'll a they say in new porn movie is
created on average every 39 minutes as
comes from
ABN media network in order to get on
their list you actually have to be a
larger
pornographer so this is an actual even
count any homegrown porn
so I would venture to say
I would be a little bit more often than
once every thirty nine minutes
that is the density
a pornography subscriptions in the
United States
and three-point play now curiously
enough the darker the color
a yeah p.m. well you know I did
it what else are you gonna do there
exactly it's safer to surf porn then
religious web sites are certain to make
the
stretch wrap it's all about security
my head so
the 4.9 billion is
just white ABN has reported and he
didn't know if the announcement a porn
award show every
Jan every January in Vegas go to it some
good all the other web sites web cam
sites personal sites
I'm those are not included in this
number we're probably looking at
four-year $50 billion in annual revenue
just on
and with all the side revenue the
hardware to software
I N it is incredible match in the
storage needed
I just one one distributor hundreds
terabytes of storage
noted
so this is what the picture looks about
that the legality of pornography
and so we can see the United States
opposed to be allowed not censored
I am now interesting enough in India
this the the stats are actually about
India although is partially legal in
India they've made some very restrictive
laws very recently
some laws and I don't think any of us
would want to follow such as any time
you want to use a cyber cafe or even
Starbucks wifi they have to I D you
in photograph that identification all
computer screens have to be in plain
sight so if you're trying to do private
banking or anything else not that I
would use a cyber cafe today
to do in a banking but all the screens
have to be in plain sight and monitored
by the staff
so nothing is private a a copy of the ID
is kept
on record on file at the local cyber
cafe
the browsing histories are stored for at
least
one-year hit up
and every month also per capita is have
to send
all other data to the Indian government
these are things that don't sound too
comfortable to me
another example
feet high a blacklist the Thai
government
a decided to institute a countrywide
blacklist against a child pornography
web sites
as a protective measure so anything that
might be considered erotic art scene
involving minors i angry with that okay
fair enough accept it turns out that
them
over 1200 web sites are actually block
because the critical up the royal family
%uh I don't think that that has much to
do with pornography
I don't know Bosak
yeah
if you've seen the royal family down yep
a and one of the biggest problems is of
course is blacklist is
completely non-transparent there's no
way to see what's on a blacklist appear
on the black was how to fight against
the black list to get your name of
in recently a
there was a US citizen that was
sentenced to two and a half years in
prison
a his crime were was tweeting
a translation oven unauthorized
biography of the king of thailand
he was just pardon this week discussing
Australia
now Australia is a very interesting
situation
they have a blacklist a run by the ACM
paying at the ACMA is not elected
and that is without judicial review they
decided a couple years ago
that they believe that women
adult women with small breasts a
encouraged
child pornography exactly
exactly they also considered female
ejaculation as a fetish
I didn't hear them blocking pornography
a
men with that less than average members
or
merely Jackie elation or well I'm tired
genre as a pornography would be off
limits in Australia
and as an example
this if she was naked would be perfectly
fine with the ACMA
Guinness Book of World Records your
comparing BP
getting the Guinness Book not me
something else and there's a a couple
other
things at about two days ago was
announced that
a new law that going through Australia
might require
every Australian resident or citizen to
him
over their passwords to all other social
networking
account so that the Australian
government can properly monitor the
Internet and social networking
this happen just two days ago alright
in the news just this week Russia
actually passed in very bad
sensors censorship law now it's
basically
a blacklist extremist content
now why is extremist content it anything
they want it to be
cell all webpages and web sites
containing ban pornography
drug ads and promoting suicide or
extremist
ideas like this conference to them
Zack should be put on a unified
additional blacklist
there's actually been a new agency for
mean
to monitor this so that's a lotta money
that they don't have
to monitor stuff that they shouldn't
care about
now there's actually a Russian search
and engine
Yandex whose stocks plummeted
over this a softy is Google for their
porn
so now our own FCC who has usually been
pretty poor
on things like this in the past actually
have the gall to come out and speak
against the bill
so it's troubling in and dangerous dire
action
how many times we felt that about the
FCC good
yeah now also in the news this week
this is actually been a very big week
around the world
for censorship ethiopia
now Ethiopia is not a good place to be
and
the government has been blocking new
sites and blogs like bit larger ones
I for about seven years now now they're
actually starting to block facebook
smaller blocks and news services
that sucks they're also blocking in
Skype and VoIP services now because they
want
everybody to use the state-run telephone
network
they can't happen monitor all calls and
make money at the same time
yes now also in the news as if that
wasn't enough censorship happening this
week
China China is actually going to require
all online content distributors
to monitor and watch every single video
and make sure it is OK
now what is OK in China so
now two different organizations but this
out the State Administration of radio
film and television
in the state internet information office
the propaganda office now boger content
excessive violence Arpana and
pornography are going to be banned
so a search engine Youku
said political speech if it isn't I
party in anti-social
it definitely will not pass that's
pretty scary
but we're in america were saved from all
that right
absolutely so up the current US claim it
right now
the US signed actor now actor isn't
a specifically popcorn I'm for free but
it does a
have some mentions about some
copyrighted material
which to is part of the slippery slope
so to speak with the protecting certain
financial interest to web blocking
sensor
content an there's quite a few parallels
between active people in so per
I am their big groups like Doctors
Without Borders have spoken out against
this
or risking not only are online freedoms
but also things like generic medications
or other medications so these things are
not good
for any a bus a
we have a current presidential candidate
who
wants to if he is president wants to
sign an executive order
up for there to be away in every
household
for someone to Press a button
to block out possible pornography he is
very anti
porn so is a sum up his backers
mister romney all to protect minors of
course from
last seen possible pornography or where
they came from
who do you think's actually installing
the computers in these homes
the kids yeah yes
yeah now you what's the real reason
behind actor pepper sober I mean it's
not to save the children
to save the money absolute its copyright
now walt Disney was sorta right when he
said
I only hope that we don't lose one thing
that was all started
by a mouse all of these legislations
all these protective actions all the
censorship
is just covering up re always to monitor
us
and make the money now everyone knows
about the Mickey Mouse copyright laws
mickey mouse will never die
it will always be in copyright so as
long as that happens
there'll be new paper's news opens new
PB lock stock
whatever cell it's a future ahead of us
we just have to
inform as many people as possible
corporate censorship
up iraq now and erotica author
sad I wanna pinch myself to see a fine
way and sometimes I wonder
is this really happening to me now
there's a whole lotta
erotica online Amazon stores in the
bookstores
for candles I am but not everyone likes
it
especially on the device manufactures
Apple all
we all love Apple well not really but
like their mac book
now Apple started censoring books in
out in 2010 anything that felt
anything that I've felt was dirty or
moral or they can get multiple countries
now they
began censoring photography in multiple
forms on their iPad
because they won a clean product wanna
my background as photography
so II and many others
have wanted to perhaps in Apple's App
Store
most my photographer friends were female
have opened up boudoir versions
up their businesses for women they make
e-books out a photo shoots things like
that Apple is constantly rejecting them
an earlier this month
a Cisco did a very interesting thing for
some %uh versa
residential can customers with some
the higher and home routers all the
sudden wind
people want to use their internet they
notice that the
the year local administration up there
own router piece of hardware that they
bought
that they set up and configure
themselves that they thought that they
own the piece of hardware and their
administration
was actually moved to Cisco's Connect
cloud service
I without a choice without notice
without anything
this is Cole cloud service was very
interesting because it had some very
arm strange Anna
shall we say a leading into censorship
terms and conditions
some other terms and conditions
were you agree not to use this product
for anything obscene any pornographic or
offensive purposes and then below it
intellectual property rights go hand in
hand don't thing
now what would
e-books be without pornography it made
audible dot com its makin Amazon's
bookstore right now
mommy porn Harlequin
I love that now milf porn is actually
holding in
the top four spots this is a three-book
series
holding the top worse by yeah
because the three-book series as a
single item
the spot number for in
yes by women go for
okay the current
international climate I was very happy I
happen to reside in the European Union
in the Netherlands
and my country a a
voted down an actor in said that a it
they were not even allowed to bring a
biller treaty to the Dutch parliament
that even resembled actor
finally the day that I landed in this
country on the fourth of July I got a
text message the actor was completely
defeated
in the EU Parliament so we're very happy
about
passion however
a
a we're still under attack in the United
Kingdom
they want to do some very interesting
things about censorship in pornography
since one of the MP's
commented that it was his goal to clean
up the Internet
so what they yeah exactly I
so what they would like to do is every
person who has
internet per your account are you will
have the
everything of pornography will be
blocked but you will have the option to
op in to see pornography just like I
would love to be on a government list
saying that I have opted in to view
pornography
the next step will probably be what type
of pornography in fetish
in material you would like to use I say
that because
they did a study in gathered some
information the United Kingdom did
a putting in your opt in and what types
of things and unfortunately the
a list due to lack of security
I was compromised and posted online
so are ready before they instituted any
kinda legal program they are ready
spread
information about their citizens they
had no business doing so I don't
particularly
trust a government having my name on a
list
associated with viewing pornography a
the United Kingdom also want to consider
a black box
like on the airlines that is installed
on every home computer up a
which can monitor all social networking
and all email traffic so that's been
proposed that's quite scary
I wouldn't want that in their home a box
monitoring L
I don't that's ridiculous the good news
for you americans
as we don't have to do anything cuz they
just give it to the government
Facebook Twitter we don't be bothered
with that done for us yes unfortunately
although
actor has been defeated in the EU and
there is something new
and other doesn't specifically deal with
pornography
it deals a lot with copyright and it's
called CDA
now cedar is quite similar to actor
it's actually somewhat more restrictive
and some manners Doctors Without Borders
has also come out against us now the
thing about cedar is
they're trying to push it in the EU with
a commission
not elected not Parliament no
nothing to do with judicial review in
this is how they're trying to circumvent
the fact that the European Union said
no to actor so
what can be done with all of this
censorship
well we have a few ideas which er only
opinions
I'm we believe in transparency we think
that
a if you have a blacklist you should be
a able to view it see what's on it and
if you're put on their inadvertently
just like a Queensland dentist was
placed on the Australian blacklist
I guess because that they thought that
that dental surgery was a little too
saucy
I'm not sure Oro I
um
censorship shouldn't be based on
someone's opinion
up for example be headed the ACMA has a
highly religious man who does not
believe in pornography
February 2012 they came out with a
report specifying that their top goal
was
actually to block uncensored legal
adult pornography so it should really be
based on
on what our representatives and what we
say
and what a judge says but not somebody's
opinion that is not elected
and outside judicial review information
technology professional should be
consulted
a for example Bruce Schneier
a perhaps should not have been
disinvited from at the Senate meeting
a we need people who no more
then the internet has made up a choose
before they start changing our internet
from this was a suggestion from a block
a from BRR
ITT I dot com transparency about black
listen censorship methods used by
businesses would be nice to you
who hears ever had to be the asshole to
install a filter at a company and
everyone hated you after
yeah thats Sox
so we need to stay on topic what's going
on on line what's going on
a with censorship because we need to
make sure that we protect our rights
in hold on to them as much as possible
so up here is a way that
people in the US the UK India and in the
EU can locate
any up there a elected or parliamentary
members
I suggest that all of us get to know who
are elected or parliamentary
up members are
so we stay on topic but it's not
something that someone else is going to
do
it's something that we need to do
we also need to stay on top and get to
know organizations that are against
censorship
an r4 our basic rights human and online
such as the ACLU employees a
give good shout out to the FF within the
audience's well
in
the International pirate party there are
now a parties
in this country that have been set up
so please check out their website by the
way their website is hosted and I swim
with us
free speech provider I'm in France and
Germany the Chaos Computer Club
attack
and please check out the international
declaration of freedom
involving the Internet
I would be remiss if I didn't mention a
how to report illegal porn
I hear some associations that anywhere
in the world if you happen to see
something that looks like child
pornography
I beg you please report it a child
pornography is one of the few crimes
where the person is a real victim I is
because I want something is posted
online
I it's there for ever thousands of
copies are made
like the State Department found out when
they tried to the man from wiki leaks
that they hand back all this stolen
information
they of course had to explain to the
state department that that was quite
impossible
and this is just a brief list to make
sure that I don't break copyright nor
the surgical 847 it will be added on so
that
hopefully a know when sousa's
and does anyone have any further
questions on earth
comments yes
him
here
brim
him all yeah the hip
while
not more but the question is how are
they planning on building the lists
a pornography sites it actually
currently exists now if you look at
sites like you are a blacklist
thats a free or paid blackness they
people can download for
& Guardian other open source software I
mean it's actually
me in the upper but there's companies a
Luke are
coats semantic like hundreds of
companies just
trying to search and make these but
I mean even a simple program now can go
out
either Google or spider themself and
based off a point calculations are the
men just searching in
build an index of love what is this
relation to
re relationship to you as a just
searching breasts as far as medical
or with other words near: and I mean
that search engine now
I'm bill in the mid 90's I was very very
basic of a single database
and within that one day they say the
methodology do it
with that if you look at things like
snore
and some %uh the email systems which I
actually have
AI built into a two-block I N if you
just apply that same logic
to web searching in you can gather hits
of me or else
open source software like dance Guardian
that's doing multiple ways of handling
it
a a user's URL lists a user's
a word references within certain points
built up
built up these values any their flags in
real time
or block set at the last so if you have
a site like Facebook
where you may not have bad material
everywhere but you're certain groups
I mean that's that's when you want to
get more the fine green technology
and we're dealing with governments who
have trillions of dollars to waste on
this crap
so their resources are endless yes
could you
talk a little more about copyright
issues especially with the rising tube
sites and the interface with some
those are actually owned by companies
that are producing confident pirating
other companies content to market their
own content
in a I'll it seems to be
very much a one way to keep a
this certain a legal firms in business
it appears a Cueto money generating
item a I must stress is actually
for my lawyer must say that this is
actually not my area
expertise so okay so what we have now
are things like Hulu
Danielle you too and it all of these
companies
paramount the MRI they are releasing
their own
on information trailers videos and
people
take em mash mott sending out to other
sites while
they hire companies to search use
algorithms
and actually search for media based off
a I
different algorithms which they are
differences pattern there's been many
times were
artists themselves have gotten DMCA
violations
because our what they posted and their
the owner
and their label on Sat but because these
third parties was talking we're
specifically about the adult sites
okay where some the adult sites are
actually owned by
pornography companies mmm I'm I
do you have any and since you're talking
about the dole industry
well I mean we've all seen aggregator
sites like the TDP sites where
it's just nonstop clicking their taking
other people's content so
I N I don't think it's a bad thing to
have large
pornography conglomerates I mean we need
someone
to put out to do the legal tracks so
aggregators they're just and for a penny
a click
so that's where real problem comes they
are stealing
content to say which is must be behind a
paywall
and look at look at an IB dot com in all
those where
people stealing often pay sites in just
posting their so
copyright does definitely come into play
this this is someone's
real livelihood and I'm not saying we
should be totally against copyright
I just don't want it to be for 75 years
vintage porn not that bad
occurred okay so
them related to what you're talking
about earlier that 7
well you talking about people read into
everything
step and then the big companies bisbee
crawling content for
for stuff that they own the copyright to
dead and taking them for years because
I've a.m.
and the legal soundtrack
I'm just wondering we get to a point
where there there's some other stuff
going on against transformative work at
other kinds
because another great big don't love
affair
at porn on the internet as far as I'm
concerned is Seth m thick
it may not be widely known that we were
talking about
its just before fifty Shades of Grey
started life
as a Twilight fan fiction yeah they just
changed the names
and a stolen Thomas entirely from and
racers
Sleeping Beauty seriously 84 there
there's no original work in literature
things like that so we definitely do see
lawsuits based around the main content
and books and publishing
that's been going on for almost 200
years SAR
I N if anything it's just going to get
worse now that
something like fifty Shades has taken
off so bigger Twilight's taken off so
big
I mean are we probably going to see a
better
love story then Twilight know it's crap
by it
in is so large that that's why everyone
references it to you
in as pretty much stolen from other
people in the past
but they might have not gone as big so
we're really on a down home at all
with much this we can just hope that
certain johner certain
material doesn't get too big how we can
actually keep it in the
in our own domain or do things somewhere
with it
just a quick comment on the GOP a
and the weight thing on or in addition I
if you get caught it set out
at last I checked 15 years in prison so
missile
it's it's pretty bad have a new
a few years ago there was a protest in
ethiopia
and the police force opened fire with
live round bullets
when the international media ask them
why they opened fire on their own
citizens they said
listen worse a poor country and we can't
afford record bullets
exactly so these are not too
and even that countries that you want to
get on the list
yes at the beginning at the time argue
we're mentioning how
adult material head are pushed
technology forward in waterways
what do you see as future arm
technology jumps because if the adult
industry
in the recent future I definitely see
things like salt state
as huge advancements when you look at
at PCIe base at solid-state
like the i/o drive I mean yes some
larger companies have used in
not that it matters cuz myspace about
one for every single server but then I
can be around much longer but
a lot of porn companies are starting to
do that on their
proxy servers especially Squid proxy
servers because if you can serve
your static content of apps on state
which is not just the salts the desk
going over and I L controller
but straight from the PCIe bias which is
much faster
I mean that has been a huge advancement
in the porn technologies
now we're also looking at other similar
San vendors
doing things like hyper dagger gets with
solid-state
and up cheaper drives like
say to within the same rates at within
the same pool
and more intelligent caching algorithms
where
they'll know which blocks are hot I'm
we're also looking a lot
at d2 techno deduplication technology is
which are better
have more granular levels for Cain
levels in smaller which candy duplicate
the actual files
even if they're encrypt it are similarly
encrypt did
be and that relates to it last orange be
needed
so that is something that certainly is a
very recent years advancement I'm but we
are still seen some advancements in
things like we an acceleration and
actual backbones
I I love internet and providers
you might hear some statistics that
YouTube and Netflix
are some of the highest band with sites
in the world
but it's not really true if you look at
all of the porn sites put together
together it totally trumps Google
Netflix YouTube like x hamster for
example
he says something like twenty nine
petabytes data and a
and about 7 percent a the world's
internet users
actually visit x hampster so
so we're we're definitely seeing in
advancements and total throughput person
can have
40 and 100 gay he in finna band has just
been growing like crazy
so these technologies are definitely
come in and no one wants to admit
that the porn industry is pain so much
for hardware and software
so it in your chart you mentioned about
how Apple was not allowing porn on there
App Store arm and after seem to be going
to the future
a lot of platforms Windows after is
coming there's the internets torture
this letters maybe a little bit more
open but those companies probably not
going to be too friendly to porn so what
do you think's gonna happen to think
usual go to alternate ill to report will
be a driver to take users
get them through their project now I
think you think will serve see
a slowing down a technology where like
the there may be some ways people could
use a
a smartphone to do for naps on in
using the accelerometer I R Jesus okay
yeah I do think that there is like were
gonna miss out on those you noses gently
guided missiles
basically in the reason you're special
because
books like Fifty Shades of Grey Apple
has gone there
ass kicked in the e-book market the
candle
as major leap and out celine the iPad
just four fifty shades of grey in the
past couple weeks
I mean fifty shades have been on the
book lists for a hundred
and eight days so there's a significant
trend
in iPad versus Kindle sales because at
that
or books been shared Apple's actually
getting a little bit more lenient
about what they're blocking the recently
took down the
no viruses thing on their website I am
yeah so there they're starting to admit
things they're admitting that the ad now
where
in the last month on the App Store sell
because I've that push
I love the user base they're going to
open up a little bit but it's not going
to be
absolute but there are still ways gaps
on your
your iPad where people won't make caps
which are directly
content holders if you look at many in
up the applications are application
development toolkits
sort of like ap salaried or titanium for
making naps on every single device
are within one program your scene ways
that you can make a
container program so to speak which will
display your content which will
show your location and if you do things
like coaster content outside of their
store
I mean you have you have a lot better
chance of getting your app approved
their is I can remember the name right
now maybe someone else will be able to
remember in
shouted out but pink something for
that the iPad which is a porn app for
I'm so it's usually reference to go to
porn site on your iPad like a donut
gamma know this million-dollar to a
month for
so those abs are definitely out there
already mean if we look back at
Betamax for purses BHS I'm HD
like that was a licensing thing which
pushed
be a chance to be the winner I don't
know why
Blu ray one because more responsible I
sons but porn push that
from HD DVD to Blu ray
I mean they're pushing in all and the
applications as well
I mean city its India was around
people had that there are some porn app
snap now they're finding new ways with
html5
and been able to use not just in
objective-c but these I abstraction
layer programming languages like
capsular reader titanium in
some other open source applications to
make the zaps
so we're definitely going to have them
and we have them now
do you think uses a largely Ruth their
phones are go Android instead Apple to
get the point you have any evidence
abusers doing that Europe to Android
sales are up
because you can
return phone there's nothing wrong with
that and because at the legal battles
between
am Apple and Samsung Apple's actually
losing
in the European Union right now some
apple products have been pulled off the
shelves
and and Germany last I heard and by the
way I just at an Apple does
allow playboy amazingly enough
I but they do not allow a smaller
organizations or companies
that have similar content are to be sold
on their devices
so very selective this is a phone that
in the US albright get a pirate
mall official some dumbass today but in
the UK the UK merchant
are the the European version was
specifically released
to be easily routed and have
like sign a like no matter whatevers
name as his
stop put on it Sao I mean we do see some
users do that
but with the advancements with html5
another
can disorientation and we won't need as
much
in the way %uh aP's to be downloaded to
have the same support and ability
thanks
so while back I read an article on a US
law that
home wanted to limit arm poor web sites
to the died xxx
I'm domain and so is can ask you guys if
he had anything to say as our
how that would affect the porn industry
and yes
the law would never pass like if point
the porn business has like enough
lobbied to you you know there there's
just too much which can be considered
porn to make that happen
that's like say National Geographic
should be labeled as playboy
you know here for sought its National
Geographic
there you go so I mean
I I just don't think that's possible I
mean I might be a good idea
may help the filter companies but it's
not going to happen I
meh I think that's all the time we have
for tonight thank you all for coming
thank you very much