14 photos of yourself and we can
identify who you are or
you think you don't have 14 photos of
yourself on the Internet then he was
asked what should people do about their
privacy reasons
well everyone should have a chance to
change their name once in their life
the guys up front
got him brother remember
these guys have this information now I
want to tell you
this is being made available only to
hope
only to her there is a way
to completely get rid of all but the
Google Data out there
is a short instructional films or should
watch this while I go back there and see
if the hope is like committed fratricide
are my people
heard about your privacy while using
Google the Internet giant so that
understands Google is now offering users
a chance
opt out and live in privacy in a remote
mountain village
tech trends reporter Geoff Tate has more
thanks Teresa
they call it the of out village and it's
just what you'd expect from Google
if you want to keep your information
private all you have to do his move to a
22-acre
opt-out village and not speak to anyone
from the outside world it's very simple
just go to the Google front page click
the up out but and in minutes a van will
come to your house and pick you up
that same day it came up Google privacy
experts eliminate your home address
guaranteeing
it will no longer appear on Google local
pages and after just two days in the
back above and
you're there in the village we can
guarantee that there's no chance
renew emails because there are no
computers and because they're awesome
under
and tracked by Google there are no banks
or hospitals residents will be expected
to know how to grow food
suture wounds and bury corpses by hand
if they plan to opt out
and Google is gone the extra mile to
ensure that users who choose to opt out
are given complete privacy in their new
home
a thirty foot tall ten foot thick
physical data security walton's
all former Google users from leaving the
village until they decide they want to
start using Google again
the Uptown village can be seen by Google
satellites because the entire town is
enclosed in a large metal box with no
openings
google says those wishing to hop back
into using Google after their time in
the village
will be allowed to do so if they agree
to be branded with the whimsical G on
their foreheads to label them doubters
if you don't want to give us complete
access to your most private party
feelings that's fine
you can just toy on the hinterlands and
ion at Carter says the opt-out villages
already getting rave reviews what the
first village residents sent this letter
praising the total privacy
inside the village saying all alone no
light hard to breathe
and that's one man whose data is secure
for the Onion News Network
on Geoff Tate thanks Jeff if you have
any oca
yeah I i look
hello what I do I am
besides the fact that I'm not going
blind her we do something about this
player who ever raise the lights
lower them the magic word is
now yeah well
art that's honestly I
them you need yeah I'm not taking
lessons from you
you know
part part a bit part of it years no no
I'm I'm cool
stand out at the like but seriously
whoever is in charge of a line
it really is not making me happy
I am the Sox okay
are I've ill talk
I'll maybe arm
the problem is people think you dole
put stuff on the web it didn't happen
now
I remember hearing about Hitler killing
himself from the bunker
problem set on fire the
the Stearns Stearns lucky happen from
the world
he's being on TV from intro
the that of course is
are more market of getting his long
overdue just desserts everything
everything is on the other
Flickr Flickr has
a gazillion know by the way Flickr is
today
only a tiny percentage on Facebook but
it has
billions in photos with things here's a
woman
her in her inbred family one around
robbing banks themself
that's for two half-brothers you know
Darrell and our other brother Darrell
I'm cheapo some 28 like act like I'm 17
most the time I love to form a shoot
guys which he did
and wrecked cars I'm a redneck and proud
of it I like milk and German engineering
and causing mayhem
with my siblings you wanna rob banks
with these guys put this up their proper
photos
as you might imagine somebody circling
picture looks from Notre
she's locked up no people put everything
up there LinkedIn
LinkedIn you put your whole life story
up there on believable for
investigations unbelievable for hacking
on believable for spearfishing I'm going
through the various sites for
quickly all
for those %uh view who believe in
passwords
which I hope a hacker conference there
will not be
ace single person who doesn't already
understand
that once you put the information out
there it's gone
its everywhere it's disseminated its
spread
it's stolen it's investigated it's sold
there's no such thing as a secure
website 0
if it's on the net and there's a net
connection
its gore you have given up control over
the information
and it will get out your credit cards
will be stolen
your social security number will be
disseminated
your job history your employment
everything we'll
get out not today maybe next year
arm you know I understand that there
were some people talking earlier
about security medical record systems
I have here with me today some people
are actually
experts on this their own security to
have the major
hospitals in in New York
gotta tell you
way worse way worse close in attacks
these people are
fighting like it like alliance to keep
your
your information safe return and it's a
close for
a close fight I went to a guys house I
was tired
course a company was being stored a big
software company
and they said will be restored somebody
sent us an email saying they have our
source code
send us a picture cover source codes we
believe it to be true
and they said if you don't give us a
hundred thousand dollars in cash blah
blah the whole
ransom drop we're going to release your
source code onto the net
I track the threaten her to a fourteen
year old kid
by a in in Southern California went to
his house
and was given concert by his father as
he was
kicking a BS to take all of his hard
drives in his computers and
signed away and I wanted his computers
is one of his computers is what are the
files
I for 50 3 the whole wasn't
pages myspace logins and passwords
now 53,000 passwords 53,000
pages have logins and passwords more
than a million
just this one pay just this one data for
and you can see some oven down there
just as wonderful
I did a print command just to see how
many pages was
a thousand 119 pages myspace logins and
passwords
you know that there are a gazillion to
Facebook passwords for around
somebody just hoover top 450,000 yahoo
password shabu socks but
and you guys probably don't use it but
nevertheless 450,000 passwords I think
yesterday
I no such thing as a secure personal
sop you say I don't care I don't give my
real name I use tor I do this I do that
honest to god meaningless meaningless
I'm not going to give you a master's
class on the anonymization
I am going to tell you it's done it's
not better and better and better all the
time
this years to the benefit of selling
stuff
this is not the show you stuff this is a
service that is being developed
for governmental law enforcement
agencies kidnappers threatens hackers
harassers
an army good papers I mean the type that
everybody else thinks are hackers
up terrorists DNR position is a big deal
and the technology is getting better and
better and better and better all the
time
and I can tell you that these are some
big data ports
generalizing Netflix posts 87 percent to
public census data the anonymized
Carnegie Mellon researchers accurately
guessed us a sense
the more data that I have the more
finally defined
I can make an anonymous persona on the
on the you know
the more likely I'm gonna die I'm going
to identify you
if I know that this anonymous person is
Chinese a tap dancer and lives in Iowa
probably one guy arm
but I gotta tell you it's pretty close
the the the
the public census data was just with the
first name
and a zip code in a lotta places if I
put in
dolores in a zip code to eat that many
I own a system where you can search for
somebody with just the first time in a
zip code
her first name in a day to birth if I
have your name
your your birth in your zip code I own
you
I only Jackson of this is Dolores
she's 43 and she lives on Smith Street
sort of I know you're from that moment I
know everything about you within an hour
to know do you not imitation is not that
horny more
here's a perfect example and I use those
all the time no I got a really raw speed
up
congress subpoena all the search engines
because they wanted to see what they
really know about you
are a all well to their credit even
though they suck at everything else
said to congress we are going to
anonymized
all about your searchers we're gonna
give them code numbers will give you the
search history
but we will we will take out their names
and addresses
and things like that now the minute this
was turned over to congress became
public records stupid
and the New York Times god bless their
pink a little hearts took
the AOL file and put a couple
researchers or
and the researchers a terrific and they
took us bring them
thing and they found here is
search your number 4417 749
which they were able to resolve to miss
the home or not
her search issue included sixty year old
single man landscapers in Woburn Georgia
shadow Lake subdivision or an old and
ordered urinates on everything
that was your search history so they
weren't and sure enough
they fell hope who is going to search
for a 60-year-old
single man a sixty year old single woman
Arnold
or no shuttle a sub-divisional Auburn
Georgia owns a dork
only one person missus arnold who lives
in the shadow Lake subdivision
in live in Georgia she's intersects
these issues in order to urinate on
everything
not hard to figure that out you or your
search history folks
start building in Austin for heart it's
going to get worse
algorithm can guess your sister
browser fingerprinting
everybody's browser is remarkably unique
I know you're logging in from a Mac I
know you're running
10 points 6 I know this is the
sponsor that you have installed on your
system
I know that you or that you have these
plugins
I know that you have previously done
XY and z. your browser
has a reasonably damn good fingerprint
and by the way if I can suck that your
history and your bookmarks file
course I own you but even without that
your browser fingerprint is so unique
that if you use their browser to do
cutie porn
and I come later and I grip your
computer I can say
even if you've overridden 97 times
with random characters or your kiddie
porn
I know that that's your browser and I
could prove it to the satisfaction of
the jury
browser fingerprinting dozens ARV
above all for scholarly papers go to
abstract sites download the stuff
read it and be freaked now I'm not free
I use this in my job and if you have
nothing to hide
you have nothing to worry about nobody
has anything to hydro need
ok there are companies that
know you hide who you or you don't give
up your data
so they're setting up browser
fingerprinting for marketing purposes
this guy Daniel Norris from blue car for
his goal is the fingerprint
$10 billion devices you already have
those
he already has 200 million devices
fingerprinted
you think you're anonymous not anonymous
from this we saw
any really is weasel because this is
stop being done without your knowledge
without your permission
that's on american if you're stupid of
not to read your Terms of Service it's
on you
if you're stupid enough to post a
drunken can include photo
it's on you that that stirs weasel
thats weasel let's all remember and
while I'm delighted by it as an
investigator
as an american I'm not real founder
cookies browsing history download
history embedded graphics track in your
ass everywhere
these little micro pages passwords
appearing in URL strings
hum you typed the wrong page
and put in your password and hit click
and the page
doesn't exist anymore your DNS server
will say
no such page but it'll buffer that page
to a boil
so Verizon will have it or Sprint or or
whenever horrible cable company use
companies like 44 doesn't exist anymore
the opera or
was too much but there are many form
like companies
who are smart enough to keep a low
profile DNS corrections
even routers Cisco three weeks ago got
spanked because they were sucking down
everybody's
no history through their order
Flash cookies made fresh cookies are
unbelievable they hide here they hide
their
they disguise themselves they are worse
than any Trojan
Ukiah go to wear normal cookies are you
can't go to your preference file on a
Mac by the way
track that stuff in the settings file to
the trash every couple weeks
and and solve it that way they just re
sport
their response by the way they hide the
history that they report
they hide it in a remote location on
your drive so that when they re spore in
the able to say
yup still the same guy now
forensic linguistics this is an amazing
free concert
this is won't have the
most fascinating forensic developments
in my opinion
since DNA and it makes all you guys
sitting ducks on the net even if used
for
even if you use a strange computer even
if you go to library
even if you were ski mask I while you're
at a large
I am the woodshop seen some pictures a
guy's do it stop at the library though
they need to I'll go on reddit from Todd
here's a guy this guy's an assistant US
attorneys a federal prosecutors name is
Sal Perricone
he was involved in a case he was so
excited just
by the people on the other side the
defendants and the potential defendants
and the witnesses he put up a blog when
he was enormously post the organization
about these people
which is a big no no if you're the
prosecutor but he was doing and under
the alias
HL mencken an real momentum 1951
arm so the people who are on the
receiving end
over this a anonymous nasty
generally legally improper postings
hired a forensic linguistics expert
and they were able to determine some
really really unique words
like do buddy do but he is the active
bean
dubious about something you every other
word
I never heard that word but these posts
all had were duping
in the entire planet there's one guy who
all these
pleadings public pleadings filed in
court over the years have used the word
do believe there's another one
another really really ridiculous word
are
all arm Paris
hope readout spelled re-do you BT like
I'm doubted again I really doubt it
nobody uses these two words so they had
this forensic linguistics guy who's a
retired
FBI agent who was doing this for the FBI
and it was involved
in tracking down the Europe armor and
people who sent ransom notes
and stuff like that he said same got
nobody else uses these words
so they got a subpoena and before they
could use the subpoena
to see where the logins were coming from
mister so-called HL mencken Perricone
prosecutors okay yup and by the way he
is obviously no longer on the case
I think he is and by the way here's the
times-picayune
article it up fascinating story cell
Perricone
Google read about it it's the perfect
example of a forensic linguistics
if I have a big enough sample love your
writing there are really really unique
things about
everybody's combination of words
commonly use phrases
punctuation I did a case with the a
woman from the New York Times issues
going after cricket person
when she started getting all kinds of
threats that were written by one guy
and she was communicating with another
guy and she noticed
that both of these people would do
parentheses space period
in a punctuation she was able to figure
out was the same guy and bust a min
so on and so forth principally West
makes it
really impossible for you to hide if
there's a big enough sample
up your legitimate writings and even you
with the nose and glasses
I can connect that to all your anonymous
poster forensic linguistics
photos photos if I know that you posted
anonymous photo on the web
I get your EXIF tags from those enormous
photos
I search on the web for those EXIF tags
and I find Bob Jones is using a
camera with the exact same unique serial
number
electronic serial number on the camera I
know that those anonymous photos
of him you know spanking a naked girl in
Cancun or whatever
that the or worse or worse it's a good
way
to catch child molesters and pedophiles
are
every digital device has a unique
fingerprint now
and I can anything that you post on the
net not use your words
but your photos in your video and your
and your
mp3 files and everything I can trace
back to you by just
comparison of digital data it is harder
and harder and harder to saw
heart-to-heart know by the way when you
could burn a photo
click the box that says do not a bad
here so I have to
if you are in fact an evil criminal
little trip to you
which thank god you're not listen to and
there or there are web is so
for can easy to do now not just for guys
like me or the NSA
that this commercial services other than
what you do for free like
Google for search engine on what have
Cameron or signatures
just even if the EXIF tag isn't in there
every camera sensor has a unique
signature what ballistics on a firearm
you shoot a ball the the scratches on
the barrel are unique to use gone
you can match bullets from this photo 5
this bullet fired this boulevard
if you have one cameras 14 is digital
voice signature and others
you can be analyzed the photo just
letting you know just letting you know
here's an example of the the digital
hive mind
up just showing in so many people know
what this photo is
okay the whole room because you're
reasonably intelligent people
unlike usual approach but up
I'm gonna be in trouble happened so that
or a
my boss in the society professional
investigators
not in business but in the Association
he will rat me out later are this is of
course the photo the actual White House
official photo
up Arbor everybody waiting for
you know tango Down geronimo a
Osama bin weasel killed Osama bin kill
2010 arm so
the next day story is written on the AP
and it says
on the AP wire hidden from view standing
just outside the frame
%uh that now-famous photograph was a
career CIA analyst in the hunt for the
world's most wanted terrorist
there may have been no one more
important this from an article called a
man who want to solve the globe
so of course all the guys on reddit
crypto McRib
dad crypt everything said got together
the hivemind
start buzzing answer I anonymous my ass
shop what can you do us from
the guy you can tell he's really free
control
you freakishly tall and he's wearing a
tie in a suit
so his blocker this photo but through
the brilliance
are Defense Intelligence Agency counter
security guys
who were responsible for this particular
moment
he's not prepared to any of the other
photos took two hours to identify the
SCA
to kill him two hours saw we've got toll
blocked off by a black suit yellow tie
here is the head of the CIA in the back
very tall guy lecture yellow tie
by the way I download all those from the
sites to be able to show you those
so you zoom in and there is again
okay know you got this photo so they
learn
here's the Situation Room gee here's a
thought
let's look at this from another angle
and if you zoom in seeing the corner
there
there is a God hurried car bomber
and he's identified and that is later
much too is
college yearbook photo many areas
playing basketball that is high school
yearbook for
I forget his name I normally have it not
real hard to find you can google it
but here is the most wanna go by the
terrorists super-secret
kept from everybody CIA protected guy
free can read it random in two hours
yeah yeah and and you guys
CIA guarded analyst you
you got a real chance to be in an arms
now by the way
I just put this up there because
I'm an idiot miss made me laugh and
that's how I include things on these
things
what makes me laugh so this girl
did you know they have these a a.m. made
things a ask me anything
on reddit so she posts I I breast
reduction surgery 24 hours ago
ask me anything I'm 18 you okay net
I'm he'd amid 18-year-old girl
I was a 34 a 36
no no no she's a hold on authority she
was a 32g now she's a 34c
18-year-old 34c girl was post the
topless photos of herself
with the head cut off and she says but i
wanna keep myself anonymous
okay 50 minutes
50 minutes after she posted edit seems
like fortune has come up with my
personal information
home on 18-year-old topless girl they're
not gonna figure out who she is
I'll be there were probably 40,000
analysts working on this
it's it's it's unbelievable you're not
to forget good
you're not anonymous you know you say
anonymous don't say
anonymous the minute you say that you
are so screwed
and there aren't any companies give you
a simplified planetary
whose job it is to shock now all love
your public data
not just stuff like public record data
like voter
and and and and and real property and
social security information or phone
whatever but they grab your Facebook in
your Twitter in your Google for
I want to grab that they sought to
Foxwood frito-lay and Nike and so on
and a turnaround and they give you
alternative loggins which you go
yeah that's convenient no its not
you need to have a separate password
every site don't believe me s the owners
obstruct for if that's true or not
right lesson if you log into every site
with your Facebook login a
the people or view facebook login have
your login to every side
and be Facebook has all love your login
information
I mean how already set to figure out
apparently
really really or at
guys so your secretive your good little
hackers you really want us to get his
mother where there's about
75 my colleagues in this room
who came we put out a big posting you
know come we're gonna give you
continuing education credits for those
I'm later I'm gonna blow a whistle and
the side of the room wall
collar that either knob character
arm this is something that every
investigator
has internal first and so should you
if you don't post your shit somebody
else will
personally think there be an ISA this is
me in bob reporting
you did Bobby Moore poster he too late
you know their sites used to again it
made me laugh
I put it up here's two sites don't date
him girl who's a rat
I show this every year the site dole
date /img /url
all large cheater Aaron Carter the third
this boy will use you like no other
he smokes weed all day every day and if
he doesn't have it he will freak out
here's his a huge his hide his way
where he lives his photo I don't care if
Aaron Carter is a ghost I gotta
thanks to a pissed-off girlfriend %uh
this is my favorite one
Johnathan Jordan reporter yet
this manner so called boys such a liar
first the said the personally said he
loved me
and we were together for four years and
then I catch 'em in bed
K problem number one with another guy
problem number two with another guy como
given pride more
so for an investigator this is kind of a
two-fer
Han you've got the bad boyfriends
clogged
and you've got who's a rat with a post
informants
and information on people I mean this is
the original toxic side
and the original Dorking side and they
put up
photos and date of birth and addresses
and schools in whatever room for
instance a terrible terrible side
are and one in five Americans now has a
personal blog
they had nothing to say they have she
boring little lives
see you know what happens irregular
thank you
I appreciate it know you should manage
your
problems so then you have commercial
data gathers
think about when using Amazon tells
people and i got really speedo
what you read what you like where you
live your bank account your credit card
your address cuz they actually have to
send you stuff so too real address
your entire profile
quick example I had a woman in my
building where I live
asked me to buy her a book she had
doesn't have the Internet old Russian
woman
told me in broke broken english by me
this book on kidney cancer
a border the book on Amazon four weeks
later
I started receiving other things you
might be interested in
and little things in my male about
cancer
I don't have cancer thank God but that's
how it works
Kindle and e-book invasion of privacy
where you can imagine
can do even knows what you highlight
and what page you stop reading on
I'm not kidding if you highlight
something course it interests you
the mothership gets a message
honestly and by the way booksellers can
have is an extra added 13
non-fiction books fiction books will be
told by Amazon
14,000 of the readers highlighted this
passage
there really were interested in that
you can pay pal come on I mean what do
he bailed paper which is the same
company of course
not know about you every freakin silly
thing you browse on
you browse about helicopters I mean
okay bank accounts I want to know your
bank account
not a problem when you open up a new
in front of every desk if the new
accounts officers a thing that says
little will sign that says be advised
your bank account is verified through
equifax eternity services
okay I go to Equifax eternity services I
pull your file
and I see the Bank of America to check
on you
I'm going with my turn over order by
seizure order to Bank of America
you know give me all bank accounts all
investment accounts anything that this
guy's a signatory 0
freezes safe deposit boxes after derecho
there on you that can only mean one
thing
it's not that you walked in US for
change a hundred right
every little thing you do is in a
database somewhere
for example you go to a bowl or they
take your
driver's license now as proof that you
gave them
an ID that shows that you're a mean age
to drink and then the data goes into a
database
shop run bombs first law write this down
there will be a test
all databases will eventually be used
for unintended purposes
example here's a USA Today story dominos
the niceness
domino's can't bite me USA Today story
how dominoes database you call dominos
they deliver you a pizza I know what
your cell phone number is
I don't dominoes database and you are
a 24-year-old person sooner or later you
can order dominos or Papa Johns
republicans one or the other and I know
that that cell phone
had pizza delivered 123 Main Street I
gotcha
US Marshal Service collection agencies
credit bureaus everybody use that serves
all database here's an example from a
real case of what I did
I for that we bought the pizza I went to
the Papa John's
this is a yeah this is Papa John's I
want to pop a joint in the printed out
the receipt new told me right where he
went
I went there grip the kid that have been
adopted
now by the way why are Americans s is
growing
here's why you're even get off the couch
anymore
to go to the form to order a pizza you
can do a rate from your freakin TiVo
I mean which by the way
goes into a database and then I know
what IP address you are connected to
when you order that pizza no trace the
IP and I got you
Papago what from Europe PlayStation Papa
John's from your ps3
okay point of purchase you use these
cards hey if you've got a RM
somebody give me a new york award elves
use a wall berms frequently record you
get a half of this law for bread 3
three sets of other sinn forty cents or
for those
I have you retire buying history what
does this tell me about you
told me you know of that there was a the
a
chain called Stop & Shop where they try
to so you're buying history HMOs
how much beer you buying how much very
few you buy
how much cigarettes you buy there was
such an opera they couldn't do it
but obnoxiously and they were shameless
about it the court is reporting service
at the insult to the HMOs
smart trackers
tractors tractors tractors baby trackers
the holy grail of investigators
binding you where are you now where were
you last week
who were you there with who your friends
a million ways to do it
know this is old school Windows every
time you use Windows
reports back to the mothership is this
unauthorized copy
in addition to reporting whether or not
it's an authorized copy it says
bob's copy connected through this IP
address
Apple Store and iTunes Windows Media
Player
every time you log in anywhere I know
where you are
Internet Explorer all the bros activated
software phone so
use Microsoft Word it connects to the
mothership every time you open it up
even we even when connects to the we
serve
ci vuole TV cable reports your activity
what you're watching what you doing on
star know by the way
on star can now be turned on with the
war
and the microphone even a few don't have
on store
taken activated remotely activate the
microphone remotely
and bug you core if there's a war just
letting you know
reporter microphone EZ Pass I pass on
pass MetroCard
passenger list courtship records digital
license plate readers
big big big deal unique serial numbers
CD and DVD burner signatures GPS
satellites the new ones the galileo
satellites are gonna be used by the
European countries report your location
within six freakin inches
I can tell not just what side of the
street you're on but what
chair you're sitting at a table that's
literally
sure literature
check-ins chechans or the investigators
best friend
I feel very comfortable telling you
about this because you know it's you not
gonna stop
I'm at Bob's pizzeria home at the movie
theater
I'm at the 7-11 who cares
now I care special from trying to find
out how you spend your day where I can
go
grab you and pick up surveillance on you
because I
washed you when you're in that yellow
light well I don't vote checking
thank you very much go over there and
watch why
why do you really think that your
friends are watching your feet going
hey barbs over there let me go hang out
with a are you that freakin lonely
you wanna see your friend say people up
it's gonna slice a pizza
check-ins really you want to be the
mayor
over bowling alley the
I mean how shared is that
how many people in here suck it up and
tell
how many people here been a mayor of
summer
your hands are going up shame on you
you look like a really nice person I
would spend time with you
don't do that stole
mayor what we had a mayor of
you not gonna tell me all your the
Hershey shaker no
okay well if you not gonna tell me
don't do it again you're forgiven
cell phone cellphone cellphone cellphone
cell phones
listen last year according to some
information just obtained
2011 want point 3
million 1.3 million
law-enforcement requests for cell phone
data
this is not wiretaps not worktops I can
promise you there are not 1.3 million
wiretaps not even not even in the book
would there be 1.3 million wiretaps this
is mostly
location data where's this guy who's the
word
where's this guy was the word where was
he last month
before we knew one of to put a guy on
him
retroactive surveillance
do
cell phones I can follow you through GPS
I can follow you through skyhook I can
follow you through enhanced skyhook
which is what I call on p2p
I could follow you through pinging I can
follow you through setting up a trigger
fish
e911 constantly goes back and forth
wifi activity from your phone smartphone
activity
all these things tomei exactly where you
are
exactly and I want to tell you the phone
companies
keep tower information to keep a
location information
for between 18 months and seven years
depending on the character
carrier if I wanna know everywhere you
war
every minute of your life last year
before I even knew I cared about you
before I even knew your name
subpoena warm grand jury subpoena
I know every where you are your entire
life
show appearance I really know the start
of this
I'll tell you after I demonstrated how
many people in this room
never never turn off their cell phone
okay look around it's more than half a
real give you a heads up
give you handsome more than half for the
room seventy-seven percent of all
Americans never turn off their
cellphones
the plug it in to charge up the table
plug it in to charge it they take it
with them
holy crop
you will never turn off your cell for
what do you think you're gonna miss at
three o'clock in the morning
up paying from Jesus I'm
and I'm Jewish I said
skyhook if GPS doesn't work skyhook
has 55 million data points where knows
if you two hundred meters from this
location
400 meters from this location you're
there
google has a similar products and
they're doing this p2p stuff now
i guess i doing this like a speed freak
if I know where you are I know what you
doing
because every board every store every
house everything is GPS code I can look
at your GPS location
I can say your in front of twinkies Boom
Boom Room
you're at the movie theater you are at
an abortion clinic
you are a demonstration in Yukari Park
you or at the gun range
whatever I know what's there was every
location is geocoding
use your GPS you press the button find
me the New Years gas station
how do you think knows that you think it
starts calling around on the phone
it's got everything located in there
so I know parking lot movie theater ball
are
Bob's house everything
behavior patterns associate computer or
a bar every night of the week
hey do tells me something about you if
you're going to
a doctor every week I know you have a
medical problem
or you taking someone who does and I can
check to see
is another cell phone going with you
it's that advanced
there's a product called rabbi that a
friend of mine in israel developed
anne's
twice the guys a call that Rabbi which
stands for
okay where where is it somewhere
although you thank you I track meet and
assist apparently
relationship in activity analysis and
behavior informant rabbi
by looking at what you've done in who
you've done it with I can tell who
you're meeting with
whose important to you I can see if you
are known associate of criminals
I can tell what results from your
activities
I'm not gonna go through this because
the clock is ticking but it tells me
know by the way
here is from an actual subpoena his
assault our response
it tells me down to 25 feet
if you look at that where you are
sometimes it tells me you're on the spot
again Google p2p Google p2p this is
gonna be a game changer this in the new
GPS satellites and everybody using
smartphones
appears a here's a this is sold to
private industry
now I'm not going to get up here a very
upfront about you
about this I'm not telling you the best
stuff I know
for two reasons for civil the publicly
available stuff is friggin of
and I'm I believe making my point
and second of all of course there are
bad people out there that the stuff
does deserve to be targeted a and it's
not my place I'm not
Julian assault charge Hui to talk about
some other time
I'll I don't believe in what doing the
Sarge is doing
I believe in freedom of information
that's for damn sure but I don't believe
that I have a right to take secret
information or
law enforcement information and decide
myself guess what
so I don't discuss that I think that's
wrong I think it's bad
by the way I do think Julian assigned
rate those two women so that puts a
membership was too
arm but this is an example of what's out
there that's used by law enforcement
not only does it suck in everything your
IP
contacts your email your profile
your social networking contacts but it
builds a profile of you
and it can follow if it knows you using
two or three froze it identifies
listen you have a regular phone and you
have a drop for
everywhere your regular phone here's
including three o'clock in the morning
her drop phones
she is it possible bob is using a second
phone I don't know about
Kamau so this analyzes that it finds
that second phone
and it and it grabs the data American
group today
after the shock and here multiple
headphones multiple systems locations
whatever
the funny thing is the US government
gives this stuff lol
and in the case a meal on it was turned
against them
historic data I'm gonna keep zipping
through this but
let me just tell you I can find out
without breaking a sweat
everywhere you go everybody who spent
time with everything you like to do
everywhere you do it and who you do it
with just from yourself
okay part of the show you a whole lotta
slides that's the bottom line
and I'm here's
you by the way here's what I've the
programs being
tested were reports locations and SIM
cards in activities
and everything the beta test name of the
program is honest to god guilt by
association
and years link analysis here's a
criminal conspiracy
you know who are the central guy's we
know that that guy's a bad guy main bad
guy everybody goes to
and so on and so forth guys I'm not
telling you anything you couldn't find
out
if you care to do so but is going on
Google
a lot of these examples because I knew
what to look for
I when I went right to the company's web
sites I will try to Google Voice up this
although
no no this is a secret now
gonna do this really relations arm
me a lot there's an example that are
given me know about me log
what there was a terrorist
or more Abu Bakkar large terrace real
terrorist
we're not going to get into that see I
thought it was a terrorist
so they sent 26 guys to Milan and a
snatch them up
and they did what's called an
extraordinary rendition which shows
a euphemism for putting a bag over his
head taping a mop and shipping them to a
country
where we won't torture I'm but they will
and in this case they ship them to Egypt
where was tortured horribly
homosexual rape beatings burnings
whatever
for a few years there's actually
a book on a really really good we're not
an opinionated left-wing book a book
that
even i think is good call the a
kidnapping in milan which I urge you to
read
arm and then after three years have been
tortured
both the egyptians and the CIA agents
who were observing the torture
for good partner said her hoops
and they put a bag on a plane and they
put it back to me a lot
arm where the prosecutor was a pretty
good guy pretty good cop
a anti-mafia prosecutor by the name of
the
bruno magli says we have to identify
these guys
so here's what he did
that by the way is from an actual
surveillance thats Omar Abu Bakkar
who kinda looks like somebody I wanna
rendition if I was in that
for a month don't judge people by looks
so here's what happened
they figure it out where he was
kidnapped
they knew where he was kidnapped us
there were two witnesses to the
kidnapping
who went to the police so they want to
the cell towers
using information by the way that have
been giving to them
by the CIA for the terrorism work
and they grabbed all all the
connections now for those of you who are
tech weenies our phone weenies
or phone phreaks is Captain Crunch in
the room for example
you know that GSM cell phone has two
things
that has a hardwired code which is
randomly called either and yes earner an
meid
or an IMEI depending on who you're
asking and it hurts
a SIM card both these things are
absolutely unique
no phone has that hardware ID
no phone has that SIM card ID and
together
they are super super unique so they went
and they identified all the SIM cards
and all the hardware ideas in the
location
and they found people who met a certain
profile
they warrant Ian the area normally
they didn't live in the area there some
numbers and their
hi mera whatever were there at nine they
did the most basic analysis and i want
to tell you
the key question for analysts to ask
years
what does X look like what is a
terrorist look like
what is a kidnapper look like what is a
money launderer look like
and once you figure out the profile then
you go out to big data to the datasets
when you find everything that matches
that more often than not you right
more from the night you're right power
for a drug dealer for one for money
order
today if I have the right analyst and
the right
general profile I can find drug deals I
can find money orders
I can find terrorist just by pressing a
button there is
an updated
so they said what with the kidnappers
look like well they would look like
people
who I'm
were in the area at the time of the
kidnapping
then checking back we would see that
they were there
intermittently we would also see that
they
came together meaning four-man team does
the snatch
four-man team does the recount in
advance so on and so forth
they knew what to look for somebody who
SIM card is there
all day because they're running a store
working in the hotel
by the way the best tower that they used
was on the roof other
don't know tell their I'll the profile
the profile was X they figure out the
profile
and they found 3
for 5 six groups have cell phones
wanted the cell phones they knew
because this anti-terrorism prosecutor
was talking to the owner that so far on
a regular basis
he was the CIA station chief
so they were haha and things started
falling apart from there
11 Sims work in the snatch location
were in cannot contact with six sermons
at
a blocking location on the a4
another three sermons were
shared serbs in the months before the
abduction 20 service had been a regular
frequent contact
with the other they were able to discern
patterns
here is by the way I want actually got
copies of the court file
here is an actual thing from the court
for these are people talking to other
people in the target serbs
and they were able to track these
sermons
extrapolating out from known people
including Bob lady the CIA station chief
and they were able to identify
for example three other people now he
gets worse by the way
after the kidnapping the snatch team in
the blocking team dispersed
they dispersed by getting together at
the same hotels
by checking in using credit cards
that we're all build to the same PO Box
where
correct gets worse
the credit cards the first 13 digits of
the credit cards were
Cirque one show all
causes me pain as an investigator
so eventually they were able to build
these profiles they were able to
identify everybody
this one goes to this hotel the Hilton
talk so that's all for
by the way they found that a bunch of
the CIA teams were shacking up
this girl in the top checking in with
this guy so it's over
which busted up two marriages by the way
when the indictment came out
no no that's really to read the book
really fascinating
and they were able to alternately that's
the indictment
20 your wits not Bravo its what a god
damn shame because these are
for the most part I've looked into the
background of these people these people
who are really good americans real
patriots
join the CIO you don't get paid real
well in the CIA I can tell you that
if you work for the government work for
private sector I get paid five times
what these guys do and they
work 87 times harder than I do in their
room ninety seven times as much dangers
are
and they're mostly doing it for american
across the kit get a private sector job
if they wanna go and become what's
called red cards
they get five times as much money I mean
literally five times as much more
arm these are these are good people it's
not a problem
so what
kiss my us
these are not not since I know some of
these people udall
they were foolish but they are not know
it is by the way
I'm the only one in this room who
actually was a Nazi owner
and Court notes don't tell me about
what's okay
arm unfortunately
these twenty-six people were poor I
don't was don't
entirely through electronic means
if this can be done to these guys
emergent your daily life
and people do it not because they want
to invade your privacy
they want to sell you stuff things are
to the point now where you are walking
down the aisle
you stop in a supermarket and you look
at a display of canned peaches
on your phone will pop up ocupado for
certain brand of canned peaches
to try to get you to buy those peaches
and if you in fact
do by those peaches which will be
confirmed because
you're gonna probably be using your so
far as the payment device but
for now using your credit card as a
payment device
Apple gets a credit or Android slash
Google it's a crime
or and markets a credit you're walking
into a
steakhouse on your four-part such top
to go to Bob's Tecos his 33 percent of
for fried steak house back into their go
to books to the right
33 percent of that is coming
has come will becoming more more MORE
it's not because they want to invade
your privacy they want to sell you stuff
and so it's so in tensely accurate
an intensely all-inclusive that these
private companies which by the way
you have no control over no control
whatsoever
retail store there is a
drug deal a bona fide Batman drug dealer
who was caught in large part because the
FBI put a bumblebee percy GPS tracking
device
on its core so his attorney
or use all the way up to the Supreme
Court this is an invasion of privacy
they should have had a war Supreme Court
agrees this guy's
convictions thrown out he has to be
retried
arm FBI said no problem
would use use his GPS data from a straw
votes
same exact evidence even more detailed
they got rid of three thousand GPS
bumper beepers
I know they're using 30 million software
it's not because the FBI wants the
tracking it's because people want to
sell you stuff
here years mobile location tracking
I want to tell you this is a
commercially available service
this is sold right now to bail bondsman
to private investigators
if I want your cell phone paint hey
a call my office I speak to cloris I say
clear solution
I watched this tale call
blah blah blah going to tell you the
name of the company but
you guys could Google this text them
pull it up right over their website like
I did
but it's not my job to tell you arm
pinging is now a commercial service I
could find out where your cell phone is
right now
ten years ago maybe the the NSA could do
it
now any smoke with an account to do it
and this is not the only one
had they can track you down to within 50
meters
within 30 seconds all within a hundred
meters within 10 seconds
and here by the way this is a true story
was contacted by our investigator in
Dallas who said we were hired by a
family
this girl three nights ago went out to
get pizza
for her for her job crew
a went to the pizzeria they wouldn't
take your credit card she went to a
cash machine took out all 100 books we
know we've got her
ATM card usage in the photo from the
cash machine and she's disappeared
so we plan to soften this is the actual
pinga so for that I did
this is my pic and we found her car and
they went there they found her dead in
the core
sale she it was a 106 degrees in the car
she had stopped a couple beers in the
car fell asleep in the car
got cooked and she died but it would've
been days before the founder and
can even imagine in a parked car in
Dallas
where the a the engine run outta gas and
there was no
AC what she would have been like but we
felt
and and i've use ping in for a lot a
case and it's an invaluable tool
and anybody can do eiffel
Apple iPhone reports every damn thing
about you
who you talk to where you are what you
buy
who you text who you email
where you eat what movies you're
interested in searching for
properties everything and they're doing
it for one reason
I air this is not Photoshop
I hear iPhone prepared hi ed
I you're screwed no
I mean up also okay are smart enough to
put up the
just so you know or your communications
with Siri
saved Safari let you strip a Reds
but reports the URL stay up again like
Google equipped to search
redoing your big favor stripping arent
no no no
then what other people to be able to
sell you it's they want to be able to
say to advertise anybody using Safari
the only way you can put in a rather
mister us
new privacy policy let sample collected
share iPhone users
precise locations why
not because cue think the guys name
whoever it was that took over from Steve
Jobs
because he cares where you are 3 o'clock
in the morning but because he wants to
sell your stuff
cell phone as a loyalty card payment
device barcode reader
store guide eBay or Amazon portal
manufacturer sinking retail object
recognition Google Goggles
all data manufacturer locator beacon
never turned off
these pacts are standard on everybody's
phone
and it gives me your life
I'm gonna switch through the superfast
I'll day we're gonna talk no
we're gonna I mean I don't do I really
need to cover with GPS does
and there is a constant implementation
it everything now
again GPS arm
I mean it's so easy in its so simple
that there's an app
that you could put in a ball or in
Dallas
I don't want to or not excuse me you can
put in a location in Dallas
and it will suck down how many girls
there are around you where you can go
and stalk
this has been polled
oh and this is the USA versus Antoine
Jones
Google that look at it understated
now market
hope why I'm runnin over I am gonna tell
you
the by the way my favorite one right
there
is the huge woman with the diaper and
the intent on
if you if you're just looking for one I
will tell you that
every subscription every eight
hundred-number call every product survey
every
product resolution registration
every credit card usage every log in
every website visit
every check in every like every friend
everything is used to define you down
to a unique person and figure what you
pay money for
your likes or dislikes your habits your
hobbies your religion your politics
your sexual orientation everything
if I buy if i subscribe to Wine
Spectator
I'm interested in wartime god I just I'm
interested in God's
he I'm a Jewish guy pas
i'm HIV-positive I mean every little
thing about you can be defined
now and they have more getting worse
that they sell
I mean I wish I could go into this a
little more gonna do this like a speed
freak now
but there are primarily to companies in
for USA
an axiom AC Xion that have
billions of records tens of billions of
records on
your major income levels home value your
health your hobbies
your ethnicity the value of your home
your job to
your household income your date of birth
your discretionary
spending and they sell
marketing lists suffering seniors only
people with cancer
this specific marketing to those people
all these burglaries gamblers over the
age of 55
axiom axiom posed together direct-mail
polls networks web sites emails displays
your mobile phone activity your text
activity your social networking activity
everything into one file about you
a neighbor 132 million unique files on
Americans
the pole and how many friends you have
how many sites you visit Facebook
Linkedin MySpace
Twitter followers social activity
segments
like a few like something
how much you spend your income your race
your religion
do you have an allergy do you have
arthritis you have diabetes
do you eat organic food are you a senior
are you interested in or its flying
computers celebrities
how many kids you have how old they are
you divorced are you a newlywed
and so on and so forth may put them
together in lists
these people know more about you on any
given day than the FBI
the CIA the KGB your own mother
are you with the glass
if I come to you and I say I've gotta go
I am investigating
he's a subscriber to soldier of fortune
magazine
American rifleman the washington times
he purchased the force a reason
is a registered Republican and is listed
in focus USA's
Christian donor's list which I could
determine about somebody pretty damn
easily
what can you tell me about this person
is that like thing on too tight
I'll tell you what it owes me he's all
probably
but you know he's a goner he's a
right-winger
his well that's for damn sure he's a
republican
and he's a believing christian a reason
to Christian politics
aka second guy
Village Voice High Times Magazine cap
fancier
reads known charm ski Green Party
contributed to the United Jewish appeal
the gay men's health crisis by the way
this is a real profile
an American friends a peace now what do
you know about him
he is on left wing he is on left wing
gay Jewish guy probably
pot smoker left-wing pot-smoking gay
Jewish guy
right now by the way I just just
just was that you
what's new now by the way I i just i
just 10
I'm not gay or leftward arm
not not not that there's anything wrong
with her
I love that light not that there's
anything
rumored okay know by the way the way
that you tell that this guy is gay just
for
those if you want to go into
investigations has nothing to do
with the with the gay men's health
crisis you say no
any literature that's only two with
databases
47 times easier you can download all of
this information
and get the same thing on your computer
almost immediately
lists cross referencing matching
can all be done in one place hiking goal
to you about marketing
I can go to your Facebook profile I can
go to your Apple profile
I can go to your myspace profile I can
go to what Google has on you
and determine this right away
psychographic micro targeting the big
sort
I can take stock in extrapolate out the
one example that I like to give urs
when VW wanted to introduce the Beagle
it had been a hold of a production for
so long
that they didn't even have must have
prior owners at work today a
so after the first year they surveyed
like man I mean the Germans are good at
it they surveyed like made
all of the VW orders and they found
every characteristic they could
are they male female white black up
Democrat Republican a income level
whatever
and they found that people who owned a
cat
any chunky peanut butter were three
times as likely to buy a Volkswagen
Beetle
so they bought up the peanut butter or a
list
and the catalysts and they cross
reference num
their mark in like hell to everybody who
showed up are both worse than this all
the time oxford's
this is not a joke this is really true
this is a marketing study
for example last
last election role but all the guys on
the democratic side figure out
butter white wine Fig Newtons fruit
filled cookies
Red Lobster drive a Volvo yoga you're
much more inclined to be a Hillary voter
re okay what up and
do you fit that profile group
horribly olive oil bare naked granola
lot to use the goat cheese cake factory
Panera and Starbucks Barack Obama
bourbon stuffed crust pizza
fiber one Cobb
not my survey parties for truckers BMW
known ago I'm
John McKay I know they would take these
lists and they would
proselytize the it is an amazing amazing
thing
amazing amazing are
don't have more time I now want to go
to this is an example of an intrusive
profile I no wanna go to campus cameras
are really really important
I'm almost certainly going to run a
couple minutes or
over but let's try not to this is this
area
right now 1998 few cameras
2003 2008
today today there are over 3,000 cameras
and the one square mile around Bryant
Park 3,000 jobs
the big thing is
accuracy and and
and resolution of the cameras facial
recognition
license plate recognition and analytics
Analytics is a big
here is Obama's inauguration here is
Obama's inauguration here is Obama's
inauguration that's how close you can
get
from that to that using something called
GigaPan
from that you can get to that
that or that I could take a picture this
room
a.m. with a high resolution GigaPan
camera
and have enough to ID everybody in your
let me give you an example
watch the bouncing thing this is called
GigaPan you can go to the website do
this yourself
GigaPan .co zooming in unfortunately I
was doing this on all swole Mac so
me take a second
just want you to see that I wasn't
making up these
these pictures now by the way I picked
these two guys right here as my file
photo
because they look kinda like mafia
Shorai with the hat
and the glasses was doing a job with the
secret service and he says
what's the story is about I said good
they were kinda creepy I want to use
them for
facial recognition example he says the
whirring
congress identification pertz so just so
you know these are your representatives
looking looking like would rely Carlo
Gambino
right so just so you know from
that to that that's where cameras are
right now perfect example was warned
1967 the first camera thirty years later
there are only five hundred campers 2008
4.2 million community safety cameras
it's estimated that you walk down the
street in London from point A to point B
no matter what your trip is your
shoulders two hundred apps drones
these guys before talked about drones
they don't know to have a
anywhere you wanna drone we can have
hydro helicopter drones
perpetual drones
little drawings that the police
department control that they can keep in
the
trying to their core drones there are
cyborgs that is a real more up here we
go
okay I hope you know what you doing no
no don't sit here
don't sit here goal go over there I'm
flying around in first make sure you
don't kill anyone and they will use the
video
cyborg drones this is a
real more that they put a controller in
a camera
devil ray when this thing needs to
recharge
it throws out two wires put it on a high
tension wire
subset of and flies a word a
experimental well
land
I coal mine invading your privacy but I
don't want to
in Bajur cranium
there are things that you can carry
around in a briefcase if you're on the
cover
open it all up prop it up and it takes
off in 40
know that's real NYPD right now has a
camera that's good enough
to from two miles away so far enough
where you can even
here the chopper look inside a car in
see what's going on they use that there
was a hostage standoff
they didn't know what happened with the
guy in the car the Aragon
so they brought out the chopper in the
zoomed in on the car
by the way at night they were able to do
it and they saw that the guy had shot
himself so they
move the issue team SWAT team and pull
them out of the car and he was
he was dead here's an example this is
just a couple weeks ago from Israel how
your own paper
israel was in the forefront to these
tiny tiny little drones platoon level
drones that they can to go with them
this is designed to look like a bird sir
can be used covertly
there it is right there there it is the
guy controlling and fly
by the way
never underestimate stupid paranoia
a Middle Eastern governments the turks
heard about these birds
and they started shooting real birds
migrating from Israel
and checking them for cameras and this
is an actual screenshot from Turkish TV
said I feel sorry for this little birdie
but
rachel s the No Nestle Waters to the
Sharks
disturbing video number one micro air
vehicles
or am a beast will play an important
role in future warfare
the urban battlefield calls for tools to
increase the warfighters
situational awareness the capacity to
engage rapidly
precisely and with minimal collateral
damage
and navies will be integrated in the
future Air Force layered sensing systems
the system's maybe air-dropped forehand
launched
depending on the mission requirements
that's really all you know
and communes the small size M a beast
allows them to be hidden in plain sight
once in place
and then a peek into a low-powered
extended surveillance mode
for missions lasting day swat weeks this
may require the in maybe to harvest
energy from environmental sources
such as sunlight or wind or from
man-made sources
such as power lines in vibrating
machinery which we may be limited
surroundings
and operate undetected and maybe so use
micro sensors in microprocessor
technology
to navigate track targets through a
complicated terrain
such as urban areas 0
and there may be operating in urban
terrain well have more chill the
challenges than larger you a beast
obstructions can cause wind gusts even
on a calm day
one way to overcome this is to learn
from examples in nature
venues flapping wings to fly
sensing an oncoming gust feedback
control directs the wings to flap
asymmetrically
compensating for the win small size an
agile flight will enable am a beast
to covertly and dislocations
inaccessible by traditional means have
aerial surveillance
and navies will use new forms navigation
such as a vision-based technique called
optic flow
this system remains robust when
traditional methods
such as GPS are unavailable multiple
anywhere you get the point and that is a
legitimate thing
arm this video presents tanks can try
you know what that's just up a drone
flying over
know by the way whoever said there's X
number of drones has no clue
the US Army is giving way hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds
have surplus drones to police forces
police forces using River
Texas I have an office in Roma Texas
Texas even has texas police
not the military even as a drawn with a
grenade launcher
a this is an unmanned vehicle with
Hellfire missiles
this is a commercial drone every
military or government drawn out there
there or somewhere between three to turn
commercial drones is an actual
commercial drone
these are guys using drones has
hobbyists when I was a kid launching
rockets
know people using drones as hobbyists
here's another guy
a hobbyist guy
doing a ski job this is a Sports
Illustrated drone
Sports Illustrated magazine has its own
drawn
to follow performs that is an actual
DRO that is the drone use or before
that is an actual DRO there is an actual
DRO
okay
there's something called
proof-of-concept
proving how frickin
easy it is for anybody who want no I use
drones all the terms investigated 0
a private investigator I use drones
I don't have the NSA's budget here's a
guy his cat died
he loved his can he loved his care he
loved rooms
she turned is dead can't into a drone
I'm not making this up
go to the Internet researcher no
photoshop
no bullshit a dead cat flying around the
street that's how easy it is
no this is just
just the US Air Force this is their
I a a declassified
configure the word for a sec this is the
declassified memo from the US Air Force
yet now five minutes left now you lower
the life this is the declassified map
all drone bases in the United States
I just
good I mean
somebody purposely shop
what you care about the time because
listen
from here word that we have in our
downstairs so I am only going to
continue for five more minutes
because we have a whole hour in a room
downstairs
I'll it's it's a let me just tell you
very quickly whether putting the smack
on
I am the vice president and educational
chairman
up the society professional
investigators this is the president here
in addition to having a Q&A downstairs
I very much i'm looking to recruit from
this group
members in society professional
investigators if you are an investigator
your law enforcement officer if you are
security professional
if you are in a forensic field if you
feel that you would
Syrian in a investigative seles law
enforcement organization
we have monthly meetings dinner meetings
the membership fees are
very very cheap I feel comfortable
telling you about this was for support a
great group
and I'm not showing for myself if you're
interested in this group come up to us
I would love to get 5 to new members
from this group a specially especially
if you are an IT security person
you work with a facility or you work
with law enforcement if you bridge the
gap between what I do and computers
we want you so come and talk to us in
the room
if you have questions you wanna ask or
you wanna talk to me privately Abreu so
whatever
come downstairs also I'm gonna do this
like a speed freak
I want to show you
analytics cameras
can determine what you're doing no
cameras can determine cameras can
determine what you doing
where you doing it for example it knows
this person asserting
this person is he doing this person is
playing
the funny thing is this is a schoolyard
but the product was developed by people
for prisons
so thanks this kid is making a break for
no no that's really true this is a
really heard from security magazine
facial recognition
every
state driver's license a
repository Department motor vehicles in
New York dps in Texas
is taking driver's license photos and
comparing them to mug shots
if you come in you apply for driver's
license you're a wanted person
you may not make it to the DMV are you
think the RBI is a pain in the ass now
way it'll real-world
Israel allegedly did a hit
in Dubai on a hamas member they sent to
hit team
Dubai little Dubai
was able to take airport cameras hotel
cameras
grab everybody and compare them to
passport photos
this is the killer this is the passport
photo
old I we don't have time for the but
let me tell you that even RI have the
ability to use facial recognition
it's that simple no when I was looking
to match MySpace pages
to sexual predators I was able to do it
when I was looking to merge Illinois
deadbeat dad to MySpace and Facebook
pages
I was able to do it sex offenders sex
offender this was the easiest when this
guy
had the biggest balls you've ever seen
he used
his sexual offender booking photo ices
myspace for
not making it up
you can look up to the senior article
when I when are revealed this
wearing a disguise doesn't help
facial recognition on only 53
you can enhance a photo no facial
recognition
only a portion of your face is now
possible
even five percent knows analytics
I mean for me it should be a search but
for everybody
where your nose is on your face the
angle
this that it's possible just from a
nosedive ID somebody
I know there's a joke in there somewhere
but whatever
gate yeah this guy well what no I
understand
okay gait recognition how you walk
if you believe up it knows that's bob's
bebop
okay I'm getting car I just wanna go to
one thing