that turn the DUI DWI talk over to Alex
and Josh take away gonna sit here I'm
gonna work okay
ob this is this talk originals gonna
given by
was going to be given by two other
people and it seemed to be that well
they have jobs and such in and people
leaned on them to not give the talk
so I Josh was volunteered to give
the police law enforcement side in I was
asked to give the legal side but I've
decided that
I warm instead present anonymously
so that way no one knows who I am
were here
your machine make it go up there we go
one screen dual no that's nice creamy
yes by alright
anyway my anonymous partner and I
Alex and me
Josh up this is not our employers
opinions
this is not our opinions this is this is
factual
but not our opinions all pretty much
we're going to talk about his factual
Miami ordered we're gonna be doing is
explaining
DWI DUI we're gonna be talking about
what happens during
pre arrest arrest but after a rest
mostly jokes
we're gonna be talking about what
happens how it happens physiological
physically psychologically also two
different things
this is not how do I beat this is
what's going to happen to me what should
I be afraid of
because we're gonna scare you straight
forgave that's the way you are
no offense intended so
we don't care about your DUI case honest
I
don't give a crap okay if you have a DUI
case
because you drink and drive you're an
idiot
if you have a DUI case because you were
hopped up on adderall and you like but
it was now call
you're an idiot if you have a DUI case
because it's DUI driving under the
influence not driving wall
drunk because you had cocaine heroin
speed
speedball crushed adderall snorted to
your ass whatever
you're an idiot don't drink and drive
don't rock and drive hell have you
probably shouldn't drive but that's
another story
this is our agenda
will go over as we go along gee this is
tough
Alex
you really want me to go over the agenda
or the other text sorry it's green on
the screen we didn't realize we do this
yours
your mission
well as you can robot is gonna rope
as you can see that is my system font in
noise people greatly
actually people try to pawn my machine
just to change the font
but you're not man enough to put on his
machine
person
our furry enough up enough
puppet with the first enough promise I
can't see the screen
myself as always
this is not going to be this is not yes
for lawyers used
would
go to slideshow
if you're running Windows details
details
you know what fuck it you guys have to
deal with yellow okay
arm my part of this Josh you're not
presenting anonymously
arm
I'm gonna go through the basics a
criminal on the United States
arm what does it take to go from what
does it take for a law enforcement
officer to legally
stop you arrest you convict you
arm the
three standards by which they have to be
able to stop you is article will
suspicion that you i've
you are the on acting
at you're committing a crime are
they can stop you if it is a I some
kinda checkpoint were
everybody gets top where check and it
doesn't have to be for DUI could be
something like
we are checking every car to see if its
toll arm
maximum gonna talk about is are what to
take to convict you
and then what defenses you've got I'll
any one of her biggest things is
in in the american justices mccauley
exclusionary rule which says
it'll evidence is a legally taken from
you it cannot be used against you
general and
what happens when you refuse to submit
to testing and serve how this plays out
between civil law
in criminal law okay
Josh alright
there's a lot of misconceptions
as lot of people going all if you do
this to work if you put this if you do
this if you're happened to drive this
way
don't take that road do this yeah ninety
percent of her bullshit
okay let's be honest here let's talk
about the stuff we got why is the legal
limit
point away as anybody now demeanor would
point to a means
my way presented your blood is actually
alcohol
okay so is there any alcohol in your
blood is any blood in your own home
0.08 tiny little fraction was not get
trashed used to be a list a 10-point
more
20.1 love loaded 2.08
federal highway funds are a lot of that
along with speed limits
a ager drinking things like that okay
but DWI
is the basically like it a point to a
2.1
a pureblood is alcohol and it doesn't
have to be
alcohol member DUI driving under the
influence of what
doesn't friggin matter okay among
cocaine
they can't give me a DUI yes they can
they don't have to have a breathalyzer
Intoxilyzer test
to arrest you were convicted for DUI
they can have
he's really fucked up but they can
actually stop you if your blood is
actually
point 2008 cocaine cos and I think
you'll ever stop
I so
okay let's talk about when you actually
get pulled over very rarely
alright it it's an amazing amount of
cars out there and they're not nearly as
many cops
they're never gonna pull me over yet
your
you're weaving all over the road to go
you know sums wrong with that guy
let's go take a look so
the actual odds of getting pulled over
and arrested are actually
not that high but their high enough to
bet on in Vegas
okay so don't do it think it's one in
20,000
actually gets pulled over and arrested I
wanted two thousand sorry chance getting
pulled over
22 percent chance of actually getting
arrested once you've been pulled over
not let let's talk about alcohol every
drink you take
whether it's a shot one ounce shot
whether it's a glass of wine I think
it's six ounces for lost time
or appear about 12 ounces gives you the
same amount of alcohol I know you've
seen the commercials they all have look
busy with this because this
this is bad if you have one drink to get
drunk
probably not you might be I'm a
lightweight
alright sirs in a job I'm not small okay
trust me
not small and three drinks and I'm going
from
I need to sit down okay some people
drink about a case and they're just fine
that's why they call a passing the bar
up so everybody's different no women
on the whole on average I should say a
drink the same amount as Amanda same or
similar weight
and they'll be more drunk okay it has to
do with the proportion of water and fat
and everything else okay but basically a
woman has
three drinks a man has three drinks in
about the same height weight etcetera
and the woman will be more effectively
drunk less capable
does that make sense and the
is that right wrong it's science sorry
dude is the way it is
okay so if a woman has five drinks in
your five drinks is a guy
and you're both driving down the road
was gonna get pulled over well
probably her sorry that's the way it is
i apologize. there is an actual real
scientific gender gap
okay so that's the misconceptions
that's the the legal ish over the limit
and everything else
all my yellow socks
the reason why we did it was that way I
knew when I was supposed to get up and
talk
so how can a law enforcement officer
first step is
I I long for some officers out there
patrolling doing what they do
they see the driver white do they have
to
what do they have to see our experience
that allows them to legally stop stop
the driver
they have to have I'm they have to have
evidence as in visual evidence that
sis witnesses or suspects a violation of
traffic laws
something as simple simple as at
inspection sticker that's invalid
out-of-date registration a
the a vehicle broken taillight
are something like I see evidence the
way this person's
operating their car our vehicle sorry
vehicles important word
in such a way that gives me a
articulable suspicion
so I just have to be like I have to be
able to put in words based on that long
that one person officers experience in
training
that I believe that person
is is violating the Criminal Code
now are they can do a DUI or other
enforcement checkpoints
this is really interesting will not do
them at ok a few if you live on the east
coast
there are these things called holds if
you live in New Jersey
their everywhere I'm sorry I grew up
there it's like oh
damn lies and one in every corner are
yep moving to the committee you know
moving like that the South alike
why do you have there's worth a toll
booth but I like
so they can picture the computer Cup
there's watchin' stop everyone just
doing a quick I am
NC what are you doing those are both
legal things that allow an officer
to stop the motorist
if all motorists are stopped that's
lawful as well
it has to be some kind of enforcement
checkpoint were checking to see
is your car stolen is they had my
ob this happens a lot in now
certain large motorcycle rallies where
they will check to see if you are
compliant with the vehicle code
I E is net muffler a little too loud
they can stop everyone for that and
while the interacting with the
with the operator to go them someone's a
little drunkie
arm 10 Eve fading
a checkpoint as in you do something and
you violate the vehicle code
to avoid the the checkpoint
bet would be probable cause that you
were doing something wrong
avoiding it is not as an your on a grid
streets and you make you know you make
the appropriate
turns to go to the next block over and
go through that
is avoiding a checkpoint not probable
cause
if you do a u-turn and that is a legal
one that stayed
bad as probable cause that you've done
something wrong and they can turn around
and stop you
now one quick note if the stop is a
legal
if there's somehow we can prove that
on defense counsel and I don't do that
work
job but if defense counsel can argue
that
the stop itself was unlawful there was
no actual
I article suspicion to do the stop we
can
truck they can try to get all the
evidence subsequent had
kicked out against you for the boys
injury right
yeah okay arm
not about DW DWI history in laws
arm the laws pertaining to UW why are
pressed down from the federal level
most states have their own laws but
there's standardize effectively in order
to get
federal highway funds
arm public notices extortion but Adams
in San I'm many parents in new ones as I
can write the slide cuz I think the
generally fairly similar art from
arresting officer must be able to
identify the person operating
and in control the vehicle it does not
require that they are
in are operating the vehicle at that
time email have to identify
I have evidence that you
were both intoxicated and operating a
vehicle and this can be something is
somewhat simple as
you're in the car you're drunk you have
the keys
that's enough evidence to show because
it does not be absolute from
you know philosophical certainty has to
be to get conviction it has to be
beyond a reasonable doubt well if you're
drunk passed out
in the passenger seat of your car and
the keys in the ignition
and your in a country road
no one else in the car how to get there
macular birth Immaculate Conception now
Bigfoot drove my car there
NY secede on the way to the front
come on is it worth big flea okay
on the blest so
I read a buncha cases to figure this out
I practice in pennsylvania so I read
Pennsylvania cases and the interesting
because the second 1a
vehicle arm reading stuff about
conveyance
and other fermented amish in my in my in
the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania
result some argument about is a
is a horse and buggy a vehicle for the
purposes at the Pennsylvania vehicle
code and it turns out it is
because it's some campaigns by which go
on the road but they're all these cases
where people tried to defend
that the I I was driving a train that's
not a vehicle
and some poor schmuck some poor schmuck
law clerk at a church thing I gotta go
argue this
the and Raven 18-page opinion going well
it's got wheels
it moves someone has to operate it
I'm really waiting for the subway one
mic operating a subway while drunk
it's actually happens I now in New York
City by the way it's actually happen
there have been cases have somewhere
operators being drunk
beat like transit police who are cops
real cops
go you've got to be kidding me we break
like you know for
into the station going grab the the
motor the motorman
and go cheese you're drunk as a lord I
mean you know I can
you reek ups vodka or whatever what the
hell egos
eyes not DWI
and they had actually had to take on the
court besides the fact that call for
substitute motorman you know and can
imagine that radio call
yeah I need a subdued motorman 0k yes go
to jail
why he was drunk driving a subway car
with nine cars for 10 to 10 cars
10 cars beloved 800 people
what could go wrong and there's vomit in
okay arm and they have to show the the
third thing after show is that you were
under the influence love a alcohol or
other drug
law enforcement are but prosecution's
case has to prove
all three points all three of these
elements of the crime
to get the conviction its
the basement human a point system I'm
not sure why that's their
sir who broke the slides I implied
consent
there's another rule bad as a part of
the vehicle code
pretty much every state there is what we
call implied consent which is
you consent to be tested when the
officer says
I wish to test you driver's license is a
privilege
when you sign up for one you sign away
some rights
if you don't have a driver's license and
you're driving a car
hectic so what they do is this you
you are if they stop you you have the
right
to turn down the test and we can
sanction you however it's not a criminal
violation
it is a civil violations you have no
rights but you won't go to jail
that this doesn't mean that if you're
hammered get more difficult on refusing
the test
they can convict me that would be
incorrect because
they can use other evidence that says
y'all were messed up
even without the test that has just
another piece of evidence
you're slurring your words your dancing
you're doing whatever else you do when
your back drunk
acting like Alex on yen
love you to church
Josh Europe
okay
so let's talk about our Terms this is
pretty straight for this quick slide its
cool is it good
it's a third presenter alright DUI DWI
driving while intoxicated
just walk away nevermind driving under
the influence driving while intoxicated
we know what that means it doesn't mean
while drunk
it means while under the influence of
something that impairs you make sense
go the the detection process is known as
the SFS tease
the standard field sobriety tests are
standardized field sobriety testing
preliminary breath test is the one they
give you onsite this is different from
the one they give you at the jail
hospital the station the whatever
explain in a minute okay a blood alcohol
level blood alcohol concentration we
understand the AC member .8 or what
point one is where you go
for the guy I turn around by chance by
back click click let's go to hell
lvl our breath breath from the deepest
part long as what they want lvl our
breath because that's where all that our
culture to circulate okay
divided attention test can you pay
attention
hi what's your name now count backwards
from 100
by tens can you do that at the same time
and by the way what's the person on your
left wearing
you know t he fails and he isn't even
drunk or try different
basically can you multitask
okay we all have ADD were probably
awesome that this re: HD NVG and
horizontal vertical gaze nystagmus
follow my finger I got get into that
morning second
and the three phase detection process
will explain that as well as Zack
so these are terms just two nomenclature
georgann
so you get the idea okay so
there's the three phase detection love
you drunk
okay one is the vehicle in motion not
what is a vehicle motion
hopefully going down a straight line if
it's not a straight line
that's a problem then there's the
personal contact the progress going in
the preliminary breath test
so it's a three phase four phase will
nobody expects the Spanish Inquisition
process this is the important part
everything has to be standardized okay
as I go through the three phases
love getting your arrested everything
has to be a standard process standard
procedure
as anybody here ever had to do that for
your data center for anything like that
I so 27001
and in like that right okay lot of
people
understand the idea at least you have to
have a process and procedure you have to
stick to it
if you don't there are penalties saw an
officer says
a.m. by the way Alex the lawyers it has
to be an articulable
reason to pull you over right okay I had
to be able to write
out arce out and the right out why I did
it
and has to be the same every time I mean
it doesn't have to be ice on serb to the
right and the left and the right and the
left
next case right then left now but every
time you have to give a very stable
solid reasoned way what you did what you
did
and you have to follow a fairly solid
formula every time
so I followed vehicle X with license
plate why
SPDC he was swerving all over the road
I determined this wasn't inappropriate
use of the roadway
and a potential violation of the driving
code therefore I pulled the vehicle over
for a license registration and insurance
check and to determine whether was a
problem with the vehicle
next case because the roughly similar
things you explain what they did
but other than that it'll be pretty much
word-for-word it's a standardized
formula
I walked up to the vehicle on the left
hand side the vehicle was
this color was this age was thus make
was this model
I determined this I saw this I saw the
open bottle of vodka in the passenger
seat
ice on leaning out the window puking I
small but comforting meters away
I determined I probably was going to
have to perform the SSD's
okay again when I was a cop there was a
very very simple maxam
they said you can only be a cop in one
circumstance if you can write it
if you can't write it don't fight it
okay
don't get into a fight if you can't read
it out because if you can't write ups
the weekend offender
you're gonna go to jails cow so they're
going to do things in a standardized
fashion
okay that's way and the reason for that
is because basically
you don't standardize it let's say I
rest these first three rows right here
about 10 people are so
and I have report after report after
report after report after report after
report after report
at all in that nice formula the easy to
read
there clearly articulated everything
works and then the
10 person she's appear and she pissed me
off
she just pissed me off I should have
done one behind you but that's okay
she pissed me off and so I didn't even
bother with the SFS tease
I just slower in the back in the car cup
and took me to jail
and her lawyers gonna go really
see the other reports you wrote that
week that month that border that year
sure they are
because that's part of discovery right
okay
and he's gonna say hey you follow this
procedure for him and him
her and her and her and him in her and
him
and you did the procedure her why was
there a personal bias
sexism ageism people -ism
because she's got a red hearses and yeah
we all know those ginger purse people
I think we're gonna walk away from this
one way the judge is gonna go yeah
sorry dude adhere everything's gotta be
the same
make sense everybody okay
so preachers texan different nuances it
changes a bit
changes if it changes a bit you know
we've told Woodson Jersey we are told
in DC but you gotta tell or in the good
old
okay everything's different different
places but the idea is the same it's got
to be consistent
it's gonna be articulated article
articulable
it's gotta be the same way every time
okay
okay vehicle motion or through the
phases pulling you over and going
paid jailed for what you've won tonight
would you like left or door number one
unless in the cop car door number two on
the right side
those your only two choices okay so
vehicle in motion visual cues appeared
operation
he was swerving all over the road okay
with everywhere
that's a visual cue recognition a
description official use
I recognized it was swerving all over
the road okay
again can you articulate it can you
write reinforcement of Use decision a
star vehicle
I pulled up behind him put the lights
and sirens on any stills world all over
the road
that's a reinforcement now if you're
you know nervous in a cup coming up find
republicans light on the
God that thats not gonna get your rest
right lap with its gonna do is likely
over
but that's not an arrest what is an
arrest when I can say is a cop pay
songs working I did this I did this
we're going to this and that
second but in it additive process I'm
adding evidence to the pile
on the ballot this high a probable cause
on the market this high
you go to jail that make sense everybody
all the evidence really talk about right
now is
added latest at it's probably not a
legal term forgive me but
it just keeps adding onto the pile okay
so the first phase
I see a car actin funny and some former
fashion
one couple points there okay we're
adding to the pile
next
we're gonna stop them is he gonna try
and fully
because that'll be fun if he's not going
to sleep he's gonna pull over that's
great that's a normal response
if he pulls over 10 minutes later that's
not normal response
if it pulls over and the people's out
peoples over and pulls up old and I've
seen it happen it's really weird
like like would you make up your mind
that's not a normal response adding to
the pile this is added
is evidence one or more like a Rorschach
test was a normal response
butterfly what's abnormal response monk
killing a cat
with the Lee plated night
okay we'll talk
these are all abnormal or the get Israel
abnormal right here
everything's been reported where is it
being recorded anybody have an idea
what in the your
you can
okay is right it's is being recorded by
dash camera video camera in the cop car
these are many many different models in
the old days there was literally
freaking VHS
camcorder turned upside down bolted the
tripod
public outdoor annual like upset like
bandages your permit lino
Hall okay they've gotten tiny
if you haven't seen hidden cameras
they're amazing and the use them in cop
cars
ominous these limits for you that the
dash cameras are
this big now like literally just hines
ridiculous
okay and the record some other record
the entire shift
some the record lay off the coke
thank you dear that's my fiance
you can see Shrek onions yes get a gauge
anyway
so record it sorry Descamps
descansar tiny you can't see them
sometimes the cameras on the cockpit
cell
ok at his desk and capetown some of them
don't have cameras on the cop
some have a microphone on the cop feeds
the camera
so you're like all I can say anything
way not and they won't hear it on the
camera
thing I need guess what thats called
evidence
route to the police we don't like you
anymore
okay so everything's being recorded
keep your wits about you you
so we got the vehicle stopped we pull
them over he didn't respond
didn't attempt to flee it was a normal
response okay I don't add anything to
the pile right
okay cool I woke up yes officer what can
I do for you
I'll okay he speaking normally not
slurring his words these
normal responses so now making personal
contact right
okay I'm seeing somebody sometimes you
see interesting things
can it be skinny that got a smaller
thereof
you can see that I'll explain it it's a
guy having his hands and handcuffed
behind his back
having a smoke up holding this guy
showed up to work reveals the tattoo
fuck the police hoops
poised on your own petard sir
okay so personal contact i'm talking to
somebody
hello sir how are you today doing
alright
he's drunk okay sir so i'd like your
license registration and insurance gonna
see this please
I don't have mine with me really you
definitely going to jail
cars getting towed let's talk about your
drunkenness for a moment that seriously
it's a personal contact thing I talk to
you I'm take notes what's going on
doesn't really matter what I say
the most was it ever got was for me for
instance using I feel like I'm on reddit
any I only I had a cat
okay so on
its personal contact its what are you
doing how are you doing it what's going
on
I'm taking or the the reactions were
giving me does that make sense
everybody I'm not really hearing what
you're saying I mean like here in terms
of
is learning issue the you know doing the
other done I don't want to get arrested
is there something we can work out here
two points know that bottom
to Wednesday additive evidence that they
were adding evidence the pile
I'm gonna stop by the way arm
challenge questions serve you been
drinking tonight
sir have you been drinking 29 not deny
sir when was last time you were drinking
today
he just said hi would you take me to
jail please
okay so basically if you get stopped by
an officer
and he says sir if you've been drinking
what he say
well okay are you gonna lie the officer
as we don't do that
sirs will officer I'd
you're gonna ask me questions to get
yelled at me I'm going to take the fifth
I'm not actually joking you not allowed
to admit guilt alright
yet heard about the Fifth Amendment
rights go talk to me about the really
nice people
okay on you go did I'm gonna take the
is gonna be like a fifth wide
but seriously don't admit guilt honest
to god because if you admit you're just
given up
alright making work for his money making
work for a salary okay
believe you're drunk you will get you
this is not a talker how to
beat this you're not going to alright
don't try and beat please seriously I
don't want you driving on the road
because you'll get me in your room here
alright the scalping my ass is not gonna
make my hair any better
don't be drunk drivers Thomas alright
but
everything you do when I have contact
with you is a clue
everything if you admit to drinking
that's not a clue that a slam dunk book
will leave it alone for now alright
personal contact pre exit interview
this is you may be okay I might let you
go but I might not
pay okay so what's your middle name
again sir which
all home dude in
not a good answer ask a question
simultaneously trying to distract
this is not a full metal jacket thing or
do you think I am
you know and ask three questions and
whatever you answer your at
okay this is getting a couple questions
you multitask and you track
okay are looking for is it Asian
a a you not drop your stone
right yes okay
am I going to proceed with an SF St an
actual test standard field sobriety test
I'm gonna go do just to dry
okay so let's say we go to the standard
field sobriety test as
this is I think you're drunk let's do
some testing
at the car let's have a little chat so
what are the tests there various tests
that actually get
combined this three main tests and I can
add a little difficulty to them you know
challenge tests alright so there's the
three-test
the second but then there's the additive
pieces and when I talk with Dad
evidence added is the test can you stand
on one leg
while counting backwards from 100 by
twelves
can you walk down the straight lines
were gonna walk back to walk in turn
test
wall reciting the alphabet backwards
again
what we doing are we actually seeing if
you can walk no
I'm seeing you can multitask can you
multitask without falling over and smack
your ad on the ground
can you answer me effectively can you
track can you
focus can you follow instructions
Minister
okay
I'm sorry something incredibly important
is backed up left arrow
try again and more
right our
who
not cool most after
mousepad known to mankind and use the
keyword
world here yeah okay let
slideshow area okay
shush yes coming to insist upon
he does that just to piss people off
miss the first lecture
alright here right here are you on
medication sir
do you have my problems are you nervous
I want to be nervous it's called you
nervous
take a break school why because when you
go to court
and you've got a DUI lawyer and dollars
a day you was on medication
uses prescription from the team doctor I
have acted a prescription
okay you can't do that if he asked you
on medication use and no one
okay his ruling out literally things you
can do in court
up front so he goes even medication
I'm high on life sir that's a joke
but are you nervous this this is
here you gotta good man like to but I on
in
I we went with the baton and you look
like that kinda you probably don't say
that
so I mean yes I'm nervous yes I'm a
little scared
yes weird for me can can we talk about
this you know in a minute
weekend I'm hard of hearing can you
repeat the questions until I can track
them because I'm drunk off my ass
problems that last part again don't
admit you're
okay fifth amendment please seriously
RXL arm
challenge questions do you have my
problems are you on medication
I'll cold you know
I mean no be honest if you have a cold
in your on cold meds tell him
it's a legitimate thing if he goes
dude you're not fit to drive I didn't
realize officer
this cold medication is something I've
tried before woozy
would you mind if I called a friend to
come get me who
we're doing a lot better now than you
had
15g and he's at Alex's room party last
night
you're probably after heart okay
so again don't try to beat it but if you
get home safely without getting a ticket
for going to jail
it's always a nice one alright
three test battery these are three big
tests right these have been proven
and and tested in court a billion times
you get the HGN the weapon the OLS
okay that's the horizontal gaze
nystagmus
the finger in from the eyes follow my
finger the walk in turn
and the one like it stands okay so
well let's dance apologize so what are
they for
the horizontal gaze nystagmus is a
physiological tests that the second but
the walk in turn
this is the one where they go hey I want
to stand up do not move until I give you
all your instructions
K under
alleges walk forward putting one foot
right from the other
for ten paces while reciting terminology
sequence
that would be a cool
he drug test how many people are
past that rock okay
miner story there's actually a guy who
wears a white shirt and his famous
lockpicking
who was given up alcohol to kill a small
rhino and he past
all the tests horizontal gaze nystagmus
test like
they ready they went to the front to
police barracks
they'd fed him good scotch
because that's what he requested he's in
there and
they're like 3 hauling away alright walk
in turn
no problem recite the alphabet backwards
in cling on
no problem you know do this do that no
problem
horizontal gaze nystagmus the only
physiological test that's what you up
kinda cool okay so the to test the one
let's dance
and the walk in turn are just attention
tests
track can you follow instructions can
you do the right things at the right
time can you
focus okay make sense the horizontal
gaze nystagmus
I'm not my finger 12 inches from your
eyes follow my finger with your eyes
he's gonna go slowly this way Swansea
your customers in this is not to screw
up and he's gonna go to your limits your
peripheral vision
you know that a little too far up okay
and is okay hang on go back to limited
your peripheral vision is gonna hold it
there
and after about 15 seconds eyes just
mister
quivering because when you're drunk your
muscles are not right
sirs will not right they start quivering
edges when they're under strain visit
at the edges ever prefer a vision there
Frank all the way over right okay
and it's a quiver that said
added evidence have a nice day that a
conclusive hit by the way
okay at that point the hi love evidence
you were swerving you have you sound
wrong
slurring your speech uses reach a vodka
gin doesn't smell you read your vodka
you cannot perform a horizontal gaze
nystagmus test correctly
and when I didn't have to do the walk in
turn reciting the alphabet backwards and
going on
you didn't know the olive character
so now we've established probable cause
that we can our rec what the law
enforcement officer can
rescue okay so these tests are pretty
straightforward explain the walk in turn
explain the horizontal gaze nystagmus
the one that gets dances really top
watching to do right now
if you didn't catch that extreme version
stand on one for you like that but wall
was an email for wall counting my
sixteens wall
doing these things get can you multitask
can you track and you focus
I know harping on this but it's the
biggest thing
okay so we've got three test battery do
all these things
don't start for the test is likely to do
so here's I'm gonna do a test
watch this is not drunk does it all
right sir please don't perform any
this until I finish instructing you on
how to do this right
a high I'm gonna want you know stand on
1 like and then recite the alphabet at
I sir please stop until I finish
instructing you
home okay I don't say simon says
bastard had my training of had to me
we did Simon Says three hours 18 that
bastard Simon
alright so horizontal gaze nystagmus
involuntary jerking the eyes we talked
about that the I tremors
look you're actually our medical
conditions that will cause this so
if you have one tell the officer because
they will jail you if you don't tell 'em
right I'm not gonna list the medical
conditions really don't want them in a
minute to go blind
okay our man I'll get like something
block or something and I mean is that
was like a drink and drive whenever
you'll be blind you'll be driving much
more okay so
don't do it
alright the preliminary breath test hang
on
shit not good the preliminary breath
test
on-site I've got probable cause right
I'm gonna give you a breathalyzer test
on-site
how does the breathalyzer test work this
the technical stuff alright
it's not admissible in most states
actually I think all
and the reason being and I'll explain
that the technical bit is because it's
not
precise this is a piece of evidence yes
but it's just really to cover the
officers ass
its debt probable cause for arrest is
not admissible and core
to get conviction right this covers the
the officers asked
help to bring him in to you see people
on the breathalyzer
yes but was a hundred and fifty percent
humidity and it was you know
112 degrees out Sox okay why would
that matter because
I'll you got to get okay to the urban
legends now
that slide but OK don't put a penny in
your time
don't swap alcohol into your mouth just
before the breathalyzer
don't like sticky tips up your nose
swear to god I've heard
if you have to watch 'em episode of
Mythbusters not that it's a bad thing
awesomely dudes but watch the one with
the test at the DUI test
Adam Savage is so freakin funny went
wrong its larious
his ended like you know fifteen years
later in like a penny and you're talking
like giving our
is the Corolla pennies under is Tyler
the
half and a
the blows really friggin drunk I think
it was swallowed a penny like pounding
on the back
you know don't hola hey I got a crap
copper so anyway arm
don't built in the breathalyzer don't
use ments mincer on we all like means
but don't do it
look if you get to the point where
they're at the station using the
Intoxilyzer
when I was a cop with the breathalyzer
the on-site an Intoxilyzer which is the
calibrated one at the jail we had it
there
someplace like a different places but
%uh the main station the Intoxilyzer
you cannot for with that thing i mean
there are ways but kinda abnormal
do that arm ice actually kinda works 12
seconds because it cools the air down
but like I'm about to take an
Intoxilyzer test mind if I stop my
mobile device first
why sure sir you go they will let you
drink the orgy
they will episode crap you're going to
take the Intoxilyzer test and by the way
you take now which okay so
let's get to the technical part workers
alright
look I mean what you read this I could
tell you to do any of these things
because they're not gonna work Jersey
if you say I'm nervous it's probably
true it's okay to say that
I'm nervous officer please go slow me ok
it's fun have a cold on cold medicine
if it's true that's fine if it's not
true trust me he's going to
go duties know about I don't care if
you're cold medicine as well even robert
rubin
you go to jail still okay I have ADD
I'm not asking are I'm guessing
year's World on
I have ADD can you please repeat your
officer
I'm a little nervous have a cold cough
medicine
you know these are things that are going
to inject some doubt it the process
don't use them unless they're true and
what you can pull nevermind arm
don't use it was the true again I don't
want on the road
drunk driving will hit me somebody I
care about you let somebody that I hate
when I hurt myself
you know I want you to do what I want to
do it so
don't get drunk driver please admit to
lesser
media defense the cops in a hurry and
you go I wasn't wearing my seatbelt
I'm sorry I was reaching for myself on
the ground and he goes works for me
you know not as a plea bargain
on-site he's
look okay if a cop right to take it is
to go to court for
its socks because Norwich on the day of
the pay 25 for 50 bucks depending on the
state to go to court
so on your day off I want you to show up
at court uniformity
hot as hell wearing gone and you're
getting paid 50 bucks for that day to go
sit in court and answer questions from
an idiot lawyer
who wants to do that
okay so
arm if they can give you something they
don't the court for you like arms
to pay this sometimes life is good you
never know but anyway
skip this
the test is on par the test area
okay DC that that's weird when a
breathalyzer
no job they're not heart what is a
breathalyzer do
it takes your breath it pushes it across
to contacts
the more conductive your breath is the
more alcohol there is in your bro
simple seriously so what's going on fact
that
temperature humidity why well it's humid
its gonna dilute your the out hole in
your breath its gonna change the
connectivity of the contact gonna be
cold water
up okay if it's cold your
the alcohol a prize correctly okay
because the breathalyzer the better
models actually heats up your
your breath to vaporize the alcohol more
effectively so get such
reading about about holding your breath
so think you would like a lie detector
anybody's afraid to take a lie detector
and they put the the the
every in everything on you want things
the reading the galvanic skin response
really how conductive your skin is when
you lines little
okay just a little bit you know not like
I'm sweating down these freakin lights
but a little bit and when you're drawn
is more alcohol in your breath and it
makes the
wanted a prize is it creates more
conductive cloud there the more
electricity
across more drunk you are and it's
calibrated against the reference sample
at the Intoxilyzer is not the right
let's remember on-site in the station
right
it's calibrated and it's calibrated
correctly
humidity control temperature controlled
environment and they don't you have a
class belies ok before you get on got
there blowing it
you be conclusive test right there
that conclusive by the way members at
the breathalyzer on site no good
Intoxilyzer real admissible in court
right
yep okay so can you make one of these
yes do I suggest you do yes kinda cool
it's really great sensing platform you
can sense how much alcohol how much
conductive
across a couple sensors tonight we know
integrated with a project have fun
buddy mindell one smart guy nose is
crappy built one
that's it and it works in
his way used on bicycling but anyway
okay this is yours
right side arm there's one interesting
wrinkle I'm going to talk about the
Intoxilyzer
this is the in either the
in station calibrated actual evidential
value
breath test by which you can get
convicted we've made
officers decided I enough I have
sufficient probable cause after the SST
are the roadside breath test are just
your %um by my impression you're
hammered
come on down bill they will now
has to do with the calibrated more
expensive machine
this is a sensor with some circuitry
and as we all know circuitry a software
and the most the state's laws
use I the NH hearsay national highway
transit
Transportation Safety something stations
a
administration arm I know should
remember that
they promulgate a list that says these
are the approved models
makes and models love the im you
evidentiary
valuable boxes you can do these tests
the problem is that when you actually
poor born it just has
make and model there's an additional
variable
which is what version for where is it
and as we all know they modify the
firmware to
for whatever reason a few smart
DUI were selected and said wait a minute
could the
different software version me there's a
difference in accuracy
why to change software manufacture
and the couple cases these became kinda
I little fights between
prosecutors are trying to promulgate you
try to use this evidence
the defense counsel China kill it in the
manufacture because the
the defense counsel goes says
I don't think that the Intoxilyzer you
used is actually certified
defense count I'm in past years ago its
make and model Mike yeah
but it changed NH TSA which sell for
version did you use
we don't have those records manufacture
which software version was on the box
you gave to the image you see for
testing
an HD and they say we didn't send any NH
use a bottom of the market so it's a
possible
bat this mission machine used is now
mission that's accurate mmm can answer
that because we don't know what version
the software
so there a couple cases where defense
council decided
we're going to pursue this really really
hard
we're going to demand the source code
and manufactures like we why do we have
to show the source code
but that's our proprietary magical stuff
because it's really hard to rate the
software
and we don't want but we're freedoms
were free that goes to our competitors
and they'll figure out the magic juju so
they they kinda they were like no we not
we don't have to give you
we don't have to give you this evidence
and some courts
some some state Supreme Court said well
really you have to show you can trust
him and the source code
just cause have to show that there is
some other outside evidence
that the box is inaccurate enough that
you have a false positive
there other states that have just said
sure the defense counsel defense can get
whatever
great reasonable discover they're
supposed to get
earth-shaking attorney the ob
so Cup its its kinda split I've noticed
this the the way
the laws practiced is one attorney
will actually splashing client will find
a high and attorney who was willing to
go
and have someone to a forensic code
review want these boxes for
a bitch million dollars and
yeah I got this guy of those you know
hundred and ten thousand dollar DUI case
for someone rather well
be but then every
I'll take any lawsuit for $99.95 a rush
job esquire
will say wait a minute I don't actually
have to do a code review I just have to
file a motion
demanded and the prosecutors gonna say
essential
freakin work is there something we keep
knobs usual you can't believe these
cases in
in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania
there are very few diverging paths
out-of-date eu-wide they're like usually
for most practitioners as
you're banging these cases hell I had a
friend on a public defender who drove a
Porsche
and how do you get to drive a Porsche is
a public defenders ago I
I'm allowed to practice on this as per
my contract and she would do
DUI defense is at 1500 bucks a pop and
she would do
15 to 20 week and
there's the same as we will play it was
the same like because most DUI defense
are different then regular criminal
defense most criminal defendants
are multiple offenders were arm
experience from offense
ob most DUI offenders
when they get arrested or this is the
first time I've ever seen jail
I'm scared I need to lawyer
I need to spend a lot of money in a
lawyer's I'm really freed what's going
to happen and
we will are not hi but people
practices people of New little bit if I
can go well
if your free times important to you
maybe you should pay the top box for the
best deal I've attorney
now there I happen to be that 90's and
and you in realizes I mean I get I've II
worked as a public defender for a little
while
I get that your you get we can actually
white-collar persons
his their imagine like you know it
no true next episode a pause
white-collar hi hats awful things
happened in Cincy
you rule spend this money because it's
easy and in the pay up front so it's
really good
it's really it's a to it's a niche
market if you can convince enough white
collar people to pay you
so to fighting this actually running
these cases is
you do these want these motions and paid
and sometimes the prosecutors will pack
of the prosecutors will like
got this a lot of work maybe and it in
also means that everyone involved in
that and that particular stop
has to show up and its slows the
officers down thank you
everybody
so a hackers for charity donated some
t-shirts for me to chuck in patches and
stop
a the auction style margin: crackers for
charity ends at 1:30 so if you haven't
been down there to get your kids be
go down there and bid on it silly ZigBee
sniffer out period right now at all
its in the vendor area down on the
mezzanine mezzanine level
I got hackers share it with them