for two years ago at the at the last
hope conference arm
we we basically went over that deserves
inspired Trojans as well as a
a few exploit kits and I'll that back
then no
that the things we're exhibit different
a lot has changed in 24 months
a bit about me for for those who are
mister first time I am i worked in a
information security
arm I've worked with her defense
contractors and and banks
doing portability alice is a penetration
testing I'm currently working with the
PLX sir team at Calexico
doing forensic so a intelligent analysis
and
a threat research on dedust tools and
techniques and I'm
also president of the heck mami
hackerspace at a South Florida and on
the border the South Florida lost
and a standard disclaimer
all the information contained in this
presentation is for informational
purposes only
but don't actually attacked servers were
going to discuss your abilities
arm don't actually a engage life system
so we've
though it downstairs in the mezzanine
level we have a capture the flag that's
running that incorporates
all the tools so we're going to be
discussing in this so if you wanna if
you're looking to exploit some crime
kits we have a very safe flight
environment downstairs to be able to do
that with
and you'll be able to try out that the
exploits that we're going there will be
going over
and you even if you do really want to
try and find
no bulletproof servers are hosting this
type of stuff don't do it if you're an
american
the FBI likes to hunt Americans and are
all information that's contained in this
was obtained legally
through third parties in according to
the laws of the land which the rich side
so
last time we spoke Zeus 2.0 is still a
private kit
that older versions is were circling
publicly but the
2.0 is still private us by I
was fairly new and hadn't yet been
publicly linked arm
automated credit card shops those were
those were
a a rare phenomenon there they had
started to
there started to emerge but they they
weren't they weren't as prevalent as
they are today
almost to the crime where kits arm
vulnerabilities that existed we're still
private they were just so
circulated among the underground within
the intelligence community's but they
weren't they weren't good
disclosed in public knowledge a like
they are today this
the blackhole exploit kit was in its
infancy today it's
me though the won the primary exploit
kit center and use
arm things like big point didn't exist
peer to peer trip to curtsy as a concept
as a merged
within the with the last year's end
Adobe products
in 2010 where the most horrible vector
that is
that is also now change and here you
know just a
bit of nostalgia years with the black
hole beta kit back in 2010 before it
publicly on the market before was
the the comprehensive product is say
with licensing and
a automatic updates and all that stuff
house we're back when Phoenix and
Praga said yes we're still still remain
exploit kits that were
circulating the underground and
sense this time Java is now the new
attack vector
choice Oracle seems to be slow to
Tupac's their
their updates automated fraud shops are
now so common that just googling CVV
shop a leading
doesn't have resulted in dozens of news
articles about a recent FBI
arrests and raids and domain seizures
related to
to that market the major crime markets
such as is and pipes by
now right now public arm the down to the
source code level we can even examine
the co 2 the builders
that are making the executables and more
abilities and cry markets have been made
public
remote file inclusion file blows and
juice as SQL injections a spy and
Eleanor
as well as others I'll
also de dos attacks have become more
prevalent the
rising act as a activism over the last
two years with the with the whole
all the different anonymous campaigns
that that their
really significantly arm increase the
focus
love me attention on dedust attacks and
the overall awareness adidas attacks
and the a more tools are now available
to conduct
up these types of attacks there are
simpler than ever up specifically Buddha
scripts
%uh the bar has been lowered when it
comes to the
technological requirements to the
understanding
to be able to launches attacks conserve
Optim botnets also emerged arm where
instead of creating set up spreading
harm our among different machines you
just convince users to run
to run a tool and %uh participate in a
in a target so you basically
it you it's becoming part about it
because you're choosing to accept party
the
part the activist techniques for digital
activism
a new crime work it's the were released
do it specifically dirt jumper which is
a
Russian de dos toolkit actually a very
potent on
itself for its will be going into in
detail later and also zemra was a
another
Trojan which has recently been released
into the news and
out leaked and also discussed in the
news and will be going into that into
detail as well
there's an again there's been an
increase in law enforcement activity
surrounding
to all this and the emergence and
there's been an emergency
peer to peer crypto currencies like
pecan but there's been a surprising lack
of interest from the underground
armpit has really but has a really
completely taken off
are and that's probably a good thing cuz
like that things can be done with pickle
I love the new attack vector Java most
new exploit kits
specifically the back all exploit kit
that now make use
love for Java vulnerabilities which are
have which are released
and Oracle is very very slow to patch
they have
pretty slow arm a patching cycle so
it could be up several weeks to several
months from the time upon a village
discloses high moral gets around
actually patching
so that window of opportunity %uh is is
very large and attackers are leveraging
that window of opportunity
and developing exploit a java-based and
including them into automated exploit
kits for things like drive-by downloads
the new version a black hole a
advertises the
to advertise a job or ability arm as a
reported on on Krebs on security dot com
and automated Ryan loss after the rise
as automated fried shop
these are basic PHP my SQL scripts
that are that sell digital goods except
in this case the digital gate goods are
usually
credit card numbers mag stripe data Pay
Pal loggins
email accounts or are basically have any
other type of bomb
collected credential that can be used
for for some type of Roger activity
the way these workers a user or users
will either pay a fee to join
the site that the usually heard about it
from a karting former something like
that
Orlando though but though you have to
pay a fee to even register
to be able to access the site and want
to pay that fee they can find their
account
and a start adding items to their
shopping cart and checkout with the
with anonymous an anonymous be currency
a in
usually get home didn't get away with
the feel
several good man a credit card numbers
for depending on a shot between two
to five dollars apiece or their seven to
eight or ten dollars
by the piece for for European cards and
arm
the scripts originally were exclusively
private scripts that were army at
be there by yet to buy it from a
developer on a cartoon form but as time
goes on
fewer customers get discover rattled and
scripts get leaked
so now on these have scripts are freely
available
show a few look around forms people are
giving them away people or
on their been hacked ones that have been
released and %uh several
on the most popular shops have been
breached on by
pretty much everywhere everyone in the
book everyone's been
been it the sites because they're their
a trove both you know pirate digital
booty and intelligence for both the
scary consultants and law enforcement
arm most recent
raid was a operation card shops took
place
and June love this year where the FBI
did a sweeping arrested a 24 people who
were engaged in
carting activity some people are also
running automated shops
and the they also had a created a
honeypot form
are called carter's profit that was run
by the FBI
and basically just kinda set back and
watched as scars from all over came
stargazing and transactions
and then they close up shop in June in
May 24 arrests
I'm one one notable breach took place
during the spring of 2011
are a French it that has reported on a a
french-language information security
block
apparently a French actor was able to
breach I credit card
selling shop and farm once they've
reached that they were able to obtain
the actual PHP scripts for the shop and
a MySQL database
and with that they're able to get
administrative actors to the application
list of all the users are the shop all
their passwords
and all that transaction data as well
they've arm where the breach a
spread pretty quickly up it was a pretty
poor prominent
site those on the did was discussed on
pace bit various other underground
forums
on when this was going on summer
researchers act Miami
were able to obtain screenshot sourby
posts on the forms by some by the person
who had done the breaches and you glad
they are
were able to up it basically are able to
see the statistics
from the administrative panel which gave
which gives a good snapshot as to the
skill the underground economy
that's going on especially when this is
just me take into account that this is
just
a single website and there are hundreds
of them out and
so let's look at let's look at some
statistics
arm the this is the class this is the
statistics paddle from the car shop from
the administrator palette you know they
can log in and manage their sales and
see exactly what they're doing
arm from between a parole 2010
enable 2012 there where there was over
six hundred thousand dollars
worth of data that was sold the problem
on the on the site
through through Liberty Reserve econ see
on their
looks like they're their largest the the
most busy month was
was August and September 2010 that's
when the the peaks they made about
about a hundred a on close to two
hundred thousand dollars just in those
10 months
and there the rest alone and the rest as
much as kinda had a trickle of
as our by I guess is they got into to
other things
arm the most most the time the the
people running the shops
art hackers themselves they're simply
are buying up
a book databases from hackers and
including as inventory in the shop in
marking up the price
here's another statistical analysis from
the from the shop
on this was the top users the top 10
purchasers
about 9 percent the business from for
the entire shock came from the top
came from the top 10 users and over the
course of the year just those 10 users
spent about fifty five thousand dollars
up on this
a bank records from the site
and the administrators obviously sloppy
which is why we will be looking at the
statistics today
arm they were able to do it for some
reason the
appeared to have a backup file called
test that tax
the head every single Liberty Reserve
transaction had ever taken place on the
website
destination account numbers a where the
counter at the way it goes
my funder coming from the the batch idea
the transaction
and the amount that was for so basically
any
anyone who ever by a credit card number
from the site
there in their a confirmation was
available for public viewing just by
browsing to test
that text on this shop
and in addition to make such as that
we've had
things like Zeus and spy that evolved
that have
a been leaked through various
public publicly accessible on our forums
the
the other there's been a significant
increase
I N in fact and infections and the
participation in these communities
overall because these
previously a private kits are now
publicly available for free
whereas these cost a few hundred to a
few thousand dollars you can just down
live and play with them
and arm again most to the public
releases
a contain back doors because they're
releasing them
with the intention %uh being able to
take over apartments once people have
started using the tools and
and making it work and of
also because these are now publicly
available you have an entire community
dedicated to
researching about the scripts and code
looking for vulnerabilities within the
command and control servers and there's
been
many that have been discovered and
publicly released that will be going
over several others
here some zoos wanna bilities and and
again all these marvellous are going to
be discussing
arm try them in a lab environment we've
got one downstairs on the mezzanine
level
all these kids are set up you can run
these exploits against them and see how
they work
arms use has a remote file upload
vulnerability
previously this was a just circulated
among very small
communities people arm mostly within the
security industry and
are also within the underground arm
basically when
jus communicates to the crowd control
server it says and encrypt the POST
request
and then encrypt the POST request will
write a file to the server that has all
their key log data and
the stuff that that children be
collected from the machine from by
impersonating a pot and sending a POST
request that's encrypt it with the key
from the server
which can and you can you text you can
obtain the key
for Zeus the encryption key either by
extracting it from where the binaries
or just with a simple brute force attack
are mute a few
encrypts a POST request sending it to
the gate that PHP drop zone for Zeus
for Zeus it's possible to write php
files executables
arm files to the server and if you can
browse if you can browse directly to the
report a directory and find where the
file is
you'll be able to execute it and you get
like a CIA nine are 57 whatever you've
uploaded to the
to the server to execute just by
accessing it arm
if you up Alyssa we've but its
very possible are the few brief you
browse through other reports directories
are on
on Nov various public to respond that's
if there are publicly accessible
there's a good chance you gonna find CIA
nine are 57 shows it off
that are already there and over his
kindness feel
CE a see the that the compromise though
by as as is and um back in fall 2010
security researcher Dan Billy reels from
excess
national bird or a him put out a a very
very cool tool it's a PHP script that
will
emulate though POST request but upload
a file to a two issues botnet so you can
if you know the encryption key you can
so you can just pop it into the script
or even senator
very little tweaking on to make a brute
force a script or just settin
try to extract it from the binary and
arm we also
up and in addition regarding a check in
the key from the binary
there's a up a blog on thread expert
called a
almighty Zeus that describes the process
of extracting the encryption key from
up from May's is binary so that combined
with bill you reassess tool
a can arm result and compromising was a
spot on it again
don't do this in the wild that its
attacking a server
you go downstairs and you won't go to
jail and it's much more fun
a spy I had a multiple SQL injection
vulnerabilities that have been
thereof recently been public made public
on their blind SQL injections on
those two files a form find wraps up to
inform cards at it
the ID parameters are on sanitized and
love soaps the barbel to SQL injection
arm there's a been a blog that was also
written by a bigass
section H E and the were they've
go step by step on extracting database
information
from up from the spy I database to the
SQL
to SQL injection attack up there's two
vectors attacked they can use
arm with an SQL injection inspire you
can use the SQL injection to read
configuration files on the server
and Paul appall credentials our way or
you can use it to read the database info
crash that way depends on how the
spy administrators set as set it up but
again only do it in my lap
on other crime where kids up have also
had %uh public Mon abilities the Eleanor
exploit kit
which show with to discuss to about two
years ago one more popular exploit kits
in 2010
they at now has a public SQL injection
vulnerability sup a PDF was released on
exploit d be caught hacking miss kitty's
which is about which is about taking
over Eleanor exploit kits
and the black energy de dos botnet also
has a SQL injection vulnerability that
allows you to
to dump entries from the database and
that was also
released by by Billy Rios the same
researcher who released the
the as use back door and they are on
again only do
why haven't you added stuff and a lab
and there's been no a resurgence love
love
good dedust side should be
denial-of-service arm
has as become more prevalent within the
last two years
mostly due to the to the rise above love
activism causes and and various global
movement
that are that are using the DOS as a
protest or
arm the the use of traditional Mauer
based
up but that's that connect de dos a
things like
things like dirt jumper that is a or or
those boards cool RC botnet centered
that do I'll adidas attacks those merged
the concept adopted botnets
and those are tools allow let go will be
going to
like the high over I am cannon and the
low orbit ion cannon which
specifically arm are one
wanna single user denial a service tools
that become distributed that data
service line of participants are
gather for the attack and the my eyes
was dead earlier
the bar has forward the technical a
barrier to entry has significantly been
lowered
for attackers wishing to participate in
the da's attacks because
the toolkits and scripts are available
now are incredibly simple to use and
very poon
um dirt jumper was is a powerful arm
but that talk it that was released
publicly at the end
2011 it was available in private a since
about January of 2011 for sale selling
for about six hundred bucks and then
again it got leaked around October
army was made a as a spinoff
from the risk a strain on our it's a
it's definitely a Russian but that's
very stripped down and simple
arm it's a breads primarily the way arm
mostly people get affected with his they
want they want I just get hit with a
drive-by download an already
and I just get hit their jumper the
usually already be infected with some
kind of an hour
and a jumper or just be a paleo that
pushed out to a later on
and they want to be able to when they
want to be realized
d DoS attack from their already existing
about that
on that commander CNC panel of butter
jumpers actually fairly secure
you can even access the login page
unless you know the user name and send
it in to get requests
and it's got fake 404 errors all over so
for trying to fingerprint it with a
fuzzy ortho
web putting up his W foes it's gonna
it's gonna give you arm
a seemingly legitimate 404 responses
but they're their subtle differences
between the
real for 4 responses and the dirt jumper
generator for for responses
see kinda get a feel for if if there is
an actual 'em
scum actual server there it advertise
that makes use of four different attack
methods
I know when we torn apart coretta
already be lectured
on we discovered that for the most part
harry just get floods and post leads
it's up to you though have several
different a
names attacks by when you look at the
traffic
just to get flood and it'll make you sir
I will try to randomize the HTTP headers
the reefers
arm the you're mostly that mostly refers
and the user agents to try to avoid
detection make it look like legitimate
traffic
arm but I again it's it always has
static signatures so we we
put together a very comprehensive
analysis ovett army can
but the we have a mitigation signatures
available to the public as well
on that project dot com forward slash de
dos dash
third dashed our jeopardy HTML are we
do really is periodic threat advisories
that right reverse engineer these
toolkits and
discuss what they do how they work and
best ways to mitigate them on your
network and
there that's available free to the
public from politic dot com
arm from the threat advisory section
here's an image of the the dirt jumper
Control Panel against a very stripped
down interface
said has 1 a.m. only has a couple and
puts I'm
where the target URL how many threads or
flows do you want a machine to run it
that run against it and then there's a
start/stop button
as a screenshot from version 3 when we
did the
when we did the analysis that's what
that was the version that was publicly
leaked
sense we've released the the threat
advisory dirt jumper 5
has come out and advertises that it has
an anti Diaz mitigation feature
that randomize additional headers during
a post-flood
are made that it at was seem to be more
hype than actual
than an actual threat regarding be able
to be does make Asian because
all it did was add an extra
randomization field on the post-flood
and called it an anti dust flood
so it it's miles mostly just a Mar
since we mostly just a marketing
technique
and O also
the also as though that's come out
within the last autumn
out became prevalent within the last a
couple years has been Buddha scripts
on these are used and denial of service
attack saddam's
daddy doesn't tax that arm there's
simple
stripped-down PHP or ASP files as just a
single file their
prevail even go to pace been a tight boo
description OC
dozens of examples of them are
essentially all they're doing
descending get floods or you TP floods
and they're incredibly simple to use up
you
you can get a what a lot of arm novice a
novice attacker doing
as attain these public a booter scripts
from from my
there are four or more pastebin then
they'll just signed up with a buncha
free hosts
put the file on the free hosts and said
it started acting at Target
and eventually free hosts kinda catch on
to that setup centuries publicly no
shells
not all of them are doing it so good so
we pre effective for short periods of
time
but arm through very simple web
application vulnerabilities
attackers are also up living these files
to web servers so
us so basically what happens is through
us a simple remote file inclusion or any
way to write about a server
arm attackers able to take convert that
that server through a single file upload
internet and use all the bandwidth
from that server in adidas attack which
is significantly more powerful detecting
a bunch of workstations
arm with the with mouth with peace in
our
and having them work altogether so
basically it ok with less effort
to to spread these up %um busy attackers
be able to use less machine center
easier to in fact
to do more to do more powerful attacks
and Buddha scripts are are a big reason
for this some we have some screenshots
of what they actually look like 10
and what that their interfaces are arm
a lot you can get these long lists of
blue shells at just circulate on
pastebin
and are they there are programs called
bootloaders which are either stand-alone
clients written by a young people were
usually just getting into to programming
or arm
these web application based bootloaders
where you can just feed a list
love above the shells into into the
bootloader
and given the target and it'll it'll
start heading home of and what what's
interesting about the the communication
methods are these these traditional
about its like dirt jumpers arm our base
are rely on the commanding
rely on command control server Shoham
who actually rely on the infected client
to connect back to the
command-and-control server
and receive instructions whereas these
sick quietly
awaiting to receive instructions from
the attacker or the bootloader
and the the only way that we see those
instructions if you know where they're
actually located
and third there's an entire economy
based around these where hackers will
just go around in fact
effecting web servers dropping better
script shows
and the seller lists two people want to
be able to use the DoS attacks likely
don't know how to
you don't know how to do a web
application tak here's a list for a few
bucks you can just use this list to
start attacking these web sites
and again he lectured is Donna a
comprehensive analysis of several
butter scripts how they work the the
economy that surrounds them
and the the entire p.m. good script
kiddie seeing that surrounds it but it's
actually
pretty sophisticated and pretty and
way more powerful than it should be
because of how r because I've
the the amount down with that the
scripts are able to utilize from copper
my servers
and that's after letting back on 4/28
advisers that HTML
here's a screenshot of the green shell
booter script very simple
straightforward php file
part is uploaded to the server on task
force the destination
and the length of time he went on the
attack for and all this does is send the
UTPA fled
so if if farm you don't wanna have to
even use the euro is this little goin to
face you can just send a GET request
well love your green showed up PHP
question mark target equals and time
people's and then what essentially what
bootloaders do is all just send those
commands to the entire list shells and
you then you're able to leverage our
pretty powerful
adidas attack using incredibly simple
tools techniques at really shouldn't
work
and 22 well but they are they're gaining
wat way more prevalent
because the its their easier to do more
people are using them
and this is this is the result nah man
what what's another stick thing about
the green shell booter script it's a
it's not displaying
here I but there's a broken image within
the green showboat a script that used to
be a big pot leaf
and I was hosted on: a host on the
server
won the why I guess I'm guessing when
the authors are the script so
what would happen is every person who
would use this tool and drop a show on a
server
a time would be accessed the image-maker
requests to the
to the service being hosted so I wrote
the script is just getting all these
nice long list serve
up infected machines and thats
fairly common with the lady is a allow
the scripts
and we're talked a little bit about our
opted indeed %uh stools
on this is the low orbit ion cannon are
missus
it's got a lot of people arrested cuz
has no support for proxies whatsoever
and most people don't know how to use to
arrive using it didn't know enough to
use BP ends
arm it is simply use its just a very
simple get flood very
this trip down here is nothing that
fancy crashes a lot
not arm it'd especially when he's a high
thread count it only becomes effective
when you have
large amounts of people arm coordinating
to but to use as an attack like with the
leg with the anonymous campaigns
and um what was I was real funny is
during those campaigns when this was
circulating among
I among those groups IRC lobby were back
doing them what to do this because
why not and everyone who is
participating attack became part of
larger botnet is the high orbit ion
cannon
very similar to low orbit ion cannon
just the the next generation ovett
ass makes you serve a booster scripts
which are these a
visual VB script files able to feed into
the tool that are basically
less %uh randomized headers and program
is headers like refers
user-agent: and that has the
attempt to bypass any type of medication
error detection
but I i again it its crashes a lot Its
pretty poorly coded
arm its it has no support for proxies
and is only effective
when you using it with a large group of
people and coordinating and we've also
got a
comprehensive farm analysis %uh love
this tool
and then reversed it and that's
available on the political advisors
section
a recently in the news arms Emrah has
been getting a bit of press
its it got a lot of hype because it's
seemingly combines the features as you
since by I
with the with de dos capabilities which
was
fairly which is fairly innovative had a
really been
been seen a a.m. to be a that
popular combination arm it's based off
the cecum our kit
almost identical on database structure
and user and and
credit roll user interface arm they make
some pretty impressive claims
about the tool I in there and the
advertisements on on under reforms
to the point where it's a bit suspicious
as to the if this is actually
a functional tool for example is only
selling for 100 dollars
and compared to the market price of
other tools
that is way too cheap for something that
supposedly has ease
has these features and also has the
ability to spread via USB infection
arms just that alone flag fly something
that there's this
not something legit about this crime or
product
and update the torso released for
private sale
I'd say about about April or may Andrew
with an a few weeks it was already
leaked and the
code was to build a coat on the C&C
power cord was available
so that all that that and why when you
go to go to shows that
the its a lot according to have been
ripped from things like the sea
on our kid but it could've been the same
author but the is also ripped from some
other arm
portion to rip some other popular German
botnet a
but that's as well so that's pretty
common among an experienced
our colors are just borrow code from
from a other projects
and sensors no copy protection licensing
or any other fatty things that now exist
in crime where kids
arm there it shows up there someone
experienced and up
that's another thing that developed the
last year's a licensing for
for crime where kids are went to the
point where it's you know
and it's the appeared this PHP scripts
will be encoded you came in cm
it's just you know it's it's bill dan
coated
to your server Antonio I'll work with
your server and they'll have these
managed Update Services at all just push
out the update still when it's ready and
I'll be based in countries where there
is
absolutely nothing that can be done
about that and %ah
another interesting thing about the
there's ever a leak which is common to
most other league products
they're all back toward by default with
the most obvious back door
that's I've ever I've ever seen I if you
just go to System command that PHP
it's a PHP CMD
comanche from Jess question marks and
equals cat at sea password
any command and that's it you you've got
it then
most evil people using his to dump
integration thousand yet login creds and
and they can take over the takeover
about that so
basically and what I'm what I assume is
that the person who leaked this talk hit
arm was just looking to take over other
credit control panels
and arm noble cause it seems to be
worked out a buncha
think how much a press so I'm I'm sure
they're I'm sure they're doing that
and arm that was just the one that
were able to see just by looking at the
files like commander papeete what's this
I'll so like I'm sure there's I'm sure
that SQL injections which is also a serb
me a horrible water bill is fairness
within his pal
its is free to school for zemra arm
you'll be able to
download and how many you can can you
find it's a it's probably probably
several
an undisturbed a brief note about crypto
currency
arm in January 2011 the Queen was born
and last year's it's gone from up to as
high as 31 dollars to his lowest in
almost less than a penny
arm and but for the last six months for
whatever reasons for remained stable
force up between four to seven dollars
arm
and addition to pick winners other
crypto currencies that have emerged
compete with that
things like solid point our midst that
solid points
definitely not worth as much tighter
probably worth a few cents a coin but
it's the same principles same a same out
with them same distributed
peer to peer networks ideal and
its it's all the prices are based on
supply and demand
and um when when biklin came out
get all the only had a few docked at
sites where do things like sell drugs
Ursel of Kelowna other illegal
transactions are
very possible with decline because it's
so because it's
just like cashiers there's no central
authority people can send
other a physical encrypt the file from
one person to another and
the the value of the file is just agreed
upon by the
by the buyers in the marketplace in
general just like me a worthless Federal
Reserve fiat currency or whatever it's
just me its trusted by the users and the
spider-man sets
market arm that's a out
and the you just humor from %uh the
Senate made a big deal about it when it
got some news about you know the
the Silk Road drug market place you
today takes decline but
that its that's really kind of an
anomaly
for the most part biklin hasn't really
made the
no been a big player within the
underground economy
you'll see it every now and then a few
people will will accept a personal she
just did has a kinda curious in the
concept of crypto currency
but it's it's not arm really an accepted
form
and I'm I believe that to be because the
market fluctuations
on their the motions actors are still
making use of Liberty Reserve
or Yandex money which is another fairly
new one arm
which is matched the which is matched no
wonder want to the US dollar whatever
currency it is in the the country
they're using
a country that there and arm the the
market fluctuations a pic 1
a make it pretty a unattractive for for
long term cyber crime operations
because day because the you know they're
they're crazy fluctuation your thirty
one dollars to less than a
than less than a penny arm people who
are
engaged in and the the its me or digital
crime for that for a living
arm they can't they don't they don't
want a place that gamble on it yet so
it's a again while there's a few a
most actors add do take that point and
there's even been
a botnets based off that point where
Army for per
if you get affected your machine just
starts mining pick one
and then we'll send the the coin that
mines to a destination wallet
and those the there are several kids
like that that are circulating and arm
I'm I have no every reversed any them
but these days seem to be fair fairly
interesting
arm but aside from those few little
curious anomalies
it hasn't really a gain a foothold as a
currency of choice within the
underground and that's probably a good
thing has begun to be used to do
a whole you a whole bunch a legitimate
cool things seem to buy hosting with a
by your bike re-invite beef jerky with
its its
really cool armies and as long as a
you know this as long as the major media
and government isn't focusing on the
the things that can be done bad %uh the
bad things can be done with it
on there's potential for a lot of good
to be done with it but my
my passion is that decline is seen as a
as a as actual threat
to arm to that to the current fascism
that's in place because it's
up decentralized peer-to-peer digital
currency
that is actually worth more than US
dollar right now
so what's to come in the future much
nowhere what's next
a most likely we're gonna II particular
I see an increase in mobile device power
as more and more people start using
their phone so to to do bank
transactions email in just kinda
centralizing
all their loggins them to their phone
specials multi-factor authentication
makes use our cell phones
arm mobile device hours going to be a
natural part
of cybercrime talk it's because you're
going to be needed to
you need to infect phones in order to
extract a multi-factor authentication
pressure that you could be needed for a
lot of web applications and thats
that's already starting to to come out
arm
as and as html5 becomes more popular
gonna be more client-side attack
specter's
arm is going to be more browser
vulnerabilities that are going to be
leveraged on client site SQL injections
going to become more and more common on
both mobile devices and
desktop PCs cuz HR 5 allows the creation
of client-side SQL injection
client-side SQL databases and it's going
to be
new XSS attacks variants that are going
to be there going to be
available arm because html5 is using
that because the channel 5 arm a allows
for
new types of commands and functions and
a as far as de dos attacks go arm as
more and more these talk it's are being
released
as it becomes easier and easier to
launch significant attacks
using using large mass bandwidth arm
it's going to that's going to be
continues to grow and
some then become a become an issue
and and again sure some
some resources for forearm anyone who
would like more information I in the
stuff that was discussed today
arm the all the the de dos tools that
were discussed
are available from the threat advisory
section that relaxing dot com
up it's free for the public just up and
go and and download it
arm a the collective intelligence
framework is a really really need
a project that's there recently been
developed where it'll take
a the feeds from all the different in
our tracking I'll
on our checking sites like as use
tracker
clean air max spy eye tracker if you can
name it it's already on the list
and then it centralizes at all so that
you're not having the
you basically bass are all these
different resources to it so
poll on credit research centers it's
just collective intelligence framework
with a centralized at all
and Paul's sources the statistics and
data through it
arm also a regarding where the political
advisors in the dirt jumper their
advisory
we have a tool that we were any Scott
dirt dozer dot
P why and you can't read a list of
command and control servers
to to the Python script it will
fingerprint them if they're
if the dirt jumper tell you the type of
attack and the target of the attack
so if you have a list of products or
services you can identify who's being
hit
I'll with doctor trefor and house
Adam some good open source intelligence
resources just to
get for good feeling as what's what's
going on in the underground open SC .ws
is a is a malware forum our mix up and
down all the time
because it's up it's in our form and
they've but they a lot a good leaks and
up gotta lotta good leaks end up showing
up there before a show up anywhere else
Krebs on security dot com as a Brian
Krebs investigative journalist Davies
eyes putting our real that information
about on
about developments in the that did did
run aground
a cyberwar news that ensures a good
gossip page for appeal
hacker group rival battles and stuff
whose defacing whose doxie who and on
zone H dot org I'm real cool archive
two-faced web sites arm is all these
different facing cruiser just
a time that though hit like a book list
of domains to face him although I'll try
to get your rep points by posting up on
his own age .org
and pastebin dot com for pretty much
everything else just search for the
keywords
and you will you will find stuff
and thank you by costar anyone lost
contact me
Alex act Miami .info arm you go we got
other crime markets down stairs for
anyone Australia vulnerabilities
and arm everette that's at the pac-man
meet able to see a pic percent 27 on the
table in the mezzanine level
and if there's any questions I'll take
questions
are thanks very much
always crash in the back
for II den here for question was the
overall situation where
%uh through using delivering
on our through peer to peer networks
yet
are yeah I I was able to to dove
only about here everything is it serves
pretty darn I D but on their their
all sorts of our vectors exploitation
which are being leverage for these
these types of talk it's arm pretty much
if if you can envision it
its it's being done
yep
rate
well the bootloaders are usually amid
their
the Justice a single executable
application that
yeah exactly there's like this in some
the real fancy ones that like a
php/mysql thing in the cell service is
so that people can
pay a fee to log into the boot loader
and then run their own lists
but for arm for the most part the the
attackers needs tardy have the list
yeah I just yeah I just need to know the
URL where the boilers at me you can send
it
a target time limits start hitting it
arm with they're they're still on at a
expose being delivered through through
advertisements like flash one abilities
arm is just not as prevalent in the
market Adobe's done a pretty good job
over the last two years I've
fixing that but there are still 0 days
get discovered in
and trash in that a are infections
throughout the dirty advertising still
very common thing
and on and of us regarding if you're
talking about
adware like the advertisers that
infected machine and XI giving the pop
ups and stuff
on those those are usually our existing
and the use that to push out
the executable
arm
will all n/an/a
in a target or there's will basically
expert his work is that no fingerprint
the attack though the hit
everything and I just see what's on
herbal and Java is usually the last
resort because
most people run Java so little try to do
a browser exploit that doesn't work I'll
try to a flashlight that doesn't like
that
they know that they're all trying to
load up to a job applicant and I'll
man honest example the target attack is
up while the Brian Krebs blog
argued here a me he would go on to
certain
underground forms and once they
discovered that it was investigative
journalist
they decided to buy ad space on his
website that was
a maliciously coated and a he had to
approve it so we caught it but it had
gone all the way through he woulda
regular starter checking people yeah it
gets very possible to
to embed the eye frames and dirty
JavaScript into its advertisers are
purchased and that's still very common
infection method for drive-by downloads
a
you
get that that does exist on there has
been on JavaScript versions are
above the low orbit ion cannon other
sanity to stores where
of people can just start stick and
iframes on on infected site sir
and basically just by hitting their
website the JavaScript to start making
the visitors started it gary queso
basically able to distribute all those
attacks against legitimate YouTube a
so-so
as long as the web sites open attacks
are being run so that that's
but definite system that's another arm
that's another step excellent where
things are paid only going more into the
future
maybe Diaz without infection air
questions
up
are I i'm believe a it is in the
Guinness Mike
hypothesis I i don't have any prove this
but I believe
a lot of the the mobile applications and
animations as the existing primerica's
acknowledges
I believe it is probably developed by
third parties or obtaining this
the leaked code and is making changes to
it but I'm
tree shared the the you know somebody
region of others might still be involved
that but there's also been your rumor
and chatter within the underground at
the authors have
retired and that type of stuff so the
really who knows is all but two handles
and all and this could be the same
person
how a any more questions
i right
are more thank you offer for coming out
guys sir my name is Valley if anyone
came here not just to listen to the
lecture but maybe
make another acquaintance you know
Russian always to my english is not
perfect but I'm available so you can
just
come to