good morning welcome to hope number nine
but I did he just got out somebody will
hear the previous talkers Balakrishnan
by town wow perhaps this is a this is
greater
i cant Saxena shit home so I'm
I can't believe I'm doing this raging
years but down so much hundreds and
hundreds of the talks
panels conveying a really interesting
information
how many people here think a technology
has changed his ID
I okay I how many people think I summer
that is for good
and summer that hasn't worked out so
well alright
route we're all a motive is here are
hackers or containers I'll taggers
and we're on a position to help shape
our
that turns out I'm technology is a
double-edged sword
and we all have an opportunity tune drag
things
so that the technology issues in ways
that will %ah
be beneficial to society as opposed to
not good
so a lot be subject to talk about that
and our
what the opportunities are and what we
can do it and I'm money produce Chris
Anderson
Gus Andrews Naturino
and Christina done by Hester
Raleigh all really up on this topic and
now
I wanna wish them luck take it away
just I had my first I we're gonna
probably a reason in the top and Mail
something all
after inside the %um kids get off a
long-handled ex-mayor realizing a
handful of us have been
y de use technology to change society
for the longest time
and a half are gathered some experience
have been yelled at by even older people
so we're sharing all the yelling at
we've had
with you good morning christians up
first
thanks below
good morning arm and I have a lot of
time so I'm gonna speak
pretty on informally and move
from I very Turner
philosophical two more practical
I and the spectrum and also on
specific and generalities are all in
here arm
and enforcement because the time I'm
sacrificing to meet the specific but
basically what
I wanted us to think about on
with the topic have how to use
technology to change society is the
topic
have failure arm and
and also its corollary success and are
basically what I'm arguing is that both
these
are more complicated than they might
mark and
what we have to think about specifically
is whether or not the technology itself
works is definitely not the only
question that we have to think about
on and I'm gonna give a couple examples
in brief
on which happened to both be ot
technology projects
that were I imported into
East Africa by Western activists and
designers
on but neither them that wasn't an
empire from them
are specific to a context like East
Africa or even a global South Global
North
transfer on so one was a radio state Sen
%ah this was actually philadelphia-based
activists who built
arena season in Tanzania name built in
partnership
with a community center are led by
former
I expat Black Panthers who had been
based in the US and
have been living in Tanzania for are
over 30 years and have a community
center
and so the us-based actress might tend
to me and baseband
a mime are hanging out having all these
workshops about
our programming your sis and I and
governments have your state Sen
and also on very nitty-gritty
you know how to operate a transmitter
where to put your antenna
all this stuff and then may they left
fully confident
that've tanzanian folks had what they
needed to run the radio station
but arm monster restart basically the
radio station want to be run as any
not-for-profit community season
this is a mistake on tax that was
shifting out are basically
are state-controlled socialist media and
starting to open after
mom a more market-based model but really
didn't have a template for understanding
community radio
and didn't have a system in place for
licensing
answers community turbine to the
government and said how do we get a
license we want to broadcast we don't
want to be breaking laws
but there certainly isn't illegal
framework for us to fit into you
any kind of stalled and on
so for years in fact later the season
wasn't
it works it was operational that
broadcast on a test basis for a while
but it wasn't working it wasn't running
om
and so my second example is in rwanda
this is again
our Western UK and US based designers
who I were in rwanda and we're talking
as Michael folks about what but would be
assertive lightweight useful technical
tool
that would be useful over here and what
they settled on
was something called an or a wiki on
and this is really great if you google
or a wiki you can find are the prototype
inside that explain it
in more detail but I'll be able to get
into but basically what this says
is it was moving our traditional form
are mediation %ah that had
I exist in a society for a long time
this role our people called buoyancy
who are if you're having a dispute with
your neighbor on
may be over land use our incentive
if you can get me we're trying to work
it out with your neighbor like
you know I've been farming this piece of
land as to get the proper term many
neighbors like well no actually this
piece of land is mine and you don't have
a clear way to work this out
eagerly this person who's wrong the
community is me it is disputed
but the Lindsay who works informally
and didn't really mass with the form a
government and laws
of rwanda other there was beginning to
be a move towards
incorporating those two systems arm
something that they told these designers
was hard for them in their work
was that day we're keeping other records
by hand
and they weren't arm able to travel very
often and meet with
happens in other communities so there
was I concern that
any decision was highly local and that
that local folks making
on these indications didn't have the
benefit of the sort well
are the other people in essentially this
role
to compare with and to the designers
wound up on building a mobile
phone-based
Arora wiki so you can call in you could
record a decision
that you had made are both citizens and
other brands you can call in and listen
to it
and the idea was that this would turn
give distribute and
crowds are city well wisdom over the
arm basically adjudication and some
these disputes and make it more
on transparent and also maybe mark
equitable so that you know that the same
certain decisions and you know the
northeastern for the country in the
central part of the country
you know that there was some are pair
parallel are symmetry
between how these things are being
handled but lo and behold
they build a working prototype 70
excited about it
our local regulatory your government has
was excited about it
but they're trying to ram it up in
actually
go beyond the prototype stage and it's
really hard to get approval
on and so again it's as working
technical artifact
but it kinda have languages and I want
say that it completely failed but it did
fail to advance to the next stage
and so I think with these examples can
tell us on
is that while both these projects were
successful technically they are also
failures in the sense that they weren't
implemented in the way that the
designers and users intended them to be
and so on I want to point out that this
is kind of different
than some cases where activists are
designers
have an idea are hackers have an idea
like who the school would be really
great
and use or have builded and think out
now build it they will come and nobody
does
in this case actually the people who
were the intended arm
users were highly involved in
collaborating to design
the 20 and so it wasn't as I K-seven
mismatch between
arm the builders and the user's
I and in fact even on
certain and CEO and regulatory people
were on board with these and yet they
still kinda languished
on so in and thinking about how to make
sense of this
when I one are you is that we want think
I a bit more expansively about what the
technology itself
is on and
basically whether or not a technology
works in a given setting
is not restricted to I'm the narrowing
down at artifact
and its material properties like does
you know can we plug listen
can we work out the bugs in the software
so that the
wiki works the way that we hope it does
because all about totally worked
also I want to point out is that when we
think about technology working
what we're actually also assuming as a
knit successfully
on unmatched basically n
a set of social relations that also
account for its working not just the
technical properties
and on really crucially this is really
invisible to us
with technology is that work on when
everything's in working order
its a lot easier to on bracket out
all the forces that go into the working
right this is absurd a classic problem
on where you don't notice like this
elevator I can add to the 18th floor
on I would really only pay attention to
it if it weren't working I was taking 18
flights of stairs right
on and so I mean we talk about
what the technology is we wind up kinda
unfolding
all these points a contact with the
social world
into you now the radio station works
right on so I just really wanna make
%ah basically an and intervention how we
think
about wanna technology is on
and of her critique here and say that we
need to you
arm take a marksman to deliver artifacts
are
and specifically when we're thinking
about it the project might work
out we have to think about where it
touches all these obvious places
including
users including institutions including
our legal frameworks and regulatory
frameworks
on and if it's gonna touch those it
doesn't mean you have to necessarily
build something that will
completely on and seamlessly matched
with them
in fact you might be wanting to build
something that
is going to disrupts
or in other ways arm certain mass where
the the system that's out there but you
have to be thinking about it right
and in particular if you're going to be
building something that doesn't
on necessarily seem like it's gonna work
at the place where it touches
I just a very very practical idea is be
prepared to talk about this
be prepared to explain the project may
be prepared to explain it
in different ways to different audiences
and sorted translated
I'm not gonna say lie but say what you
need to say
to on the people who need to hear it and
I don't mean that in a
and assorted patronizing way but if
we're thinking a
you now greasing the skids to get a
project to work and that a fail
are basically we need to think about
white would constitute success
arm and a whole bunch of different
levels not just the sort of micro
on out whether or not this yr artifact
itself is in working order and has the
bugs worked out
and not even again asserted micro are
whether or not
artifact works and the people who want
to use it you know why is that the way
you built in
because again in these cases all that
works fine
and yet these projects have died on the
vine so we backed
cautionary tale and how much time I turn
I think that's about it perfect okay
great thank you on way
lol
breaker on so
this talk and is going to be a
reflection on my own experience
on in a project I tried to use
technology to change the world
I'm in the memories of my experience
with that project on have sorted and
filtered through academic research that
I did after I
was done on so sorta mashina personal
and on stuff up thought about as a as a
researcher and as a as a grad student
and now is a Professor
on the organization I want to talk about
was called The Independent Media Center
Obama also called in the media are the I
am see how many people here have ever
heard
independent media high-tech so if you
have I'm
on the less then on I would maybe have
thought at a conference like this so
this is this is actually good n
and Hisense what I'm gonna talk about on
the title is panel a somewhat in the
media was because if you don't know
where we're in the media is
it's a complicated thing because it's
actually still around on
but not really operating in the way that
it used to
I'm what anybody was very quickly was
that it served
as one of the world's and I say world
because it really was a global thing
I love the world's first citizen
journalism organizations
although we didn't call it at the time
there was no concept no one had claimed
that
that's too bad phrase yet citizen
journalism um
what we said we did was we said we
allowed ordinary people to provide their
own media coverage
I'll protest offense and political on
things they were trying to do
and actually cover themselves because
the mainstream media wouldn't have them
properly on this is something we now
call citizen journalism
on and it was very important
particularly during protests
on pride Occupy Wall Street that sort
previous waiver I love
have radical protest in United States
were center and something called the
the and once the anti-globalization
movement but the anti-corporate
globalization movement whatever you want
to call it
and in the media grew out of that
movement it then tied into a lot of the
anti-war protests are going on in 2003
2004 I'm okay summer
on this talk I wanna give
is a story of failure to success on
and what I mean by failure to success is
that the technology and the
technological methods
that in the media pioneered actually
went mainstream
I'm beings like
tax updates from protests that we're now
treated as journalism
ordinary people sending their thoughts
and their feelings up in ways that are
aggregated collected by traditional
mainstream news organizations
a pop-up newsrooms right newsrooms that
appear and disappear
arm around particular offense arm
decentralize coverage
other dams filtered through the
aggregation have different perspectives
on blogging sorted people taking this
idea that you know I'm going to reflect
on you now have my own participation in
this event
I'm all these have become absorbs into
the general population but particularly
into the mainstream media ecosystem if
you listen to what the traditional media
is talking about now
this is all they're talking about this
sort of thing
dominates what news organizations in
2012 think they have to do in order to
be relevant
and serve up %uh and I don't think it's
hubris check and I don't think it's an
exaggeration to say
that when it comes to the force is
currently shaking the world a journalism
each of them has grappled with by an
activist media organization
in the late 1990s and early 2000's I'm
so real briefly i want to talk about
what in the media did in a particular
moment
2003 to 2004 alman journalists were
working on building a media center that
could cover the Republican National
Convention in New York but remember that
fun time republican national convention
here gas
%uh those were the days I'm so in the
early days in the media
and coverage protest coverage the the
citizen journalism methods are actually
pretty simple
someone told me and this is a quote I'm
pretty sure we distributed a high volume
of paper cards
to would-be protesters saying call this
phone number
if you have information about something
that happened in the protest and then we
had people singing buyer
found typing up reports that would come
in over the phone and then we would
actually enter that into the breaking
news wire
our website I'm and and this was a new
thing then
on this was not not traditionally done
outs away the in the media website was
set up was that you had a right hand
column which was sorta
called open newswire which was
individual submissions from anybody
about something to report
up photo to upload a story to share you
then had
a breaking news box at the top would be
sort of
short little blurb updates on what was
going on and then you had something
called the center column
I which was for them Henry gation love
on at everything that has been going on
the rest to the website
please let me know about time to give me
like turn it on ok
I'm so that was for the basic setup and
if I wanted to go to the whole hassle
putting up slides I would show you a
slight but you basically just three
column architecture where you had
stories moved from low verifiability to
high verifiability
right so you had disorder be the stories
were increasingly
verified and filtered out as they moved
towards the center column
right and the ideal why'd you get all
these perspectives you get all these
things flying in
sorta generated in a dispersed way you
bring into the center and that's where
they're most verified inaccurate
information
I'm so during the Republican National
Convention though
%uh there was also an additional source
of information something hot
text moms as anyone here ever heard
text moms okay one to 3 couple people
aren't good
on tax mobs I this was sorta
what they said about tax mobs in a in a
press release they said it
text mobs were Qatar
AV though were equipped with a wire
whisk and protesters were quick to the
wireless
tactical communications device connected
to a distributed information service
that provided detailed and nearly
instantaneous apps updates
about route changes street closures and
what police were doing
the communications device was a cell
phone I and the information service
a collection open source web-based
programming scripts running I'll xserver
in someone's closet
was called text mom on text my was
basically an elaboration a previous
flash mob technology that had been used
to coordinate
loosely structured relatively autonomous
political and social dance
even before the IMC I'm so basically
what it did was the service allowed you
just
users to register with various protest
oriented message group
and receive and send mass text messages
to members of that group
buyer there somehow writes Ian sign up
for a group if you want to send a
anonymous message you could send it out
over your cell phone
it would then be received by the group
right very useful for things like
helicopter closing off Broadway let's go
sixth Avenue instead
right I'm at the same time
I M journalist with in the medium
monitored text mobs as
information source that they would use
to produce journalism and they use their
own tax moms group
as an additional way to distribute news
and a supplemental service launched just
before the
Republican National Convention even
translated these tax updates
in the human speech that you could
listen to you by calling a telephone
number this was a great
I'm okay wrapping up quickly now on
you may be thinking this sounds a lot
like a technology that people currently
use around protests any
guesses on what that is Twitter right
yes
Twitter I'm allotted you might be
thinking hey that sounds like Twitter
and a lot of you might also be thinking
wow thats what a remarkable coincidence
and the thing is it's not a coincidence
I'm tax mob was actually one love many
not not the only one
on it's important to say the one of
several open source projects
that the founders of Twitter were
hacking on when they invented square
while working in a company called
oh yeah I can shorten our leaders
Twitter appears similar to the
SMS protests systems develop nearly a
decade ago
is actually the Senate that very same
software so here's the basic gist
in some ways the DNA have a small
marginalized tax project that no one
else in the world has ever heard out
now sits within the body upon the most
powerful social messaging systems in the
world
okay Chris houses the story valliere
write this on the historic success
witnesses a story a failure I think is
that if you define your success in
technological terms
you might be successful in technological
terms only
in other words in the media and people
using text mobs
incredibly ambitious an important social
political
economic goals that they saw technology
being in service to
right Twitter does not have those goals
Twitter does not care about social
justice in the way that the people who
invented text mamsted
he did not care about economic policy in
the same it people who enter text moms
and then a text mamsted and my argument
here that you can be incredibly
successful technologically
incredibly unsuccessful in all there is
all sorts of other ways
and I think also discuss last thank I
think that those of you who have worked
on free software for many years
who have seen free software become open
source software
become this thing that everybody does
right I think you guys know more about
this than anyone because I think that
you see this conflict
in your day-to-day working life right
what happens when this social movement
baser and technology becomes mainstream
in ways that maybe you
have lost some the original social goals
at the technology was minister
alright so that was quick I hope it was
coherent on and happy to talk about it
more
the Ampex well
teach ok
you do the turn
not
morning hackers my name is Matt
Currington
I just finished my second year has a
professor at Adelphi University here new
york
by been developing a new program in
educational technology
so I can have this idea that we can use
technology
to change society especially in the
couple that with education
and I've been working on this and it's
an ongoing project some action wanna
says when Gus invited me
to the panel about how technology fails
to change this I'm
federal court of competent by I'm gonna
tell you about what I've been doing
what worked what hasn't worked and some
other things have in 10 min as we go
so I
I think this is relevant to hope because
eventually I want this program
can be a school for hackers and to be
some tribal impetus
run which
you eat eat eat occurring at a comp
night this is a battle I lost they would
let me set up my own website
and I'm I'm reopening that friend I gave
up on it last year
on see this is this is more interesting
than
then the corporate site that their
she warned me into down anyway
a so if we go back a couple years I just
finishing my dissertation
and I was very happy day damn job offer
new york I was
particularly happy because as governors
opportunist our new
masters program kinda from scratch I was
the only one working on it I'd met with
the fact be there they were happy to
have become an
they knew the kinda stuff I did so it
seemed great and
buyers rep the cezanne I think it's
relevant hope because
I kinda want this idea of attacking
education
and have creating education hackers that
as organizing principle for the program
so when I say that hackney education are
one oppose it to maybe this idea
education reform
you think a performance its getting
schools back on track or even like
radical reform
would be getting back to the first
principles for school
whereas when I say hacking education
what I want to do is
try to make schools do something that
they were never intended to do
or something that most people never
imagine that they could be
so I don't think that there's like one
big hack for this but
weekend in need to start on
or Delphi could be part of a movement to
get people search
thinking this way nom your
don't want to talk about education too
much I want to speech or presentation
basically i think thats cool even when
they are excellent
in succeed by by their own internal
standards that they can still be
harmful to society and education
consider broadly so this is where I'm
coming from
and I started Delphi and I i laid out my
guiding principles for what I wanted
these
my students to be able to do so these
are people interested in education
interest in technology I'm the
for saying was there I wanted to be all
hands-on project-based learning that
they be building things that they'd
produce for the world in some meaningful
way I'm
second I wanted them to have hands-on
skills for technology
on everyone to learn to write software I
wanted one
to learn we will set up a network to
edit video too
at least when they were students here
that they'd have the skills so that when
they left
they wouldn't be afraid of technology
and they be confident they can learn
things on their own
now the third thing there was important
to me
was that they had some background in
theory and philosophy
so that they wouldn't fall in two sum
these the straps that they have a
prospective beyond just the technology
or
beyond just education in them my idea
for this would be that the whole program
will be run around the lab in this lab
is kinda my vision a paradise
a you coming to lab in fact in students
who work together they'd
good right Freese offer for education
they contribute other projects aim I
built a multimedia
the kinda set their own agenda and they
work together and study as a wine
and it would be kinda hard they go out
to the community spread the ideas
know along with the lab we would have
seminar where as a group we would decide
what we want to read
we needed we talk about it we'd write
about it and again
this focus on getting ideas out into the
world
night so when I first started I A for
this idea briefly
even had a worker's an acronym for the
lab it but
clearly wasn't going to fly
so broke up lab in seminar in the
fifteen courses
and I created fifteen new cell by I
wrote in all the smart people I knew to
help me
Gus now on these courses
and I finishes in about two months at
work hard and then
this is where I hit bureaucracy
so I was going to make a flow chart
outlining the process
love how to get a new program approved
but is pretty much mostly Santa possibly
think you're doing is today
so I'm just gonna tell you how I how I
remembered best
it's about ten steps in first need
approval from YouTube department chair
the school education be in the Provost
office to begin working on
then your department fact the vote on it
some in a
army department called curriculum
instruction
right next I'm
the school education has a a committee
that reviews in this is about a hundred
fifty-page document that
that these different groups are working
with to the committee looks at it
and they prove you're not once a preview
your the whole school education vote as
a faculty
in Needham I think it's simple majority
to move forward
next it goes on to university-wide
academic affairs committee that does the
same thing that the school that academic
affairs committee justed
I and then there's a fact the Senate the
represents University books on it
from there the Dena Beliebers approves
it
or maybe he approves it before the
Senate measure
next it goes to the Board of Trustees
and at that point your lead the senate
in York State
in the nave prove it in I don't know
what they do
on yeah I was told it was unknown amount
of time in an unknown process
and we were just send it to them and see
what happen so the
problem it doesn't seem too bad like I
want to finish it in the in this year
and was
use only the end of October when I
started except that much these groups
only meet once a month
the border Trustees meets quarterly so
if I didn't get approved any meeting the
whole thing would fail and base KB back
doing the same thing again the next year
with seemed like I might quit
in go back to writing code cell
be basically along the way
a runny ran into some problems I have no
I skip this cat I had to me with any
other
units at the university there my overlap
with me and in this case I met with
computer science and with communications
communications were totally cool they
just said you can't use any work women
static var laps with you that there is
OK
computer science so wanted to steal pre
my courses and lessen his computer
science courses
arm which I didn't really care but then
I was told that then they would get the
side who teaches them and they would be
able to hire new factory for computer
science
which would help to leave me alone is
the only factor remember my program
in the end I settled with them gave them
one course in is able to keep too and
I'm teaching a course
so it's not it's not too bad
and other one my academic affairs at
school bed
maybe add five paragraphs to each of the
15 courses
about these distribution requirements
the university has I had to do this
basically overnight before I met with
the university-wide committee
and then that committee may be removed
the mall because they didn't want
undergraduate students taking graduate
courses to fulfill these requirements
they want to protect their
enrollment on in the end
New York State approved two master's
degrees one in educational technology
that leads to a teaching certificate
and one that's more educational design
in the
approved a graduate level certification
technologies Robin education
so yes like
don't speaker not well
what happened now is that at the end it
look like
a good but pretty much any other
graduate degree
in this area in the country and really
wasn't why I'd set out to do it's now
my vision about higher education should
look like it's not really my vision and
what we should be
are the best way to educate these this
teacher so and taken
step back in kind look at where
how things worked out where succeeded
where things get knocked off track in
bed
one to okay
so basically everything that happens
is depends on how many allies you have
with you
and whether you're able to succeed or
not and really the opposition that I
faced
was geared around two things procedures
and standards
nobody at the University said I think
this is a bad idea
at any point they would say instead
you didn't have the choir room for this
role or this wasn't presented
in enough time for us to review it so
every time I i ran into opposition was
on procedural grounds
and mostly I was able to overcome this
by having ours have my own arm
basically I did work for people for free
and they became my allies so I worked
with
with anyone that need a website are
needed I'm
you know that that kinda stuff that I
had good good skills and I was able to
bring that to garner
allies and more CA overcame a procedural
grounds
the second though the standards for
something that actually stymied being
there are two main group that actually
mandate what needs to be taught for this
degree to be approved
New York State has its own set of
standards and then
this is quasi on be governmental group
that oversees
teacher education programs called and
Kate and
you can't grant degrees in a school
education that deadly desertification if
NK dozen approved
so anytime I try to do something
in that my enemies didn't like they
would say
I'm afraid that you're not adhering to
the standards here
and now it's kinda like the commandment
of God if you if you don't
the standards were something that were
beyond us and
I had very little to success gaining
allies
to pose a standards and
now good I'm happy to be welcoming my
purse
class in the fall and try to launch its
website this summer
and I've taken on wanna my new goals
is trying to get support from outside a
adelphi to build a movement to to kind
overthrow the standards or subvert them
as much as I can
well
thanks I really am so pleased to be
presenting when this game is awesome I
breast colleagues and my press has my
best college
and outflow credenza I'm
so I and I was for a summer rise and I'm
put this in a broader context of
technology and social change
on because there I is literature out
there that is just not searching a
thoughtful allow that I would be doing
some special about schools but I think
just because I've what Matt was telling
us there on you all have a sense that
that's cool stuff is really thorny and I
think a lot of us just glaze over me
think about it sell
I know a lot of us immediately try to
make the and run up going to do
something like OLPC and
the reason I actually put this panel
together was a
at some point online earlier this year I
ran into yet another young person doing
we're gonna leave laptops for the poor
in its gonna change everything and I was
like we've done at
and so previously in talks on a given on
machine I miss get a couple reside did
haven't previous stock rose like it used
to say since enactment sin fuck you
access protocols
socially do you have to go through and
and
eraser let lol BC I'm it has been done
it was never party there
and one in my previous talks I was
pursued even Chris sticky got sick
and 2008 on but even points out as the
file PC security officer that nichols
had a party has done
well PC a number of times before he
didn't senegal
he did it in a school in Boston other
jawn in school which you can see their
web page is still under construction so
how the new technology
he did something like in Cambodia
Cambodia the the road our results are
still out on that and then there's RPC
and you know and so ultimately the
question is ninety just does this happen
and social good you know not up and
waiting
on so I think there's some excess
options that we need to question I make
a hill who still works on all PC and has
a big
arm evangelist says you know we know
that laptop recipients will be able to
benefit to be an
from being able to fix improving
translate the software to which even
replied
no its not backlit by fact we do not
know that laptop recipients will benefit
from texting software
on so our there's
we do we actually haven't figured that
out so I think um
these that's the reason I brought
everybody hears assorted go there are
things that we know
about on how technology an axe social
change one thing so he knows it's not
just the technology
on I wonder for all you to a book that I
miss site heavily here
I ever Rogers is diffusion of
innovations if you've read the tipping
point by Malcolm Gladwell
it's basically stolen will cost from
ever Rogers adhesion the nation's
which is just as readable book actually
is well worth going in and taking a look
at it it's also are much more detailed
has wonderfully entertaining case
studies
I'm so I'm sorry my notes are kinda
giving me trouble here
I'm trying to figure out how to undergo
on so Rogers's elements
and rather things that ever Rogers puts
forward and fusion innovations
are a complex system I want a size that
you can understand the system
and try to understand as a system don't
just say oh it's the social side of
things
i'd lynn i think is as technologists on
a time we sort of girl
on you know this technology in and
that's what we're gonna focus on
on ever Rogers elements there's five of
them I think
and the technology itself innovation is
only one of them
on and but the thing he he says also is
that the technology is not just a
technology
technology may I be almost entirely
composed information
so examples are political philosophy
such as Marxism
a religious ideas such as Christianity a
news event I'll write policies anybody's
the sound like
another concept and it is really with
shouted out
meems basically so every Rogers's idea I
love
other technologies also I mean so
technologies me means technology
on and and that sort of thing so when we
get into that territory no we're not
just talking about the things we can
actually hang on
on so up a lot you have to communicate
is about how to use the technology
answer the second element is tech nerd a
invasion is
is communicated through channels and so
is the point at which minimises hackers
got PR marketing screw those guys you
now sell
but you know this means dealing with TV
it means being on point
having talking points for Purdue working
in the press
you know going to face buttons like as
well third element the system
Rd the innovation diffuses overtime on
and that's where else is having a
history beyond our control we don't
really know we can do this we might get
slashed on it and then nobody pay
attention to their again
I and then and the fourth element is its
diffused among members of a social
system and so our God suddenly it's a
social situation how did I get here I'm
not good at the social dance
this is not my beautiful life this is
not a beautiful house I'm so this is
where we
we hit maps wearable flow chart I'm
unfortunately this is something
unfortunately this is this is the point
at which
many on many so many innovations I just
founder and fail and it behooves us to
understand
I you know as matt said your allies are
on
in and yeah so Anna
another thing to remember I'm if you've
read The Tipping Point is at
and not every a doctor technology is the
same you have your early innovators you
have your early adopters
on-air the ones who end up spreading it
to the early majority
blame jordy weights and watches to see
what other people are doing and you have
your laggards
and see you have to talk to people in
different ways you can't just go and
talk to all from the same way so
it also the duty to know who you're
talking to you at a given time
on and no person I think about here's
Bunnell a tour
on wanna christina was a lot of his work
pilot orders on us for sociology of
Technology
and he says we have an actor network
system cell
add the technology is in amongst a whole
bunch of other technologies
and technology said to be adopted in
clusters so you have to know about the
other technologies they're out there
on this course if remembers the history
the Betamax is one of the main reasons
as I can you have to the tapes and
VCR and you know there'll be elements
a the TV broadcast system as well
Rd have to think about um another thing
to think about
a the printing presses a great one we
often go back to that as scholars a
a technology education on you can't
really say the printing press
cause the spread of Protestantism they
were very much symbiotic so I
you know present church depended on the
printing press to get the word out there
about Bible and you know the Bible
depended on
you know that the printing press
depended on the passengers to help
spread
its use as well so basically take away
here is beware every search
as well not just am I'm not just not as
research but also articles in the press
the treat technology as the
only agent a change in a situation
because there are many many agents at
work
on and another thing to keep in mind is
that a lot innovation research has a pro
diffusion bias
so if you're reading something that says
he has to be defused really well
remember they've probably gone looking
for the diffusion is a look at the
methods that a particular study into
girl
haven't I don't I'm Nano is Kenny
Williams and every I ask you human and
animal had a little question answer
center
a after its so I am smoke
too much ethical I think Dylan a rodgers
also points out
a that it's not just the technology but
it's perceived attributes that matter
and these are
these things to happen a screen here
relative adventurer technology think we
understand pretty well
but combat compatibility is a huge huge
issue is with
on people's existing values as well as
well as the technology there is a very
very good study done
about early diffusion I love I Apple
computers to classrooms Apple follow
that closely
and research did and there a couple
things that teachers didn't get
and one of them was that you know kids
can teach themselves so
even teachers I am the kids and teach
themselves as less of a sort of a siege
on a stage model teaching it's a guide
on the side for this computer
the teacher standing next year helping
you you work through our technology
on even teachers who prefer the guide on
the side model now
sometimes did not adopt that model the
technology in the classroom
because they were so busy learning the
new technology that they simply didn't
have time
so the end up doing a lot of fun you
know the end up doing a lot of training
for themselves
on so that is that's another part
compatibility attorney about
compatibility in the school
I complexity I in schools especially
house in a book
the new meaning educational change by
Michael fallen and points out there
a school suffer from Christmas tree
syndrome where
everybody's trying to add more programs
onto the school awesome or program start
less likely things I'd take because
teachers start burning out answer going
why are you doing this I don't see the
point
I'm trial abilities important %uh the
door Aki bored many view be
may be familiar with that and say it's
the greatest thing since sliced bread
but the problem is it takes a week's
worth the train and get somebody
a who has been trained on Corti up to
speed
so trial ability is not really a good
with work for people who aren't needed
you know not slow down their work
process any in order to adopt in
observability also is really important
in classrooms and hard handling
classrooms because teachers generally
can't
observe each other and how they're using
technology in the classrooms because
they just don't have time
it's not my schedule so all these things
will shape
on how you end up how technology end up
getting
top 10 couple takeaways were quickly and
technology has meaning
beyond are meaning I love you know
the Linux kernel as it kinda freedom you
know free software is free
that's not the only kinda meaning I have
this particular side because Sam
if you have a hole in the wall project
in India is had computers where kids can
interact with them with no guidance
whatsoever
and the kids ended up calling the
hourglass
a drama and the pointer in need of
because that was what they would like to
them and their culture cell on
you know they people will sign their
meanings to it and if you are not
helping work with him
on what the meaning of the technology is
the meaning you know
you are going to be the guy on the side
and not the sage on the stage and that's
what we want you to do with technology
lets you do that people are not
necessary to pick that up from a
technology itself
this is a non-trivial problem on but if
you know you know how to understand it
you know there is
room to work with is complex system but
this does take I am
you know a understanding in reading of
social science work
I know many who think that's very
squishy and very much down on the social
ladder from
you know physics and math but frankly
physics and math are not studies of
human beings and unfortunately human
beings are complex you can apply to
science there
you have to look at social sciences and
there's a just anthropology and part is
great
I'm not too fond of social science or a
sociology paper your at Sydney
I but sad yes 11 we've seen is in a
couple cases this idea that belief
is an important with Christina's and you
know the
group didn't have a template for
understanding community radio they just
did not
have a concept to see the concept has to
be taught along with
the actual teaching technology itself
otherwise you end up with users doing
things that you don't
really what to expect like using the CD
trained as a couple dir
our the CD itself as a near so on
users have to agree with you on our
technology means what it meant to do
if it's to make the intended change I am
has
a Christian says when everything's
working order we don't see any social
forces
I am but we have to work on them if we
want anything to actually be adopted
that I have said we can bring lights up
with him a little bit acumen acres in
every likes tequila nannies
and Metcash and we have police 10
tenants
okay yes hi I'm really glad to have
someone identified that
I not Gladwell ripped off ever Rogers
Welsh
act without admitting it without
acknowledging my all that frustrating to
me when I saw that and I
I i have found this very useful on the
scientist at work for a federal agency
call and and that I work in a big I work
in a big bureaucracy nathan Deal
to live in a complicated system and so I
I am working I work
I have with that kinda invisibly within
my agency using a
an approach called the there's a theory
of living human systems developed by
Yvonne a gazillion
who is a add it started out it's a it's
a synthesiser
individual dynamic group and psychology
and group dynamics
but it's been it's been grabbed onto by
a lot of people who are interested in
science because it offers some very
practical
I operationally defined to find
your theoretical ideas and practical
approaches and so for example one thing
with
the the idea that if you're is to look
at the hierarchy
systems human systems that you're
operating in anti get your intervention
to the middle system
that that you're looking at so not the
not the managers and not there the
people who are just gonna at importantly
don't have your say an honor to once
more
interacting you can get them to change
then they can influence both systems
another idea is to in any kind of
discussion in a group to
focus on decoding the yes butts that if
you can
explore the yes and explore the butt
then you have an opportunity to
identify and a great summer the
differences that are in that in that
particular group so they're not every
practical tools
happen if you wanna learn a bit more
about it but there it's something that
really growing and and Desert Ridge
traveling in a despues Inc out at the
inn
psychology I good dynamics
organizational development girl
into some other worlds I wanna follow up
on that a little thats a really
wonderful point i'm glad you brought up
that particular author I've never heard
her
on but an I have a
Etienne acquaintance who went off to
african peace corps
arm and ended up teaching technology in
school and a
was frustrating kept saying I just want
these people to see logic and reason
that's all I wanna do this and
you know I like thanks Christopher
Columbus for being a colonialist but on
so and and I kept saying to him you know
people have different
takes on his things and I don't think
science was even I miss talking about
the social construct nature science
sciences socially constructed everybody
in here is gonna tell me it's an
abstract truth but now
on the thing to keep in mind is that
thank you
art science as we understand it
as people who have been through up
through
undergraduate education or high school
is not the same
as what somebody who writes NSF grants
constantly
you the people who write in a separate
costly understand it is a very different
process what we do in school is
memorized science was you had a really
good
curriculum on we are not actually
engaging in scientific inquiry we are
not actually
and you know and
waiting the grants and and and
negotiating with the other scientists
who are doing similar research in
positioning ourselves versus than
so I we forget sometimes that there are
the social factors even in the things
that we're memorizing as
abstract truth on and it's worth started
working on our own beliefs
about what is true that way and I'm I've
was going to emphasize that another talk
but I'll shut up about it now
presented my animator some the other
micro
me there a.m.
now I totally agree that people working
in technology should read some social
science
on as winning I mean
it is to question but very overwhelming
ike if you can make recommendations were
even better though if they're
RSS recommendations that you know for
people working technology
to get their feet wet & Sons call that's
a great question
I'm so that was Yvonne magazine ran was
the name but
agassi re and even a gazillion social
organizational psych
I after posting on my course syllabi and
get help
and even for King courses it so that we
can collaborate on them
and some I would recommend the real I
said God of us who've technology courses
and
course in digital literacies they're
probably have
some good thing some think details are
all kinda but we're in
yeah I'm running a drill it or he's also
a fun read sir
person hungry oksana rougher sledding
others via
arm I would recommend a pretty classic
essay by langdon winner
called do artifacts have politics is a
philosopher
it is a very clear read arm
that would be one there's also a classic
essay column
letters all construction and technology
I think on
by Trevor pants kak arm that is
yeah it's 8 its I'm about to get on a
bicycle
and the 19th century but it lays out a
framework for understanding
I how certain artifacts Alliance s all
processors to send affect each other
anybody wants is you can see me after as
I write them down
I'm gonna him I'm gonna embarrass
Christina by also saying that if you
google her name
amana manic technology she's got a great
blog post from a couple years ago which
was started a blog the fight version
other I'm a class act as insiders I'm so
that's a great meeting less than a dozen
more than its worth a narrative eyes
being less
I'm so and Henrik receptor actually
chris is last talked to get help as well
as for the new picture our farm
specifically a content farms and thin
brought my friend is different in your
as I hear yah under israeli like I've
been fins working on a fabulous book
about spam I read it drafts on
it is a really beautiful picture I love
the arms race between
and technology and has a wonderful
metaphor about web sites that are
readable by human eyes and web site web
sites that are readable by robot eyes
but
theory was like I said I'm be ever
Rogers
and if you really have to you can read
even remember Manuel
I am but sad yeah and even critics
article on
am OLPC his post mortem I'll PC was
really really good and the other person
he's working with
I forget the name of the guy he's
working with that he there's not a guy
at all PC who he likes to use
doing and a continued you lot of good
work will be /c on the social side of
things
on we were on questions yes
yes I a 7-1/2 Co yards in what way do
you think the
twitter is sort of a failure because it
because it to plus it's a costs and
why do what I don't think Twitter is a
failure know ed
in the sense of the more more from next
month
writer I don't winners actually been a
remarkably successful hack
I love up text mom but I don't think it
comes
in bed it just because it's the same
technology doesn't mean that it comes
embedded with the same social believes
that the technology was meant to foster
where was text but the social believe so
are steel
late you good you can embed them into
the platform
that the thing is that I i believe that
just because you can like said in a
Twitter account to follow can US
and then you can make bump into things
that you would have never bumped into
your name and yeah an epic actually
the thing I'm sorry time other things
that I keep thinking about is actually
I'd like Twitter's doing remarkably
better than Facebook
an ans does continue to have that in
that the
the company continues to make good
decisions better decisions about privacy
movies but
not that was once but better for the
most part live gone to bat for privacy
every once in a while
here's what I would say quickly I think
that the there's a the question is is
Twitter good at serving certain
activist causes because it has this sort
of
text ma BD n/a built into it right is
there something about
the the affords the platform that allow
it to do certain things really well
um for Sega time I'll simply say the
answer is yes but
on and I don't entirely disagree with
you actually I'll
but I do think for the purposes of this
talk it's important to keep in mind that
the two things are not automatic
I don't think I think even in bed
affordances
don't make certain social behaviors and
don't make certain social beliefs
automatic but at in primarily I just
think that
the relationship between textiles winter
is a great way to house
and a conversation about this right it's
a great way to have an argument about
you know to what degree are social
technological affordances embedded
within technology because you can see
the relationship the relationship is not
hidden there's an actual genealogical
relationship
between these technologies and I think
another thing to remember is that human
beings have free will
don't forget that they will do things
like help let up in
in in the CD Drive I mean it's just we
come up with inventive ways to do things
and to believe that things are
in a lot too bleak coded into the
technology
is to deny free well I think we need to
keep just
continue to engage with that as we're
thinking about this last week
believe that no longer exists some much
one more start we have stopped thanks on
our side thank you so much
amazing crowd for 11 on hey on this year