slight the second side um for anybody
who just walked in
I'm tight Fernandes mud I have a handle
in the program I don't care I just
really didn't want my name associated
with this
on the web on so money's tight Fernandez
I'm here talk about
semiconductors %uh is a QR code on here
if you want to follow along
on your iPad a Android device or other
I going like that'll take your Dropbox
and you can follow along on slides
so I called inseparable from magic thats
I'm
as an end I'm an engineer I kinda find
the term magic a little bit insulting
when people refer to my work
re: or the work of other engineers on
because it's not magic
its sweat implied and mental stability
that goes into these things to make them
work I use the term several magic
because
from working in the industry I can tell
you that's a fairly standard response
a what happened we don't know why does
it work
it's magic on that's from the people who
now sup
inseparable from at cal/osha looking at
here is the first
ever solid-state transistor Bell Labs
if you haven't read the book the Idea
Factory it talks about this in detail
it's incredible on so disclaimers not
read the disclaimer I'm gonna talk about
something else um
family time p.m. for questions if you
have a question
everything has a slight number in the
bottom right which we can actually see
which is fantastic
please reference the slide number helps
me out with the answer your question
more detail I'm at the end if you missed
the download link
I have the download link people who are
the six just audio there's a download
link at the end
I will read out I hate that this light
is necessary but
semiconductor companies are kind of me
the federal government look silly in
terms of IP security and like I said
I like this industry to work for so this
is me
I have the degree in mechanical
engineering at work in four different
facets of work in a
wide range weird things from by
chromatography to
I micro metrology too thin films
deposition to what we call yield
analysis
I've worked in the range of things from
academic research to
development to production thats me at
work
so I played out attach I shouldn't have
that picture
that's a diff story sup what we talk
about
was still statistics first um this is a
human hair
upscale 40 micron diameter human hair
that's a fairly average human hair
in 1971 Intel ready released the
Intel four thousand and four that was a
10 micron
device %uh line size so that's
a scale 10 Mike that's in 1971
here's 1990 806
here's 2000 138 meters
can everybody see that dot if you can
see that dot
raise your hand okay there's a dot there
that's 2010
two years ago um 13 at a mere
is in relation to human hair a week
I did the math at one point you can put
something like a gigabyte of information
nowadays you could store gigabyte in a
human hair
with modern transistor technology on
so this is the basis as whom do we know
how a transistor works
self-destruct from a semiconductor
solid-state physics am point there are
six
major parts to a transistor you
substrate that is the silicon wafer the
the back the background have the
bottom-up on that's what everything is
built on top of you have the source
and a drain those are effectively think
of them as the terminals there
the where you plug in the wires up ones
positive ones negative
what we do is we put impurities dope
it's things like phosphorous
arsenic I other stuff
I'm just say other stuff into the
surface the way for changing the
electoral characteristics of it
so that we can make it more or less %uh
electro
electrically conductive electrically
resistive
things like that are on the top we have
a gate insulator that insulates the gate
material which is where we flow the
current
that is the on-off switch up from the
body of the transistor here
K the last thing on top is the gates of
what happens in a transistor is
we flow electricity through the gate the
that generates a field
that enables us to turn the transistor
on and off
K so here's what it looks like in
practice this is a
the I research transistor this is not
anything you ever see in manufacturing
so what you're seeing here electoral
test ads
so that anyone who wants can connect to
the transistor
I'm so that kicks down into contact with
her where they actually
access things a source drain a gay
so if we at power to this with
intellectual bias cross these two
adding power here connects these two
alright
so here's how it looks in the
I guess Microsoft art I as we apply
a possible tage we begin to formally
pinged channel
on thats electricity beginning for
across the transistor
as it we continue to turn it more and
more on and
on and off become relative which is fine
I'll
this is what happens we actually begin
to forcefully for me on transistor
on the parlance that is used in the
industry
is I'll electrons and holes
cell electrons go this way electron
holes or the absence electrons go that
way
we don't talk about I you when you if
you think back to high school chemistry
humor
valence electrons on
lot of materials have either one or two
elements in their outer valence
a lot of materials have one or two holes
now turbulence we deal in
trading electrons for holes as they move
the process how we create
kind of flow sup I first thing that's
going to break your mind
transistors are not ditch
so we we make digital logic circuits out
of them but they're not digital
this is what arm the electronic response
curve other transistor
looks like so on the top on on the
y-axis here you have
on effectively current that is flowing
across the transistor
and on the bottom you have how much
voltage were applying to the
there are four things you should key
backer
this is of if you notice I we're looking
at
this is a large scale so wonder the
negative second on time today a second
that's not zero up on
is kinda nebula state where it's mostly
on
so we start to talk about things in
terms of the threshold
the threshold voltage is where we get
that shoulder where things start to turn
on where things start to behave like
their on and not of
and everybody talks about power and heat
in transistors and computer chip usage
this is affectively the majority of what
they're talking about
they're talking about the change the
fact that our of state is not as of
as it could be which is a term the kinda
master be for a while and I started in
this industry of being offered
is very very important sup basis of
construction
arm we're talk to some other tools on
the technology they're using to
manufacture these
that we're gonna get into what the
transistor actually look like Alex up
personal a fat reno's Elise what a fab
you guys probably think I've
love them a bunny suits Intel
commercials lotsa stuff
this is what a fat actually looks like
it's about four to five levels
on this is a picture Samsung's brand new
spanking new fad in Austin Texas
that nowadays in their usual spot
remover to wafers will talk about that
next slide but their usually modern fab
sir about 300
thousand square feet manufacturing space
so that's large
now consider there was a class one thing
class run
one clean room means there's one half
micron
particle one per cubic foot I didn't mix
units stake you can talk to
I saw arm sold as a reference
ever use really operating rooms
operating rooms are class 10,000
so so if you want to have surgery this
is probably a better place
so I wafers wafers are cool on these are
what we manufacture on
their poll they are actually a single
crystal on everything back to
crystals in science in chemistry if I
were to take
on this this is an Indian they grow them
like this in a furnace like this
using something called the X cross key I
can actually pronounce this word process
it onto its on wiki look it up on the
making its
we making kits that are literally a
single crystal and then we slice them
into individual wafers
that India if I could look at it on a
molecular slate scale
arm from me atomic stamp I could take it
I could turn on and
cut off the front cut off the back and
look
if you're a whole between all the atoms
from the front to the back
they all lie to perfectly arm
thats very important because the only
way they can make the process work
contamination levels about .1
parts-per-billion
is the is the acceptable higher went
2000 was 2011 earthquake in Japan
cut worldwide wafer production by 25
percent
scared the heck out of everyone on
reason is
that see big furnace that melts silicon
when the power goes off to it
what happens it'll crystallizes it's now
shock
it has to be replaced restart takes
about a month
up solely for sites everybody's probably
making
so we make these in circles yeah we make
my circles and
this is like 1955 one inch wafers so
dime nickel sized right I nowadays
everybody who's anybody uses 12-inch
wafers about the size of a dinner plate
on we're doing twenty to Nana meter
feature size on something the size of a
dinner plate
with is darn close to 100 sack uses we
could
there's a initiative called the global
450 initiative
up in Albany they're making four hundred
and fifty millimeter wave technology
work so this is a 12-inch wafer
Tom I'm also a 12-inch wafers put your
palms together
this is the diameter up outside your
office is about six inches
those are 18 inches arm thats very
very very large
K folks front opening unified pots
I talk about clean rooms I am modern
fab you don't touch waivers you don't
handle wafers on
even with two pairs lots on the SOL from
the Swat on your skin
will contaminate them they're trashed
folks
art lesson front opening if i Pods
that's where we put the silicon
wafers when we manufacture them they are
totally handled automatically
I robotics they are held at subclass one
are cleaner mark last one thing is no
water clean enough
to make these things work if you're back
to the first light
human hair obverse is what the die sizes
you can see why that
kinda happens it prevents contamination
they also kala ko them
to prevent contamination i guess i
enter contamination between waivers at
different stages a manufacturing
sup a tool this is the photography
photography is two largest at the core
technology
I love semiconductor manufacturing sick
or because for years and years and years
and years and years
its usually been the technological
limiter in terms of making
things small I know I'm anybody is your
nose on
knows this field I'm prolly stretching
it a little bit but
lithography is important photography is
photography on E
very weird scale on so what happens is
we caught the way for
in a thing called voters steady photo
reactive chemical
I we then have be pattern radical a mask
is interchangeable terms for and shiny
very very
right light through it and printed on
the way for
on these two pieces of equipment
vaulting doing modern the fuck
track here this peace agreement only
handles the photoresist
it coats the way for you're talking they
measure the sicknesses and and strums
names 10 have an animator I
and eight develop it date printed they
bake it so that we have
which replicate that pattern the other
piece is this year's hottest efforts the
scanner
that's the piece of equipment that
actually manufactures actually
Prince that pattern onto the surface up
the way for
I this year modern one $35 million
dollars
up that's not such a big deal some a
connector factories
eighty monthly time that's a big deal
some manufactures
especially because on the lens set on
these
you if you think about your printing the
same pattern hundreds if not thousands
of times a day
I everything so i cant think that a
camera lens key where out a camera lens
when we're talking about this level love
precision
you can start to wear out the lense on
your shooting photons
the exact same spot on the lens over and
over and over again
you where the lenses out on from put on
a corrosion
suck and it's not that they don't work
it's that
the art accurate enough anymore army
takes a couple years
you're starting to see it though people
these eight-inch still om
look staffers are wearing out from
Lindsay's arm
modern technology uses 193 enemy light
I'm if you've been paying attention you
know we're not making transistors 193
animators
so we're making things smaller than the
wavelength of light were using to print
features
sup that makes life hard that makes
lithography weird
we get cool stuff arm lockerbie
technique improvement what
optical proximity correction so if I
want to print
this l-shaped on a wafer you think might
put that
l-shape on a mask if I do that
I get that she that doesn't work in some
areas it's bigger it doesn't like
internal corners doesn't like external
corners
this shape Sox
so strike at what if I printed that she
that shape on is numerically determined
basically %uh calculated in a
supercomputer
on they do it on ever almost every
single layer every single mass
every single device it prints a shape
that looks like
so overlay here %uh the cut and is the
old shape
the graze the sheep that helps us
immensely
I because still were using light its
bigger
then the devices so next step
I anti-reflective coatings I'll the top
sold these are large features
used to you demonstrate this technique
on the left this is without the coating
which are seen you see that pattern
the kinda the repeating pattern the wall
that's the photon possibly
yeah so without the coding um
it bounces back in a totally different
might bounce back
it does its own thing if we put coating
called anti-reflective
it is lots a different terms this one's
copyrighted I'm using anyways
difficult coating on the bottom we
control the reflection
we make we play with constructive
destructive interference
we make that that's an improvement so
this is a big feature the top on two big
feature
I you can see the pattern this I could
still make it to myself
let's go to the bottom bottom is when
you make it to a normal
by sight this is without that looks like
crap
this is with that looks like railroad
tracks right
so this is huge enabling technology um
the next enabling technology on the talk
about to get the same time is
I a quick advances what you're seeing
here is
have a a couple of pictures about
immersion lithography
you just heard a commercial harbury's
it's the big thing intel's doing this
now wow
arm basically we're taking advantage
%uh the affect you get when you tryin
bro rocket something apart it misses
you get refraction water has a very
different index refraction
than air I this is our land see you can
follow the individual beams a light
with air the they're all spread out with
water
we compete we can use water clear water
between the lens and the way for
piece them together day art
better quality control and using that
same 193 and you're like
we can theoretically physically make
smaller features
arm getting this to work took
the decade they've been working on this
for years odd dues
two different kind of theories on how to
do it one of them is def the entire way
for in water
that's really problematic because you
have to move the way for around
are means you're getting a lot ripples
in the water the water moves around
enlargement around
you can't print straight through it so
instead
the kinda generally adopted solution om
is
recovered water its in a lot of ways
worse
but it works they don't get the whole
way for what they do is they have the
feed side
look what they call it would supply and
liquid recovery
and establish a pee bottle of water
between the lens
and the way for on the stage which moves
it from
chip to chip are continuously the water
par that major delay was
producing water clean enough to do this
by the
do it now its incredible arm
I'm blown away that they actually got
this to work
self the other one that you can start
hearing about in a couple years
actually there's a press release this
week Intel just invested a billion
dollars
in making this technology work this is
S and L's other company company that
makes these things the UV
UV means extreme UV
we're pushing the wavelength of light
that we're using
to print these down down down the
smaller the wavelength of light
the better we can make these features
for all the other reasons we talked
about
on the problem EV is what I'm extremely
light debt
you can't do it in an air environment
which means you can't use merge
of because all the water evaporates UV
is so week as a light source that you
have to do it in a vacuum
or the wavelength the wave property so
this is
up in albany I am they've been releasing
some pictures this is the
currently as far as I know only the UV
development tool
on this is just the stepper this is the
part that does the printing not the
coating
that's a human being this is the tool
there's one of these right now arm so
this is what you're gonna see in 10 or
are up hopefully five years not
reachable
are ion implantation site talked about
gates and sources and drains
this the sources in the drains are
what we used to kinda generate each in
sister that behaves the way
one om to do that we insert opens %uh
lots of different materials into the
service the waiver
the the used to do it when they called
spin on class
and the diffusion a fact it's been a
contaminant on top overlayer
lithography and then you debate the way
for and using the properties at Fusion
the way for would suck it in nowadays
the use
ion implantation I and implantation is
the LHC struck size down
it is literally a particle sorry take
the gas that you what
you put it in here you
run it through particle accelerator and
you shoot it
embedded Adam by Adam in the surface of
the wafer
on materials for this include
gas if I'd arsenic I'll
xylene which was initially as a that
that story is told me as eileen was
developed as a nerve gas now use
semiconductors
up the wafers about 400 degrees C
and these things use permanent magnets
there are very large and run about 400
amps
lot the people who work on the answer
weird the people in the fab who
don't work on these stay far away
are dude is the constant story of a
rumor that is not supported by any
statistical fact that
the people who work in these only have
girls on the disproven that nobody
believes
so chemical vapor deposition
I wanna put a layer on the surface of a
way for its very controlled how do I do
it
on chemical vapor deposition that he is
one of the three ways to do it
visible vapors that deposition is
another thats starting to go away
because it's
imprecise I'm imprecise is a relative
term so chemical vapor deposition I have
usually in argon curtain are gone
isolation gasser
something inner week you could hear the
UC on
me on it doesn't matter anything from
the far right into the periodic table
then we start flowing other gases oMG
might flow
I you know what say that home
you float to compounded gases that form
a chemical reaction
usually it's a service on the reactions
were doing a chemical reaction on the
surface of the wafer
that literally causes the layer of what
you want
to organically grow usually to
temperature you can control
on growth rate temperature or you can
control
your for me for temperature uniformity I
didn't mention uniform we talk about
building a dream only way
we can control thickness better
in a lot of ways to me but you have to
control uniformity
if you talk about something that's will
say 5 nanometers thick
a layer that's five meters thick if it's
five millimeters thick
everywhere on the way for you're happy
camper the transistor or behave the same
everywhere if it's five at one point for
another
38 another 6 another you have
infinite number very differ transistors
so
uniform is a big deal chemical vapor
deposition is very good
at uniformity something that's better
uniformity
is called atomic layer deposition on
this is what
I think most companies are starting to
use now for any
%ah fitness and uniformity critical
layers
it's basically not dissimilar to the
concept of a pox it's two parts
you flow one part one
pre reacted over the surface the way for
then you
evacuate use a vacuum pump on then you
flow the second
they react you pump out the byproducts
and you're left with
one layer I love Adams form a lot
molecules on the surface the way for
it's incredibly conformal
conformal is huge because you start to
get things that are very tall in very
narrow
what you're looking at here's how to
test structures is to two hundred and
beers right here
let's think about that we have the exact
same thickness
up until it pinches all the way around
chemical vapor key deposition
you can't do that physical vapor
deposition really struggles with it so
you will resume in here
you can see layer by layer by layer by
layer
its really bombers developed in the
nineteen sixties in Russia
I in about 99
there so they finally started to figure
out how to use it and it started to
really come into play I
its I'm Ste gonna say around 2,000
5 2008 somewhere in that in that range
on the benefits are twofold like I said
the first is conform Allen the
pic it's the same thickness throughout
the entire length layer
on the other one is when we're doing at
layer by layer
sickness control becomes really easy
because we just
matters track players we don't have to
worry about timing nearly as much
you can do a lot of different materials
with this unfortunately
here do you have to engineer the
reactions
om from the precursors and so it gets a
little complicated
by you part because you can't do things
like silicon nitride silicon nitride
is a very common material to use on ash
top
mom in semiconductors using that stopped
to control the shape
DEP the profile things at you moving
from the way for
and so it the college top silicon
nitride you can't do I
as far as I know can't deposit silicon
dioxide
either with alte atomic layer deposition
which up up until very recently silicon
dioxide is being kinda the
the standard dialect recurrence live
material for chips
account I'm okay sewn up science and
me talking I mention hoops let's watch a
video
see how this works
so I kinda mentioned group
this is afoot foo 25 wafers
I'd say you're talking sixty thousand
dollars in revenue from a
up leading edge way for on terms revenue
in
chips and RAM memory 25
wafers in a full 60 grand makes
now 1.5 million dollars this is a bad
day
I concept one
don't do that concept to from anyone
who's working a technical field the
radius a plane
I the
if you notice the time clock
a basic EPS in time but they're it's
five thirty in the morning
so what happened here
um and engineers day just got very bad
are if he's not up already the engineer
got woken up now
I the
I'm not kidding and huh
oh yeah no cameras
on at least one other places I work we
had phones
they want to be like in touch you 24/7
when I got my phone
it was a blackberry had a hole drilled
in the back where there used to be a
camera
it was yet its
you prolly VoIP on they're trying to
move away from using radios which they
used to use
radios will screw up the tools EM for
radio will
shift all your parametric ce it may even
shut down the tool
so what happened there we mention fukes
and wafer handling and subclass one the
tool
has a robot arm that does all the way
from its the robot missed
um the reason there's a video cam their
video cameras are not comment in fact
they
they just arm most likely those weren't
really
those were cast wafers what they call
cycling wafers they're trying to figure
out what the handling problem with was
the with the toll was
they found um the robot
most likely had a a misalignment and
when I tried to put the way for it holds
the way for you vacuum
hit the Foo rather than com
is uniquely normally the poops a lot to
the table
if it unlocked to the tool om it would
have been worse
because the two the way for with a
broken inside the tool
and making it clean again may not ever
happen
it's back so what they did there wasn't
a lot
through so that if that happened it'll
they thought it would probably mover
shifter catch the way for
I out the plan that for the win running
sup
so that's cuff alright so
the steps here's what in modern
transistor kinda looks like so
first thing is we have are substrate we
have such a hearing blue
first step that always happens nowadays
is
what's called so shallow trench looking
trench isolation the devices are so
small so close together
I'm so kinda not behaving like we want
them to we can just keep
control over them that they start have
started to things where they basically
insert
insulator between each device I speak
French crosstalk
it prevents leakage prevents one
transistor for turning on another
transistor
so that's the first thing that happened
second thing that happens we put down
our gate insulator here's a part that we
know
we had six parts we're gonna turn it
into a lot more parts
object the gate insulator
goes down and it does two things one it
is our gate insulator it
isolates the gate at the transistor from
the body the transistor so we can
make it working not have a short to when
we
openness of itself Alliance for us
all the steps we're going to do after
insulators highly critical
and because that they want everything
everything is to align with it
so they do this step first the deposit
Rd
get material for years and years and
years think of polysilicon sir
hold the question thanks I'm
I'm is a lot in here arm it's in poly
silicon which is a
different crystalline version is seldom
use a substrate
its more electrically conductive its
tall
I'm so it can stand up to all the future
processing
that's what they've been using their
going away from that now top
pas our source in our dreams dope are
sore surgery
so we begin to form with and I am
planner the
regions that we won to connect the
transistor do that we want to be a
transistor
then we form a small spacer spacer does
a bunch of things
it's not electrically really part of the
transistor but it's absolutely necessary
modern
transistors because it contains the gate
it also narrows these openings
which becomes really important when we
do was quite deep source injury
the initial opens here very very light
that we do a heavier doping
on this allows us to begin Tran having
the single region
for the source in a single region for
the drain I you're getting very much
towards custom profile its
curve rather it analog versus digital
sources dream
disagree with on then we far south side
so at some point we have to connect
these transistors to the outside world
if you think about a city the transistor
is your house
everything that goes above it allows the
transistor to talk to the outside world
is the streets the highways gets
progressively big
Saleh side what they do is effectively
they're kinda makes a museum
metal and silicon the former
a I guess ur helluva
gap coverage so that we can actually get
them to talk
we do on top each the source the train
and on top of the key
then we drive the Dolphins so we talked
about the two
two different these are really like
fourteen different
implants to get this the way we want
then we set we heated up a very high
temperature
over 1000 BCE for less than a second
and diffusion diffusion happens and
everything moves around and we end up
with very much a profile in here
that can channel the locations in the
densities of electrons
and holes very much exactly where we
want them so we control things like
the leakage the threshold voltage things
like that
that would posit I lectured at this
point were done making what we'll call
device down here now we begin the
connected to the outside world
so for some it was we see all the whole
thing that happen so that they
Cantley we don't want om electricity
getting from one to another
and we want to build isolate up edge
trenches and contacts this is the first
step in
having something they can talk to we
deposit
a medal in there we still have a week
off till contacts in trenches
we have twice that we back in processing
so this point we have your house we have
your driveway
um then we start building with a metal
layers switch in the back and crossing
that
I get to really hear but which is what
interconnects
individual transistors individual places
in a logic circuit in the logic circuits
into
memory Kors into everything you need to
make
a computer chip out quantities on I
talked about these is like
what 10 or 11 steps here these are steps
these are what we would call in fab
parlance segments
on like this
14 15 steps if not more this whole set
by the time it goes to what you call the
back end it's about three weeks later
if you're good and somewhere in the
range I'd say five hundred steps
that's I'm plea arrangement but 500
steps
we've done 500 different things 500
different tools to the way
as it takes I have the backup site
through it
how you build the shallow trenches
without any trilogy
quality control error checking mom
inspection it's at least 13 different
steps
just the physical actions required to
put those trenches
Witcher probably the simplest feature on
here in place
sup that's what it looks like when we
talked about it as a theoretical device
this is what it looks like now
here's what it looks like in a7 picture
so you can start to actually see the
features here are those trenches
we talked about com aspect ratio very
very called
very very narrow you can see these are
the contacts
that we talk at the last up the connects
to the outside world here
that little car a white dot that's our
Saleh side
here sources and drains
everything in here exists policy in the
air this is like the transistor itself
this is the things you're probably
thinking I've
and if you look at it like this let's
zoom in a little more
kept this is a 2010 you're a sixteen
animator device
right now om think
Toshiba has a 14 animator
grammar memory technology that they're
starting to manufacture so that's
what is a former 5th or 4th the size
here is the zoom in of our source our
train
our gate our contact our south side in
our contact at
16 and here's why this is in a lot of
fun this isn'ta whole lot
let's zoom in more here's the key so you
see that
that's 1.2 nanners arm
you reached a point at this point this
is using a traditional a silicon dioxide
insulated
gate insulator they don't measure that
name used to measure
sanctions when you're here you talk
about monolayers
I guess what a model areas the layer
about us
that's four
how deep a tolerance on three probably
shorts out
five probably won't connect
it takes a minute it takes me a minute
processed
yes I'll the link between the source in
the drain
that channel that we talked about on
this device
282 monolayers 182 Adams between the
source and drain
this device i sat 2010 arm
I'm not really sure where this came from
it was a research paper
on the coated the clock speed
up the a V chip that this came out as
10 gigahertz I don't know if that's
right of trial
I don't care but they also gave
really interesting number which is the
transistors eats everything's what clock
speed you think about
from a gigahertz is my processor so this
a
10 gigahertz clock speed
it's a 200 gigahertz transistors
so that's not uncommon you're talking
these things are switching on/off
in the picosecond range arm so that's
to me really cool what does that look
like so here's
zoomed it this is what it looks like in
the context up your whole check
that little chip you have inside your
computer cut it open with the
electron beam she this is what it looks
like here
this is Intel 20 name is a publicly
releases don't worry
and here is Apple's 45 net Meter process
for Samsung
that's in your iPad at the top you can
see the very large metal layers this is
what the outside world
next to this is what the packaging
connects to
metal layers get apparently smaller
smaller smaller small smaller
this is all back at all we've talked
about the green park here
yes see that down there those the device
that's all in one package this the
is I to estimate a 100 micron
vertical thickness here same thing over
here you can see
the contacts there that all narrow
things down there
then you can start to see the individual
devices in the in the parks down there
so that's war-making that's what all
those individual parts on the front
I so modern improvements
thats fairly modern where we going in
the last four years where we going in
the future on the goals
archive threefold really make
of of I'll
for additional vice to a weird but word
producing leak for making it so that
when we tell it to be off
it's all we wanna make the difference
between on and off
sharp we want to me as are ability to
turn things
on and off faster means we can go faster
and we can start
changing other features the transistor
because reality is decision
like these are independent parts every
single point on here is related to every
single other point
if we can make the sharper weak and
inherently return our process to make
of of and the other thing is make
on sooner I'll if we can make on and off
sharper
if we can make of offer we can start
making on sir
we bring it down the voltage scale means
we use less power
and we have to ramp that both the job
even if it's a big risk even its
half a bolt we have to ramp that voltage
up
from zero that takes time
doesn't take long but it takes time so
freakin lower threshold voltage is a
little bit
wearing a faster chip were used less
energy because energies cumulative
in all that are we take ramping up TT
cell
every changes we make Israel eat kinda
change one of these three things
arm first strained silicon I I forget
the year
people started doing this it was like
um its controlling
in a way the electrical properties you
deposit a layer on top
arm daddy's Larkin so pure silicon atoms
there
this close together we deposit something
like silicon germanium
on top of it misses I guess those
pictures upside down
it stretches are silicon I depending on
the device type we might want to stretch
it out
we might want to push it together we can
use that to control
the electron mobility the silicon we can
make things faster we can make
slower we knew everyone on this is
credited with a 35 percent
improvement in transistors be once
is actually up forty sucks but one
change one design shit
next us is a strained silicon practice
here's our transistor
strain channel we put it in there we
spread the sort Adams out
we've created less traffic the problem
is we have to do other things because
less traffic means Italy but the ability
to have less traffic means we can start
doing other things
we also start straining the source in
the drain it allows us to do even more
detail control
then and this is very high level but
very more detail control
then the I'm opens on
how the transistors behave how that
source in the dream him what the
electoral properties Mr
so alright high-k metal gate if you're
serious
Intel pimps this very hard other people
are doing it as well
it's not just so couple size I showed 8
2010 are a transistor with a
normal key was for for Adams right
you can't manufacture really thinner
than that with a sort of quality control
soul the only way to do it is we needed
to
act electrically like it's dinner so we
make it stick
Wii U removed from silicon dioxide to
other materials with different on
cautions
that allow us to make it thicker will
make an electrically act
Center om has it's really just I'm
too thin to be practical awesome
material changes
here's what it looks like your Tom
silicon substrate Hughes Rd
I and you see metal gate which is the
second technology will talk about that
a second and here's the high-k we had
four monolayers
can see there's a lot of monolayers the
law
that's good for the areas were making
things bigger makes things better
it's rare in this world um the other one
is metal gate
so really desire to technologies that
kinda got issues
same time because it's in sector
manufacturing reasons but
the metal gate is here's your hike 8
I'll
I lectured and you're starting to do
different
things in here besides poly silicon the
advantages metal has far lower
resistance than the policy
it's more efficient we can do things
faster
lower leakage the differences very
touch I'll that deep drive step that I
talked about we're moving to open
surround can you be any manufacturing
process
will destroy your day if you're not
careful see have to be very very careful
very fragile on metal was actually the
original
material the use back in the seventies
and so forth
four gates they got away from it because
it had manufacturing issues
the don't have a choice now they have to
go back to it to keep the improvement of
what they want cell so here's how it
looks
so the gayest holler
and then this goes from being one step
something stacked up
Southside stacked on the top it to
why don't wanna reveal anything but a
lot of different steps
a lot of different materials because
what you're doing is you're engineering
an electrical field here by how you
stack medals
here and how you flow electricity so we
can control that feel better
we can target that field I N there's
been some
theoretical research done on basically
using antenna theory where it's
normally a field is right fairly
ubiquitous nearly circular
at FM antennas they can do directional
antennas
interference they're starting to talk
about using that here so that our field
goes here
and doesn't go here in here that's
hugely beneficial because we can put
transistors closer together
so order operations going back to
what I how much do these are the steps
the
gate insulator was the first thing right
that doesn't work anymore with a lot of
new technology the gates are fragile
the high came gates or fraud I kick its
leaders are fragile
the metal gates are from cell we build
them last
but we still need that key their to
define our transistor ship sell
we move from the county first which is
where we do the key first two date last
what the last releases in most cases d
first
and then do it again last cell we got
the gate
then we removed so this creates on
proscar the spacers are still there and
this is
and over dramatization of what's going
on but it works
arm the spacers are still there but we
have nothing here
we might have a little layer silicon
dioxide still in there but character
then we put our hike again with her
Holgate
because we had the spacers there we have
to be very careful how we feel this this
is where
alte comes in as otherwise me and big
open legal
void whole inside the key the socket
doesn't works om and we build
everything else normally right that
icing is in some cases you can get rid
of the south side
on top gay wish for it does remove steps
because it's metalitz easier to connect
cell back depletion up till now we
talked about
building things on our nice blue I don't
know why sulcus blue but it's blue
I substrate the problem is
all that energy all those electrons can
we crown axle semiconductors not really
electrically conductive it's not really
a slave years kinda in the middle
we take advantage when we start to have
problems with things
leaking all over the place that we want
something to build on that is more
electrically resist we want to totally
customize
everything about this transistor silicon
wafer is it a good starting point
so person we do put ice layer dialect we
just say
to hack with this way for or we might
even change out the entire way
say Rakhi Sawant name or email you
something else courts
is one of the ones it's been proposed
then we put our own substrate
then we put our own semiconducting
material that to this point we just
replicated the work
of the way for but in a much much more
controlled fashion
this is the exact thickness that we want
it's the exact material that we want
dope at the we only have exactly what we
want for starting point
then we do normal trench our normal
isolation trenches to this point I know
have
almost Faraday cage in fact fairy cage
but it
eyes where I can build my transistor its
isolated on all three sides I don't just
have a site isolation
like I do now isolated the bottom two
electrons can't ski
out of then everything else same
it's just compressed it's a lot smaller
area we can control it a lot more
ends up with the same transistor sitting
on top of a nice piece of insulating
material
it helps every here's the last
arm so Intel
least these in a way they said 2011
and the press releases like they've been
working on it since 2007 or before
finfacts on everything
as I said is about turning things on and
off faster better
offer are we have this year this is our
standard design explainer
the key is on top the gate is basically
interrupting
flow this one om if you think about
think about a a lens of a camera be for
your camera lenses
you have your aperture if I
had eighty aperture and I just closed it
from the top
that'll take a certain amount time for
to travel the distance steady spiral
lectures
I have an aperture if in fact all three
sides I
gate on all three sides I can close out
of much faster I can generate feel much
faster
I can improve everything about the
transistor
this is what they look like you're not
growing silicon teens
in the space um what you're seeing here
is they're actually starting to rather
building one transistor their building
one transistor
that they can there so from a survey
the used to use different size
transistors different sized mayor
transistors for different
power different voltages things like
that in this they've moved away from
that model
you make one size fit it's very hard to
go the things we don't want to try and
produce
to or five different sites say 1 and
then they
link them together like this so what
you're looking at here is you see the
ones that go in this direction
does the fins those are our source in
our drain they just stick up
so because they're the stickup
electricity still flows in same
direction
and then we are key Rd surrounds all
three sides you can see that here
here surfin now we have gate all 3 sites
everywhere you look
there's a lot more T a lot closer to the
source and drain
so what does that do in terms of
performance
power 50 percent lower
while also not or also
being forty percent faster
the trade-off its socks to build these
things
I don't know how intel does it i wish i
did. I wish I could tell people and find
out
I have my guess is I don't know it's
incredible
up so here is our the black lines
traditional transistor
the blue lines are kinda our choices
what we can start
do you with the trike its and this is
the first generation trike
its om egos even further you can
theoretically doing T
all around which means you have to build
the game of the transistor to which
means you're doing
eat first team in the middle last I
don't know if anyone has gotten
the manufacturing that right
sup where he had I
may have this year Paul Otellini who is
I don't know what you did in telling
your buddies I'll I think you never
tired
disclosed and noms it was a quarterly
earnings call
that they're doing seven and your device
R&D in 2011 a number of different
company started selling
fat 22 nanometer transistors tumor that
human hair
forty am yours yeah I'm 14 and appears
on track
from what I've in toll 4 2013
so we in two years we can go from twenty
see a mere 14
here its not really a structural change
because
they don't have tried it's right nobody
us com
laps docked it's really refinement
everything some people are talking about
transitioning to 450 millimeter-wave
sites those half meter diameter wafers
on
2015 this is in development this is not
an research this isn't develop
you know bell labs you know the
difference on lithography uses
is their families as they called tipple
patterning so we talk about the
photography
if I shoot the party wants I end up with
something looks certain ways patterns a
certain way
if I using different photo versus that
requires rather than
one photon and I do mean one photon to
polymer rise an individual strand use it
it requires two
that's double patterning is this is a
horrible
description of it go look it up on week
because the people who write these
things on Wikipedia work I don't know
who they work for that work for somebody
who knows what they're talking about
printable patting patterning is taking
five
shots oval the tiger beetle to generate
one thing and this is uses averaging
up combination different masks different
techniques
so that you can use all those together
to generate what you want
on at this point that's theorized dot
sematech says
high-k that thicker gate that were used
is now a monolayer one one layer
one atomic layer collector so we are
back again
high-k becomes alter high K we just find
a different material because
if they can do that I'm I'm gonna use
only high five
I'll lots of problems here
Intel and IBM have publicly discussed
solving the problem
11 and I'm here by skipping at that
point
we're no longer in their
microelectronics wear nail trucks
2017 2019 that's what they're talking
about doing
re: research on now I'll the device size
seven and eight years
you can't get away from using UV on just
the UV light the use now
can't reach that at all just falls apart
up you be like I said doesn't work Intel
just invested a billion dollars in ASML
is a major vendor to try and make TUV
work
it doesn't work there's a lot of there
are people in the field who say
it will never work because you're trying
to use a
for to react polymer any back in
chambers a mayor
know anything about back in chambers it
will
you're talking about something that's
for solvents when you put on the way for
he will outcast so it's how do you
prevent everything from out gassing
because if you are out gassing out
gassing up of the way for
is in between the way from the less you
have gas we didn't want gas nothing
work cell that'll be interesting to Sol
then things get worse
um electrical interconnect start to have
your problems just because making things
that are electrically conductive that
small
they start talking about optical
interconnects I
they're talking about using rather than
really what I would call
digital a quantum transistors two morow
what they're calling
interference transistors where the
electrons interfere with one another
and kinda quasi turn it on and off they
don't really turn it on and off
the just thing the transistor think
that's honor of it still flowing
up they're controlling where electricity
is coming from and constructive and
destructive place
out kinda ran off the bottom here 2022
for an animator I'll there's a lot of
ideas
here ranging from quantum two things are
more exotic than quantum
I'll right now anything that's built the
decisive
actually time arm is done using a
scanning tunneling microscope what
they're doing is they're not building
things
there manually stacking aP's to make a
transistor current from what I've seen
the current winner
is a group that will be 38 Adam
transistor
sup why is this here well
here's like a every single computer chip
every single
being in your pocket uses stuff om this
is kinda how I got interested in it like
I'm interesting coating on a mechanical
engineer this was a good fit for your
car has the sings it everything as
I want more cuts I thought you guys
might want to know more about it too
I talked to a couple people and I just
started talking about it because I
you of this field and they just sat
there like oh my god
I know right it's like oh hell
just might think that is so here here we
are sup
up last like less request I at
nine minutes I actually did this right
on time which is creep
I have my Moore's law teacher on
morse okay that's the wrong question to
ask I'm sorry
know it's almost like isn't just about
sites
what is it about dance there's a lot of
things are going to density
beyond just how small we can manufacture
some but it's not just about density
either to
price as these things mature the
to get cheap Moore's Law got
I T a decade left in it before it
becomes a problem and that's
more going to be costs driven than
anything else
so other questions you ask anything I
have to backup site
yes
neutrinos are propped I the so what what
are the standard
a research and development quality
control tools is
on take one chip
you set two chips runs in Test 30 take
one down a mine
and take one of an airplane you that
used to be a problem they've just kinda
everybody has taken the approach
it's a problem will deliver software
will deliver a rich checking in circuit
design on because
if you look at the statistics those
neutrino collisions
its it happens it does happen
but if it's not going to happen odds
having the same place
in two different parts to the chip same
time highly highly unlikely
om the what there was a
this sorry
others yes
he asked about doping migration so if
I'm going to backwards here slide us
to
depletion yet so when he says doping
migration we have those
arm used laser pointer point the suckers
the sources in dreams when we put
impurities
in there they do have a tendency to over
time
around are its the law of diffusion it's
it's a physics problem
it hotter than shit gets the more likely
it is higher user cycles
I I would respond I have a saying
depletion %uh
fully depleted will help because is less
electron mobility
in these areas means they're less likely
to move around the other thing is
it depend it depends on
which wait your street if you're yes
yeah its side it's it's physics arm
I don't think people keep these chips
long enough for two people
if you look at the refresh cycle so most
if you're talking a bank summit this
high frequency trading
the NSA they save money
the chips are getting so much better so
much faster for me
our alone stemming from a power in
computational density
company you know instructions for what
competition for what
standpoint that they can replace them
every 18 months to make money it saves
them money to replace them every team's
in back
the so the question was R&D costs are
spiraling ridiculously out of control
om what's gonna happen to competition in
the industry
I so currently
to answer questions there is more than
one third the company bomb
yeah I i know im but its it's a I am
I consider it a problem as a as a hacker
as a as a person who wants to buy these
things for
the least amount of money possible on
are it's not so much the cost
as the difficult I mean
its you're going to see contraction
but do doosy I think inherent natural
trait of these things is
the companies that do the company's it
in manufacturing and do the tool
development
archive very very closely interrelated
and
because it that they have very clear
path their mind they don't always
tend to think creatively Lake hackers
I like like academics do on you're
seeing
with atomic layer deposition is is a
great example all the major tool vendors
is right see 5 major to lenders have
LD systems is also pits crop a lot of
smaller companies
that have credible guilty tools because
that's all they do because they have
people who did research on this
and they've worked all developers they
were scientists and the hooked up with
engineers they're doing really neat
things
from from standpoint the intel's the
GlobalFoundries
IBM's the TSMC's you're going to see
narrowing
I the the industry itself though at
least
outsiders I miss a outside logic is
fairly competitive
and that will I think keep prices down
but I'm not I'm not a business guy I'm
I'm not economic system do there are
definitely some structural problems is
likely 450
is going to cost anybody who wants to
build a 450 millimeter toward
massive weaver's be lot of money and so
you will see some contraction
all I can see is what I can say week see
I'd don't anybody else
in the way way back I can just barely
see I
I can't hear you
so he asked will see fit which is
focused
ion p I huh the the physics
right now other did the the right now
says we almost have to
om whether it's I don't know how they
make it realistic for manufacture
technology for so yes you'll have
focused ion beam
it's cool it's how you can basically
Adam by Adam
manufacture things I don't know how they
can make it work
so its 12:57 I got is that this one more
question
yeah alongside
right there
I don't know it scares me that's
someplace I thanks I don't