awesome hello everyone and welcome to
content security policy a successful
mess between hardening and mitigation
we're super happy to be here today this
is Mickey my name is Lucas we book from
Google Switzerland and yeah
Hawaii's awesome really enjoying this
conference so it was really rough to
travel okay we have a pretty stuffed
again agenda today we have some general
recommendations that should be usable
for for developers and security experts
but we also have some pretty advanced
topics where we go very much into detail
so if there's questions feel free to ask
me at the end or be around at the
conference so we're happy to chat about
CSP 24/7 just to grab us yes so Mickey
will start with vulnerability trends and
I'll take over in a bit oh this is for
work okay hi everyone so we'd like to
start with real world data so we focus
on cross-site scripting or exercise
vulnerabilities right and this is also
what we aim for what you mean CSP CSP is
this like a huge umbrella security
header which was originally thought as
like solving many of web security issues
but we focus on as exercise in all our
previous talks and in this Docs too so
we wanted to start with real world data
and what we have is
all the XSS vulnerability is reported to
us to Google in the vulnerability reward
program since 2014 and you can see that
like around 2/3 of them are actually web
application web platform baths and
drilling down in this web platform baths
we see that approximately 3/4 our
cross-site scripting XSS vulnerability
so XSS is a major problem and this is
reflected also outside of Google in
other sources of data other bug bounties
or vulnerability reward programs so for
example hacker one has a similar result
and also Mozilla in Zilla box reported
to Mozilla we see that XSS is actually
the top vulnerability reported there so
there is a need or defense in depth in
this field mostly because the web mostly
because the web platform is not secure
by default unfortunately we are still
not there so it is important especially
for very sensitive web applications to
have some kind of defense-in-depth
mechanism in case the primary security
security mechanism we should not be
neglected at all and actually people
should focus with them in case they fail
and we'd like to spend a word on what we
call mitigations because mitigation is a
very complex and overloaded word it
actually comes mostly the first
mitigations in computer security are in
the let's say memory safety world so
mostly for mitigating exploitation of
buffer overflows and so on right and
when we talk about web mitigation
techniques these are a little bit more
and more recent more modern so we
believe there are no mitigations are
made equal and there are some good
mitigations and some mitigations that
are less good and I'd like to start with
them first so some mitigation Zain to
just raise the bar so they have an
economy in the matter mindset is based
on an economy of cost they want to make
costly for an attacker to exploit a
vulnerability they want to slow down the
attacker so in this case in the web
world I would say that a traditional CSP
which you might have seen or read in our
previous papers and talks the whitelist
base he espies are automatically by
possible so as Jim said earlier on more
than 95% they're automatically by
possible so you attacker has just to
find bypass in the whitelist to exploit
the same bug write a symbol that was
there so in this way the the mitigation
technique did not really reduce the
attack surface but on the other hand
good mitigation techniques are the ones
that also reduce the attack surface by
for example disabling and safe api's so
for example not having unsafe Evo we see
later the details in a CSP policy means
that all evil based XSS cannot happen so
this is an actual reduction of attack
surface and this is what we call a good
mitigation there are other examples like
the nospace ESP but we see later in in
great details another important thing is
good mitigation should actually induce
hardening what we call hardening of the
application from a code point of view
for example CSP a good CSP actually
induces the developer to for example
refactor inline event handlers which are
bad for security or to use our
contextual artists getting templating
systems which greatly increases the
security with respect to reflected XSS
so with this I go through a little bit
more in detail that would kind of XSS
we're blocked at Google by CSP so this
is real world data it's the first time
we present with this detail so coverage
of CSP at Google so this effort has been
mostly three years and in three years we
are covering 62% of all outgoing Google
traffic with an enforcing non-space CSP
and these are more than 80 Google
domains so Google has a lot of domains
subdomains as you might might guess but
80 is still pretty significant number
and more than 160 services and for very
sensitive domains the traffic cover
with what we call strict CSP is very
close to 100% and the number of services
that have almost total coverage of CSP
is around 70%
how many exercises that were reported to
us got blocked by CSP so in 2018 more
than 60% of exercises that got reported
to us got mitigated successfully by our
CSP so among 11 XSS vulnerabilities on
very sensitive domains 7 of them which
is around 78% got successfully prevented
by CSP and taking into account all the
69 access vulnerabilities on sensitive
domains we have around 60% so here in
numbers with pie charts on the left very
sensitive domains on the right all the
sensitive domains I'm going a little bit
more in detail on the very sensitive
domains 11 exercises got reported of
them 9 were happening on endpoints that
were covered by CSP and CSP coverage is
actually a problem maybe we'll go into
that a little bit later because it's
important to cover all organ all of your
endpoints will CSP and of these 9 7 were
mitigated by CSP and the other two that
were injection in the SSC attribute of
script could have been mitigated by what
we call an additional whitelist policy
so we see later this is a pretty
advanced thing we're not going full
circle and advocating for whitelist
based policies so please bear with us
and we'll show you exactly what we mean
and all the - that we're not covered by
CSP they could the excesses could have
been mitigated by by a CSP we see here a
detail of our exercises and God's
reporting in 2018 we see here the the
causes the root causes what the works
have been exploited via and there are
many
many sinks or injection points but what
I'd like to highlight is that JavaScript
URI plus inline event handlers plus data
URI make up for approximately one third
of the injection points and so having a
CSP that just didn't contain the unsafe
inline keyword that actually covers
these things as shown in this table
would be enough to actually mitigate
successfully for one third of the
vulnerabilities this was also slightly
surprising for us it's pretty pretty
cool conformation so in this table we
have access sinks on the left and what
makes us be successfully block them so
there is not really a 1:1 mapping of
this to be completely honest but this is
good enough to give an idea so for
example for JavaScript your eye it's
just not having a safe in line it's
enough to block them the same for data
and the same for inline event handlers
so then we have inner HTML context that
can be either inner or not inner HTML
context which means either reflected XSS
that gets reflected by a server or a
programmatic injection in the inner HTML
property of a Dom element and and both
are prevented by not having unsafe
inline in the policy then we are evil
which is governed by the unsafe evil
directive sorry keyword and then we have
injections in the text of a script tag
which also here can be both programmatic
and reflected CSP helps if we know that
sorry if we hash the script or if we
nose and manually nonce it so strict
dynamics makes adoption easier but also
makes trust propagation and we see later
what it means so not having strict
dynamic and manually
seeing is the way to protect against
injection text to the script and it's
very likely the same for the SRC
attribute of the script then we have
some kind of complex web frameworks that
do some symbolic execution or they try
to parse they have their own templating
languages but would not go into that now
and here I pass to Lucas for some more
detail yes thank you so much Micky in
this section we would like to introduce
some common CSP recipes that you as
developers or security engineers can
reuse they basically are ordered by the
ease of deployment and by the amount of
syncs they're covering everything we
talk about in this section is about an
on space CSP and I will give a very
quick intro and it's a kind of a mix of
like high level stuff like just use this
policy and you will get these guarantees
versus like a really detailed
explanation of like what kind of
guarantees you will get for that right
so that you'd not just like blindly
trust a CSP because people say yes they
have a CSP but what does it mean right
they could just allow everything or they
can also have a default source non
policy that blocks everything right it
really doesn't tell you anything so are
the obligatory slide on why not the
white list I feel like almost like a
broken record on Twitter telling people
to not use by at least anymore thank you
so the thing is usually they're
trivially by possible because as Jim
already mentioned we did a study a
couple years ago based on the Google
search index we took all the CSP
policies we found almost all of them
were rightly spaced and as soon as you
know a couple of JSONP end points or
angularjs libraries hosted on popular
dns CD ends you basically can bypass all
of them right and even if you host if
you only allow self as soon as you have
like you know JSONP endpoint or your
host some angularjs library it's also
makes your policy completely by possible
so basically with a whitelist you tie
the security to the policy not being by
possible per se rather than actually
closing a sync
and just a couple of talks we had in the
past so there's links in the bottom you
can look them up later will not cover
this topic any into any more detail
today what we will cover is known space
CSP and I just wanted to ask the
audience have you heard about known
space CSP before is it the first time
awesome some hands up nice so just a
quick recap the idea is basically only
scripts that have a random nonce
attribute that is random pair response
will be allowed to execute and this
non-spell you in the script tag has to
match the nonce value in the response
header the content security policy
response header only then the browser
will execute this script tag so in that
case if you have a markup injection and
the attacker injects a script with
invalid known to revert announced the
browser will block this script from
executing so CSP is a client-side
defends and type strategy right so
non-space CSP has been around since many
years it was actually introduced in CSP
too but it was not really picked up by
anyone the reason is that this is very
hard to deploy in normal applications so
in CSP free strict dynamic code added
it's a small modification it basically
instructs the browser to only allow are
to also allow scripts to execute that
are created dynamically within an
already trusted script so this makes a
huge difference because the only thing
you have to do now is actually nonce
scripts in the response body and you
don't have to knowns all the scripts in
your application and that's especially
important if you for example load
widgets from third-party sites where you
don't control the JavaScript right if
they do like dynamic script creation you
will not be able to make them pass the
nomes or you can file a feature request
and hope that they do it but usually
that's a blocker otherwise so what we'll
focus in this part is basically
incremental rollout of content security
policy
GSB is often a trade-off between the
amount of sinks xs/s sinks you're
actually covering with your policy and
the effort to roll out the policy which
is mostly the refactoring work you have
to do if you remove a sink right like if
you remove an answer if API like ebo you
have to make sure that the application
is not using this sink right otherwise
you'll break so there is a refactoring
effort and the the the refactoring is
mostly based on the type of CSP like how
many sinks are closing and your
application of course like the size of
application the amount of inline event
handlers to code quality etc so we came
up with a couple of templates that
basically we mapped on the following
slides to the table that Mickey
presented you before so if you start at
the bottom you basically have a lot of
remaining attack surface what is very
easy to adopt if you go further up it's
harder to adopt but you cover more sinks
and the the goal is eventually to get up
to a nonce only policy I guess but not
it is not possible in every application
right so and since it's loco moco's sec
we also have a level 1 CSP that uses
like brand-new CSP free features that
haven't been presented anywhere else yet
I think it's very interesting for some
use cases but usually I would recommend
to start either before level 2 level 3
CSP and if you can move up to a nonce on
the CSP so level 2 CSP is like arbitrary
definition we choose for a non spaced
CSP that has strict dynamic and also an
safe Evo it's kind of a sweet spot
because it's kind of easy to roll out
because the refactoring effort is kind
of manageable but it covers a lot of
very common exercise things as a matter
of fact this type of policy is set on
60% of all the outgoing Google traffic
on sensitive domains and that was the
one that Nicki meant with
which mitigated between 60 and 80
percent of the exercise so it's a good
starting point but if you can usually
you know go further the nice thing is
because it's a non speech policy it
mitigates all the classical reflected
and stored XSS in your application right
and it also works if you don't control
all the JavaScript yourself if you have
a widget that you load from Facebook
Twitter Google Analytics whatever and
these widgets are trade dynamically
create script tags they would still work
with this type of policy and there's
good browsers report which is also nice
the drawbacks of this type of policies
you still haven't covered the Ebel sink
and since there's strict dynamic a
portion of the dome XSS is still
uncovered so here's a list of the sinks
that are covered javascript your eyes
are covered because this policy does not
have unsafe inline it might have some
say finland but this is just for browser
backward compatibility every browser
that supports nonces will drop unsafe
inline implicitly in the presence of
Ananse also data your eyes are covered
because there's neurons of inline the
HTML injection into HTML context and
inner HTML context is also covered
because every script tag needs to have a
nonce to be executed evil is not covered
because you have unsafe people in that
policy and then there's a very
interesting section which is injection
into script text and script SRC so if
you have code that does like a create
element script dot SOC and then assign
some user controlled input or it's
scripted inner text assigning to user
controlled input that's not really
covered because strict dynamic dynamic
propagates trust to discharge scripts
inline scripts would be covered if you
replace this with the hash yes and also
angularjs like template injections are
not covered because these happen
entirely in JavaScript and CSP basically
has no access to that so in this case we
really recommend just to move away from
angularjs because it's kind of
and you should use like angular 2 and up
because they have a offline template
compilation which doesn't have these
kind of bugs so that's very interesting
what kind of refactorings you have to do
to make your application compatible to
this type of level 2 CSP first you have
to remove in you have to remove
javascript your eyes second you have to
refactor inland event handlers usually
remove them and instead use the
JavaScript API to register event
handlers it's usually not a lot of work
but if you have a lot of inline event
handlers it can sum up right and the
other thing you have to do is you have
to basically knowns all the script tags
that are in the response body not the
dynamically created ones this just works
because of strict dynamic and that
basically is a huge advantage in terms
of refactoring so our one step further
level 3 CSP is nonce based plastic
dynamic no answer if evil exactly the
same properties just that you basically
now have only the Dom XSS sinks that are
going through the script text script
inner text of script SOC evil is covered
by this policy so also almost the same
refactoring steps you just in case you
have evil you have to refactor it to
something else like if you do it use it
for tracing parsing you can use the
native browser IPS chasing that parse
if you do module loading you can like
create a child script and there's also a
very interesting variant of this type of
policy which is actually hash based and
not nonce paste this policy is extremely
useful for static or single page
applications which are static and you
don't want to have a nonce on a static
page because nonces should not be cached
and if you have a non-static page is no
static anymore right so what you can do
is you can replace the nonce with the
hash of kind of a boot loader script and
you do the same refactoring steps as
before but you basically move all these
host scripts into the bootloader script
and just like you know dynamically load
them by that
dynamic we'll make sure that these kind
of things are allowed and only screw
only that bond script will be allowed to
execute in the initial markup because
that is the hashed one and if you know
this is P evaluator it actually uses
this kind of policy because it's also a
static site you can check out the page
code and look at it as an example and
then there is kind of the holy grail for
non spaced CSP which is a nonce only
policy why because it actually covers
the vast majority of XSS sinks that are
tractable for CSP it's supported by all
major browsers even Safari and it's very
nice property has a very nice properties
because it basically means every script
is running was explicitly mark as
trusted by a developer if announced
value right so on the other hand the
drawback is that you now have to
renounce all the scripts which means you
need to have some knowns propagation
mechanisms to dynamically created
scripts right so what you now have to do
is three head one slide I'll show you
that in a second what you now have to do
is you also have to do like a set
attribute notes on dynamically created
scripts looks easy might be easy in your
application but if you use a lot of
external widgets or you do like very
complex stuff this can become a lot of
work and maybe even impossible if you
don't control all the JavaScript code in
terms of the covered XSS sinks this
policy performs really well the only
injections that are left are like you
know if you if the developer marks
something is trusted with the nonce and
then they steal put like a user input
into a script tag and the script SOC
then that's still exploitable right but
there's no automatic propagation of
nonsense in this model and also very
important to note here you must not add
a whitelist here now right because then
it's an orphan either announced or a
whitelist that would make the policy by
possible
yes so here's the nice overview about
all these properties and there's also a
column for trusted types which is a talk
held by Quattro in the afternoon
Christopher khottabych and it's really
awesome because it is very well
performing on all the Dom XSS parts and
it complements CSP perfectly right
trusted types is a GS based hardening
and it's doesn't apply for stored or
reflected XSS server site for that you
would need to have csps mitigation but
for the client-side code it's it's
really awesome so really recommend going
to that talk as well yeah see you
speaker rich at Google we already
mentioned that to some extent the only
thing I want to highlight here is we
basically all our or services that are
cava PI CSP started with a level 2 CSP
and then last summer we started to
slowly upgrading to level 4 CS peace
with Evo and just this year we also
started to upgrade the policies to
remove evils so almost 10% of the
outgoing traffic has a level 4 policy
now for Google and we mostly do this for
super sensitive services but even the
even the just level 2 CSP was quite
effective in mitigating quite a lot of
power excesses externally reported XSS
attacks for google
or here's an example of like a very
short example of domains that already
have it
for example photostat google.com has a
level for CSP it's a very complicated
application it's totally doable it just
takes a bit of time and dedication and
just be prioritized by domain tiers so
very sensitive domains got the most
attention and they almost are almost
hundred percent like 96 percent covered
by two CSP and level 4 CSP is there on
already four percent so with that we
move to advanced ESP techniques some of
that is really advanced but it's also
quite Noble and
I before like loco moco SEC is probably
the audience to present that right so
new in CSP free there is two new
directives which is stripped sauce
element and script source attribute same
thing for stealth but we'll talk about
that later the difference is it's like
script source but these two basically
cover different parts of the water
script source directive would cover
script ROS element just covers script
tags right inline scripts and source
scripts and script source attribute
covers all the script execution that
happens through attributes in HTML tags
right like inline event handlers or
JavaScript UI so why is this useful
because through this thing you now can
use hashes of attributes like hashed
inline event handlers or hash JavaScript
your eyes and explicitly player bless a
couple of inline event handlers so if
you have a site very for some reason
cannot refer to some inline event
handlers with this type of policy would
still be able to rule out CSP without
breaking your site it's not a finger I
would shoot for a first but it's
definitely an interesting development
it's as I said it's brand new and it's
only supported in chrome 75 that's also
limitation other browser browsers will
probably follow but it will take a bit
of time the big benefit of that policy
is that just like almost no refactoring
required and of course having this
policy is strictly better than having no
CSP right because the classical
reflected XSS server-side XSS are still
covered by this policy drawback is of
course that this policy covers not all
the things that good non-space TSP could
cover right and in case of an HTML
injection there's also a culprit here
because if you hash inline event
handlers in an injection you could read
an attacker could reuse distant handlers
as long as they are hashed so if you
have an inline event handler does this
like delete user
and then there's a mark of injection and
someone injects like image tag X or sex
on air or delete user that would Erik's
execute right if you just write list
return Falls or JavaScript wait zero
that is not really relevant but this is
very important to mention here and yeah
the attacker doesn't have full script
execution in that case but it's still a
thing right I can't go to detail because
of time reasons but here's a small POC
that you can try out yourself if you
want to learn more about it the covered
sinks are similar to the level 2 CSP but
now here the inland event handlers also
have like until they're because
depending on what you have you have a
different security guarantees the nice
thing about this policy although is that
you can actually use this for static
content and auto generate a policy so if
you have static content you could have a
proxy that hashes in an event handlers
and puts nonces and to generate the CSP
for that on the fly that's the first
time that this is possible but it should
be static content right and not
something that has templates or user
control input or whatever refactoring is
really easy it's just basically adding
ancestor scripts in the response body
and hashing these things so yes that's a
new thing in CSP free and there is also
something else that is pretty useful
sometimes which is double policies or
multiple CSP policies I don't know if
you're aware of it but you can actually
send more than one CSP header in a
single response why would you do this
because it basically allows you to
really add even more constraints to what
the policy allows usually if you have
only one one script source directive and
you put nonce random and self in the
same directive it's an or operation
write a script will execute if any of
these requirements are fulfilled if you
set these as two separate policies they
will be enforced in depend
by the browser and their script in order
to execute has to pass both policies and
you can either set double or multiple
policies by having separate headers
separate content security policy headers
or you have a single content security
policy header and separate them with a
comma
this looks basically like that
if you come a separate them it's very
important to not confuse that with the
semicolon right but this is a HTTP HTTP
header specification multi-value headers
are separated by commas so what does
this fing do is to CSP s1 is a whitelist
and the other one is a non space CSP and
the script will only execute if it
fulfills both properties or if it
fulfills the properties of both policies
in that case this script executes
because it has two random notes and in
that case and it also executes because
the script is sourced from the same
domain in the second and the third
example the script does not execute
because here's me the nonce is missing
and here it's not the same domain source
so if he would basically merge these
into here into single policy all of
these would execute right so this is
really the nice thing about this type of
policy and we use this in a couple of
places at Google it has the nice feature
that actually also non scripts that get
redirected would be covered by this
policy and also injection into script
SOC are much more limited to what they
can do the drawback is of course now you
have to have an own space policy and you
need to maintain a whitelist right which
is actually quite complex so not the
first thing I would shoot for but for
high sensitivity applications definitely
worth looking into
and it also reflects here right it's
it's actually pretty strong and yes so
almost done with guru section last bit
is what about style injections like if
you have a markup injection you don't
only can inject script tags of course
right you can also inject style tags and
because of CSS free just some pre
advanced attacks you
carry out we are using a CSS selectors
or import statements the very important
thing to mention here is that these only
work in style blocks or source styles
and they don't work in inline Styles so
what you can do is you can use style
source nonce and the random token to
basically enforce an ounce on all the
style tags that is the preferred
solution of course but since inline
styles are so frequently used it's a
refactoring nightmare right so you can
use the the nooses be free directive for
styles and basically enforce the nonce
is just for the style blocks while
allowing arbitrary inland inline Styles
right this is a mitigation strategy
right but you definitely block the more
powerful CSS selectors and import
statements and of course this policy can
be or this policy can be combined with
script source policies and with that I
will head over and over to McKee for the
production izing CSP part and you're
almost done
so now we talked about what you actually
deploy CSP in your website you'd like to
see what's going on so what is being
blocked and if there are more
refactoring steps needed or if there are
some even some attacks and you want to
be aware of them so normally you can put
a report your I and a so called CSP
violation report is sent by the browser
every time a resource is blocked to your
collection endpoints and then you can
you know store them in a database and
then look at them it is very helpful in
this case to add the report sample
keyword this makes instructs the browser
to add a sample of the blocked
JavaScript actually the first 40 bytes
in the script sample property and this
is really really cool because you can
actually
distinguish between actual things that
need to be refactored
from for example extension noise which
are false positives here I want to be
really really quick about ESP fallbacks
so city has been designed in like across
many years and the browser's support of
CSP is a little fragmented so it's
important to have backward compatible
CSP policies it actually falls open on
older browsers so you can take a look at
that later but very simply I'll just say
two rules and say if in line is ignored
in presence of the norms or a hash and
any Wyclef's is ignored in presence of
string dynamic everything else is more
advanced so for example the street
dynamic policy that we presented earlier
with nonsense strict dynamic which
should be just knows and strict dynamic
463 compatible browsers like modern
chrome chromium firefox opera and so on
actually sometimes is presented with
HTTPS which is a broad whitelist
and unsafe teen-line so why this is very
confusing right but this makes it so
that the same policy actually works you
know across all browsers so browsers
that do not understand strict dynamic
actually see HTTPS because trick dynamic
makes the white waste disappear and
browsers they do not understand anything
just have a fail open policy which is
unsafe inline of course it doesn't
provide any security guarantee but it
does not break your site sorry about it
so this is very overwhelming right so
CSP is is a mess right it's it is it is
a mess for us too and we worked on it
for more than three years it it has a
lot of complexity like so many
directives so many cultures like there
is this and there is that this makes
this no longer work and I saw you
enjoyed the comma
a lot it's really really hard but what
I'd like to make very clear is that you
don't need to know all of this you don't
need to
through all the levels and variants of
CSP that we presented but to have a
reasonable amount of security for your
web application you can actually you can
actually get it pretty simply and what
we suggest is to start with strict
dynamic policy and level 2 policy is a
good trade-off between security and ease
of adoption if possible upgrade to
non-zombie this makes it even better but
actually as we said already 60 to 80
percent of exercises at Google in 2018
were already blocked by a strict dynamic
based XSS and the usual reminders is P
is a defense-in-depth mechanism so you
should fix the box you should not just
put as well yes we say that every time
you did not just slap a policy on it
right it's very important it's very
important it's not an excuse not to fix
the underlying box right and please take
also verify your policy with a CSP
evaluator - which focuses on XSS
protection so very briefly wrapping up
please use announced bathe CSP policies
with strict dynamic if you care about
excess protections sorry that was level
3 it was not level 2 you can read out a
C and say V both depends and possible
upgrade to namsan resource which is our
level 4 also maybe add the fallbacks
which makes it harder to read and Mahalo
thank you very much thank you so much
everyone if you have any questions
[Applause]
so can you describe the amount of time
energy and process that vent into
refactoring the Charro's script code at
Google in order to broadly a dog proudly
supports ESP well yes it took a long
time
can we have two questions also on the
screen maybe I'll get numbers so it
depends so for the strict dynamic paste
content security policy the refactoring
was mostly focused on removing inline
event handlers and less so on
refactoring JavaScript for upgrading to
announced only policy it almost took us
like I think 12 or 18 months to
basically refactor all the libraries at
Google to do nonce passing and basically
teach the frameworks to do it right now
we were to spot where we basically just
have a framework that has announced only
policy and does Auto noticing on the
context-sensitive templating system and
the module loaders they propagate
announces they use safe types internally
and basically when you create a new
application on that framework the
developer doesn't even need to know that
there is a CSP right it just works out
of the box but it was quite some journey
there but I think it was worth the
effort and with the CSP coverage going
up they also saw box being mitigated so
cool so the other question is have you
had any successful XSS attempt against
an elf or policy so absolutely yes the
elf for policies announced only policy
right without anything else yes we do
of course so I would say there are maybe
two main kinds like one is when you have
an injection in the script SRC so in the
source attribute of a script that is
actually announced our blindly announced
and another is when actually you can
upload user content on the same origin
and so for example if you can upload
like some JavaScript or SVG or some HTML
and you can actually embed this this
might be a problem or of course you can
instruct the victim to go there directly
so but this is a little bit out of scope
because it's actually a coverage problem
it becomes obvious coverage problems and
the blindly sourcing is yes so their
user upload is actually mostly a problem
for non chrome because chrome if you
have an ensemble policy also blocks the
PDF since this kind of stuff but yes so
this is really really complex right it's
very hard to say we can cover 100% and
it's also not the aim of a mitigation
technique right but we can cover a lot
and we can cover a lot in a in a pretty
fair effective way so I think the teal
they are for level 4 policies if the
developer notes as a script and still
put something untrusted user
controllable input into SRC it's it's
still by possible right way possible yes
it appears that non-space policies work
for execution of web azzam is that
correct
if so I am now very happy I think for
web Azzam you have to have unsafe evil
to allow it to execute I think they were
discussing about an ANSI of Azzam
directive but I think it's not part of
the specification yet more directors so
yes so it is possible but you have to
put unsafe evil
do your back counter researchers still
report XSS parks even if they can't
bypass you speak yes they do and yes
they should because they're still
getting paid and if they also bypass
disease be I think they get paid extra
so please don't stop reporting bugs