so I want to talk today about adapting
app SEC this is me as Jim said I've been
around for a while I've worked with
quite a few people in this field
yeah don't yell at me for having let's
and VARs and the same that's actually
swift someone yelled at me and no that's
not JavaScript so I'm now at contrast
security I'm our director of apps sec
yes we're an application security
software company but we still need app
SEC for our products and whatever else
I'm a dad I golf or I tried to golf I'm
really interested in IOT in mobile so I
kind of do some of that on the side now
so that's me in a nutshell so I want to
dig right in right the rules of the game
have kind of changed you know I've been
an app SEC I still remember I think it
was 2002 I took an app set course from
Jeff Williams who was Kona the
co-founders of a wasp so it's been a
while so I've seen it change over the
years but the last year and a half two
years it's really really changing and
business is changing right I mean
business successes is really dependent
on developing great software anymore I
mean there's like 23 million
professional developers in the world
that was the last number I saw and and I
don't know how they determine that but I
assume that means that these people are
writing code all day every day right so
things are changing software is being
built it's great it's huge there's
billions and billions of lines of code
and we're building them faster so over
time we've seen it go from very
monolithic apps who still has these by
the way yeah everyone still does write
to more agile where there's like n tears
and you know maybe you're getting into
some of the VMS and and you know
spinning things up and breaking them
down and now this whole DevOps
thing microservices containers clouds
it's it's gotten crazy but I mean
honestly most of it is kind of a mix of
these like you like like waggle ops
right like her
shall fall or something right like I
don't think anyone's truly one or the
other of these except for maybe some
really bleeding edge new stuff so what
hasn't changed though because in apps
tech like I said it's been around for a
while you know and and things have
changed in development space things have
changed in apps SEC but what has it well
Tigers still to go right right so old
things still work right but there are
quite a few things that that really
haven't changed in this space we still
need exact level support hands down
they're the ones paying them up
paychecks they're the ones handed out
money to make sure that their products
are sold bought and and whatever else
right so we need that support and that
won't change over time
we still need programs with governance
people process tools right again that's
something that won't change
collaborative relationships we're
getting better at that right and I'll
talk about some of that as I go on that
hasn't changed you know specific things
to different control areas those still
exist right some frameworks some tooling
some whatever else may make them easier
but those things are still issues and
things we have to think about the need
for threat models secure design it's
it's almost more imperative now as
disparate as these systems are getting
right with all the different micro
services I mean I've seen I was going to
show you so we just started a bug bounty
and I was going to show you the
environment that we set up just for the
bug bounty and it's really simple all it
does is people log into Cognito and it
spins up a docker image running webgoat
and our tool right that sounds simple
but there's like 40 different parts on
this this diagram to that simple process
right so it's imperative we start doing
these more because I've had people tell
me that we don't need to do threat
modeling we don't need to do secure
design and there is that camp out there
but I'm in the camp that believes that I
think we do
and we're still writing code right so
security standards who has security
standards for app sec can I ask those of
you who didn't raise your hand why not I
like it to be interactive so you know
yeah let me throw things at me I don't
care no one there we go all right anyone
sure something that developers know to
use perfect I asked you to something
that developers can look at use
understand like hey for authentication
you use this framework you use this tool
set right okay Neal where are you gonna
say something
yeah it doesn't say no crazy old
standard process Docs that no one wants
to read right but there has to be an
understanding of these different control
areas and how developers should approach
them in their code right application of
risk categorization I can guarantee you
that no more than 20% of you do this
like this this has been the hardest
thing to do for organizations as time
has gone on I mean you know some of the
some of the companies that I've worked
overtime they've got three thousand five
thousand different apps where do they
even start
right but we have to i mean wasp has
ASVs right but if you don't know the
risk categorization of your app you're
not sure which path to follow
as far as how you assess your apps and
the security posture of that app and
secure design principles so I want to
talk about this a little bit does anyone
use ghost no one
the popular node blogging platform all
right so these guys pissed me off so I'm
gonna I'm gonna talk about this a bit so
they have a set and this this is all on
their site of five different user roles
and I've got those there right
contributors authors editors
administrators and owners they all have
different things they can do and things
they can't do
well my esteemed colleague found that
you can easily elevate your privilege in
this system and they have an open bug
bounty so he submitted that to them I
think it was July of last year never
responded not once to him all he had to
do was embed some JavaScript in an app
and get an admin to preview it so
there's like a CSRF thing and all that
going on but it was really easy to do so
ghosts response not to Matt was to
change their documentation they're not
interested in privileged escalation they
sell this tool right and they say right
here this is this is the part that's
crazy ghost is a content management
system and all users are considered to
be privileged and trusted really like
what year is it do we do we create
access control systems and then just say
now with that we don't really need that
everyone stressed it anyway so it's
stuff like this like they didn't use
secure design principles here right like
which ones are they missing here least
privileged is the obvious one right
maybe separation of duties I mean that
was the whole point of this is to kind
of separate the duties of the different
roles of users but obviously they it's
oates over their head so if you use it
press them on this please their fix is
basically putting it on the users of the
system hey you should run the admin
interface on a separate domain okay I
mean you should but that shouldn't be
the fix to this and then software
integrity like this is becoming more and
more of importance with all of the
third-party library issues we've seen
right does anyone use Ruby come on Ruby
guys
right I know get everyone from github
better raise their hand so there was
recently the bootstrap sass ruby gem
issue did people see that and it is so
someone I don't know if they've really
come out and said who or how or what
committed this code which basically just
took in a fake HTTP header and eval dit
and I don't know if you know Ruby but
that's just meta programming you can
pretty much do everything right and it
was committed to an older version of
this Jim thankfully I don't know who the
guy is but he called it out when he saw
it committed even though it was an older
version but it was something that was
downloaded about 1500 times yeah yeah
yeah it was it was interesting right so
I mean simple things like that this
stuff is happening right and this can
happen in your code too so we've got to
have some process around how we're
determining the integrity of our
software and threat modeling you know no
one likes it it sounds like a
four-letter word who does threat
modeling that's awesome do you make it
fun at least right because if you don't
no one's gonna want to do it like
talking Batman terms or something right
make it fun make it quick and I'll talk
about some of that as well so those are
the things that haven't really changed
in my opinion things that have changed
our art patterns right like our
architectures are drastically different
development methodologies over time have
changed for sure the speed of
development you know it's it's only
increasing it's crazy how much code
developers can write I think the last
sad I saw is like the average developer
writes about 10,000 lines of code a year
I don't know how accurate that is but
that seems fairly fairly accurate to me
need for tooling and automation is
only increasing because there's just too
much code new infrastructures and and
responsibilities are changing and and
really as a business this is kind of key
right like as a business you're being
pushed into writing modern software
using these modern architectures right
it's not as easy just to stand up an
antiquated Java system anymore right
like where you gonna put it who's gonna
host it can can we can we not have
deployment parties that last two days
right like like things are changing
you know agile devops micro services all
that stuff but the harsh reality is this
is like every year the number one
security threat is application code
breaches I don't see that changing
anytime soon right I mean the amount of
Cobre writing you know infrastructure is
code you know all that good stuff coming
in it's not gonna change
but we're still seen as the slowdowns
like us security folks right developers
like oh you're slowing us down right so
72% of developers say you know that's
really the slowdown and then what's the
big deal on the security exec side right
talent shortage so we have some some
issues to deal with in this this modern
era of development and securing
development because developers are being
asked to basically continue speeding up
their process writing more code
delivering almost ten times the amount
of code right and we still have to make
sure that that code is secure so how are
we going to do that it's it's almost an
impossible economic thing right like
like we have we have tools we have very
teeny budgets right we have some
specialized security staff but then
we're writing that much more code right
I mean this this is real like who's else
is seeing this
right we don't have time you know 20
years ago when I started in consulting
it was really easy hey we have this huge
monolithic Java app it's seven million
lines of code can you look at it for six
months sure you don't have that anymore
right I've got these 300 micro services
written in 17 different languages and
how are you going to assess them all oh
and by the way I don't really have a
proof of concept they just some of them
are HTTP some of them are exposed to API
gateway and it's like holy crap okay
like how are we going to do this so the
root of the problem really stems back to
we're using an antiquated security model
for trying to secure modern day
applications you know we're using the
old scan and perimeter based model with
SAS desks
you know dynamic scanners laughs all of
that stuff and we're having issues right
those tools all that good stuff was
built for kind of the pre cloud era it
really was
I'm not saying they're bad tools are
great like everyone should use them you
have to use them but we're kind of stuck
in this this slump if you will and I
think we need to get over blaming speed
right that's that's the easy thing for
me oh it's just too fast
well catch up right
I mean they're not slowing down they're
not gonna and they're gonna drive right
over us as security folks if we don't
keep up with them right we don't we're
not building moats anymore
you know we've got these high-speed
airplanes coming at us and you know we
got to figure out how to help secure
them so it kind of requires this modern
software security model who here can
100% accuracy tell me what their
software security posture is or are you
gonna hand me a report from six months
ago because someone came in and looked
at your code right right most of us
cannot and now we don't have slides oh
there they are
hi cat so this is kind of the the way
that that we're trying to integrate
right like security and dev are always
like this we're going in opposite
directions who still has separate
tracking systems like here's my security
bugs and this directory over here here's
my software bugs yeah don't be shy I
know you do
right we're trying to get past that and
then process integration like it's not
it's not this unicorn right like I mean
your curtains are great don't get me
wrong but it's really not right there's
if I could give you an easy button I
would but there is no easy button every
org is working differently they all have
different process they all have
different tools so you know as a product
security person don't go in there
thinking everything's gonna be no
rainbows and unicorns because it's not
gonna be right some things are gonna
integrate well some things aren't maybe
you'll have to reevaluate what tools
you're using so they do integrate better
but you know don't don't come in there
like oh I'm gonna I'm gonna change the
world
I got I got a unicorn here and then this
this is huge
right like
I can't tell you the number of times I'm
like seeing the old great gray beard
which is kind of like me I guess I'm
gray beard now come in there oh you will
do this all right well I'm just gonna
find a way around it
right I have a story it's funny it's
about my first job out of college I had
just gotten onto the security team this
is 20 some years ago and old old dotnet
javo I don't remember what it was it
might have been Java like com+
but there were times that this app the
database would get corrupted for who
knows what reason
right so the developers would have to
put in a request through email or
something to our security team and that
would take two days for them to respond
and give them access to go in and fix
the prod at abase so what do you think
the developers did yeah
they wrote functionality in the app
where they could just pass a sequel
query in the URL mind you to fix the
database because it happened frequently
and no one could figure out why but
security got in the way and it took too
long it's like this app would be down
for two days at a time right the
business said nope figure out a way
around it so the developers did and
they're gonna continue to do that right
so we got to be very careful with with
gating and then relationships right like
I wasn't consulting forever so I
understood that side of the relationship
spectrum right like that relationship
with my clients now I'm like internal
that's a whole different game for me
right like my relationship building is
not only with my DES but with my product
managers right the product managers are
driving everything so if I have a poor
relationship with them you think they're
gonna do anything for me probably not
right and then you know earlier I talked
about fret modeling I think there's this
this thing of like sprit threat modeling
not only like in your dev Sprint's but
doing it more quickly right
when it comes to threat modeling and and
what I mean is gotta hate clowns I don't
even know I like scared looking at every
story should be examined for malfeasance
doesn't matter what it is maybe you're
only adding some drop down box takes
seconds to talk about it and examine
that story for malfeasance right and for
something that could possibly go wrong
with with that and and and some attacker
getting after you so then we we've got
this continuous integration which is
important everyone here probably uses it
to some extent right what what what does
this provide us not only from a deaf
perspective but from a security
perspective one don't be shy yeah I mean
it's really for speed right I mean the
old deploy parties who was involved in
those by the way okay you get to come in
tonight and we'll give you a beer but
you get to stay here all night while
this deploys and fails and then you got
to fix it see I was added to help that
issue right like we can continually get
those things moving with security we're
like oh we can get into that process run
some tests not just unit tests right we
can run security specific tests in our
CIS right and then we get into
continuous delivery right people get
these look confused there's continuous
delivery and continuous deployment can
someone tell me the difference Tanya
sure yeah very good I mean sort of so so
my answer is continuous delivery is is
basically all of your deploy all of your
builds could go to prod but they don't
necessarily all go to product whereas
continuous deployment is everything just
goes to prod without approvals as Tanya
mentioned right like every bill just
gets pushed to prod I'm not sure how
many people are actually doing the
latter there's probably a few but this
is another place that we've been able to
help inject some security process and
should write like okay we have a build
maybe we're running our SAS task tools
at this point right so we have a build
that succeeds so it is a New York New
Era though right software security is
kind of falling behind there aren't
really great tools for the distributed
systems that we're creating and I say
that as a tool vendor right like there's
no magical unicorn answer as far as
software security goes from a tooling
perspective because there's a ton right
I'm sure everyone uses some of these
maybe they use them all she's got
unlimited funds right this isn't nearly
all of them either right these are just
ones that it's like oh I've seen those
I've used those and they all work in
different places in the process right
some may work better in your org some
may not but you know setting them up is
definitely something that is part of
your overall software security program
and then the streamlining piece you know
I kind of talked about this earlier you
know this looks very easy right you have
your IDE you have your code repos you
have your pipeline and you have your
hosting provider which is probably a
cloud
you know some of you may still be on
bare metal but the key here is they need
to kind of all integrate into that
single defect tracker right this defect
tracker is where devs work day in and
day out that's how they know what
they're supposed to do over the next
couple of weeks or however long your
Sprint's are right so if your security
defects don't get into that defect
tracker devs aren't going to pay them
any attention right and on the same
respect if they are in the defect
tracker they'll be treated just as any
other software security buggers are not
even security but software bug is
treated right and the criticality will
be assigned and it just follows the
process this is key to make sure that
your security debt does not just
continue to grow you know in my
consulting days I can't tell you the
number of times I had clients come to me
and say all right I got check marks in
here I ran it and now I have a report
and it's in this directory that no one
looks at can you help me I mean yes I
can come in and help you and help maybe
vet some of those but you're not
utilizing that investment correctly
right like like what's the point oh I
have the tool running right but what are
you doing with the output right and this
really helps to with all of the people
in the org right your developers are
using that single defect tracker your
managers who have to respond to the see
so when they say hey how many software
security bugs do we have or how many did
we fix over the last sprint they can go
to one single location and they know
exactly how many right security teams
there and your tooling it's all pushing
pulling from that single centralized
tracking database is that you Kenny you
know and this is the hard part this this
is what I'm struggling with and maybe
someone has some insight here because
this this whole internal security
product security stuff is pretty new to
me but as a security person as a
consultant it's very easy to be like oh
hey these things are bad and throw it
over the window right lay or throw it
over the fence
now as a product security person I'm
like oh crap they're bad but how do I
assign risk to that based on these 25
other things right that that are ongoing
and maybe there's some revenue at risk
right like that's that's definitely at
play right so I I don't have all the
answers here but you know coming up with
some sort of risk matrix makes sense but
it's not always gonna work just know
that right
have at least a baseline whether that's
ASVs and have a feel for that but yeah
and then dev sec ops right like I didn't
want to go into this this is a whole
nother topic three or four people have
already talked about it right but I
think it's very promising to me what it
really comes down to and and all the
things that I talked about are kind of
put putting that security culture out
there right like being friends with
people instead of sitting in your little
basement dungeon telling people what to
do right understanding how much work it
actually is going to take for someone to
make this fix versus this product
enhancement that's going to either bring
in eight million dollars or not if we
don't get it out the door right now
right so all of those things start to
get weighed and in and it comes down to
that building that security culture and
and the relationship building between
the different areas so I wanted to talk
about how am i doing I'm good how we
ship secure code or at least semi secure
code right it's not perfect this is our
process these are the tools that we use
you know the IDE IntelliJ we have or
bitbucket sorry github folks you know it
is what it is right so we use bitbucket
for our pipeline we use it for our code
repos for chat ops who doesn't use slack
nowadays right like a slack
you know and I love it like all the
integration points are amazing
especially for my bug bounty stuff we're
building in some burps cans with burb
enterprise to to scan all of our our
builds and we use JIRA for tracking and
we you know this is a shameless plug but
we use our own tool on our own tool it's
contrast on contrast you know but hey
that's not gonna work for everyone um so
it's a pretty simple workflow right I
mean most people probably follow
something similar maybe your tooling is
in a different place you know but I
think the key here is it's pretty
seamless right we have our developers
working in their IDs they're interacting
with JIRA for their sprints for their
issues we've got contrast running on our
product if there's an issue that issue
is automatically created in JIRA great
developers see that it gets assigned out
risk levels assigned once they've fixed
it a notification comes to slack and
it's automatically then populated back
to our tool saying hey it's fixed
so like that whole process sounds
amazing but it's not easy to set up
doesn't matter what tooling you're using
but I highly suggest find something that
works for you it may not be a hundred
percent perfect but it gets you further
down the road right but make sure that
that whole thing that whole process is
as easy as clicking a few buttons to
update all your different disparate
systems right that's the whole that's
the that's the key here you know be
comfortable with whatever tooling you're
using integrate them well and give
developers that ease of push-button
fixing because the hard part is writing
the code so then maybe if you get to
that point you can have a better feeling
for what your current security posture
is right because that's really to me the
key like working with our compliance
team working with our sales team to be
able to show clients that hey we feel
pretty good about our security posture
and here is why
and I'm not just handing them a report
from six months ago from a third-party
consultancy right I can be like alright
this is exactly where we're at today in
printable reports and send it to I think
that's kind of the key so this is the
slide that I want everyone to take a
picture of because it took me forever to
put it together Wow you guys listen you
don't really don't have to but so these
are in my eyes where I see things going
I guess right tools are going to
continue to evolve they have to because
if they don't they're just gonna get
thrown away and we're gonna be up
creek you know there is a lot of really
smart people there's a lot of really
awesome tool work going on
I mean we've we've been looking at some
serverless
tools I don't know if anyone uses them
you know they're they're writing AWS
layers that help instrument your your
micro services and lambda functions and
things like that there's some pretty
awesome things going on and that's only
going to continue to evolve heck Amazon
and Microsoft and them they're probably
already working on it as well I think a
key to this whole stack here is we have
to figure out a way to enable developer
self-sufficiency and what I mean by that
is we don't have the security people to
continue to find all these these
security issues so we need to basically
make developer self-sufficient so it's
easy for them to find them and fix them
right without even maybe doing security
specific testing there's tooling out
there that does this right today whether
that's building in some SCA tools some I
asked tools rasp whatever else but it
helps developers basically become
security people right because we need it
we need it badly
open-source risk management obviously is
a huge problem it's not going away it's
getting worse I would love for everyone
in this room to
continue talking about that and getting
together and figuring out how to make it
better instead of just saying I'll see
the ease or right I mean really
like as a security practitioner we're
really good about saying that's bad and
then walking away of course it is but
let's fix it like let's find a way to
make it better right you know protecting
legacy portfolio stuff is still
important there's still a lot of it I
mean ice-t-- you know in consulting I
looked at code that was 20-plus years
old so that's not gonna go away so
whatever process and tooling we use
hopefully it will still work on some of
those unless you're still running COBOL
and a mainframe this the the optimized
penetration testing is interesting right
and I'm working on that internally like
I know what our tools are good at so I
don't necessarily want to spend my time
and effort looking at those sorts of
things like SAS desk I asked all that
they've got specific things that they're
pretty good at right xs/s most of them
are good at sequel injection most and
we're good at and there's a list right
so have some comfort level there and
then focus on the really hard things
like access control issues right have
the brains the smart people come in and
look at the specific issues or specific
control areas that you you know your
tooling and your systems may be lacking
right because I as much as I think tools
are gonna evolve I think there's always
going to be hard problems that tools
can't help with and I may be wrong
hopefully prove me wrong and then
ensuring that continuous visibility kind
of the we know what our security posture
is everyone in the company knows what
our security posture is everyone knows
our setup our tooling and all of that so
this is really kind of abstract in the
modern world if you will in my eyes and
I think it benefits the whole company
right I can't imagine how tough it is
being a CIO or C so in this world
there's a few in this room I know right
answering to everyone but if we follow
this this modern-day process we can at
least help the sea so the sea levels
understand that we're trying to close
that security gap and have them sleep
better at night right and then the
security team you know every one of us
has been a position where we're working
too much because we don't have enough
help if we can get a process set up
where we're comfortable maybe you know a
40-hour week isn't such a bad idea or or
less and then the dev team right instead
of being the you must do this and not
working well with them let's enable them
to work with us right
and then ops you know ops a lot of times
it gets kind of left in the dust and
they're the last ones we blame but if we
get this system set up correctly ops
will just be streamlined into it so I
ran through that fast because we started
late Jim but I know I'm good I was
hoping so what did we learn today AB SEC
is hard ice is harder fundamentals are
still important like let's not forget
them sometimes we forget them because
things are going so fast but if we
forget them things are only gonna get
worse as time goes on tools help a ton
and really are a key to your success as
an or as a software security vendor but
we all have our different needs right
like I know what my needs are and
they're they're different than github
sneeze they're different than slacks
needs in Microsoft and what-have-you
right but we can all create that process
and build relationships like don't be
the person
don't be Milton sitting in the basement
treyton like be there you know one thing
that that I love at contrast is most all
of our calls or video chat for for a
remote company it's amazing I used to be
kind of against that but I'm like you
know what I like seeing the people I
work with and it's it's a lot easier to
talk to them when I can actually see
them so just a helpful hint of someone
who's been in it for a while so that's
it that's me in a nutshell
yeah did you have a question Jim I'm
putting a tool in a developers hand to
help them become a security professional
or just become scary literate I think
that's a great goal how long do you
think it takes a developer who's not
been educated napsack once you give them
a tool how long does it take before they
start understanding proper remediation
and the subtleties of triage and similar
so I guess that's a great question Jim I
guess I wouldn't necessarily give them a
tool like I want the process to utilize
tools right and then the developer
probably uses the output from those
tools right how long does it take them a
while right like I think you know when
it comes to understanding app SEC there
is a training component when it comes
down to it that that we have to
definitely use and I know you as a
training event or probably like to hear
that but no it's not but i-i've always
been a proponent of good app SEC
training and and I think that's
something that needs to continue all
right being back on the customer side of
consulting is there something you wish
you would have done differently as a
consultant to help DevOps great question
of course my answer is gonna be yes but
I know that I never really would have
been able to if that makes sense in
consulting clients always had pretty
specific needs and a lot of times those
needs were driven by bodies outside of
something that I could influence like
compliance or regulatory bodies or
internal process you know thankfully we
were able to find those partners of
clients that we could help with these
sorts of things and help them evolve
their DevOps process and building
security into it but frankly they were
few and far between