all right hello people
i'm very happy to see you
in person
i've been giving presentations to like
my computer screen for the past two
years and
it's really hard because you don't get
any kind of interaction whatsoever
so anyway i'm marcel and i'm here to
talk to you about one of my favorite
tools cyber chef
this is let's get cooking with cyber
chef so hopefully you're in the right
room
so so a little bit about me
um i am pretty much at marcel lee on all
the socials if you want to find me i
also have my contact information at the
end i just changed jobs like three weeks
ago so i'm like still drinking from the
fire hose at a company called equinix
which is a
really big global data center company so
it's kind of a different environment for
me i'm used to working for mssps but i'm
still doing threat intel which is my
favorite thing pretty much in the world
i'm also an adjunct professor at umd and
umgc if you take any classes at umgc in
the cyber area you might come across me
at some point in time
all virtual of course but and then i'm
also on the board of directors for a
number of different organizations but
the one that i wanted to mention
specifically is um women's society of
cyber jitsu which is not just for women
despite what the name implies and i'm
going to do a shameless plug
for
and i'm going to grab some water too for
an event that we have coming up in june
june 18th it's cyber jitsu khan it's
going to be at
the maritime conference center which is
out by bwi airport it's actually a
really cool facility that i had like
never heard of before um so it's gonna
be a great day i highly recommend you
register volunteer if you want to
sponsor if you want to all the things
okay so a little bit about you know just
what is a cyber security researcher it
can mean a lot of different things
um
this is sort of like my joking
interpretation of what it is you know
the collector of shiny cyber things
that's what i say that i do all the time
right
identifier cyber badness
googler extraordinaire that is like the
key tool that we all use right
and an expert copy paster because that's
also something that we do lots of
but what is it really so it's a lot of
different things and these are just kind
of like a brain dump for me of of things
that i do regularly in my day-to-day job
right so who here does
security research like it's her job
a few people yeah
anybody want to do it that doesn't do it
right now yeah a few people i do have a
talk um floating around out there i
think i have it on my github
that's called like a day in the life of
a security researcher that kind of does
a deep dive on this topic as opposed to
like one slide
so anyway but this is what i think it is
right so you're obtaining and digesting
threat until data from a variety of
sources and that could be you know ocean
human
obviously telemetry from within your own
company
government sources
the list goes on and on
doing google dorking of course
is a good thing i definitely learned
some things from nick
um and then analyzing the data that
you're finding and identifying trends
patterns campaigns it's like a big thing
so say you know you you come across a
phishing email and then you dig into it
maybe using some of the techniques that
nick mentioned like looking at exit data
metadata whatever
um and just pulling the threads to
figure out like what is this phishing
email representative of is it a larger
campaign did it come from you know like
a quack box thing or you know whatever
so um
i think like a natural curiosity i think
really helps with this kind of thing
because you do
end up in a lot of rabbit holes which
i got a tattoo that says
down the rabbit hole because that's
basically where i spend much of my life
um anyway so and then applying
frameworks mitre attack is obviously a
very common one that most people are
familiar with i use that one a lot
um extracting indicators so what do i
mean by indicators hashes ips domains so
on and so forth
and um
and just really collecting gathering
knowledge or creating knowledge about
these different threats
and creating countermeasures might be a
part of your job that's definitely
something that i did with my previous
employer which was secure works and we
would work with the countermeasure team
to
essentially say we identified some new
malware or something you know how can we
work with them to make sure that we've
got signatures in place that are going
to detect that um activity
accessing exposure to your
corporation and and then last but not
least everybody's favorite reporting the
findings but none of this is any good if
you're not reporting it so
that's a big piece
and i want to acknowledge i did a cyber
chef trading from matt
weiner weiner i'm not sure how to say it
and i think that chris sanders possibly
actually built the course but it's
really really good if you go to
applied network defense you could also
take the same course
and you might even finish it which i
haven't i
had work pay for the original like six
month period or whatever and i've been
paying 20 a month for i have no idea how
long and i still haven't finished it but
anyway um
so that's a really good class
so um
let's get into what is cyber chef so
first of all who here has used cyber
chef before
oh good lots of you wait so why am i up
here telling you about it you all know
how to do this already
um anyway cyber chef comes from gchq
which is basically the british
equivalent of nsa um that building there
is referred to as the donut and
that's their headquarters wherever in
england
and so there's really i mean it's one
github project but they have two
different links there so
their github project and then the actual
direct link
to the tool
so you can run cyber chef either locally
or
through the website and either way the
operations are performed client-side so
what you put in shouldn't be visible at
the server side
all right so let's talk a little bit
about the layout
um
cyber chef as the name implies is all
about like
recipes and cooking and things like that
in fact yesterday i was having lunch at
like bonefish grill in
some place but uh the waiter was looking
at me working on my presentation and
he's like
oh are you a chef and i was like no and
then i'm like but let me show you this
really cool tool and he was just
probably thought i was crazy anyway
so so you have your operations section
which is that um left-hand pane there
and there i'm gonna as y'all show you
many many many different operations that
you can use then the middle pane is the
recipe and a recipe is just basically
some kind of
combination of operations
then the input output pane the baking
piece of it
and then
the operations are or just all the
things that cyber chef could do for you
you can also favorite operations so this
is something i recommend doing it's not
wildly intuitive how to do it but if you
click on the star
next to favorites um here i'll just pull
it up right now
where did i put my glasses there they
are
so i got lasik during the pandemic
because i really like couldn't stand
having a foggy glasses from the mask all
the time but now i have to wear like uh
glasses for close up and this is the
first time i've done a talk where i have
like actually have to see people out
there and see this so
i guess i don't have to see you all but
i want to see you
okay
let's make this a little bigger
let's make it even bigger
how's that is that right
okay
so the favorites um if you click on the
star right here and you can edit
favorites and this is how you would you
know add delete or whatever we'll delete
reorder and then if you wanted to add
favorites you would just do that from
the actual um
operation you have an option there
okay so that's that
and
the recipe part so what you see on the
screen here is a combination of
four different recipes right so from
base 64 to binary reverse raw deflate
and that's giving you some crazy output
right but it's just an example of like
how you can stack these operations
and so the layout um in that recipe pane
you have options to
save the recipe
load the recipe
or just delete not really delete the
recipe but you're deleting what's on the
screen there
you can also delete what's on the screen
in the recipe section just by double
clicking the recipe
and then the input pane has a new tab
and i can't even tell you how long i use
cyber chef before i realize you could
have multiple tabs open in there so
just all the things you learn
open a folder open a file you know these
are as input of course reset the input
screen
and reset the layout and then on the
output side you can save copy
move
to the input pane so basically what's on
the output moves up to the input which
is useful sometimes
and then also you can maximize that
output pain if you're trying to get you
know a bigger look at it
and then cyber chef has something that's
called magic and
basically it's a little like
i don't know what is that a magic wand i
guess um a little magic wand that lets
you um
kind of well let's cyber chef take a
crack at whatever it is you're maybe
you're trying to do right so so let's do
a for example on that one whoops
okay so
[Music]
i have an example over here
so i'm going to copy this hash
and throw it in the input
and i'm running cyber chef locally here
as you can see this is like a version
number if this wasn't local it would
just basically say download cyber chef
here where the version number is but i
like to write it locally it stores all
your
recipes in the cyber chef folder which
is kind of handy because
they're there then um forever pretty
much
so
um oh and it's not going to give me the
magic
hold on
let's do that
i'll put a still
there we go so
it's giving me a little magic thing and
if i
hover over it hover over it over
whatever i can't say it um
uh it's telling me from hex will produce
b-sides charm it's like a hint and i'm
like oh okay so let me go over here and
do from hex and lo and behold it says
besides charm this does not always work
and the next example i'm going to show
you you'll see where it doesn't work
okay
um actually before i dive into well no
let's go ahead and do the next example
so we're going to start cooking
and this is where we're going to um
use cyber chef to analyze a hash so you
know how sometimes you'll get like a
list of hashes and you're like i don't
know if this is md5 or shaw or whatever
you know if they're not identified if
it's long i'm like oh it's probably
sha256 but it could be shaw one i can't
remember exactly what they look like um
so you can use it for that
so let's let's try this
i'm going to take this hash and we'd
want to take a guess what hash that is
what algorithm
hold on let me put it in here so you can
actually see it
what
shot 256
i think that seems reasonable it looks
pretty long right
um
so let me
actually clear this first and then put
this in
okay well
from hex is clearly not the operation
that we want to use let's get rid of
that
um so let's see what cyber chefs tells
us for the magic on this one
and it says
from hex will produce um something that
i cannot possibly say so sometimes that
magic thing is not right right it's
thinking it's x but it's and i guess
technically it is hex but but not uh hex
encoding so instead we want to do an
operation which is um
i think it's analyze hash yes
only because it is a british tool the
words are british so that might be
confusing for some people i'm like why
do they spell analyze like that anyway
but that's why so yes so we see here
that the answer is indeed uh it's a
to shaw 256. there are other
possibilities too but i think
generally speaking we would go with shaw
256 and not panama
whatever um so anyway i've never even
heard of a of my hash
so let's get back into this so i want to
just kind of
skim through some of these and just give
you a taste of
just the
the breadth and
depth of things that you can do in here
so data formatting this is like the hex
stuff that we've already talked about
you could do decimal conversions
um binary octal
all the bases that you can think of um
so on and so forth all kinds of things
so
like i don't even know what some of
these things are and i haven't had a
chance to like try every single thing
it's kind of like kali linux right kelly
has like a million tools in it and i
personally have not tried all of them
has anybody here tried all the tools in
kali linux
no no it's like impossible i think same
thing with cyber chef so and you kind of
have to have like a use case to to do
these things oh one thing i want to
mention too about cyber chef is it's
awesome for cyber competitions does
anybody here do cyber competitions
really just a few people if you're not
doing them you should be doing them
they're so much fun but anyway it's a
super useful tool for cyber competitions
you can solve all kinds of challenges
using cyber chef
so it's like one stop shop okay so um so
lots and lots of different kinds of um
data formatting things there and then
encryption and encoding like you can
encode decode encrypt decrypt all these
different things right so
rc4 for example that's one that we see a
lot like in malware activity um so this
is pretty useful you can throw it in
combine it with other operations xor is
also something that we see a lot of in
malware operations so that's another
good one but yeah just um
you know if you need a feed and cipher
you could get that here i don't know why
you would need it except for a cyber
competition but anyway you get the idea
i'm not going to show you every single
one but it's very very extensive
public key same kind of idea you can
also do key verification in here which i
actually just did that recently and it
worked pretty handily so
okay um
arithmetic and logic so this is useful
too um
the xoring we already talked about but
the ending and ordering and nodding and
all that kind of stuff you can do in
here you can just do straight up math
too but i don't think i would open cyber
chef just to do like a multiplication
thing because google will do that for me
i just have to say like
um
four
times 20.
this one i could actually do in my head
but
um oh look it's 80. yay so that's
probably faster than launching
uh cyber chef
but you get the idea
and what else
uh networking so
if you are aware of me at all you will
know that my very favorite tool in the
world is wireshark and i love network uh
forensics it's like my favorite thing um
so ask me questions about packets
anytime i love that and i have managed
to weave some wireshark into this
demonstration so stay tuned for that
anyway um so there's lots of things you
can do in here networking wise
you know doing an http request like i
want to check out some
website maybe and not necessarily you
know
go to the website i could do it here
parsing all kinds of headers url
encoding and decoding that's something
you'll see a lot of
in network traffic it's kind of nice to
do a quick decode here
if you need to
um
ip formats grouping ip addresses this is
kind of cool so if you have like a list
of ip addresses and you want to know
like which ones are in which subnet or
whatever you can do that too so that's
kind of fun
um well it's fun for me
defanging you can defang
urls and ip addresses which is super
handy i can't even tell you like how
many times i've like copy pasta of
course indicators from some document
then i put them into like notepad and
then do a find and replace to get rid of
you know the periods or whatever um
super tedious this is way faster
okay and some language things this is
actually the shortest section i think
um and then a zillion utilities one of
the ones i use a lot here is removing
null bytes so like if you're looking at
um
say you um
have like a powershell script that was
like encoded or whatever and when it
gets decoded it's got a bunch of little
like dots and stuff in it which is kind
of distracting just do the removed null
bytes and it takes care of that for you
you can do all kinds of case things you
can do all kinds of
data manipulation sorting uniqueing
heading and tailing all that kind of
stuff so many many things there
then date and time this is just another
kind of useful thing
actually good for cts also like you get
like a unix time stamp and have to say
like what the time is and just regular
time
and then extractors so this is really
cool um say you have a big blob of text
or whatever and you want to pull out all
the ip addresses all the domains
whatever it'll do that for you
automatically
and
file pass so on and so forth so i like
that a lot too
um all kinds of compression activities
i'll have an example of that
then all the hashing things so many
hashes
and code tidy which is pretty much what
it sounds like but if you have some ugly
looking code it'll it'll make it look
nicer for you
it doesn't help like with the actual
code if there's issues with it but it
will make it look good and then
forensics which is one of my favorite
things also um some exif operations here
so i was thinking of this when nick was
doing his talk too so cyber chef i'm
going to have an example for you of
looking at the ex of data in cyber chef
multimedia
and i'm going to be i'm almost at the
end of this too because i don't want to
like go on and on with this list but um
so many things that you can do with
multimedia manipulating images
adding data to images all kinds of
things flipping images
and
then there's other which i'm not really
going to get into but there's lots of
stuff there and then flow control
which the main thing here i think that i
like is uh forking but um anyway so that
gives you like a general idea of just
like how much stuff there is in cyber
chef it's lots right
all right so let's get back to this
so we did this we determined it was a
shaw 256.
um so the encoding and decoding i kind
of already showed you that one but let's
just get rid of
this stuff which i'll do by deleting
delete that
and let's say we want to do
i'll
do besides charm because i'm super
original like that
20 22
and
we'll say we want to
do
um
well let's just do rot because you know
rod is so much fun
and there's a little button down here
that you can see next to the bake and
it's auto bake so technically i will
have auto bake turned on you usually
want to just because then it'll do the
things automatically without you having
to click the bake button the exception
to that is if you're dealing with like a
really big input um and you might want
to like you know
not do auto bake because it'll be
kind of clogging things up all right so
let's do some
very unique rot13 and there's our output
right so actually it's interesting it
doesn't do the number just does the
words but uh that makes sense because
it's alphabetical anyway but i like this
also for cyber competitions because
sometimes the cyber competition people
will try to trick you and do like rot
something else besides 13 right so this
is a good way to just easily like be
like oh is it this is it this is this
and
you kind of can figure it out
okay
so that's that
now making http requests i did mention
this earlier but i'm going to give you
an example
so
we're going to
load the http request recipe
and so i'll delete that
and
http
i guess i could have favorited these
that would have made sense
and put that in here and then i have
i actually have a recipe
well am i going to use it yes i will use
a recipe for this one
because i have a couple of other things
we're going to do
but the url i'm going to go to is
ipa
api.com which is going to give me what
do you think
might be addressed exactly so let's bake
that
and we get down here
basically the output from that um so
it's telling me pretty specifically i'm
in rockville there's my zip code it's
got a lat long all that good stuff my
provider and of course my ip address but
let's load a recipe here so if i click
on load it's going to pull up
basically all my recipes and in this
case i want to do
this one that i created called http ip
defeg
and
the way it works is it just shows you
like what that recipe does so basically
it's just plugging it in and then if you
want to share recipes with people you
can do it like this but you can also
just share like that link that i will
have after i run this operation
or recipe
so let's load that up
and let's bake it
okay so i have this output of
the defend url there really should be
screens on both sides i guess
anyway if you want to move it's okay
so so let me show you a cool thing here
that you can do so i have http requests
i have extracting ip addresses and then
i have defanging ip addresses those
three different
operations in this particular recipe
but i can set like a break point at each
one of these so if i break it here then
that just shows me that the output of
that first
operation
i'll let that go again and then i can
break it here and that's going to show
me
the ip address before i defend it right
so so that's a really cool function too
and then if i wanted to like just not do
one of those things say all right i
don't want to defang then you click on
that circle with a line through it and
that just basically pulls that one out
of the operation
okay so let's do another example
so qr codes
so
how do we see what's behind the qr code
do we just scan it and go to the link
that's there
somebody please say no
[Laughter]
no we don't um and and i think most of
like
photo apps and stuff are getting better
about like at least showing you the i or
the domain before it just automatically
takes you there but you can also throw a
qr code into cyber chef so let's do that
so i'm going to use a recipe i created
for this which is
just delete that
load recipe and it's going to be
where's my qr code oh it's right there
at the top
load
so you can see i've got parsevar code
defang url http request to something
and that's about it so let's use
um
open file for our input i'm going to
load this qr code
and say bake
and what we've got is output of
said this could be malicious.xyz records
null but let's do the points here too
so
we parse the qr code
oops why does that not break though
oh is it not doing that oh auto big
thank you
um okay make it again
all right so we'll break this here and
so we can see this is the um domain
that's basically behind that qr code
which is one that i literally made up of
course this could be malicious.xyz
and just fun fact
helpful hint if it's dot xyz i guarantee
you it's malicious i've never seen a
legit.xyz domain anyway um okay so
so we could break it there
and then the http request i did was just
basically an api for doing dns
uh lookups right in an s lookup thing so
so that gave me
not great results because i made up the
domain um and then of course the uh
defending piece at the end
so yeah so it makes it really simple to
like kind of do a lot of things in one
like quick
uh
one quick recipe
okay so let's do another one
how am i doing on time oh i'm good
okay so i mentioned there would be
wireshark in this presentation just had
to work it in somewhere so this is like
a totally nerdy thing that cyberchef
does that i love because i am a packing
nerd
but you can extract
uh ipe headers and i haven't seen them
do any other header extraction but i
feel like that's something that would be
good um also i didn't mention but cyber
chef is um it's a project that's in
active development anybody can like
contribute to it you just like fork it
and do your thing and whatnot so um so
that's pretty cool so you could build
all kinds of functionality in it
okay so let's do this one
so what we're going to do
is go over to wireshark
and
you don't really need to see that much
what i'm doing but but essentially what
i'm going to do here i have just a
random capture
and i'm going to select
the ip
section here and i'm going to copy
as a hex stream
so that's just copying like you know all
those bytes right there
and then let's pop that back in over
here
[Music]
delete
paste delete
and i don't need a recipe like a whole
full blood because it's just parse
ipv4 header
and
you get
like literally
let me pull this up a little bit
the different header fields and whatnot
so if you would imagine like a tcp or an
ip header these are this is what it
looks like right so i told you it's
going to be nerdy but i love this kind
of thing and i want to build it for like
tcp and udp and all that but i don't
know when that's going to happen so i
don't know about you all during the
pandemic but
i did a few things my hair got way
longer so like if you saw me before it
was much shorter i got lasik as i
mentioned i got like five new tattoos
because my tattoo guy was still working
and uh
anyway and what else did i do
um oh yeah i started gardening like
crazy we built an addition to our house
our contractor built an addition to our
house and
and i got pandemic chickens so
i'm like more busy doing things like not
hands-on keys these days which is a good
thing i didn't do this stuff before i
think
because i was always traveling and that
came to a screeching halt of course so
so yeah i think you know that was like
an upside of the pandemic for me is just
being able to um
not endlessly be on the computer but
anyway i'm also supposed to be writing a
book i have a contract i've written like
one and a half chapters in a year so i
don't know when i'm going to finish that
one day maybe it's about packet analysis
um okay so let's see where were we
okay so a block of ip addresses and i
feel like this one is going to resonate
with a lot of people
so
you have a report
that somebody wrote and it has a bunch
of indicators on it and you're like i
need these indicators um so
there is still going to be some copy
pasting involved with this but it's
definitely better than like how i ever
did this before so
i have up here
where is it this one hot off the press
fbi flash on uh black cat alpha v
ransomware this came out this week does
anybody get these
fbi alerts yeah they're super useful if
you don't get them there's a number of
different places where you can sign up
i'm a big fan of um the new jersey kick
of all things like they have
a really good service of sending out
things like scissor reports and
fbi reports and
whatever
and they also have a really good like
repository of information about
different threats so highly recommend
new jersey kick
and i'm pretty sure anybody can join um
well i don't know if you said like
terrorist at
iran.com maybe they would not let you
join i'm not sure but uh there probably
is some level of vetting
okay so let's see
so
la la la all the information and then we
get to the indicator section
and i want these ip addresses so i'm
going to you know as we security
researchers do
copy
and paste but instead of pasting it into
um
like a notepad or whatever
i'm going to
actually paste it into cyber chef
and so
look i still have a jumbled up list of
ip addresses not fabulous right that's
hard for me to do anything with so i'm
going to run
a recipe
which is ip block
and
this is going to do a bunch of stuff for
us
and it comes out with the number 13.
we're like what does that mean
so i'll go through the steps for you but
basically
so the first thing we're going to do
is a split so that's taking all that um
dump of information and basically
inserting a new line character after
each one and you delineate
what you know that that is going to be
that you're using right so it could be a
number of different things
um
then
i'm going to sort it
so now it's sorted for us
and
of course it still
does it like just normal sorting number
wise um so okay now i've got a nice list
and okay i want to defang them
because perhaps they're all malicious
and i don't want to send somebody just
you know malicious links that aren't uh
defect
and then the last thing that i did
basically was account occurrences and
this is just like doing like word count
or something like a lot of the stuff
you'll recognize is like command line
kind of functions that you could run um
and you could certainly like build
scripts that basically do all these
things too but it's just so convenient
in cyber chef
um
so there's some regex here i am not a
regex guru but it does give you like
some possibilities of things that you
could um
plug in
um but anyway yes and if you want to
google like
like ip address regex or whatever people
have done this for you already so you
don't have to like start from scratch
they exist um anyway so we have
13 ip addresses there so you get the
idea right this whole like flow of
things where's my water
okay
so now we're going to get into some some
good stuff so
anybody ever seen a powershell script
that was base64 encoded that wasn't
malicious
yeah me either
oh you have
my
engineers in
germany
yeah tell them not to do that
i mean it's such an easy like uh
countermeasure thing right like
powershell plus base64 equals no don't
do it
that's a very simplistic countermeasure
of course but um anyway so so we see
this a lot with malicious activity um
so in this case it's not really a very
fancy one it's just powershell encoded
blah
so we're going to copy paste this into
cyber
chef of course
now let me clear all that go over to my
notes
because this is a long one
oops god i hate that it always does that
no i don't want a dictionary definitely
not for this content
okay
and let's pop it in
bless you
okay so we are going to do
again a recipe that i built earlier
in this case it is my
base64 url defang recipe
all right let's load that
and
again we have multiple
operations happening in this example
right so the first thing that we're
going to do here is
extract the base64 bit um
which you know i could do manually by
just like deleting all that kind of
stuff but that's kind of a pain um so
we're not doing that
oops not that one
and so you can see basically it's just
gotten rid of everything that's not
base64 encoding here
and from there
we are decoding this text so now we can
see what that powershell command
actually is right so
essentially it's
downloading a file from what is most
likely a malicious website or a
compromise website perhaps one or the
other
and
then we're doing a find and replace just
to um
to pull
out
the actual ip oh no not there hold on
find him replace what was i doing with
the find and replace here
i don't remember
something anyway
um and then yes
then we're extracting the urls
so there's the url that was in there and
then again defanging the url because
that's just good cyber hygiene right so
so that's uh the powershell one
and then i have another powershell one
so um this is a little more extensive
and and these are the kind of options
that i typically would see when i'm
looking at like a malicious powershell
script the other example was kind of
simplistic but we see some things
happening in here so we've got
in addition to the basics before
encoding you know it says here oops
sorry
from base64 string but we also have some
compression activity happening in here
so let's uh
take a look at this one
delete and delete and i could be opening
like new tabs like i talked about but
it's a little
cleaner for demonstration purposes if i
just stick with the one tab
okay
so let's copy this
pop it in to cyber chef
and let's load our recipe
and let's do the basics before inflate
defang
look at whatever
okay so we've come up from all this with
a nice defend ip address which is a c2
right undoubtedly um so again let's kind
of take a look at the the different bits
um
we've got the base64 extracted there
now we're applying the raw inflate to it
oops oh no sorry
yes
oh yeah so
before we do the raw inflate the base64
looks like this which is puzzling
because you're like i know this is
base64 but why is it coming up as
gobbledygook if it's coming up as
gobbledygook it's probably because it is
compressed somehow so let's do a raw
inflate
and
then we can see
the whole like script here basically
right so
um we also want to
now
extract ip addresses and and then we do
fang them as well so what was kind of a
hard to process powershell script you
can pretty easily just dissect it using
cyber chef i mean i'm sure you could use
a python or something like that too but
but i like cyber chef as i've mentioned
um
did i say i like hypershaft yes i think
i did anyway actually one of the things
i think i want to start doing on my
github is is
start a repository of cyber chef recipes
i think that would be kind of cool i'm
sure other people do that too
although i haven't found like a ton of
them out there the guy matt um who was
the course person for that class i took
has a ton of different like examples um
but he doesn't always provide like the
input files so um
so
all the stuff for the most part were
things that i just like hunted around
for like a virus total or wherever
um okay
so let's see
okay let me go back to the deck
okay
so here's our exif data one that i said
we'd be doing and this is um a file
called dolls.jpg
and it's something that i created
for a cyber competition challenge right
so
um i'd like to take pictures of weird
things so i can use them for cyber
competitions basically so this dolls.jpg
has gotten a lot of a lot of use
anyway so
i think one of the things that i ask um
people is like where was this picture
taken i also asked like what's the model
of the camera so on and so forth so you
could absolutely check this out using
exif tool which is also one of my
favorite tools but you can also use
cyber chef for this
so
let's do that
all right so i'm going to open a file
dolls.jpg
and
we can see what magic says
render image will pro
do something let's try render image i
haven't actually done that i think it's
just going to show us the picture that
makes sense right
yes a very zoomed in version of the
picture i think it's even creepier now
we're like looking up a doll skirt
anyway um
okay so let's get rid of that recipe
uh so what we actually want to do is um
exif
extract exif but you could also remove
exif so i haven't tried it we'll have to
see how well it works um but extract
exif
and it's giving us it says here 50 tags
so lots and lots of data behind these
images right
and
so for example this is one that i
manipulated because it definitely didn't
and that's probably super hard to see
let me make it a little bigger again
okay
so yeah so i i manipulated this of
course um
just for fun
so the image description is no code
execution allowed here the make is
three-letter agency the model is spy
camera
i'll let you guess what three-letter
agency is associated with this none
really but you know you can use your
imagination and then we have gps
coordinates which is how you would
identify the
uh location
and
and then all this other stuff which i
still don't care about like the actual
like photograph part of it
um so yeah so this is super super easy
to do
the exif
analysis piece
okay
so
i have some time for questions i can
also
like take requests to try things
they may or may not work because this is
all live demo but if it starts being
like live demo where i wasn't even
planning it it might get a little crazy
um
and i think they said this goes till
noon but i'm not sure if it's nooner
oh one yeah okay it already is noon that
happened um
so yeah so i was planning to wrap up
around 10 minutes before four questions
or if people want to come up and like
try stuff
you could do that or if you have a
computer with you and you want to try
some stuff that's cool too
originally when i submitted this talk i
thought about doing it
as
a workshop
would you all be interested in the
workshop
like this like where you were doing
different operations and trying things
yeah okay i think i might do that at
some future event
um
also did i mention cyber jitsu con june
18th be there be square it's cool so
here's my info as i said i'm pretty much
marcel lee on like everything um my
medium is blogs mostly about cyber
competitions um with occasional other
things sprinkled in for good measure and
my linkedin you have to have my email
address to connect with me so that's
your first challenge
if you want to do some research you are
security research people right or want
to be
so it's not that hard to find my my
email address but you would need to do
that to connect with me um and then i'm
on twitter of course too so
so yeah so questions
ask me anything yes
yeah no you absolutely could do all this
in a script and not use cyber chef at
all oh
[Music]
yeah i don't know that's a good question
we'll have to look into that
command
so there's line scripts there
all right so if you didn't hear that uh
splunk has a
cyber chef integration interesting
there's actually different tools out
there um
i'm trying to think there's one i was
just using the other day like security
tools where they have cyber chef like
baked in to use so they're pretty common
um i don't know you with a hat
yes yes yes
did i not do that one okay
yeah let's try that
all right
uh i don't know let's try apples
grapes
bananas
whatever
okay and
let's do fork
and
then let's what operation do we want to
do let's say i don't know rot 13 or
something like that
yeah so
so i'm not sure if we needed the fork in
this case but that's how it would work
basically
right it could be either
oh i see what you're saying do two
different operations
yes
you definitely could do that there's a
whole section on
and i would have to like think about it
so i'm not going to try to do it right
now but
in this other section i think maybe
is
no not other where is it um
oh utilities maybe
i don't know where it is right now but
definitely there's options of things you
can do with fork and other like um tools
so great question so i don't know
exactly how to do it but
uh yes
um so just to identify the type of file
oh yeah yeah so you can do that um
i've never actually used it in here to
be honest because typically i just run
the file command
from command line but i think that
that's what this would do so let's
in the forensic section okay
all right
detect file type there we go
let's put that here
i'm going to delete that delete that
let's um
open up dolls again
oh thank you
there we go yes so it does do that
very good
thanks for the forensics tip
all right
any other questions i feel bad cause
like half the audience is leaving like
we don't have any questions oh nick
you're like behind my microphone
[Music]
no it's not so it's all
uh client-side everything is done
client-side
so that's super cool but especially if
you're doing it locally um you're
definitely golden so like right now i
wouldn't even need to be
um like you can see i'm just writing it
as a file on my local host and
everything is done
on this side my computer side so great
question thank you
all right any other questions
okay
well i think that that is it so
give you back five minutes of your life
and you can go to lunch early beach the
crowds
and thank you so much for coming i
really appreciate it
[Applause]