all right everyone hi thank you so much
for coming to our talk on dark side
striking back as black matter
my name is lindsey k and i'm director of
operational outcomes at recorded future
um
an insect group so i run our technical
arm of our threat intelligence team so
by trade i was a software engineer for
many years before getting into reverse
engineering and malware analysis and hi
i'm james niven i'm a principal threat
researcher also recorded future and
previously to record future i did a lot
of red teaming for offensive security
and crowdstrike and it gave me a unique
perspective into how operator how actors
would actually work day-to-day
awesome so before we get started we're
going to talk about a couple of
high-level terms in case you're not
super familiar with ransomware and
ransomware operations so first
ransomware is a service so at a very
high level this is a program who's run
by a group of people called
administrators so they're responsible
for creating the malware managing the
infrastructure
and other aspects of the actual program
itself and people called affiliates or
advertisers will obtain membership in
the program in order to get access to it
so they'll do so in a couple different
ways so either by vouches or by paying
for access and part of the benefit for
an aspiring affiliate of joining a ras
is actually being able to kind of have
that name recognition so you can imagine
if you want to lock someone's net and
you want them to pay
having that name recognition that
ensures that if they pay you they'll get
the decryption key is good but also the
rasp will take over some of the you know
other aspects of it because you get
access to a developer who can add new
features do bug fixes other things like
that
some of the victim payment
infrastructure different things like
that so you don't have to do it on your
own
so next tools and ttps so very basically
things that actors use at a technical
level so you may hear things like
malware malicious tools and then how
they actually use them
so big game hunting so around 2019
instead of targeting individuals
ransomware threat actors began actually
targeting organizations largely because
they have more of an ability and
willingness to pay the ransom than those
individuals and then finally the
underground ecosystem so this is where
one would buy and sell malware malicious
tools and different kinds of access to
organizations so we'll get into some of
that later but that could include stolen
credentials vpn rdp etc and then finally
how threat actors can communicate with
others
so ransomware is a business and we're
going to talk about a couple different
aspects of what this business entails so
first gaining access so how does a
threat actor first gain access to a
target system or organization
next acquiring data so how do they apply
the data what does it include and then
what can they do with it
next buying and selling of tools and
data so largely dark web marketplaces
and shops and then finally things that
they can acquire to enable operation and
infrastructure aspects of the ransomware
program
i hand it over to james excellence so
speaking of underground ecosystem and
the way that they have ability to buy
and sell things they've commoditized
almost everything it can range from
something small like netflix accounts
credentials there or it can arrange up
to uh initial access so pulse fortinet
vpns
logins for rdp sitting on the net
and these are done by initial access
brokers so as she spoke to earlier
ransomware can also be commoditized
where you pay a certain amount of money
to get into the program
0.1 bitcoin or something for instance
for non-rat non-russian speakers um
malware checkers steelers exploits brute
forces for credentials all this is sold
and hashed out in different programs
so it can also range to c2 frameworks so
cobalt strike for instance it's not
necessarily paid for i mean it's not
necessarily open source but you have
cracked versions of it lying around and
you have cna scripts or aggressor
scripts which can make a lot of this
stuff just one click you right click and
you can cover roast an entire network
so on the business of that this is
actually exploit this screenshot is
black matter when they first arrived and
this is the the country codes that
they're looking for and the reason they
choose these country codes is because
those are the people that are most
likely to pay we have cyber security and
whatnot more mature companies will pay
for that and they say that they don't
want any access for medical or state
institutions
they want
companies or networks that have
over 100 million dollars worth of
revenue and
more or less they're looking for access
here so
there's two primary forums for
russian-based ransomware it's exploiting
xss
and the way that it will typically work
is if you see this post and you want
information on it doesn't make a lot of
sense to respond to it right there
because then law enforcement or another
researcher just watching it is going to
get privy to that and start hunting you
so what you do is you send a private
message to this but knowing that forms
can be compromised you want to leave as
much information out of that private
message so you would create a one-time
note like a priv note that would say i'm
interested in this here's my talks or
telegram account or jabber and then take
all communication off that platform so
even administrator or compromised the
forums
they would have no trace of it
ex and once the colonial attack pipeline
attack happened everybody was really
bearing down on those forums and just
watching every single word
so how do they hide uh ransomware actors
are much like normal everyday red
teamers they'll use things that are
built into windows lol bins for instance
mshta and ms build if you send an hda
file it's essentially an html file and
tell it to build
code on the machine using.net framework
ms build or csc you essentially build
the payload on the victim machine and
bypasses a lot of initial detections
they will also use windows management
tools so active directory
they can do a lot of damage by having
access to active directory uh tell all
the machines to start updating and
looking for a specific file for instance
the locker and sis login or netlogin
directory on the domain controller
everything can read it and it'll fire
away at once
common applications that are on a lot of
networks slack and octa slack's a really
good example give us two so if you have
a password for a guest wi-fi it may be
applicable to other things in the
network that you could scan for
and red team tools so sharp hound rubios
cobalt strike
those are all
not all of them are open source but
they're on github and they're very
heavily documented and the actors will
use them and not have any real issues
with it and they can also customize it
so as we were speaking they innovate
they
this is an example of the real panel
before they were shut down so this shows
that
revix at the bottom as their linux
locker it shows all the changes with it
and different architectures it applies
to reveal 2.7 was not their last but it
was the one right before their last
update and it shows all the changes that
happened to that in the entire time we
tracked revolt they had about 15
versions of windows ransomware
cool so why does this actually matter so
revo was not kind of an anomaly right
threat actors especially ransomware
threat actors will keep innovating
largely because they have to
so first they are following security
trends so you might hear new
vulnerabilities that are discovered
if you ever read any sort of like it's
in response reports to look at how other
threat actors were caught what defenders
are looking for any sort of new research
that's coming out so if we have access
to it consider the fact that they also
do and they are learning from it so
they'll read news articles research
things that we publish ourselves so they
are getting insights there and following
those trends and often incorporating
that into their own ransomware so like i
said that they have access to a
developer is part of the ransomware as a
service program so this means new
features that affiliates are requesting
or you know might be effective in
helping get the companies to pay the
ransom um different sort of
optimizations because in a ransomware
tech they want to encrypt as much as
they can as fast as they can things like
antivirus evasion and anti-reverse
engineering techniques so make it harder
for the defenders to catch you and then
take it apart and figure out how to
write effective detections for you and
then bug fixes so
if something is broken the developer
will often fix it
so what this means is that we really
can't just use one approach to finding
them and rooting them out so we often
like to talk about tracking the
different versions of their tools but
this can really change over time so 15
versions of ravels windows ransomware
alone while not everything changed
between versions this is something that
does evolve over time we can't rely
entirely on it
infrastructure is something that is spun
up and down
so you can't really use that as sort of
a long-term tracking thing necessarily
and james talked a little bit about some
of those common ttps and red team tools
that they do use so you can leverage
some of that but that really isn't the
whole story as well
so what we're going to do is we're going
to talk through an irl example of how
this happened
at the mid to late part of last year
so looking specifically at how a
ransomware threat actor rapidly evolved
their software in response to several
external factors like discovery by
security researchers
and some of the demand for new features
in their malware so we're going to use
black matter as an example and we
actually discovered the group in july
2021 and shortly thereafter put out a
technical deep dive on the
malware the way we discovered black
matter was it was right place right time
but with some good knowledge so
we're familiar with the colonial
pipeline attack it caused a lot of
issues at the pump got a lot of law
enforcement
focused right on dark side so darkseid
really went into hiding some of their
people got caught and they backed down
for a bit so with dark side out of the
picture for now
we still have reveal so rival has
windows linux locker like we talked
about in esxi locker so esxi locker is
really really important because you can
have all these magical tools for windows
to protect windows host but if you host
them all on esxi which has none of these
cool tools and you lock the data store
the entire network's locked so esxi is
really really effective and so with all
the pressure on dark side them going
away
re and this was time during the time of
the us and russian talks about
ransomware as a whole so
this
screenshot on the bottom is actually uh
from the rebel panel and it's from the
administrator he says uh well previous
to that he said no attacks on usa for
two weeks until these talks are over
this thing actually is addressing the
jbs foods case so jbs foods the top one
is from jbs foods to the fbi saying we
got attacked by rival
we're shut down we have a lot of issues
so
everyone said jbs foods is usa company
it's not technically and that's what
that post is saying it's jbs sa out of
brazil um jbs foods usa does exist but
it's a subset so they are arguing that
they didn't attack a usa company so
this caused a lot of focus on reveal and
started them to shut down we knew a lot
of information about their actors and
affiliates so using this knowledge
communicating to them on talks and
jabber and other services looking for an
esxi locker is essentially how we landed
on black matter
so this is actually a
black matters panel his first day you
join you get all this information so it
says we take the best features from
rival dark side lock bit we've tested
all our platform and our vulnerabilities
to give you a little context darkside
had the decryption issue in the past
which we'll talk about later
and there's talking about it uses on
all the things it works on all the nas
devices linux esxi all the windows
versions and
go ahead
so here you see on the left is dark side
panel on the right is black matter panel
pretty visually
similar to them
you'll have the way to
do your different builds on the top
right all the company victim information
the bitcoin addresses
you can see it's relatively the same
panel
cool so at the outset there were two
versions that were released initially
one for windows and one for linux and
esxi so
the windows ransomware did have some
fairly extensive anti-reverse
engineering and anti-analysis
capabilities
nothing insurmountable but definitely
harder than average
comparatively the linux and esxi one was
very straightforward so it actually
included function names that they did
not actually scrub from it and the
configuration file which gives you kind
of information about you know what it
should do that
a fed actors configured to do was
de-obfuscated which made it
substantially easier to reverse engineer
so on the bottom right you can see
examples of what those function names do
and in case you're not a reverse
engineer one of the things that's like
really kind of just gold is when thread
actors leave these things in because if
you're trying to figure out what a
function is doing it's really helpful to
have the name with specific things such
as get running vms so that really does
help speed up some of the analysis there
and on the top you can see an example of
the windows ransom note that it dropped
so
generally when we talk about tracking of
threat actors tools there's a couple
different things that we'll start to
look for so really what you want to look
for is something unusual or distinctive
that that specific actor does
so um some places that i generally like
to look so first cryptographic routines
so
these can range in you know interesting
kind of combinations of the
cryptographic routines which we'll get
into soon um or things that they
implement custom so not true crypto but
like string obfuscation uh routines and
something like that um sometimes threat
actors will roll their own and they'll
do it incorrectly and if it's something
they do that is particularly distinctive
you can also use that signature on so
one example of black matter string
decryption routine you can see in the
top image we'll look at the key init
function soon but this was something
where they had
strings were not in plain text they made
it harder to reverse engineer by
doing some light obfuscation to them but
it was one of the elements of the first
signature that we were able to write for
them because it was unique
so other obfuscation techniques that
threat actors might use
can also help you start tracking them
especially again if they are unique
so for example um we can look at some of
the call obfuscation that black matter
used so on the bottom is
a very normal kind of windows api call
really how you would see it when you're
reverse engineering it you can see call
to the specific function black matter
didn't do that so in order to make it
harder to reverse engineer what they had
was they had a magic value
and then they'd xor that value with
another value and then jump to that
address in order to make the call so if
you're doing static reverse engineering
now you have to figure out where it is
jumping to where in memory what's loaded
there which complicates it substantially
however this was another element of the
signature that we were able to create
because this magic value appeared
all throughout the code and it was
something that was just baked in and
pretty distinctive
so again magic numbers very helpful
especially if it's something that you
know they derive on their own and nobody
else is really using um and while black
matter did not do this one of my
personal favorites is misspellings so
sometimes you'll see um you know error
messages or log messages or you know
file names mutex names different strings
that are in the malware that they've
misspelled and if it's particularly
distinctive misspelling and it goes
throughout versions they don't change it
that can also be pretty useful
so
we put out a report in july and after we
released this report new versions of the
windows ransomware started to appear so
some of them were fairly simple changes
such as that magic x or key started
changing
and then others were more complex so the
addition of new features
so
one of the examples of how the string
encryption actually changed so we talked
about that key init function on the top
was the very simplistic one that they
used in their first
version we put out a
little python script to decode the
strings and then several versions later
we actually noticed the encryption key
initialization for the uh string
obfuscation change substantially became
substantially more complex and you can
see that on the bottom
ultimately we never actually saw another
version of the linux and esxi ransomware
not entirely sure why but there you go
and ultimately between july 2021 and
september 2021 we saw them release six
different versions of their ransomware
um version numbers 1.2 to 3.0
so let's talk a little bit about some of
those feature editions so
we'll get into some of these but things
like printing the ransomware note on
local printers to add some excitement i
guess when you encrypt
encrypting additional file types so
adding that support as well
letting the threat actor identify
specific computers not to encrypt so on
the right you can see an example of kind
of the build panel where you can
configure it and say you know what kinds
of folders to white lists
files different things like that so you
could identify which computers to avoid
um the implementation of their
cryptographic algorithm and then looking
for large files and encrypting them
differently so in a ransomware attack
time is of the essence for the thread
actor because they want to encrypt
everything as fast as possible so that
the victim can't you know stop it midway
and they really have kind of maximum
impact so being able to encrypt large
files you'll sometimes see thread actors
encrypt only pieces of them add
increments whatever to just
make them so that they're not usable but
not waste any time in getting as much
damage as quickly as possible
so let's look at a couple of the uh
specific features so between versions
1.6 and 2.0 we saw them
modify some of their printing
print the ransomware
note to printers function
here's an example so on the left
in versions 1.6 to 1.9 we saw them just
say print anything as long as the
printer isn't named pdf because that's a
virtual printer but over time um they
actually evolved this to say ignoring
pdf and then some additional virtual
printers
so
kind of another interesting element of
their obfuscation you can see instead of
looking for the specific names they take
a hash of the name to make it just a
little bit more complicated it's custom
hatching algorithm
we talked a little bit about encrypting
different kinds of files so on the left
you can see they add the ability first
to encrypt microsoft exchange files um
that's kind of how they did it and then
they added the capability to handle the
large ones differently so we talked a
little bit about why there's a point to
that um so what they do is they check
for different extensions and then behave
differently accordingly
so you may remember mzsoft actually came
out with a decrypter for black matter
ransomware that said victims do not have
to purchase the
cryptokey to decrypt and they can still
decrypt their ransomware which suggests
that there is some kind of cryptographic
issue
so the threat actor supposedly fixed the
issue in about late september 2021
um we can't really speak to the specific
cryptographic issue at hand here but um
you can kind of see some evolution in
how at least the key initialization code
um came between the different versions
so there are other kind of changes in
the other crypto code but we won't get
into those
so you can see version 1.2 2.0 and 3.0
kind of stacked right there
won't necessarily get into that but it
is interesting to see sort of like how
they make those little changes
especially if there was a bug
so
we talked a little bit about the overlap
between darkseid and black matter
so
other researchers actually
suggested that looking at how the kind
of cryptographic
key material was generated so using the
custom salsa 20 matrix that had
previously been originally unique to
dark side so we talked about like unique
and interesting crypto was now something
that they were observing a very similar
um cryptographic routine in black matter
so what this looks like between them so
you can see the random buffer
initialization for black matter for dark
side on the top followed by the rsa 1024
encryption and then you can see black
matter's implementation on the bottom so
not entirely
you know exactly the same but you do see
some similarities
so slight difference in how they
actually did the generation of the
random buffer but semantically it's
pretty similar so that's what the
researchers are pointing out we just
want to give an example of that
so i'm going to hand it back over to
james to talk about the end thanks
so
dark side had the colonial plaque plant
attack they messed up on that a little
too high profile for them they also have
the decryption issues which we didn't
talk about specifically but with black
matter we did so they've had
decryption issues for black matter as
well they hit a
agricultural
entity really heavily that caused a lot
of issues and the security researchers
jumped into that chat and just
took over it and they couldn't
differentiate between victim and
researcher and just had had they're
really flustered at the time so they've
made critical mistakes and they just
announced that they're done with it
they're shutting down so this is
actually the panel saying in 48 hours
we're gone we're gonna hand out
decryption keys so it sounds like it's
the end of black matter but it's not
so
this is actually an interview by one of
our colleagues that reaches out to
another ransomware called alpha and it
he they basically admitted to it so if
you read through it it will say that
with the
victim chats having issues and not being
able to tell between victim and
impersonator
and the decryption issues this caused us
to shut down and then we see another
actor lock bit say this is black matter
doing a rebranding so what that what
black matter did was they they were mad
they just fired the entire dev team for
the locker and we'll show
so this right here this is alpha and
this is basically the intro to their
their new
ransomware project and it says we have
esi lockers you get a certain percentage
of cut
they completely redid the locker wrote
it in rust
lots of new fancy features they made it
specific so if you capture a ransom note
on virustotal you can't actually do
anything with it because you have to
have a specific access code to be able
to visit the victim panel they rewrote
the
entire panel itself they added a lot of
features
new support tools new faqs built-in
mixers
they're actually working on another
thing called morph which allows
uh real near real-time de-oper
obfuscation of the locker itself to
bypass some signatures
so they're still around
so
as probably defenders uh we're probably
asking what is it now that we do because
it seems like
they spin up they spin down they rebrand
they join new programs so what is it
that we can do so one of the things i
want to underscore is that in order to
successfully find malicious thought
actors um after they kind of disappear
um it really does require a very
multifaceted approach so not only the
technical
skills and signatures and things like
that but also subject matter experts who
know kind of how to find them and what
to start looking for
um also detections like you know i have
to mention that so looking for things
like those commonly used tools and ttps
so things like cobalt strike will remain
eternally popular with abts and
ransomware threat actors and
it's very easy to get so while that
won't completely solve the problem being
able to detect these sort of malicious
tools and their use does get you you
know some of the way
um looking for also the latest threats
so things like pre-ransomware tools or
new open source technology and tools is
really important um like i said they
they can read the same things that we
see like they look at github if they
find new tools that they like and you
know help them accomplish their goals
they're probably going to use them so
keeping abreast of like what is going on
now what people are releasing and then
what could be useful
is also important
um you know kind of very well known
detection types so things like yara
sigma and snort uh wherever possible to
be able to track either you know
from a defensive perspective or if you
like to threat hunt or look for malware
to take apart um can help you start
finding these specific or threat actors
specific tools like some of what we
talked about
other ioc fees as well are super useful
so known command and control servers
malicious hashes things like that
um and then we all talk a lot about
logging and turning on logging but
making sure that the logs capture
exactly what you think they should
so that in the event that something does
in fact happen you're able to get the
information that you expect and would
probably need to figure out you know
what happened in case you weren't able
to stop it
um doing things like implementing common
security measures so account pruning
strong passwords etc
active directory james talked a little
bit about you know having access to
active directory is pretty powerful so
making sure you're doing cleanup
disabling legacy objects and then
implementing best practices there
and then finally consider using
multi-factor authentication for things
like remote access services like rdp and
citrix so these are still popular with
ransomware threat actors and they will
take advantage of them
so with that
are there any questions
well it doesn't really come as a whole
package it all depends on what you're
looking for if it's a
so if you're if you have access to a
whole bunch of compromised machines and
you want to buy information stealer it
costs very little because all you're
essentially doing is buying access to
the panel you're generating the builder
and then you're sending it to the
networks you already own um so it could
be a few hundred bucks a month maybe
less it all depends on usage and how
much you want to get access to so what's
the actual like
themselves
so they're free
all these are free yeah
yeah so what they do is basically if you
join as an affiliate they have a core
set of administrators the people inside
these groups don't know who each other
are there are certain subsets so the
administrators know themselves most of
them personally this small subset so
let's say for instance you joined and
you were the one to own the keys if you
have that guy that guy and that guy that
don't know each other in real life but
you know enough to work and get a
network
they're not going to know any of that
and other teams will know that as well
it's only just who you have so
the more depth you compromise and more
successful payments you have depends on
the cut so initially so for alpha it's
since they just started it was ninety
percent so ninety percent goes to you
your team to be out how you want and
then ten percent goes to the
administrator for building
additional functions paying buy new cars
whatever it is
and you'll see a lot of it go like that
if you don't do well you can either get
kicked out of the group or kick down to
80 75
but they want as many people as she said
they're advertisers that's how they view
themselves by locking a network you're
advertising for them so
um
right
yeah so there actually was uh innocence
agreeable with that and there was so
when you have access these panels
normally if it's a really good victim
and you are if you're an affiliate that
don't doesn't feel
comfortable talking to a victim you can
just say i want administrators to handle
all the communication get the payment
and then send it to me so they and they
can even ask questions so the
administrator if you're an affiliate and
you block this network the administrator
wants to know all these things he wants
to know the zoom info revenue he wants
to know
what they are as long as they're not a
hospital because like after the dark
side incidents they put up different
rule sets like don't block hospitals
don't log oil pipelines so they moderate
it before you can even lock it there's
mistakes always but
they'll also um
i just lost traffic a lot that what was
your question sorry
yes so they have the ability to already
see all those chats right and there are
cases of where they will jump into those
chats and take over uh there's a whole
big i think there's a few threads on it
on exploit about uh
signature that was saying how they stole
all this millions of dollars of money
through that back door using keys that
were built into the
locker itself so they do there's no
honor model they use and they do
actually
hijack each other
these guys are still doing it years
later like at first the rants start
they're just new but they'll learn but
they're still doing it so is it is this
to avoid detection or is there some
other research
i mean it's honestly hard to say why
right so having the something that you
know will avoid detection right that's
great or maybe like oh hey it's this
cool new thing so it really is hard to
say why they do it obviously like they
shouldn't right because mistakes do
happen and then it's like
you know bad for business if you're not
actually having to like sell the key to
kind of get it deprived so
in terms of like the actual kind of
locker
would not roll their own in terms of why
they do custom crypto through a lot of
the string type stuff so
their job is to slow people like me down
like make it harder for me to figure out
what the hell is going on with their
ransomware or understand what's going on
or write those detections so having
those unique string kind of obfuscation
crypto algorithms having any sort of
unique obfuscation yeah it takes longer
to do
as long as they protect the key
yeah i mean
in terms of
the kind of like actual hardcore like
crypto to actually you know encrypt the
files yes absolutely
the string encryption stuff like that's
never really like real encryption that
doesn't actually matter so there are
those kind of like two parts of it but
like yeah they should totally use actual
crypto with the protected key that's
proven but the second question is on the
key generation itself
um
inputs
so i'm not a deep crypto expert um you
might have to ask one of them
so i would say logging would be more
useful for um you know figuring out what
they had access to what they could have
accessed um you know exfiltrated did
they have any network connectivity did
they exfiltrate anything so it's really
more of the like oh something has
happened what did happen you know did
they query any databases things like
that if it makes sense
i can actually add to your first
question a little bit for an example
they do it so we said that they're
advertisers as they like to put it
lockment if you go to their site on
their
public blog they say we're the fastest
locker out there and it's because they
only do a certain amount of uh locking
per file so of course you're the fastest
if you only lock a megabyte worth of
data
and then the second aspect to that is
you have to realize who these people are
a lot of them are extremely arrogant
they drive fast cars have a lot of
retail or real estate they're they think
they are better than you they think that
your best practices are you're sitting
at a nine to five practices but they can
do better than you so they feel
confident in rolling that well they want
fast and sick while they just use
tonight
why do they walk corporations
that if you know the playing text that
crypto file and the number wouldn't know
what it was it is also easier to break
into a bible in your own
party some of the research
anybody else
all right say nothing thank you guys so
much
[Applause]