>> ANNOUNCER: Please
welcome Mark Russinovich.
>> MARK RUSSINOVICH:
Good morning, everybody.
Try that again.
Thanks for coming.
It is Friday morning, a long
week here at RSA conference.
My name is Mark Russinovich.
I'm the Chief Technology Officer
of Microsoft Azure, and I'm here
to talk about -- let's see if I
can make the slide go back here.
About -- okay, title
slide is missing.
I'm here to talk about
open source security.
That might seem an odd thing
to some of you for a Microsoft
person to be coming up here to
talk about open source security,
those of you that haven't been
watching what Microsoft has been
doing with open source security.
Microsoft, for those of you that
haven't been paying attention,
is deeply an open source
company at this point.
But then how does that
relate to me being the CTO of
Microsoft Azure?
Why am I here to talk
about open source security?
The reason is that when we take
a look at Azure as a Cloud
platform, a ton of it is
built on top of open source.
We consume open source.
We also publish open source.
And so when you think about the
Cloud provider's responsibility
to our customers, they don't
really care what we build our
platform on.
What they care about is that
we're keeping them secure.
And that means that with
whatever we use to build that
platform, the buck
stops with us.
If there is a problem in our
own software that we create
internally or a software that
we're consuming or a hardware
we're consuming from third
parties, if there is a problem,
customers expect us to deal
with it and keep them secure.
And so this is very near and
dear to my heart in terms of
what can we do to make
Azure more secure.
It leads into the supply
chain of Azure, which includes
open source.
I'm also here because the
COVID-19 thing hasn't gotten too
crazy yet, so I thought I'd
show up today and risk it.
But imagine a world where a
hugely popular open source
package gets compromised and
people are consuming it and
deploying it and operating
it and the world becomes
compromised because of this
open source dependency.
It sounds like something that is
theoretical, but, in fact, it
has happened and it's happened
multiple times and it continues
to happen.
These are just some of the
examples of open source being
compromised and then
being consumed in that
compromised state.
Some of you might
have seen these.
These are both from
the last two years.
Webmin, an incredibly popular
web portal administration
toolkit, this was compromised
for a whole year with a DDoS
backdoor and a credential
stealing backdoor.
It allowed an attacker to get
into the web server that's being
managed by this thing and deploy
arbitrary software onto it.
Downloaded a million times
during that year that it
was compromised.
Rest-client.
This is a package that a lot of
developers used to authenticate
to rest APIs.
This was backdoored to steal the
credentials that came as part of
that authentication.
Event-Stream, a package that was
downloaded 1,000 times or 1,500
times a week.
This thing was backdoored.
And then finally, VestaCP,
another control panel platform
for managing websites, this was
backdoored in a source control
system and also served as a DDoS
malware distribution platform
for the attackers
that got into it.
These are all examples,
and there are many more.
Here is an example of one
timeline for a very popular open
source package
called Boostrap-sass.
This package has been
downloaded in its lifetime
28 million times.
It was compromised
you see on this date.
The package was compromised in
the MPM repository -- in Ruby.
Sorry, it's a Ruby package.
It was compromised by an
attacker, the package, that got
control of it, removed the last
good one, and then published one
that had an exploit in it.
And you can see that at the time
that it was discovered, at that
point, there was no last known
good to fall back on because
they'd removed it.
And so at this point, the
Ruby package management was
scrambling to figure out how to
get people that knew that they
were compromised to get back
into a secure state and a good
one was eventually published.
But you can see a total of
eight days where really anybody
dependent on the upstream Ruby
package management system was in
a state where they couldn't get
fixed if they downloaded the
vulnerable package.
Event-Stream is an interesting
one because this one has a story
where it shows us we're so
dependent on people that we
don't know producing the
software that we consume.
In the case of Event-Stream, the
maintainer for this Event-Stream
package -- like I said, it's
incredibly popular - just felt
he didn't have time to
maintain it anymore.
He got emailed by somebody
saying, hey, you know what, I
see you're really busy.
I'm really passionate
about this thing.
Why don't you let me help?
The maintainer gave management
control to this volunteer.
This volunteer made some
changes, published an update to
it, everything looked good, and
then they introduced after that
a dependency, that dependency
was a malicious dependency that
was aimed at stealing Bitcoin
for anybody that was at a
company called Copay off of
whatever wallets were sitting
there on the servers that it
happened to get installed on.
That's an example of somebody
trust -- kind of getting trust
inside the open source ecosystem
supply chain and then being able
to infiltrate and
get a backdoor.
Fortunately, like this package
is incredibly popular, but the
fact is that it was only
targeted at this particular
Copay Bitcoin.
It wasn't going after a general
purpose compromise, in which
case the effect would
have been much broader.
Let's talk a little bit about
the agenda because I think the
way that you have to frame the
problem -- and by the way, I
want to make it clear that the
problems that I'm talking about
aren't specific to
open source in many cases.
They're general software
supply chain problems.
The fact is that open source is
such a massive ecosystem that we
need to go after it specifically
and there are some specific
implementation points in the
supply chain that need to be
addressed for open source.
Let me talk by framing the kind
of whole problem about how we
consume software as a supply
chain, and then I'll get into
the various steps of that supply
chain, what the issues are,
examples, and what is happening
for open source ecosystem to
help address those points
in the supply chain.
I'll start here by talking about
supply chain in the context of a
food supply chain, which is one
that we're all familiar with.
A farmer is growing crops, a
buyer is purchasing those crops,
a distributor is taking and
shipping the products into
stores, and then a
customer is buying them.
If you map this onto software,
an open source software, you've
got open source developers,
there are source code
repositories where they are
storing their source code, there
are application developers that
are consuming the output of that
source code, and then they are
providing an end product to
their customers.
This is the simplified form.
It is actually much, much more
complex and this is what makes
the problem especially
challenging because along the
supply chain there could be
dozens, hundreds, or even
thousands of participants at
different points of different
source code repositories,
package management systems,
consumers, products, and
other distribution points.
There are many
loops here as well.
But if you take a look at it
from this framing, then we can
go after specific parts of it.
The question when you're
consuming from the supply chain,
and this one applies to us in
Azure, is how do we prevent
unwanted products from
entering the supply chain.
How do we make sure that only
packages and source that we've
got some assurance are
trustworthy enter our
supply chain?
How do we know what's
in our supply chain?
Kind of that begs the question.
And how do we ensure that what
we know about that supply chain
is reliable?
When somebody says this is
trustworthy, hey, I've done code
reviews on it, I've got MFA in
place for checking the source
code, how do we know that
that's really truly the case?
And then what do we do when
there is a vulnerability?
How do I identify what is
affected by that vulnerability
and how do we roll back
to the good version?
Those are all the kinds of
questions that we've got to
answer when we take a
look at this from a supply
chain perspective.
First, how do we find
vulnerabilities, how do we help
the open source ecosystem find
vulnerabilities in the source
code at the source, kind of
where the crops are being made?
And if you take a look at it
from a crop perspective, this
means how do we end up finding
that there's E.coli somewhere in
those crops before it gets out.
We need to stop it from
even getting in there in the
first place.
Or if it gets in, stopping that
from getting down into the
supply chain.
And when we talk about
vulnerabilities in source code,
this applies to open source and
closed source as well, there
could be credentials in the
code, there could be improper
validation of inputs, there
could be ability for an attacker
to upload arbitrary code and for
that to be executed by the code,
and there could be denial
service opportunities where
you're taking a dependency with
a customer-facing piece of
source code, piece of open
source or closed source, and it
has got a vulnerability that
lets somebody bring down your
whole service.
One of the ways that something
can get into the supply chain
that's malicious is a technique
called typo squatting.
This has been known as a
problem, especially in the Node
ecosystem where package
names are extremely short.
Has anybody ever used one of
these packages in your open
source projects?
Maybe you have.
Maybe you haven't.
But they all kind
of look generic.
They look like, if you're
looking for something specific,
like I'm looking for the
dateutil for Python 3, and you
know that there's a popular one
out there, you might go and pull
this one.
The fact is that these are
variants on well-known packages
that are popular in
the Python community.
You can see cross-env, dateutil
instead of Python 3 dateutil,
and this kind of typo squatting
is a way that we've seen
compromised open source
get into the supply chain.
There have been efforts to go
figure out how we can prevent
typo squatting.
There is something called the
Lichtenstein Delta which looks
at how close words are to each
other and there have been
proposals to say, hey, we don't
let packages come in that are
too close to existing popular
packages in terms of that delta.
But the fact is when it comes to
Python and Node and others where
they've got very short names, it
makes it very difficult because
this graph shows that a huge
number of packages have very
short distances between each
other of well-known packages.
This is a tough, challenging
problem, how do we keep
developers from getting
compromised versions of things
that have names close to
what they're looking for.
Static code analysis is another
very popular way to go and
address vulnerabilities, looking
for the vulnerabilities in the
code, scanning automatically
during a CI/CD pipeline, and
really stopping the
vulnerabilities from getting
into the supply chain
in the first place.
There are a few different open
source efforts or products,
services that open source
publishers can take advantage of
and open source consumers can
take advantage of to make sure
that vulnerabilities haven't
been entering them through this.
One of them is called Synopsys
which looks at every line of
code and execution path
looking for vulnerabilities and
flagging them.
You can see that it's got a huge
number of vulnerabilities you
can see that it will check for.
As is common in many cases,
for open source projects, this
service is completely free.
This is something that's just
easy for somebody developing
open source to
take advantage of.
It's why not do this if
it's going to make your code
more secure.
Microsoft purchased GitHub a
few years ago, and one of the
purchases GitHub has made
since that time is a company
called Semmle.
Semmle is a source code
vulnerability analysis platform
based off of language that's
been called -- renamed the
CodeQL for code query
language that lets you do
variant detection on
common vulnerabilities.
And so the idea here is that if
a vulnerability is detected in a
piece of source code of a
certain pattern that you can
write a CodeQL query that will
find now just that specific
version of the vulnerability but
also variants that are close to
it through the query language
that has regular expression type
syntax as part of it.
One of the services that GitHub
is offering for open source
developers is something called
Security Lab which, for open
source projects, is free, and
for research projects for
research is also free, which
lets you go and scan open source
projects using Semmle queries,
CodeQL queries, a growing
ecosystem of them.
There is a full ecosystem of
CodeQL queries that look for
very common and exist a kind
of vulnerabilities that have
already been seen in source
code and lets you find them.
And then there is snyk which
is a way to stop open source
vulnerabilities from getting
into your supply chain, ones
that you might be
consuming as a developer.
If you're going to pull from a
package and that package has a
known vulnerability,
this will let you know.
It will also scan your source
code repos looking for package
dependencies and let you know
if you've got vulnerabilities.
And, again, this is something
that is completely free for open
source repos.
I want to show you a quick demo
of CodeQL so you get an idea for
the power of this for
open source projects.
I have got a GitHub repo here
for a project called java-test,
and you can see I've made a pull
request on it which is labeled
with a name that describes
just how bad this thing is.
A lot of users
submitted content.
If I click on that pull request,
because I've enabled Semmle
scanning or CodeQL scanning
on this, those scans have
identified a problem.
This pull request introduces one
alert when merging, view it on
lgtm.com, which is where the
free CodeQL service is hosted.
And at this point, what you can
see is it will show me right in
the source code the
vulnerability and the path of
the vulnerability.
I'm not going to spend time
diving into the source code
here, but what is happening here
is that it's taking unsanitized
input from the user,
deserializing that, and then
executing it.
That's this execute right
up here, Mona.dance.
It's basically deserialized
this untrusted input into this
dance method.
This is very obvious,
of course, but just here for
demonstration purposes.
If I say show pass, this takes
me and shows just the snippets
of code from the source here
where you get input stream right
there, which is the untrusted
input, into the deserialization,
and then finally how that gets
packaged up and made part of
that method.
All of that is just right
there at your fingertips.
You can see which queries you've
enabled on your open source
repo, and the built-in java
queries that have been enabled
on this one includes, for
example, character passed to
StringBuffer or
StringBuilder constructor.
This comes with a description of
the type of vulnerability being
scanned for with an example of
it as well as recommendations on
how to avoid or fix
these kinds of problems.
Very powerful tool.
Like I mentioned, it is an
ecosystem of these kinds of
queries that has been built up.
Here is the GitHub repo for
the CodeQL queries that are
available and a bunch of
different languages available
here for CodeQL to go query.
Again, completely free for
open source development.
Let's go back to
the presentation.
One of the other types of
vulnerabilities very common both
in closed and
open source software is
uninitialized variables.
And one of the ways to fall
into the trap of uninitialized
variables is uninitialized heap
and stack, which is come hit,
especially native code, C
and C++ code, very commonly.
Heartbleed is one great example
of it where uninitialized
buffer, you could trick the open
SL server into passing a buffer
back that was longer than it had
been filled in with legitimate
content, and then see what was
beyond it, and what was beyond
it could be information that
would allow you to steal
credentials and keys and
compromise other users of
that site.
There have been efforts
here that have taken place.
The reason that I mention this,
it's going after eliminating
entire bug classes and doing it
in a way that gets to the heart
of open source ecosystem supply
chains, which include compilers
like Clang.
And so this is an effort that's
been supported by Microsoft and
Google and others to go and
modify these to default to
initialization.
One of the reasons why these
compilers historically have no
initialized is because
of performance concerns.
Going and zeroing memory is a
waste if you're going to just
immediately override it,
but then you end up being
susceptible for something
like a Heartbleed.
The goal here is to change the
default to initialize to zeroes,
and then somebody that sees a
performance issue with that
understands that they have not
exposed themselves by disabling
it for particular initialization
buffer can go and disable it if
they need to for
performance reasons.
Here is just an example
of a tweet by one of my
heroes, actually.
Just let me pull it back.
John Carmack himself
getting bit by these things.
Number of days since
uninitialized C++ variable
caused me grief, zero.
This is something that even
professional developers that
have been in the business
for a long time get hit by.
Another way to go find
vulnerabilities is through a
technique called fuzzing that
I'm sure everybody in this room
is aware of.
Lots of different types of
vulnerabilities can be detected
through fuzzing.
The question is how do I get
access to a fuzzer and how do I
get access to the platform that
will fuzz my code automatically.
In the open source world,
they're Google stepped up here,
and it's created a
platform called OSS-Fuzz.
This is a free service
for open source projects.
You go and request access to it.
You provide points to the repo.
You provide an email address
with the maintainer.
And then once you get onboarded
to it, you get -- your code gets
automatically fuzzed by this
service, and you can see that
it's been incredibly successful,
17,000 bugs and 250 open source
projects already detected
through this fuzzing service.
It supports a number of
different fuzzing engines.
It supports C++.
It supports Rust and Go.
This is an example of the kinds
of efforts that we really
support to get the whole
ecosystem in a better place.
Let's talk a little bit about
dependency management now
because we've taken care
of trying to keep the
vulnerabilities from getting
into the supply chain in the
first place in those crops, but
how do we then determine when
there is a vulnerability that's
been exposed, where that came
from, and what's impacted by it.
This is all about supply chain.
Here is a great example of
supply chain in action of open
source ecosystem Electron,
which is the rendering engine
underneath a bunch of popular
products, including Visual
Studio Code, Atom,
Slack, Discord.
This had a vulnerability
introduced into it inadvertently
that allowed the integration
of no JS to be enabled.
By default, when you're running
on one of these platforms like
this, it's disabled, and it's
disabled because enabling it
allows somebody accessing the
interface to deploy arbitrary
node code, JavaScript code,
and executed as system in the
context of that app.
The vulnerability that was
introduced here allowed an
attacker to override that
control and turn the setting to
allow execution of arbitrary
node code and that would then
allow the attacker
to take over the site.
You can see the downstream
dependencies on something
like that.
Every one of these projects
that depended on that upstream
Electron with that vulnerability
now had to go and remediate.
But the first question is: How
do you even know that you've got
this dependency?
How do you know that
there's a vulnerability?
And then how does the whole
supply chain through all the
dependency chains update in
a way that gets everybody as
secure as possible.
And one of the questions this
highlights is -- one of the
issues this highlights is just
how deep dependency chains are
in the open source world.
Here is a little snipped of code
where I am actually depending on
the express web server.
This looks like
I have introduced one
single dependency.
Now all I have to do is monitor
express, and if express is
showing that it's not got any
vulnerabilities, I'm good.
But, actually, the story is a
little bit deeper than that,
because once I import express, I
actually import a whole bunch of
other things with it
that it's dependent on.
In fact, here is the
dependency list for express.
It's got 48 packages that
it imports for its use.
And so what I've just done by
importing express is import all
of these.
I've imported all of the source
code development practices of
all of these packages.
I've imported basically all of
the contributors to all of these
packages as well
and their intentions which are
hopefully benevolent.
Now I'm dependent
on all of that.
I came across this
tweet last month.
This is NPM install, what
somebody likens it to, because
the node ecosystem is one of the
ones that has the deepest and
broadest number of dependencies,
and the reason is because people
just import little snippets,
and so a single project could
literally import thousands or
tens of thousands of these
little node packages to make
up a reasonably sized piece
of software.
In fact, let's
just do a survey here.
What's the average number of
packages trusted by installing
one node package?
Anybody want to take a guess?
Forty?
Anybody else?
Sixty?
The answer is 80,
so not too far off.
The interesting trend we're
seeing with this in these
ecosystems is that when
something gets popular, it gets
even more popular.
This is the average
package reach over time.
You can see the packages in
this ecosystem have gotten
more popular.
The reach of these packages in
terms of the number of services,
other packages that take a
dependency on them has continued
to grow.
Eighty was just the average, but
you can see the tail goes up
into the hundreds.
And here is the top five most
referenced packages in the node
supply chain.
You can see that you're talking
now 150,000 dependent packages
on one of these.
Vulnerability in one of these
and the downstream effect is
pretty monstrous.
Here is another great example.
Do you remember when we
took a picture of a black hole
last year?
That was kind of a cool event,
and it was done all with open
source software.
Here is the project,
ehtim, eht-imaging.
The interesting thing to note
about this is if you take a look
at the number of contributors,
15 contributors on this project
involved with developing a
software that could go analyze
these images and basically
photograph a black hole.
But if you look underneath
the hood, because of all the
dependencies they took on other
packages, there were really
24,500 contributors
to this project.
This truly was a much broader
ecosystem effort, really, if you
take a look at everything
that was used to build this.
It went way beyond the
original 15 contributors.
So how do you know what your
upstream dependencies look like?
It depends on the type of
software that you're using,
of course.
One of the tools in the node
ecosystem for looking at this,
which is a free tool to go use,
it is an interactive tool where
you can go take a look and
get an idea for what you're
dependent on, but there are many
automated tools out there for
the different ecosystems that
you should consider using.
Let's go take a
look at this one.
You can see here the
URL is mpm.broofa.com.
Up here, you can enter a module
name and it will go look at the
dependencies it's got and show
them to you, and it will also
show you the contributors
that were involved in making
those dependencies.
Anybody got a
node pack -- anybody here a
JavaScript developer?
Just raise your hands.
Okay.
Name a package that you use.
Singular?
Angular. Okay. Angular.
I don't know why
that's not coming up.
Zero dependencies.
I don't know.
That doesn't make sense.
Let me try and make
sure this is working.
Yeah.
I don't know why it came up with
zero dependencies for Angular.
Maybe it's fully self-contained.
But Express, which we were
looking at earlier, 48
dependencies, 56 maintainers.
I was curious, like NPM
itself, what that looks like.
When you run NPM for NPM
install, you're actually taking
a huge set of dependencies, 380
dependencies, and the number of
developers, 188 maintainers.
I want to make clear that that's
maintainers, not contributors.
The number of contributors is
probably in the thousands or
tens of thousands.
All of this isn't feeding
into your supply chain.
When you run NPM on your server,
you're dependent on all of that.
All right.
Let's go back to the deck.
The takeaway for this section is
automate your dependency mapping
and your build pipelines, apply
those tools that can go identify
dependencies so you understand
what you're dependent on, which
will come in use when you're
looking for vulnerabilities.
It also becomes useful when
you're looking at importing
things and making sure that
they adhere to the policies you
define and that they're also
being maintained in a way that
doesn't allow vulnerabilities
to get into your supply chain.
Let's take a look now at build
systems and package managers
because this has been another
area where in the open source
ecosystem itself, this is kind
of like going to the grocery
store and compromising the
product there by putting some
chemical on it and now people
are walking away with it.
Because the farmer did the right
thing, made sure there's no
E.coli, the shipper got it to
the store in okay shape, but at
that point now the consumer is
walking in and picking up a bad
product because the attacker
was in the grocery store.
Same thing can happen here.
There have been multiple
examples here of the open source
supply chain getting
compromised at this point in
the supply chain.
Here is an example here where an
account was compromised and this
allowed somebody to put a
backdoor into a specific
package, the rest client
that I talked about earlier.
This rest client,
incredibly popular.
The kind of cool thing about
this is that the developer, the
maintainer of the rest client
package basically lived up and
stepped up and said, hey, this
is my fault, here's the hacker
news thread where they're like,
hey, hey, everybody probably
knows right now that rest client
has been compromised, the reason
why, I was reusing credentials,
it's a project that I started
ten years ago before I had
password manager, and that
password was compromised through
some other site, and I reused
password and so that let
somebody get in and compromise
this rest client.
They were producing good
software, but at this point, the
attacker was able to get in and
compromise the package in the
Ruby-Gems package manager.
Here's another example.
This one, though, goes right to
the heart of the source code
distribution for Ubuntu's
Canonical's Ubuntu.
This isn't a problem just for
the guy that's maintaining
something in their spare time
and kind of not applying best
practices, but even major
companies that are very involved
with the open source ecosystem
have major impacts on it can
make these kinds of mistakes.
How do we help
everybody step up here?
The answer is to step up
and to get into multifactor
authentication.
Now all of the package managers,
the popular package managers
support multifactor
authentication.
All of the popular source code
repositories support multifactor
authentication.
This is something that we
absolutely have to start moving
towards mandatory
enforcement on.
It is just beyond the point
where we can just allow people
to introduce problems through
the supply chain because they
just feel that multifactor is
too onerous for them because
they're having an effect on this
massive downstream ecosystem at
this point.
Another example where
problems can show up is in
build tampering.
The artifacts get produced,
and at that point as the build
system is packaging things up
for release, the attackers
compromise the build servers or
the release management servers
and introduce these problems.
The Webmin case that I talked
about earlier was an example
of this.
The source code in the repo,
the master repo for Webmin and
GitHub was fine, but in
SourceForge, it wasn't, and this
allowed the attacker to get in
and put a script in because they
put a script into the build
server to inject the backdoor
into it.
This is an example of kind of in
the middle of the supply chain
the producer of the software is
doing the right things, but the
server was compromised.
The server could be compromised
even if they were following all
the best practices for
securing that server.
But how do you detect that
is kind of the question.
One of the tools that we've got
at our disposal for detecting
these kinds of problems is
something called reproducible
builds, and this is something
that Microsoft is involved with
pushing the industry towards.
Microsoft has been involved with
reproducible builds for its own
software for some time.
Windows is now reproducible,
or at least large parts of it.
What reproducible builds give
you is the ability to take some
source code, and if somebody can
rebuild it and know that given
the compiler, given the
artifacts that are pulled into
it, that when they do a build,
the artifacts are going to have
specific hashes, then they can
verify that if somebody says
here is a legitimate build,
here's the hashes for it, they
can verify that nothing has been
tampered with by rebuilding from
the source, that nothing got
into the middle of that supply
chain from build to
release management.
Linux itself is moving towards
the reproducible builds itself.
The problem with reproducible
builds is it's a very tough,
challenging technical problem.
The build has to be
entirely deterministic.
One of the challenges Microsoft
had in making reproducible
builds was getting time stamps
out of the Windows binaries that
were signed as part
of the signatures.
And so if you take a look at
the time stamps now in Windows
binaries, they're completely
garbage, and that's because they
needed to be made garbage.
Effectively, they're not time
stamps anymore because we needed
to get to reproducible builds.
And so that's just one example
of the efforts now the whole
ecosystem needs to take to get
to a place where we can have
reproducible builds across all
these different technologies.
Another way that here in the
supply chain problems can go
wrong is somebody yanking or
compromising the distribution
units, the package manager,
and this is a great example of
this one.
This package called left-pad,
that's a node package called
left-pad.
It's just about a dozen lines of
code for left-padding a string,
got incredibly popular.
It's been leveraged by basically
the whole web was dependent on
it at this point back in 2016.
The maintainer of that little
snippet of code was -- had
another package called kick and
there was a product called kick.
The lawyers for that product
said, hey, you're violating
our trademark.
The maintainer of
left-pad said I don't care.
So the lawyers went to node and
said, hey, pull this guy's kick
package off of node with a legal
order to do so in violation of
that trademark.
Node pulled that kick package.
When the maintainer found out
-- left-pad and kick found out
about that, they got upset and
they said, okay, fine, I'm
pulling everything that I've got
off of the node package manager,
and they were
maintaining at that point about
100 different packages.
They pulled them all off,
including left-pad, which ended
up breaking the world.
And so at this point, you can
see that Node took this very
unusual step to unpublish --
un-unpublish that package.
That's down there in
that tweet right there.
We took the unprecedented
step of un-unpublishing.
I think at this point
the maintainer wanted to
un-un-unpublish the package, but
they'd already lost control of
it and so they couldn't
do that, unfortunately.
But this restored people's
build systems now that were so
dependent on this left-pad
little snippet of code.
The lesson here is to
mirror your repositories.
This is an effort that we've
been taking internally at
Microsoft, and this is a very
tough one, to go find all the
places where people are pulling
directly from public repos into
their build systems versus
setting up mirrors and pulling
from the mirrors.
The fact is that mirrors have
a couple of different very
valuable properties.
One of them is availability.
If the upstream package repo
has a problem, it goes down for
availability reasons, or it goes
down because it gets cut off
from your build system for some
reason, you've got a place to
go to.
But the other kind of more
serious reason for security
purposes is if there is a
compromise of that upstream
system, you can
shield yourself from it.
You're one level of a direction
and so you can sever and stop
mirroring the
compromised vulnerability.
In the case of that package that
was pulled, you've got a copy of
it locally.
In the case of that package, the
Bootstrap-saas package that the
developer pulled the last known
good version, you have got a
copy of it, so you can continue
to build securely in the face of
a compromise somewhere
in the supply chain.
It is just a very good best
practice to mirror your repos.
Now this next topic, I think
it really gets to the heart of
addressing this problem because
we've talked about ways that
developers can go scan their
source code for vulnerabilities.
We've talked about the way that
package managers -- the way that
package managers should use
multifactor authentication and
the way that you should be using
mirrors if you're consuming open
source software to insulate
yourself from problems at that
point in the supply chain.
But one of the challenges we
talked about earlier in the
supply chain is really how do
I make sure when I'm consuming
things that it has followed best
practices, that the developers
have used MFA, that there was
vulnerability scanning that
was performed.
How do I check all that?
How do I ensure that it was
done with a reproducible build?
And what were the reproducible
build artifacts that were used
to build this?
All of these questions require
the supply chain together to
cooperate and having this
information flow downstream to
whoever eventually is
going to consume it.
The effort that has started in
this space is something called
software supply chain, software
bill of materials, which lets
you answer these
kinds of questions.
Where do things come from?
Who produced it?
Is there a strong identity?
Do I trust them?
That way I can say I
trust these publishers.
What is the product itself?
This is one of the challenges
in open source ecosystem.
If you've ever seen
vulnerability in package version
blah, what's the source
code that fit into package
version blah?
Maybe I consume that directly.
How do I know that
that's been fixed?
How do I know what other
dependencies that source has,
what other packages depend on
that vulnerable piece of source?
Those are all questions that
having some kind of tracing of
this source was used to build
these things would let you go
back up and answer those
kinds of questions.
Licensing is one of the
questions that enterprises have
around when they're consuming
open source software or when
they're modifying
open source software and then
redistributing it.
Is it MIT?
Is it PSD?
Is it -- what license is it?
Am I violating it?
Am I being conformant with it?
And then, like I mentioned,
how is the product created?
And then what materials were
used to build the product?
Software bill of materials which
tracks all this information as
it flows down the supply chain.
Let me give an example of how it
might defend against an advanced
persistent threat
sitting on a build server.
Developer commits some code,
the build system builds the
artifacts in the normal path,
the release management system
takes those artifacts, packages
them up, and then sticks them in
a package manager or it releases
it as part of a product.
In the malicious case, we have
got somebody that's tampering
with those artifacts
in the build system.
This is like the Webmin
case, for example.
The release management system
creates a malicious build from
that release and then everybody
downstream is compromised
by that.
If we had software bill of
materials in this flow,
developer commits the code, the
build system compiles the code,
it generates and signs the
software bill of materials and
publishes the build artifacts.
The attacker then tampers
with those build artifacts.
The release management creates
a malicious release from
that build.
It's malicious because some of
those have been compromised.
Now, downstream, the release
management system attempts to
verify that the malicious
artifacts was against that
signed SBOM and sees that
the artifacts don't match.
The ones that came from the
build system don't match the
ones that were published
by the release system.
At that point, it says, wait
a minute, something has been
compromised upstream, so I'm
not going to release this.
Another example is just making
sure that there are policy gates
in place.
The software that I'm consuming
had to go through specific code
verification, either static
vulnerability analysis or check
for credentials in the code.
How do I know when I'm
consuming the software that
that's the case?
And, again, with software bill
of materials in the mix here,
along the way, they make sure
that what's being consumed
downstream matches
those policies.
We won't release software
that doesn't adhere to
these policies.
I don't want to
trivialize this effort.
If you take a look at what's
required here, it requires
massive changes to
infrastructure everywhere to
support software
bill of materials.
But the fact is that we,
Microsoft, Google, others, have
all come to the conclusion that
this is absolutely necessary.
And so this massive
industry-wide effort at this
point to first step define a
software bill of materials and
then standardize it.
There are a couple of projects
already in existence for this
that could be suitable for this.
One is called SPDX, Software
Package Data Exchange, which has
declared a format.
It was originally targeted at
licensing, tracking licensing
through supply chain.
But they're now looking at
extending this to support the
requirements for software bill
of materials, including strong
signatures and identity and
policies that can go along
with it.
Another one is called in-toto.
In-toto was created specifically
to address or to target the
security side of the supply
chain with the software bill of
materials where they've got
different personas and those
different personas can apply
policies, can leverage the
in-toto tools through their
build systems or release systems
to augment the artifacts with
in-toto SBOMs, and those SBOMs
then can be verified against
policies using, again, the
in-toto tools.
The goal here with all these
companies looking at this is to
come up with let's come up with
a standard SBOM specification
and let's get that adopted as an
industry standard through this
or some other means, and then
let's have the whole ecosystem
start building tooling
and putting this in their
infrastructure so that we now
have this information flowing
for everybody.
I want to give you a quick demo
of in-toto so you kind of --
what it can do.
So I've got Visual
Studio code here.
I've got a package here
that you can see I'm using the
in-toto run.
I'm going to clone a GitHub repo
called demo project Jekyll.
I'm going to CD into it.
What happened right there, by
the way, when I did that clone,
in-toto, because it was
monitoring it, is keeping track
of every command along the way
and the artifacts that were
produced in that command,
including their hashes.
Detailed tracking.
I'm going to move that into this
folder called verification.
And the next step is I'm going
to run a linter on it right
here, an HTML linter.
This would be me doing a static
code verification on it.
Again, that is going to end up
creating this linker artifact,
linter artifact for that
command, the same kinds of
artifacts there that
we saw annotations.
I'm going to copy that here
into the verification folder.
And then the final step is to do
a docker build on this thing to
build it into a container.
And now I've got my docker build
and I have the one last there
in-toto artifact SBOM artifact
that I'm going to drop into the
verification folder if I
can reach it from here.
There we go.
And now at this point, I've
got all those artifacts there.
What I can do is run
this in-toto verify on the
whole project.
It looks like
I've made a mistake.
What should happen is that
this doesn't find any errors.
I have made some mistake
in the flow here.
But you get the idea.
Really, this is what this
should come back with is the
verification of the artifacts
against those hashes.
I can even have a policy file
that says I want these policies,
which are also signed as part of
those artifacts to be enforced,
and in-toto would ensure
that that's the case.
That's a quick look at in-toto.
Finally, let's talk about
responding to the threats.
Once there has been a compromise
someplace, and there will be
more compromises even
with all of this.
When it comes to food
compromise, everybody gets food
safety alerts.
The goal is to find the
original crop where the E.
coli came from and ban only
everything that came downstream
for that, not just all
lettuce in general, ideally.
Same thing happens here is we
need to understand both this
impact, the severity of the
vulnerability, as well as what
parts of the supply
chain are impacted by it.
This is part of tracking the
contaminants through the
supply chain.
Everything that I talked about
earlier up to this point feeds
into this, especially SBOM.
With SBOM, with the strong
naming, with the hashes, with
the source attribution, we can
-- ideally, in a world where
everything is flowing through
SBOMs, downstream, at your code,
you can check and look at all of
the BOMs that have come with the
things that you've pulled
dependencies on and go all the
way back upstream with
automated tooling back up to
the source files.
I asked that question
a little bit earlier.
When there is a vulnerability in
a package and that vulnerability
came from a piece of source
code, what other packages
depending on that source code,
that is something that SBOMs
ultimately can answer just
through automated walking back
through the chains of
dependencies in the information
in this metadata.
So just want to
emphasize how useful this is.
Now that's not to say that some
of the other things we have
already talked about that are in
place and you can take advantage
of today, like these automated
dependency tools, to say this
package I depend on, what
projects of mine are leveraging
it so that I can go make sure
that they're all patched and
using the latest version, are
useful in the -- today before we
get to this world of
software supply chain.
But at least for the projects
that you start up if you're
producing open source, recommend
that you already start looking
at getting SBOMs just
for your own hygiene.
That's software
bill of materials.
So brings me to one point I want
to make here, and that is the
way that we look at open source
security is this isn't something
that we want to differentiate
on when it comes to Azure.
Really, our goal is to
lift all boats in the whole
ecosystem here.
This is why we're working with
a bunch of other companies,
including some that I mentioned,
on this problem and why I'm here
to socialize this problem and to
tell you that there are growing
efforts across the industry that
you should be on the lookout for
chances to participate in.
The fact is that none of us are
competing on the security of
open source.
We all want to make it better.
Making it better keeps us --
our software more healthy, our
services more healthy, and keeps
our customers secure and healthy
as well.
Now just the concrete things you
should take away from this today
besides the fact, knowledge
and the fact that things are
happening and that you should be
looking out for ways that you
can participate more
deeply in these things, like
the SBOM effort.
If you're producing open source
software -- actually, if you're
doing anything with anything in
software or systems, enabled
multifactor authentication, run
static analysis tools, onboard
your project to
reproducible builds, understand
your dependencies.
And as a consumer, know what
you're consuming, automate the
mapping of your open source
project dependencies, learn more
about software
bill of materials.
And this is a very
critical one, I think.
If you've got a mission-critical
business where you need to be
able to build something at
a moment's notice or you're
building product and you need to
be able to update it regularly
and you're dependent on upstream
open source is mirror those
repos, mirror those
package repositories.
That's one of the big
takeaways from that.
That brings me to the
conclusion of the talk.
I hope you found
this informative.
I hope this opened your eyes if
you hadn't been aware of the
kind of issues here that we need
to go address together, this is
more real for you, and that
now you're walking away with
something concrete to help your
open source security posture and
even proprietary
security posture as well.
But looking for, again, big
takeaway is participation from
the whole ecosystem is required
to get us to a better place.
With that, I want to
thank you very much.
I hope you had a
great RSA conference.
I hope you stay
healthy yourself.
Thanks.