>> ANNOUNCER: Please
welcome storyteller, poet
and six-time TED
speaker, Rives.
>> RIVES: Good
morning, everybody.
Good morning to you all.
Welcome to day two.
Welcome to the session.
The theme of the
conference this year, of
course, is the
human element.
And as part of that
theme, we have got these
beautiful installations;
they're called
the human element.
There are three of them.
There's one upstairs,
there's one in the sandbox
area, and there's one
directly out those doors
and to the right.
And they're cool.
It's a big magnetic board.
It's a colorful cerebellum
shape made up of
these little nodes.
And as you get closer, you
see the nodes are buttons.
They're magnetic buttons.
You're encouraged to
take off one or two.
Put them on yourself.
Wear them like I've got
with troublemaker and
peacemaker and like
many of you have here.
And the buttons
have words on them.
They've got descriptors
and the descriptors cover
a whole range of
characteristics.
You've got MacGyver and
giver and nurturer.
Bad ass is very
popular, I'm told.
George Takei chose a
little green sensei pin
for his presentation
yesterday.
But if those words don't
exactly represent what you
are trying to represent,
there are the blank buttons.
Take a blank button.
You take a white gel pen
and you can fill in, draw,
design whatever you want
your button to look like
and that really
gets me going.
A lot of my work is
interactivity and self,
you know, kind of
realization, and words.
So, I thought I would like
to make a document of the
write-in candidates.
So, I loaded blank
buttons into a tablet.
I took a stylus and I
wandered around the RSAC
Conference grounds.
I met many, many of you
which is an easy thing to do.
You are friendly,
talkative people.
And I showed you how to
pick out a brush and I
showed you how to pick out
a style and you can write
or draw whatever you want
and I put them all together.
I told people this is not
a physical button, right,
so you don't have to
wear it, but it is you.
So, put something on there
that you want people to know
about you, something they
may not know from looking.
And I put together the results and they look like this.
Get a little
music for this.
First of all, there is a
very strong body image,
self-image vibe
going on here.
Someone wrote sexy.
Someone else wrote sexy.
We have a proud
chubby hubby.
We have an I'm an OK
Boomer in an intentionally
fuzzy font which
is a nice touch.
And then pretty
fly for a tech guy.
And this, this is -
maybe you all know this.
I did not.
This is the word "hot" in
binary, just H-O-T because
what is hotter
than binary?
Nothing.
Nothing is.
Leaning in.
Pronoun preferences.
We have a biker in the
house, a baker in the
house and then we have
a biker in the house.
We've got dad of nine.
I love that the dad did
not write the number nine,
did not write the word
nine, just nine strokes
for each loving child.
Kind of kind.
I love this.
Tired, to be honest.
Mot going to lie, this is
my Monday button going forward.
Work in progress.
Also kind of
humble, right?
Maybe someday we will get
the period onto the actual
button, maybe not,
doesn't matter.
Who cares?
You don't need to.
Think outside the button.
A lot of swagger
in the house.
Bitchin' speller,
for sure.
Also, this guy, this
is the button that
the person designed.
I am going to now - me,
I am going to digitally
mirror image this so you
can see that is no joke.
I can't do that
well forward.
Beat Stanford.
Apparently after
consultation, this is Cal
Berkeley blue and that
drawing is a bear and it
is the back - it is
showing you its bear side
is what that
is apparently.
This person wants you to
know that not only are
they a Leo but they have
lovely design sense.
I love this button.
This person might not be
who you think they are.
This person, I don't know
how they're going to wear
this, where
they're pointing.
But you know, represent.
Same thing.
If you think this might
be related, either this
person is a trained Navy
SEAL or they're enjoying
the conference in a breezier
way than some of us.
Or me anyway.
I don't know what
you guys are doing.
This is a 2020 exclusive.
This person got a positive
pregnancy result.
They said they are not
ready to share with anyone
but they are willing to
share it with everybody.
So, congratulations
to you.
Your colleagues will be
finding out very soon, yeah.
Heavy nerd vibe in the
room which I am 100% down
with my nerd
brothers and sisters.
We have Atari.
We have one button for the
resistance and one button
for Star Fleet Academy.
So, that would be a Star
Trek/Star Wars tie.
That tie is broken with
a lovely shoutout to our
helmsman Sulu.
Oh my.
Yoga fire.
Now to some of you, this
might be - yeah, this
person really gets into
their yoga practice, and
to some of us, maybe you,
it means what Dhalsim says
to you before he breathes
your face off in Street
Fighter 2?
Who is with me?
Street Fighter 2?
No?
Yeah, there you go.
And then there was a heavy
kind of RSA Conference tilt.
Ask me about my Kara
Swisher obsession.
This person came back
later and said I want to
make this a little
less threatening,
so they added this.
Blockchain for President.
Build a Firewall.
Hodor, a man who holds back zombies much like you do.
I see threat people.
And my favorite,
I'm with Alice.
I'm with Bob.
Thank you very much
everybody who contributed.
Enjoy your session.
If you are interested,
we are going to be doing
it again today.
Come up and talk to me.
The question today is what
do you want your 2025
button to look like?
Enjoy your session.
Thank you.