(upbeat music)
- The World Economic Forum's
Global Risks Report 2020
was recently released in Davos.
It included the global
risk perception survey
to measure which global risks are likely
to increase going forward.
Cyberattacks in the top five.
Now 76% of respondents believes cyber risk
will increase in 2020.
- We have attackers putting
malware into bespoke USB cables.
So you can buy these USB cables
where there's malware
actually, in the cable itself.
It behaves like a normal USB cable
so you could use it to sync your phone
to charge your phone
to charge your computer even.
You have to be tremendously careful.
If you find a USB cable in an airport,
it could be the cable itself attacks you
and think about this.
The persistence is in the wire.
You eradicate the
malware from your system.
The next time you go to charge your phone
or sync your phone,
it reinfects it.
- Our most critical
data lives in the cloud.
Cyber criminals and nation
states can siphon off that data
today and unlock it tomorrow,
when Quantum Cryptanalysis
becomes practical.
But we can't think of quantum
in terms of eventually
or tomorrow,
because quantum is a real risk today.
- As all of you have probably seen,
it is enough to take an image
and change a few pixels,
and then the neural
network is making all kinds
of very strange decisions.
I think that we are now
starting to understand
what is going on.
But until we will solve this problem,
I think that it will be very dangerous
to use deep neural networks
in autonomous vehicles,
for example, in making life
and death decisions in medicine, etc.
- I know this room needs no convincing
that there are virtually
no industries today
that are not vulnerable to cyberattacks.
And the auto industry is no exception.
I think you know, the auto
industry is fiercely competitive.
But cybersecurity is an
area in which we must,
and where we do act as a
united front to collaborate
and share best practices.
- Some of the the
challenges that we're having
or threats that we're
seeing in our environment,
on the IT side of the house,
it's probably what
everyone else is facing,
we get a lot of phishing emails.
You know, we have to try to
educate our team members on
how to protect themselves,
how to not click on the links,
but no matter how many times we tell them,
someone's still going to click,
someone's still gonna
enter their credentials.
So we're hoping that you know,
we have our basic cybersecurity
principles in place
that can help protect our assets
when people do click those links.
- Is easy to get the illusion
working in academic
industrial cryptography,
but there some playing fair
and intelligence is
not about playing fair,
it's about succeeding.
And there's no reason to
be sitting waiting for them
to make up cryptographic algorithms
that maybe you can break,
and maybe you can't.
If instead, you can push one
on them that you can't break.
- Security is about adversaries.
And we have to be cognizant of the fact
we need to design our systems,
to have procedures in place,
their people checking other people
their people checking machines.
- We have to change security
from an authoritarian control model
to a collaboration model.
Now, let me ask you,
do you think that we are
the ultimate authorities
on security?
Should we be making all
the security decisions?
No.
I'm going to put it to you that sometimes,
users can make better security
decisions than we can.
Security should be designed to be adopted,
rather than engineered to be enforced.
- The attackers aren't stupid.
None of them are.
But they fail anticipate
just how innovative,
how ambitious
and how aggressive the problem
solvers, the humans would be.
They underestimated the target
and they underestimated those teams.
They underestimated the creativity
and they underestimated the compassion.
And they fail to anticipate the one thing,
the actual human spirit.
If you take nothing else away
from what I'm saying today,
take it from me that in cybersecurity
investing in the human element
will always give the good guys an edge.
- Tech is being democratized.
And so it is time to democratize security.
(upbeat music)