>> ANNOUNCER: Please
welcome Chief Security
Officer, Akamai
Technologies, Andy Ellis.
>> ANDY ELLIS: Good
morning, folks, and
welcome back to another
lovely day here in
San Francisco.
First off, I'd like to
thank the RSA organizers
for providing closed
captioning for the keynotes.
As someone who suddenly
became hard of hearing
last year, I personally
really appreciate the
inclusivity being shown
and I hope this makes it
more accessible
for more people.
Every year, a group of
security vendors gets up
here on stage and regales
you with stories of the
new and novel threats that
we all face and tells you
about the new buzzwords
and technologies that are
going to solve
these new problems.
I thought I'd take a
different tack and instead
look at how we
got here today.
For those of you who
aren't as familiar with
Akamai, we're basically
the shopping mall
of the internet.
What do you buy from
a shopping mall?
It is a trick question.
Shoppers don't buy
anything from a shopping mall.
Stores do.
They buy access to the
infrastructure necessary
to bring their experience
closer to the edge where
their users are.
As the Chief Security
Officer, that basically
makes me the
internet's mall cop.
2020 is an opportune
time for us to use our
hindsight, and
conveniently for me, I've
always been at Akamai for
twenty years and gotten to
watch the evolution of the
internet from what I think
are the best seats
in the house.
And it strikes me that
the problems that we face
don't actually change that
much from decade to decade
as we rebrand the same
challenges, adopting new
technologies that expose
us to similar hazards that
we've already solved.
In our first decade,
Akamai was best known as a
content delivery network.
Some of our old
slides there.
That is an edge company
that made websites perform
better by caching and
delivering pages closer to
where the users are.
We had some performance
products and security
features and it was
those features that our
customers would sometimes
rely on to protect
themselves in the
early days of the web.
Why?
Because security embedded
into a business system has a
better chance of
success than security
tacked on separately.
Security comes in many
flavors and I personally
like the Information
Security Triad as a
reasonable model to
use to sort them.
One of the early security
controls that I helped
work on at Akamai was
object integrity.
Many image formats
used on the web have
a peculiar feature.
If you begin reading part
of one file and then start
reading the end of another
file, your browser will
render that as
one hybrid image.
That's a challenge for a
content delivery network,
especially if those
images were from
two different customers.
Even as rare as file
pointer errors are, when
you are delivering
millions of objects every
second, a one in a billion
error is going to happen
dozens of times a day.
So, we added a system to
embed water marks inside
each file so that we could
continuously check that we
were still reading the
same file that we'd started.
A few years later with the
dawn of the encrypted web,
a similar challenge arose.
How did we really know
that the origin website we
were talking to was the
one that we intended to?
Again, we needed to design
a working control system
to ensure that we could
validate the origin site
in the same way that we
had validated the object
we were reading before
connecting an end user to it.
We had to design and build
a site integrity system to
detect when network errors
might create this problem,
leading to content going
to the worst or wrong places.
And today we've seen the
rise of another integrity
challenge as more and more
websites are assembled
dynamically in the browser
from origins that are
controlled by a number
of different entities.
This HTML supply chain for
our banking, our news, and
our entertainment sites
exposes us because it
includes JavaScript
sourced from third party
libraries and
advertising networks.
How do we all make sure
that our browsers aren't
running code injected
by an adversary?
Sitting in the middle of
the user and app ecosystem
as I do lets me understand
and see how apps work, how
users engage with them,
combining that with the
threat intelligence from
attacks we've seen, and it
lets us identify this
new threat vector, form
jacking, of the sort
that the Magecart group
exploits on a
regular basis.
Today, the average
site is composed of 35%
third-party content.
Much of that content is
scripts, of which the most
common form is JavaScript.
The Magecart group has
been creating a new
reality by exploiting a
lack of security controls
in the browser, either
corrupting the supply
chain for the company
publishing the site or
corrupting the ecosystem
provider that publishes
content that then gets
included into the site.
The result is experienced
by businesses who have
seen massive GDPR fines,
not for directly leaking
user identity but for
failing to ensure page
integrity where the content ended up being exposed.
Web page integrity is the
next challenge to solve in
the integrity domain.
While we were building
these integrated integrity
features on the back end,
if you will, hazards on
the front end bring
different challenges.
Availability is often
overlooked as part of the
information security domain,
but nothing has presented a
greater threat to it than
DDoS and flash crowds.
The first DDoS
attacks we ever saw were
primarily self-inflicted.
A viral marketing campaign
for Victoria Secret or
BET, a Super Bowl ad that
the marketing and IT team
hadn't really planned for
its success might lead to
a flash crowd that would
take down a website.
Maybe a virus with an
attack payload like code
red when it targeted the
White House would lead to
a conversation about using
offload capabilities as a
security measure.
But there wasn't really a
full-fledged market for
DDoS attacks and defense
in the early 2000s.
But flash crowd management
made site availability a
real challenge for
all of us to address.
In those early days, I
recall an anti-virus
vendor whose anti-virus
updates created a problem
because downloads took
over an hour for each user.
And since updates would
download at the same time,
local time every day,
computers in the next time
zone would hit that
time, they would begin
downloading and their
servers would be crushed
all day long.
Basically, they had
implemented their own
predictable DDoS attack on
themselves unfortunately.
But the traffic only took
an hour because they
couldn't handle
that attack.
When they moved that
delivery out to the edge,
that flash crowd just
becomes hourly spikes.
But complex marketing
campaigns like when
Logitech wanted to
give away keyboards to
everybody in America, or
at least some subset of
them, but wanted
to ensure they were
well-distributed, would
drive edge computing needs
as lotteries would need to
run closer to the edge,
protecting infrastructure
from massive traffic spikes.
Site availability
requirements would drive
computational features
that users needed from
those lotteries to imagery
sizing and management, to
video archiving and
playback, and a whole host
of other capabilities
at the edge.
But that absence of a
primary market for DDoS
defense, that would change
with Operation Payback and
the rise of Anonymous.
DDoS had spent several
years mostly as
internecine warfare
amongst businesses who
operated in legal gray
areas like offshore
gambling and organizations
who might attack their
rivals on extortionists
who would try to shut down
smaller enterprises.
The first generations
of DDoS attacks really
focused on front end
resources like your ISP's
network capacity,
sometimes consuming them
with a lot of traffic,
sometimes targeting
carefully chosen
resources, like Slowloris
attempting to use the
fewest possible packets to
keep open all available
web server connections.
But the rise of Anonymous
coincided with the
democratization
of attack tools.
Low orbit ion canon, or
LOIC, was the most popular
for straight DDoS attacks,
but we started to see a shift.
More and more adversaries
were targeting the web
applications themselves,
either to gain access to a
server, potentially to
conduct a defacement, or
to attack a more
valuable resource.
As we learned how to
defend against each of
these, we realized that
we had shifted from site
availability to
application availability
and that required not just
capacity at the edge, but
bringing compute to bear
on that problem as we
implemented not only web
application firewalls and
application performance
management, but context
aware rate limiting to
bear on this challenge.
When we first entered that
last market, what we had
heard from everyone
and, frankly, believed
ourselves, was that rules
had to be tailored by hand
for every application
because web application
firewalls were finicky
devices and that
integrations were
therefore long and
expensive and
time consuming.
To all of those early
customers for WAFs, ours
or someone else's, I'd
like to apologize on
behalf of the industry.
We were wrong.
You see, many of the early
WAFs had started with
carefully tailored
rule sets.
But over time, as they had
grown through community
involvement, many of the
rule sets weren't tested
in a diversity
of environments.
So, this rule, intended to
catch Little Bobby Tables,
worked lovely unless of
course your user was
searching for that
drop-leaf table that you
were selling.
WAFs were too literal
without optimized rule
sets, optimizing
that rule set.
But more importantly,
shifting to a model where
multiple indicators
could be looked for
independently would take
the WAF market forward,
taking it from being a
hindrance to the industry,
with WAFs sometimes stuck
on a shelf, to being a
transparent and effective
security control that
everyone is
expected to use.
But adversaries have
continued to adapt and evolve.
And while we still see
DDoS attacks, just at
larger sizes, we're now
seeing attacks in excess
of one terabit per second.
The way in which one of
the most modern attacks is
conducted, credential
stuffing, mirrors those
earlier original
DDoS attacks.
An adversary has a
collection of usernames
and passwords and they
would like to test on your
site which ones will work.
Once they've succeeded at
account takeover, they can
then complete the next
stage of their attack
which frankly might just
be to sell that higher
quality data because like
ten years ago, tools were
being shared; now
the work is too.
The gig economy has come
to the DDoS and fraud
spaces, with professional
bot herders who will
assemble and operate a bot
network and rent it to
someone who will only
conduct their attack for a
few hours or maybe
a day or two.
Those attacks might just
be in service of selling
more information, that
breached personal data or
information about accounts
that work in a given space
or at a given site, with
the additional benefit of
separating information
across attackers, making
defense correlation
much harder.
We've even seen
adversaries starting to
use defender information
sharing platforms for
reconnaissance.
Each attack they'll send
unique attack signatures
to a site and wait to see
which ones pop up on those
information sharing
platforms, letting them
know which sites
are being monitored.
This new world of account
availability will continue
to evolve and present
major challenges as we all
seek to better engage
in bot management.
Of course, we can't have
discussed two legs of the
InfoSec Triad without
talking about the third,
confidentiality.
In the early days of the
web, no one really used
TLS or really, we should
call it SSL because that
was its name then, but
since it's changed its
name, we'll go with TLS.
We realized that
to support the
confidentiality needs
at the edge, we need to
design and build
for object and site
confidentiality, a
TLS CDN, if you will.
This entailed building a
distributed lights out key
management system and
growing trust in the idea
of conducting sensitive
transactions across the
internet which you might
all recall we had all
believed had already
reached its pinnacle of
achievement in the distribution of kitten pictures.
For many of the customers
of ours who had moved to
TLS in that first decade,
we had transformed from
merely an edge delivery
company into a performance
or edge compute company
with both offload and
security products and
that's when Aurora hit.
I got up here two years
ago to tell you about Aurora.
RSA hopefully has
that video online.
But a short takeaway is
that passwords suck and
the lateral
movement also sucks.
With other security
products starting to gain
traction for us, a breach
of this type couldn't be
allowed to repeat itself.
So, as we had in
redesigning our content
delivery network a
decade before, we began
transforming our
enterprise network.
That Zero Trust
transformation has taken
Akamai most of a decade,
much because we were
breaking new ground
alongside other companies
like Google with its
BeyondCorp initiative.
The challenge that we
all faced was enterprise
confidentiality and it
was this belief that
architectures were rooted
in a single, secure
enterprise land.
It probably never really
was all that secure, but
most importantly
originally it was disconnected.
And as our networks began
to be more and more
interconnected, the
hazards to enterprise
confidentiality outpaced
our architectures.
I'll be honest; our first
attempt at redesign was
ineffective.
I tried to lead us down
the then best practice of
network micro
segmentation, but in a
modern enterprise, that
presents an administration
and logistical nightmare
for implementation.
The obvious place to start
is by isolating your
servers from
lateral movement.
But so many servers today
are parts of an integrated
ecosystem, from back up
servers to configuration
management to
vulnerability scanning,
time is short.
If you'd like the whole
list, go walk the show floor.
The real problem wasn't in
which computers could talk
to which computers,
but really in which
applications could talk
to which applications.
And rather than trying to
isolate piece by piece
could we instead isolate
the most unpredictable
part of the
enterprise, the users?
Now, this isn't a blame
the users tirade.
Users are unpredictable
because they provide
business values in ways we
can't predict in advance.
And they'll do things
we couldn't anticipate.
And, at the same time, we
provide them with tools
that are fundamentally
dangerous to them.
The two biggest hazards in
the enterprise are the web
browser and the email
client, both of which are
basically designed to let
you or the adversary hide
important safety
information from a user.
And it doesn't help that
we demand our users click
on sketchy looking links
to get paid or to engage
in HR training right
before we then tell them
to stop clicking on
sketchy looking links.
So, we wondered if we
could ensure enterprise
confidentiality by
isolating our users, not
from the internet but from
the enterprise itself.
We redesigned our
enterprise connectivity to
put our entire edge
network between our users
and our corporate systems,
giving users a predictable
and consistent interface,
security controls enforced
at the edge, cryptographic
protocol selection,
authentication styles,
as well as application
security controls for our
internal applications.
Along the way on that
redesign, which paralleled
some of those early Zero
Trust initiatives, we
relearned an important
truth about good design.
That this arrow, trading
off performance against
security, is wrong.
In a well-designed system
you can end up with both.
Which brings us to
the next challenge in
confidentiality, identity
confidentiality.
As regulations like
GDPR and CCPA indicate,
protecting identities, not
merely from breaches but
also from internal and
corporate misuse, is an
area that companies
with far flung user bases
need to address.
James Pavur presented at
Black Hat this past summer
about how GDPR compliance
activities can create
a new risk.
By sending demand letters
on behalf of his fiancée
with her knowledge but
without any form of
explicit transmittable
consent to 150 companies,
he was able to extract her
personal information from
dozens of them.
Complying with these
regulations while keeping
this data safe is going
to be a new hazard in
confidentiality for
businesses to address.
While I haven't even
touched on many of the
other environmental
challenges that will take
existing hazards and give
us new challenges, like
IoT with its challenge
of unpatchable embedded
systems, or 5G which might
someday give us ubiquitous
internet to connect all of
those IoT systems with,
let's all recognize
that addressing those
challenges will, at least,
keep folks in our industry
gainfully employed for
the foreseeable future.
So, I'd like to thank you
all for coming out this
morning and may you all
have safe travels back to
your homes or onwards to
your next destination.
Thank you.