(soft music)
- You know, if you look
at an RSA conference 2020,
we've really tried to focus in
around this idea of the human element.
And you've seen it everywhere,
you see the posters,
you've seen it as a theme,
and a lot of the talks,
- With the human element,
- The human element.
- Investing in the human element,
- And it's one of the greatest
unsolved mysteries I would say
of the security space and
a bunch of different ways.
One is, we need humanity,
we need diversity of thought
and views and perspectives
to be able to deal with
this security problem.
That's one, and we've
had a lot of sessions
and workshops focused on that.
We also, need to understand
that our users are very diverse,
and have certain ways of thinking.
And, we need to know how
they're gonna assess risk,
and look at a problem.
But we also need to understand
what our limitations are as people.
- We need to collaborate,
not just within security teams,
but with business risk IT and users.
Let's change our culture
to a culture of perfection,
to a culture of pragmatism.
Don't let perfect be
the enemy of the good.
- What I want us to think
about is what do we not do
that involves our phones?
The addiction to mobile
is what makes them so vulnerable.
Think about this,
if you get into my phone,
you are getting so much more information,
than probably if you got into my Mac,
because I live on my mobile device.
- We look at the fact that
when a user makes a mistake,
it's the user, that's the issue.
The problem is not that
users make mistakes,
but that we put users
in a position where
they can initiate loss.
They don't cause the loss,
they initiate a chain of events,
and that's a really
critical issue to deal with.
- It would be super convenient.
If you could just buy
a piece of technology
that would do everything for you.
Unfortunately, security scanners,
and firewalls can't solve everything.
Their effectiveness is directly related
to the skills and the manual effort
of the people who must tune
them to a specific environment,
monitor them regularly,
and filter the signal from the noise.
- What needs to happen
is for every technologist
inventing something really cool,
like differential privacy,
or quantum computing or whatever it is.
We probably need something like 10 people
whose role it is to
explain it to the public,
and to policy makers.
And more importantly figure out,
how our public institutions need to change
to best adapts to these technologies
and minimize the harmful effects.
You know, not lobbyists,
we need neutral people to be doing that,
that's something that I
think we're lacking today,
and something which I
hope we can figure out
in the next 20 years or so.
- Humans will remain at
the center of our story.
In this world the defenders
will be better organized
than the attackers,
and the spirit of the
defender will be strong.
- So I guess it all comes
down to the human element.
(audience clapping)
(soft music)