um Craig Craig laba which is up next if
he's around I'm seeing them otherwise
okay Craig Gaza I think if i remember
correctly Craig was nanite program chair
back in the day one of a long line of
distinguished program chairs for merit
or wherever in those days and I'm
pleased to introduce Craig as serve our
first speaker this morning okay you guys
left me some extra time yeah please
awareness
she's talking
so she's telling me I'm leaving with us
I don't know what kind of mix is this
control oh thank you thank you very much
that's helpful okay great is the mic
working okay well thank you my name is
Craig labovitz I also worked with
Farnham and parents I'd have worked with
most of them the folks on the podium
here at one point or another today I'll
be speaking about really what was a two
year effort very large effort and a very
large collaborative effort between
University of Michigan Merit network and
arbor networks and was going to say that
I didn't quite have enough time to make
it through the entire deck so I was
going to aim for a sort of a speed in
between a Kim claffey and appalled vixy
but I think varname very politely left
me enough time to perhaps make it
through the deck so begin talking about
the Atlas internet Observatory in the
two year effort really over the last two
years we've made it to work with
commercial vendor who has now put and
deployed and maybe seventy eighty
percent of large Tier one tier two
regional and many of the content
providers around the world we've been
able to leverage this infrastructure and
do something that I think is quite
extraordinary we've been able to somehow
convince a hundred and ten I'll be ideas
large content is PS literally around the
world to do something that I previously
wouldn't thought they'd be willing to do
which is shared data quickly secured
some security data and east
coarse-grained traffic engineering data
so today Atlas represents what I will
unabashedly you know claim is perhaps
the largest Internet traffic monitoring
infrastructure in the world we're
monitoring the val de pika give or take
14 / bits per second I think in an
upcoming tech report we make a claim
that's approaching 300 exabytes of data
offered load through the last two years
and again it's real-time traffic
engineering and security information and
I'll stress on this slide
many of the slides that all the data is
anonymous and the participation is
voluntary so it's a subset of the
commercial deployments that he have
agreed to read legal language and enable
the anonymous staffs on the checkbox
also just before I get into the meat of
the report I should just just be
anything Frank that I think most of the
results we have are not things that
haven't appeared in the press before or
haven't appeared at nanog or in other
research papers there's been lots of
discussion the past about how big is
Google was YouTube a good acquisition a
bad acquisition is google making money
losing money there's really no shortage
of articles folks estimating the size of
the internet i just read recently about
the great exif like that since it income
last year it's going to come in a year
now much like the biblical end of end of
the world approaching but there's been a
lot of I think press written about
aspects of this and some of it quite
good I think when the key challenges
though is it's quite hard getting
quantitative data about these trends
whereas most of the previous analysis is
based on secondary indicators like
routing table growth bgp market finding
data and so forth so i think that this
really represents one the first
large-scale quantitative studies on
internet evolution over the last two
years using quite a bit of data
something's turned on
okay is this better should I repeat
everything I said
okay actually I'm getting feedback so
perhaps I'll just give up on this so as
I mentioned that there's been quite a
bit of related work certainly build
Norton's rate about the evolution of
video we have akamai's doing regular
reports now Andrew at mints has written
quite a bit about doing size estimates
of the internet based on exchange point
data so this list by no means is
exhaustive but certainly there's quite a
bit of effort out there again some of it
quite good with that I'll segue into a
brief discussion about methodology so as
I mentioned we're leveraging commercial
infrastructure deployed around the
internet around the globe have to pose
for rolling over here commercial
infrastructure that's fairly widespread
typically the infrastructure about
ninety percent ninety-five percent is
getting data from routers sample data
based on flow esflow J flow whatever the
name de jure is about five percent or
less probably is port spin or in-line
deployments getting data typically these
deployments are round appearing or
transit edge of the network and for
these 110 providers really monitoring
most of the peering or transit bandwidth
other deployments are customer edge
other aggregation edge but by and large
really the transit edge of the networks
every hour or half an hour depending on
the deployment these deployments will
send up an anonymized xml file up to a
central server we don't track from where
the files came from and there is no
customer or otherwise isp identifying
information in the XML and as I said the
wired likes to compare this to the NSA
and I really wish they'd stop doing that
this really is nothing of the sort this
is just a s level very coarse-grained
data there's really not any fine grained
visibility there is no fine grain of his
ability at all in the data so it's a
high level of the observatory and just
again before I get into the meat of the
report just want to spend a minute about
what we're measure
and perhaps more importantly what we're
not measuring so the observatory data
really I believe provides fairly good
insight into the relative traffic
between ISPs inter-domain data we are
monitoring 110 a esas give or take out
of whatever the number is today 35,000
37,000 with that said the 110 were
monitoring we believe represent as
perhaps Randy bush would call it the
clue core which is the larger Tijuana's
tier tues larger content providers and
again the distribution of asn intends to
be really heavy tailed in terms of
traffic distribution where it really is
the first three or four hundred by far
dominate the traffic and then you've got
a trailing very long trailing edge of
thousands and thousands of multihomed
enterprises based on tell geography and
Forrester data we believe our
distribution roughly approximates what
we'd expect from the commercial data or
analysts data and our focus throughout
the report really isn't on absolute
traffic volumes but if the most part
through all the slides we're really
looking at percentage our estimated
percentage of all internet traffic and
that's really for a number of reasons
including the fact that the data is a
little bit noisy as people add routers
lose routers join the nonnamous
deployments leave and do all sorts of
things that I don't think I could ever
explain so it is a very noisy data set
with that said inter-domain traffic I
think volume and ratios do provide a
very important perspective on one of the
key metrics of internet Engineering
again peering ratio estimates of traffic
I really how we design the network in
fact are behind many of the commercial
and negotiation strategies with that
said I will stress what we are not
measuring the system is not measuring
web hits tweets commercial transactions
customers or anything of that fine grain
detail it by definition is monitoring
inter-domain traffic so it does not have
visibility into VPN VoIP services video
services and so on and perhaps was
critically of all traffic is an
important metric and percentage of all
all internet traffic is an important
metric but it is only indirectly or
vaguely related to anything like ISP
success or profitability so please keep
that in mind as we go through the deck
so jump into the major findings as i
said i think that there's been a lot of
texts written by analysts and even other
academics about these changes i think i
was struck by really how quickly these
changes are occurring and really how
dramatic some the shifts have been even
over the last two years it used to be
the case I think at least in the popular
imagination at least I youth my mother
as an estimate of the popular
imagination that the internet was is
very democratic nebulous cloud and she
believes that when she's connecting to
sins were in Detroit a car company
website that she's really going to a
server in a ford building across the
street that the internet really is
distributed and content is really
distributed across hundreds of thousands
of data centers and websites of course
what my mother doesn't realize is that
likely she's going and this is few
Patrick she's likely going to akamai or
she's going to limelight or jus really
going to Rack Center a rackspace data
center and so forth but we'll show
coming up in a few slides a really
dramatic change in the distribution of
traffic across origin asns of last two
years really the traffic migrating out
of the edge out of the enterprises into
large carriers as well as consolidation
amongst the googles and Microsoft's of
the world perhaps the most compelling
result in the slide deck I'll come to
and I think three or four slides is that
in 2007 it really was the case that
thousands of ASNs contributed you know
really you had to get to basically
several thousand ASNs to reach 50
percent on average of internet traffic
as of July 2009 you only need a hundred
and fifty origin asns to generate fifty
percent on average all internet traffic
so very dramatic shift not only has
where the traffic been coming from
shifting and consolidating but also the
applications have been changing as well
basically over time Warren
our traffic is migrating to the web and
we're seeing declines basically in all
other well-known ports and application
groups you know the one way I think of
this is that the great vision the great
battle for the end-to-end network has
been fought and it's been lost as IPS is
IDS's firewalls even microsoft recently
converted xbox which used to use all of
its own protocols and ports just to port
80 presumably to simplify some the
headaches of customer management and
configuration so increasingly we're
seeing a shift to port 80 and
increasingly I think the data belies the
shift others have written about about
the web increasingly being the front end
for mail and all other applications
finally I think the most interesting
point at least from my perspective is
that what really is fascinating about
the changes is the degree of economic
change and logical topology change that
we're seeing for the first time I think
we've crossed the threshold where the
majority of traffic now flows directly
between consumer and content networks
over time the average BGP path has been
dropping from four hops maybe seven
years ago to three and a half hops 2 3
hops and we're seeing even more dramatic
shift when you look at traffic as
opposed to a s path distance along with
a shift we're seeing most isp's shift
from focus on connectivity to focus on
content and higher value services it
should mention to as we did this report
we spent a lot of time talking with
maybe 30 40 different providers walking
through the data trying to gain insight
into the trends and although most of
this was under NDA most of them did
describe very significant economic
innovation particularly particularly
experimentation with things like patron
pay transit new models of hybrid with
patrons and sulman free and things like
paid content which I'll talk about
shortly so segue into a discussion of
the Internet core so I used to teach
classes about internet and Internet
routing and this is comes from a
textbook
and for the most part you know the nice
higher hierarchical model that we got
out of the end of the NSFNET and large
tier ones at the core with all traffic
and generally most money's flowing up
from the consumer networks enterprise
networks to regional than to from local
into regional and into a poor the most
part I think that this you know rough
logical model held true modulo the name
changes I think perhaps only sprint is
still has kept the name though I do
still have an Aegis coffee mug on my
desk at work and you know when we
actually look at the data again looking
at all asn traffic from their
perspective of the 110 ISPs giving us
anonymous traffic data I'll stress again
in the gray box that the data here we
have is no relationship to Observatory
participants the analysis here is based
on the view of these ISPs from all the
other ISPs around the world but roughly
in 2007 July the top 10 ISPs in the
world roughly correspond to what you'd
expect from tier ones and by the way
rather than get into a long discussion
about what is a tier 1 what is not if
you're one I'll say whatever wikipedia
says must be is truth so this just
responded i think the page patrick
helped edit on the list of tier once and
again this is a weighted average percent
of all traffic with level three global
crossing the top in the other tier ones
but then what was true for maybe 10 12
years of the internet the world has been
changing it's been changing for a long
time but the changes have really
accelerated over the last 23 years
certainly everyone in the room has been
familiar with many of these bullet
points the price of IP hole and the
price of IP wholesale transit has been
dropping and dropping quickly over time
while the same time advertisement
supported content and revenue has been
climbing dramatically more recently
we've seen the entrance like Panther and
others really depressed the price of
cdns where the price are the cost for an
is to host their content in a CDN has
dropped dramatically over the last 23
years and we continue to see a real
scarcity I believe in some of the more
modern data centers particularly as
heating exuma cooling not heating is the
opposite problem as cooling and power
virtualization have changed the
footprints and really made older data
centers much more difficult to operate
efficiently as well as raising the bar
in the market entry to build new
internet scale IDC's so these two slides
actually aren't my data one of them is
actually from bill norton and dr.
peering i can't really read the true
even I can't read what the graph is
showing in the topic suffice it to say
this is the price of IP wholesale
transit and it's dropping it's not at
zero but if you wait long enough he'll
get pretty close overtime is the general
trend the bottom graph is showing the
price again this should mention both of
these data sets you can find in cal
geography and analysts wall street
journal is at similar graphs I don't
think there's I think this is
interesting data but I think it's fairly
well documented as well the bottom graph
is showing really the inverse that as IP
wholesale transit has dropped you've
seen a very dramatic growth in the
amount of money being spent on
advertisement supported content and
these really are two of the really key
macro level economic trends that really
have been reshaped the way ISPs think
about the internet the way they
negotiate and really the underlying
topology in the economic system so very
large forces at work which quite
literally are reshaping the internet
over time they'll explain what I mean by
that so those forces all bring us to the
Atlas 10 today in July of 2009 the left
hand or it gets the left hand chart is
the data showed previously and on the
right hand side is the data from July of
2009 I should mention that I think in
the tech report will the full list of
the top 10 or 20 I think we're still
want to focus on I think the results and
we want to be careful with I think just
on the commercial sensitivity of the
data and showing
you know declines or other changes in
isp traffic but on the right-hand side
you'll notice that level 3 in global
crossing particularly given some of the
very large content that they're hosting
and some of the sites behind them have
grown in the percentage of internet
traffic and what I find really the most
interesting is here you have two
companies that really weren't anywhere
close to the top 10 in 2007 I mean we're
an even the top 20 in 2007 are now in
the top 10 and these are companies that
aren't typically you know are in fact
not on the Wikipedia page for tier 1 at
least they're not there today and their
companies that typically are not in the
business of providing at least weren't
in the business of providing transit so
you know Google at roughly five percent
in climbing perhaps when the fastest
growing origin is groups or AAS groups
on the internet and Comcast making the
top 10 as well I should mention again
that this is based on weighted average
percentage of all internet traffic of
all the hundred ten ISPs exchanging
traffic with Google and calm gas and
level 3 and so on has no direct
relationship between Observatory
participation and let me stress again
that I think we've been often misquoted
or received that tier ones are still
very very large dear ones are still
profitable like some of them in fear
ones are still carrying significant
volumes of traffic the point we're
making is more about the change in
trends and trajectory of the internet
than saying that alter ones have all
traffic is evaporated because that's
clearly not the case in fact some of the
cheer ones many of them are in fact
still growing their business this I
think is perhaps the most interesting
slide in the deck so if you've not been
paying attention for the first however
long it's been 10 15 minutes this is
perhaps the one slide that is
interesting I should apologize to that
this is a cumulative distribution graph
and even amongst academics there's a
running joke about kima living
distribution graphs because most
academics don't actually know how to
interpret them I mean present company
here you're welcome Farnham but i'll
tell you what i think the graph is
showing we really have two lines
plotting the distribution the percentage
of all traffic the vertical axis is a
cumulative percentage and the x-axis is
really the number of a SNS so in 2007 or
the red line basically to get to the I
don't have a laser pointer but to get to
the fifty percent mark it was really
really heavy tailed in fact it was so
heavy tailed we cut off the graph
because it really goes off and off way
off into the distance you really had to
get into the thousands of ASNs across
the fifty percent mark the blue graph is
showing July of 2009 in July of 2009 you
don't have to get to thousands you need
to get to 150 to get to fifty percent or
more of internet traffic and this really
is a very dramatic very abrupt change in
a two year period I don't have time to
get into it right now but you know this
more or less maybe what you expect it
may not be what you expect it may
approximate a power-law I don't have the
time or nor the inclination again to a
Hera law discussion and then but you
know is very an exponential is a very
abrupt kerala distribution and perhaps
also was in 2007 but clearly the knee of
the curve has changed so i'll pause on
the slide and just let everyone get a
get a look at it since this again i
think is one of the most dramatic
changes we've seen and really belies
some of the economic and some of the
logical changes that are occurring as
well you know one of the key components
that's really driving the change we call
them hyper Giants in the tech report
coming out soon really because black
hole had a negative connotation so the
next biggest was hyper Giants but hyper
Giants are really the 150 the couple
hundred large ASNs at the far left-hand
of the curve one the key components of
the hyper Giants really are the CDNs and
it's been very significant growth in
both the number of cdns as well as a
traffic volume of the CDN s 0 in this
graph for graphing over time the top
five share play CDNs
by grouped origin asn and again this is
weighted average percentage I should
mention that saying pure-play CDN is
perhaps increasingly misnomer as all
CDNs basically now offer transit and I
you know other typical carrier services
and then you've got most tier one ISPs
and even many tier two are offering CDN
so the distinction between all of this
is increasingly blurred and i'll leave
it to far more educated analysts to draw
these market segments boxes than all
ever attempt but i should mention too
just so Patrick doesn't send me more
email that we're only really graphing
the interdomain traffic due to akamai
hear that Akamai's many of you know of
course typically as boxes deployed
within the provider IP space but really
just seeing the data that's going to
update the caches and not all back my
traffic in fact we would guess that
Akamai traffic overall is probably a
third or quarter we're only seeing a
third or a quarter of the Akamai traffic
but over time cdns as a group we'd
estimate are approaching about ten
percent or thereabouts-- of all internet
traffic is coming from a CDN and again
when my mother thinks she's going to the
forward web page she's most likely not
and it's most likely again coming from
one or more of the the CD ends so fairly
significant changes in the distribution
of traffic across or geneious ends
fairly large growth overall in CDNs and
I don't have the slides in this deck but
there's been fairly significant changes
in the sort of a s level distance or the
distance traffic is going as it goes
from content and consumer or of course
it's getting pretty close to 0 through
direct peering I think the question is
what's happening what's really driving
all these changes so clearly
commoditization has been coming has been
occurring and accelerating for quite
some time much like other industries at
the turn of the century and oil or other
commodities the price of IP wholesale
has been dropping price of CDN and video
delivery in particular has been dropping
and we're seeing a lot of enterprises
just it no longer makes economic sense
for enterprise
to post their own content so we're
seeing all that content migrate very
quickly into the cloud we're also of
course seen consolidation it used to be
that YouTube photobucket I could
probably go on for you know tens of
minutes all of these smaller companies
were once smaller companies many of them
have their own ASNs in their own traffic
in their own infrastructure today they
do not the big get bigger as Microsoft
and Yahoo and google vie for market
share and dominance of really the portal
in the interface to the new internet
we've also seen I think real success
both from the tier ones folks offering
business enterprise services in bundling
services and delivering things that may
have been purchased from other carriers
or other suppliers and past these are
MSSP and video and backup and other
delivery services and we're seeing folks
like Comcast and others see great
success with the triple play now the
quad play and even told this a quintuple
play coming but also belonging all these
changes are also new economic models and
this perhaps is the hardest to quantify
since a lot of this takes place under
NDA but there's a lot of experimentation
with paid content such as ESPN 360 or
the sky and the UK we're seeing a lot of
folks experiment with paid transit and
more I think most broadly what really
are seeing is in economic terms
disintermediation we're in the economic
sense of the world word this really
means removal of intermediaries from the
supply chain as both folks like Google
and Akamai and others are looking both
at cost but increasingly it's not about
cost it's actually about performance as
the CD ends and the hosters and others
have s la-based metrics and very
interested on the getting best
performance from the content to the
consumer so this brings us at least to
my diagram of what if I don't show what
the new internet looks like increasingly
the data shows a new internet really
looks like a much more densely
interconnected cloud of large consumer
and content all direct peering whether
it be settlement free or paid transit or
other
things under NDA the cheer ones are
still large they still are a critical
piece of the infrastructure they're not
going away they're very large amounts of
traffic but there is now a very new
significant component of directly
connected content and consumer and I
think that you know there really is no
local provider anymore the locals have
all been absorbed in the regional so we
have much flatter internet as well just
a quick case study of a case study on
Google and a case study on Comcast this
is looking at Google's percentage
weighted percentage of internet traffic
again from the from the perspective of a
hundred and ten ISPs who exchanged
traffic with Google we also plotted
YouTube's ASNs in the red mainly to give
a sense of how much how much of Google's
growth may be due to the YouTube in
folding youtube traffic into the Google
asn in Google infrastructure so you can
see Google is absorbed YouTube overtime
in Google represents really one of the
fastest growing collection of a SN in
the internet today I think when I
recently looked at it topped six percent
and was still climbing Liana you know
you can say what you want about was
YouTube a good idea or bad idea but this
is I think a fairly dramatic change to
make an acquisition alpi it for several
billion but to gain six or seven percent
of internet market share at least by
traffic volume is a pretty dramatic
shift from less than one percent two
years earlier next since we talked about
Google earlier google made the i think
was number six on the slide before and
google i think caught our interest as
trying to understand how did google go
from you know 30th 40th you know wasn't
anywhere near the top 10 earlier well in
2007 google looked like a typical msl it
looked like a typical MSO from there
peering ratios it looked like a typical
MSO and that they had more of a
fragmented backbone than a single
backbone and they basically were
dependent on a number of transit up
streams they did very little external or
relative comparatively little external
appearing with other providers my 2009
comcast is different
Comcast of course entrance the top six
of in terms of traffic volume with all I
spes on the planet there traffic ratios
shifted from an eyeball network to a
content looking much more like a content
or a transit network and I'll show a
slide of that coming up and as we've
talked to a providers you know around
the net about what's happening we've
talked to analysts it really seems to be
the case that Comcast successfully
execute on the triple play they entered
completely different business models
like cellular backhaul wholesale IP
voice transit Metro Ethernet so very
different provider and I think an
interesting example of some of the
transformations internet providers and
even mso's are undergoing as the
internet evolves and just quickly this
is a graph of the peering ratio of
Comcast basically the left-hand side the
vertical axis is a curing ratio how much
is content versus how much how much as
an versus how much is out the x axis is
time and you see that over time Comcast
shifted from basically a 65 70 percent
eyeball network to where's today they
are most decidedly what I put in the
content can't do it again some of the
changes in the business model and as I
mentioned you know I find increasingly a
bit of a misnomer to distinguish now
between content networks and sumer
networks CDN ISPs we really are seeing
consolidation not just in the topology
but also in the business models although
of course it varies from provider to
provider as well so go to shift gears
were the last few minutes I have and now
talk about some of the changing
applications so this is hard to read or
it might be hard to read but hopefully
you all have access to the pdfs this is
as of july two thousand seven in july
two thousand nine and nine weighted
average percent of traffic due to
different broadly defined application
groups or classes i should mention that
most of this data is based on well-known
port analysis we do have data from five
or six payload based deployments which
in the tech report we augment some of
our analysis and discussion with
so for example peer-to-peer here is
listed at you know in july two thousand
nine point eight five percent but based
on payload analysis we believe that most
appeared appear is obfuscated a-- dan
door encrypted and probably the numbers
globally are much closer to eighteen to
twenty percent certainly very little
peer-to-peer traffic actually is using
the well-known ports we have similar
issue with video for example and of
course there's an awful lot of video
within port 80 progressive HTTP download
namely youtube and so forth so i think
broadly the conclusions would come from
looking at both the well-known ports and
the payload data is that web by far is
the engine of growth in the internet
picking up ten percent and by the way
this is change in overall internet
traffic not change in HTTP followed by
HTTP so really is web and video are the
growth engines peer-to-peer is declining
and basically everything else is
declining as more and more traffic
migrates either to flash or relate to
port 80 and i don't think i included the
deck of port 80 but again I think that's
largely we were seeing just again the
end of sort of the end-to-end argument
as more and more and more application
network designers migrate traffic report
eighty to evade firewall headaches and I
guess and NAT and so on I'll spend a
moment talking about peer-to-peer this
is mainly because wired and other people
as they describe it here to peer back in
two thousand two thousand seven was the
boogeyman of the internet we had a you
know for lack of better word alarmist
articles in the popular press about the
end of the internet was near the traffic
the exa flood was coming peer-to-peer
growth was sixty seventy percent all
networks were bending down FCC you know
there's no neutrality discussions
there's just incredible amount to press
all around peer-to-peer so it's perhaps
interesting that when you look at
well-known ports as well as payload
based analysis of peer-to-peer that by
2009 the great evil boogeyman of the
internet is retreating and retreating
quickly again this is market share so
absolute volumes of peer-to-peer may not
have dropped it significantly but as a
percentage of
traffic peer-to-peer is not growing as
quickly as other traffic forms so it's
losing market share in fact we believe
there's an absolute decline as well so
this is the most popular well-known
ports but the analysis is the same if
you look at Korean ports if you look at
Chinese peer-to-peer if you look at all
of the sorts of data sets and I should
mention that you know the trend varies
by region Asia actually has been much
slower to decline in peer-to-peer than
other parts of the world so peer-to-peer
there are still significant volumes
appear to peer peer to peer is not gone
away it's still in some some networks
it's still thirty forty percent of all
traffic but broadly we think it's closer
eighteen to twenty percent globally on
average today and the growth has slowed
so that's declining in terms of internet
market share from all other applications
I think when we look at the data we
talked to providers we talked to
analysts we really come to three
conclusions about why the shift is
happening number one there's clearly
some evidence of provider traffic
management again providers in different
parts of Europe and perhaps a few in
North America actually doing different
sorts of traffic engineering but I don't
think that's really the significant
story and neither his next one which is
there have been significant improvements
in peer-to-peer it used to be the case
when we look at peer-to-peer clients
again it would as happily go to Asia to
get a seed as a wood to the you know
other boxes on the cable hidden so it's
been very significant improvement
performance-based apology based
peer-to-peer but really I think when we
look at the data it's just quite simply
that puter peers a pain to watch the
latest movie you have to wait six seven
hours and you're not sure what you're
going to get is it that shaky camera and
the video theater with a guy standing up
in front of you and coughing all
throughout the movie or is a true HD
movie you know mainly peer-to-peer has
been eclipsed by streaming CDN and
direct download and it should mention
that by streaming in CDN really it's a
success on the commercial legitimate
sources like I player and iTunes and
Hulu and so forth as well as direct
downloads which have varying degrees of
I think focus on intellectual property
issues this is just one example and I
like this graph because this very
clearly allows us to distinguish the
contribution of direct download this
graph is part of a quiz can anyone guess
when megavideo became a customer of
Carpathia Hosting I can't Homs all I'm
running out of time so I'll jump to the
answer it clearly was that dramatic
spike November of early two thousand
eight and you can see the very dramatic
spike in the contribution really over
overnight Carpathia went from you know
very small I mean in terms of traffic
volume to now approaching five point
five point six percent of all internet
traffic so I'll try to finish with just
a few minutes left for questions again
there is a tech report coming out which
is 30 or by the time we're done you know
maybe even longer pages hopefully will
be out shortly providing much more
detail about all of this but broadly the
Internet's at an inflection point for
the first 10 12 15 years of my career
with the internet certainly the focus
was all about connectivity speeds and
feeds today we're really seeing the
economic discussions the academic
discussions technical discussions really
shift to content and along with us the
old really you know the last 15 years we
basically had only handful of economic
models of care metered based internet
we're seeing a lot of economic
innovation as the business model
literally of the internet evolves in
racine new entrants shape what we mean
by internet and isp and CDN we're of
course also seeing I think significant
new technologies which like whether it
be netbooks or cloud and I have no idea
what cloud means anymore by the way but
we're seeing wealth cloud the migration
of applications the web and at least
from I think an engineering community
perspective all this is kind of cool it
means there's lots of work for us that
means there's lots of really interesting
security challenges in engineering
challenges and finally this is just the
beginning as we talked to some of the
LTE folks as we talk to other things the
mobile space since
we think the rate of change based on the
data is accelerating and we'll even more
dramatic in the next few years with that
I think of exactly four minutes for
questions
hi quick thanks a lot for sharing this
one thing that jumps out at me is of
course video is a much larger amount of
traffic for any interaction one might
have with an application right when you
download a video that's going to be lots
and lots of megabytes versus downloading
an email or Twitter or whatever I wonder
if that's kind of skewing things in the
analysis I mean if the growth of video
traffic you know it goes pretty big
anyone screaming video traffic will show
up very very high in your analysis right
so we're kind of discounting the
importance of those who are not doing
video would you agree with that yes I
think I think in the tech report you
know it takes an awful lot of tweets to
make up a single HD screen whereas you
know clearly as SMS is demonstrated
volume and difficulty of delivery don't
always equate with pricing Patrick I did
mention after my yes you did thank you
so in the report you mentioned inter a/s
traffic and you mentioned that you try
to group companies so lots of companies
you know telia tisk lead telefonica
comcast etc have a backbone and then
they have an AS with eyeballs in it are
you measuring from their backbone or are
you grouping that together are you
measuring the backbone to eyeball is
edge or how does that work yeah it might
be easier to take it offline business
gets a little bit complicated but we did
look at a s paths to avoid a number of
issues including double counting of SN
so tried to capture as close to the edge
of the network as we could the group asn
okay and just to add some data to the
paper optimized peering a s is less than
twenty percent of our traffic okay Thank
You Patrick since the gentleman from
Carpathia has nothing to say I'll ask a
question when you rank so there are
networks that are bigger on inbound
networks that are bigger on outbound and
you showed some of the ratio stuff when
you rank the network's by traffic is
that sort of taking ignoring the vector
dimension of the traffic and just
ranking total bytes
seen inflows so a large so if someone is
number five or number six it could be
all in all out or some mix yeah so in
the most of the ranking it was in plus
out so it was the overall vector though
he did to the analysis separately which
was you saw you know some vestiges of
that and like the comcast discussion
which is kind of an interesting metric
right itself is some of the data
presented in the tech report broken out
that way or it's mostly just the hidden
plus they out mmm maybe a little bit
more but I think it's mostly in plus out
we ran out of room in time and okay
thanks yep you already asked a question
Patrick now I have another is this what
are the number is 95th percentile pink
average the primarily average so bites
delivered toes yeah okay thank you okay
I think I'm out of time I should mention
that my co-authors Farnham and I think
Scott and John are here gandee's Mike I
think he's hunting and kill some wild
animals but thank you
you