nanog 48 in Austin data foundry and
giganews our sponsor so see you all
there but before we close out the nanog
part of this I wanted to first thank our
hosts Aaron I'm sorry our hosts Arbor
and merit which um let's give them a
round of applause the joint the joint
meeting with erin was fantastic it was
great being part of it let's give the
Aaron people around of applause all of
banana books all of our other sponsors
and speakers great we had a great we had
a great agenda really went well and then
finally all of you for coming and
participating you guys all deserve a
round of applause to so thank you so one
final thing I want to do before we close
this all off is that um as betty
mentioned we we have new SC members but
we're also at the first point since the
kind of restructuring of nanog where
people have served on the pc or SC and
our reaching term limits and those
people are rent provo Todd Underwood
Josh I think it's Josh no horn and Joel
yay glee and so they have contributed
immensely to the program to the
structure to the to the viability and to
the quality of nanog and I think they
deserve a round of applause as well
so thank you all for coming and have a
great Erin and we'll see you all in
Austin and one last comment please take
a moment and complete your nanog survey
it will be open for another week thanks