I'm really looking forward to the Nano
get the agenda looks great I want to
open it up say welcome and turn it over
to the various people who are going to
speak to you this morning um I did want
to I did want everyone to take notice of
the hosts merit and Arbor and we'll have
some words from those hooks in a second
but we want to thank them for helping us
put this all together and I wanted to
thank all of you for coming out and and
supporting the nanog crew out here so
with that welcome to now 947 and Betty
that he has something to say
good morning everyone and again as Dave
indicated I just wanted to extend a
thank you from merit to our CEO dan
walsh for allowing merit to be part of
actually hosting the organization nanog
and hosting this meeting so done just a
little gift of our appreciation this is
the the traditional host award it was a
little unique to put this together
generally it is merit thanking a host
and this is the Nana support team at
merit thanking merit we also couldn't
have done this meeting without our
co-host Lisa Quimby has done a
tremendous amount of work in putting
together the other parts of the hosting
responsibility and this is truly a
recognition of merit to arbor networks
for their partnership so Farnham and
Lisa and again it is it is with great
pleasure that were able to host the
meeting the other thing that I would
like to do if anyone would like to see
the home base for our networks in ann
arbor or make a trip over to merits home
base and see our data center and some of
our facilities contact me i'd love to
make a tour available and get you guys
over to innerwear it's about 30 minutes
from here um okay so now we're gonna
have a few words from our host so don
Welch
yeah here we go no problem
okay thanks everyone so in this strange
position a guy asked Betty just before
we came up do I give the award to myself
because I usually give them thank you
but anyway so we we are hosting but we
also normally do nanog logistics and so
I just want to take a few minutes as I
usually do I usually take a few minutes
in the fall meeting to talk a little bit
about merit and what's going on and just
a many of you might wonder why why's
mirror do this what's what's the
connection so just very quickly merit
we've been around since nineteen
sixty-six we've been doing this
networking thing for a while but one of
the things that we did in our early
history as we were a research network
that dabbled in production is we won
along with some others the NSFNET
contract and in part of that of taking
NSFNET and then helping to foster
internetworking was the creation of
nanog so it's really historical
president that we've that we have been
the host of nanog honest is the internet
is involved the industry is involved and
merit is involved we've still stayed
involved with nanog and we provide the
logistics for nana and it works pretty
well we're nonprofit we we serve
primarily the research and education
community and so in some sense we can be
somewhat of a neutral ground because is
you know many of you aware of not
everybody is really comfortable coming
and sharing all their secrets with with
their competitors but we create this
neutral ground and we also know a little
bit about networking so it's a good
combination i think it's worked very
well over the years so as I said we
primarily provide networking to the
education community libraries and so
forth and some states have similar types
of organizations to do the same thing
we're a hybrid network or mostly
fiber-based where we can't afford to
invest in fiber we do circuits and we
provide layer 3 and
and additional network services on top
of that like many people we've got our
hand out waiting for money from the ARRA
grants so with luck we'll fill in a lot
more of our network with fiber if we're
successful as I said you know like many
of you we find out that networking alone
is not is not exactly what our
membership wants so we provide
additional services up the stack and
I'll just very quickly finish up this is
the way the network is working today
hoping it's working well for you we've
got an 80 circuit that AT&T is
graciously provided to get back to our
headquarters in Ann Arbor and then you
ride our fiber backbone out to Chicago
and off on to other places out in the
world so I hope you have a great nanog
hope you're in gear is a little less
messy than this photo and thank you for
being here it's really great to have you
all in Michigan it's great to be a host
of nanog partner
ok
thank you very much done good morning
I'm farnham Johanna and I'm co-founder
of arbor networks and also chair of
computer science and engineering
department here at the University of
Michigan on behalf of my colleagues at
arbor networks it's my pleasure to
welcome all of you to nanog 47 and a
special thanks to our co-sponsors Don
wells and his crew at merit as many of
you probably know this that the
underlying technologies from arbor
networks came out of some of our
research at the University of Michigan
with some of you folks in the audience
and in fact merit played a very unique
role in the early days it played an
instrumental role i should say in the
proof-of-concept deployment of the
technology in the very early days of
arbor networks we're happy to be able to
co-sponsor this event again with merit
in a couple of minutes that i have i
just wanted to share a few thoughts with
you about some of the challenges and
opportunities ahead i'm a college
professor so if you were hoping for a
sales pitch you're not going to get it
thank you but more seriously we've seen
a breathtaking pace of advancement
that's brought has brought computing and
communications into the forefront of
business science medicine arts
entertainment you name it in in many
ways this was not even imaginable 10 15
years ago the explosive growth of data
wireless connectivity at broadband
speeds and connecting potentially
billions of devices and seamless access
to services and applications in the
cloud are transforming the way we work
the way we conduct business the way we
learn the way we play educate students
communicate and collaborate there's
there's no doubt that information
technology will integrate more deeply
into society and as this picture
probably shows that's my telephone in
1988 we'll see proliferation of new ways
and new application
for communication collaboration and
sharing and this proliferation of course
will continue what I think it's truly
exciting is that networking and
communication the business that all of
us are in will continue to be at the
center of an ongoing societal
transformation perhaps for many decades
to come of course these advances are
going to bring some enormous challenges
I'm going to highlight a couple of them
first and foremost traffic is growing
rapidly on fixed and mobile networks and
the data is there IP traffic is expected
again to double every two years for the
next couple of years at least video
internet will drive much of this growth
I just recently read actually a couple
of days ago that more than just in
August alone more than hundred and
sixty-one million viewers watched an
average of 157 videos I think my teenage
sons were definitely two of those her
viewers during the month of August and
Google alone was estimated to have
served more than 10 billion videos
during during that month during the 30
day period the other challenge which is
closer to my heart has to do with
security threats that clog the bandwidth
of your networks and increase costs
there's plenty of data out there that
that supports the fact that significant
amount of internet traffic is these days
is malicious and attacks have grown
rapidly over the last decade and botnets
are of course everywhere and I don't
need to tell this group pricing for data
is fixed or dropping and of course
competition and regulation pose
significant additional constraints craig
hlavaty bits in it just a few minutes is
going to say a few words about is going
to give a presentation about some some
exciting new research that craig and
some of the colleagues at arbor and
university of michigan and merrick have
gone on evolution of internet traffic so
let me address something unrelated to
that having to do mostly with the
evolution of security threats so let me
focus on that for a couple of minutes
over the last decades the threats of
availability and security of Internet
has gone
undergone a a rapid and dramatic
evolution a few short years ago we
witnessed emergence of highly visible
attacks against the internet users
infrastructure's including massive been
on service attacks and highly virulent
warm internet warms what I want to
highlight is that this transformation
that's taking place initially what we
saw this was the era of look at being
attacks primary motivation for these
attackers was bragging rights worms and
viruses were simply intended to impact
the availability of the underlying
infrastructure I refer to these as
availability attacks and they impact
that network access services and often
reputation of content providers and
service providers what's happened over
the last few years is that we're finding
ourselves in the middle of a fundamental
shift from what I refer to as
availability attacks on the
infrastructure to coordinated attacks
that are launched from malicious
distributed delivery platforms let's
call those but that's of course the
malware the malware that we see
propagates takes control of hosts
enables command and control
infrastructure and delivery platform for
various kinds of malicious activities
these coordinated facts of course
launched from everywhere and harvests
resources of compromise hosts they fuel
they have been fueling a rapid increase
in spam phishing identities theft you
name it and there's no question that
distributed attacks are going to
increase in size and sophistication
targeting specific applications
including their layer 7 and we're also
seeing proliferation of attacks that's
spurred by financial gains and political
motives including examples that you've
seen as stoney Oh Georgia and so on so
what's ahead in 2009 2010 and beyond
there's no question that security
challenges the future security
challenges will follow adoption of
Internet profit motives are of course
are here to stay politically motivated
attacks das attacks especially are going
to be here forever cyber networks
seems to be are the new frontiers for
counterintelligence botanist will
continue to dominate ha attacks are
launched and of course as a result of
proliferation of botnets attribution
will be increasingly difficult and as I
mentioned we should expect that future
security challenges will follow internet
adoption patterns for the efficient
proliferation of wireless devices and
social media platforms are going to open
new avenues for their attackers and
bring evolving security challenges and
of course as all of us talk about clouds
protecting the cloud infrastructure is
going to be key to long-term adoption of
the new cloud model so I want to leave
you on one message probably what's most
important here is that collaboration is
going to be needed more than ever before
nanog with its long history of over the
past couple of decades is a terrific
example of collaborative nature of the
work that this community does and the
collaboration that can taken place over
the last two decades we're going to need
cooperation information sharing between
private and public sector among Internet
service providers and between
governments and that's going to be
critical to the success of running the
Internet in the future cyber world
there's no question is going to be
increasingly important economic
prosperity and national security I can
tell you that it's never been more
exciting time to be in this business
thank you very much
well thank you guys