welcome to day two of Nana um I trust
everybody had a reasonable evening last
night hello out there hey good morning
folks um I just wanted to get us going
here a little bit um this morning is
going to be a little bit different than
our normal you know few minutes before
we get into the agenda we have a few
minutes set aside to remember one of our
dear colleagues he's no longer with us
and Kathy Aronson is going to do that
for us so what I want to do is just hop
into that right away and then I'll turn
it over to Tom for the rest of the
agendas so Kathy yeah let me see well
you know I don't know if I know how to
operate this thing yeah oh well things
just to remember as you look at these
photos that they were before actual
digital cameras so some of them are in
various stages of blurriness I'm the
engineers does it take to operate
windows I don't know hi um I don't
usually write things down but i'm just
going to read this because otherwise COV
it's you Oh anyway okay my name is Kathy
Aaronson and I thought we should take a
few minutes out of our day to talk a
little bit about abba abuja I asked
quite a few of you for pictures and
thoughts for this talk and I want to
thank everyone for helping us celebrate
ABBA while I give you this talk I'm
going to cut there really fast is that
really five seconds okay too many of you
she was your friend your mentor your
colleague or someone you saw present at
a meeting many of you never met ABBA but
her impact on our community is profound
she wrote documents she chaired IETF
working groups the routing area she
presented she mentored I mean there was
really no one she wouldn't help her you
know Shepard along one of the other
really great things that Abba did was
she helped she and i formed net girl
and at most of the meetings women get
together and share ideas we did it last
night have cocktails or dinner and
interact with other women and networking
because you know there's only like 10 of
us so you know it's easy to get a table
at this point there's actually net Girlz
meetings at meetings all over the world
because there's like we have a bezel as
net girls Europe we have we're working
on the net girls Asia we have t-shirts
if you're interested the thing I always
remember about Ava's she she was
constantly in motion she did research
she presented papers she worked on
network management tools and other
software that people use all the time
even though she was always super busy
and I always had she always had time to
explain something or help someone learn
something new so many of us in this
business worked too hard and don't get
enough sleep and it tends to make folks
less pleasant to their peers but I've
always always had a smile and lots of
patience the other thing I remember
about Ava's that she was the only one
who could compete with Casey for the
rapid speaking award she talked to
really fast because she had to get
everything in in a really short period
of time there's been a scholarship fund
that was set up by her folks and some
folks at U of M quite a few years ago in
2002 for women in science and
engineering and on the nanog website you
can donate to that and also if you order
annette girls t-shirt the proceeds from
that i'm going to match them and then
donate them to the scholarship fund so
what I'd like to end this with is as you
go through this meeting and when you go
home take a little bit of bobble with
you mentor someone answer someone's
question contribute to a document even
if you might not normally make to make
the time remember that all the folks
that you deal with are just regular
people trying to do the best job they
can thanks