okay i'm getting the thumbs up we're
going to go ahead and start
so this is the session on porting your
ipv4 applications to v4 v6 dual-stack if
that's not the session you intended to
attend then you're in the wrong room the
gratuitous why is this important slide
that figure is not actually updated as
of last night that figure is from a few
days ago as you can see we have about
700 26 days remaining in the hi Ana free
pool for ipv4 given the two-year
development cycle on a lot of
applications it's time to get moving
there is a lot of text ahead in the
slides I apologize for that but there
just aren't really good cool graphical
ways to present this information at
least I haven't been able to come up
with anybody if you have ideas I'm open
to them okay the basic steps in porting
your application there's a sample code
available at that same URL and you're
welcome to use all of that example code
all of the examples are written in v4
and then ported to v6 there's three
languages there currently see Perl and
Python coming soon will be Ruby and then
probably Java change the variable names
if you change your variable names as you
start changing structure types and such
then the variable names can actually act
as a flag for the other places in your
code that you probably need to update I
didn't do that in some of the cases
further on because the code was simple
enough but sorry about that
it can actually be a helpful technique
it certainly helped in the sea version
look for the old variable names as
markers and then basically once you've
done that it boils down to the usual
compile repair recompile followed by
test p bug retest the general changes AF
inet becomes known as AF inet 6 it's
kind of a misnomer that it's AF inet 6
because it will actually support map to
be for addresses as well as v6 in that
address family sockaddr in becomes a
sockaddr in six except that if you need
something that sort of refers to enough
space to accommodate either hand or can
be used as a pointer for both that can
be cast back and forth as needed there's
this special structure called a sockaddr
storage that's defined that is
guaranteed to be a superset of all of
the different sockaddr types supported
on the system
most of the structures have the same
members although sometimes they renamed
them fortuitously they have very similar
constants and mostly it's just the
address size that changes in most cases
you may actually depending on your
application have to check address
scoping v6 introduced a new concept of
address scope where you have link local
addresses that are only good for the
local subnet they're not routed to other
networks you have site local addresses
that may have a differing meaning as to
what their particular range of grouting
is and then you of course have global
addresses which are what we're used to
dealing with it before
most of the applications you'll be
porting from v4 that won't be an issue
because that concept didn't exist in
before but it's not really covered in
this example so heads up for that other
possible gotchas that are not covered in
the examples if you keep IP addresses in
log files or have them as fields in your
databases things like that you're going
to have to resize those fields in the
database prevent potentially and you may
need to update your log parsers as well
as your log writing software to handle
that and any other parsing or other
routines that need to deal with IP
addresses mostly these should be library
functions so you update the one library
function and it pretty much accommodates
for most of your code but yeah it's
something to look out for
with that we'll delve into each of the
three porting examples again heavily
referencing the handout data the handout
actually contains side-by-side gifts of
each of the sample applications there's
a client and server for each language
and there's a v4 version of the client
on the left side of the diff and a v6
version or a dual stack version on the
right side and then all of the source
code is easily downloadable from the
same website and you're welcome to use
it for whatever purposes so the easy
part of migrating the server went pretty
straightforward there's an additional
include file that you need for C which
is net I net / I n dot H i renamed sock
ft the sock ft 6 just so that i can use
it as a tag for finding things that
needed to be updated sockaddr
instructors changed to sockaddr in 6 as
mentioned before and i renamed the
variable which was desk soon two deaths
in sick so i can track that as well
there's a few changes to the way that
that structure gets initialized in the
process there are some different
arguments in the socket call as well as
setsockopt bind and listen
and then there are some changes to the
variables in the socket related error
messages am I going too fast too slow
just right everybody's sleeping I'm
seeing nods to just right okay I'll
continue the client migration was a
little bit harder than the server but it
was actually pretty similar the hairy
parts of that were that you needed a
helper function to front and the inet
m2p call for the different possible
return structures from get out our info
depending on whether returned an inet or
nine and six type structure it's
unfortunate that high net n2p was not
written with the fact that that could
happen in mind such that it could just
be called with that information get post
my name gets served by name get changed
out to get a tour info which is actually
kind of the Swiss Army get whatever by
whatever solution it's actually a lot
easier to use once you learn to use it
but it is quite a different paradigm so
that changes things and then the other
big thing to worry about is if you use
get a tour info it dynamically allocates
a linked list for you and returns a
pointer to you in the thing you called
it with
so that's that memory needs to be freed
or your application has the risk of
leaking memory if you call it repeatedly
this is the eye chart warning if you can
read this your eyes are better than mine
copyright 2009 hurricane electric all
rights reserved moving on so the old way
we did a get host by name and an inet
adder call to parse it if it was a IP v4
address the new way and then we had to
call this get served by name to resolve
the service multiple separate stop steps
the new way we just call get add or info
with all the right arguments and it
returns everything for us so you can see
this is much simpler than all of the
code on the previous two slides and it
does pretty much the same thing
the process of trying to connect is a
little bit different in ipv4 this is
where it gets hard to read the you know
we had to do a loop to try each of the
possible addresses but they were all
ipv4 addresses so we only needed to
create one socket outside of the loop
and then iterate over trying each
connection on that socket with repeated
calls to connect it to a successful
connection in the in the new paradigm we
we actually have to create the socket
and destroy it each time within the loop
and that's because we don't know whether
we need nif for a 9 f4i net6 type socket
when we create the socket so we have to
create it inside the loop as we parse
each one
the easy parts again use the same
variable name flagging mostly update the
same structure names and calls through
exactly the same method get a tour info
will automatically return quad-a and a
records so v6 or before is automatic
with one code base and inet m2p needs
the helper function that was discussed
earlier so before we move on to Pearl
you know what happens if we aren't ready
well this is probably a little more
graphic than what happens but it's
something like that your ipv4 client
your ipv6 home we clients are going to
have a hard time talking to your ipv4
only servers
moving on to pearl any questions so far
on see I went through that kind of quick
okay either everybody's lost or they
don't care or it's all working out well
refer to the source code examples again
same spiel in the pearl case I didn't
bother retaining most of the variables
it's a pretty small code base and it's
not that important add socket six to the
modules used you still need to call the
socket module as well but the other
problem is that the Pearl documentation
for socket six is pretty minimal and
assumes that you just sort of magically
understand it's mostly sort of like
socket but not completely there are some
good examples out on the web and
hopefully by referring to this code
you'll have the rest of the puzzle
pieces if you need them gut and replace
the yet star by name calls no surprise
there with get a tour info change the
protocol and address families in the
socket and buying calls and some minor
changes to processing how incoming
connections are handled the biggest
change is the get star by name to get a
tour info process similar changes to
what was done in the seaport because
underlying it is the same see libraries
see get a tour info returns a linked
list the Pearl version does not return a
linked list instead it returns a single
list and you're expected to know that
every fifth element in the list starts a
new set of items
in the list this actually turns out to
be pretty easy to park parse in Perl
i'll show you how that's done on the
next slide one other gotcha i ran into
in Perl is if you call get a tour info
within 6 adder any as the argument the
return value you get does not include in
six at or any as what you're going to
bind to and instead it gives you back
localhost so unless you are intending to
bind to local host of local host only
you will want to change that in the
return structure before you call buying
that wasn't a problem in c by the way so
i don't know why curl does that
differently
so the parsing routine it's so a little
bit of an eye chart but you can see in
the second line of the new way of doing
this at res equals get a tour info blah
blah blah then we'll step through at res
using basically you know the five
variables we want to stick the tuple
into comma at res equals at res well fam
does not equal a a fine at six the
reason I skip everything that's not an
AF inet six entry is because I want to
provide dual-stack services with this
one code base so I want to only bind to
the v6 address and that way I'm binding
actually to support mapped before
clients as well as v6 clients on the one
Sokka
you don't have to actually create
multiple sockets and all that on most
systems there are a few systems where
that doesn't work
unpack sockaddr in six is pretty
straightforward and very similar to the
before stuff any questions on this okay
ipv4 only version we call socket and
call buying guess what the ipv6 dual
stack version same thing except we have
to use PFI at six instead of PFI net big
whopping change their ipv4 only two dual
stack additional code changes this is
how we how we accept a new connection
unpack the the address pretty much the
same process we use get name n fo
instead of get host by adder
I net into P instead of into a for the
for the logging information formatted
the client migration very similar to the
server and even more similar to the sea
client had the same module rearrange the
address resolution stuff add some
handling for AF inet 62 the connection
loop and convert inet into a 2 i knit
into p and protocol family stuff for the
socket call
code changes same stuff
this is pretty straightforward you get
at our info thing now we're actually
going to just parse through it and
connect to the first one that works we
don't care whether it's v4 or v6 as long
as it just works but in the loop where
you're trying to connect an ipv4 the
socket can be recycled for multiple
connections but with dual stack you
again need to move the creation of the
socket inside the loop so that you can
create an inet Orion at six socket as
needed same stuff as the others the ipv4
only version of the connection loop
clearly I'm spending too much time on
some of these slides the ipv4 only
version of the connection loop and the
ipv4 v6 dual stack version the
connection loop as you can see there's a
lot more content inside the connection
loop it's not as bad as it looks mostly
it's stuff that was outside got moved
inside the loop because you don't know
ahead of time which kind you're trying
so before we get into Python a more
realistic look at what's really going to
happen if people's applications aren't
ready for dual stack it'll be one or
more of these situations where you end
up with translating routers or multiple
layers of map or TCP relays or this DS
Lite thing that Comcast and a couple of
other people have been working on which
actually is one of the more promising
one so far
how to do this if we don't have content
on the six better already
Python actually Python was the easiest
language to do the port in which pains
me to say because it's not my favorite
language
but mostly it's a matter of getting
replaced the the get star by name calls
replacing the default fatal error
process with a try process that iterates
through different possibilities
and some minor changes to how we handle
incoming connections because it starts
returning the fort opal instead of a two
item tuple
get served by name to get at our info
still pretty much straightforward
listening it's still straightforward but
we have to do this iterative process now
instead of the original single attempt
there's your two people versus four
people change for the parsing the
address that gets returned by connect
this is to use to make the address
presentable in debug output user
messages client migration pretty
straightforward get out our info again a
little bit of handling for AF inet 6 in
the connection loop and I knit into a
10-2 p protocol family in the socket
this is the way we used to try and
connect this is what we have to do now
primarily this expanded due to having to
handle the two different families as
possible returns from the resolution
there's minor modifications required in
the successful connection message
because the variable names changed in
the print arguments do the family
changes and not a lot else needed the
slides are online at on the agenda now
as I understand it there's a handy
function replacement guide that pretty
much maps to all of the languages and
there's also a structure replacement
guide at the end so it's going to add
those to your toolkit for your
applications hope it works out well for
you feedback is welcome at that address
presentation all the resources are also
available
so seriously questions comments
discussion we've got it's 220 and
tutorial that was supposed to take 90
minutes from two o'clock
yes come on up to the mic
and I don't have to be porting related
questions if you've got questions about
implementing d6 deploying v6 we're here
to help hi larissa Shapiro and from ISC
and I just wanted to say that the thing
that you were talking about the
carrier-grade NAT
upon my
it's actually a pretty good stuff I
think I think it's the most promising
thing short of dual stack that that's
out there hey I mean isn't it's an early
version but
it still breaks most of the things that
nap breaks but it doesn't break all of
the things that double Matt breaks so
it's better than double map which is
what most of the carrier-grade NAT
amounts to any other questions concerns
comments thoughts
can you go into a bit more detail on the
you had talked about matching against a
database structure and things like that
when it comes from storing on the ipv4
and destroying both ipv4 and ipv6 how
you actually well I didn't approach that
in my designs because I wasn't actually
storing those things but in general and
ipv4 address is this big and so you can
store it for example in a var char 15 if
you really wanted to or you can store it
as a 32-bit integer and ipv6 addresses
this big and so you need to at least
widen the fields and you need to at
least allow for the fact that the
content may be in a different format if
you're storing it as a string and if
you've got any routines to do parsing on
that and if you're doing a dress mask
notation or things like that you may
need to update your parsing routines to
allow for that or make sure that you're
using a parsing library that already
does
I can you quickly comment on any changes
that you need to make for like putting
any kinda where applications because I
heard like ipv6 actually has is doing
something different out for any kinds of
I would love to unfortunately I have not
gotten completely up to speed on ipv6
any cast as yet so I don't actually know
that I will try and research that and
know for next time yeah the others
okay I guess everybody has lots of free
time they weren't planning on having
thank you all for attending and I hope
you enjoyed the tie line pictures
ok come play trying to turn it off for
you
see it's probably was
Safari Firefox
everyone in a lot of microsoft stuff
yeah yes I believe
so sorry i didn't have a better answer
for