It's a pleasure to be here.
What's my accent? Anyone knows? What, what
is my accent? Where are from? Where am I
from?
Any guesses? Okay Israel, all right. And
enjoys I am Israeli. And in fashion I
want to start with a direct question. So
if you know of Israelis that's part of
what we do, often. Who is this guy?
Anyone knows? I have one per person. Yes.
Okay. This is Kevin Finster. He's
instilled and respected security
researcher. And he found the one
thing that, according to reports, leaked
personal information of DJI consumers,
according to the media reports. And at
time when Kevin has done this research,
DJI in fact had an active bug bounty. They just
launched a bounty and Kevin, although he
has you know, lots of hair. As you can see.
He wanted to do the right thing, he waned
to wear the white hat. He wanted to report
this vulnerability under this new, just
launched DJI bug bounty. Now, the way this
bug bounty was launched at the time,
according to the reports, as you can see,
was in this kind of fashion. There wasn't
really a clear policy, with a clear scope.
It wasn't a bug bounty kind of
policy you are used to seeing, you know.
Contract with the elements. It was more
of a PR announcement along this lines.
So, because there was some unclarity
according to reports, expected scope, Kevin
contacted DJI. And he asked them is this vulnerability in scope? And they said
according to the reports, it is in fact in scope.
And you're authorized to conduct
this testing.
Now we got the active ability. They
offered him a thirty thousand dollar
reward for that vulnerability. So I don't know if we have bug hunters today in the room with
us? But, thirty thousand dollars throwback is pretty high. That's a pretty high back.
That's my priority back and then the
plot thickens. DJI also wanted, according
to media reports, Kevin to sign an
agreement. An agreement that he found was
one-sided.
One that lets him legally exposed. So Kevin
refused to sign this agreement, and in negotiations as far that process, a legal rep
drafted a letter mentioning that
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act was
exchanged, according to the reports. Now,
this is an interesting example, because
this is one of the first time that we
heard about a potential legal question
going public in a bug bounty settings.
So how does this story ends? Anyone knows?
Anyone heard? Kevin ended up walking away from an improved thirty thousand
dollar bug bounty. So, refusing to sign a
contract and walking away from that
improved background.
And I think this is a bill you know,
there are multiple versions to the story.
This all according to reports and I
encourage you to go online and you know,
look at all the versions to the story
equally. DJI responds to this article.
But isn't this is, in fact an
interesting you know, story that just
relied on some of the emerging aspects that
we're seeing when it comes to the
legalese and the interactions of
bug bounties and one ability
disclosure programs we don't want. So
what I'm going to be sharing with you
today, is a bit about that landscape. So
just show hands anyone here is you know
with my prior work? Not at all, great. Because we
have a whole hour to dig into that. So
again, so this is mostly repair work that
I did before I joined Intel. Today my
director, I had a director global cyber
security policy with Intel. And also
teach at UC Berkeley, the master in
cybersecurity program. But I did this
work before I joined Intel as part of my
doctoral degree in the law, at UC
Berkeley law school. And part of that work
I really dived into a lot of contracts.
Hundreds of contracts. Both along with
the disclosure programs, backgrounds and
platforms and most important feedback
bounty programs. To inquire what is going
around in that landscape, and I'm gonna
be sharing a lot of that research we do
today and also going into some of
the transform here seen with respect to
bug bounty legalese and just you know,
looking at some myths that are
circling, circling around. Why is this
important? This is important because
there is a conception among the
information security community, among the research community, that you know, the law
matters here. That they're legal risks.
And you know that's the empirical
research. So this is one example, this is
work done by since D. Anyone here from
you know, the city Phoenix and democracy
technology there are doing very
important work and this type of in this
research what they did is they interview
twenty leading information security
professionals hackers and other
professionals working in this field and
they asked us specifically about the
laws and fifty percent than half of
those researchers said in that research
that they literally think about
copyright law and the CFAA and laws that
are going to be talking about them today
as they're doing their testing so much
that this is a consideration when
everything when they are thinking what
if they disclose the mobility and they
might even change the way they test
because of these because of this law
moreover we know from additional
research that was done among 100
security researchers that 20% of them so
this is research looking at 100 research
also from that academic center setting
that's 20 percent of them said they were
threatened in one kind of way legal
action and a broader research that was
conducted in 2015 with more than 400
researchers they found that 60% 60% 6-0
of the researchers reported that this
consideration of legal risk is something
that are thinking about when there are
that Junction when when they need to
decide where it reports to a cooperation
of our mobility so we know that this
conception is emerging that is existing
among the community and there might be
some gap between how the law operates
and that
reception but it really matters because
one foster that collaboration between
security researchers between hackers and
companies and even governmental
governmental entities we want to foster
but collaboration because at the end
getting the research to the right to the
right hands matters right and this is
for a lot of what my work was focused on
and I'm not alone in this kind of
relaying there are a lot of people that
are operating this remained in fact City
T is part of this work they also
collaborated and basically got a lot of
experts in the field of security 50x
which sign a letter to explain that we
need to address this issue of the
culture of legal risks that we have in
information security to ensure that we
and bond we want advises the release of
elbow vulnerabilities out there we don't
invite folks quarter and we are able to
foster coordinate disclosure practices
so a lot of ones you're gonna see here
today is basically a means a way to
foster that collaboration to build a
bridge between companies and hackers and
this is focusing specifically on bug
bounties but of course this is just one
example of what we can do in the broader
data system so let me start with this
question about this how many of you
familiar heard about the concept of
course these are programs in which
corporations big corporations and even
other entities are in Buckingham
statistics systems in exchange for
monitoring their interpretation of
reports so how many of you
see something that looks like this this
is a background in program that we've a
website over by party okay
even from from those for the for the few
that I have here that have seen
something like this have you ever read
the legal terms okay great so basically
what we are seeing is this landscape of
bug bounties that is operating that all
this matter of invitation to conduct
testing all this market even if you will
legal even exchange of abilities is
operating under contracts okay so this
is the first kind of inside this this is
an area that is mostly dictated by trans
abuse contracts like EULA's right and
utilizes license agreements that you
probably are canoeing or
other I exact terms that you click on on
every no your everyday kind of practices
you go through the internet and I'm
going to be looking at those contracts
and giving you some of the background
and how those contracts interact with
computer crime laws and other aspects
would be see the back bumper lien but
first of all I want to clarify then
again I'm talking about the entire
research before in details
I'm though I'm a lawyer in Israel I'm
not your lawyer this is not legal advice
and I'm expressing my own opinions there
you have it you know of the fine cream
the disclaimer just in line with the
other I accept terms that you want to
see here today so the bottom of the
phenomena phenomena is really expanding
this is a this is being a trend we know
there is value in that
stand right we have seen it not only in
Silicon Valley corporations like Google
Intel Facebook and others but also a
more traditional sectors like
transportation aviation and even the
government the government has conducted
multiple formats within the center
bombing in the Department of Defense I
think they're into the fifth or sixth
program they're doing right now they
have extended it to more platforms in
which they actually invite people from
all over the world to hunt and find
vulnerabilities on what you might
consider you know the most substance
systems of all and because of the growth
of this phenomenon it wanted to take a
look and see how we adjusting the legal
landscape to support that because this
is all you can say a newly emerging
field in security but it's definitely
expanding very rapidly and our time to
say that Intel the company that I work
for also has a bug bounty program that
is very successful so I first of all
would like to invite you all cyber
security professionals here in the room
to hunt on our program but the point is
that we're seeing this expansion in
multiple sectors including in the
hardware and firmware sector and this is
just one success story coming out out of
the back bounty relax that there are lot
of conversations
founders that I what I'd love to kind of
stress out the more the most is that the
way the battery these programs actually
allow us to develop the pipeline for
track security so this is Jack Campbell
any of you know him you know he's a
great guy I just met him a few weeks ago
now he studies in Stanford but this guy
Jack
before joining Stanford why after
basically graduating from his last year
in high school got to make that we
turned into ten tomorrow that's after he
participated in multiple programs of the
Department of Defense nearly we need all
the best challenge points out there for
the hack the Pentagon Act the army and
after US Air Force programs and what a
best life about Jack is not only that is
really cool nine disability story about
how that buddies are being used to
foster the timeline and get people
excited about security and even hired
them in very non-traditional ways if you
can think about it but also because of
this segments so Jack's tells us that
part what he likes about the bounties as
he can eat is able to participate in
paying for skill set in America is legal
without having to hide his findings or
to be worried about the legalese or the
implications and I think that is one of
the major advantages of bug bounty and
that is why I want to make sure that as
we are operating in this field we also
think about the legal aspects of it and
as I mentioned really cool story that
because of that black multi
participation Jack got to spend three
months before
with a Pentagon okay now another
landscape that is really developing is
the vulnerability disclosure landscape
and I want to make sure that I'm
distinguishing between bug bounties and
vulnerability disclosure programs so the
main difference between pack bounties
frameworks and which corporations are
invited external hackers to test their
system in exchange for monetary rewards
and vulnerability disclosure programs
which are basically frameworks to create
a channel of communication a weapon
security I'd email process for in which
you details how you're gonna address and
received vulnerabilities from external
researchers that are reported to you
without monetary rewards that's a key
that's the distinction between one
bility disclosure programs and bug
bounties now we also see a major
especially anomaly because believe it or
not regulators are actually pushing
towards fallibility disclosure products
they are saying that you as a user
corporation is part of your security
maturity as part of your reasonable
security practices you need to have that
channel of communication in place so
that when someone is fighting someone
something they were able to report it to
you and you need to have a process to
handle that not only that there's deceit
in two cases so the main federal the
main regulator who deserve protection in
the Mountain States the Federal Trade
Commission actually mentioned this
aspect that needs to have the one
ability disclosure program or the way
that is really the process and it can
process a place to receive on abilities
into cases in which yes armed with other
circumstances they viewed the lack of
such process unreasonable security
measure
so basically illegal under the law
because of this expansion for mobility
discussion
as well and the fact that it supported
by so many regulators are out there we
are also seeing more and more of these
policies accepted as well and of course
they have legal implications so let's
dive a little bit into the moment
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act the main
active hacking federal law in the
nineteen states from here some of you
are okay there are misconceptions around
the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act and I
do encourage you to learn more about it
if you're looking for a great resource
by the way little Bailey who is one of
the biggest experts out there he's a
special muscle to the DOJ computer crime
division has a lot of talks from
blackhat and besides online and it gives
a really great overview of the law
including some of the things we're gonna
focus on today so if you're looking as
you know for something as an additional
resource that's one thing that is out
there so the Computer Fraud and Abuse
I've been an actual the important
concept you need to kind of there are
many things to think about but they
really the poor or that law is like this
notion of authorization and the main
language suggests that whoever
intentionally exists accesses a computer
without authorization or in a manner
which exceeds the authorization I'm
going to speak about that and obtains
information from a protected computer
that is defined pretty broadly to
basically include any computer is
connected today tracks it is inspecting
commerce shall be punished by this and
that etc so this law has both criminal
and civil liability and if you look at
the statistics that is provided by the
Department of Justice interestingly
there are not a lot of criminal cases
that are using this provision against
security researchers they're really
really not a lot maybe two in all the
history of the State Fair the reason
however our additional component a
component of similar
which means that private parties can use
the CFA to other private parties
individual companies employees etcetera
that part of the CFA is more litigated
when it comes to this section so what I
want you to take away from here is this
idea of fluoridation now if we have any
pen testers in the room yeah
so often you take this contract but you
always have is consent to test us it's a
key component of any of any contest
contract which interacts with this
provision that relates to authorization
it's this idea that I consented for your
testing of my device on my computer now
we do have something that is called
circuit splits and my cervix leak I
don't mean an actual circuit I mean
there is a conflict in which different
states inside the United States in the
federal system are interpreting the
opinion and specifically this notion of
optimization and what does it mean to
explain conversation and that suite is a
lot of the kind of poor tension and
debate when it comes to state faith I'm
gonna give a very quick overview and
reminding everybody this is not a good
advice you should always seek your own
console so there is one key kind of
interpretation that is focusing on
circumvention of technical measures
this means that of authorization is
based upon technical measures ok I
include authentication barrier on the
way I could have password wall you need
to you know you need to provide a
concert forget it if you have
circumvented
password you have circumvented a
technical nature technological assurance
and answer convention could be exceeding
authorized access so that's one kind of
key interpretation that is being used
mostly in the ninth circuit for example
in the first circuit ninth circuit by
the way is California among others so
all the Yukon Valley and that is a
narrow definition to the CFA and it's
notional conversation because you have
to have those technical barriers in
place now there is another another kind
of way to think about this and according
to that kind of approach even
circumvention of contract language so
violation of employment contracts could
be exceeding authorization because I
have established the boundaries of the
flurries they should be our contracts
and if you violated something for
example you use the information in a way
that is not consistent with the contract
you have exceeded authorization and
violated the CFAA and that approach is
mostly debated and caused a lot of case
law and if I can recommend you one case
to look at is the nazil case in which
California looked at this approach and
said wait a minute this is not what the
CFA was meant to address the CFA was
about happy it wasn't about contract
breach of employees so this debate is
still actually ongoing it's a really
interesting debate we have one case in
the DC Circuit so in the Washington area
that is actually looking at the practice
I wouldn't equality so these are people
that reverse-engineer algorithms from
the outside and whether spreading is the
violation of the CFAA in public facing
websites so that question of the
legality of scraping under the CFA is
actually right now highly debated in one
case in DC and to another case called IQ
in the Ninth Circuit so it's a really
interesting area of the law and I know
you're really curious about that but the
case no but I do encourage you to take a
look it is it is an important area now
in addition to the CFAA the Computer
Fraud and Abuse Act we have another one
the DMCA how many of you heard about
Nixon many hands right the DIA is very
famous among the security community also
because of the extension and the trial
proceeding proceedings in which the
Copyright Office created a special
exemption for the purpose of good faith
security research so I'm going to talk
about that the reform what's to do with
the CF with the DMCA the density at the
Digital Millennium Copyright have and
the together you get I mean any
Copyright Act is in fact a provision
that is prohibiting the circumvention of
technological measures that effectively
control the access to software as a
copyright protected and there's some
statutory exceptions so the law itself
has exemptions for the purpose of
encryption and research in that area but
they have a lot of limitation for
example for security testing you leave
you know you have some conditions that
you need to follow in order to get them
but the copyright that the law also
recognized that with technology
development and innovation we might need
new exemptions from this active hacking
provision that we like that we have in a
copyright law so they created a process
a process in which people can go to the
Copyright Office to write to an
administrator regularly runs operating
operating in this field and tell them
give us an exemption for three years
from this anti-circumvention provision
for the purpose of doing something that
we the public need and is not really
undermining copyright protection and one
of these exceptions that started already
to the 2015
really because of great work many people
was actually be nude and expended last
year so we do have an exemption from the
DMCA from that specific law remember it
only gives you that the NCAA doesn't
deal with the CFAA that still operating
in the background and that extension
enables which it fosters whose face
appear to be our research but it also
has some limitations now one the
humanization was the device limitation
original 2050 this was actually never
narrowly applied to consumer voting
machines and Auto munille among others
and also medical devices but that device
limitation was removed so now this this
exemption is applied to many other
devices as well but there are still
other issues like you need to lawfully
acquire the device you need to only
engage in the practice solely for the
for the purpose of good security
research you still need to not violate
any other law including the same there
you're going to talk about that and you
need to carry the the reason we need to
conduct the research in a manner and in
an environment that is done to avoid any
harm to individuals or the public which
is really the key concern that's why we
are so focused about quoting one ability
disclosure because we want to minimize
that harm that potential harm for
end-users so you see there are many
conditions to this exception as well but
it's pretty it's already broader it's
applicable and what we knew once already
in 2018 so I encourage to keep following
those preceding and where that exemption
lies but most importantly where the
spark battlefield
you know gets into that discussion where
does bug bounty interact with that
discussion so in fact in that kind of
relationship between all these law the
key ideas of conversation also in the
context of the DMCA the practice the
goonies exemption one
the practice that you originally didn't
get the authorization of the owner for
if you have those certification the
percent of the owner then you do not
need that exemption because you you are
you have the consent consent to this
system and the way those laws are
interacting is essentially the backbone
T terms where are we going to see that
notional authorization played out now
when I first conducted this research I'm
talking about the year year and a half
ago when I was looking through the
torrents of our bounty programs this
notion wasn't as developed we haven't
seen a lot of are going to terms
actually including specifically this
idea of authorization inside their
program and specifically authorizing
access for the purpose of this law but
since then we have created industries
created standards in this area to really
address this tension and use the
contracts of the bug bounty to address
some of the legal risk in order to not
be relying solely on the DMCA exemption
that as you saw has multiple conditions
that you need to address in order to get
it so what is this notion of a bug on
the safe harbor so safe harbor the
concept yes we do have something right
so this is this is the idea the idea is
in a contract I can give you
optimization and I can in my contract in
this case in a bug banking policy
includes our provisions that will allow
you to test and not basically feel that
risk or be worried about the legal
implications because I specifically
addressed those those risks in a
contract language now in that landscape
you're discussed a movement so when I
first did the research again we didn't
have a lot of safe harbors out there I
looked at the tentative part of policies
and in fact although we that we already
had some guidance for the Department of
Justice in there Frank
to talk about where they said you know
these legal considerations with respect
to the CFA it's something you need to
consider when you're establishing the
back bounty although we we have that
already adoption of safe harbor wasn't
as as popular but then Dropbox was
really the first company to come and
adopt a safe harbor into their policy
and I prefer to say that I had something
to do with this in fact I encouraged
them to adopt the DMCA exclusion that
you're seeing right there at the time
and again is from my work I started a
movement called legal bug bounty it
operated on Twitter and I had a lot of
basically specific programs that I I
looked at their terms and I published
some tweets around it and I work with
many of the companies in Silicon Valley
to foster more adoption of safe harbors
into bug bounties are going to speak a
little bit about that but what this is
geared to do is basically take that
contract of the bug bounty and
specifically address this question of
anti hacking was within the language of
the back party proof so you would expect
to see in this regard again a legal part
of a bug bounty not just a technical
scope or definition of what is it now
then how much you're going to get for
your bugs and some may be other parts
and also apartment is impressive example
the legal concerns and in that part in
some respects we're now seeing more safe
harbors learned a language that
specifically addresses the issue of
legal risks now why is this important by
the way we do have some empirical
research out there that looks at the
market of bug bounties and this is very
important academic work that is done if
you're looking for a little bit you know
of academic work that can give you some
insights about the real economics of
that market I really I really invite you
to take a look
but the worth of plastic I tell the
zaccharas now they have multiple papers
in there in this area in fact they're my
co-authors in future work but I'm going
to recommend you to take a look and one
of their work looked in 77 policies from
Haku one as of January 2016 so yes this
is updated work I recognise that fears
in bug bounty industry is a lot a lot
has changed since then
but over but then at the time they found
that 17 from 77 analyzed policies had in
fact that clause that suggest that the
corporation will not take legal action
if you follow the terms of the bug
bounty but they also found that having
that Clause from an from a statistical
perspective didn't effect the crowd so
it didn't cause the crowd to change
their behavior or to operate differently
just from statistical academic
perspective so really interesting but
again we're talking about the partial
safe harbor just an obligation under
pristine legal action Knopfler is a sure
and also we're talking about data from
January 2016
one of the interesting things to see is
how is this what a change now that we
have seen such a movement in this area
we also know that sometimes policies
have different they have language that
really relies on the reading
capabilities of the reader so they also
use this image that is called that is
really areas that is used widely that's
them
what they found is that the average
readability score of back parking
policies is around 40 which requires
some college education now it could be
because there are a lot of typical terms
in back bounties and it could be just
because of how this academic is geared
to offering but it's still very
interesting because we really want to
clarify that language and make sure that
we are communicating the base
communicating in the best way possible
okay so what happened in this safe
harbor movement what we basically saw is
more and more companies agathi this
language and I think one of the
interesting things that we also saw this
tesla doing this really noble move so
again I have to say that I did have
something the doing is in fact Tesla
gave me one of their challenge points
one of only 20 in the world because of
that interaction and what they did in
their language that they not only ate
the safe harbor and address the legal
risk in terms of saying that they will
not pursue legal action against hackers
but they also did something that is
pretty novel and they said that if you
are cleared if you are pre-approved
researcher so you need to sign up with
their bug bounty which is public by the
way it's a public work on it so it's
open to all but for the purpose of this
provision you need to be a pre approved
researcher if you sign up your Tesla as
a bug bounty test not and you have
conducted testing and something went
wrong because it could happen you they
will fix it for free if you follow the
guidance of the program and if you sign
up you're here yourself as a researcher
then we'll fix it for free so they gave
you waivers from the warranty
limitations that they usually have in
their EULA's in the end-user license
agreements for the purpose of the bug
bounty and that's one of the kind of new
abilities that we are seeing in this
legal netscape that is really
recognizing that especially when it
comes from cars for example these are
very expensive devices so in order to
foster that testing in that cooperation
with a crowd
with the external community they had to
go and basically create this legal
novella and I think they really deserve
are you chat out for that okay so what
are we doing we know that we searchers
care about the communication elements
when it comes to one ability disclosure
and coordinate one ability disclosure we
know from research that when when they
were asked a majority that said that you
know they would like to coordinate and
to coordinate disclosure with a
corporation if they don't do it it's
because something went wanted went wrong
in terms of their expectations and we
also know that policies and disparities
in this empirical research again ii l
the policies that have more contact more
content actually attract more bugs so we
know there is a lot of impact to the way
a policy could be drafted in this regard
so what are we doing how we basically
fostering this tonight's game and how
are you operating as an industry in this
community to make that legal landscape
more solid and more innovative as the
research continues and as this economy
grows so this is one key document and
what I really would like you to alter
Michigan up that in this document that
it has actually to the Computer Crime
Commission at the DOJ so this is the
people that are really the experts on
the CFAA and DMCA are hacking provisions
and then July 2017 that this is why
after I started my research I already
had some research and some presentations
going out there and then in the OJ
published this work that really
complement in my work what they do here
is this saying when you are thinking
about what I'm going to be these
cultural programs policies so those
channels of communications that you need
to establish with the crowd to make sure
that when someone finds something they
are able to communicate with you
effectively they are able to report that
and they
they're able to find that and you're
handling that correctly when you're
thinking about establishing those
channels and we're when you are thinking
about establishing the bug bounty
program which is essentially a standard
phone contract it's a
take-it-or-leave-it contract that you
are putting on your website or if you're
using a platform
bug bug departments have you heard about
that concept that's the hacker one and
back routes of the world
absolutely so back bounty platforms are
basically market facilitators there are
plot there there there are companies
that are coordinating and sending up bug
bounties to allow companies to interact
with a crowd and they have their own set
of contracts as well at place so when
you are setting up those back bounties
and one ability discussion programs that
frameworks gives you a little overview
of what considerations especially from
the legal side you should be thinking
about now this is not binding this is
our accommodation this is just a list of
consideration it's only seven pages it's
pretty short
I encourage you to think about it I
encourage you to go to your put them to
employ or whatnot whoever you were
working with and tell them have you
thought about a vulnerability disclosure
program have you thought about
establishing that channel come in of
communication and when they're doing so
I encourage you to give them this
document it's really short again just
set seven pages and what we have in that
document are some key considerations for
example them to discuss on how you
should be describing what is the
authorized conduct and what is not
authorized in very plain language to
ensure that you have established that
communication is very clear and
establish those expectations and we
don't have any discrepancies or
conflicts or question marks to allow the
hackers and basically the researchers
that you're inviting to test your system
to basically follow the law moreover
they're talking about establishing bound
boundaries so one key element is what's
going around with
minimize your POC or proof of concept in
order to ensure that you are not putting
users data at risk how you minimize your
interactions with users data at all so
if you ever swap back bounty for example
you will often see a term staring saying
only use your own you use your
credentials your own dad I've never
interacted with the dialog of others
that is a very important element that
the Department of Justice kind of
clarifies and emphasized in that
document they also talked about this
approach of you have to be prepared you
have to be mature in order to to do this
kind of to have it place these kind of
programs and they either talk about the
legal language and the safe harbor
component that I just showed you with
respect to the authorization and
basically clarifying that we will not
pursue legal action against researchers
that are complying with the policy now
all of this is to say we are setting up
clear expectations and boundaries this
doesn't mean that you have an approval
to do whatever you want this suggests
that the document the bug bounty
contract it's a really important
document you should be reading carefully
because that sets the boundaries of the
Flores engine that we just talked about
if you remember when we talked about the
CFA yeah in the DMCA in the importance
of our ization in the context of anti
hacking laws in addition this document
also talks about scoping so in a bug
bounty you will often see a technical
scope which is important by the way if
you see a bug bounty without and scope
that should raise an a question mark
because this old notion of scope it's
basically what am i inviting you to test
and when you are preparing that scope
you need to know what's going around in
your scope in order to ensure that if
you are providing a post safe harbor
authorization you are actually in the
legal position to do so and you're not
authorizing
staying on other people's product so
this is this notion that you need to
consider what kind of components and
data you are putting in scope that might
implicate third party interest now you
also need to setup this according to the
Department of Justice according to this
document you also need to set
expectation then it comes to perfect
concept so what are you exactly
expecting from the crown when it comes
to the type of proof concept that they
are delivering to you where do you want
the crowd to stop
is it an exploit or what is the level of
kind of POC that you would like to see
from them to ensure that you are
protecting your users now these are some
of the considerations that you really
need to drill on and I mean one of my
key elements are main key messages to
everyone considering back parties out
there especially if this is a bug bounty
in which you are actively paying money
for research and inviting the justice
system do anything for the legal leaves
my prior work again that I've conducted
two years ago has showed multiple
programs in which there was no legal
part at all how many of us so there I
don't we don't have a lot of hunters
there but the hunters here might not be
surprised to hear that they probably saw
in the past a bug bounty with no legal
part at all because that was a phenomena
out there and I'm proud to say that you
know since then the market really
matured there is excellent work done by
DOJ another work that I'm going to share
with you here some more but it was it
was a thing so one of my key messages is
when even if if you're on hunter or if
you are program manager or if you're
considering anything along the lines
make sure that you consult your lawyer
because this has legal aspects that you
need to consider now this question by
the way is not just emerging here it's
also emerging in new york this is in
fact a very interesting document
prepared by CPS that's a task force that
reviewed all of the european computer
I'm landscape in the context of on
ability disclosure and what they
suggested is this issue of legal
liability due to some of the laws there
as well is a little bit murky and we
need to think as industry what we can do
in that regard
okay so again as I mentioned if you're
not familiar with my work again this
project you tell this song my prior work
I try to get industry to push industry
to to adopt more safe harbors and
basically standardize that landscape of
the legal language of both parties now
you all are familiar with standards how
many of you are familiar with open
source licenses right or Creative
Commons which is the general license
that we have in the copyright community
that allows access to work basically by
enabling the owner to use one contract
to waive some of their rights in the
creation will go the law default is
something else those type of license are
operating as a standard and because
there is one car one contract there are
many benefits that are associated with
that and I'm going to talk about that
but my main kind of focus area and that
in this work was actually to work with a
lot of companies again to foster the
adoption of these terms and one way that
I did that with the help of coin here
Ryan who is actually cyber con organizer
right or founder even though or not
absolutely
that's that's amazing is to create this
big of a bounty hunter orange reserved
only for companies that I know time
adopted a safe harbor okay what I also
did is to create this github repository
where I wanted to establish a language
that lawyers of companies can take a
look of course the you know people saw
their own legal advice but this we had
one
my standards that people can take a look
at and was informed by the Department of
Justice framework to consider when they
are drafting their mark on the policy
and I'm proud to say that you have
recently adopted this language and
created another fork of that language to
kind of better better situated the
language as this landscape develops and
again Dropbox also adopted this language
and the interesting thing here is that
we sued the crowd is that in and out so
Justin here Alan is a great guy as well
he says you know way to God Dropbox
adopting this policy I'm going to be
hunting on a program because of this now
since since I started this legal bug
bounty movement and stomach work I
collaborated with background to start
disclose I know disclose AO is another
physician project in which all of you
can take a look and check out their
language six to create one language for
bug bounty programs that is also
addressing this legal landscape issue
and it's open source you can all use it
they just in think that back pad also
did is incorporate disclosed i/o into
their filtering system so as a hunter if
you are professional hunter and you want
to take a look at programs that are that
have language that includes safe harbor
you can actually filter in their
platform for programs that have a safe
harbor I think that that's one of the
recommendations that I originally did in
my prior work and on in my larger paper
and they adopted it and I think it's a
great it's a great system and a great
tool I mean that this is a selection is
key because then we have one language
and we have one standard and this really
serves the benchmark and reduces the
information burden on the researchers or
in the crowd and raises awareness
towards decision and it also it gives us
transactional cost drastic costs right
because you need to consult a lawyer but
at least
we have something one language
certificate all quite a thing to agree
on now this type of work will actually
be key as we see that expansion of back
monkeys into new areas and new arenas
for example this Facebook's newly data
abuse program that is focusing on using
the bug bounty not to encounter security
flaws but to uncover privacy violations
in fact that can also share with you
guys that I'm a proud recipient of a 10
$10,000 $10,000 but not me alone me in
my quarters from UC Berkeley on a
privacy enhancing type of academic work
so as we are moving this backpack the
concept to new areas and your rayna's it
would be important to also look at the
legalese so finally and I'm about to
finish up I just want to put here on the
screen some research some basically
websites and some that points you can
all seek and look for if you're looking
for more information from the new jframe
work I also did a podcast with general
Baili again great expert on the CFAA
from the Department of Justice but we
only focused on issues of deep bug
bounty kind of legalese including the
interaction with extortion there is a
recent CFA indictment that involved
Linda subsidiaries did that in fact
involve the bug bounty and someone
coming to a party with an extortion at
CFA event it's a very interesting and
Agnes the first one that I'm aware of
that has an interaction with the CFA a
so that's another thing to take a look
at it if you want
and we discussed it a look at at the
post task that also puts you here the
links for that encourage you to take a
look at our standardization work
disclosed ago and little bug bounty and
if you want to see my prior work in this
area you can check out this paper
private ordering changing cycle it's
shaking cybersecurity I'm proud to say
that I did negotiate that take it a
liquid conflict with the publisher so
that paper is going to be free although
it's part of the book and it's
accessible to all on SSRN and with that
I'm gonna finish up this presentation
thank you so much and I hope you look
for more information in this area you
can always keep the conversation going
with me here's my handle in the Missouri
really appreciate you coming here today
you