[Music]
hello everyone
thanks for attending my talk i know it's
a remote presentation but i hope
you can still get the key idea of our
work
so the talk title is cloud leak dnn
model extraction from commercial mlas
platform so the presentation with the
should be provided by me
my students hong kong and my
collaborator tony ho
but due to all the technical issues and
the recent situation i will be the
person
who gives the main presentation
so first myself
i'm irjin an associate professor
and an iot term professor at the
university of florida
so i think you know a lot of hackers
you may not be very familiar to
professors so i list my research
interests
i'm also using this opportunity to
recruit
students if you want to do phd or master
in the in this area cyber security area
and we are also interested in iot and
cps security
as well as hardware security
my collaborator johnny ho he's a
professor
in the department of computer science in
national qinghua university
in taiwan so he's also the program man
director of taiwan's ministry of
science of technologies ai innovation
program
that's why we are working on ai
luckily we are not of
our collaboration uh
turned out to be very productive so
i hope we will continue this
collaboration
and the third speaker is hong kong i
will let him introduce himself
a good morning welcome to my talk
my name is hong kang yi and i am
currently a visiting phd student
working with dr yajin my main focus is
on the machine learning security
and besides i also doing some research
such as on the embedded system security
iot security and the machine learning
computing system design
today i'm going to talk about the
adulthood example based model staining
attack
and now my advisor dr yajin
will give you the full talk
okay so these are all the speakers
so let me quickly give you an outline of
what we will discuss
so i assume that many of you already
know ai
and ai security adversary example for
example
so that's why i would quickly go over
this background and then i would
introduce you
how the model extraction attack can be
applied
to those commercial platforms
in microsoft in phase plus plus in ibm
in google
in clarify all these platforms
so we will also discuss the potential
so first deep neural network
has been quite popular these days and
it's become deeper and deeper
so very in the original
implementation we have one layer then we
have multi-layer
and now we have deep convolutional
network neural network
the neural network is nothing new it's
been there for decades
but until recently there seems achieved
a great success
in all different areas such as voice
recognition
image recognition and
one main reason is that using the
dn we we're using more resource
so that we can get better
classification results and as a result
we can see that the parameters of a
typical dn structure
also increased from several thousand
to tens of millions
so this is also become one challenging
that in our work
if you want to steal a dn model you
needed to recover
millions of parameters it was deemed
impossible
so i would show you how we make it a big
possible
so before that let's take a look at the
application
of commercialize the deep neural network
okay so we have mainly two parts of them
in two
different markets one is we call the
machine learning as a service
so it's mainly deployed in the cloud
platform we're using a lot of
resource and the other is more or less
in the
like cell phone so it's become we are
using tensorflow lite
and these are all different areas so we
use them
on the cloud we're using them on the
cell phone so what we are focusing on
in our work is mainly focusing on the
machine learning as a service
so what is machine learning as a service
the idea is that someone as a supplier
they have a data set so
they using a training api which is
provided by cloud
instead of training locally they rely on
cloud resource so the cloud resource
would provide
the training api and the supplier would
put their data set
inside and do all the training and
eventually after the model had been
trained
the cloud will provide a prediction api
for users so user would put in a picture
for example they want to recognize
a flower what type of flower this is so
they give this flower
if you like fishing you will give a fish
picture
and for each query they will charge you
some money
so we know that for the data set
original data set is normally sensitive
data and
for the machine learning model it's a
black box
so eventually for this machine learning
as a service
they want to achieve two goals
first they can provide a very rich
prediction api
second they can provide the model
confidentiality
so this is the key idea
of the machine learning as a service
and it's become very popular because the
machine learning
as a service model can save the local
computation resource you don't need to
buy this expensive dnn servers
right that's why all almost all the
cloud
providers they have their service
machine learning
uh as a service we for example we list
microsoft
face plus plus ibm google uh
clarify all of them and
some of them provide a general purpose
machine learning model some of them
provide a dedicated machine learning
model for for example the clarify
their product is not safe for work they
are screening
images that whether you can view them at
work or not
some of them allow you to customize them
some of them already customize
everything for you
and but all of them are using black box
using neural network as a model and
they also uh
monetize them which means that you need
to pay for the service
i want to emphasize one thing is that
almost all these services provide you a
confidence score
it's actually very important for you to
extract the model
but in our attack
we can eliminate the use of confidence
score which means that we can rebuild
the conflict score so that's again
something we will emphasize later
so this is a black pet
i think everyone is thinking something
that whether i can hack something
now we have machine learning as a
service people are thinking that okay
how can i hack it so one typical hacking
is we call the model extraction or model
steering attack
so the key idea is that okay you put a
model at the black box
in the cloud and the model will generate
money because everyone will
query it and get the result but if i can
steal the model then i can put the model
in another cloud service
other people other users will be using
my model
and pay for that so if i can extract the
model
then i don't need to go through the
data set collection process i don't need
to
pay for the machine learning as a
service the cloud service
a lot of money to train the model for me
okay so you are not alone people already
started working on that
in the last decade here i just list the
fourth
interesting paper that
some of them would uh
provide you high accuracy of the
extraction model
but if you look into this table you
would realize that
if they want to extract the machine
learning model
with a large parameter size hundreds of
milli uh million parameters
their query will be also very high
so with a high query for example they
needed to a thousand
a hundred thousand times to query the
model
then the cost will be also very high
which means that
as a hacker if you needed to spend a lot
of money
in order to extract the model then you
would ask the question did
it really worth it
because with that amount of money you
can train the model by yourself
okay so still an unanswered question is
that
is that possible that take a very few
query
so there to reconstruct the model and
the asian ccs7 2017 paper give you
answer but
this answer is not perfect because
they're only using 7000
query but the reconstructed model have
very low accuracy
if that's the case then no one would use
it
okay so for a while people believe that
this is something that is not
easy or that's not worth it if you query
that
many times and
we look into the area the same area but
we look into the same
area from a different angle so now i
want to introduce you
another machine learning attack
a diverse example for those know
otherwise
example you were the
thinking that what's the linking between
model extraction
and adversary example for those
who may not know the diverse example i
have a quick example for you here
so the adversary example is trying to
leverage
the machine learning models intrinsic
vulnerability
that is you have one image the machine
learning model
would successfully clarify classified as
for example in this is a panda
right but if you adding some
perturbation
it's more like random noise from our raw
eye
so you generate another picture is the
third
uh panda image there but now if you give
this image to the machine learning model
they may tell you that it's a dog or
something else
so this is adversarial example and
the moment people notice that in fact
the adversary example
is way more popular than model
extraction attack
so people come up all different
solutions i mainly divided them into
non-feature based or feature based again
it's only my
kind of like a category so
here are some examples of a c and the w
attack you have the source image
you're trying to include some uh
perturbation
and you have the other virtual image so
the left figure
zero and the the plane is the source
image
and the write all three figure
are the adversary image so that if you
tell
ask the machine learning model to tell
you
what they are they will tell you this
number could be one could be two could
be seven
uh the plane could be any anything else
so and we also have feature based
so the idea is that you have a source
image
and you also have a guide image the key
idea is that the perturbation would be
carefully designed
so that the source image
plus the perturbation will become the
guide image
so for example the left bottom four
figures
the adverse example the pie will be
recognized
as another small animal here
so this is the key idea so okay now
the point in the what is a diverse
example from mathematical background
i sometimes allow to investigate
or study the mathematical background i
know many of you
using ai your job is just to adjust the
parameters
why bother the underlying
math right why we do ai is because we
don't want to do math that's why we do
ai
ai will provide the magic to solve all
the problems for us
so we don't need to learn the math but
my
focus is that okay what is the math
background of the adverse example
so here is a simple view step by step
let me show you what is a simplified
view of adverse example
so first you normally have a source
example the source image
the source image is to the right of the
bar
assuming that the bar is the boundary of
the machine learning model
so you would generate adding when you're
adding
perturbation you would generate a lot of
examples
and this green circle is still
legitimate example which means that
the perturbation is not large enough
so that the classification is still
correct
but the dark green circle is a bit
tricky
the perturbation is large enough
very large but still not large enough to
flip the
classification result but the confidence
score is already very low
and go further the red
triangle is the perfect at the first
example
they have high confidence but the class
classification results
are wrong or incorrect okay
so in normal adverse example we are
trying to
build this red triangle
so there to fool the system but in our
case
we realize that what is the really
useful
example for us is those
gray triangle and the dark green circle
are very close to the boundary
sometimes they are classified correctly
sometimes they are classified
wrongly but they all share the same
property that this classification will
give you very low
confidence so we noticed that if and a
diverse
example with a very low confidence
then the adverse example is
likely close to the boundary
that's why the classification will give
you very low confidence
so what we are doing is that if we don't
need to generate
all this example but we only generate a
low confidence example
so that we can quickly recover the
boundary
eventually what we want to recover is
the
boundary because the boundary defines
the model
okay so now you see the two links
that with the
at the you leveraging adversary example
we may be
able to extract the boundary at a very
low cost
because we're only using instead of
using randomly generated
queries we're only using this low
confidence
either legitimate example or otherwise
example
to query the blackbox model to identify
the boundary
so now another simple question comes
how to generate these boundary cases
with minimum confidence so we can
leverage all existing solutions
like all the
all this adverse example method can be
leveraged
in fact we come up with a new solution
just the one
on top of that we call the feature full
so this is
more like a dedicated solution to help
uh generate the adversary example
close to a boundary so the math is
here feel free to read us through them
and
i always encourage people doing ai to
read this mess
it's actually very simple it's just the
key idea is that minimize the distance
to the boundary minimize
the confidence score
so a visualization visualize the
process is shown here so step one
is that we get the source image and we
get to the guide image and we have the
adversary perturbation
so we extract the features right after
we extract the features
and we start to compute the class uh
salience map
right to decide uh what a point we
needed to adjust
in order to make the adversary example
all the
legitimate example close to the boundary
and
then we optimize the
perturbation and do the optimization
again
and do this loop from feature extraction
to salient feature and to the
box constrained bfgs optimization
so this is a a process so eventually
we would generate a set of data for
training so
here are three different examples
so let's just take a look at the left
bottom corner we have three
images here the first image is a
general in image the source image so the
classification with a correctly
classified it's as the
neutral
and neutral phase and the confidence
is 99 percent which is very high
confidence
right and we also have under the second
picture is a guided picture
it's a happy face and the classifier
will tell you that it's 98
percent of uh confidence
the third image is the image that we
are working on if you are just trying to
develop
an adverse example then we need a third
image
is based on the neutral phase will be
classified as
happy phase with very high confidence
score
that's a very successful adversary
attack but for our case
we want is
it's been classified either as correctly
as neutral
or incorrectly as a happy phase but
the confidence score is only one percent
very low
because this image and all the third
column
on this three set of image in those
i would just call them the bad adverse
example with a very low confidence score
but a very good example for our boundary
extraction okay
now we prepared everything so it's the
job
to
do our model stealing attack
okay so the approach is that
first
we using all the adversary we're using
the feature full method to generate
all the adversary
examples with low confidence and then
we would query the machine learning as a
service model in the cloud
using this adversary example and we
generated
their ex their response
we only needed from the cloud that we
only needed the classification results
and then using this result
we would take a candidate library we
call the model zoo
it's an existing machine learning model
and we're using the cloud query result
to change our own model
and this becomes a steal the model
so this is just a high level
let's take a look at the real example so
what we do is that first
we have two sets of data one is
genuine domain data which is just the
not adverse example or not being
modified
we also have malicious domain data these
are
data being modified very close to the
boundary
will be classified correctly or
incorrectly
so while we still need the traveling
domain data
remember that we are targeting the
machine learning model on the cloud as a
fully black box
we don't even know what kind of label
they would provide us
so the journaling domain data is mainly
to query the
the machine learning model service to
extract
what kind of labels they will provide
and the malicious domain image
or the data set will be used to extract
the boundary
so you see in order to extract a fully
black box
learn machine learning model we need to
know what is the functionality of that
what kind of label it will provide
and then what boundary they are
and then all the query the data
become a synthetic data set
we call the stolen labels and
then we have our own machine learning
model locally
this model have multiple layers some of
the layers are reused layer which is
already fixed
some of the layers are retrained the
layer and
normally the return the layer is at the
end of the machine learning
models and then
we train we're using our synthetic data
set
to train this model eventually to change
the
last few layers in our case we normally
train the last two layers or sometimes
one layer
a full connector layer so in that way
we generate a model and this model
would be very
would have very similar behavior with
the machine learning model
in the cloud okay so this is the thing
so for example using a motion
classification
so what we do is that we first
choose a local model say vgg phase
and then we are generating a collected
images relevant to the classification
problem
for the we call the relevance uh
relevant query
and then we currently learning model
and then we train the local model to
replace
the remote machine learning model
so now a few questions
i guess you may have so i can answer in
before
in front first what kind of local model
you need to use
the answer is that you can using any
local model
which means that in the cloud
server they have a face recognition
locally you can using any local model
a car plate recognition model for
example
but if the local model is slightly
relevant to the remote model
the performance will be the best
so if you know i think you kind of have
some idea
if the the overall goal of the remote
model if they are like a recognized
face then the local model you'd better
choose something
like a face recognition if the
remote model is classified the flower
the local model better is related to
flower
this is public information and that will
increase
again you can use any other models as
the local model
but a relevant model would increase the
successful rate
okay so that's one thing the second
thing people are
asking that how can you generate
the low confidence
malicious state image because
even though the cloud will provide you
the low confidence
the confidence score we don't use that
but how do you know that because you
don't
you have not extracted remote model
this is an another very interesting
example we called
much adversary example transfer learning
again a diverse example is one attack
transfer learning another attack
this can combine together so the key
idea here
is that the boundary in the local model
a similar model is very similar to the
boundary of a remote model
which means that any two machine
learning model
as far as they are classifying similar
image or similar
items their boundaries are similar
we are working on don't worry don't ask
more questions at this moment
we are working on the mathematical proof
for that now
no one have proved that many people
notice that
so now let's take a look at the
experimental results
say we're using the microsoft service
and
we're using their traffic machine
learning model and
the flower classification model so
you see that we only query a few hundred
times or at most
2000 times and the price is
only a few like dollars
and we can achieve very high accuracy in
fact if we
query like 2000 times
which costs us two dollars or seven
dollars
in the two uh data set our feature full
is ff means our feature full based
extraction attack cw is cw based
feature model extraction attack again
our
model extraction attack we can using all
existing adversary example generation
method
it can achieve uh 76
accuracy and 88 percent accuracy
or even 89 using cw this
value is already very close
to the original modules accuracy so we
using 2000
query we can fully recover that
so if you want to compare our method
with the previous
method we eventually leveraging the
another adversary example case we can
extract parameters around the 200
million parameter size machine learning
a deep neural network model
with only three salt in the query and we
can get a very high accuracy
and the steel cost is very low
so i think i'm running out of time
just a quick defense so so far i have to
say that
in academia we have developed some
defense
but in the machine learning model in the
in the cloud
environment the defense is not
there yet so some of the defense is
mostly trying to identify the input
so in our case we can easily adjust our
parameter to evade those detections so i
don't want to go deep in that i would
because
people would argue that it's only one
defense how about other defense but
overall
our claim is that so far the defendant
no work
and even worse for this inefficient
defense the machine learning model in
the cloud has not applied them yet
right so as a quick conclusion here
that
we have proved that different
machine learning attacks can be combined
to become an even more powerful machine
learning attack
so so far i have discussed in our
work we combine the three technique
model extraction adverse example
transfer learning okay so if you don't
really know this concept
precisely uh just a check google it
so and these three attacks
will develop kind of independently for
different
on the different thread model
and we proved that this thread model
all these attack vectors can be combined
together
to become even more powerful
attacks so now i hope
that including to my students on myself
we want to understand more of the
mathematical background
of all these phenomenon
because so far we are using machine
learning model more or less
like okay it's a black box i don't know
why it's work
and if it's working i don't care right
but it's actually leave a kind of like
a big miner for the hackers
so this my talk is just one example and
i'm sure that a lot of ai attack example
will be coming out
and there will be different combination
of different technique
and the funny thing is that for the
defender for the ai developer
they don't know why their method works
so they don't know why the attacker
works either
from a text perspective we are most of
attacks are also in
blind we don't know why transfer
learning will work
or why adverse examples work but we just
combine them together and to make it
work even better
our goal is that can we explain the
situation can we explain the
mathematical background
why it doesn't work or why it doesn't
work okay
so and in the future we are also very
interested
uh in extracting the model from ai chips
and ai accelerators which are
embedded in our computer in our cell
phone
and we are using this method and with
the combination
of uh hardware outside the channel
we have some work trying to measure the
em electromagnetic
emissions so that we can tell you what
happened inside the ai chip
so that we can rebuild the ai chip okay
so
again this is a black hat talk so i'm
focusing more on the hacking side
if you are interested we can work
together to come up
with stronger defense okay
uh thanks for attending my talk so i
think i still have a few minutes for
questions
yeah thanks for attending my talk so i'm
looking forward to
any questions
yes actually i already answered some
questions during the presentation
i mean this question are great
so one last thing uh i think there is
one comment not a really requesting from
eric is so it seems very difficult
to develop the defense which are
universal
um like uh work both
uh so the the the final conclusion we
have is
actually the opposite way a lot of
attack
with the universally working on
different ai models
but the defense seems quite ad hoc
so there are two very interesting
research directions
here beyond the developing of the
virtual example
one is how we can mathematically
understand
that why this attack with the universal
work
right why this boundary will be similar
second
would be how we can combine all these
other hawk defense together
uh well i'm talking i do see a few
question
uh comments here so
uh one one comment is
uh how can we look into the
triple wise for
this kind of model extraction attack it
is our work
uh in fact we are a bit concerned
to perform this task because we know
that
the chip manufacturing they spend so
much effort in developing ai chips
they want to keep all the secure secret
and we don't we have no desire
to kind of like steal their ip
but we still want to see whether
leveraging this kind of like
a model extraction attack along with all
other for example side channel attack we
can extract
the internal of this we call it ai
accelerators
internal structure and our goal
is as a researcher our goal is to make
them more secure
rather than just to hack them but if we
hack something we will present
in blackheads
so where can we oh the white paper
uh you should ask a blackhead because
i did submit the white paper to
blackhead
but yes folk mentioned the
ndss paper that paper actually including
more technical details
yes
okay so i guess we need to wait for
a couple of minutes to see if there are
an other questions
so okay so
uh one thing uh uh i would encourage
people to look into
is trying to i think the other other
talk i i glossed over
other uh talks afternoon there is
another talk
uh mentioning that how we leverage the
adverse example for the effect
this is a very interesting area so
uh we know that a diverse example is
prevailingly available in all this
design so now the question becomes how
we can leverage it
instead of attacking them to protect the
system and also
using this for uh like watermark
fingerprinting
uh i would say these are all very
interesting area
so overall the key motivation
of our work is that we want to help
people
better understanding the security of ai
before we widely use the ai
and the ai has been applied in almost
all different areas and the security i
i know that the security as a hacker so
we are so happy that
people are using different ai so that we
can hack in all different system
uh like in 1990 or 2000 that we're
hacking all the operating system
but i hope that we will not go in the
same old route
that we develop a lot of system on
secure system
and we're hacking all of them to ask
people to uh
kind of fix those problems we hope that
we can
build a security insight
okay so again thanks for attending my
talk and
please feel free to send me email if you
have any questions
my contact information is on the slides
on the white paper and you can easily
search my name and
find my web page we do hire a recruiting
postdoors phd students who are
interested in this area
okay okay thanks