[Music]
thanks for joining me
this is decade of the rats custom
chinese linux rootkits for everyone
i'm kevin levelli director of threat
intelligence at blackberry
now i realize i'm dressed like a lawyer
today and i've been told i look like a
lawyer
but i'm not one so be sure to note the
fine print here
written by actual lawyers and understand
that i'm speaking for myself today
not my employer and before i go any
further
i do want to say a few words of thanks
first to the black hat review board
thanks for inviting me to speak to the
current leadership at blackberry
thank you for the continued opportunity
to do research like this
to anthony freed thanks for getting it
out the door
to the past leaders of the research
department at silence where i started
especially john miller ryan smith and
tom wabashevitz
and jeff tang and the current members of
the applied research team
thanks for your encouragement your
guidance and your support
finally to the person who conducted this
research with me but who wishes to
remain anonymous
researcher x you deserve the largest
measure of thanks
you're one hell of a teammate and that's
rather important given that threaten
tell
is a team effort thanks man
you know that team approach to security
research is worth dwelling on here for a
minute
because no matter where i've gone in my
career i found that a group that's
comprised of people who think
differently
conducts better investigations and gets
better outcomes
that was certainly true of my time in
new york city where i supervised an
investigative squad
at the nation's largest independent and
civilian police oversight agency
a pursuit that seems rather timely these
days
and investigative journalism is also a
team effort
and prior to my time as director of
threat intelligence at blackberry i
filled that role at 60 minutes
tip of the hat here to one of my former
colleagues freelance director of
photography chris albert
who's shooting this right now thanks
brother
now don't worry this talk won't last 60
minutes
it'll only be half as long and before
that time is up
all of you watching at home should come
away with an appreciation for why all my
time in journalism was spent
behind the camera okay chris back up man
nobody wants to see that
you know threat intelligence and
investigative journalism have more in
common
than perhaps you realize and at the risk
of falling into another talk track
already
i'll simply point out three important
areas of overlap because i think it
might help us today
first both are focused on finding hidden
truths
emphasis unhidden second both only work
when people pay attention to them
that is when they result in interesting
narratives ones that make sense of a web
of complex
and arcane and often boring detail
and finally and most importantly both
are motivated by the search for answers
to critical questions so that's what i'm
going to do now
i'm going to pose some key questions
that motivated us
and bring you along on the journey we
took to find the answers
now spoiler alert not every question has
an answer
but instead of wasting your time
explaining things you already know
like how root kits and backdoors
function which i kind of think of is
merely
lifting the hood to gawk at an engine
i'm going to try to impart something i
find more valuable
and no it's not a list of iocs for your
threat intel feed
though i can help you with that if
that's what you're here for
instead i hope to leave you with some
concrete examples of how
to think more critically about how we do
malware analysis
and i'll try to show you how to spot
your own cognitive bias while in the
midst of your research
briefly put i'll show you examples of
how to question your own findings
and how to question your own thinking
now doing both of those things should
help make the overall intelligence
products
that we all create better and more
meaningful
all right so let's begin with the first
question the reason we're all here
that is what exactly did we find
well to begin with we've found a whole
lot of linux malware that's been sitting
unnoticed for a very long time we
started by doing something that i feel
doesn't always happen
in today's infosec community that is too
often focused solely on what's new and
what's next
that is we look behind us
you're sitting down to check on some old
apt activity
and you turn up a new backdoor that
nobody's seen before
and then imagine pulling on that thread
and finding a rootkit
and then bam a whole stack of linux
malware
and it's compiled dynamically and it's
customizable to targets
and then later imagine finding that this
malware is being shared among a splinter
cell
of five different groups that you've
been tracking separately as distinct
chinese apts
but when you look deeper you find
they're all really just derivatives of
the original
when nti group air quotes here
included in these five are vestiges of
the original
kaspersky lab defined when nti group
such as it is these days
but also groups like bronze union better
known to some of you as
apt 27 or emissary panda
a group called pascv a group microsoft
calls lead and which we track as casper
and an emerging group that we're
tracking as win linux splinter
now i'm going to return and untangle
that messy air quoted when nti
attribution statement
a bit later but for now let's get back
to what was in the linux toolset
all right we essentially found six
things
number one there was an installer script
it took a few parameters as arguments
and it was nicely compressed inside of
another script
now this installer script interacted
with a remote build server that was so
easy to use
my seven-year-old can install this
malware in a matter of minutes
just follow the prompts answer a few
simple questions and voila
custom chinese root kits for everyone
the build server item number two on this
list was
to be more precise online only in some
cases
and others it was local to the target
either way though the build server would
custom compile the malware package for
the target
on the fly and then it would be
downloaded to the victim
it's as if attackers were showing off
their best practices for ci
cd you know continuous integration and
continuous delivery
the custom delivery package consisted of
a root kit
a back door complete with an
installation script for the target we're
going to call those items
three and four then there was a bonus
item
number five on the list an attacker
control panel
capable of managing both windows and
linux targets simultaneously
which had its own graphical user
interface another easy button for
attackers
you can see it here next to the list and
finally there was item number six
a botnet better known to the community
as the linux
xor ddos botnet of 2015 fame
and yeah i'm really saying that we
believe winning ti
is responsible for the original linux
xor ddos botnet
more on that later now on the c2 side
we saw a lot of the usual win nti
behavior
but with one or two distinctions worth
mentioning
first among the hard-coded network
callback data
we saw some 10 dot ips some
not all this suggested that there was at
least some command and control
infrastructure
inside the target organization now if
you're a network defender and you wake
up and see that
it's not going to be a good day right
not a welcome sign
indeed it's highly likely that all the
linux malware that we found
was not first stage malware but rather a
persistence tool
a beachhead if you would and that the
compromise of the targets
ran much deeper and was much more well
established
what else did we find we also saw
extensive abuse of legitimate cloud
provider infrastructure
this continues to be a really worrisome
trend that we're tracking
one which dramatically complicates
historical analysis
most of the time oh and by the way we
didn't just find linux malware
you know too often i feel that security
research is focused too narrowly on one
thing
researchers tend to tell us only about
the malware on one platform that they
find
or that they know exists and it's
usually out of context
i mean geopolitical context yeah but
also technical context
if they'd only widen the lens they'd see
that state-backed attackers
almost always target multiple platforms
and that provides some key context
this time we found some of the same
group of attackers
in command of some android malware and
others wielding some windows
malware i'll talk about both today
though i won't say a ton about that
malware here we did write a detailed
white paper that i'll reference in the
last slide
that you can go read if you want to know
more
all right so back to the original
question what did we find
short answer we found an excellent
vantage point on an entire malware suite
and good evidence of a cross-platform
approach to espionage
okay now on to the second question
why is it that now in the year of the
rat we've only just uncovered these rats
the linux versions of which have likely
been out there for nearly a decade
i mean it's not like we don't know this
kind of malware exists
linux malware in the hands of
government-backed groups has been
written about before
kaspersky lab has documented its use by
the russian terla and american equation
group
and among the chinese groups we've seen
research on leviathan or abt40
axiom deep panda and apt41
now there's some more messy when nti
related attribution questions in there
in that laundry list and if you read and
believe intrusion truth
they've done some interesting work to
try to detangle it but you know that's a
tangent i don't want to digress
you know i think as recently as may our
colleagues at chronicle published some
interesting research on ipt41
that's another group we associate with
one nti on their use of linux malware
that even included info about an lcam
rootkit
and the write-ups are there not in great
numbers
but they exist the point here is that we
should be watching for this kind of
thing no
and what about the explosion of av
vendors that we've seen develop in the
last 10 years
if we were all in vegas right now we'd
be steps away from the floor show
where most of the companies in the epp
or edr market
would be carnival barking and luring you
in with swag
so they could show off the latest in
their advanced fill in your buzzwords
here technology
no one can claim there haven't been many
bites at the apple
so what gives let's consider some
possibilities
which may in turn give us some insight
into the attackers in their strategy
now we use that word strategy here
because our conclusion was that the
targeting of these linux servers
was strategic in nature now first
i don't have to tell anybody in this
audience why the always-on
always-available nature of linux makes
it a great beachhead
i mean how often do you take off your
web server or your database server how
often do you take those down
is it is it somewhere in the
neighborhood of never
i don't have to tell you that linuxrun
servers constitute critical
infrastructure within the government
agencies and businesses
that make up modern society linux runs
not just web servers and database
servers
but also proxy servers file servers vpn
help stock exchange servers it's
embedded in iot
it's embedded in network appliances it's
embedded in cars
and i don't have to point out to this
audience that linux run
web servers are perfect for hiding
massive amounts of exfiltrated data
or that attacking linux jump boxes
erases a key layer of protection for an
organization
or that linux database servers offer
attackers pretty much
one-stop shopping for crown jewels
material like passwords or
trade secrets or other intellectual
property
but think for a minute about the people
who've never seen the inside of a rack
room
what about the people who sign the
paychecks or make the big decisions
how often does the word linux enter
their conversations
second for those of us who've had the
opportunity to work for vendors
tell me how do your epp and edr
offerings for linux
compare to your offerings for mac and
windows
put it this way how many linux deals
does your sales team close
i'm willing to wager that in general
security industry support
of the myriad linux distro and kernel
combinations pales in comparison to the
support given to windows
it's just economics you supply the
engineering
and marketing and sales effort behind
the platform that creates the most
demand
but a consequence of that is that
detection of linux malware
particularly complicated malware like we
found might turn out to be bad
third for those linux enthusiasts out
there and i know you're out there
i think it's fair to say that linux is
generally thought of or assumed to be
more secure due in part to its open
source nature
fair enough but remember openssl
heartbleed it was there too in front of
millions of eyes and no one saw it
in this case i can tell you that
analysts who study chinese espionage
more broadly
say that chapter one of the playbook is
the exceptional exploitation of
open source material so it's not too
hard to see
how groups that we assessed to be
engaged in espionage and the interests
of the chinese government
have taken full advantage of the fact
that they can create malware for an
operating system
whose source code is an open book now
even if these three possible
explanations for the low detection rate
fail or fall apart there remains one
more explanation
inherent to the malware itself that is
the whole stack revolves around custom
kernel-level rootkits and rootkits of
course are designed to be hard to detect
now i realize rootkits are old-school
sort of a relic
or a paradigm from an earlier age of
infosec
today most attackers tend to just live
off the land right or hide in the noise
and really effective tools are often
just publicly available for apts to use
and they do use them to devastating
effect thanks pentesters
while other custom tools tend to last a
year or two before they're burned
however here's where challenging your
own way of thinking pays off
if you think root kits are old news you
won't build products to detect them
and you won't expect to find them and
that impacts the way you do your
analysis
keep in mind here what ought to be
another maxim of infosec everything old
eventually becomes new again any
convincing
think about macros just from reading
public security research i can tell you
that they used to be a big deal
then they went away and now they're back
again email attachments
huge problem and not so much now it's a
thorn in everyone's side again
same with rootkits perhaps reading these
research papers you thought they went
out of style
but when they're running on the kernel
side of multiple linux distro kernel
combinations
they're going to work whether it's the
year the rat or the year of the dragon
okay they've got survival skills even
bear grylls with envy
all right so let's take a closer look at
them we found two variants
both of them lkm's designed to work with
an associated backdoor
we saw them tailored for kernel versions
2 and 3
but with up-to-date c2 so we knew they
were still in use
this older kernel version targeting by
the way is likely a reflection of the
fact
that many linux sysadmins are just slow
to update for various reasons
we found examples of malware that
targeted red hat enterprise
sentos ubuntu and debian but it's a good
bet
given their custom nature and on-the-fly
compilation that there are others out
there
who knows maybe some of you have found
them or can help uncover some more
vt scoring on them at the time of
discovery was at or near zero
the first one we found looked like it
had code lifted right out of somebody's
book
namely ivan skylarov's programming linux
hacker tools
uncovered sorry ivan while the second
rootkit we found
looked like it was just a modified
version of the open source sudorusu
rootkit
more plagiarism i mean open source
exploitation now as i said earlier the
rootkit was installed
via a bash script we found it inside
another shell script while looking at
backdoor callback data
the script communicated to one of two
servers depending on whether the target
had a 32-bit or a 64-bit cpu
architecture
the script prompted the attacker for a
username a build
and something called force mode option
it checked to see if malware already
existed for the target distro kernel
version
force mode would force the build server
to ignore an existing build for a given
kernel
if one existed and rebuild the root kit
you'll notice here that it calls itself
lancer version two
we never found version one or version
three or anything later
now here you're looking at the path
names and the various build environments
that we found
the first three you see here were all
reaching out to a remote server
and they delivered the root kit not just
by md5 hash but by username as well
and hey check out those usernames i'd
like to stop and
give a shout out here to yang and mao
mao
and uh he he i'm sorry we interrupted
your work
though i'm sure we didn't set you back
for too long you had a good run anyway
each of these users had a customized
environment configured
that would use his or her predefined c2
servers
while compiling and delivering the
backdoor package
okay now these pathways you're looking
at here
all pertain to build environments that
were local on the target already
don't ask me how they got there i don't
know but they delivered the same result
custom root kit and back door for each
target
now you want to find even more of this
splinter cells handiwork
beyond what i'm presenting today here's
something you won't read about on our
white paper
the build server provided another really
interesting nugget
while down on those weeds we realized
that the domain names
contained in the installation script
both had the number 3389 in them
as you see here and that rang a bell
because it was very similar to another
historic past cv domain
with the same number in it namely
3389.hk
using that we were then able to identify
new hosts using similar subdomains
which resolved to these ip addresses
here
they both used a relatively unique http
server bigos server 1.6.0
now at the time we put all this together
there are only like 20 servers on the
internet
running the same software okay happy
hunting everybody
now what all this demonstrates is that
the attackers
and remember there were multiple apt
groups involved here the attackers took
a lot of time to set this up
establish a foothold on the target
devise a way to quickly compile
sophisticated malware for multiple
combinations of linux distributions and
kernel versions
and then readily install them that's a
lot of love
and attention and development and time
and testing and refinement and overall
ref
overall effort required to keep it all
going you know and on top of that you
know you got taking care of the kids and
grocery shopping and walking the dog and
you know
covet 19 to deal with
now earlier i mentioned something about
a botnet and promise to answer what is
now our third motivating question
is win nti responsible for the creation
of the largest known linux ddos botnet
well the short answer is yes and by that
i mean
we judge that the original botnet was
developed by when nti group
now these are intelligence assessments
okay not edicts carved in stone
nevertheless our confidence level is
high
so how do we make that connection and
what does it tell us
again let's start by looking back as a
reminder
linux xor ddos was discovered i believe
by malware mustai
in 2014. akamai wrote a lot about it
and told us about its high bandwidth
attacks which ranged up to like 150 gigs
per second
notably they said that the botnet spread
by using brute force
shhh attacks to get creds for target
servers
yeah apparently that still works i guess
nobody likes exponential back off or
failed to ban or just changing port 22.
anyway here's another example of
something old becoming new again
now akamai said that they saw about 20
targets hit each day this is back in
2015.
20 targets hit each day with the
overwhelming majority like more than 90
percent
in asia and at the top of the list we're
video game companies
now that sounds like win nti right there
doesn't it
if you remember the 2013 seminal
kaspersky lab report on win nti group
was called more than just a game because
it drew a connection from the group's
infamous criminal targeting
of video game companies to their
espionage activities and other verticals
now the five apt groups that we were
tracking also engaged in both historical
and active targeting of video game
companies
but were there more concrete connections
the answer again is yes
when we discovered our first backdoor we
noticed that it used a certain device
for rootkit functionality
the botnet used the exact same device
with the exact same name
next we noticed that early samples of
the backdoor that we found
used a particular string as an xor key
to obscure network traffic
the botnet used the exact same string
for the exact same purpose
then we noticed that both the root kit
that came with the back door and the
botnet
were based on pretty much the same
modifications of the open source
sudarusi rootkit
in a write-up by avast on the botnet's
rootkit
they pointed out that for the kernel
modules to work its vermagic value
needed to match the kernel version on
the target in other words the malware
would not work
unless the kernel versions and the
kernel modules matched
just like we saw with the rootkits we
found and when we looked at the way that
the botnet
interacted with its build server we saw
very familiar interactive prompts
username kernel version and so on as you
can see here
so given the age of the botnet the code
reuse
the xor key overlap the same
customization and similar interaction
with the build environment
not to mention the same targeting all
that led us to assess that the botnet
was likely created by the same group
but what did they do with it i mean how
useful is that for espionage
strangely what we didn't see when
looking into all of this
and combing through the flurry of
coverage about this botnet was really
much indication that anyone
had actually been knocked offline or
denied service now i mean i'm
sure it happened but it wasn't grabbing
headlines
not at least as far as i could see and
not in a way that you might expect given
how much firepower this thing had at the
time
so that begs another question why build
a ddos botnet
if you don't use it to ddos
well here's one of those places where
the trail of evidence that we can point
to
goes cold and we can only speculate
was our collective perception of the
botnet as a denial of service tool
reflective of reality was it there to
disrupt video game companies for some
reason
or can botnets be used as a tool of
espionage
if only to deliberately misdirect
forensic analysis and research
was it perhaps just a means of quickly
and efficiently gaining a foothold
to collect code signing certificates or
could it have been used to gain access
to the primary espionage target servers
and install the recruits we found
perhaps the answer to all these
questions is yes
wouldn't that be something kind of makes
you wonder what other aspects of malware
analysis
may be subject to the same narrow
thinking take for example
the use of mobile malware by state or
state-backed groups more generally
now in previous research we've shown
that groups acting in the interest of
governments
have been integrating mobile malware
into their espionage campaigns
for a decade or more this is another
area
where attackers have enjoyed a huge jump
on the security industry's response by
the way
given that epp and edr capabilities for
mobile phones
are still in their infancy and again
while public-facing research about
mobile malware is certainly there
in my opinion it's been scattershot at
best and maladroit at worst
and what i mean by that is that it's
almost never put in the context of
campaigns that
integrate other forms of malware on
other platforms
so as a result of our collective narrow
focus and poor av coverage
apt groups have been able to exploit the
mobile space with
pretty much near impunity for quite some
time
all right let's get back to it let me
follow my own advice now and widen the
lens
the interesting questions that motivated
us during our research didn't just arise
in analyzing linux malware
they came up elsewhere too and the most
intriguing question to arise on our
examination of the android malware
was this one is a chinese apt group
behind the development
of one of the most widely used
commercially available rats
let's see if we can find out all right
taking one of the linux splinter cell
members a group blue coat first named
pass cv and about which we've published
some previous research
we followed a c2 trail and found some
domain crossover which led to our sample
a file that had the the string wave
dancer in it
and as we took it apart it looked like
it might just be a test the giveaway was
it had strings in it that said
test and it hadn't been touched in like
five years
now parsing some xml strings coughed up
some c2
which led to dual domain which led to a
domain that was registered by the same
email address
as had been used in lots of other past
cv work we've been following so
we could tie the sample that we'd found
with confidence to a win nti group
but it was the guts of this malware that
turned up something that we didn't
expect
after decompiling the code of the
implant we saw structural
structural layouts and huge swaths of
code that appeared to match identically
with the android version of a tool
called
netwire now systems administrators and
pen testers will know netwire
as a multi-platform commercial
off-the-shelf rat
you can license from a company called
world wired labs
for lots of purposes including quote
even monitoring your children at home
as they hopefully tell us on their
website probably not a great selling
point during the covet 19 lockdown
though
anyway many of you watching will also
recognize netwire as yet another one of
the publicly available remote support
tools that have been
picked up and co-opted by criminals and
government-backed groups to steal and to
spy now of course that is not
worldwide lab's fault right tools don't
hack targets people
people hack targets
given all that at first we thought hey
what's the big deal you know apt groups
use and abuse
publicly available tools like this all
the time right passive
probably just picked it up and put it
into rotation right
well here's where things got a little
strange look at this timeline
the last modified date on the past cv
implant was june 16
2015 but the first public announcement
by worldwide labs
about forthcoming support for the
android os was made on january
2nd 2017 that's nearly 18 months
after pascv's implant was last modified
a second network announcement was made
in march of that year indicating the
android release was going to be delayed
and finally netwire version 1.7 a
was released on march 23rd of 2017
marking the first public release of the
android host that's nearly
two years after the past cv malware was
created
so how do you explain that is a chinese
espionage group
behind the netwire tool well the truth
is
we just don't know i mean i can think of
more than half a dozen
possible explanations for this but i'm
not going to subject you to that here
okay now rest assured we did try to find
similar samples to help clear it up we
tried hard but we came up empty-handed
why is that well maybe the past cv
implant was highly targeted
or maybe it was really just a test that
leaked or maybe pascv abandoned the
implants for some reason
or maybe google did a bang-up job of
keeping it out of the play store
or maybe we just don't detect it or
didn't anyway in 2015.
if any of you have seen samples that fit
the description i'd love to know please
reach out
now we could go on like this posing and
answering questions about the last leg
of our research the windows malware
but there's going to be plenty of
windows malware discussed in other
sessions probably right
and i want to use the rest of our time
here wisely so
let me just highlight one thing and that
is
we saw a notable shift from the typical
winning tip behavior with these droppers
that we found
students of win nti know that one of
their hallmarks is the use of code
signing certificates
stolen from video game companies here we
saw that with all the groups we tracked
but they now also included certs taken
from adware companies why would they do
that
because adware is boring and alert
fatigue
is real when nti is betting
correctly that network defenders and
security researchers who find their
adware
will put it at the bottom of their list
of priorities or ignore it all together
i mean the fact that this small change
okay there was a there was a new packer
there too right but this small change
helped put some
20 year old rats that we should all know
about and stop like
ghost rat pass the majority of avs when
we ran them i think
the the the graphic here will show eight
that tells you just how deeply ingrained
that cognitive bias has become
all right let's move on throughout this
talk i've said that the activity that we
tracked was the work of five separate
groups
that derived from the original win nti
group and i put
win nti in air quotes why did i do that
and when you encounter win nti in the
press or in research
how should you understand it what does
that name even mean
and what does this research tell us
about that threat actor
my opinion is that when nti has come to
represent more of an approach
rather than a moniker for any single
crew right it was a back door then it
was a group
then it was an umbrella now it's an
approach my view
is that it represents a way in which a
group of what are probably civilian
contractors
is assembled tools are shared and
targets are split up
now the tools and infrastructure favored
by each cell or group differs
but sharing is happening to a greater or
lesser extent
so for example with the linux malware it
was the tools that were shared
but with the android malware it was the
infrastructure that was shared
in general all this sharing suggests
either that the contractor community in
china regards sharing favorably and
tolerates it openly
unlike elsewhere or that members travel
between shops over time
or groups of them break off to form new
ones or both
now it's also possible that the
government which we assess to be their
likely customer
provides something in the way of support
perhaps giving out tools
in some formal fashion fireeye wrote
about this concept and called it a
digital quartermaster
it's possible here but i think it's the
least likely scenario
the use of stolen code signing
certificates typically from video game
companies but
as we've just pointed out today also now
from adword companies
is probably the easiest common
denominator to identify across these
groups
but there's more to it than that
kaspersky researchers really did well
to illuminate the common criminal
ancestry of the original when nti group
for us in their seminal report
that financially driven criminal
approach is really worth pausing and
thinking about
because it tends to run counter to the
type of behavior we normally associate
with government-backed groups engaged in
traditional espionage with the north
korean groups
sort of a notable exception in this case
the criminal approach has colored the
original group's descendants
all these years later particularly in
their wide and voluminous targeting
from a distance it looks like spray and
but as i've demonstrated it's almost
always done with much more strategic
intent
now pretty much all the groups that i
mentioned today past cv
when nti group lead casper bronze union
they've all been discussed in other
public security research
whether these groups were actively
collaborating casually sharing
comprised of some of the same members or
in actuality were just
smaller parts of some larger group it's
beyond our means of analysis i'm
we're not a government but one thing is
clear
this isn't a single crew with a
one-trick pony
we are looking at a long-standing
well-thought-out
richly resourced intelligence collection
operation with a sizeable software
engineering team
to build and maintain all these tools
when nti then
is really a way to combine a team that
collects code signing certificates
and a team that puts malware on the
target and a team that creates and
manages the build environments
and a team that works up the mobile
malware and targeting
and a dev team for linux and a dev team
for windows
and another for android and you gotta
believe another for ios
all that is behind the air quoted when
nti threat actor
okay i'm afraid we've arrived at the end
of our time together
hopefully you've come away with some
understanding as to why the old story of
chinese espionage and ip theft
which everybody practically knows by
heart by now and is sick of hearing
about
is still surprising us with new chapters
hopefully you've learned that when nti
isn't more than just a game as kaspersky
lab taught us all those years ago
it's now more than just a name hopefully
you've seen that even from a handful of
l-files we can infer
a strategic approach hopefully i've
demonstrated
that rigid thinking inevitably leads to
rigid malware analysis
and inaccurate conclusions
you know in one story i worked on at 60
minutes near the end of my time there
i got to know a former treasury official
who taught me a lot
about the loopholes in our collective
financial transparency
and anti-money laundering efforts months
later
after some investigative reporting shed
light on some outrageous and surprising
behavior
he'd come back to me and say yeah kevin
but just think
if we could just turn on all the lights
just for a second
imagine what we'd see i think that's
really relevant here
we flick the lights on for a second with
this malware analysis
but it leaves us to consider perhaps the
most important and motivating question
of all
what are we not seeing thanks for your
time and your attention
i welcome your questions