[Music]
hello everyone and hello people of the
future
uh my name is kevin perlow and i am the
technical intelligence team lead at a
financial institution
today i'm going to be discussing a
concept uh called financial payment
standards
so where i'm going to be discussing two
standards here the iso 8583 standard
which is for cards
and the extensions for financial
services standard which
is a you can think of it as an api for
doing uh
for interacting with hardware on an atm
i'm going to just be discussing how
threat actors incorporate these two
standards into two pretty specific
malware families
uh fast cash for iso 8583 and
injects pure for extensions for
financial services
and in the context of how these malware
families work and sort of the inner
mechanisms of them
i'm also going to be discussing the
advantages and drawbacks that come with
integrating these payment standards into
a malware family
so jumping right in the first thing i
want to discuss is isolated 583
iso 8583 as i said as a standard for
financial card transactions so any time
that you go
to an atm or anytime you go to a point
of server or point of sale device out of
grocery store to do say a self checkout
all of those are going to create an iso
8583 message and an iso 8583 transaction
and what this is is a standardized set
of fields and
standard structure of fields for
transmitting the data from your card and
from
for your transaction over to a payment
switch
from that payment switch to a bank and
then on back to approve or reject the
transaction that's happening
this is the basis of the fast cash
malware which is what we're going to
talk about in in just a few minutes but
first
just an example on the screen this is
very literally an iso 8583 message and
this is sort of what all the fuss is
about
so just breaking this down into a couple
of different parts there are three parts
to one of these messages there's a
message type identifier which
you can think of as sort of a file
header or message header and that has
some metadata about what type of message
something is there is a bitmap which
will indicate
what fields are present in one of these
messages
and then there's the data elements which
are those fields and so the purpose
behind items two and items three there
are
that there are over 100 different
options such as the primary account
number the transaction date and time
and all sorts of other data that can
happen or that can be tied to one of
these transactions
and so you don't necessarily want to
transmit all of these because most
transactions don't use
all of these fields and the bitmap just
is there to specify which ones are there
for the payment switch to look at
i do need to break down the message type
identifier just a little bit further
there are four parts to this so there is
a version which is the first digit there
is a message classification a message
function
and then finally the source of the
message where do the message originate
from the bank or the atm or some other
entity
so going into the example message that
we had on the screen before
if we break this down into a couple of
parts we can see the first four digits
as i mentioned are the message type
identifier
and so the first digit of those four
digits indicates the version and in this
case this is
version 1987 of the iso 8583 standard
the second digit here is the
classification and this is really
important for
the fast cash malware that we're going
to be talking about the classification
indicates whether or not something is a
financial message which in this case
it's set to two so it is or whether it's
a chargeback or an authorization
the third digit indicates whether
something is a request or whether it's a
response coming back and then finally as
i mentioned
uh the fourth part is the source of the
message
so breaking this particular example down
and this is just one that i pulled
online and made a couple of changes too
the first thing we have is the bitmap
and
this one specifies a couple of fields
that are present so we're gonna look at
the first three of the four that are
specified
uh field two which is the primary
account number field
seven which is the point of service
entry mode and
excuse me field 7 which is the
transaction date and time and field 22
which is the point of service entry mode
um and if you want to decode a bitmap
manually that's a bit too time and sense
they're
time intensive but there are some
options there on the bottom of the
screen for you to
take a look at on on your own time most
people though just run this through a
decoder and they have it tell them hey
these are the fields that are in a
message
so real quick here you can see data
element two or field two and
this is the primary account number the
first two digits in this specify how
long
the primary account number is and in
this case the first two digits are 16.
so the next 16 digits are this user's
primary account number
and this is just again one from an
example online it's of course not a real
one
here you can see just a time stamp in
utc
and finally the point of service entry
mode for this transaction and this one's
pretty important for
when we get to the windows fast cache
malware but this point of service entry
mode is set to 0 1 1. the first two
digits in this
indicate whether something or indicate
how something was
entered into the terminal so in this
case this is a manual entry meaning
someone typed in the data
but if you look at something where
the digits are set to nine zero that
would indicate a card swipe
and so there are a couple other options
in that regard the last digit in this or
the third digit in
the point of service entry mode
indicates um
whether or not a terminal has pin
capabilities and of course most
terminals these days do
have pin capabilities but this way the
device doesn't send a message back
saying hey can you enter your pin when
there's no pin to be entered
as sort of a safeguard against that so
those are the core principles that we
need to know for working with the fast
cash malware
now what is the fast cash malware if
you're unfamiliar with this malware
family this belongs to a very specific
subset of north korean threat actors
that also engage in swift heists
sometimes people use fast cash to
or they use fast cash as a term for that
threat actor i i
wouldn't necessarily recommend that and
sometimes people use this term lazarus
group
for just broad north korean activity but
this malware
is tied to a very specific set
of activity from north korean threat
actors there's a very
small cluster of tools and techniques
that go along with what they do
so what this malware does is
it is injected into a payment switch and
it is intended to
either fraudulently approve uh isolated
583 messages from the attackers
sitting at atms and allow them to
withdraw money or
if the transaction isn't originating
from an attacker
it can transparently pass that
transaction to and from the bank and no
one would ever know that anything
happens
that's the general idea behind this
malware family and we're going to look
into the reverse engineering and how
this integrates with
iso 8583 there are three types that have
been
at this point all three are actually in
public uh
in the public domain we're going to look
at two of them we're going to look at
the first aax type which was the one
that you assert reported
back in i believe 2018 and we're going
to look at the windows type which is one
that came out
i guess you could say came out or was
used last year
now all three of these are tailored to
the environments that they work in
and the reason for that is that there
are
slightly different implementations of
iso 8583 depending on
your own architecture and depending on
uh the payment
provider that you use so whether you use
uh visa or mastercard
or star or something along those lines
there are going to be some
different implementations or
interpretations of the standard
so jumping right into the reverse
engineering for ax type one if you were
to open the us cert report and then you
were to open the sample yourself in ida
you're going to see uh just a few small
differences
one of them is that the strings that i
guess you could say should be there
won't be there in your sample and so
this first slide here is just to kind of
give you some tips on how you can go and
collect
those strings you've got to probably
write a script for it but i personally i
just did it manually you can go into
this section of hex
uh look at the offset that it specifies
and what you get is
just a pointer to the string that you're
supposed to be working with so
this one is actually a debugging message
and there are a lot of these
there are a lot of debugging and logging
messages within this malware to help the
threat actors operate because what
they're doing is fairly complex but
we don't need to worry too much about
that for the purposes of this talk i've
got all of the strings labeled
what is uh significantly more
interesting
is uh the strings and the interaction
for how some of the functions that are
built into the malware are called so
on this slide you can see a couple of
different function calls and these are
prenamed within the malware
there is get field string and set field
string on this slide there are a few
others
like copy field string all of those are
related to interacting with an iso 8583
message
and so the important reverse engineering
concept that you need when you're
looking at one of these is to understand
that
there is a pattern for how these work so
before set field string is called for
example there is a load into
register three for a digit and that
digit is going to be the field that is
manipulated
and above that there's a load into
another register
for a string and that's actually the
data that's going to go into that field
so as long as you know that pattern you
can really do the
reverse engineering for all of this and
get field string is very similar there's
a load for the fields that is
going to be retrieved but in this case
since it's not setting any data there's
no data load
once you have all of those principles
kind of in mind you can go through and
map out how this malware works and so
the way you would read this graph here
is from left to right and top to bottom
so
you can think of this as again this
malware is injected into the payments by
entering the software in the payment
switch rather
and uh a new iso 8583 message comes in
and this will intercept that message and
call this function
new read from there it will call check
sock and check sock we'll call get ip
init address and
it will perform a check for a valid ip
to make sure that the message is
originating from where it's supposed to
be and then it will move on sequentially
down the line to check for flags and
then read receive and so on and so forth
we're not going to go into every single
one of these we're going to go into some
of the important ones
for this payment standard
so again the first thing here is a check
sock function and i have on the left
side of the screen
the i guess you could call it like the
overhead for the new read function
when check sock is called it performs an
ip address whitelisting check it wants
to make sure that the
transaction is coming from a valid
internal ip address there's nothing too
uh too much to worry about there but as
we kind of move along and on the left
again on the screen you can see how
we're
progressing sort of through this code
once it does the white listing check
it's going to retrieve a bunch of
information from a couple of different
fields
so the the fields that it's mainly
interested in at first
are the message type identifier the
primary account number
the processing code and then it also
pulls the advice reason code
and depending on what data that it sees
there it has two
options it can either transparently pass
this message on to the bank because
the primary account number didn't line
up with a white list that the threat
actor set up for example
or some of the fields that were supposed
to be there weren't there and
if any of those things are the case it
will send that on to the bank and
nothing it will be as though nothing
ever happens the bank will send a proper
response and that response will go back
to the atm
on the other hand if it does see data
that it's interested in and we'll dive
into the mechanics of that a little bit
more in the windows one
it can generate one of three types of
responses so here there are
generate response transaction 1 and
response transaction 2.
and there is also a response inquiry and
i'll dive into those in just a second as
well but depending on this fraudulent
response that it generates and sends
back to the atms
it will assuming all of that works it
will
log that it's blocked that message and
it will send that response back and then
the process will repeat
so diving into transaction type 1 and
transaction type 2 is actually very
similar to transaction type 1.
um the malware will intercept the
icw8583 message
it's going to uh again pull those fields
that i had mentioned
but then it's also going to copy it'll
dive into this and it'll copy a bunch of
data from the original iso 8583 message
there are some different fields here and
i've got a full list on the next slide
all of the data that it copies it's used
to construct the message that's going to
go
back to these atms and part of that is
because the atms probably although we
don't know for sure
but we can we can make an assessment
that the atms probably expect to receive
data
in a certain way again this is all
environment specific stuff so we have to
make some inferences about what the
threat actor is doing
um so with that in mind uh the fields
that it's going to copy
are the primary account number
processing code and so on and so forth
it's
there's a there's a long list of these
things here um and then for transaction
type 2 it's the same list but minus
a couple of track2 fields now
once it does that it reconstructs the
message and sends that back
it's going to generate a random balance
for a random transaction amount as part
of this process and then the
atm will allow the threat act to
withdraw to withdraw cash
so the other type of uh response that it
can make here is the inquiry response so
this is a response to a balance inquiry
if you walk up to an atm and you put
your card in and you say hey how much
money do i have
this is actually the type of transaction
that would come back
now i think the threat actors probably
set something like this up to allow them
to test their malware
i i can't really think of any other
reason for doing something like this but
it would be very obvious to a threat
actor if this were working properly with
a balance inquiry and you'll see why in
just a second
so inside of the balance inquiry it
copies fields in a very similar way to
that transaction amount but there's also
this format string which i have is kind
of the multi-colored thing on the
top right there so this format string is
very important it's for
determining how uh or it's for the
structure of information that's going to
go back into field 54 which is the field
that handles
all of your account balances and so
breaking this format string down just a
little bit
we have a three or we have two kind of
non-important
items and one very important item so the
non-important ones
here it will say that the amount
type is set to zero one which indicates
that the amount going back is something
called a ledger balance
for the purposes of this malware uh not
not too important we'll see an available
balance
a little bit later on but the main thing
here
is the currency code and so this
currency code is set to 356 which is the
indian rupee
and what you can infer from something
like that is that for whatever reason
the atms on the receiving end of this
expect to receive data in that
denomination
and so you can make some assumptions and
do some open source research
and i can't really go into victimology
in a talk like this but
um that will it will make it pretty
clear as to why
this might be the case and why uh or who
this victim probably was
so once those are set there's also a
randomized amount of currency that that
goes along with this
and that gets sent back to the atms as
well as a fraudulent balance inquiry
response
so putting all of that together we have
injected the malware
into the software on a payment switch we
have done some
uh preliminary checks uh anytime an iso
8583 message comes in to see if it's one
that we're interested in
if it is one that we're interested in
we've taken some decision points and
we've either passed the transaction on
or we have uh blocks the transaction
and sent a fraudulent response either a
fraudulent withdrawal
or a fraudulent balance inquiry
again i don't have time to go into type
2 of the aax malware but this graph is
here in case you want to reverse
engineer it on your own time
if you can reverse the first one you can
reverse the second one
uh the the concepts are the same there
are just some structural differences and
this aax type 2 is sort of a bridge to
the windows one and
so from a high level perspective you can
uh if you were to look at this graph you
would see that a lot of the payment
logic has been consolidated
and so that's really what we're going to
look at for the windows version as well
is how they consolidated and sort of
changed this payment logic
so within the windows version
we have one once all of that same stuff
happens a whitelist they've added a
blacklisting function in
but it's done the ipaddress check it's
on all of these decision points it is
going to go into what i call the
generate response parent it's sort of a
new function
that was added into this malware so the
response parent is responsible for
taking in some additional data and doing
some additional checks before proceeding
with whether or not to generate a
fraudulent response
the response parent has two checks the
first check
is that it is going to look for field
zero the mti
and it's going to check whether or not
field zero's
third and fourth digit are set to zero
zero if we think back to our original
example
we had a financial message that was zero
two hundred
and that indicated that something was a
financial request
so here it's looking to see if something
was also 0-200 or 0-100 to indicate
hey that's also a request as opposed to
if it were 0-10
which would indicate that something was
a financial response
the malware doesn't want to indic or it
doesn't want to intercept a financial
response because it wants to just pass
that back on
to the the device that's expecting that
response so that's the first check
the second check is for the point of
service entry mode
now the point of service entry mode
again if you think back to that example
it's how the data was entered into a
terminal and here it's checking that the
data in the point of service entry mode
field starts with a nine which indicates
that this was a car transaction rather
than manually entering it
and that's just an operational
expectation from the threat actor that
there aren't people here just manually
entering in
a whole bunch of data so assuming those
tracks pass
it will jump into a response
workflow and this does there's a little
bit of redundancy here but this will
again grab the mti and then it's going
to grab a whole bunch of fields that you
can see here on the screen
and the first check here is to just see
do these fields have data in them and
one of these is field three which is
used in
uh in just a second as well but for the
most part that's all this check is
uh concerned with initially and if these
fields don't have data in them
the malware can't uh or doesn't expect
to be able to process this properly and
so it's going to exit the
it's going to exit this workflow now
assuming all those checks are met the
next set of
uh the next set of logic here is
for looking at that processing code
which is in field three
if the processing code starts with a
three that's going to indicate that this
is a balance inquiry and we'll see a
workflow like we looked at before and
that we'll look at again
if it starts with a zero it's going to
indicate that it needs to do
a fraudulent transaction response and
then finally if it's none of those
things
it's going to return
an invalid pin response to the user
so i have here all three options kind of
on the screen and this is how they look
in ida if you
were to screenshot it out and we see
that format string show up again
i know it's a little bit hard to see on
the graphics so i've kind of put it in
multi-color again on this next screen
but we have as part of our balance
inquiry response
instead of the indian rupee we have
changed the currency
to turkey's currency and that's pretty
important again
uh this would indicate that for whatever
reason and
most likely it would be tied to
victimology that
for whatever reason the malware expects
or the 18 the malware expects to
interact with an atm
that in turn expects the currency to be
turkeys
and so that's a pretty important threat
intelligence factoid there that you can
pull out of something like this
and and it kind of gives you an idea of
how this can be a little bit more victim
specific
than just something that works
everywhere uh and again i have the other
the other two options here for one of
those responses so
that essentially is the fast cache
malware i'm next i'm going to kind of
jump into extensions for financial
services but while i do that i would
consider these three points as sort of a
frame of reference for comparison so
the first point is that a lot of things
need to go right uh when you're
when you're working with malware like
this uh it's pretty
challenging to interact with all of
these devices at that level and so it
interacts with all of these protocols
and so when you're doing that and a lot
can go wrong and that's why the malware
has a whole bunch of logging
information inside of it to help the
threat actors out
i think those are the two main things
the other thing is that there are some
pretty heavy
operational requirements that you need
to set up you need programmers that can
do this
and can make these changes on the fly
you also need a network of money mules
basically people that are there to
withdraw the cash from the atms and so
if you're a north korean threat actor
not the easiest thing to set up and then
finally you need access
to this network and you need to get
pretty far into the network in order to
get access to that payment switch and
and
to you know take a stab at this so it's
pretty challenging but it does allow the
threat actors
to operate uh the atms without putting
anything on the atms
and and to do these cache ads so with
that in mind the next thing i want to
talk about is something called
extensions for financial services
you can think of this as a standardized
api for how
software vendors are supposed to write
their software for interacting with an
atm
so any atm you go to is able to withdraw
cache it's able to
you can actually deposit cache there it
has all these blinking lights all of
those things
go into the extensions for financial
services
standard and we're actually going to be
looking at one called jxfs which is
java extensions for financial services
now we're going to be looking at this in
the context of a specific family but if
you're interested more in traditional
xfs malware
there are some links that i have here
and there are a couple common api calls
none of these actually appear in this
particular family but they are ones that
you'll see
fairly often uh within other atm malware
that's out there
but we're interested in this malware
family called injects pure now
i i can't go too much into the incident
that
in which this malware was used but this
is an atm malware family that
relies on both xfs and a proprietary atm
implementation the reason i want to go
into this is less to talk about how the
malware dispenses cash because
i think that's been kind of done to
death in open source and it's not
super interesting what i want to talk
about instead is
what people can do to an atm
once they get this level of access and
so that's really the context
that we're going to be uh looking at
this malware kind of the frame of mind
we should have
uh and we'll see some pretty interesting
capabilities there that aren't
necessarily
built into this malware but could have
been so with inject superior the
operators can do some pretty traditional
or they can perform some pretty
traditional actions of course it's atm
malware
so they can dispense cache they can
query device information
and that's really used to kind of
find out how much cash is in the atm and
they can execute arbitrary code
all of those things are pretty common to
any atm hour family and honestly aside
from dispensing cash they're common to
any malware family just in general
but we're going to focus or we're going
to dial in on the cache dispensing
function
and the xfs components that follow that
if you are interested in a full reverse
engineering of it it's
again it's been kind of done to death in
an open source and so here are three
uh just references for that the third
one we are actually going to reference
again and that one's a very good one and
so we'll come back to that but the
important thing that you need to know
about this malware is that the threat
actors
uh essentially deployed this malware to
a bunch of atms
and the malware when it runs it creates
an http server
and that server can accept get and post
requests that carry out those commands
that i mentioned
before and that's really the core
concept there are two workflows to kind
of get you to this spot
if from from the malware's viewpoint the
one we're going to be looking at is the
one that is just directly responsible
for
um all of the different commands so
we're going to dial in on the suspension
commands but the other ones are up there
um this sits within the server that's
created and i have that here on the
screen
basically it opens a listener on a high
port and just listens for those requests
so within this dispensing commands there
are two
possible branches that the malware can
take it can
query i call it querying the device
information but it's really querying the
cassette information
and it can dispense cache and so dialing
in just on the first one the query
we can see a couple of different xfs
callouts here so we have
get cash unit we have a
dispenser call and we have get number of
cash units
so these are things where if you're
looking at the code
these are not standard java calls
whereas pretty much everything else
is uh and they're not standard
javascript calls and again pretty much
everything else is in that regard as
well
so these look like they could be xfs
implementations
so how do we how do we figure that out
well if we take get cash unit
and we throw it into the magic google
box uh you will get this google book
uh it's some sort of atm book i think
it's in german it's from like 2004
um and you can see here that uh call to
get cash unit within this jxfs
implementation
within this book will return this.cash
unit
not super illuminating if you're trying
to figure out what this is doing but it
at least indicates that this is probably
we're probably on the right path to
determining that this is xfs
so the next stop and probably the the
better stop once you know about it is to
go to the actual documentation
and so if you go to the send
documentation and you look at book five
uh which holds all of the different
uh i guess api calls for this malware or
sorry for
uh xfs if you go in there and you look
for get cash unit you will indeed see an
entry in the official documentation
for get cash unit and this uh with a
little bit more research this
essentially returns the information
about the
money that is stored in the atm in
different cassettes and
there is there are some differences
between how this is written out here and
how the malware
or sorry yeah how the malware uses it
and how the proprietary atm software
uses it
but essentially uh this you could call
this an xfs implementation
and i would be comfortable saying that
the developers for the atm probably just
built
their implementation on top of uh on top
of xfs rather than
in place of xfs so that handles one of
the api calls but what about get number
of cache units
i've got to give a huge shout out to
frank baldwin who did a presentation
last year
more specifically on how this malware
works and and the context in which it
was used
but one of the things he discovered was
that the uh atm software as part of the
incident response
was actually uploaded to virustotal so
i'm not going to just paste some
all of the vendors code um you know all
over the place on here but i'm going to
show the relevant things
so get cash unit sits within this atms
code for peripheral
under the context of peripheral notes
deposit dot get cash unit
and the same goes for get number of cash
units
and what i want to talk about here is
less about what these are doing but and
more about
uh what the threat actors could have
done
uh so under that peripheral.notes
deposit call
are a bunch of other fairly mundane
calls
in terms of interacting with the atm but
they would allow the threat actors to
to query a lot of these types of a lot
of these types of information
so most of these aren't super exciting
um there's some extra calls for
retrieving more information about the
cache units
if you haven't heard enough about the
cache units uh you can get the media
status
you can get some other settings nothing
too groundbreaking but it does give the
thread actors a little bit more
information
so the next step here
if you're interested in thread actor
capabilities on an atm is to actually
back
that up as uh like one notch and instead
of looking at peripherals.notes deposit
you would look on the atm software for
just what the peripherals did and again
this is something the threat actors had
access to
so looking at just the peripheral class
instead of notes deposit there are some
other options you can call
peripherals.screen and
peripherals.host.systemservice.pinpad
and under each of those
are some actions that you can take the
most important ones i think are this
idea of disabling and enabling keys
why might a threat actor want to do
something like that well
if you're trying to coordinate a cash
out
what you might want to do is maximize
the amount of cash that is actually
sitting in an atm and if you just let
people use the atm all day
you might be sending a money mule to an
atm to pick out cash
or to pick up cash rather and there
might be none in there there might not
be as much in there as it could be so
this creates an option for threat actors
to perhaps
disable and enable keys on an atm to
stop it from functioning the way it's
supposed to
so that other people try and use it and
have to walk away from it
um that is sort of a high variance
strategy because if you
have an atm that's not working you raise
the risk that someone's going to go look
at it
but depending on how you're timing this
if you do that say late at night
or earlier in the morning those are some
options that a threat actor could take
if they're willing to kind of roll the
dice a little bit on how much money
they're taking out
there are some other things that i
haven't listed here they're a bit more
mundane
one is you know the blinking blinking
lights on an atm you can
make those blank all you want but from a
security standpoint you know
go for it we're more worried about
people taking the money out i think
but those i think that really speaks to
the capabilities that a threat actor has
there
so kind of just circling back on um
or kind of closing the loop on the rest
of this we have
uh one other part of the dispense
function which is just the actual
dispensing of cash
and so dispense itself is possibly an
xfs implementation
i can find it in the documentation but
it's implemented um
significantly differently i think within
the proprietary code that that's
available
so it's a little bit unclear if this one
is built on top of xfs or built in place
of xfs
but again it you know it speaks to the
threat actor capabilities when they're
interacting with a device like this
and so that is really what i wanted to
talk about from the extensions for
financial services approach so if we
think about the fast cash malware and we
think about this
kind of in the same context in fast cash
we were able to
send people to an atm and they would
you know run a card into it and as long
as it's one of the threat actors cards
it would fraudulently approve a
transaction
here we have a threat actor who
developed proprietary malware
um they were the way this works is they
would have sent
people to those atms at a specified time
to have the cash
uh come out of an atm and you know via
post request and then they would
withdraw that cash themselves
and so that's sort of the comparison
approach there one of the problems here
is there's some increased development
time because they had to
develop malware specific for this atm
and they also had to work with some
proprietary implementations when they
did that that might not necessarily be
documented
so that's a little bit challenging and
testing's always a little bit
challenging
um and so those are some of the things
that kind of come up there but
you know ultimately they did have the
opportunity to
run an attack like this and so
with that i will teleport myself back to
the future and back to another room
and i'll have just this slide up there
if you want to see some concluding
thoughts but at this point
uh thank you for listening to my talk
and i'm happy to take as many questions
as i can
all right so first of all thank you all
uh there are two things
i want to just uh mention before i go
into a couple of the questions that came
up during the talk
the first is there is a slight slight
error on one of the slides which is data
element
60 i have listed as being the advice
reason code that is the advice reason
code
uh for certain payment switches but not
all of them that's actually a private
reserve field that is corrected than the
slides that
are uh going to be uploaded the second
thing i would mention
is that there's white paper that covers
a little bit more on
ax type 2 and also has some of the
some additional context and tooling
listed so feel free to check that out
when that goes up online tonight
there are a couple of questions that
came in and we're on about
uh 45 second delay here so if you hear
me say this and you have a question it
means you should type it
um one of the questions that came up is
can i elaborate on what a payment switch
is so that's a great question
i probably could have done a little bit
of a better job on that a payment switch
is a device that sits in between
uh all of the payment devices and a bank
that needs to approve transactions so
um you've got atms and you've got
uh your grocery store point of sale
devices and this payment switch will
process all of the messages coming into
those and decide whether or not to
forward those onto a bank
and then when the bank decides whether
or not it wants to approve or disapprove
a transaction request it'll send that to
the payment switch and the payment
switch will send it out it's a way of
just processing all of the different
types of data that are coming in
and so that's why it's so important to
the ecosystem so another good question
that came up was well should we just
change the iso 8583 standard
i would never recommend that and it
would also be impossible even if i
thought that were a good idea
um but the iso 8583 standard is the card
payment standard for
absolutely everything um there are some
things that go along with card payments
um such as
like envy transactions for for example
and that was something i thought someone
uh
might ask and i think this is kind of
related to it um
there are different ways to do these car
transactions that could randomize the
data
um but ultimately um and and
by randomizing it i mean they might make
it less predictable for what's supposed
to be going back to an atm
so those things might make it harder to
do these types of attacks
but ultimately what's happening here is
that the payment switch is compromised
and there's nothing wrong
at all with the payment standard being
used the atms are
working the way they're supposed to be
in a very real sense they're processing
these messages
so that rolls into the next thing which
was um
i think uh cat was the one that asked
how do you even detect an attack like
this
uh the i don't give official
recommendations but
um i touch on this a little bit in the
white paper all of the
mechanisms for getting to this point
where your payments which is compromised
all of those are or almost all of the
tooling used by this threat actor
the fast cash threat actor specifically
involves powershell it involves
scheduled tasks or created services and
those are all pretty standard things
that you can and should be looking for
in in your enterprise so if you've got
that kind of endpoint detection
uh then it just becomes a question of
identifying uh those anomalies and
and having the right analysts and having
those analysts do the right analysis
on all of those things so uh by the time
it gets to the payment switch and this
cash out happens
you'll detect it because the money will
you know all your atms will be empty all
of a sudden
um and so you don't the idea is to stop
it before it gets to that point
it's i'm probably not supposed to say
it's too late but it is basically too
late at that stage
um now um i have another question here
from sean which is how does injects pure
actually get on to a payment switch for
the atm so indrex pure doesn't get onto
a payment switch and i think that's good
to touch on too
um injects pure is a
different adversaries uh method this is
a latin america adversary i can't really
talk about the context for
a couple different reasons but um they
deployed of the malware
um directly onto
the atms i don't think i can really
disclose how they did that but i can
tell you that
that's not a novel like a full atm hour
deployment is not necessarily a novel
technique
um so thinking about one that's in open
source uh if you
can read korean um a couple years ago
there was there was one in south korea
where
there was an issue where they used i
think the anti-virus
management tool to deploy malware to a
bunch of atms
so i'm not going to comment on whether
or not that's what happened here
but that's the type of attack you're
looking at to get that there now what
that means though and the difference
between these two attacks is that
someone's got to be there to pick up
that cache that's getting automatically
dispensed and if you go on twitter you
can see some
examples of uh where someone wasn't
there and cash just got
like spat out onto the ground um so
i wanted to touch on that and clarify
that
um i know that question wasn't too late
um
i think that uh there's one other thing
i did want to talk about here which is
um you know so we've got all this
technical intelligence and i've got kind
of a minute or two to touch on this like
how does
um how does all of this like fit into a
threat intelligence picture
so it's not enough to just
track that uh there are all these
technical characteristics
of this malware and to understand how it
works you certainly need to do that but
you also need
if you're in this industry to be um
doing really good collection with uh
other peer financial institutions
because this data is rare and these
attacks are rare
um but they're so impactful so that will
help you build an operational picture
out of it and it will also help you
build a
strategic intelligence picture in terms
of starting to make business decisions
or starting to make security level
decisions at a bigger scale
um on on these types of topics and
with that i think we have uh run through
questions and i think we are about out
of time so i just want to say thanks
again for
everyone for tuning into this i know
it's tough to sit through a lot of
webcasts but it really means a lot to me
and i really appreciate it so thank you