[Music]
before we begin i need to mention this
forward-looking statement
i'm not a lawyer i don't play one on tv
or on the internet but this slide states
the following presentation is not
talking about any future
products services strategies or
commitments of salesforce
do not try to use the following content
for purchasing or trading decisions
it probably won't go well thank you for
tuning in to our talk
i'm spencer curtin and with me is alan
stegenovic
we are on the abuse operations team at
heroku where we keep users from doing
bad things on to and from the platform
this talk focuses on abuse
and how we hunt for it on heroku
heroku was purchased by salesforce about
10 years ago
it's a platform as a service that offers
an easy interface to quickly go from
idea to
online application without having to
manage and configure the underlying
infrastructure
so developers are free to focus on code
and deploying it to the internet with
very little effort
it supports multiple languages and
provides features like
scalability backups continuous
integration
same default configurations and much
much more
and all you need is an email address to
create an account
to give you an idea about the size of
the platform over nine million apps have
been created
over 2 million databases are managed and
the infrastructure handles
billions of requests a day and heroku
runs on heroku
all right so heroku is a platform as a
service right we run anyone's code on
the internet as directed from unknown
sources
millions of times a day
okay we are rce as a service
to be fair the part of the platform
we're talking about is referred to
as the free tier or the common run time
heroku has other offerings that are not
like this but we won't be talking about
them today
our focus will be on how we defend the
common run time
from abusive bad actors we
define abuse as the unintended
monetization of
anything so if you have a free service a
free trial
or any offering that has an angle to
extract value
somebody is already trying to figure out
a way to make money off of it
it's a very fine line between a business
trying to get off the ground
and an abuser trying to take advantage
of your services
sometimes it's obvious like theft of
resources other times it's not so clear
for example think about a social media
poll it's intended for honest input
but it's gameable because it's not one
person one vote
it's one account one vote so the person
in control of the most accounts
wins the problem isn't new the scams
aren't new
but we see them leveraging more and more
of the cloud
now is there a single view that captures
the full picture of the entire operation
across the industry we may have that
full picture but not today
from our limited view we've identified a
number of puzzle pieces that we feel
have been under reported
now on a more practical layer we see a
portion of that picture realized through
misused malice and crime
on our platform legal documents like the
acceptable use policy the aup
provide a list of prohibited content and
actions so it's like the list of don'ts
for users to follow
and it also serves as a set of
guidelines for our team to uphold
obviously this can't cover every type of
abuse activity
and even if it did it could act like a
laundry list for an abuser to know what
kind of badness
could be performed from the platform so
let's look at how we group
violations of the aup
there are unintentional violations and
there are intentional violations
to determine if intentional or
unintentional or good or bad
we establish intent and we do that by
collecting and connecting as many
indicators of abuse
as necessary so unintentional could be
a customer that deploys a poorly written
app that consumes more than its share of
resources
and now they've become a noisy neighbor
so not malicious
but kind of like they were accidentally
jerks totally unaware that there was an
issue with their code
until we suspend their app and open up a
support ticket so they can fix it
the intentional abusers are what make
this job really interesting
these users have skills that range from
script kitty all the way to rogue
advanced developer which we call our
apex actors
skids will be skids and deploy code
found on github youtube
or whatever their buddy gave them to run
at times we'll get what feels like a
swarm of abuse
centered around a particular app like a
proxy kit or a peer-to-peer app
then there are the quick and loud
abusers they could care less about being
detected
and will attempt to stand up at ddos
farm and attack a target as quickly as
possible
the actors that are patient skilled and
criminal are the more dangerous group
these actors attempt to iterate past our
detection capabilities
they may try to social engineer support
staff to gain insight
into how they were detected after being
suspended
and will try anything to maximize their
use of our platform
now these users are not exploiting
technical vulnerabilities within the
platform itself
they take advantage of gaps in business
logic
the majority are not too advanced but
are very persistent
so if you like to think about apt small
lowercase a
and a big capital p and again
financially motivated
now when we say persistent we mean that
an account that after an account has
been suspended
the same actor will use a different
email address or a sub inbox of the
original email address to create a new
account
we'll cover a couple campaigns during
the show and tell section of the talk
so here's a fun one how do we define
ourselves where do we fit within the
company
well maybe we can start by listing the
things that we're not
we're not red team but we learn a lot
from them
we're not blue team but we borrow from
them
we're not purple team but we talk to
more groups across the organization
we're not c-cert but we conduct
investigations
we're not security but we monitor for
outbound attacks
we're not grc but we write up risks
around business rules
we're not anti-fraud but we use the same
data
we're not service reliability but we
help keep the platform stable
we're not encompassed by any one of
these groups but we overlap in so many
ways
we are abuse operations we exist because
the business understands that there is
risk of having
unwanted activity given an environment
that's rce as a service
overall we define abuse operations as a
specialized dfir
team that requires a wide view across
the business as shown
our goal is to push bad actors from the
platform and put a spotlight on abuse
patterns
so that engineering teams in the
business can address them
heroku is exceptionally collaborative
teams openly share views and metrics
and just ping us when things look odd on
their end this enables us to move
very fast now pack your bags because
alan's going to walk you through
how we hunt alan
thank you spencer hi i'm alan
strojanovic
and we hunt we don't want to wait for
the badness to have to hurt us
we're looking for wolves in sheep's
clothing after all most of our hunting
starts with
suspicious indicators suspicious
indicators derive from a combination of
internal user data and external
information
about that data for example an app with
an abnormally high cpu would generate an
event based alarm
and on the slide is a short list of some
of the sources of these indicators
just understand that the indicators
we're getting are considered low value
by themselves they rarely have enough
context to make a decision
now given a starting suspicious
indicator we
form a hypothesis about the intent of
the actor
we start looking for related indicators
to try and prove or disprove
that hypothesis for instance it just so
happens that given a high cpu
with high network usage a match for a
popular file download program and the
substring torrents
in the app name is probably a peer to
peer app
true story now each of these indicators
is not proof of intent individually but
you can see that collectively they make
a really strong case
a collection of low-value indicators
does become a very good footprint of
malicious activity
to increase the confidence we keep
asking the question
what else you got and as more indicators
are discovered we try and think about
why they are the way that they are for
instance a
face rolled email address like shown is
a pretty good indicator that
the user doesn't really value the
account it's likely a throwaway account
but this is not necessarily by itself
bad a face rolled app name similarly
is not necessarily bad it could be
something for a quick test something to
be discarded
however a face rolled email address with
a collection of face rolled app names
and multiple failed attempts to verify
different credit cards
and finally landing on a working credit
card that has been previously used by a
previously identified malicious actor
is worthy of further scrutiny i'm sure
you will agree
by the way in case it's not clear the
difference between a face world app
a face world string and a random string
is whether it's created by hand
or by computer think keyboard mashing
now establishing intent is as one would
expect the art of figuring out what the
actor's trying to do
now our we have two goals here uh goal
number one is determining what the actor
is trying to do
while goal number two is determining
what the actors trying to do before they
do it
now we usually reserve goal number two
for actors that we've seen before so
that we can avoid that whole pre-crime
scenario
we really try and not really try hard
not to kick someone off the platform
before they've actually done anything
bad
making a decision and taking an action
is of course the crux of the matter at
this point we have collected a bunch of
indicators and
that should give us a reasonably good
idea of the intent of the activity
it's time to take action if the intent
is bad then suspensions evidence
collections deletions
all that kind of stuff comes into play
if the intent is not bad
then watch lists or allow lists or
adjustments for false positives or
opening of support tickets are among
some of the things we can do
analyst discretion is kind of necessary
here is it good
or just not bad yet sometimes
undetermined intent really just means
there's not enough
indicators to establish an intent to
make an action
in which case it goes back into the pool
no other actions to be taken
and it'll be reassessed when it
percolates to the top again due to a new
alert
now we have a bunch of indicators we
have enough to establish intent we've
made our decision and we've taken the
corresponding action
now we look to see how widespread this
activity is we gather all the accounts
associated with the
indicators we have and we look for other
common indicators that we may have
missed
we then add those indicators to our
collection and see if any accounts
match that that we may also have missed
this strengthens the footprint and makes
it suitable for
automation automation is how we reduce
toil
we never want to see the same abuse
again so we automate the collection
detection and actioning of the footprint
the one we just actioned our automation
can also be set up to run
the new footprint retroactively so that
older implementations of badness will
also be detected and
actioned as well this cleans up any
stragglers
we log the action that is taken so that
we can use that information next time we
run through the loop this is how we get
that
have we seen this before question
answered there's of course trade-offs
automation will result in some loss of
visibility the investigation performed
in the previous step
helps build robustness so that there's
longevity in the automation
of this action counter-intuitively
taking this extra step helps reduce toil
in the long run why do we use the term
footprint
simply because fingerprint or profile
implies something a little too unique
a footprint as a collection of
indicators helps us remember that an
actor can be more than one person
can be a bot can be multiple specialized
actor groups
or some combination thereof
and then of course we do it all over
again
let's recap suspicious indicators come
to us as high-water mark alarms abuse
complaints or as the results of artifact
exploration
including previous historic events we
add context
and more indicators from both internal
and external sources
so that we can increase the confidence
when we're trying to establish
intent so that we can make a decision
and take an action
we then investigate often retroactively
to find more indicators that
collectively
are suitable for automation and then we
rinse and repeat let's talk about some
tools
we have an event collector that acts
like a classic sam it handles our
alerting and reporting and can send info
to other tools as well as receive them
we have database query tools that can
run queries automatically
and we also run them manually when we
need to test hypotheses or
you know check to confirm that the
results of automatic suspensions is
still working properly
we have malware analysis tools that can
scan apps statically or dynamically
and they send the results to other tools
as well we have a ticket system
now most places don't consider ticket
systems as part of the tooling
but we do if for no other reason than it
is
we need to be able to reduce the toil
there as well
and we have our suspension tools that
suspend users and apps
this encompasses a complex rule set that
is implemented as guardrails so we don't
accidentally you know
suspend the entire world
we track two general types of activities
campaigns and prohibited software
campaigns track actors and victims and
custom software that they may have
written prohibited software on the other
hand looks for known malware
tracks c2 communications and similar
artifacts
and known abusive software that anyone
can install including those
with that deployed heroku button
let's put that together any tool can
talk to
any other tool even if it is the machine
equivalent of i see bad
do you see bad any tool can tell the
suspension tools that a user an app
needs to be suspended
suspension tools have their own allow
and deny lists and internal business
logic to help identify and stop mistakes
before they become costly and everything
that these tools do
is recorded now this may sound complex
but this is what gets us the flexibility
we need without taxing
any singular system now after the jump
cut we're going to continue with section
5.
let's talk about responding and reacting
we align with the business they have of
course set the task in the priority but
it's up to us to be able to interpret
them
the business wants us to remove abuse
faster fair enough
but this means that we need faster and
more accurate detection logic
the business also wants less abuse or at
least less costly abuse
fine but that requires us to study the
actors and what they are doing and how
they affect the platform and the
business
now what the business really wants is
they want the problem to just
go away now this does seem simplistic uh
but after giving it some thought we
realize that there actually is a path
here
uh it's via platform hardening and
demotivating actors
if we make the entire thing less
hospitable to abuse maybe we can get
close
now we in abuse ops we're selfish we
want all of this
the first two items in the list on the
that previous slide they kind of have
competing requirements
the first requires us to respond quicker
and the second to study the actor in
their actions and hence respond slower
there are pros and cons to each of these
strategies the big ones being that
quicker
is usually easier but prone to false
positives while slower
produces better situational awareness
but since the actor may still be active
it could be more damaging
we have found that it's sometimes worth
switching back and forth depending on
what we're seeing at that moment in time
and we've also found that going slow
first
does allow us to act quicker later with
more accuracy
now moving quicker requires some
visibility situational awareness
not only requires visibility but also
requires studying the actors
and hence going slower so overall we end
up
going slower to ultimately go
faster but with accuracy
but when we first started out we had to
go fast just to get our heads above
water
so between visibility and situational
awareness just understand that
there's a little bit of hidden
complexity here
now tracking actors is hard
tracking persistent returning actors is
hard
okay not quite but there does not seem
to be a well-defined way to track actors
by
footprint as we defined it and that
gives us the flexibility that we desire
we want to know if an actor changes
behavior we want to know in an automatic
way
and when they do we want to be able to
add the new indicator to the footprint
in as few steps as possible we want to
be able to split and merge
footprints as we track multiple actors
and we want
this to be a tool just like the rest
remember the requirements back in the
tool slides
no we want a lot today we
track actors mostly manually this is a
lot of toil
we are looking to build a system that
enables us to spot returning actors that
have changed a ttp
pivot or spot when a footprint is
covering multiple actors
like a splash or fingers crossed spot an
actor that returns and starts from
scratch
re-tools let's look at those definitions
a pivot is what we call a change to a
ttp of a returning actor
different from a pentester pivot if a
footprint is a collection of indicators
then given enough of them
a partial match usually indicates a
change in behavior
by the same actor actors are people too
when they're suspended they will test
how by isolating for variables and
making small changes one at a time
until they get it working again
so a form of threshold detection like
shown works really well as an accurate
way to detect their return
and still take some action then updating
the footprint with the new indicators
reflecting the change they just made
keeps the footprint accurate
this is designed to make it difficult
for a persistent actor to regain a
foothold
on the platform and it frustrates the
heck out of them
especially if we cut them off at each
pivot
and before they make a profit
sometimes instead of seeing a singular
pivot we see multiple pivots
but with different partial footprints we
call this a splash
every slap a mud puddle this seems to
mean that there are multiple actors
operating under the same set of ttps
we have found great value in looking for
how they are sharing their tactics
um are they reading all the same forms
or are they
using the same youtube instructional
videos
we find that the source that we find
that if we find the source
that we can have even more fun imagine
knowing what they're going to do before
they've even implemented it especially
if it's a code change
and adding those as indicators to the
footprint before the change is even
deployed
frustrates them as well now shout out to
our fantastic threat and tell team
they help us find this stuff out there
when we have all the tooling in place
when pivot detection is working as
designed
and when we manage to stop actors before
they've even begun then they have only
two choices
go somewhere else or retool when they
retool they change significant portions
of their apps their code their
infrastructure and their behaviors
that makes them indistinguishable from a
new actor
this used to bother us quite a bit but
then it occurred to us
so what the only reason that we could
think of that we needed to tie two
actors together was for law enforcement
purposes anyway
so that we could collect more evidence
but this doesn't apply to all the actors
and is actually kind of rare
so retooled actors end up being
identified as new actors just by the
nature of how our hunt works
and because we're pretty thorough in our
indicator collection
sometimes we find evidence that the new
actors in fact the returning actor
retooled after all
actor reactions are fun some actors
outright call us names others open
tickets
and try to social engineer support to
get their loot or their infrastructure
back
others may be seeing the writing on the
wall realize they've squeezed out what
they can
and go about convincing others to run
their kits sometimes for pay
look what i did you can do it too it's
like they've
found their own replacement for that
actor's footprint
that last business category though
wanting the problem to go away
it can be achieved by devaluing loot if
we devalue the actors loot by making it
worthless after the fact like
getting like reporting stolen
credentials to get them reset or making
it
not worth the effort by like limiting
cpu usage so that an actor can't
cryptomine anything of value
then it's more likely they won't return
now we have done this but so far with
mixed mixed success
now this is where hardening platform
comes into play since we're already
studying how the actors act
and how the platform reacts we recommend
fixes to make the platform less
hospitable to abuse we
push left to use the classic find me
later
and i'll tell you a fun story from a
previous job about devaluing a fischer's
loot
on top of devaluation of loot of killing
off roi
there's an even wider goal of
demotivation
if we really want to keep the actor away
we should work towards making it so that
they don't want to come back
all of the things we've talked about
adds friction to abusive actions the
monetization of free
and since our ultimate goals are to make
abuse less valuable
and less desirable without affecting
legit customers we need to break the
spirits of the
bad actors break spirits not code
now these last two sections they contain
a lot of information um
there's a lot of notes in the slides and
when the slides become available feel
free to download them and read them
i hope that there's things in these two
sections that resonate with you and
maybe help you define what you
want or need to do but enough of all
this philosophy
let's go back to spencer for a little
bit of show and tell
thanks alan let's look at a couple
campaigns that have touched our hearts
and well we'd like to think we've
touched theirs too the first actor is a
huge fan of decentralized currency
loves blockchains and hates electric
bills
they first appeared on our radar by
spinning up 100 apps per user account
all from across multiple accounts all
from free email providers
so a user account is limited to running
five apps until they verify their
account by adding a payment method
like a credit card after that 100 apps
is the new max
so new accounts immediately adding a
payment method
and spinning up 100 apps that's not
normal
i'm not exposing any detection logic
here giving anything away
normal users don't do that that activity
gets on our radar really quickly
and to top things off fraudulent credit
cards were used to verify each account
and all 100 apps were identical
so we inspected one of the apps and saw
that they were running a tor hidden
service
accessible through ssh here's a
screenshot of the script that would run
once their app was deployed
we suspended the accounts and very soon
the actor was back and the cat and mouse
began
now one clear sign that it's on with a
bad actor
is when they start getting cute with
their app names
obviously this is the g rated end of the
spectrum
after a short while the code changed and
we saw what they were really after
mining monero the apps were mining with
lib xmr and sending all traffic through
tor
to maximize profit each app was pegging
cpu resources
fantastic now after seeing this we
believe that the initial wave of apps
was part of some capabilities testing
some
real live bad actor devops
we suspended the accounts and the actor
would pivot each tr
each time trying to minimize their
footprint to avoid detection right so
the top image
in this slide is from an app that packed
the tor and the mining binaries
in a zip file which would then be
unzipped with a unique passphrase
at the time of deployment the bottom
image
is from a later pivot this time using
gpg encrypted payloads
with unique names and unique passphrases
so decrypt
unpack and mine sending everything
through tor
this type of activity at this scale
threaten the performance of some of the
shared resources
other customers were impacted due to
these noisy neighbor situations
we had to stay on top of this actor but
they were automating
their operations and getting faster
mostly during our off hours
so playing never-ending whack-a-mole
like this was unsustainable and it was a
path toward team burnout
so we took a step back and we looked at
all of the data provided
by this by this actor as they use the
platform
we were able to identify five unique
indicators to form a ttp footprint
this included indicators observed before
code was even deployed
like at the point of signup they came
from a tor exit node
from a particular free email provider
and used an email address that matched a
naming pattern
it's three right there and no code has
even been deployed
so a system was developed to gather
these indicators as well as a few others
and compare them against the overall ttp
footprint
if five out of five were present
automatically suspend
if three or four out of five it was
likely a pivot and will be manually
reviewed
to see if the footprint needed to be
updated this worked extremely well
we were now able to detect the actor
early in their campaign
and soon after this we stopped seeing
them for a while
um they did return a few times with
totally different kits but we were on
top of them right away
and impacted their success mining
now an important note here from the more
recent attempts
the apps check to see what kind of an
environment they were on
specifically it looked to see if gpus
were available for mining
that's not our platform this kit
appeared to be tooled for
multiple platforms so they may be
someone else's problem now
something to consider let's look at
another persistent actor
hopefully it's clear that fighting
fishing campaigns is a challenge on a
platform like heroku
infrastructure gets reported to us
either directly by wonderful people on
the internet
or through third-party services we
subscribe to
the infrastructure may be landing pages
or just back-end functionality
or artifacts that point toward a full
kit that includes message distribution
most of the time we'll perform a quick
investigation to confirm fishing
suspend the user from the platform and
get back to our queue
however if the same fish gets identified
again
the actor will be tracked as a campaign
like allen mentioned earlier
so this particular actor was targeting
customers of an insurance provider
when inspecting the app we see the
following directory structure within
their
code which contains message sending
capabilities through third-party
messaging add-ons
now this may be for distribution or just
for how they handled the loop
we suspended the accounts and hunted for
more and found an entirely different app
used in the same campaign this time it
was a javascript react app
which had some added functionality like
now they were after credit card
information
as well as credentials so this image
shows the collection of credit card
number
expiration date and cvv in french
we developed a ttp footprint for this
actor and continued to update the rules
to apply friction
they were very persistent and continued
to pivot this one pivot started using a
search engine add-on
to handle loot from their campaign as
well as still having the option to mail
it out
here's a look at information that they
were after
we also noticed that they were
distributing their efforts across a few
other service providers
the next big shift was another kit
although it does not appear to have been
created by this actor
but used in the same campaign the root
of that app looks like this
with some very obvious indicators that
stand out right drove in zero zero three
antibots and in the index.js file
they really didn't try to hide what they
were what they were doing
as the cat mouse continued we noticed
that this actor was further spreading
out across
other service providers the front end
would be on one
the back end on ours and distribution
would be on another
we want to break this bad actors spirit
not help them improve their coding
skills as we go back and forth
typically being in proximity to
sensitive information like what this
campaign was gathering
is like playing hot potato with toxic
waste unless you're the bad actor
then it has value but it's only valuable
if the information is valid so
considering this we did our best to get
that information
into the appropriate hands so that
passwords payment information
can all be reset and nullified strip the
value out of it
also we found ways to notify the other
service providers that were used in this
campaign
this put even more pressure on the actor
these two things disrupted their
operations enough that it appears to
push them from our platform
but now they're someone else's problem i
wish we had time to share more but for
now
consider these cases as we go into the
lessons learned section
so during my time working on the abuse
operations team we've gone from being
underwater to treading to surfacing high
enough to see land and set direction
we'll still get hit by some big waves
now and then but we've learned some
lessons that have helped us stay afloat
we've identified three guiding
philosophies for our team
the first relentless incrementalism
break complex problems into manageable
tasks
so that each is a step toward the final
solution
move fast and fix things it's a think
agile framework right
the non-repetition we never want to see
the same abuse pattern twice
nobody wants to be a button pushing
drone this keeps the job
interesting although as you may imagine
this is much easier said than done
and this is the closest we get to
prevention
and third hyper automation every click
counts toward toil having tools that
talk to tools including the ticketing
system
enables hyper automation and reduces
toil without losing accuracy
automation can be quickly putting the
right information in front of an analyst
the idea is to create more than just
detection rules but imagine entire
detection chains
know the business you are serving it's
said a lot but we're not here for the
sake of technology
or security or playing whack-a-mole even
though it's a lot of fun
we are here to serve the business so
learning about the different teams
across the organization their data
their language what kind of alerts they
have enabled what keeps them up at night
as we understand the priorities of other
teams we can help remove some of their
pain points
caused by abuse it gives us increased
situational awareness
and that in turn allows us to spot abuse
much earlier
this helps all of us succeed
most importantly though our
collaboration provides a channel
to let the right people know about the
gaps in business logic
this results in a platform that's too
much trouble to abuse by the bad actors
because now we can take that information
and push left and harden the platform
now this works for us but does that
really solve abuse
bad actors try to use heroku for a
variety of abuse scenarios
this is only one view of a much wider
problem
have you ever had a scam phone call
during dinner or have you purchased a
product based on what turned out to be
phony reviews
or were you unable to get a grocery
store pick-up time because somebody
reserved all of the slots to resell
we've listed what we don't allow in our
aup but that's a limited list especially
when you consider that abuse is
the unintended monetization of anything
now we are barely scratching the surface
and this definition is just an initial
attempt
maybe there's a more accurate definition
a more encompassing one a more
appropriate one
think about your free services or any
service that your company offers
how are those being abused how do they
fit in to the larger picture of abuse
and what are you doing about that
we want to take what we've discussed to
the greater internet
right now abuse feels like a zero-sum
game
we push bad actors from our platform
they take the path of least resistance
to the next
or distribute their workflow across
other service providers
abuse is a people problem removing the
actors motivation
will be much more effective than
continuously actioning what gets
reported
but it requires more there are some
challenging questions to work through
like these loaded questions
how do you define abuse what do you do
with malicious customers
how do you protect the good customers
while sanctioning the bad
how do you devalue loot when it's
treated as a customer's private data
is the internet worth saving
we are co-founding a cloud abuse ice act
with the cloud security alliance to have
these difficult conversations
more than just sharing ttps and stolen
credentials
if you're already a member you're
already invited
the sharing groups and backed channels
that exist today although excelling in
their own regard
are hobbled by politics procedures and
business policy
let's take a deeper look and see if we
can make this better
how can we help we should talk
thank you again for attending our talk
and thank you to black hat for having us
hi everyone thanks for uh tuning in to
our talk
thank you thank you for being here that
was this is an experience for sure
does anybody say one of the sorry the
quick things just to mention before q
a uh i think it might be worthwhile to
know that we do do a little bit more
coverage of some of the technical
aspects in
a blue team village talk on saturday if
you're uh
if you're there and interested and it'll
be on their twitch stream
and in that one we actually look at a
third uh
case for show and tell third campaign
that's a little bit different
oh actually hasn't quite stopped playing
it okay yes
[Music]
yes now
let's uh see if there's any uh questions
well we did have a question earlier
about um detection or response
tooling and just how we how we divide
that um
alan do you want to go into any any of
that as far as
um how we have our our tooling and our
development
or i guess engineering kind of separated
where we have ops tooling that we may be
responsible for that helps us in our
day-to-day
workflow and then we have uh stuff that
gets productionized which we have an
engineering team
but we can work together and set those
requirements we we do a lot of
abuse right alongs where we show them
what we're doing where those pain points
are
and they will be it's you know they
focus on getting something
uh productionized and ready for the
world
i think you just said it all quite
honestly
the the the turn around of that is kind
of the uh the the big piece there being
able to turn that loop around as fast as
possible in kind of that standard
agile environment especially if that's
what you're into or whatever other
development
uh system this you're using
you see jamie's question did you see
trace no um yeah
yeah i i guess uh
i would actually i think that that is a
the jamie's question
uh is fantastic for the seo stuff yeah
that took a little while to unravel i
was thinking about that we had um
uh dmca take down requests where it was
um the report was that there was a book
somebody's copyrighted material was
available for download
and when we looked at it it was just
kind of like the cover art and the book
title
um and inside were just links to go
download it elsewhere go sign up for
another account to go download it
somewhere else
and it really seemed like one of those
low value things you could just write
off you could action you could
and then go on but it would seem very
persistent it started to get
reported every so often and so when we
really looked and picked this this app
apart we found out that this was
spread out across thousands of accounts
and each app was uh was running um
oh hey
each app was running um uh black hat seo
black hat seo app where it would take
thousands of book titles like hundreds
of thousands of titles
break those into links flood the seos
the different search engines
all of them um and make it appear that
those books were available for download
and this was just one of those
uh low and slow operations where you
can't even imagine that they were making
money off of it but it had to have been
uh only profitable because they had
thousands of accounts all under control
and uh that was a lot of fun to turn
over a stone and actually figure out
that there are a lot of bugs under there
and i started putting rules in place
spinning those accounts and pushing them
from the platform
and making it much more difficult for
them to come back
dave asks do you use any data science
techniques or machine learning to
analyze your data and track
and tracking of bad actors over time uh
we've had a couple of brief forays into
that uh haven't done
the level uh that one would expect at
this time and it's mostly simply because
we're still trying to track
tackle kind of the simpler stuff uh it's
uh if we can do most of the stuff that
we need to do there
first and then turn on some of the more
scientific stuff for
uh what's left uh i think that we're
gonna ultimately have a better offering
in the long run
yeah that was one thing we were thinking
about sharing as well is how how far you
can get with just uh descriptive
analytics
or uh descriptive statistics where you
you know just using sort
in a command line and and some really
basic sql can show you some of these
patterns and you see how
um it really helps expose those
indicators that you can use
to form your footprint uh fernando asks
about uh homegrown versus open source
versus commercial uh so a lot of our
uh code is homegrown but most of that is
the integration code to make stuff talk
to each other
um on top of uh commercial offerings
um yeah and uh and
you can imagine that that does uh bring
about that complexity that we're talking
about briefly
[Music]
let's see uh got a question from jason
about how the
the organization was born and that's
that's funny because um it's
it's not really clear exactly how it was
born i think it was definitely more of a
uh
it was security that was tied to um
heroku itself and um as the company grew
and as salesforce grew and and
uh you know you'd have reorgs and shifts
of focus
it was funny to kind of try to find a
home for ourselves because we don't
really fit
it's like alan allen has said a lot is
uh abuse is kind of like the
in the twilight zone of information
security uh it doesn't really
fit in one's a particular place and you
look at other other companies and
they'll have
abuse as a function of fraud because if
you offer
you know a lot of times fraud will be an
enabler to uh to abuse
um and so we've kind of had to to work
with that and find our own place and
carve it out where we can which which
really does lead to a lot of
collaboration
actually uh before we run out oh darn
i'm gonna answer in chat
thomas thank you for your time thank you
for coming thanks everybody