[Music]
hello everybody
this is frank block and you're watching
hiding process memory
via anti-forensic techniques this talk
is based on the research
that i've done together with ralph
politger patrick reichenberger and
dominic schwepper
from the university of erlangenberg so
this was a cooperation between the emw
research and the university of erlang
to the agenda we will start with a short
introduction some technical background
then dive into the subversion techniques
there are three of them
then we'll talk a little bit about about
challenges and some considerations
after that we'll have a look at
evaluation so we have
evaluated our techniques with memory
forensics and life forensics techniques
after that we'll talk about and have a
look at detection approaches
evaluate those two and at the end some
conclusion
there's some radiated work that i wanted
to mention also to give you an idea what
this is about and what
is different from them the first great
research that i want to mention is
shadow walker by sherry sparks and jaime
butler
so what they basically did was changing
the mapping between witcher and physical
memory and by that any subsequent
access to a which address would not end
up anymore at
the actual physical content for that
mutual address
we are doing something similar but there
are three major differences between
those two approaches
on the one hand shadow walker
only focused on the kernel space it
required a hook in the
page fault handler in order to work and
the third difference is that it doesn't
work anymore
on current cpus so sadly or luckily
and the second related work that i
wanted to mention is gargoyle by josh
los pinozzo
he concentrated on the process address
space so similar to our approaches
but he didn't his approach doesn't hide
the actual memory content but he
changed some characteristics of the
injected code
in this case the executable state and by
that
tried tries to hide from detection tools
uh our approach is here in this case
different we are
solely interested in hiding the actual
memory content so we don't change
characteristics
uh the memory is still executable for
example in some cases
but the actual memory content behind it
is hidden
okay let's talk about a little bit a
little bit about some
technical backgrounds so the procedure
space contains
different data executables dlls
schedule shared libraries or heap
stack data whatsoever and all those
memory areas are described by what we
will call in this context
memory error structures so mes
structures
on windows those are virtual address
descriptors on linux those are
virtual memory areas and as you can see
one thing that both those types have in
common both those structures have in
common
is a start and an end pointer so you can
see here that
the start address points to the
beginning of the memory area and the end
pointer to the end
and normally every memory in the which
address base of a process is described
by at least one
or ideally by one memory error structure
so the second second part that we're
going to talk a little bit about is the
depends are the paging structures
so the process of translating a virtual
address to a physical
page frame the relevant part for us here
in this case is
just a page table so at the end of the
translation process
we will end up for a which address on a
specific pte a page table entry this one
contains a pointer to the actual page
frame that contains the memory for the
switch address
and the widget just also has a page
offset into this page frame where the
actual
byte is that byte is located where this
address points to
and yeah exactly this is something that
we are going to
[Music]
tamper with also to mention right here
now
is uh on both operating systems on
windows and linux there are some reverse
mappings
so in windows there's the page frame
number database and the linux
the page structures and those are more
or less the
physical point of view and the memory
but we will dig a little bit
deeper into those two types a little bit
later
and the third part is shared memory so
the idea of short memory is to just
share data between different processes
and the relevant part for us here to
mention
is that shared memory as um despite
in contrast to private memory is still
accessible
if the shared memory has been unmapped
so if it's not
part of any process for example anymore
not in
not mapped in any virtual address space
it can still be wrestling in a physical
memory and can still be remapped as long
as at least
one process has a handle to the shared
memory
so that's something to keep in mind and
there are different ways to create
shared memory on windows there's
especially this
api sequence on linux there are at least
three different
ways to create shared memory that we had
a look at and we will see later
okay let's start with our separation
techniques in general
we are trying to hide process memory
with those
those techniques can be used
independently or can also be combined
and our scenario is for example an
attacker that injected code into another
process
and now wants to hide this memory or he
wants to hide memory that is in
his own process space
so the first technique is what we will
call
mas remapping so the idea was
to do this technique is because that
many tools
attention tools depend on the
information provided by those structures
so you rely on those and this is why we
wanted to remap some of the information
so to change the information in order to
hide
our malicious memory um one thing to
note here is that this technique will
require kernel level privileges
so this is something to keep in mind so
we are here right now at the beginning
with our malicious memory
and we are now trying to hide it by just
simply
changing those pointers here so you can
now see here the effect so what we did
is we placed some benign data in the
beginning
which is not malicious any in any way
and we are changing the
pointers in that way that the malicious
memory which is
placed right after is not described or
not contained
in this area so they're not described
by the vm and vm start they are not in
this range
so there's no mes structure anymore at
this point of
time that is including this memory area
right here
but still it can can still be accessed
especially by the cpu cpu executed
because the cu cpu doesn't care about
the mas structures
it only is interested or
uses the ptes in order to do the
translation and to access the memory
and those are still valid and are still
there so this
works after this modification fine
one advantage of this technique in
regards to the other twos
to the other two that we will see right
now
is that there's no it is not necessary
to reverse
this modification in order for the
malicious coach to execute
so the second technique also requires
kernel privileges
in order to work and it also requires
some restoration so
it is necessary to all the time unhide
and re-hide
the memory in order for it to work and
we will talk about
two different flavors of this technique
so we are calling them
pt subversions and we have the pte rimer
peng
and the pte erasure and the beginning in
both cases is the same so we have here
our malicious page
and we have a benign page with data that
is yeah not malicious at all
and our goal now is to remap in the
first technique to remake
remap this witcher address to this
benign data by simply changing the pfn
so there's a field and this pte that
points to the physical page
and we are just changing this volume so
that this which
address does it uh from this point on um
point to this benign data down here
and this page here has no pte the point
switch is not mapped in any virtual
address
and hence can't be accessed simply by
enumerating or
accessing which addresses anymore
the second technique is what we call pte
erasure so in this case
we are nullifying so we are erasing the
pte
just putting zeros in there so there's
also in this case
no more reference to this malicious page
it's not mapped in any rich address
space anymore
and any access to this which address
will end up in no memory
which is not a problem per se because um
this can be
for when it reasons the case for example
if the page has not yet been accessed
um then this would be look the same so
it's not suspicious by itself
if there's a rich address that points to
a pte that is zero
and the third technique that we want to
talk about is shared memory subversion
so the idea here is now to use shared
memory in order to hide our manager's
content
and it is not to mention
i wanted to mention that it is not
necessary to share memory
um between poses shadman we can also use
solely by one process and this is also
the way we are using it
our evil process does use this memory
more or less like private memory
but with the advantages that come with
chad memory from the attacker's point of
view
so what the attacker does is he creates
a shared memory segment
and puts his malicious code in there and
then
the first step unmaps it so it's not
visible anymore
and then after that anytime he wants to
use it he will remap it and again and
again one
major advantage of this technique is
that it doesn't require any kernel
privileges so it can be used with solely
users with
solely standard user privileges
so the attack process after we have set
it up is more or less like this
as soon as the evil process wants to
execute or access the malicious data
it shortly unmaps it into
its memory space executed or reads data
from it and then unmaps it again
and by that we successfully hide from
most of the tools or from
nearly every detection tool that we
evaluated by simply
with the with the simple trick so
why is that that this memory can't be um
detected by any of the tools that we
will
see later let's dig a little bit into
the details
so with the unmapping what happens in
the background
is that the page tab entries for this
shared memory
are zeroed so they are not pointing
anymore to the malicious pages
but there must be still some reference
to it because it is possible
to remit it remap those pages so there
must be some kind of reference to them
and this reference is more or less
hidden behind this memory handle that
the process keeps
in order for the pages not to be erased
in the case of windows this memory
handle is a section
object so a pointer to a section object
and this section
object the section structure is located
in the kernel address space
so if you're following the section
structure we are getting to a control
area field
this one points to the controller area
structure
which is more or less um pointing to the
file
if there's a if there's a file related
to this memory area
and right after that more interesting
more interestingly for us
is a subsection structure or there can
be multiple ones and those are pointing
to the so-called prototype pds and this
is the interesting part for us
because those type ptes contain the
actual pointer to the malicious pages
so the reason why we are that we don't
find this
malicious memory also if we scan the
kernel
address space is that the pages are not
mapped into the kernel address space so
those prototype pds are not part of the
page tables for the kernel address for
the kernel
so they are not mapped into the current
address space but only
those prototype pd's itself are part of
the virtual address space of the kernel
so it's just data
lying in there those ptes they are not
part of the
page tables itself from for for the
kernel and that means that
those pages are not mapped into the
address space and hence the memory
content
can't be found when searching the
witcher address space
okay let's have a look at the evaluation
we implemented our techniques for
windows and linux
and tested those in multiple vms
for windows and linux and both in both
cases on x64 architectures
and this is the those are the results
for the memory forensics point of view
we used multiple plugins we used
yarascan plugins
we use recall and volatility for all
those plugins
and what you can see for yar scan for
example is that volatility cr scan was
not able to detect
any of our hidden malicious content
but recalled it the reason is that
recall does a raw search so it doesn't
rely on any
virtual address structures which address
translation structures
it only searches the raw memory and by
that
he finds our hidden code but
obviously this only works if we know
upfront what we are searching for
so it doesn't work as a generic method
we also had a look at some dumping
plugins so we dumped
the memory content of the processes and
only in the case of
the mas remapping and only
with volatility we were able to find our
malicious code in there
with the other tools and other plugins
it was not the case and
also we did find our malicious code by
if we accessed it directly so if we used
recall or volatility the interactive
shell
and the reach for the virtual address in
this case also it was possible
to detect the malicious memory but only
in the case again for mas remapping
and a third time again with pte num
we were also able to find our engineer
code for mes remapping
but besides that in all other cases our
malicious code
was not found by any of those plugins
in some cases there were some indicators
that could
maybe give you a hint about something
fishy going on but the actual memory
content was only detected in those cases
that i mentioned earlier
so from a live forensics point of view
it gets a little bit worse
on the one hand we also use the tools
yara
and scanned all the processes um
none of our hidden memory has been
detected by yara
um we were able to detect our malicious
content
in the case of mas remapping again with
the
debugger but only on windows so with the
wind debug
tool we were we were able to find our
manager's content by searching
and also by directly accessing the
visual addresses but besides that
none of those approaches were able to
find our
hidden malicious code we tried
dumping the process address space with
debug with gdb within debug
also used process explorer on g-core but
our image's content wasn't in those
dumps but at least in some cases there
were errors
um pointing out that some of the
addresses seemed to be that
seemed to be something wrong with them
so there were some indicators but the
actual memory content
was only detected in those two cases for
mes remapping and not in the other cases
and also to mention the shared memory
scenario with shem get
on linux was not at all in any case in
any way detected by any of those
plugins or tools okay
let's talk about some challenges and
considerations some things that you have
to consider when you're implementing and
using those techniques
and the one hand as mentioned earlier
for pte subversions and chat memory
we need still some control code that has
to be somewhere so this could be
detected
in order to unhide and re-hide the
memory we did also
lock our memory in order to prevent any
interferences from page swapping and
also to prevent any side effects we
are doing we are undoing all our
modifications
right before the process exits also
especially on linux
there are some fields that you want to
have a look at and might
in some cases have to that you might
have to adjust in order to prevent side
effects especially if you're not on
doing the modifications
then there are some counters that you
might have a look at and might have to
adjust in order to prevent any problems
okay let's talk a little bit about a
problem on windows with the standard pfn
remapping
so if we are doing the pfn remapping as
explained earlier
this will lead to crashes especially if
we for example
scan the process with yara then a pretty
reliable crashes after
the pfn remapping so we came up with a
little work around in this case
this is an initial situation so the pte
points to a malicious memory and what we
now do in order to prevent
the detection is to in the first step to
erase to
erase it similar to the pta ratio but
we added some additional steps so what
we then do after that we are doing a
read access to the switch address
which will lead to the creation of a new
page because the
operating system will think um there has
not yet been created any page for this
um virtual address so we are creating it
that means that after that we have two
pages
which relate on correspond to this pte
and after that we are simply switching
between those two pages
in order to hide and unhide our
malicious memory and by that we are
preventing the process from crashing
if yara scans it there's still some
issue left with this approach at blue
screens
as soon as the process exits we have not
yet identified what exactly is the
problem with that so this is something
to be done
and will be hopefully fixed in the next
few weeks or months
so let's talk about memories of version
detection
first mas remapping detection what we
are using here
are the paging structures we are
enumerating all the page tables
and examining the page table entries
each page table entry corresponds to a
virtual address
and by examining the page table entry we
know which virtual addresses are
currently valid so they
are referencing page frames that are
currently mapped
and we can use this information to check
whether or not they are
virtual addresses which are not
described by a vm area structure but are
valid
so in this case we have those two which
addresses which seem to reference
valid page frames so there's actually
memory content behind them
but they are not part of any mas
structure so that's something suspicious
which we alert on
now the pt subversion detection on
windows it's on linux
different story so we are splitting this
detection into parts on windows we now
have here the initial situation
so the messages pte points currently
still to the malicious page and
in this case here now we have also the
physical point of view
on the memory the phn database which we
mentioned earlier briefly
this is just an more or less just an
array of mmpfn structs which are indexed
by the pfn number
so the pfn here points at the one hand
through the page
to the page frame and to a mmp of
instruct over here
each mmpf instruct for valid page
also points back to the pte that
belongs to it so we have here a kind of
loop
that points back and forth so we are now
doing the pt remapping so we are
changing the pfn value
the pointers get modified
so we are now pointing at the b9 page
down here and we are also referencing
another
mmph instruct so that means we have
a broken loop we have a valid loop down
here because um this mmph instructor
belongs to a valid page
the benign patch is already there and we
have a valid loop here
but we have also the pointer from from
over here
which does not point back over here so
this is something that we can detect on
also by enumerating all the mmpf
instructs we will encounter this one
here which points to this pte
but the pte does not point back so this
is also something that we can detect
and the third part here is the pfn
number so by enumerating all the ptes
and collecting all the page frame
numbers
we can detect duplicates
and by that the pt remapping this only
works for shared memory for private
memory
with shared memory this doesn't work
because with chat memory it's quite
common that multiple ptes
point to the same page frame to the same
page frame
also this detection here does not work
with shared memory because for shared
memory
those mmpfns don't point to this pt but
to the prototype pte
so we don't have this loop that we can
detect on so this detections here
only work with private memory on windows
the detection that we will now see for
in a few seconds on linux does work also
with shared memory
okay now the last slide for windows
in this case we see now our motif or
modified pte remapping
because the original one as i said um
crashes when yara is for example
scanning the process
so this is the situation the detection
is more or less the same only the
situation
is a bit different so we can see now
here um we have
our pfn value which points at the second
page which has been created for this pte
so the uh also created mmpfn struct
points back to this pt so this loop here
is fine
it points back and forth validly so
there's nothing suspicious here
but there are two um things to mention
over here
at the one hand we have again an mmp of
n struct which points to this
pte but this pt doesn't point back and
also we have two
mm pfn structs which point to the same
pt
so those are two characteristics that we
can detect on
okay let's now look at linux
the physical the point of view on the
physical memory
on linux is are the page structures so
there are several page structures which
are more or less also
indexed by the page frame number and by
enumerating those we can collect
pages which belong page structures which
belong together and also physical pages
by that manner
this is done by looking at the mapping
object that is referenced by those page
structures
this mapping object is also referenced
by the vm area structures
so by this mapping we can correlate
pages
with their corresponding vm area
structures
um a little thing to mention over here
there can be multiple mappings
per vm area structure and the one end
mapping camera can be referenced by the
f mapping so this is the case for
files that are mapped and also in this
case they can additionally be the n on
vmat chain
pointing to mappings there can be
multiple ones this is especially the
case
when forking and when using copy and
write
protections and then getting private
copies being created
those are then referenced by those
mappings so there can be multiple ones
just something that we have to keep in
mind when investigating this issue that
we have to
collect all of them behind those mapping
is
in this case for the nmn vma chain uh uh
n on vma structs
and for the f mapping it's an
address-based struct but this detail
doesn't really matter for us
uh the only thing that we are interested
in is are the um the
object itself which we can use to
correlate the page structures
with the vm error structure so the
fields of those
mappings are not really interesting to
us just the object itself
okay now let's have a look at the other
side so when we are now enumerating the
which addresses foreign vm
area struct we can resolve them to the
page frame number and by that
get the corresponding page structure and
again we can
um collect them based on the mapping
and in this case we have three virtual
addresses with the
three page structures which belong to
this mapping which also corresponds to
the
mapping for this vm error structure if
we are now looking at
our our attacks in this case the pt
erasure
the initial situation is that we have
the analysis page over here which is
still referenced
now we are erasing the pte the pointer
goes
goes away and when we are enumerating
the witcher addresses
we now only get two pages because this
one doesn't um
belong to any page structure anymore
because it doesn't have a corresponding
pfn so when we are collecting those for
this
vm area for the witcher addresses we
only get two pages
for this mapping or with this mapping if
we on the other hand
enumerating all the page structures
collecting them based on their mapping
and then looking for each vm error
struct for their corresponding mapping
and the pages
we will see that we will end up with
three pages page structures
so we can clearly see a diff two on the
left side
three on the right side and this is
something suspicious which we alert
so and the last step uh is our shared
memory subversion detection
it's small it's the same on linux and
windows and we are basically just
enumerating all the shared memory
handles
and looking for those which are
currently not mapped into the original
address space and alert on them
on windows we are additionally checking
for the executable permission
so we are only alerting on executable
memory because there would otherwise be
a lot of false positives
on linux we are not checking for the
exitable state because it's a not a
reliable way
to detect this kind of memory and hence
we
also have some false puzzles on linux
which we'll see later
okay let's now talk about detection
about the
evaluation of our detection approaches
we use the same environment as for the
memory subversion evaluation
additionally for the false positive
positive evaluation we
started several browsers office
applications
and also pdf documents and
this will the results of that we will
see a little bit later
okay here are some some examples for
detection on windows
in the first case we have an output of
our recoil plug-in for the standard pfn
remapping
so not our modified version so what
would look would look like in the output
if we would use the standard version and
also for the pt erasure
so the first two entries here are
an output for the pfn remapping so we
can see here in the dot pfn
column that we have a true for the first
two entries so there
we can see also here in the pfn column
that there's in fact
the same pfn value for those two entries
and what we
also can see is a true value for the pte
pointer div
which means that the pte with its pfn
points to a certain mmpf instruct
but the mmp instruct doesn't point back
so we have a
diff over here and this also means that
the second entry is the malicious one or
most probably dimensionless one
because it has the value true in this
case
and this the third entry is an example
for the three zero for the pte erasure
we have in the column zero pde a true
uh we can also see that the pte value is
actually zero
and um this means that we have a mmpfn
struct identified which is valid and
points to a pte
which however has a pt value of zero
which shouldn't be the case and this is
something that is
detected over here and the second
example is an
example output for mas remapping so in
this case we have in the column
orphaned page a true value for those two
virtual addresses
which means that they are currently
valid but not described by any
mas here are some examples for
the evaluation on linux first pte
remapping
so here we can see output essentially
two mappings that
have been identified by our plugins the
first case is in
false positive so we have in the systemd
journal process we have
some mappings that are reported here but
it
is not an attack so it's no subversion
technique that has been
resolved for this so in linux we have
quite some false processes in some cases
but the second output is in fact a
result of our pte subversion
attack so we have two pages
which are not referenced by the virtual
addresses but are
part of the page structures so this is
detected over here and the last output
here is an example for shared memory on
linux in this case
so we have a shared memory handle which
is currently not mapped in any process
or not in this process so this is
reported
okay now let's have a look at false
positives first windows
regarding mes remapping there have been
some false positives
in the context of chromium so
there were pages which are not described
by any mes structure which is
interesting and we
are planning to have a closer look at
regarding pd sub versions
there are no false poses at the moment
known at least we didn't
find any in our test environments and
regarding shared memory
subversion there can be false positives
obviously if the process has a shared
memory handle but
does not have this memory mapped into
its address space
but in our test environment we did not
encounter any shard memory
segment that is executable or not mapped
at the moment
with linux mis remapping is not
implemented yet so
we can't make any statements there pd
subversion
on linux there were quite some false
positives especially for the firefox
and for the systemd journal process so
this is something that we
are trying to optimize in the next time
some
hopefully we'll come up with a solution
for that and regarding essentially the
shared memory subversion
uh in our test cases uh also again with
the firefox we had quite some
false positives 40 shared memory
segments that were reported by our
plugin
so it's also something where we might be
able hopefully in the future to
improve the output okay let's come to
the conclusion
here we can see a simple short
comparison
of the techniques from a ticker's point
of view we already mentioned
all the advantages and disadvantages so
it's just for the documentation
to conclude with this research and with
this talk we
introduced three novel subversion
techniques
which are able to hide memory from
memory and live forensics on windows and
linux
we are releasing with this talk also
some proof of concept implementations
for both operating systems
that implement our subversion techniques
and our plugins
the recall and volatility plugins that
we've implemented which are applying the
detection approaches which
we have described in this talk and those
are all
referenced in the next slides where you
can
grab them some limitations
um we still have the issue for the
subversion with the blue screen and
windows
with our pd subversions so this is
something that we need to
fix also the detection approaches for
the pt subversions on windows
can be circumvented by shared memory by
the usage of chat memory
so there's something that we have uh in
the future to have a closer look at
also there were quite some false
positives with windows with linux
with the detections so that's something
that's not
ideal at the moment also an additional
problem in linux there can be page
instances so paid structure instances
that have no
corresponding mapping and by that
it's not possible for us at the moment
to attack those
pages with in regards to subversion
techniques
and also again on linux our ptc version
detection implementation is at the
moment quite
time consuming the main reason is that
we
have not yet implemented the ms
remapping detection because the same
approach
for that is also used to speed up the pd
subversion
so as soon as we have implemented that
also the pd subversion detection should
be faster but at the moment it's quite
slow okay some words to future work
one thing that we want to have a closer
look at is different ways
for mapping shared memory especially
using subfuse
and by that maybe circumventing our
detection approaches
also we want to resolve the windows
crash obviously
and we are also wanting to have a closer
look at the
new windows 10 memory combining feature
so this might be something that
interferes with our detection and
subversion
techniques and we should have a closer
look at
and last but not least manipulating
everything that we've used for detection
so far
so the mmp mmp fans drugs paid
structures
messing with those might be interesting
to look at in order to
prevent the detection from being
successful
so with that thank you for attention if
there are any questions hopefully we
have some time for them
here are the resources so all the links
to all the proof concept implementations
and plugins
and with that are there any questions
okay hello everybody i hope you can hear
me fine
i'm not sure if it's working right now
because my screen freaks here
and now i see there's a movement
yeah hello
yeah i started to talk but i'm not sure
if everybody can hear me
maybe in the chat someone can tell me if
you hear me fine
but do they hear me because i don't see
any reactions in the chat
okay yeah
hello so if there are any questions feel
free to
do it in the chat um
otherwise thank you for your attention
hope you enjoyed the talk and the rest
of the conference
oh yeah okay now
yeah thank you let's see now that you
can hear me
i had a little delay in the chat so i
was not sure okay
thank you very much
i don't see any questions right now
then yeah feel free to contact me um
there's some
coding information in the github page
feel free to email me
uh my linkedin handle should also be in
my profile so
yeah if there are any further questions
later on feel free to
uh question and put a question somewhere
in the
mobile world uh otherwise
yeah enjoy the rest of the conference
see
you too thank you