[Music]
hello everyone
my name is tamagna basu and
i'm here to talk about how i use ai to
clone myself
in the digital chat so let's get started
so brief about me i am the cto and
co-founder for neoid
uh i have like tickets of experience in
this industry
uh currently i work on neoid as the cto
and apart from that obviously i kind of
advise couple of startups
and i'm a mentor for stanford cyber
security course as well
in terms of domain i do work in cyber
security machine learning and you know
i've been working
in various domain like finance insurance
uh gaming ecommerce etc etc
and uh i'm a frequent speaker on
multiple conferences
i've done it in past and uh primarily i
did it because of
obviously as part of my community
activities
so that you know we learn from community
and we also try to give back
to the community right so moving on
as part of our current company what i do
is
we actually work on a science called
behavioral science
or behavioral analytics as few of
you might be aware of that subject but
what i do is
we actually try to profile a person
based on the behavior they do they
acquire over the time the habits they
acquire on devices for example
how you type how you hold the phone how
you walk
all these are unique for each individual
so together we
capture all these kind of parameters and
try to build a profile of a person a
behavioral persona
and uh and use it for protecting your
identity so that if someone tries to
impersonate you
we can identify based on the behavior
saying that is that you
or is somebody else who is trying to
impersonate you
right and why this is important because
that's what uh
also sets the background of this uh this
this talk so today's agenda is this we
will be talking about uh
obviously the background the demo the
architecture
and as i mentioned then i will be
releasing the code so i will be showing
on the code
code base and and obviously
the next steps what are the next thing
can be done
and and see if any of you would be
interested to
contribute to this or not i'll be more
than happy to collaborate and i know
secure support of this
right uh moving on so the inspiration
uh was uh two part
one was as i was mentioning uh while
working in new york
where we're trying to do behavioral
analysis so
one side we were trying to use behaviors
to protect your identity to prevent
identity fraud
so our objective was can i use ai to
identify
if there is any fraud impersonation
happening or not
now while doing it we got this other
idea also
more from an adversarial aspect uh
saying that
okay uh what if we use it to
replicate an identity what if we can use
it to clone someone right
so that is the kind of idea we had and
uh
and you know obviously the uh it got
kicked by this episode of blackmail uh
which was actually
season two uh first episode called be
right back
where uh the story goes like uh this
lady martha
she uh she lost her boyfriend ash
on a car accident and
she was very upset and obviously she was
trying to get back to life but
couldn't cope up with the depression now
there was a futuristic company which
kind of you know approached
to her saying that i could bring we
could bring back ash
to you uh via chats via
you know via social media via
video and audio and stuff like that so
she registered and the first interface
became a chat interface where
she could chat with ash over let's say
some sort of messenger
and moving from there it became a phone
call where they upgrade to a next plan
where you know we can actually have a
disc
a phone call with ash uh with ash's
voice and then obviously finally there
was
a 3d kind of a model that's actually a
person comes
so so that's how the story goes so
definitely this actually
uh kind of you know hit me and i thought
okay why don't you start like the same
way
and see if it's possible or not so i
started like a small experiment
that's uh that's how it started so here
is a quick chat about i created
and i just want to show some of the
sample chats
uh which a conversation happened between
a human and the bot
so here it goes this is the first one so
so here the left side
of the of the screen was bought and the
right side was a human and this human is
a co-founder of mine lsu
so this is a discussion how it unfolds
uh so unless you ask something start and
then you say start what
then the bot says uh lsu's is bought
uh this is what is a guy and uh nice to
meet you bot nice to meet you too
so what can i do be a better bot so i'm
not about this guy become like you know
say i'm a wrong person so
so you can see the it is able to handle
some sort of chit chats
a bit a little bit of sarcasm as well
and uh then the human says really
then it and emphasizes yes
i am raw pencil right so uh so nice to
meet you
and says yes uh nice to meet you
and uh then comes you seems like an
intelligent guy i says i'm glad you
noticed
so where are you i'm at kevin no where
are you
i'm outside so uh so it looks like a
very general conversation uh now what
lsu tries to do it try to
get into little more knowledge aspects
of the bot so
what he asked that you know are you an
intelligent guy can you tell me about
something are you a cyber security
person
uh bob says no the necessary quantum
physics the bot says yes
i'm a quantum physicist then he asked
okay can you explain particle anytime uh
what says i have no idea what that means
so
so yeah uh and then since you are not a
quantum physicist
so you're about there yes i've been told
so right so
uh this this there is a funny aspect
there is a sarcasm there is a normal
kind of chat chat is happening
now uh there are further conversations
happened on the similar line with other
people
this is another person uh a discussion
happened between bot and another person
and uh this guy asked how old are you
what says some sort of you know funny
joke is just a number
uh you're so as also this is but how old
are you
what do you think how old i am that's 18
and then it cracks a joke it says you
know what sounds like you know i can
crack a joke for you
now this is another person and this guy
tries to become little more
philosophical
so he says okay fine is that a
philosophical question
so this is an interesting question you
know do the
and there's some random discussion so
that's again
uh a behavioral trait which i have let's
say
when i talk to my friends randomly you
know switch the topic
show some sort of sarcasm you know be
funny at times
so definitely it looks like you know
those kind of flavor
of behaviors is able to replicate here
right and uh and here is a small social
proof of that
uh the idea was uh when i built this
as sort of a beta testing i tried with a
close group of friends
and when i said friends they are all
working professionals
entrepreneurs as well as cyber security
experts who are you know
friends in my network i've just given
them this
bot over whatsapp or telegram and ask
them to chat with it
and and in our common friends group this
is free of the friend has responded back
saying that you know
it feels like uh it looks like you know
it's
it's not a part but they thought uh it's
me actually is chatting uh
with with them right so so although uh
i'm not saying that i have passed the
turing test but uh but definitely this
gives me a to some extent a bit of
satisfactory
uh result of feelings saying that okay
fine you know what it looks like you
know it's
it's try i'm trying to achieve a part of
the objective which i have all right now
now here is a small video demonstration
taking it to the furthest so let me show
you the further now what kind of final
outcome we're looking at
and this is actually a bot which is
actually talking over video
hey how's it going good how are you
i'm doing very well thanks how are you
good okay hey
need some help if you don't mind tell me
well it's a bit awkward to ask you this
really sorry
right so uh we will see this demo
further
more details but you can see that you
know it's quite quite achievable
and uh it's it's something you know i'm
able to
uh able to do uh uh with with
with the video and audio um so that's
that's that's the ultimate goal i had so
my
ultimate objective was can i build a
an avatar of mine let's say which can
be used uh to actually
have a conversation uh over text
voice and video uh as a channel right so
so that's what i know we're trying to do
so so let's deep dive into the
architecture and see
how how how this this has been built
right so so at the entire project i have
kind of you know split it in three parts
uh i call it the brain the voice and the
face
all right uh the brain is the engine
uh the the nlp engine
which is the crux of this entire entire
project where
it knows uh a sort of you know what kind
of discussion what kind of questions
uh and what kind of answers i should
give how we should generate answers
in what context i should generate
answers and when i'm generating when i'm
responding to somebody or you know
creating an answer
it should resemble uh some sort of some
part of my behavioral threats
right so this is this is something this
is the crux of the
entire
and the next part is the voice and the
face right so the voice comes which is
uh
about the voice cloning uh where i can
try to then
clone my voice and see that we can talk
like uh in an
audio which is sounds like me and
finally the face
where you know can it be in my face you
know my uh
appearance right now uh just to
mention here uh we guys already know
about
you know defects right you know the uh
defect
on voice defect on face and audio so
there's a lot of videos like that has
been there
so as i said i'm not here to make
another
solution which is better than what is
there in the industry so i'm pretty sure
defects or you know
voice cloning the the neural network
whatever is there is fine
which is much better and you know work
perfectly fine
the point here i'm trying to make is is
can i make it
interactive can i make it more lively
now in the chatbot domain
uh this can this kind of concept is
called open domain chatbot
now this is one of the most difficult
area of research where can i build a
chatbot where you know
based on with an nlp and neural network
where i can have a free flow discussion
right so that's what is the
part which eighty percent of the time
i've spent
during this research right so let's dive
into this
uh this part and see what exactly i have
done right
so the brain when i talk about the brain
right it is it is
the it is an engine which learns from
the
my past behavior known as the past
behavior
it's just my past conversation so what i
did is in terms of in a nutshell is
basically i have kind of
extracted out all my possible lesser
chat
histories which i have used you know i
have kind of you know spoken to
different
people in facebook whatsapp linkedin
uh over email and i've kind of collected
all this data
i have processed this data created in a
meaningful manner saying okay you know
what this is
this is the kind of the sample data
which you should be trained
and with this data you should understand
that my way of saying things
right is so that you know somebody
who has already spoken to me in past and
the person
again tries to talk to me the person
should get the similar feeling right in
terms of you know discussion
now then i fade into various kind of
model and this part was the tricky part
because uh
honestly speaking there was not much uh
a good model i was getting so basically
i tried multiple model
uh sequential model neural machine empty
model
uh and then rule and intent based model
uh these are model
various kind of you know ways of you
know generating text
right in nlp family with nlp these are
these are various ways you do it but
overall the uh the idea was actually we
use a sequential model
uh we try to feed in some context to
that and
and then generate an output now the
output as i said uh
wasn't uh always good so what i tried to
do is basically
i created multiple model feed in the
data
uh whenever there's an input comes it
generates an output which is a response
and then looking at the confidence score
find out what is the best
possible answer which i could get and
then give that back to the
step so that's this is a very basic uh
explanation of how it works so this is
the training part once this training is
done
we generate the model and
we do it now the problem with this is
all this model
are good in terms of it is able to
get the let's say the utterances the the
words kind of words are used and stuff
like that
however most of the time it
is not able to generate a sentence which
makes sense
so it generate a collection of words
but those words together doesn't form
meaningful standard
sentence in that context that was one of
the challenge i had
and that then made me you know take a
different route for this approach
right and and this is where you know
that the next
kind of category of approach which i'll
be spending time on
so what i try to do first is i try to
look into this data and categorize them
into multiple
uh branches saying that okay when i'm
having some conversation what
kind of conversation mostly i had or i'm
kind of you know i can i can feed this
into in different buckets
so there are four categories uh possibly
i could identify one is chit chat
chit chat is nothing but simply hi hello
how are you
those kind of discussion second is
historical data historical data means
this is something i have spoken or i
have told
or i i kind of had this conversation on
this context
and the same kind of question was asked
to me again
right so uh so maybe you know something
uh which somebody you know can i come to
your house today
and you know or shall we meet tomorrow
right so
something like that which is which is
already been discussed or probably you
know in on a specific context right okay
fine i am going to this hackathon
are you coming to me uh coming to uh
join me
something like that now comes uh that's
called category two now the category
three
was a topical factual something like
basically how is the weather today or
what is sequel injection or probably it
could be let's say
okay how long it will take for you to
come from uh
bangalore something like that right so
there is some part of knowledge is
required for that
that is category three and uh category
fourth was
pure generative uh philosophical
anything which is not the category one
two or three which is basically is a
free flow chart right
it could be you know what is the purpose
of life you know what is love
you know defined life something like
that something
generic so these are overall the four
category and what i
i tried to do is i realized that you
know when i
i try to create do a different treatment
for this different category
and uh that's how we can actually you
know i try to
get a better response or better result
of this
this engine right now how do i handle it
this is how i handled it so rasa is an
open source
chat chatbot framework using which you
can actually create a chatbot this is
mostly used for
let's say not open domain but a closed
domain chatbot where actually you have
some specifically say a hotel booking
board
or some business toilet and what people
ask it now how it works it has basically
there are four three four properties
first is called intent
this is nothing but okay uh what the
user is
want to know or want to do what is the
intent of the user
so for example if user is saying hey hi
how are you
good morning what's up intent wants to
greet me all right
if a user says goodbye good night uh
see uh then which means intent means
user wants to
uh say goodbye right so this is called
intent
now then you define okay if this is the
what is the response i would i should
i should i should say right if someone
says bye i should say bye
if someone says great i should say hello
or how are you
or hi just like that right so this is
the responsibility of five
and then you club to stitch them
together so this is where you actually
this is called stories this is called
intent this is called utterances and
this is called stories
and this story is nothing but you say
this is where you say okay this is the
if there is a grid you should do a
respond to it at all to it
if there is a tank uh you will play with
a turnover is
like that right so that's how you club
it together and say okay if users is buy
what says by user says thanks bot says
no worries like that
so this is where the category one the
chit chat can be handled because when i
say chit chat hi hello how are you
the the majorly the the response will
not change right it will be the similar
kind of response
so i used rasa for the category one uh
kind of records
now comes the category two which is
historical data
so this is where a lot of data
processing uh
comes so what i've did is we
we as i said no we used multiple data
sources like
my whatsapp chat history facebook chat
history
linkedin you know discussions or over
messages
and we kind of pass all this thing
together and uh
and i know i created this this format
say okay this is the message and this is
the response
which essentially means that okay this
is what i was asked to me
in past by somebody and this was the
response i have given
in return so so for example someone says
thanks boss then i said okay
why thanks this is a little bit of hindi
but thanks sorry for not getting much
involved
stuff like that right so yes can we meet
let everything say sure come over
this is hindi right so so this is what
uh the format of the structure i added
the structure and created
now what i use this for now there is
another open source chatbot
framework called chatterbot i use this
for
handling this because what it does is
this is where
you can actually give a collection of
user
uh a free flow question answer and get
it
right and what happens is so that next
time
if someone ask any of this the first one
then the respond will be second one
if someone says third one the response
will be the fourth one
so like that excuse me uh chatterbot uh
works uh so this this is where i handled
historical uh data and the conversations
right we use chatterboard for that
now third is the if you remember third
one was the topical they're asking the
questions right you know how far
bangalore is from delhi
or how far less anywhere is from
california but what is the time right
now in
in san jose uh something like that
so uh for that uh we again use
rasa but rasa has a different component
called custom actions
what is that means this is where you
define a structure in terms of
you can call a third party api right you
can call a third party
service to gather data and using the
data you can actually
uh identify uh the response and do it so
for example this is one
uh kind of action create i created which
is which goes in wikipedia and get to
get the result out of wikipedia
so if you ask something which is let's
say what is uh
i don't know maybe same thing what is
particle
quantum physics or particle entangle
entanglement uh it will probably go to
wiki and it will get the response and it
will send it back to me
right so this is called custom actions
uh that's what i used
now comes the fourth floor fourth
category which is free flow
now free flow is very interesting as i
say uh
this is where you know it is it can be
any discussions
now uh for that uh already there are
two interesting you know model i found
one is paul
ai parlia is created by facebook
uh it's an open source free flow open
domain chatbot
and these are some examples given so if
you go to the website
you can actually see that you know this
this this actually
talks uh in engineering so there is not
much
uh other thing but when basically i say
can you have a dinner and so it's a
tough one okay
interesting choice so what question do
you ask him okay i would like to know
how he came up with the idea
for the ipod okay to diaper change the
way everyone listens to me so you can
actually have a discussion
uh like that why did the mushroom go to
the party i'm not sure but i'm glad
it did uh like that no it was supposed
to be a joke
sorry i didn't get it what kind of joke
it was i like jokes
so so this is how uh it was so basically
the blue ones are the
bot and the the gray one is the human
right so
you can have a normal conversation here
so that is what you do
however there is another model i found
which is
called dialog gpt which is uh created by
microsoft
and uh this guy also does the same thing
and you can have so this is some samples
where you know you can actually
see how it works users does my money buy
happiness
what says depends how much money you
spend on it right
this is what is the best way to buy
happiness so you just have to be a
millionaire
by your early 20s and then being happy
so you can see that you know there is a
to some extent an intellectual
conversation you can have
and and this is this is the two model we
found
now gpt has multiple version gpu and
gpt2
and most recently now openai is kind of
about to release i think with gpd3 also
and that's this much more bigger and
better so gpt is a model which
allows you to generate text and what
they are saying now the gp23 can
generate any kind of articles
uh statements uh uh poetry and stuff
like that so
so it's very interesting uh things are
happening there
now for free flow i had these two
choices and out of these two two choices
i personally favored uh
microsoft dialog gpd because power line
was good
uh it has more but it sounds more formal
however like when i'm talking to my
friends this i don't want to be
very formal right i want to be more like
in whatsapp dude kind of
a conversation right so dialogue gbt has
that kind of you know
intimacy in terms of you know
conversation so overall
i kind of created this as an
architecture so the way it works is
uh we first is the interface so i have
exposed it over to whatsapp and telegram
whatsapp white will you one telegram
flash because python class server could
create
so we created an api gateway where this
comes and this is where the user
identification happens so based on the
number
or the username i recognize which is the
user because based on that user you can
actually
send some context right the previous
history chat history of that person
that defines the context or probably you
know the data
which control and then we do some
logging and stuff
then it goes to rasa and it first gets
checked you know is it
category one or category three and based
on that it responds back from
here but it says no it's not cat 1 or
cat 3 then it goes to
chatterbot for the category 2. you get
the data back from here
and then it
responds back and then for category four
it can use either one of this so right
now i'm showing people
uh the one but this one also kind of you
know
uh in the process of integrating so both
both of these this together can
do it now what happens here is there is
a scoring mechanism also so what happens
is it gets the response from here
uh every time i get a response from one
engine i check the confidence scope
uh if you confirm set a threshold there
so this let's say the threshold is 80 or
higher
then only i'll get that accepted
response and send it back
because it may happen that you know i am
able to get a response from one model
but the problem is you know it may get a
response which doesn't make sense
uh and the way to define is and
obviously the the confidence it
it has on the response so uh
so that's how the structure works now
this was almost near real time so you
can actually have a conversation you
could have a conversation over chat
over this interfaces and do it so so
that's what uh
that's what uh that's how it works now
moving on one thing was missing so far
was
context right so so if you see the data
structure although
so far i have been this is a q a kind of
option right this is the question as
this was the answer this is the question
this is the answer
so there was no way i could actually
establish a context
now this was another model i tried and
this was actually already there
uh it's a transformer model where uh the
idea is
let's say there is a discussion happen
you had a chat
now uh whatever response you have given
the previous four or five or six
defending you can depend define what is
the number of context
statements you want to do those
statements become the context for to
get this as a response so essentially
the idea here is
saying that you know what i will only
say this
when i have this as a context
so there is a discussion there is a
history i'm talking about right
uh so there could be references of
something which i know five statement
backgrounds
you spoke about so this context this can
actually give you a sense of
conversation
so this is one concept which takes your
uh
takes your uh takes your chat from a q a
perspective to a conversation
perspective
right so this is what again you know
another thing has been tried
and uh unfortunately i did not get
good results however it was uh it was
okay
uh so so this part can be you know
fine-tuned and improved
know which can be what can be done so so
yes so overall this is
what generates the the engine right the
the context
uh the chat engine now moving on the
voice
the voice part is uh there are primarily
three model
uh which i've tried which is one is taco
tron two which is again you know it's a
google
google publish this model for voice
cloning
uh this requires a lot of data uh
so i tried uh with let's say around 500
samples of
my my talk i've recorded with let's say
a speech or five to 15 seconds each and
then i try to feed it with tacotron i
didn't get much uh
a good result because they say that i
need at least i don't know maybe some
10 hours of recordings uh which is
pretty tiresome for me
so i couldn't do that real time voice
cloning the third one was a very
interesting though
this thing this is uh which
works at the very less data uh and uh
it actually can generate a voice which
is sounds like a cloned voice of yours
however the problem is uh this the
pretend model was
on u.s accent unfortunately being an
indian i have an accent problem right so
uh so my accent doesn't fit well there
now that's why
right now as we speak that there's a
training going on on the
the middle mall model which is called
cycle gun the cycle gang is
actually uh transforming so gang is
actually a
category of you know neural network
generative
adversarial network which is basically
uh what they do is uh
they actually transfer your properties
of your voice
to a pre-recorded voice and and it's
supposed to work with much lesser uh
lesser uh data so this training is going
on uh
although there is too much of error so
here is a small sample i could get
this is what i'm going to play for you
guys so here it out
this is the original one printing in the
only sense with which we are at present
concerned differs from most if not from
all the arts and crafts represented in
the exhibition
all right and this is the generated one
as of now
so as you see there is too much of loss
and it was actually not so i could i
could make
figure out the wordings sounds
sound the voice sounding is slowly
getting
towards my way of saying however you
know the clarity is missing and
it it's still getting trained so i hope
you know it will improve over the time
so so over the time what so this is the
second level of architecture and voice
with it so assuming the stackatron i
have enough data i can train i am pretty
confident that this works
now people have tried it and as i said
you know my job is not to prove that why
is cloning work because there's already
a model it's a matter of data
and time and gpu and cost my objective
was to build this chat engine
or the conversation engine which can
actually have a conversation with
it so now what i did i club this thing
together and create this as an
architecture
where what you do is you can actually
talk uh say something
and it can do a speech to text uh
conversion
uh using google's uh google's api a
speech to text
then the text goes to this engine and
this engine generates the
response this response then goes to that
voice model
and the voice will actually you know
will take the text and generate a voice
out of output of that
saying that same text and that gets uh
replied back
so while this is happening this training
is going on
just for the demo what i did is i use a
google
this another hack i did which is i used
google text to speech
as a service and i try to take the
so thanks to speech google as multiple
person you can actually figure out
get defined that you know you can you
want an indian speaker you want an
indian speaker with a bengali accent
or uh let's say a south indian accent so
i
i'd experiment with them and try to get
one which actually
has as a probably a similar accent or
similar voice
right so together with this it can
actually you know create a voice engine
which works perfectly fine now comes the
face
this is very interesting now again i say
deep freak and those kind of things
already there that was not my objective
my objective here was to
can i generate a a face
in the real near real time uh so that i
can simulate a call
let's say a zoom call or hangout call
and
and it should be able to say whatever
you know i am
i want them to say uh in terms of lip
syncing in terms of you know generating
the voice and
i know syncing the lips as if it looks
like you know i'm saying that
so i have used uh two uh uh
two libraries uh a project there's a
leap can an audio driven topping
headphones
now out of these two uh
the the lead gun was uh actually a
project which gave some more
more realistic result so uh so here is
some demo
uh so initial first one is the audio
driven talking get post the first one
hello how is life whether is going today
when two so today i am not here over who
are you where is your house
as you can see the face is a little bit
shaky uh so it is not actually
giving me a good result so this is the
second one
today today i am not a robot who are you
where is your house so this was much
better but still you know i could see
that you know there is a little bit of
uh shake and uh it was it was not very
very convincing so then uh the lead gun
was more convincing so these are the two
demo first one was on best generator
from a picture
so let's show you how is it environments
pack provides it is one of the most
interesting that has been working before
okay as you can see the leap movement
was you know kind of uh
realistic now putting it together on a
video this is how it looks
the examination and testimony of the
experts enabled the commission to
conclude
that five shots may have been fired
so here you can clearly see the lip
syncing was much better
and it was very convincing uh to some
extent right so
so definitely this this overall between
these two model lip can
give us a much better result so now uh
now i club this thing together right so
let's stitch it together so the winter
flow the way it works is
uh first it uh as i said the brain which
generates the response
then it should go to the voice engine
which will generate the voice
and then it will should feed this voice
uh into the
to the face engine where it should take
the face video
and impose this voice and it will do a
lip syncing
uh so that uh finally i'll get a video
which looks like
in real time you know it's saying what
i'm saying
now how do i club it together uh for
let's say take it further is
this is where you know the the next
component comes which is the video
streamer
uh cam twist uh with this
what i do is i created an app uh which
stream between two videos so there's one
video which is a silent video
uh listening as if that i'm just you
know staring at the camera and listening
to uh what the other person is saying uh
that's a listening video and
what it does you know it keeps listening
and saying no that video gets to played
uh
and using cam twist i made it as a as a
virtual camera
uh to to list a hangout uh so that you
know hang out
whenever switches on the camera somebody
will see that
this this video a streaming video now
the other thing was this
clone engine which is has a speech to
text recognition and stuff
so the way it works is uh let's say i'm
talking to you
uh so in in hangout you will say hi basu
so my speech recognition module will
take that it will generate the text it
will go to that engine
engine will generate the response that
will go to the video
uh video will generate the video saying
the response
and then my streamer will switch from
the silent video to the
talking video as if that you know i'm
just stopping it so this is how this
entire model work
and let's see it live in action how it
works so this is a call between lseo and
me and instead of me it was my bot who
is talking to lsu
hey how are you
i'm doing very well thanks how are you
good
tell me
[Music]
well
i have no other options for now i am
asking few close friends can you help me
on this
okay
[Music]
i just need it for this month
we'll play back in 10 days once i get
from fox to from me
okay
thanks again so what's new in your life
call me once you are free we'll talk
bye yo
you are the funniest person i have ever
seen
right so yeah so this is what uh is a
prototype which i have created now as
you can clearly see here you know there
is always a gap
however this gap was in terms of uh
making the voice more convincing uh
making the facial expressions
probably you know adding some more
emotions to to the
to the voice so those are the things
which is in the roadmap which definitely
you know has to be done now if you
really want to try it this is the source
code and
this is uh in my cheetah now if you go
to this date of titan lambda identity
cloning
you get all the documentation and and
the steps to set it up and run it uh
on your own right road ahead as i said
you know
expression uh you know probably
bypassing some
biometrics those are the things we can
try it out
and as i said i'll be happy to uh happy
to
hear your suggestions on this now last
but not the least uh
obviously our vision was create
futuristic technology that's what is
neoid is for
and we are doing behavioral biometrics
and also prevention mechanism to such
kind of adversarial attacks
so we would definitely need support so
we're looking for
obviously angels and other people who
can support us to build this kind of
technologies
right these are various references and
the community support i got
in terms of this idea to prototype and
building and all this
and last but not the least as i said no
i
with my knowledge and understanding
whatever i have i would definitely
try to you know kind of build it as a
course as a workshop
which which i give conduct in various
times so
so thank you so much uh i appreciate
your time
uh and yeah please check out the
repository thank you
okay hi guys so thank you for watching
and uh
i think i've already answered your
questions
over the over the chat so in case you
have any further questions uh you can
reach out to me
over email or you can shoot me
an invitation in linkedin so i'm happy
to connect and probably
talk further and if you have any quick
question i can answer thank you