[Music]
good morning ladies and gentlemen and
welcome to my talk about http request
smuggling in 2020
my name is amit klein you can read more
about me in this
slide and today we're going to talk
about the http request smuggling
which is an attack that involves three
actors one is the attacker who
who is a practically a client and the
other one
and is there a proxy or firewall and the
third actor is a web server or it can be
a chain of proxies and firewalls leading
to a web
to finally to a web server and the
attack involves the attacker
connecting over port 80 tcp
to the proxy and sending the proxy uh
an http stream consisting of three um
chunks or three parts a followed by b
followed by c and we designate the a
part in red the b part in green and the
c part in blue
the proxy interprets this stream as the
first request being
a followed by b and the second request
is
c and it forwards those two requests to
the web server and the web server
however interprets those two requests as
the stream i'm sorry as a request first
quest a
followed by a second request b
and c and thus it responds with uh the
responses for a
and for bc and the proxy then caches
uh for a b the response for that the web
server provided for a
and more importantly the proxy caches
for c the response that the web server
generated
for the data for the messages bc
and that latter part is exactly where
http request smuggling takes effect
and ends up in web cache poisoning in
this example
this the http request smuggling attack
is also called the
http dsync attack per james cattle's
recent research
just to illustrate this in more detail
this is the street this is an example
string where a
the red part is
is the first uh chunk that uh the proxy
receives
uh in green we see the second chunk and
in blue we see the third chunk
and let's say that uh the proxy uh
interprets the or or uses the last
content sent header
in such case the proxy will interpret
this
stream as two http requests one with
44 bytes body consisting of the red part
followed by the green part
and the second one is the blue part
which is entirely new
http request um
so from the proxy's perspective
the proxy will see the first request for
hello php
and the second request for target html
whereas
say we have a web server
with that interprets the uh
or that uses the first content length
header in such case we'll see the first
request being the red part
uh which is a a request with
zero body lens followed by another
request
green and blue parts so from the web
servers perspective the first request
will be to hello php with zero bytes in
the body
and the second request will be for the
poison html
um resource with some extra headers in
blue
and as you can see the proxy will
therefore cache
for the target html url the data that
the web server provided for
the poison html url and thereby we
achieve a
web cache poisoning
uh a short history of http request
smuggling as we can
see in 2005 that's a decade and a half
ago
uh the seminal paper http request
muggling was published it was followed
by several air research uh
small papers uh and then for almost a
decade there was no
substantial uh research in http request
mark in the https
request muggling area there were of
course vulnerabilities published
but no no significant research as far as
i know
in 2015 2016
regis leroy published his hiding rookies
in http
reviving the interest in this area and
in 2019 james kettle uh published his
series of
papers around http dsync attacks
in blackett usa and in black at
europe so given all this
my question is is http request smuggling
still a thing this is
2020 and we we are after all aware of
the attack for
uh over a decade and a half uh it was
back to the limelight in recent years
thanks to james kettle and regis leroy
and our so our mainstream weapon proxy
server is still vulnerable
uh this the scope of my research is the
usual suspects
and you'd expect them to be all immune
by now but
since i'm here in blackhead the answer
is no
let's see some interesting variants
first is a header
followed by space or card return
followed by some junk for example
content length header followed by the
content length followed by space
followed by abcd
with a value of 20 and as it happens
squids
squid ignores this header completely but
it forwards it as is
whereas abyss x1 web server converts it
uh into just the header part without the
space
or or the junk so cache web cache
poisoning attack
with squid in front of uh of abyss
may cons maybe uh um constructed as
following
we have this the legitimate content
length header with 41 bytes
and uh followed by uh this uh
um not so legit content length header
with space and junk with the value of
three
uh squid uses the valid content length
header and ignores the invalid header so
from
squid's perspective we're talking about
a body length for 41 bytes
whereas abyss uses the second
a content length header which is which
has the value of three from abuses
point of view so abyss will see the
second request for poison html
and serve it whereas um squid
will see the second request as get
welcome html so it will cache
uh the content of the poison url
served by abyss to the url
html and now what if we don't like
this to feed the abyss with two content
songs headers
uh what if we suspect that this will fix
this
soon so we discovered an interesting
abyss behavior something that is also
exhibited by other web servers which is
if the
request is partial it may still be
fulfilled
by the web server and by partial i mean
that the the
full body bytes uh was were not yet uh
received
so um abyss in such case will wait 30
seconds and then
it will invoke the back-end script and
provide the
proxy or the client with the data that
this script
generated and after additional bytes are
received
on the in the tcp connection they will
be silently discarded
until the full body is red and then and
then abyss will start parsing the next
request
so how would what would an attack uh
look like
uh in this case uh we have just the
connection the the invalid
uh content length header uh in which
case uh squid will interpret this as a
zero length uh body request
and will only send the headers to to
abyss
abyss will weight 30 abyss expects 39
bytes in the body
it waits for 30 seconds then invoke
hello
invokes hello php hello php generates
some answer this is forwarded to squid
and then squid sends the next request
that for
its from its point of view this is a get
welcome and so forth
and then abyss will silently discard the
39 bytes that belong to the first
request form's perspective
and start serving the second request
which is get poison html so again
web cache poisoning
some variants interesting variants i
discovered relate to
how mod security plus crs
behave specifically this
community rule set uh mod security plus
plus crs is actually a free and open
source web application firewall
it provides us some rudimentary direct
protection against http request
smuggling
uh it has the perennial levels uh it
runs by default in paranormal level one
and it can it has some more strict rules
in parallel level three or four
but these generate a lot of false
positives so they
practically cannot be used in in
production environments
and our bypass works for paranormal
levels one and two
so let's let's look at it
let's review uh what
what the challenges were and how we uh
we overcame them
um so the problem with uh
the problem with mod security plus crs
is that our http request smangling
payloads
got blocked by the http response
splitting attack
rules so for example uh we have two
rules
uh a 921 130
that looks for a pattern of http slash
and we have another one that looks for
character 10 and line feed in argument
names
both are geared towards blocking http
response
splitting unfortunately for us
they also work against our http request
smuggling payloads
uh walking around the last one the 150
is trivial
we just moved the attack from the what
what what security considers as the
argument name
to the argument value by prepending the
n argument if
a bogus or fake argument name x y equals
something and then we move away from
being an argument name
as for the 130
the trick is to use http 1 2 instead of
http 1011
and as it happens iis apache engines
node.js and the bs respect http 1 2
and they treat it as http 1 1 and in
their
in their proxy head squid h a proxy kdn
traffic respect http
1 2 but converts them into http 1 1.
there's still a small problem with rule
uh which is uh triggered
because the the payload contains
something that looks like a unix direct
command execution
the space followed by slash but that can
be walked around too
by using the full proxy url
as you can see below
and then we discovered a much more funny
bypass which is to use content sense
text plain
uh this one in paranoia levels one or
two simply
makes uh the content rules community
rule set
uh to disregard the body entirely and
so we can get our http request smuggling
attack
uh nicely through
the through mod security plus series
and the fifth variant is actually um
is documented
somewhere in burps http request
smuggling module as a 0drap
but i don't think i have seen any
successful
use of that until today
so we discovered that squid ignores a
header propended by a kurd return
it's it just forward it as is and abuse
respects this header
and here's an example of an http request
smuggling attack
ending in web cache poisoning uh using
the wait for it
trick again so we just feed this
this invalid content length header squid
ignores it
and abyss respects it
one last tip for overriding existing
cache items so sometimes a page is
cached and you want to poison it
you can use a cache control no cache for
the request that
that involves this page and the header
may be moved around so you need to be
careful about it
when you calculate the uh payload
lengths and and offsets
uh let's see this uh those variants in
action
we can see we can start with the abyss
web server version as you can see it's
pretty recent
followed by the squid version which you
can see it's fully patched for
at the time of testing and then let's
see now variant one we first
load uh the target page uh
the original target target page which
makes it also
which makes squid cache it
and then we run the smuggling script
to see our options we use now the
first variant
and now we load the same target page in
a different browser to avoid the
browser caching issues and we see indeed
that it is poisoned
moving to var into the second variant
again we load the url
we see that the page is cached correctly
now we run the second variant
the time fast forwards for 30 seconds
and we check that
the page again from a different browser
instance and we see that it's poisoned
finally we run the fifth variant again
we load your
the target url now it's cached in the in
squid
we're on the fifth variant
time is fast forwarding 30 seconds
and we load this url again
so this for the proxy and we see that it
is cached
it is poisoned so
uh i reported all those
variants to squid and abyss and and osp
community rule set
it was fixed in abyss and in wasp
community rule set and
hopefully by the time this presentation
is is screened
uh uh squid will also fix those
issues in its product
and after seeing that the issue is still
real
i started considering what the possible
solutions may be
first i want to
discuss some flawed approaches for
protection against hp request smuggling
for example some people claim that
normalization of outbound http headers
for proxy servers
is a solution and i think that
obviously it's a solution for the http
devices behind the proxy but it's
completely ineffective for all the tasks
that take place between the proxy and
the devices in front of it
so for example if you are a client and
there is a proxy p1
and then your proxy p2 in this chain and
finally there is a web server
then and p1 uses say the first
contentment header and p2 uses the last
content length header
then the then you can mount an http
request smuggling between p1 and p2 now
if you ask whether this is uh whether p2
is to be blamed or to
to shoulder part of the blame
think of the p2 to the web server
connection
as an abstraction for web server ws
prime
so now the client is communicating
through a single proxy p1
to web server ws prime and ws primer c
accepts multiple content length headers
and uses the last one
now would you say in this case the ws
prime is vulnerable to http request
smuggling
because if you say yes then obviously p2
is vulnerable to http request smuggling
because
ws the original ws can be
fully 100 percent rfc compliant
and yet http request smart and web cache
poisoning can take place
so if you accept the premise that in
such case a web server
is vulnerable to http request smuggling
then obviously a proxy is two
same argument applies to having a tcp
connection per each
outbound request again something that
proxy servers
can do it's good for http devices behind
the proxy but it's not effective for
http
devices in front of the proxy
so uh moving back to uh finding a
solution so my first stop
was obviously with mod security plus the
crs
it has some obvious pros like being a
true web application firewall
being free and being open source but it
also has some
some serious cons which is it only
supports a
small subset of web servers and it only
has a rudimentary defense
uh against http request smuggling so
from my perspective
it's not good enough
so i started thinking about what is an
ideal solution
would look like and my concept is
something lightweight and simple and
easy not a fully fledged dwarf
it should be it should focus on specific
protocol attacks like http request
smuggling
and maybe additional attacks it should
be secure obviously
and i want to develop a proof of concept
that doesn't
need to be production quality it just
need to demonstrate a concept that then
vendors can take and
implement in their products or
third-party
security providers can uh
implement as a production and
production uh solution production grade
solution
and more specifically the architecture
would be or
or the the solution would revolve around
having a very strict validation of small
subset of the http standards
so i'm talking about anything that can
affect the request length
uh specifically the content length
header and the transfer encoding header
and having unambiguous line ends and
header block end
and of course monitoring the request
line for uh for verb names
it should be unambiguous because the
verb name sometimes dictates that their
the request mustn't have a body or or
typically doesn't have a body
and an ambiguous protocol designation is
in order to avoid the htp-09 the http 09
syndrome
and maybe other headers that i haven't
thought about yet
i want my solution to be generic so it
doesn't tie to specific
technology or product or platform so
specifically i don't want to rely on
windows lsp or wfp
and it would be nice to have that
that it can be extended beyond the http
like
having a power decrypted the https
traffic
and maybe other protocols and of course
it should be secure so i think that
the only way to do that is with in-path
monitoring and not
something based on sniffing and
architecturally the solution i arrived
to was is the good all the function
hooking
for in this case for for the socket
layer uh functions so a few words about
function hooking
uh while completely non-standard it's de
facto
uh used very commonly in major operating
systems like windows and linux
and there are even cross-platform
function hooking libraries like
fan hook that i use in my in my project
stability and robustness may be an issue
but again this is a proof of concept
library it's not a full product
and uh and hooking is just one piece of
of the game and one needs still to
inject the code
or at least an initial code in windows
this can be done by using a standard dll
injection
in linux you can use ld preload again
problem with stability and again i don't
care about this at this
for this project and the way i
implemented my project is
using two layers one is the socket
obstruction layer
and the other one is the actual firewall
and the socket abstraction layer allows
me to abstract a native socket
into standard open read close view
so i need to manage the sockets from
cradle to to death
and i need of course to maintain a map
from this
socket file descriptor to to a user
object that handles
each socket each socket gets its own
instance of a user object
and i don't want to interfere with the
system operation so there's no buffering
at all
that that i am allowed to introduce
and i signal to the user object
important actions
by using the contract the constructor to
signal a socket open
an on-rate invocation which
signals the socket read and the
destructor signals the socket
closed i provide the user object with
the socket
file descriptor so the user object can
interact with the socket
and the user object signals back to me
in the return value whether it i should
forcibly close the socket
so what do i need to hook you can see
that
in windows i just need to hook
seven functions to get to cover the full
functionality of the usual suspects
and same goes for linux tested in 64
bits
again a nice area of of
web servers is car is covered by
hooking uh seven functions only
while implementing this the socket
obstruction layer i learned a lot about
the internals of
of web servers and and in sockets
of course especially in linux worker
processes and forking must be
supported this is not fully functional
yet in my library i just run a single
process instance of the web server for
testing uh locking of the socket
management table is also desired
so far i haven't implemented it
preserving the correct error state is
mandatory
you can easily crash a system
or or make the system malfunction if you
do not
preserve erno last error and wsa last
error
std out and std error are not always
available so write your own log file
for some bizarre reason squid on linux
doesn't like f claws so i had to
resort to using the direct i o
functions statistically linked
executables with stripped symbols
are a serious problem for my approach so
compiled go products like traffic and
credit are not supported at this time
interestingly enough linux receive
implementation
actually invokes the receive from cisco
this is a bit surprising
accept or accept for are sometimes
invoked with address being now this is
valid but
also surprising and node.js uses a
library called uv lib
which invokes the syscalls directly
so you can't i can't hook uh there's no
point in hooking the
uh usual socket functions i need to hook
specifically
the uv accept four function in this case
in order to get
the full functionality on top of the
socket obstruction layer i
implemented another class called the
request smuggling firewall
that that uses the socket obstruction
layer to implement
the request smartening firewall
surprisingly
and in it enforces the strict rfc 2616
on the relevant parts of the http
request like request line format
header name format uh content sense
transfer encoding
header end of line chunk body format it
it operates with the default deny policy
it only buffers is a single partial
line uh internally it it always sends
the data immediately to the application
to the web server but it buffers
a single partially a partial single line
and so that there's no there's never
a full line with violation transmitted
to the web server so it stops
immediately upon the first violation
and the violation can cause it to send a
400 response as we'll see in a moment
and to terminate the connection and
let's see a demo
okay demo
so we run squid with the rsfw
library and then we try
the first we first load the target page
to squids cache as we usually do
now we run the first variant
we can see that it fails with a 400
response
and if we load the target page again
this time
we can see that it's actually not
poisoned
now we run the second variant if you
remember it should run for 30 seconds
but actually it just exited immediately
and same with the fifth variant
so during my http request smuggling
research i bumped into some interesting
promising or suspicious anomalies in
some http
devices for which i can describe a
matching behavior
so if i found something interesting in a
web server i could describe a matching
behavior in a proxy server
that leads to http request smuggling
however i could not
find this matching behavior in my zoo of
products so far
just to illustrate let's say we go back
to 2005
and i noticed a web server which takes
the first header in a double content
length
request a matching behavior would be
then a proxy server
that takes the last content in such a
request
but keeps both headers but let's say
that in my lab back then i could only
find proxy servers that either take the
first header
or reject the request then in 2005 this
would have been a
very interesting and relevant example
naturally in 2020 this isn't uh there
are
probably no web server proxy server that
behaves so naively but you get the idea
so courage return in a header name
is interpreted as a hyphen so uh
just like i mentioned one web server
treats this
contents kerger 10 length as the header
content length
i suspect this is due to a quick and
dirty upper casing using all with
ox 20. so if you or
ox20 with a card return you get a hyphen
the matching proxy behavior is to simply
ignore this header and forward it as
is and the attack in this case would be
the having a web server
expect a body and using a get request
the web server will immediately forward
the request to the application without a
body
and this and on the other hand the
matching proxy
uh will uh so the matching proxy will
treat it
as a zero length body and the web server
expects a body of a certain length and
therefore a
web cache poisoning ensues unfortunately
for me it is an attacker all proxy
servers i have
either rejected with a 400 response or
modify their
their request
this is this may be uh fixed
by the time this presentation is aired
so
i urge you to to get updates
on my uh for the white paper
uh so i'll be able to hopefully i'll be
able to update
and to name the a relevant web server
in the white paper signed content length
i'm talking about adding a plus sign in
front of the
value obviously it's non-rfc behavior
because the
content length only allowed digits some
proxy implementations use the api
like a2i that does accept the sign
uh the matching web server behavior is
to simply ignore this header and the
attack is obvious the web server has
defacto content length zero
whereas the proxy servers is one two
three four
this doesn't work of course if the proxy
normalizes the content limit header
before
forwarding it to the web server all the
web servers i have either reject or
honor this request as
is so no good here
uh and the vendor the i reported it to
several proxy vendors it was fixed by
squid
abyss and go
content length value with space so i'm
talking about
content length one two space three four
again it's non rfc engines ignores this
header
what i look what i want to find is a
proxy that uses
one of the values one two three four one
two or three four
and four the request a header is is the
attack is obvious
all the proxy servers i have either
reject or remove this header
i reported this to engines and they say
they won't fix it because it doesn't
look like vulnerability in engines the
requests in question
cannot be passed through a compliant
http proxy with the header interpreted
as a content length header so they say
finally
there's one web server that simply
ignores transfer encoding even in http
one one obviously this is not an
rfc compliant behavior
what i look for is a proxy server that
prefers transfer encoding over content
length but does not modify
the request and the attack would be to
send a request with both transfer
encoding and content length where the
proxy would use
the transfer encoding header and the web
server would use the content links
header
all the proxies i have normalize the
request either per the content link
letter or per the transfer encoding
header
so this becomes a non-relevant so i
cannot
exploit it in my lab
to conclude uh
we see that http request smuggling is
still a thing in 2020
in common off-the-shelf software uh
existing open source
solutions are lacking there's there is a
more robust approach for defending
against atp request smuggling and it is
feasible i'm talking about
implementing a lightweight solutions
specifically tailored for http request
modeling
in path it can be applied by vendros or
third-party
security software and there are still
some interesting challenges
in this area thank you very much
right um so thank you very much for
attending my session uh
right now i see there is one question
but
uh what a question this is uh the
question
is uh let me read it for everyone
are there good fuzzing frameworks for
testing for http requests smuggling
besides
manual testing eg through burp or zap
so to the best of my knowledge
some web application scanners
have uh http requests smuggling
testing attacks incorporated
in them uh having said that
i think that there are some obvious
hurdles in automatically testing
for http request smuggling as some of
the uh
people on the on the chat mentioned
so in essence one needs to be
very careful about um the impact of the
attack which can be very tricky in the
case
of http request smuggling including a
long lasting
effect on the uh on the cash
um and uh
at large i think this attack is somewhat
more difficult to control or to
predict the uh the outcome of the exact
attack or the variant compared to other
application vulnerabilities or
application tax
um i think james cattle in his uh
last year's blackhead presentation
touched
uh some of the issues about uh
securely and safely testing for http
requests smuggling but
obviously it's uh it's non-trivial so
the network the net answer or the the
bottom line
uh with respect to this question from at
least
from what i know is that some automatic
application scanners do test for it
but there are in some inherent problems
in
automatic and large-scale testing
uh that perhaps prevent a
large scale and and and and
and intensive fuzzing
around this uh around http request
smuggling
okay and i see that there is now another
question
uh
right so okay i got an excellent
question here when you showed the
poisoned page and on the demo uh it
looked like an attacker injected it
there
i missed the beginning and you
but the the question says you can only
use the http request modeling to access
pages already on the web server right
not for an attacker to introduce new
content
absolutely or you're 100 correct
um but think about it this way
an attacker can still save on on some
sides there are
attacker-controlled content like uh
comments or blogs or or
or personal areas in the website which
the attacker
has a lot of control over uh
and also think about this about this say
let's say that there's a hot
news about some uh i don't know kovit 19
vaccine being tested by by company xyz
uh and then you you uh
replace quote unquote or make this a to
make the url
be cached with the content about the
same company having
an earlier
vaccine variant shown
ineffective and that can that can have
impact on on that company and on the on
the share price of that company
and so what i'm saying is even if
the attacker cannot uh
have his or her own page on the website
so that the
url uh the cached url uh
is uh is cached together of the content
from the attacker's controlled
page the attacker can still uh
incur a lot of damage by having one url
caching the pay
the content from another page which is
not intended for that url
so um so yes but technically you're
absolutely right
you can only do this attack with
a page with a poison page that is
already on the website
absolutely right
actually i don't see any further
questions right now
okay
all right there's another question here
but i think that we can just uh
now so there's a question here sorry
there's a question here about the
variance
uh i demonstrated the attack against uh
the testing against proxies the wasps
built in-house no the attacks were
against a combination of
common off-the-shelf two common
off-the-shelf pieces of software
one is the squid proxy and another one
is at the abyss
x1 server
could http poisoning work
in tandem with a url redirect attack to
another site
i guess the answer to that is
no because the the attacker we are
talking about here about http
requests that are generated by the
attacker
if there's a redirect in the website i
don't think it affects the attack it
only redirect works at the
browser level and we are talking here
about http level
so it's a bit a bit more raw if you if
you get my meaning
uh how do you see the light weight
implementation of your suggested
fixes with hooks on large-scale proxy
networks like cds excellent questions
obviously cdns are not going to
incorporate my code this was more like
a wake-up call for vendors and security
vendors
to show them that http request smuggling
protection is possible and i think the
way to do it
is by focusing on http request smuggling
and providing a excellent security
specifically against this attack
instead of trying a catch-all solution
like uh
application firewall which which has its
problems and and has its drawbacks now
i'm not saying this is not a useful
product but
obviously it's more difficult to deploy
than a point solution against
http request smuggling
um let's see
anything else
okay where can you find the content of
your test scripts
it i shared the url in the chat room uh
early in my presentation uh so
and there's a it will be of course uh in
a link in my white paper
that will be published tonight
all right now i think i think we are
done here and you can
contact me directly for if you have
additional questions
thank you very much it was a pleasure uh
providing giving you this presentation
in blackhead
and answering your questions thank you