[Music]
hi
everyone and welcome to my talk about
the impact attack
before we start let me introduce myself
i'm david ruprecht phd student at the
wonderful rural university bowhom
and my aim is it to secure mobile
networks
by finding flaws and fixing them
before we start with the talk let me
motivate this topic
and i know everyone knows lte is
everywhere
so we use it to stream music even some
serious and buy things on amazon
but also our first responders use it in
case of emergencies
and there is a second a third use case
the industrial use case where iot
devices
or factories are connected via lte to
control units
this and the fact that lte is the
foundation for our future 5g networks
makes it important to look into the
security measures
of 5g
so i will talk today
introduce you to the impact attack
impact stands for impersonation
attacks in 4g networks and when we talk
about
impersonation we need a common common
definition of
impersonation by impersonation i mean
that an attacker is able to act as you
towards the network
he can send arbitrary ip messages or
packets
towards the network and even through the
internet with your identity
for the aim of this talk is to
understand the impact attack
the attack vectors that are exploited
and what implications
of this attacks exist
before we get there we need to pass the
basic agenda
first of all i would like to introduce
you to some lte background information
then we would like to or i would like to
show you the alter attack
the ultra attack uses the same attack
vector as the impact attack
but is more easy to understand than
defect attack
third we will look into the impact
attack
we will dare understand what attack
vectors are used
and how the attack works
we will further discuss the implications
implications of these attacks
and in particular see if 5g is secure
against
these attacks so we will start with the
lte background information
so as always we have a small lte
network um architecture so we got the
phone on the left side
this phone is connected towards the
closest space station
and this phone is connected to what's
the closest space station also called
e-node b
and the not-b or the lte network itself
has many entities they are not important
for us today
it is important is that um the ip
network provided towards the phone
is separated via firewall to from the
rest of the internet
firewall or not so any incoming
ip connection does not cannot pass
through
the phone
so when we talk about lte or 4g security
we definitely need to talk about
about the security aims the first
and very important security aim is
mutual authentication
mutual authentication ensures that you
are talking to the correct provider
and the provider knows that you're the
correct person
as some of you might know 2g does not
provide any network authentication
and this is why still so many
two 2g attacks are possible and
or mccarthy attacks the second
important security aim is traffic
confidentiality
traffic confidentiality ensures that an
passive attacker is not able
to eavesdrop your phone calls but also
even your internet connection
here i'm not talking about https or tls
i'm talking about the radio connection
between your phone and the base station
the third
most or unique
security aim for mobile networks
is identity and location confidentiality
an attacker should not be able to know
who you are
just being close to you and also the
attacker should not know
where you are when he only knows your
phone number
so today we are going
mainly or we are going to break the
mutual authentication aim
on the user data because impersonation
contradicts mutual authentication
so how are the security aims
basically fulfilled therefore lte has
some security features
and the main part of the security
features
are based on a shared secret in your sim
card
and in the provider's home network in a
secure location
based on this secret key and at the
beginning of each connection
handshake with or mutual authentication
is established
based on an authentication and key
agreement protocol
this key agreement protocol is secure
with mathematics proofs and
this aka also derives some keys which
are
used for secure the further connection
for your internet traffic and even some
control traffic
today we are going to look into the
security measures
and which are taken during the
connection
and how they are protected
before we do this we need to distinguish
between two kind of
traffics first of all we have control
lte specific control traffic this
control traffic is
generated when you for example hand over
from one cell to another cell
this control traffic is encrypted with a
stream cipher
in and integrity protected further
we have user plan traffic this user plan
traffic
is generated by your app or your your or
your web browser when you visit a
website
it's only um ip
traffic um and this ip traffic is
encrypted
using a stream cipher however this is
not integrity protected
like the control plane
as i said earlier we use a stream cipher
to encrypt
packets and
so how does a stream cipher work so we
have a plain text
which is only four bit long and these
four bits
are xor with the key stream for example
a is in counter mode
this xor results in a cipher text this
cipher text is then
sent over the air towards the base
station
the decryption is quite similar to the
encryption so the base station receives
the cipher text
xor the key stream generated with the
same input parameters for is encounter
mode
and this will result in the plain text
so we already done we are already done
with the lte background information
let's start with the auto attack
the aim of the alter attack is to steal
credentials
for example when you visit a website you
get redirected
towards a malicious web page where
login prompt is shown and you enter your
credentials
and the attacker is able to gain the
information of this
login you are not exactly connected to
re
to the real network you are connected to
something which we will call
lte relay or man in the middle attacker
so what kind of attack vector
does the attacker exploit the attacker
exploits the missing integrity
protection
of the user plane data which i have
shown you in the background
so missing integrity protection
you with um in the combination with the
stream cipher
leads to malleable encryption and
malleable encryption
is always a bad thing
just assume we have an active man in the
middle attacker in the position
between the phone and the base station
this man in the middle
attacker can actively change the cipher
text by flipping the third bit in this
example
the base station has no means and no
measures to detect such bit flips
xor is the same key stream as generated
before
which result that the same bit flip is
contained in the plain text
the question is can this be done
deterministically
yes it can be done under the assumption
the attacker knows the plaintext
so in this way the attacker can
calculate a mask by xoring
the wanted plain text here on the right
side
with a known plain text and the mask can
be applied
to each packet where the plain text is
known to change it
to the wanted plain text the question is
now
where do we get the plain text in
particular in the context of lte
so the answer to this question is quite
simple we will use the dns server
which is set by default during the first
attach
so each provider has a set on default
dns servers
which are known to us or the attacker
and we use this ip address
to to perform a redirection attack
further it's important to note that dns
packets
are particular or good identifiable
based on the length of the packet so
there are good distinguishable between
normal tcp traffic and tns requests
knowing the default dns
we got the non-plane text and
we can basically redirect any dns
request
towards the malicious dns server
so the aim of the ultra attack now is to
redirect
the an outgoing dns request
with an active attacker which is in the
man in the middle position between your
phone
and the network and to redirect this dns
request
towards the malicious dns server
so the phone will connect
to our man in the middle relay because
this attack is quite similar
to mccashin attack so the relay sends
out
the identifiers of the network then
the network the commercial network and
the phone will perform the aka
this will happen and the relay will
relay all those messages
without any modification in this way
the phone thinks he is connected to the
correct network
and the network thinks he is connected
to the right customer and the
relay further forwards all messages
until
a dns request is received by the relay
when he received the dns request he will
detect it based on the shorter length
and will xor the mask he has calculated
and this mask can be easily applied due
to the missing integrity protection
he basically sets the destination ip
towards the malicious dns server
and forwards it to the network the
network has no means
to detect the manipulation decrypts the
packet
and routes it towards the internet
and basically is received by the
malicious dns server
the malicious dns server and receives
the dns request
and responds with a spoof dns response
and sends it back to the network
everything is encrypted
while the network for the over air
transmission and
um for water to the red radar to relay
on the radio layer
and the ue receives the packet on the
radio layer
and with the spoofed response it then
uses the
spoofed response for the
outgoing http request so
all the subsequent hdp connection is
directed towards a malicious http server
so we need something in the man in the
middle position
between your phone and the commercial
network
right and on the left side
we already know that mz catcher or fake
base station at
exist attacks exist so
towards the phone the relay must act as
enough b
um as commercial e not b by sending out
the identifiers
and x as normally not b
however the relay also requires to act
as ue
towards the commercial e node b so
on the radio layer um they look like
it looks like it's a recon ue connecting
in between everything um
is forwarded all layer two frames are
forwarded in both directions
and only dns requests are altered
so we built this relay based on the open
source software stack
and called sslte and i will show
now show you my setup
so sslte requires you
to send us messages using software
defined radius
we got here one software defined radio
and by address that costs about
um you know 1000
dollars and this simulates the
ue towards a commercial network
we got a second software d5 radio here
connected wire cable towards the
shielding box and within the shielding
box we got the antennas
here and they open up the cell
and which our commercial phone um here
nexus 5
connects to the commercial phone
contains a commercial sim card and
without any modification
except everything is controlled via adb
and usb cable we close the shielding box
to not
interfere with the commercial network
so that the providers can use a spectrum
and so this was a setup and i will now
show you
the demo video of the ultra attack
so we see the lte relay here and the dns
server here and the http server here
we have the victims phone here
we initialize the relay we start both
software defined radios
and we are going to disable the airplane
mode
and at this point the aka is performed
all control
control traffic is relayed and the phone
thinks it is connected to the real
commercial network
the victim might enter a web page or
website like hotmail.com
and here we already got the redirection
so the relay reader
detects the dns request based on the
length xorsa mask
and the ip packet gets redirected or
routed to the malicious
dns server seen here
and the phone sends now the http request
towards the malicious http server
the http server delivers a fake website
where the user might enter the
credentials
and here you can see that the user
entered the credentials
and everything is locked by the
attacker and he can obtain the
credentials so you now have seen that
the alter tag
can be performed in a commercial network
for stealing credentials or redirecting
people or victims to a malicious site
and the question is can it be worse and
yes
it can be worse with impact
so we will proceed now with the impact
attack
as i said impact stands for
impersonation
in 4g networks the question is
or or there are two variants of the
impact attack first of all we have the
uplink variant
in the uplink variant the user or the
victim
the attacker impersonates a victim
towards the network on the user plan
so this is the limitation we only focus
on the
user playing user ip traffic for example
the attacker is
capable or able to access a website with
the identity
or ip address of the victim
the there is a downlink variant of this
attack
and the downlink variant enables an
attacker
to impersonate a network towards the
user on the user plane
thereby he can circumvent the provider's
firewall directly accessing the phone
wire network connection
this both attacks break the aim of
mutual authentication
on the user plane in both directions
because the provider does not receive
messages from the wrong
identity but assumes the identity of
another
and also the
victim or the phone receives messages
he should not or it should not receive
what do we exploit for impact we exploit
again the effect of missing integrity
protection
and we combine this attack vector now
with something we call reflection
so i think all of you know the icmp
ping protocol and the icmp ping protocol
works as follows when you send an ip
packet and the icmp ping request
and which contains some data the phone
will respond
with an icmp ping response
and copying the data from the
original packet thereby
the phone um the data can be arbitrary
long
so it can be the full mtu size of the
the packet and which is replied to the
to the um requesting party
so the basic principle um of missing or
off the impact attack is that missing
integrity protection
and combined with the effect of the
reflection mechanism
allows us to build an encryption and
decryption oracle
and this is because we need to encrypt
something
towards the network and receive
something from the network
and both oracles allow an impersonation
so we will start with the encryption
oracle and basically introduce the idea
of the encryption oracle
and then we will i will show you um
the decryption oracle
so from the outer attack you know that
um we are the attacker an active
attacker and the man in the middle
position
is capable to flip some bits
in the receive plaintext when he knows
certain parts of the message so we have
seen that we can flip one bit
under the assumption we know this bit
however knowing the whole plain text
would allow
us to change the whole plain text
so the attacker when he knows the whole
plain text the computer can compute a
mask
for all bits in the plain text in the
packet
and can change everything in other words
if the attacker knows the whole plain
text he can
extract the key stream and reuse it
to encrypt his own packet towards
the network and this is something
um their encryption oracle does
so we got some entities for the
encryption oracle again so we got the
victim's phone here
we got the relay in the man in the
middle position between the network
between the commercial network and the
phone
and we got the key stream generation
server this is
something under the control of the
attacker which is basically a
server on the internet and the target
server
aim of the attack is now to send a
packet
towards a target server with the
identity
of the victim so
the key stream generation server will
start with this attack
it will send an ip packet containing the
udp
and a known known payload
towards the network so this payload
is particularly important and
the attacker will basically know the
plaintext the whole time of this attack
because the keystream generation server
is under his control
sending this packet towards the network
um
would result usually in
in the firewall to to to drop the packet
so this is something we assume need to
assume now
um but um there is a firewall or nut
tool already
um open um for for this incoming packet
so i did a shortcut here um to
do do not bore you with with the
preparation phase
and so let's assume that this nut port
is often
open the network will route this packet
on the logical level to the phone
and he the network will encrypt this
packet
for the over air transmission but on the
radio layer this packet is sent
towards our relay the relay has
can now manipulate and the whole content
of the
traffic but only focuses on the udp
header and changes udp header to an
icmp ping request with a known payload
here everything is valid encrypted and
sent towards the ue the ue
will now trigger the reflection
mechanism or
because it's an incoming icmp request
um from from an ip and will respond to
this icmp
ping request with an icmp ping recomply
copying the original payload from the
request
which is generated actually by at the
keystream generation server
so the relay has now the chance um to
compute the whole key stream because he
knows the plain text he knows also the
icmpingreply
and reuse this keystream to encrypt his
own new payload
which he would like to send towards the
target server
he also sets the destination ip
to the ip of the target server ip
everything is valid and sent towards the
net network encrypted
and the network has no means to detect
any manipulation
and then decrypts the packet and
forwards it
to packet towards the target server
so the target server has now received
the packet
and he will respond to it for example if
you haven't
tcp connection which should be built up
you've got a tcp
syn packet and the
target server will respond with a tcp
syn egg
towards this packet so
we need to receive the sun egg packet
as an attacker to build up a fully
functional
connection so the idea of the
decryption oracle so this is why we need
the decryption oracle
the idea of the decryption article is
now that
the response of the target server is
manipulated in this way
and that it also reflects the packet
and the reflected packet is also again
manipulated
and redirected to an entity called key
decryption server
so how does it look like in the sequence
diagram
the target server will respond for
example with a tcp
synag with a unknown plaintext a payload
with an unknown
payload we would like to receive this
payload because we would like to build a
valid tcp connection
towards the target server the network
received this
and it's actually directed on a logical
level on an ip level
towards the ue towards the phone
and on but on the radio layer this
packet is sent towards a relay the relay
has again the chance to manipulate
the plain text or the payload of this
packet
and now there is a also a second
reflection mechanism not the icmp ping
reflection
this is something we call unreachable
in case of um changing the ip protocol
header
we can change it to an unsupported
protocol and the ue
will reflect the payload the the packet
with the payload
of the incoming packet so this is where
the
um payload is where the reflection
measure nozzle is triggered
and um this reflection contains the
whole tcp
packet original coming from the target
server
and now the relay changes the
destination ip towards the decryption
server
and the network again receives the
packet
and decrypts it and forwards it or
routes it towards the
decryption server we can now access the
original packet from the
from the target server and
are able to access the information we
need
so
[Music]
using the uplink and downlink an uplink
encryption and downlink decryption
allows us to fully impersonate a vector
so we can start with the uplink
encryption oracle
to build a tcp packet
receive the tcp synag and perform
the uplink encryption again to send some
data to the target server
and the target server will respond
so we have performed the experiments
using the same
setup as shown before with a commercial
network with a commercial phone
and all these attacks do not require
any user interaction this is because
we use um the initial check
of android phones to be intercepted
which is android connectivity and
connectivitycheck.android.com
and we perform for the uplink
impersonation we perform two experiments
so just to recap the aim of the uplink
impersonation
the attacker would like to access a
website or
a server with the identity of the victim
and we performed an experiment
where we visit a website which is only
accessible by the victim
and therefore i need to introduce you to
server sites
server sites are sites hosted by the
providers that allow you to manage your
account
they allow you to book data plans or
even sometimes to show your phone number
the authentication is just based on the
ip address
so this is something called header
enrichment and the provider
at the gateway towards the server
inserts
insert a header and that says okay this
is this customer
he has his rights to be accessed
and we performed this
experiment and we're able to access the
server side
um without any interaction of this
victim
we further uploaded a 10 kilobyte file
to a server with the ip address
of the victim we will now see
the demonstration of the uplink impact
attack where we access the server side
with the identity of the vector
so we are again in the man in the middle
position
between the lte network and the phone
and here we see all the internet
entities
but we focus on the man in the middle
relay
we see the victim here
and we start the relay
we lay started we will disable airplane
mode now
[Music]
and start some management script that
perform all things automatically
and now the phone is connected again so
the aka has happened and everything is
fine
and we download the website using an
automatic call script
and here we go we downloaded in total
35 packets and the victim has still
functional lte internet connection
so we see the um basically the html
source code and we see that we are able
to access the information how many data
volume was used during the last period
of
and we are able basically also to book a
new data plan which is a day flat where
you can have free access for one day for
24 hours
so we should we have seen that the
uplink impersonation is um works in a
commercial setting and we will also see
that the downlink impersonation is
possible
so i didn't talk much about the downlink
impersonation however
it's quite similar to the uplink
implementation so you got an
encryption oracle and a downloading
encryption oracle and a decryption
oracle
the aim is um the other way around
so the attacker impersonates a network
and is able to send any kind of ip
traffic towards your phone
and he can use this to circumvent the
firewall for example if you have an app
listening on a particular port
or an iot device or something like that
and which should be
this should be protected by the
provider's firewall and
towards any incoming traffic right and
the aim of the um downlink impersonation
attack is now to circumvent this
provider's firewall
and send arbitrary ip messages towards
your phone
so we will see this um
so the aim
and we are again in the man in the
middle position between the lte network
and the victim
and we focus again on the um man in the
middle relay
and here we got the app that it listens
for incoming traffic
this is basically netcat just listening
we start the relay
the relay has found a cell and sends out
the identifiers
and we disable the airplane mode again
and so we
start some management scripts
and disable the airplane mode so
the aka is performed and the ue thinks
okay it's connected to the
network and already the attack has
happened and
here we see um hello downlink impact
which is in string
which is sent towards the towards the
app
so we now have seen that
the uplink and downlink impersonation
attack
is is a real attack vector in commercial
networks
and it's very important to discuss the
implementations
so the first question i would like to
answer
and who is affected and i guess if you
are not ordinary person and this is
something that should not or will not
happen to you
and the attacker needs to have
specialized hardware
and customized lte stack and conducting
and this attack outside our shielding
box
um is quite difficult however for
single targets and very high value
targets this might be an option
so we know that um mz catchers and
stingrays are out there
and used by agencies for conducting
attacks
and i recently came about an article
or report by amnesty international which
describes
an attack vector or an attack to a
journalist
um yeah where he got some spyware
installed on the phone
and basically i would like to read out
some sentences
and for the network injection the
attacker requires um either physical
location to the target
or access digit and the first sentence
of
um the describes
something similar to an mc catcher
attack so you need physical
approximation to the target
and there's another sentence which is
quite interesting to read
the phone's web browser is then
redirected to a malicious web page
or website and this is exactly the
author attack
so you get redirected and then might be
get infected by
a spider so an ordinary person might not
be affected by this but it might be
exploitable now or even in future
by some um agencies
besides besides the estimation of the
risk we would like need to talk about
consequences and first of all for
providers
providers rely on mutual authentication
for billing purposes
so for example and they use this server
side where you can book the data plans
but also
an attacker is able to generate a lot of
data in your name
and this would be built for your to your
bill
right and this would result in over
billing and this is something providers
should be currently
concerned about i think there are some
laws
in some countries that allow not to
overcharge you as customer
and there are also also um the risk of
authorization so um yeah accessing the
server side for example consequently the
impact attack is
a risk for the business model of the
providers
and second law enforcement agencies
rely on mutual authentication in case of
an investigation
for example when an attacker visits a
website
which is only or which visits the
website's
texas websites or upload illegal um
content to this webpage
and the police investigates in this case
and asks the
provider for the identity of a
particular ip address
and the wrong victim get gets blamed and
this can be
this is bad um for for for for
the police investigation and so
it's a kind of serious threat for
current and future
um investigations that are softly based
on ip addresses um in mobile networks
last but not least the consequences for
users
so what are the consequences for users
obviously this is a privacy thread
for example um when the server side
displays your phone number this
phone number can be directly linked to
your mc
and this can be used for further
tracking attacks right
and this is something you don't want but
also for industrial
users like having a factory connected
via lte
or iot devices ylte connected to your
control unit
would allow an attacker an attacker
to circumvent the provider's firewall
and thereby directly accessing the port
of the iot device
for example bad configured iot devices
that have over
telnet ports would be open to such an
attack
so um the question is how can we
mitigate the problem and the only valid
answer is
perform mandatory integrity protection
on the user plan
and there are two questions first of all
is
lte um capable of performing this
and what is about 5g so
lte is already around for 10 years
things are deployed and i guess there
will be no mandatory integrity
protection on
the user plane on um on
yeah for all devices because back
porting would be very expensive
however um 5g
yeah and and the situation and fight 5g
is
um different so
in 5g there is a standalone mode which
will be deployed
maybe we are 2022.
and um this standalone mode
in this standalone mode integrity
protection of the user plane is optional
but it's mandatory to support in full
rate for all devices
and this is something which is um only
yeah one month old so um
basically mandatory integral protection
on full red
level is um only supported since um
at the beginning of july but it's still
optional to use in 5g
so we will monitor the providers if they
will enable it
and this is how i would like to end my
talk um
so thank you very much for listening to
my talk
still healthy and feel free to contact
me if you have any questions
hi everyone and so thank you for
listening to my talk and and i hope you
enjoyed it
and so i don't know if i have much time
for answering q a i guess every most
yeah questions should be set by now at
least in the chat so
if you feel free to contact me if you
have further questions
and so yeah thank you for listening
again hope you enjoyed it