[Music]
hi everyone today's talk is about making
an
impact from india to the rest of the
world by building and nurturing women
infosec community
we all know that women are
underrepresented in the information
security sector
the world average female literacy rate
is 79.7
while in india the average female
literacy rate is just
65.46 percent as per women's web
in india a million engineers graduate a
year
but there are only 10 of them are women
in it
now after the 10 percent we will only
find
0.5 percent in n46 that's how the stats
are more or less
the ratio in the cyber security teams
are really dim
everyone knows about it and it's widely
recognized
now i have some questions for the women
in the audience
have you ever felt that you are one
among like thousand people
have you ever felt that you needed a
mentor but couldn't find one
you wanted to talk to somebody what was
hesitant in speaking
thinking that or they might judge me or
i wouldn't be able to articulate the
things well
everybody knows that this field that
women role models
and how many intersex women champions
are there especially when we talk about
india handful of them there are so many
unconscious bias we
all have whether i'm inadequate to be
part of i.t
or infosec whether i'm good at it or not
we are hesitant in speaking with the
people who are not like us
we always look for safe space to speak
without feeling being judged we as women
always want to be 10 or 10
be family meet workplace feed anywhere
else
everything should be well at home
husband to be best in
space child to be have the best of
life which leaves very less space for
our own aspirations
weekdays are hectic weekends are even
more hectic
especially to think about anything else
than family
now according to one of the surveys
women represent
only a quarter of the overall workforce
in cyber security
this is significantly a higher number
than 2017 which was just
11 but we still have a long way to go
i also felt all of that and that's what
motivated me to take up
a new a community which can help
bringing more women in cyber security
now men in the audience if you want to
bring more women in infosec
and your area of work i have given a
talk
at uh by at global apps at dc
on bringing diversity and inclusion so
you can take a look at it now
what this talk is about this talk is
about infosec girls community
the community we have built in india
what the community means to us how we
started
the community and along the journey of
the presentation
i'll share the framework on how to start
a community
and join the community of your interests
we've been giving trainings across
the years so we will be also releasing
the training
with their stock now before we deep dive
into the presentation i would like to
introduce myself
i am vandana verma my day job is with
one of the multinational companies as a
security solutions architect
and i'm also the president foreign goals
i use for pro bono work and i keep on uh
spending my free time uh with various
initiatives
with ovas with infrasec now and many
other initiatives
apart from that i regularly host speak
and a part of be part of multiple local
and international conferences
now i wanted to portray
infosec rules in one of the pictures now
when i try to search and when i try to
visualize
this one gif does the job brilliantly
than anything else it sums up and for
cigars really well
now what is infrastructure it's a
community which is always thriving
and working hard to support women and
students to be part of infosectors
and part of infosec now the core aim of
is to encourage them make sure they
don't leave the infrastructure space
we started infrastructures with the idea
of giving the safe space to women
but then we expanded it to the students
in a short span of four years we have
been able to
uh leverage our own community and bring
together
uh many people we have provided
one-to-one mentoring
to more than 200 women there have been
multiple career counseling sessions
which then resulted in more than 20
final job offers
we have built a thriving community of
speakers
more than a dozen out of them have gone
out and spoken at global conferences
infosec girls started in 2014
we had a downfall for some time but then
we rejuvenated back to community in
2017.
since then every year we are trying to
uh outgrow the number from the past year
we started the community with only
bangalore chapter
as there were multiple questions in mind
how many participants
and speakers would be coming and
with our regular jobs and family how are
we going to manage all of this
some of our some of us including myself
had more than a fair share of family
responsibilities
including infants so hence we started
the humble goals to begin with
and preferred slow and steady growth
wherein we're trying to achieve few
numbers
every year now we have over 15 chapter
leaders around the world
covering multiple cities in india we've
trained over 3000
women across the globe everything was
not a rosy picture
along the journey we did face our fair
share of
struggles we did had ours we did have
our own uh downfalls and issues
along the journey and when we talk about
building a community
or running a community the biggest
challenge is
that when it starts and where will it go
unlike an exam we study the courseware
and we know
whether we'll pass we will fail or we
will get the definition
but with the communities anything better
than yesterday
is good enough but how to keep that
going
now the first challenge was gathering
the people
sparking the initial interest making
sure that
we are trying together more people we
are trying to spread the awareness
so another big challenge was how they're
going to balance the family
how we are going to balance the families
especially to come to the mains and
when we talk about less number of women
in security so how
have how we can actually bring all of
them together
another big challenge was the venue how
are we going to find a space
to collaborate and come and meet with
each other
so when we started hosting meets uh
first time
we had a lot of concerns especially from
the venue providers like
there were a lot of trust concerns like
what this community is about
how it's going to cater to the goals
that they have
and especially there were a lot of
people
who asked the uh who asked for the money
from us
and we didn't have money another thing
came into picture wherein
how we will find a venue which is like
centrally located
and people can come there because
reaching a venue is one important thing
another big challenge was now we had
figured out okay this is how we're going
to gather the people
this is the venue that where we will be
hosting our meetup
but finding the speakers who can
actually have confidence in our own
goals and vision that we had so
there were so many people who had
preconceived notions
especially women like i would like to
mention the disparity
traces back into the school i've often
heard
that people preaching uh that women
are not meant for tech and especially
not for infosec
it has nothing to do with gender and
another big question was that people
didn't know about that there can be
a women community or actually women can
support each other
another most important factor was
apprehension
if we were rude or bullied for speaking
something which
which was not right and everyone has it
even i
did have it not just women men also have
the same thing
time management how will i be able to
manage the time
with the family we had very low
participation
due to the less outreach and less people
knowing about the cause
we did not realize that spreading
awareness was very important
we were not following multiple mediums
to reach the audience
in the beginning it was difficult to
bring in like more than
three or four people we had like a bunch
of people coming into the means
but we never lost hope we never
uh stopped trying hard
now two of the founders started the infa
figures
they tried something did a few things
he had an idea but could not take it
forward due to the personal and
professional reasons
or commitments at some point
infrastructural stopped we rejuvenated
it
but after that we were worried how to
stop the same
uh happening the same again hence the
sustainability plane plan had to be
there
how to make it run for a longer period
and another point how to stay motivated
we did receive the acceptance after a
while
when people started showing interest in
the community
they started reaching out to us they
started
uh asking that how i can be part of it
when your providers started trusting us
and supporting us like with sponsorships
and
telling that okay you can use my venue
now we do have four to five venues
available in most cities that we have
our employee girls
and we host meetups they were saying
keep doing the work good work don't wait
for the reward
things will automatically turn out to be
positive and that's what happened to us
and you can see in the uh on the screen
now we as part of the emphasis girls
do contribute in some other way and
the things that we do i would like to
share with you all
so what do we do we do host regular
meetups
and as part of the regular meetup we try
and meet and connect with each other to
share the technical knowledge
we also connect over uh informal lunches
so that we have a human touch we get to
know each other
and bond with each other we also
do meet over uh ideas and we
share ideas like i have some idea but
you might have a better idea
so we just talk about it how we can
actually
or bring in something new so that's all
or we do it at our meetups and
uh at discover time it's really not
possible to meet in person
so uh we felt the same way back in 2017
that
not all of us would be able to join
in-person meetups
so we started the virtual meets wherein
uh
we started our own youtube channel
and we started hosting all those
global meets wherein women around the
world can chime in and connect with the
indian women
so at every need there is one indian
women for sure
and out of those all the sessions that
we had
there are 80 percent of them are like
first-time speakers
we started collaborating with schools
universities
and many such places so
not much has been done in um
educating the students especially about
cyber security
we do have a lot of things going on okay
let's do this
let's do a hackathon let's develop
something but how about
imparting cyber security knowledge and i
believe
there has to be a separate program for
bringing up cyber security awareness
amongst the kids and students
especially college students the pros and
cons of cyber security needs to be
assimilated deep down into the roots
right from the start from the school
this is how we can make a change
and make our nation's cyberspace
one more approach other than the
awareness program would be giving them
the exposure to unmediated scenarios
in the form of games or challenges this
will catch their attention
and make them brainstorm about the
importance of cyber security
we started bringing cyber security to
the college students
and giving them opportunities before
even moving out of the college
and hence entire team of employee girls
spanning across india and outside
is trying to bridge that gap we
collaborate with international
institutes
when we talk about cyber security it's
all about ideas
and idea rules the world
learning is a lifelong process the
earlier it starts
the better so how about providing
scholarships and sponsorships to the
students
and women as part of infosec girls we
provide scholarships to
for various forums and conferences we
collaborate
with many conferences and colleges to
make sure that
uh students and women go out and be part
of the bigger conferences bigger
community and experience
how the world looks like when we talk
about infrastructures
it's not just a cocoon come out of your
cocoon and talk with people
share your ideas so
now the gap has been identified
our mission is to bridge that gap and
educate
more and more women passionate towards
security
by providing them the training via meets
and workshops
so we started giving workshops and
trainings at different cities
colleges and other conferences we have
given many workshops
at global conferences as well so these
are some of the trainings that we have
given
around the world in india outside india
like us egypt or israel
uh south africa and many more countries
now the tech uh industry is actually
grappling with two bike challenges
first it's struggling to make sure that
we have the right set of people
in information security how we can have
diverse set of people
so we started giving our free training
at
the conferences and colleges
so today i want to share
what this training was all about so here
is the link for our web application
security
for the people to get started and
you can actually see there's a flow
step-by-step process to start off
what is web application security what is
a proxy um
what is an attack look like what is sql
injection
what is a class site scripting what is
an idol what is an xxc
so everything is documented step by step
how you can replicate it
you've used multiple vulnerable weather
applications to train people
so we have outsourced everything here
you can take a look at it
and if you have any confusion you can
reach out to us anytime so this is the
link for our training which we wanted to
release
and um so today we are making our course
content public
to the wider community and world so that
they can go
get benefit from it and train other
people
especially for college students if you
want to kick-start your career in an
application theory
you can actually take a look at it we've
also helped
some of the organizations and colleges
to perform ctf capture the flags
so we've done partnership with them for
what
to encourage the diverse candidates
including students around
infosec these challenges really really
helped
and especially bring curiosity in them
when we talk about the infosec skill gap
people really talk about it especially
from past few years we've been talking
about
there's a skill gap but how to address
that
that's the number one problem now
another problem is
how to fix that gap both of the problem
are even more acute
when it comes to cyber security there
are more than one million cyber security
jobs
that needs to be filled which is like
projected
and now when we have such a huge gap
to fill those one million cyber security
jobs the industry must
look at crosstalk people bring people
from diverse groups fresh ideas
so how do we actually bring them
to increase the number first step is
like
we have to approach the people who are
there
to make them active okay yes you can be
part of him for psycho
now once you have active people how
about
converting converting in inactive people
to the active people
branching out reaching out to the people
who don't know about infosec
i have trained myself like the qa
to bring them to security developers to
bring them to security
people who are part of system admins to
be part of network security
so it's like cross-training people
there's nothing more beautiful than that
now what better way to show you the
impact
from the ideas and thoughts of people
who have been
impacted by us so about jasmine
she started uh coming to imperfect girls
and
she felt that yes she can actually
overcome her stage fear she had a
huge stage fear but we helped her in dry
run stem runs before she actually gave
her first talk at imperfect girls
kieran learned from other speakers and
she has spoken for the first time at
infosec girl's online meet
manisha cannot forget the want and the
vibe of the community
she is one of the director for for a
company but she did not feel that
there is an age gap irrespective of
any age group this community supports
each other
community has advised her with the
latest
and greatest things that are happening
in the infosec
about shifa she has got a place to learn
grow herself and share her knowledge as
she's this uh she's a startup owner
now about henna she got the place to
learn grow and share her knowledge
and learn from the workshops that we
have been given
shivani got to know about infosec goals
from her friends
and when she joined for the first time
she felt formed
and welcomed then there was no looking
back for her
she has been helping us refining doing
multiple things multiple initiatives and
prosecutors
now what did we achieve so far
we have actually multiple chapters and
chapter leaders around the world
we have um we have been encouraging
the talents especially the fresh ones so
we have
80 percent speakers
we have been upskilling people and we
have trained over 3000 first
women around the globe starting with
india
now we are open and accessible sometimes
in-person needs are not possible as i
mentioned so we
do host online sessions at our
youtube channel and all the sessions are
recorded and available there
and we have over like 1000 subscribers
now and we have this
community support for that now we also
trained over 500 school students on the
area of
austen and cyber security we have we
host
10 to 15 meetups every month considering
the different states
but during the time of covid we do the
meetups
every two weeks so that we can connect
with the global audience
we've also won a program of the year
award
at rsa by intelligent cup this
was like we should say thank you to the
uh
to the award owners
we've also uh tried and connected
uh and tagging up with multiple colleges
across india and abroad to spread the
knowledge to restrain
students and we try and help the
colleges refine their curriculum
especially
when it comes to cyber security united
we stand
if i'm managing alone i will fail i
would never be able to perform
what i really want to do especially when
it comes to a community
so with unity as and when there have
been
any or mishappenings or any uh
criticization we always have been there
for each other
we always have been there and stood for
each other
whenever any leader felt low
we always strive and talk to each other
whenever
uh we are trying to coordinate a session
we make sure we learn from the session
not just coordinate we all
work together and we all respect each
other
whenever there's a leader who's stepping
down we respect them
we help them look for the future
endeavors whenever they want to come
back
the place is theirs now the recipe for a
strong community is their
passionate people leaders
and compassion we create grooming the
new speakers
doing the dry runs with them before the
even talk happens
to help them gain confidence because
that's very very important
when i gave my first talk i couldn't
even look at the audience
i was dead nervous now
we try to make sure we bring the
confidence in them
now people who are hesitant in speaking
we help them in understanding okay this
is how the first time ever speaker is
doing this is how you can actually give
your presentation
so we help them in their talks
we keep experimenting we keep
experimenting with our own formats
like uh when we create banners or we
we find new speakers every time we keep
grooming them
and now we experiment with the new
avenues venues
like right now we are in the kobe times
we've been experimenting with different
platforms that how to stream live
on a channel how to do the live
trainings
how to perform the meets how to connect
with a wider audience
now when we talk about infosec girls
chapters we have over like as i said
15 chapters and these are some of the
leaders around the globe that we have
without them infosec girls wouldn't have
been possible
and wouldn't have been existing or
sustaining
so what we really do with the community
we always ask for feedback
we ask them what we can do better
what can be important what all things
can be done
especially when we what new we can bring
now as for the feedback from the
relevant uh
feedback we embed in our own journey
we all uh we all take a tab on
the feedback and keep enhancing on that
now we all have a question
when we talk about community should i
start a community of my own
or should i contribute to an existing
one
now i have something to tell you or
you should ask these questions to
yourself why would you create a new
community
if there is no community around if there
is a community
then toss it matches your vision and
goal or what you want to do
test the goal of the community matches
the core values of myself if no
then do we have the bandwidth to start a
new community
however building a community is a giant
effort
so if you start a community ensure you
keep it running
now if the goal matches we can join the
community
so we started taking the steps in
building the community a few years ago
we had a lot of questions a lot of
challenges along the journey
which we tried to solve with this
particular framework
we're trying to help you with your
journey of infosec
so the first thing is there are four
pillars
which make this framework building
managing improving and before that
sustenance now when we talk about
building
naming the community is the most
important thing finding the right name
for it
which can match the goal and the vision
that you have in your mind
finding a venue plan the meetups
creating a mailing list creating the
social media handle so that
you people get to know that you are
going to start a new community
there's a community that they can
resonate to
announce the meetups partner with the
venue providers so that the
meetups can keep on going find
colleagues community is not a one-man
show or
not women one women show it has to be
with multiple leads so that it keeps on
running
planning the frequency of the meat is
very very important whether it's going
to happen
every month every two months every three
months what platform we would be using
announcing the meat on the website on
all the social media handles
now when you have on the social media
handles
you should have a code of conduct that
yes this is how we all are going to
behave
when we talk about the meetups we
are going to have meetups every now and
then but how about sustaining it
we had our downfall but we came up with
a plan so that
we can actually keep the community
running so we have to discuss with all
the leads that how should we keep it
running for longer time
we can have shorter goals okay let's
keep it running for one year
let's keep it running for two years now
now what new we can bring in the
community
then how we can improve on the feedback
from the community
that's what keep the interest of the
people
yes the community is actually my
community
people are listening the leads are
listening and i can be a lead one day
it's very very important to take the
feedback and work on that these are some
of the ethos
uh that we have built for our own
community
and which can resonate with any of the
communities
we should always give back to the
community in some form or the other
like we have learned from the community
now let's give it back
now community is inclusive of everyone
right from a common college student to
a old age person it can include anyone
there's no age for learning something
new
the enthusiasm of the community members
we have to keep it running
we have uh we have created a future
roadmap for us
a goal for us a vision for us so that
we don't have a downfall again or we
don't see
the downfall again so uh we have a plan
for the next ten years okay
let's keep these many chapter leaders
going we have 15 capital leaders how
about reaching
every part of the country especially
stats from india
and every part of the globe there are
uh so many unsung areas where people
don't think of going
how about reaching those areas host free
conferences for the community to learn
and share knowledge encourage more and
more participants
and let them speak at the
conference at the means give them a
space to speak
focus on educating underprivileged
people
there are some key takeaways now we've
heard
all the things that infosect girls have
been doing or what we should be doing
how about we pay it forward showcase
the positive differentiation by making
security
much more secure and if not
let's take help from different
organizations how about
partnering with them we are making good
progress
but we do have a long way to go there is
a lot of work that needs to go
in there is a mantra
that we that we consider
good better best never let it rest
till good becomes better and better
becomes the best
there's a beautiful quote by mr obama
which we live by
every day a greeting comes
a greatness comes when we appreciate
each other's strength
when we learn from each other when we
lean on each other
and not to forget support each other
you can reach us anytime on these social
media handles we have a mailing address
you can email us anytime for any queries
or
questions or feedback
namaste namaste is the common greeting
and gesture to send a message of
peaceful
and spirituality and it's a form of
thank you
thank you till the next time we meet
hi everyone thanks for listening to me
if you have any questions
please do ask me
uh i can see some questions in the chat
box that
i do a lot of help to my organization
or my companies and colleges recruiting
effort
and constantly see that when's uh
interest in
data science but um have you been able
to identify why women are not pursuing
infosec
so i would like to say yes there are a
lot of challenges first of all
a lot of women are not aware that this
is the field wherein
they can experiment uh so
that's what we are trying to do we are
trying to make them aware about that
there is a field that exists
uh and we need to take a step forward
and be part of this industry because
this industry need
creative mindset which we have
and people are so supportive in their
this industry that
if you want to come forward and be part
of infosec
everyone supports there's no gender bias
there are few things which we hear but
then uh the community that i have been
with
they're all supportive and
we all need to work towards bringing
people from college and telling them
that yes
you can be part of information security
there is a domain that exists
there are colleges who are who have
courses on information security but then
we still have a long way to go
so that we can have more and more
diverse candidates
in information security
so um now while we are getting more
questions i would like to say that
if uh you want to know more about the
framework which i have shared i would
love to discuss about it
um and especially i would say or please
look at the training that we released
because uh if you are getting into
application security
that is a good training to get kick
start your uh
career in application security and i
have a few other resources which can
help you
getting started in application security
there are a few resources i have for
docker container security so i can share
it with you
and uh even though we do have leaders in
india and few other part of the world
uh few other parts of the world but we
still have less hands
so we would love to get we would love to
get you on board
take your feedback and if you want to
volunteer you want to be part of it
it's everyone's community even though we
started in
india but we wanted to go global
we want people to know okay uh there are
some resources which are available which
we can leverage
and it's not that that we are not
joining hands with other communities
it's always good to have collaboration
with other communities as i mentioned
that
it's always good to have multiple hands
multiple eyes supporting each other
absolutely we are anticipating um and we
are releasing more trainings in the
coming up sessions
so that people can take help from it uh
if you want to have virtual machines
that we have created
uh we would love to share that as well
so
how will you be sharing these training
so by this uh presentation we have
shared one training
and uh uh probably after the session you
will have the presentation
access uh you can take the
url of the training from there and
you can get started with it and if you
have any confusion questions around the
training
i would love to uh connect with you and
share more resources and if you want to
share this training train more people i
would love to support you
anytime
foreign
so uh the presentation will be there uh
on the blackhead site so that
you can you know take help from that uh
take inputs from it
or even around the training the
resources that
we have we would be uh like we have made
all of these things public so that
it can help other people like we have
trained over 4 000 women now
around the world even uh when we were
remote
we've trained a lot of college students
we have trained a lot of
people at the conferences and we have a
target that
we can keep training people we um love
to collaborate with the
colleges and institutions so that we can
impart knowledge for free because that's
very important
so um how do we get involved with the
community as in how to start
you can just drop a note to uh hello at
infosec girls dot in
and i can share all the resources that
we have and the people the leaders who
are part of it
uh they are ready to help you at any
given point of time
so all the real leaders which are
currently there they train the new
people who want to get onboarded
if you've missed to ask questions please
feel free to reach out to me anytime
and i would be glad to have a
conversation with you
i absolutely do have a resources around
what hiring managers can do to make sure
that they are doing their part or
we all are doing as a hiring manager
so i can share it with you