[Music]
hello everyone
i'm jonghyun cheng i'm happy to come
here to share our research
operation camera apt operation targets
semiconductor vendors
my college in dilling chandeljung and i
will show the apd group called kimera
which is discovered in 2018 and 2019.
now let's briefly introduce ourselves
i'm ck chang
i'm a senior researcher at cycraft
west in university studied for my phd
degree
i play the ctf and founder city of team
called bamboo fox
and we joined the devcon finals
it's 2016 and 2018
and currently i just retired
i'm also met the view board at the
hitcom
and hitp so
i'm an active member in the security
community
in taiwan community i also joined the
cia route
which is the best hacker group in taiwan
my partner shonda zhang who is a
security researcher
at cycraft and he also found a local
hiker group called uccu hackers
and indilin is also the security
researcher
at scicraft and he's a reverse engineer
hobbyist
and learning how to reverse from his
high school
and playing ctf he also presents
a lot of research in hika and rukang
our company cycraft is a star company in
taiwan
and now we have a branch in singapore
and japan
while focused on using ai to solve the
security problem
currently we have three products the
sensor
which is used for three hunting and the
secaria
or apt investigator always use this
system to do an apt investigate
and the cyber total australian
intelligence platform
so today's our research have a lot of
help
from these three products
our company also joined the mitre ntt
and ck evaluation
in last year and compete with the top
vendors
in the world and get a nice result
if you are interested about that you can
come to see our blog
in this url
so let's start today's talk so this is
today's online
we will give the introduction uh first
to give a overview about taiwan
semiconductor ecosystem
and to illustrate the three actor camila
and then we will move to case study to
understand the activities
of the hacker next
we will go deeper to three actors
digital
signal which shows how to reverse
and the technical use by malware
we will also show other incidents in
taiwan
which may relate it to kimela
in the end we will make a brief
conclusion
to give a take away to the audience
as taiwan has a special political
position
we encounter a lot of cyber attack every
year
in 2018 we have a tsmc ransomware
the tsnc is one of the largest uh
enterprise
in semiconductor industry in taiwan or
even in the world
and he is being hit by one of cry and
hold down their bottle line for two days
and cost them 170 millions
in last year kaspersky has discovered
the shadowhammer
which is a supply chain attack to asus
and in this year in may we have a cpc
attacked by a co-lock ransomware
the cpc is an energy sector
and has a lot of gas station so when
this attack happen
a lot of gas station is of service
so it's a serious attack to the critical
infrastructure
amount of land the semiconductor is
mostly catch our eyes
even so taiwan is a very small country
we have taken important role
in the semiconductor landscape
with our government paid a lot of
resource to develop
this industry we have established
ourselves as a leading player
in the semiconductor industry and we
have some well-known leaders
including tsmc and mmtk
so in 2018 and 2019 forced the
market sharing and the waffle capacity
we are in the leading ship in the world
and according to tawa news report we are
the largest
and fast-growing semiconductor equipment
maker
which make the revenue about 12 billions
so what's attack to this vendor will
have very serious impact
first because this vendor take a lot of
part
to taiwan's economy so attack to
list vendors like tsnc will make a
serious impact
to taiwan's economy and it will also
affect the entire global supply chain
in this report we mostly focused on i.t
security
compared to the ot security for example
bankrupt production line hold up
will immediately show the damage
the attack to the i.t for example steal
intelligent property
will not show the damage immediately but
however
it will have a long term and serious
impact to the enterprise
so we should take care of both ot and
i.t security
because our company cycled
is a taiwan local security company so we
have a very high visibility
in semi-conductor industry in taiwan
and between 2018 and 2019 we have
discovered
several attacks to these vendors and the
victims
are mostly located at shinsu science
park
central science park is a century of
taiwan high-tech industry
and especially for semi-conductor
vendors
we have first published this report in
this year
about april and after we publish our
report
we receive a lot of feedback from other
security researchers
other vendors and our friends
what you reveal a lot in factly there
are more than seven vendors in taiwan
and europe were also being attacked by
the actor
so we would say this attack is very
intensive the tanker have ability
to launch a large-scale attack to many
vendors
at the same time
and the this fpga
group is not choose their victim
randomly
and they choose their victim precisely
and very well coordinated
aside from the vendor themselves a lot
takers also attack their subsidiaries
and competitors so let's show the trend
that from the old time the attacker only
attacked
the enterprise itself which is a single
point attack
and currently we move to the supply
chain attack
and for now in this case what we see is
the attack
on the entire industry survey
and in all this texts uh the techniques
the tactics were similar so we believe
that this attack is conducted
by the standard director and their
targets of course the semiconductor
vendors
um the more they use is the merge
by different open source tool and
commercial tool
like a dumper mimikos and cobb's truck
so that's why we named this actor kimela
just like camilla is merged from a
different animal these attack
mutual different more and insert their
cosmic code
to make their own mower
in order to avoid attribution the
tech uses c2 hosted in public cloud
like a google app engine and azure
the goal of the attacker is different
from the other tech who want to steal
the
like the credit card information the
user information
in this attack the director focus on
steel documents
source code and sdk of chip related
project
so we can see the motivate
the motivation of the taker is to steal
the intelligent property
so we start our investigation during the
2018 and 2019
and we take the investigation in more
than three vendors
and analyze more than 30 thousand
endpoints
today we will show three case studies
from three vendors and we find these
three vendors as cass dottie
the first reason is because they are all
take a living global position
in their own market segment
and the other reason is that because we
get into investigation
at a different high point so
the analytical perspective of the
tech campaign was different
for a company who is our long-term
partner
so we regularly monitor their activities
which allow us to have a more detail
about a taker's activities
and also we can treat him to a root
cause
so in this case study we want to show
you
the activities that taker do and
how to track to the request
for b company is a one-time ir service
so when we get into investigation the
tech is already beat down for a long
time
so we cannot recover anything back
but however we can highlight the trade
actors
long long-term activities and
discover what kind of data was leaked
and stolen
by the attacker which can help us to
understand the taker's
mission and motivation
and the c company is also our long-term
partner
and at different points like our
security team has very high security
ability
so they can help us to deeply
investigate
and get a lot of free feedback from them
so please give us more information and
help us
to profile the story actors
so next we will show the case study
and turn to the junk to introduce and
explain
each of the three case studies thanks ck
and john i will introduce a two case
study in
this session so let's start
and uh before we start the custody i
just want to mention
all the every machine and username are
the identified
now original name so the first comment
you want to use
we call a combining a cast study
and uh in the cast.a we
is our long-term partner and we discover
and
stop the threat editor in a facial time
and we found there's a 50 endpoint and a
six
user convert compromise and the right
hand side
is our investigation grave which is
energy
rate it tells us what endpoint has been
compromised
and the compromise endpoint when the
thread
later moves to this end point
and then the first malware we found in
this environment
is a cobalt strike beacon and uh
the corporate we can pertain as a google
update
and then we found this uh file in the
tumor string
but the they are same malware but they
have a different hash
so the australian has customized their
vector for a different endpoint
so we can find any file hash match in on
the file files total
just like previous mention the editor
user
user backdoor pertain as a google update
so they also choose
choose the google cloud player phone as
a
c2 comment as their c2 communication
but that's an interesting point is
the first day the first first couple
shots began
they use a google cloud player phone
but the second day they get a new
endpoint they deploy the
new cobots vegan they change
the whole hosting server
they choose another one cloud service
for the c2 communication
but there is a sense related in our
point of view
is a solution is a multi a
it's a group so there's a multiple
attack in the group so everyone has
their preferred cloud service so they
change the cloud service
and we found it a
two remote execution tool in the
environment
which is a schedule desk under the wmic
the slider uses a sale text tasker to
use uh to copy a file and the
execution the backdoor
and then they use the wmic to
check the target endpoint has an
international connection
so why they just why they just chose one
of them to
do the data movement
because the diamond ic can get as stdl
information so this can get output
information to check the status
and they can use a cache credential in
the
environment so they use the target
analysis to do this kind of a
goal
and
however we're finding there's a schedule
desk
and the wnic so we can draw a simple
investigation graph like this so there's
a
one server called server lauren has user
schedule tasker and the wnic data
movement to
these three endpoints and then this
swimming one of them is a domain
controller
so we find there is a server lauren has
a remote sq
uh ir tool collecting the
domain controller data so what they have
they correct is the
rigid tree and the system and the system
ngts.dit file
so why also i had to want to collect
this two files
is because a threader cluster file can
get the windows 80 information the
ntts.dit
store the encrypted
windows 80 username password in
email.com something like this
so they collect the file but the layers
and still need a decoration key so
the integration key is stored in the
windows registry so that's why they the
swear term need to connect two file
and then they use the wing ir and the
pretend as a
name as a file name as a recording bit
ims which is a
digital file name
so based on finding and
our air explication tell us the
there's an ambi clear user schedule test
deploy google
update to the server lower
so we track back into ambika layer
so ambiguous timeline tell us
before the scheduled test execution six
minutes ago
then there's a
rdp log on successfully from the ip1
so we think it is a possible is a higher
low cost about
this attack and then we notice after the
rdp logong
they use this uh user account to do a
system recognizance
and do the schedule test code to deport
remote deploy the malware
so
we notice the switch editor has a not
has a data it's refrigeration
for some file like the
reconnaissance reconnaissance result and
they
use a one byte to modify ir file and the
rename as a
later file name like a recording with
ims as
ju check dioxy and we found
this uh fairhead in multiple case study
so we think it is a same sorry editor
and
the best on the previous
technique and the file the ring irig
file they store
so we sing a signature technique of
operation key mirror
and then we transpected the rdp ip
so we noticed this on scan hostel and
which is a vpn server vpn server so
vpn server also can be compromised your
vpn account not
cannot be the last line of your defense
and the above are the first casualty
and the second casting is becoming and
just like previous mention becoming is a
ir service covering
we're doing ir service for this company
so the just quick overview the status is
a
big company has been compromised very
long time
and due to the there we have a frenzy
coming and the c comings
has a business collaboration with big
company
so because due to the bitcoin
corporation so
they had some network interactive so
communities carry the sound security
anomaly
activities from becoming so they
introduced uh to
do the investigation so
when i do uh when we do a ir service
we we summarize the time period starting
uh
2018 to 2019.
and we found others in speaker study we
found on the thread that used a
powershell but still send the user
posture is killed in the
cobra strike b speaker and the migrated
cobblestone back door to the svc holster
but this most important thing is we find
in the
powershell cable strike begun
in the tank end point but they have
included two domain console is a very
serious and
just like the previous led attack
the threat use the cloud service to
do their to do the c2 communication
so they use a google cloud platform in
this time they also use the
microsoft azure cloud service
so based on the previous because
becoming has a has been serious hacked
so it's a very difficult to manually
investigation so the following the
screenshot is all ai generate
cyber situation wave so it tells
what endpoint the endpoint has been
compromised and the
this endpoint has connection to the
something
manager we which we didn't scan so it's
tell our ir team can
do some investigation on this endpoint
to
trigger the compromise scope
so starting the 2018 november
illustrator has getting the environment
and the understanding they come back
quarterly best to convey the new data
they want
so every coil they will come back to
here to
get some new file a little bit
so probably they need to do some reports
to their boss more
or their buyer
until 2019 november the australian
deployed one new weapon before that
the threat of the commonwealth score
didn't get extended
so until 2019 november
they deploy a new malware and the 2019
december
they extended the compromise score so
which means
the previous pro in maui has a has a
has some it's work
for them
so first of all our investigation
we found we made an inventory about the
big data
so following uh the straight ato
targeting is frequently the threat of
collateral portal map the back of the
workspace and attribute
sdk information and just
their target is about semiconductor
intelligence property
so we assume there's a business spy or
state sponsor attack
some country won't benefit a certain
industry
but which one we are not sure but we
show is a
attacker intense is stealing the interns
property
so i will move on to the we will turn to
the our colleagues ck we'll introduce a
test.c
so ck okay thanks for john
and next i will continue to our case
study policy company
and company c is our long-term partner
and have a very high security skill
and there is a principle in our company
that when we conduct our investigation
we will try to minimize the data and
files that we needed
from the victims environment this
is for protection to victims privacy and
confidential
so if the blue team in logan victim
organization has a very skillful
that can help us to get deeper deeper
so in this case when we finish our first
investigation we tell the result to land
and the protein helped us to find out
more
to profile the stray actors
so from the experience of this cast
there is a recommend a lot
even though security service are also
seen
your blue team must have a very high
skill
so that you can interactive with the
outsource vendors
okay in this bed in this case we first
find
a more we call it three in one cloud
storage tool
i use a g drive uh dropbox and onedrive
to upload the steel file
and their hash is hit this here and
when we discover it this one has no
recording
bt and because of this use
this mower use the webs api to transfer
file
so it's able to bypass level 7 firewall
we also have discovered the other cloud
storage tool
that uses open load
and because we have monitored some
command
used by the hacker and in this command
we can find the authentication
token and upload the file pass
so we can find some file upload by the
hacker
and also we find some files a lot
in victim environment that is possible
to be leave by a hacker and one of the
files like that
so this file is like a cheat sheet of
the director
and let me follow the trick step 3 to
export
the ntts so in fact we also monitor
the similar activities and follow the
link here
we can find a very famous security
foreign
in china so this can give
us some hint about the campaign so we
can
guess while the campaign has at least
one member
understanding chinese
and we also make a profile about the
active time of the actor
so we find that they are most active
in the segtender birth in 2019
and their working hour is from the
morning 8
30 to night 8 30.
from this time period we can guess
the taker's time zone is located in utc
plus 8.
and their working day is monday to
friday and most busy
in wednesday and sometimes if some event
or submission is needed they may also
work
as saturday so from this information we
can guess the campaign
is at the same time zone to taiwan
okay so with the help
of the blue team of our partner
we have more information more profile
about this campaign
so next we will go deeper about three
actors digital
signal and indie will show you the mower
and the technical use by this malware
okay so that's your turn indeed
hi i'm indy reverse engineer from from
sci-craft now i'm going to introduce
actress digital arsenal
we have observed four main tools they
used to carry out
the attack the first
we are going to talk about is cobalt
strike beacon
cable strike is a commercial red team
operation framework
they use global strike beacon as their
primary
backdoor in lease intrusions for the
persistency
they override google chrome update
utility with
their kobo strike beacon this
there is no any new autorun entry was
created
so it will lower the chance to be caught
we found this backdoor on several
company
so we linked the intrusion events
together
our project detected some suspicious
memory block
the interesting part is that it is
a p file and also a show code
cable strike beacon and metal spotted
meter preacher both use this technique
the hybrid payload this technique is to
embed
show code into the pe file header
the pe magic header mz
could be decoded as valid instructions
and the list instructions will work fine
in most of context
so you can ignore this in instructions
and append shortcut after it
the show code will locate its address
and execute the reflective loader
to load pe image in memory in memory
cable strike uses a special strategy to
inject payload into other process
first cable strike will spawn a new
process
or choose a target process then inject
the show code into the target process
we call it stager the real payload will
be transferred through
numpy and executed by stager
the stage the list strategy
will bypass some sandbox or emulation
based scanning
here is a wing rar it is a popular
commercial
conversion software it was used in this
operation
the actor used rar.exe to compress
and encrypt the files they store
they try to ambulate and be create
the program with existing file path
the reason why we mention this file is
this file is different from the original
one
we grabbed this old version of weak rar
and compare it with the
one hacker used we found the difference
part was located
in code section and such patch may
lead the program to crash we have two
hypothesis
first is the actor change the byte
intentionally
to make file hash different so
hash based detection will not find this
file is
rar if your organization do not use
wing rar the file may be detected
and triggers on investigation
second hyposit it is just a bit flip
during copy charged by
the age of file it is highly possible
at that time we are going to talk about
the most
interesting malware used in this
operation
the skeleton key
we found a unique malware that made with
two open source hacking tools
dumpert and i believe
everyone here has heard about mimikaz
it is a well-known hacking tool to dump
credentials from memory
but it has more capability like
bypass group policy and spawn
command-line prompt task manager
or registry editor
maybe you don't know dunkirk it was
made by a security company called
outflank
it is a proof of concept program to use
direct system call on windows unlike
linux we can't directly use
system call initial code because windows
system call numbers changed from release
to release
the only stable interface is explore
functions
from the shared libraries that is why
windows show code must rely on them
and always begins with locating
functions in memory
by traverse peb loader data
and pe structures
so how do dunker doing doing it
first it use rtl get version to
determine
which version of windows you are using
and
select different embedded system call
function depend on it
after that you can bypass any user's
facebook
and doing anything you want without
trigger or
alert or get blocked
for the one who don't know what skeleton
key is
skill london key is an abd malware
discovered by
dell security works in 2015.
it will implant a backdoor password to
domain controller
in an active directory directory
environment
then attacker can authenticate as any
user as they want
with the backdoor password but the user
must be
a existed valid user meanwhile
original password was not affected
any other round password still will be
rejected
so how does skeleton key do it
it will it will alter the the
authentication flow
by hooking some crypto functions in
lsas.exe
although original skeleton key malware
was never released
publicly author of mimikat still made
his own implementation
skeleton key is a very powerful weapon
against
active directory because you don't need
to dump admin credentials
for a lateral movement if you use
administrator credential to
access endpoints in a domain you may
trigger a lot of alerts
but if you're logging but if you're
logging with normal users
the situation will be different it will
leave
only nearly no clue only bunches of
logan success event
and most administrator or investigator
will ignore normal user logon events
easily
and skeleton key can not be
removed without reboot it will be
painful to reboot a domain controller
because you may break your
organization's daily routine
we also observe some other apt attack
that using modified version of mimikaz
against
taiwan government agencies
next we are going to introdu introduce
the new finding after the white paper
published
we found winter backdoor was used in
this operation
at the first time charged by
command-line event log and the program
usage
we thought that was a network probing
tool
but after detailed analysis we found
that it is actually a winter backdoor
because of the magic number used by the
wiki backdoors protocol
so that was our finding about operation
camera
now i'm going to share some recent apt
events in taiwan
as we mentioned at the beginning
taiwan's national gasoline company was
hit by a new ransomware
called codelock it was based on
an open source ransomware called eda2
investigation bureau found that cobalt
strike
and investigation bureau found the cable
and some suspicious activity in their
domain controller
they say this event was related to rinky
group
also we had monitored several attacks
against taiwan government agencies using
skeleton key
but with different backdoor password
they use a modified version of mimikaz
executed in memory only we think
skeleton key might be a new trend in the
near future
now ck will make a conclusion for us
about this talk in the end
let me quickly to give some conclusion
here is some takeaway in this
talk we disclosure a large-scale aptly
attack
targeting semi-conductor vendors and
there are more than
seven vendors are compromised and these
vendors are in taiwan
and europe taker
has a precisely a text they are not only
targeting
leading semiconductor vendors but also
attack
their subsidiaries partners and
competitors
different from other apt group their
goal is to steal
intelligent properties like the document
source code
and sdk which will make a long-term
impact to the big victim enterprise
from this motivate we may guess that
taker
is a business competitor or a stent
sponsor
to enhance their semiconductor industry
we have find some ioc in the appendix
so if you want to find some ioc you can
reference
to the appendix in this slide
and from technical part the taker
widely utilized some open source tool
and general tools
so it's hard to make the attribution
and they also like to merge a different
kind of of mower
to make their own malware
and english to sure case study
their ad and vpn uncompromised
so which julia the enterprise should
consider the resilience
of their i.t system and avoid to relying
on a single security service
we also discovered that attacker used a
skeleton key
which is rarely used but very powerful
way for the taker
and which makes adversaries looking like
a normal user
to achieve the persistent and defensive
invasion
so in the end uh i would like to say
that no system is safe
so we need to regularly to do the threat
hunting
and shorten the mean time to detect and
mean title response
and thank you for your listening and
will come for your questions