[Music]
hello
and welcome to our virtual black hat
presentation entitled
repurposing neural networks to generate
synthetic media for information
operations
my name is phil tully and i'll be joined
later in this slide deck by my colleague
lee foster
we work together at fireeye where i'm a
staff data scientist on fire ice data
science team
and lee is the senior manager of
information operations in fireeye's
threat intelligence group
for a bit of background about myself
i've been at fireeye for two years and
i've been working at the intersection
of cyber security and machine learning
for over five years
in a previous academic life i earned my
doctorate in computational neuroscience
and nowadays i perform research and
development on fire's malware and intel
product offerings
lee and his team of intel analysts
specialize in identifying cyber driven
nation state influence campaigns online
he holds a master's degree in political
science a second in
intelligence and international security
and is currently pursuing a third
masters in analytics
so some quick bookkeeping to start out
at first
in this presentation we're going to try
to convince you that open source
pre-trained machine learning models can
be leveraged to generate custom
synthetic media for malicious purposes
after introducing some core background
material i'll dive into three successive
proof of concepts for how this can be
accomplished today
in the text image and audio domains i'm
going to channel the three wise monkeys
and organize these experiments into
three sections
see no evil hear no evil and speak no
evil
i'll demonstrate how to fine-tune
pre-trained natural language processing
computer vision
and text-to-speech neural networks in
order to generate customizable synthetic
media
lee will then wargame out these
capabilities in the context of social
media driven
information operations or io and assess
the challenges underlying detection
attribution and response in scenarios
where actors can anonymously generate
and distribute
credible fake content we'll start off
with some background
initial material and for starters it's
worth pointing out that
synthetic media is by no means a new
development methods for
manipulating media for specific agendas
are as old as the media themselves
you'll see some of the more famous
examples illustrated here
including when the chief of the soviet
secret police was photographed walking
alongside joseph stalin
before being retouched out of an
official press photo after he himself
was arrested and executed during the
great purge
an image of the pyramids was altered to
fit the cover of national geographic
magazine
shifting two of them closer together to
emphasize their size
digital graphic after effects like this
became prominent with the advent of
photoshop
now fast forward to 2016 where carefully
crafted social media messages were being
posted across several platforms
in order to disrupt public discourse and
influence online opinion leading up to
the us presidential election
then later in the 2010s the term deep
fake was coined
there were several viral deep fakes
including one targeting mark zuckerberg
screenshotted here that was designed to
be a warning about the future of digital
manipulation
deep pick videos including techniques
like face swapping and lip syncing are
concerning in the long term
our talk will focus on more basic and
arguably more believable synthetic media
generation advancements including in the
text
image and audio domains we'll provide
evidence later in the talk how some of
these are already being leveraged as
part of i o campaigns today
social media has greased the wheels for
this type of activity by providing
anonymity immediate global reach and the
ability to go viral
rife data disclosure and most
importantly a seamless way to share
content publicly
the low-hanging fruit nature of this
threat environment was illustrated by
previous work i was part of led by john
seymour
four years ago at black cat we
demonstrated how to generate credible
synthetic texts to manipulate social
media users for the purpose of simulated
fishing attacks
the snapper bot was shown to combine the
best best of both worlds
the shotgun approach of fishing think
nigerian print scams that take little
effort and have relatively low success
rates
and the more targeted approach of
spearfishing that takes additional
upfront research effort
but typically pays off in terms of
higher success rates
by seating a machine learning model with
content read off the target's twitter
timeline
and generating text pertaining to their
recent tweet history
then simulating this at scale we could
get click-throughs more often and with
less effort compared with humans
all due to machine learning such
generative machine learning models can
also be used for good too
a few examples covered by the popular
press are shown here on the left
they can be trained to mimic the voices
of those with degenerative speech or
language disorders
allowing people to synthesize words in
their own voice well after it's been
lost
museums have brought dead artists back
to life using machine learning models to
interact with visitors in compelling
educational new ways and activists can
narrate their own stories more safely by
superimposing fabricated faces over
videos of themselves
allowing viewers to more and more easily
empathize without exposing anyone's
identities
but as these capabilities proliferate
there are just as many if not more
misuse cases that have arisen in the
real world
a few of those are called out here on
the left including one case in which a
scammer used an artificially generated
voice
of an executive's boss to fool the
executive into handing over two hundred
and forty thousand dollars
another in which deep fakers created
disturbingly realistic porno videos of
women using photos of them
involuntarily scraped from the internet
and the last one where a computer vision
model was
used to generate fake profile pictures
for a linkedin persona
that socially engineered so um senior
government officials
so there's existing evidence showing
that machine learning can be used to
generate synthetic media for evil
purposes
and in this talk we want to focus on one
specific technical methodology that's
been
that's drastically reduced the amount of
time and effort involved in making this
happen
transfer learning is a paradigm for
machine learning in which we start from
a large generic model that's been
pre-trained for an initial task where
copious data is available
we then leverage the model's acquired
knowledge to train it further on a
different
smaller data set so that it excels at a
subsequent related task
this process of training the model
further is referred to as fine tuning
which typically requires less resources
compared to training it from scratch
this is illustrated in the diagram on
the left normally when there are two
separate tasks that need to be solved
a data scientist has to wrangle two
separate data sets and train two
separate models
in this example a classifier on the left
and a regressor on the right
independently in order to ship them both
to production
and transfer learning shortcuts this
process if task 1 is related to task 2
in a way that task two can
benefit from the learned representations
of task one then we can actually use the
neural network train to perform task one
as a starting point for task two all of
our while requiring
significantly less initial data for test
two
you can think of this in more relatable
terms if i'm a professional tennis
player
i don't need to completely relearn how
to swing a racket in order to excel at
badminton
in a technical sense this fine tuning
can be accomplished in several ways
by lowering or freezing learning rates
by making architectural modifications to
the network or by
only allowing updates in specific
weights or layers
transfer learning works because early
layers produce features that capture
general attributes of the training data
set
whereas later layers capture properties
of the task it's being uh trained on
as such a common fine-tuning approach
simply involves freezing the early
layers from the pre-trained model
and retraining just the last layer using
a small data set for a new task
this is computationally much easier than
training a new model from scratch
since the most most of the learned
parameters are taken directly from the
pre-trained model
a much smaller number of parameters
needs to be learned during fine-tuning
so transfer learning allows certain
tasks to be toggled and take less time
with less effort and at a lower cost in
practice though this only works
well when people share their pre-trained
models lucky for us the culture machine
learning research nowadays has given
research to a rich open source model
ecosystem
it's become commonplace for
well-resourced industry and academic
researchers to release their model
checkpoints
when their state-of-the-art or sota work
gets accepted into
into a top tier conference typically
this code is released in the form of
github repositories with extensive
how-to guides
well-documented readmes and from my
experience they're generally very well
maintained with lots of attention being
paid to open issues and bug reports
oftentimes this allows other researchers
and grad students to easily reproduce
figures from the initial papers
and potentially use these models in
source code as a starting point for
their own research projects
this and this process plays out in the
loop ensuring a healthy
self-reinforcing model supply chain and
ultimately a quicker pace of scientific
innovation
however while this emergent model
sharing ecosystem beneficially lowers
the barrier to entry for non-experts it
also gives a leg up to those seeking to
leverage open source models for
malicious purposes
but just how much has this barrier to
entry been lowered though
as a starting point and hopefully this
statement shouldn't be too controversial
in security and especially the malware
space
we know that adversaries use open source
tools like cobalt strike
empire powershell and mimikats the same
concept holds for synthetic media
generation
if there are tools out there that make
this easier to do it's safe to assume
that those tools will be used
to put this into perspective we
experimented with a pre-trained natural
language
processing neural net called generative
pre-trained transformer or gpt-2
a pre-trained computer vision neural net
called stylegan2
and a pre-trained text-to-speech neural
net called speaker verification to
text-to-speech synthesizer
or sv2 tts on the right-hand side you'll
see a chart showing these three networks
that we'll dive deeper into on upcoming
slides
followed by the self-reported resources
that the authors used
in order to develop their respective
models so what's striking about these
figures
if and when they were available is that
the thousands of dollars weeks or months
of time
sheer training data set sizes and large
gpu
clusters puts pre-training well out of
the reach of script kitties and other
low-resourced adversaries style gan 2's
authors went above and beyond by more
realistically quantifying research
sutures from the id
inception all the way to the open source
release figures that might give
even well-resourced adversaries some
pause
in comparison the fine-tuning
experiments which i'll go into next
can be each done in a fraction of the
time cost
data size compute and flops compared to
these pre-training numbers
whether it's a cloud cloud-hosted
notebook with gpu access like google
collab pro
or an aws p3 instance reservation for
just a single day
we're talking on the order of just tens
of dollars to fine tune one of these
models
skill wise fine tuning is not
necessarily trivial but it's also not
brain surgery
authors or other open source
contributors often release additional
code and tutorials for how to fine tune
so that all you really need to have is
some working knowledge of python to do
this
furthermore it's important to point out
that each of these models were released
just within the last year
so our demonstration should be seen
through the lens of the present
however open source trends we point out
here are accelerating and the bar for
generating credible content will likely
lower even further in the years to come
so our first proof of concept will be in
the image domain where we'll demonstrate
how to fine-tune stylegam2
in order to generate custom portraits to
impersonate a targeted individual
we'll start with a brief overview of
stylegen2 which like its predecessor
stylegan
is architected as a generative
adversarial neural network organ
gans consists of two underlying networks
that are pit against each other hence
adversarial
a generator which generates new
instances of data and a discriminator
which evaluates these instances for
authenticity by deciding whether each
one belongs to the actual training data
set
or not in this way the gant can
synthesize indistinguishably fake images
based on a training data set
which for the open source version of
stylegan 2 used here was
flickr faces high quality or ffhq
a set of 70 000 human faces that are
diverse in terms of age
ethnicity and image background but also
in terms of the presence of accessories
like glasses earrings and hats
so if you generate images from this
off-the-shelf pre-trained model
you get results that look like this
alternatively you can visit this now
infamous website that will generate a
new sample from the pre-trained model
every time you refresh the page
in either case these images are not
present in style gain 2's original
training set
but are completely fabricated from the
generative model
these people in fact do not nor never
have existed
pre-trained style gan 2 outputs random
high quality
and highly diverse images that appear in
a similar orientation as the images that
it was pre-trained on
but it can also be fine-tuned on private
data sets
to generate outputs for a custom task
that i as a consumer of their open
source model am in control of
in this example we've downloaded a few
hundred images of tom hanks
from an online image search engine run
them through an automated cropping tool
called auto crop
so that each of them are fee centered
and 512 by 512 pixels as required by the
pre-trained model
and simply continue training style gain
2 by pointing it at this new smaller
data set
using a slightly slightly smaller
learning rate
after less than a day of training on a
single gpu we then generated outputs
from the fine-tune model
using a ready-to-use script available
from the original repo
the three images you're seeing of mr
hanks on the right are fake they're
generated from our fine-tuned model
you could see that they exhibit a high
level of resemblance to mr hanks and in
theory
we could collect cropped images from any
target of our choosing
and perform the same exercise to
generate arbitrarily many fake images of
them
in summary we can cheaply generate fake
portraits belonging to a target of our
choice
at scale from freely available images in
them on the internet
our second perfect concept will be in
the audio domain where we'll demonstrate
how to fine-tune sv2 tts
in order to generate custom voices from
arbitrary text to impersonate a targeted
individual
sp2 tts is a complex three-stage model
that's capable of performing voice
cloning
or text-to-speech from arbitrary text
inputs
to captured reference speech in real
time so
how does this system work it's comprised
of three underlying networks
first the speaker encoder is trained on
thousands of speakers in order to learn
an abstract representation of human
speech
and squeeze it into a compressed
embedding of floating point values
then the synthesizer which is based on
google's tacotron 2
takes texas input and returns a male
spectrogram which is a numerical
representation of an individual's voice
lastly
the vocoder which is based on google's
wavenet takes the mouse spectrogram and
converts it into an output waveform that
we can actually listen to
to emphasize how much data it took for
this model to learn useful
representations
the tools authors state that it was
pre-trained in over 2 500 audios of
hours of audio
from over 8 500 individual speakers
which is just a herculean task for the
people involved in that dataset
collection
so to demonstrate the kind of output
that pre-trained sv-22gs
model can generate i'll let it explain
itself using custom input text spoken by
an existing voice from their training
dataset
is cloning using an open source model
we're using a pre-trained speaker
encoder and providing custom input text
in the upper right white box
the pre-trained speaker encoder creates
a vector representation of the speaker's
voice
these embeddings can be seen in the
lower left heat
maps the voice embeddings and text
embeddings are combined by a synthesizer
to produce the mil spectrograms in the
lower right hand corner lastly a vocoder
takes these spectrograms and generates
an audio waveform which you are hearing
right now
so the pre-trained sv2 tts can be used
to generate speech
using arbitrary text from one of a few
hundred or so voices
one on which we demonstrated in the last
slide it can also be fine-tuned to
generate speech
in an arbitrary voice using arbitrary
text
all we need to do is collect some audio
samples which are freely available to
record via the internet
load up a few of the resulting m4a files
and use the pre-trained sv2 tts model
as a feature extractor to synthesize new
speech waveforms
listen to a snippet of one of those m4a
samples of tom hanks that we used for
fine tuning now
so examples of mr hanks like that one
and using them
as new inputs i'll demonstrate the
result of fine-tuning on a few texts
that were chosen by
us to resemble commentary that is that
is representative of some broader i o
themes
it demonstrates that we have a common
enemy but i would not count on this
relationship to go beyond
that this regime has shown it will not
hesitate to burden good relations for
its own financial gain
the leaked documents clearly show that
the foreign minister is corrupt and that
he has misdirected funds
the intelligence services have indicated
that these anti-government protests have
been organized by foreign entities
they are bent on stirring up trouble and
causing harm to the people of our
country
you'll notice that the timber of the
voice is very similar to mr hanks in
that it's able to synthesize tom's voice
from custom text
neither the text nor the voices have
been explicitly contained in any of the
original training data sets
in principle i could generate such cell
phone quality speech audio from
arbitrary targets
as long as i could acquire audio or
video files of them on the internet
and then make that speaker dictate from
arbitrary custom text that i control
it's also worth noting that i don't even
need gpu to do this the pre-trained
model was fine-tuned locally using my
laptop's own cpu course
which also suggests that that quality
improvements are possible as well
our last proof of concept will be in the
text domain where we'll generate we'll
demonstrate
how to fine-tune gpt2 in order to
generate custom social media posts
reflecting narratives stemming from a
social media i o campaign
gpt2 is an open source neural network
that was trained on the causal language
modeling task
the objective here is to predict the
next word in a sentence from previous
context
meaning that a trained model ends up
being capable of language generation
if the model can predict the next word
accurately it can be used in turn to
predict the following word
and then so on and so forth until
eventually the model produces fully
coherent sentences and paragraphs
in terms of architectures which you can
see here on the right side of the slide
transformers use attention to decrease
the time required to train on enormous
data sets
they also tend to model lengthy text and
scale better than previous generations
of feed-forward and recurrent neural
networks
again to emphasize the sheer amount of
trading data this thing was pre-trained
on
gbt-2's training data set consisted of
over 40 gigabytes of internet text data
extracted from over 8 million reputable
web pages based on high reddit karma
an example of gpt2's output generation
is pictured here for predictions primed
by the phase
it's disgraceful that the passage
displays relatively formal grammar
punctuation and structure that
corresponds to the text present within
their original
data set i won't read through the entire
passage now but you can visit our blog
post at the link below for more
technical details
or download this slide deck for closer
inspection overall though
the content is prosaic sets a scene up
between a few different people and
includes dialogue of their interactions
in a consistent and logical faction
so to make gpt2's output text appear
more more like social media posts with
their shorter length
informal grammar erratic punctuation and
syntactic works like hashtags and emojis
we fine-tuned it on a new language
modeling task using additional training
data
this data consisted of open source
social media posts from accounts
operated by russia's famed internet
research agency
or ira troll factory for fine tuning
we simply process social media posts
from these open source data sets
through the pre-trained model whose
activations were then fed through
adjustable weights into a linear output
layer
these fine-tuned text generations are
formatted like something we might expect
to encounter scrolling through social
media
they're short yet biting express
certainty and outrage regarding hot
button political issues
and contain emphases like an exclamation
point they also contain idiosyncrasies
like hashtags and emojis that
positionally manifest at the end of the
generated text
depicting a semantic style regularly
exhibited by actual users
so now that i've gone over some
background and technical proof of
concepts for how to leverage fine-tuning
of open source neural networks for
customizable purposes
i'll hand it over to lee to show you how
these capabilities can in turn be
leveraged for il campaigns
hi everyone once again my name is lee
foster and i run the information
operations analysis team at fireeye
which is dedicated to identifying and
tracking state-backed cyber-driven
influence campaigns online
now that phil has detailed the various
technical aspects of
synthetic media generation and
demonstrated the ease with which
existing models can be fine-tuned for
specialist use cases
i'm going to explore the risks that such
capabilities present in the information
operation space
now the misuse of synthetic media for io
has been hotly debated in various
circles for a few years now
some argue it will change the game to
such an extent that it will become
difficult
to ascertain whether anything we consume
online is true or false
others argue that the threat is way
overblown and that there are
much simpler yet still effective
influence and manipulation techniques
that negate the need for threat actors
to even entertain the use of synthetic
generation
however the majority of such debates are
often overly narrow
over prioritizing or focusing only on
deep fake videos
without sufficiently taking into account
other types of synthetic media
that are easier to produce from a
technical standpoint and can be more
readily integrated into the types of i o
campaigns my team identifies daily
so what kinds of techniques do we see io
actors use currently
they are numerous and while i don't have
time to touch them more than a tiny
proportion
it's useful to highlight a few current
tactics that we've observed that would
be particularly conducive to leveraging
synthetic media
last year for example my team uncovered
an influence campaign we termed
distinguished impersonator
which we assess is being conducted in
support of iranian political interests
one prominent campaign tactic involves
fabricating journalists personas
and reaching out to real world experts
and political figures
to disingenuously solicit audio and
video interviews
that advance an iranian political agenda
the link at the bottom of the slide here
directs to some of our public reporting
on this campaign if you're interested in
more detail
another common tactic we see is the
development of cross-platform online
personas that are used to infiltrate
target groups or disseminate fabricated
content to specific audiences
there are many many examples of such
activity out there
perhaps most famously the russian
internet research agency that phil
mentioned earlier
however another recent example is the
ghostwriter campaign that my team has
uncovered
a campaign that has leveraged website
compromises and used multiple
well-developed personas to disseminate
fabricated content
such as falsified correspondence of
officials in eastern europe in support
of russian security interests
another extremely common tactic is the
use of large networks of inauthentic
social media accounts pertaining
pretending to be random unaffiliated
individuals
which are then used to amplify political
narratives across platforms and
geographies
one prominent recent example of this are
the networks we have identified
operating on western social media
platforms pushing pro-china narratives
around issues such as democracy protests
in hong kong
and the covet 19 pandemic the link at
the bottom of this slide directs to a
presentation me and a colleague gave
on some of this activity last year
and finally other very common techniques
include the use of appropriated
photos of real individuals to backstop
false personas
and the repeated use of identical text
on social media to astroturf political
commentary
synthetic media has real potential to
exacerbate the use and effectiveness of
these tactics
for example we already regularly
observed the use of artificially
generated profile photos for inauthentic
social media accounts
and false personas but we can readily
envision an escalation of this tactic
in which convincing personas are created
using artificially generated profile
photos trained on images of real people
from a target group or geography
that correspond to say a particular
minority group and are used to instigate
political conflict or incite animosity
and violence
the use of synthetically generated audio
interviews in a campaign similar to the
pro iran distinguished impersonator
campaign i mentioned previously
trained on a real political expert's
voice would lower an
actor's burden by removing the need for
them to engage in direct outreach to
real people
which would also make attribution more
difficult for investigators by reducing
available leads such as contact details
and modes of communication between the
actor and target
and synthetic media would drastically
lower the barriers to actors
seeking to disseminate diverse
text-based
content at scale reducing the investment
required to manually create a large
corpus of content
and the need to repeatedly reuse
snippets of identical text
the unifying finding our theme behind
all these example use cases
is that they would materially help
thread actors scale campaigns
at low cost and better evade detection
fine-tuning in particular presents a
problem for blue teams as it allows
threat actors to evade classifiers and
detection models that are built for
pre-trained outputs
this is worrisome as as a would-be
threat actor my fine-tuning data sets
are private and unknown to the defender
at test time
to illustrate this we perform detection
experiments in the text domain using
gpt2
after releasing gpt2 openai released
source code and a pre-trained classifier
called roberta
which does not share the same
architecture or tokenizer as gpt2
but could reliably discriminate between
gpt2's own
output generations and its original
training data of high karma reddit posts
we use roberta first to verify their
findings that one can reliably
differentiate between fabricated gpt2
generated text
and the authentic gpt2 training data set
which is shown by the blue bars in the
plots on the right
the first plot shows the scores returned
by the detection model on text generated
by the pre-trained gpt-2 model
the fact that the distribution is skewed
all the way towards the right
close to one means the detection model
with a classification threshold of 0.5
can easily classify the generations as
fake
this results in an accuracy score of
over 97 for the detection model
as shown in the lower right plot however
when we perform the same exercise using
the pre-trained classifier to try to
differentiate our fine-tuned io
generations that feel
detailed earlier the accuracy dipped to
around 78
as the distribution of scores output by
the classifier for these fine-tuned
generations
shifts closer to chance i8.5 as shown in
the red in the top right plot
so if thread actors were to fine-tune on
a custom data set
they themselves collated this would
present a problematic asymmetry between
the data used to create the synthetic
generations and the data with which
blue teams would have access to or
knowledge of with which to build a
commensurate detection model
so as mentioned previously we already
frequently see i o campaigns use
synthetically generated profile
photos for inauthentic accounts on
social media
and here are some examples of recent
intelligence reports on i o activity my
team has detected
that i screenshotted to give you a sense
of both the scale and
diversity of this current use case so
we've seen
the use of synthetic profile images in
the pro china networks that i
mentioned previously in a recent
operation that appeared designed to
support government officials in a region
of argentina
to backstop a fabricated journalist
persona that was used to amplify
awareness of the defacement of a news
agency's twitter account in kuwait
and in a social media operation that
promoted cuban government political
interests
and this is what that looks like in
practice along with some of the markers
of inauthenticity that often clue us
into the images being artificially
generated
you can see in these examples from one
of the pro-china networks the common
format of a closely cropped headshot
with a blurred background
anomalies around the ears and neck and
difficulties with fully rendering
glasses
phantom hair strings being generated
outside a credible area
common issues with the rendering of
earrings and shoulders as you can see in
this image that was
used in the argentina related activity
set
and hilariously in in these last two
examples
the operators behind the pro cuba
network didn't even bother to crop out
the text placed by the this person does
not exist at all
stating that the images were generated
with style again prior to use
now one of the criticisms that is
regularly leveled at concerns about the
misuse of synthetic media
is the high level of effort required on
the part of malicious actors
however it is important to note that in
many cases the difficult technical work
has already been done by organizations
and individuals who have developed and
released
either to use applications and services
or source code that performs generations
for a number of non-malicious
motivations
including hobbyism i.e personal learning
or simply for the fun of it
an ethos of the open sharing of
technical research
and direct commercial applications for
marketing and advertising
corporate communications and training
materials and even for the creation of
assets in video games and other
consumable media
synthetic media as a service is
particularly worrisome
as it is important to note that we have
already seen actors outsource the
organization and conduct of specific
influence campaigns
to public relations firms and other
organizations that possess a nuanced
understanding of
how to target audiences and create
engaging content
for example facebook has announced
multiple takedowns of accounts and pages
on their platforms
engaging in foreign interference that
were operated by pr firms
last month they removed assets operated
by a canada-based firm
but engaged in election-related
influence activity in south america
and in may removed assets operated by a
tunisia-based firm
that poses locals and independent news
outlets in sub-saharan africa
it does not take much for io actors to
make a similar leap to the use of
commercial providers of synthetic media
generation
to augment their campaigns and further
bypass the technological barriers to
entry
beyond the use of transfer learning that
phil detailed earlier
indeed the the adoption of commercial
outsourcing would provide numerous
benefits to i o actors
including providing multiple avenues for
operational deployment
which would reduce direct ties back to
sponsors and make campaign attribution
more difficult
for investigators increasing the
diversity and specialization of both
assets and content by
drawing on external expertise lowering
the investment and expertise required by
a sponsor themselves to partake in
synthetic media augmented io
and adding multiple layers of anonymity
and plausible deniability against
accusations of responsibility for any
particular campaign
so what should we take away from
everything that phil and i have
discussed
throughout this talk first and perhaps
obviously it highlights the need for the
research community to focus attention on
the development of technical detection
and mitigation capabilities
there are already some organizations
focused on this mission and multiple
avenues
of research that can and should be
pursued these include statistical and
machine learning approaches to detecting
synthetic media
as well as the identification of
fingerprints and forensic indicators
such as text-based grammatical and
image-based positional indicators
that can be detected both manually and
in automated ways
other avenues of effort focus on the
content authentication side of the
challenge
developing ways of allowing producers to
verify
mark or sign legitimate content for
example through the insertion of
trackable metadata
at the content generation stage and
similarly ways for the developers
of synthetic generation tools to
watermark those tools is output
and then of course there are hotly
debated policy considerations around
content moderation social media account
registration authentication
and fact checking that are currently
nowhere close to being resolved
technical approaches to the challenge
alone won't suffice however and there's
the human aspect to all of this
which we've tagged patching human
perception this includes the importance
of building a community-wide
approach to mitigating the human impacts
of synthetic media augmented io
and ensuring communities of researchers
coalesce around approaches to overcoming
the challenges of detection
threat modeling how synthetic media may
be used in future i o campaigns
and encouraging commercial providers of
synthetic generation tools to
acknowledge the potential for their
abuse by threat actors
and verifying customer use cases prior
to service provision
indeed the sankey diagram here is the
output of an exercise we did in which we
surveyed the offerings of some current
commercial providers of synthetic media
generation services
which we define as those that explicitly
offer paid services instead of
or in addition to free tools
looking at image video and voice
generation offerings
we asked two questions what specific use
cases
do these providers market themselves
towards and do they explicitly
acknowledge the potential for misuse of
their services
through any kind of ethics statement
of the 14 companies we looked at less
than half had any kind of ethics
statement
perhaps equally if not more concerning
some firms did not even feign to market
themselves to any particular use case
whatsoever
effectively leaving it up to end users
to determine the purposes their
synthetic generations might even be used
for
only a couple of companies specifically
in the voice generation space
explicitly stated that they verify and
sign off on their customers as end use
cases before agreeing to provide
services
and there also remains the need for
raising awareness and educating
consumers of online content
about the risks of synthetic media in a
responsible manner that doesn't
misrepresent the threat
as well as developing legal and
regulatory approaches to dealing with
information operations and synthetic
media
the final takeaway we want to raise is
that we are really in the calm before
the storm stage of synthetic media's use
in
information operations as phil
highlighted these capabilities continue
to become
cheaper both monetarily and in terms of
computing power required
easier more pervasive and outputs ever
more credible
and there are numerous trends that risk
further escalation of
threat the amount of effort required to
fine-tune existing models or train new
models will continue to decrease
multimodal content will likely one day
incorporate synthetically generated text
images and audio in single pieces of
content
image generation capabilities and even
commercial services are already
moving beyond merely headshots and
facial generations to full body shots
and advanced video generations
and end users will enjoy increasing
control over and ease of content
generation
both through being able to steer
generations towards particular
attributes at more granular levels
and by being able to leverage an
increasing amount of low code or no code
applications for content creation and
one really important factor to keep in
mind is user susceptibility to
misleading content
some criticize the threat of synthetic
media as being overblown because there
are still telltale signs of
inauthenticity in contemporary
synthetic generations but even if we set
aside all the trends i just mentioned it
is critical for us to acknowledge that
synthetic generations don't need to be
overwhelmingly credible to have that
desired effect
people are accustomed to consuming short
authoritative
error-riddled social media text at speed
without dwelling too much on its
linguistic features or origin
they are accustomed to consuming poor
quality audio and video snippets
and most users are unlikely to give a
twitter's a twitter account's profile
image
more than a cursory glance as they
scroll through their feed and ingest
the written content at rapid speed all
of this points to a crucial
consideration
the quality bar does not need to be
particularly high when it comes to
synthetic generations it only needs to
remain good enough
for a majority of users to not question
it in a world characterized by
high speed high volume information
consumption
so to summarize fine tuning for
generative impersonation in the text
image and audio domains can be performed
by non-experts and it can be weaponized
for offensive
social media driven information
operations detection attribution and
response is challenging in scenarios
where actors can anonymously generate
and distribute
credible fake content using proprietary
training data sets
and we as a community can and should
help ai researchers policy makers and
other stakeholders
mitigate the harmful effects of open
source models
we'd like to thank you for your time
today and look forward to answering your
questions
all right folks so thanks for your
interest and attention in this talk
um see a few questions in the chat uh we
have a few minutes here so if you have
some more please get those in first want
to address you
sorry about the audio quality so um
what i'll do is i'll drop a link to our
blog post that should have the audio
samples there
for people to take a listen to um so
i'll do that now
and uh also so someone had asked about
the availability of a paper um this blog
post would be the closest thing to that
from our side
if the question was more pertaining to
the papers we discussed
in the talk um our slides will be
available
on the black hat website uh i think soon
and um we made sure to put references at
the bottom of each of those slides
otherwise you can just google these one
of the beauties of this
uh prison or i guess the thesis here is
that these are all open source
all these models we used so um not
necessarily trying to make this a how-to
guide for bad actors but
you yourself can go up and try and play
around with these things
but uh but otherwise let me hand it off
to lee for all of
these thanks phil i know we've only got
like a minute and a half here so quickly
breeze through the questions that
uh came up um for us here so robert asks
about companies like uh liar bird
have made much of their willingness to
restrict the sale of model output
um what are your thoughts on these kinds
of models uh from the perspective of
future
concerns um as i alluded to in one of
the slides there we did note that a
couple of firms in the in the voice
space
um actually do their use cases and
uh confirm that the consumer has the
legal right to use the voice that
they're trying to um
fabricate and so i do think that this is
a good model
um in general the question is how do you
try to normalize this
across this entire industry uh when you
have kind of
very different tiers of of players here
patrick asks uh for the pr marketing
firms engaged in this have you found a
con pricing model
um if your question is about the uh
outsourcing of
of i o campaigns in general to pr firms
um no um and i would presume that those
are kind of
custom spec but on the synthetic
generation a couple of
models did emerge um one is kind of a
timed use model
uh and access to a services api
another is kind of a custom quote
depending on the scale of the project
and then finally gabriella asks
have you seen any liability cases for
using ai
images that actually look like a real
person if you're talking from a a legal
perspective
no not that i'm aware of um but
definitely you know something
to uh kind of look into i think i'm for
sure
i think we're out of time now um so if
there are other questions please hit us
up
uh on email or twitter and we'll be
happy to chat with you